<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Afghanistan" ColCode="afg" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="af" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Afghanistan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although occupying the same latitudes as South-Central USA, the mountainous nature of much of Afghanistan produces a far colder climate. Being landlocked, there are considerable differences in temperature between summer and winter, and day and night in lowland regions and in the valleys; the southern lowlands in particular have intensely hot summers and harsh winters. Spring and autumn are the most hospitable times to visit: April-June, and September-October.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier is Ariana Afghan Airways (<a href="http://www.flyariana.com/" target="_blank">www.flyariana.com</a>), based at Kabul airport.</p>
<p>Kam Air (<a href="http://www.kamair.com" target="_blank">www.kamair.com</a>) also operates local routes between Kabul and outlying cities such as Herat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Much of the Afghan road network was destroyed during the 2001 conflict, but large parts have been restored, including&nbsp;the Kabul-Kandahar highway and the Kandahar-Herat highway.</p><p>International Driving Permit required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public buses operate within Kabul, but the service is unreliable, with many of the buses alling into a state of disrepair.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Ariana Afghan Airlines (FG)<em> </em>(<a href="http://www.flyariana.com/" target="_blank">www.flyariana.com</a>). There is a United Nations presence in the country, with aid mission flights in operation. For further information, consult a local embassy or the British Foreign and Commonwealth Office (<a href="http://www.fco.gov.uk/" target="_blank">www.fco.gov.uk</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>AFN200. Children under two years of age are exempt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Kabul International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 16km (10 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There is generally a severe shortage of lines for operator-connected international calls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is coverage in cities such as Kabul and Herat, and in other small pockets throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The first public Internet service opened in Kabul in late 2003, and several post offices have since been fitted with Internet connections.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Afghanistan's media were seriously restricted under Taleban rule. In late 2001, <em>Radio Afghanistan</em> returned to the air in Kabul after the Taleban deserted the capital. One of the first signs of change was the music broadcast over <em>Radio Afghanistan</em> for the first time in five years. Days later, <em>Kabul TV</em> was back on the air, with a woman presenting the news. Afghanistan's newly-invigorated press enjoys freedom of expression, although print runs are small. A law bans media criticism of Islam and other religions.<em> Kabul Times</em> is an official, English-language newspaper; <em>Kabul Weekly </em>is a private, English-language publication. Foreign radio stations on the air in Kabul include <em>BBC</em>, <em>Radio France Internationale </em>and <em>Deutsche Welle; </em>USA-funded stations include <em>Radio Free Afghanistan</em>, which uses the name <em>Azadi Radio</em>, and the <em>Voice</em> <em>of America</em>, which brands its Dari and Pashto broadcasts as <em>Radio Ashna</em> ('Friend').</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the resilient capital, Kabul</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Since the US invasion it is estimated that one-third of Afghanistan's public buildings and roughly 40% of its houses have been destroyed. Miraculously Kabul has survived much of the carnage and there's still plenty to admire in the ancient Afghan capital. There are beautiful parks, the ancient walls of the citadel, Bala Hissar, and several newly restored museums.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the recovering Kabul Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Though the museum's contents have been dramatically depleted over the years, the beleaguered Kabul Museum still has a good amount of artefacts on display, including Greco-Bactrian Buddha statues, and a marble basin from Kandahar often referred to as Buddha's Begging Bowl.</p>]]><p><b>Gawp at the “Red City” of Shahr-i-Zohak</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take in Shahr-i-Zahak, also known as the "Red City", about 17km (11 miles) from Bamiyan. Here lies one of Afghanistan's most breath-taking ancient citadels, situated atop a cliff overlooking the intersection of the Bamiyan and Kalu rivers. The mud-brick towers rise eerily from the rock face, as though natural formations.</p>]]><p><b>Hike through the Valley of Paghman</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If the security situation permits it, head to the rugged Valley of Paghman, which is about 90 minutes by road from the capital. Here many of Kabul's wealthiest residents once kept second houses and you can see why – the landscape is spectacular. Today, alas, the area is somewhat quiet.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the Hindu Kush</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take some time to explore the Hindu Kush, a wild and remote region consisting of two huge mountain ranges. Although travelling by car is possible, the steepness of the routes makes vehicles prone to breakdowns. For those who make the journey, the mountains, valleys and lakes provide stunning scenery.</p>]]><p><b>Scale the Bibi Mahru Hill</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It was at the top of Bibi Mahru Hill that Moghul ruler Babur first looked over Kabul. This is a popular spot for walking and for the views of the lands around. There's also an Olympic-size swimming pool atop it, but problems with pumping water up hill mean that it's rarely full.</p>]]><p><b>See Afghan art in the National Gallery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Displaying a range of historic artwork and more contemporary pieces, the National Gallery in Kabul has, like the Kabul Museum, seen its fair share of destruction. However, many pieces have been salvaged, and the staff offer guided tours around the exhibitions.</p>]]><p><b>Take a trip to Jalalabad</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If the security situation permits, visit Jalalabad, the capital of the Nangarhar Province, which used to be a pretty winter resort, before decades of war saw it become a no-go area. Today, it is awash with cypress trees and flowering shrubs.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Ka Faroshi bird market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In a little street tucked behind the Pul-e Khishti Mosque in Kabul, you'll find this market selling birds of all shapes and sizes, including <em>kowk </em>(fighting partridge), which are made to fight on Friday mornings with bystanders betting on the winner. Some visitors may find the <em>kowk </em>fights disturbing, but it remains a much-loved tradition here.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around Babur's Gardens (Bagh-e Babur)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This striking and historic garden in Kabul was created under the first Mughal ruler Babur in the 1500s. Inside the high walls, visitors can explore 11 hectares (27 acres) of greenery, assorted flora, a pavilion, a marble mosque and Babur's tomb, which reads the inscription: "If there is a paradise on Earth, it is this, it is this, it is this!"</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at the unique Sultani Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Neighbouring the National Gallery in Kabul, the Sultani Museum hosts an extraordinary collection of Afghan artefacts put together by gold trader and arts dealer Ahmad Shah Sultani, who assembled most of these items while in exile in London. His museum hosts an array of early-Islamic manuscripts, precious coins, ancient pottery, woodcarvings and much more.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$11.7 billion (2008).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fruit, nuts, carpets, natural gas and cotton.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Capital goods, food, textiles and petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan, the EU, India, Russia, Kenya and Korea (Rep).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Decades of continuous war have completely wrecked the Afghan economy. Reconstruction of the agricultural sector, which accounted for about half of GDP, has been severely hampered by abandonment of farms and the huge number of minefields. This has led to falling food stocks and Afghanistan has had to rely on foreign aid. The lack of funding has led many farmers to rely on growing opium and selling it illegally to survive - a practice the current government is trying to end. <br /><br />There have been some positive advancements in recent years: in January 2003, Afghanistan signed a trilateral trade agreement with Iran and India that designated the Iranian port of Chabahar as a major port for Afghanistan. In May 2008, Afghanistan agreed a US$2.8 billion contract with China for a project on copper extraction, which it is estimated will provide 20,000 jobs.  <br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Price bargaining is expected and oral agreements are honoured. Formal wear is expected and meetings should be pre-arranged.<br /><br />Business is a personal thing in Afghanistan, and you should try to forge a strong relationship with your business partner. Bear in mind that prestige and honour are hugely important in Afghanistan, so never intentionally - or unintentionally - damage these. <br /></p><p>Generally Sat-Wed 0800-1200 and 1300-1630, Thurs 0800-1330</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Afghanistan Investment Support Agency</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 103 404
					Website:http://www.aisa.org.af/
					Address: ,Opposite the Ministry of Foreign Affairs,Kabul,]]><b>Afghan Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 025 854
					Website:http://www.acci.org.af/
					Address: ,Chaman-e-Huzuri,Kabul,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Indian cuisine has had a huge influence on the Afghan kitchen, with much of the country's diet revolving around various rice-based dishes, while n<em>aan </em>bread is eaten with most meals. Despite this, Afghanistan is country of enormous ethnic and geographic diversity, and its food reflects this.</p>
<p>The country's varied climate means that almost any food can grow here, although Afghanistan's main crops are wheat, maize and rice; these feature heavily in the country's food. Dishes also include plenty of coriander, onions, tomatoes, garlic and fresh yogurt. A whole range of fruits, particularly pomegranates, grapes and the local melon, are widely consumed, too.</p>
<p>Apart from curries, rice dishes and Middle Eastern influences, Afghanistan also has its own kind of pasta in the form of <em>mantu</em> &ndash; meat-filled dumplings that are steamed and served with sauce. In Kabul, more refined approaches to traditional Afghan cooking can be found, as well as international influences.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pulao</strong>: Steamed rice with raisins and carrots, usually served with a side dish of meat, vegetables or beans.<br />
<strong>Qabli pulao</strong>: A popular variant of pulao served with lamb.<br />
<strong>Shorma</strong>: Soup using various different recipes such as.<br />
<strong>Mantu</strong>: Meat-filled dumplings steamed and topped with a sauce of yogurt, mint, lemon and garlic.<br />
<strong>Fruit: </strong>Afghanis eat plenty of seasonal fruit, most notably melons from Mazar-e Sharif and Maimana, grapes and pomegranates from Kandahar, and oranges from Jalalabad.<br />
<strong>Kababs</strong>: Lamb kebab typically served with naan, and rarely rice.<br />
<strong>Lamb chops</strong>: Grilled and cooked with spices.<br />
<strong>Qorma</strong>: A rich stew cooked with onions and a variety of fruits, vegetables and spices.<br />
<strong>Kofta</strong>: Afghan-style meatballs.<br />
<strong>Chai</strong>: Indian-style tea.<br />
<strong>Dugh</strong>: Yoghurt flavoured with rose water and salt.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Service is normally included.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Illegal</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good buys include Turkman hats, Kandahar embroidery, Istaff pottery, local glassware from Herat, nomad jewellery, handmade carpets and rugs, Nuristani woodcarving, silkware, brass, copper and the ubiquitous rug.</p><p>Generally Sat-Wed 0800-1200 and 1300-1630, Thurs 0800-1330.</p><p>Many craft items may only be exported under licence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Kabul there are very few hotels that currently measure up to Western standards; good options are the Kabul Inter Continental, and the Kabul Serena Hotel. Only basic accommodation is available outside Kabul. In some rural areas there may still be hotels run by the provincial authority, but these are of a low standard. You may be able to stay at local tea houses for a small fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Kabul there are very few hotels that currently measure up to Western standards; good options are the Kabul Inter Continental, and the Kabul Serena Hotel. Only basic accommodation is available outside Kabul. In some rural areas there may still be hotels run by the provincial authority, but these are of a low standard. You may be able to stay at local tea houses for a small fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Kabul there are very few hotels that currently measure up to Western standards; good options are the Kabul Inter Continental, and the Kabul Serena Hotel. Only basic accommodation is available outside Kabul. In some rural areas there may still be hotels run by the provincial authority, but these are of a low standard. You may be able to stay at local tea houses for a small fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical care was very limited before the 2001 conflict but now medicines are in even shorter supply and many hospitals have been damaged or destroyed. Doctors and hospitals demand immediate cash payment for most services. Medical insurance, covering emergency evacuation, is essential. International aid groups operate in some cities and villages.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against hepatitis B and tuberculosis are sometimes advised. Hepatitis E is present. Typhus occurs and trachoma is common. Giardiasis and other waterborne diseases are common. Diarrhoeal disease and other gastrointestinal infections are common causes of ill health, especially in hotter months. Outbreaks of meningococcal disease have been reported. Rabies&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations.  During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Revolution Day; Loss of the Muslim Nation :
							28 April </p><p>Independance Day :
							19 August </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Afghanistan without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; A reasonable amount of tobacco products and perfume for personal use.</p>
<p>Advance permission is required if importing agrochemicals and pesticides, animals and animal products, armoured vehicles, endangered species, foodstuffs, fresh fruit and vegetables, military equipment, films and DVDs, ozone depleting substances, pharmaceuticals and medical equipment, printed publications, seeds, telecommunications equipment, or veterinary equipment and medicines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports to Afghanistan include alcoholic drinks, arms and ammunition, chemical fertilisers, cotton seeds, pork and pork products, drugs and plastic bags.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must seek authorisation from the local authorities before exporting antiques. Buying artefacts from the Kabul Museum is illegal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Afghani (AFN) = 100 puls. Notes are in denominations of AFN1,000, 500, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. The US Dollar is also widely accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not accepted. There are several ATMs in Kabul that dispense US Dollars and Afghanis but many are located in military camps where access is limited. The Intercontinental Hotel has an ATM that accepts Visa credit and debit cards between 0830-1900 daily. It is recommended that visitors carry sufficient funds in US Dollars.</p><p>There are several ATMs in Kabul that dispense US Dollars and Afghanis but many are located in military camps where access is limited. The Intercontinental Hotel has an ATM that accepts Visa credit and debit cards between 0830-1900 daily.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is not currently recommended to take traveller's cheques to Afghanistan, since they are not widely accepted and may take up to two weeks to clear. If you must take traveller's cheques, it is advised to take them in US Dollars, Euros or Pounds Sterling denominations.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Sat-Wed 0800-1200 and 1300-1630, Thurs 0800-1330.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To visit Afghanistan, a passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry tourist or business visa: &pound;140; multiple-entry business visa: &pound;420 (six months) or &pound;800 (one year).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry tourist visa: 60 days in three months.</p>
<p>Single-entry business visa: 30 days in three months; multiple-entry: 60 days in six months or 180 days in a year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). You can apply in person or by post, but need to book an appointment at the embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing takes two weeks, with a three-day fast-track service available for an extra charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's not usually possible to extend a tourist or business visa. If you're travelling on a different type of visa, you need to apply to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs in Kabul for an extension.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[33.832998]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[66.025009]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>652,225 sq km (251,773 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>33,369,945 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>49.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kabul.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Landlocked Afghanistan shares its borders with Turkmenistan, Uzbekistan and Tajikstan to the north, China to the northeast, Pakistan to the east and south and Iran to the west. On the eastern tip of the Iranian plateau, central Afghanistan is made up of a tangled mass of mountain chains. The Hindu Kush is the highest range, rising to more than 7,500m (24,600ft). The Bamian Valley separates the Hindu Kush from Koh-i-Baba, the central mountain range and source of the Helmand River. To the north and southwest of these mountains, alluvial plains provide fertile agricultural soil. To the northeast is Kabul, the capital; the other major cities are Jalalabad, Kandahar, Mazar-i-Sharif and Herat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Islamic majority with 89% Sunni Muslims, 9% Shi'ite, and Hindu and Sikh minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Outside Kabul, Afghanistan is still very much a tribal society. Religion and traditional customs have a strong influence within the family, and there are strict male and female roles in society. It is considered insulting to show the soles of the feet. Women are advised to wear trousers or long skirts and avoid revealing clothing. Homosexuality is illegal, as is alcohol, narcotics and pork products. Handshaking is an acceptable form of greeting, though nose-rubbing and embracing are more traditional. Eye contact between men and women should be avoided.<strong><br /><br /><strong>Photography: </strong></strong>Care should be taken when using cameras. Military installations should not be photographed.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Supplies may be seriously affected and powercuts frequent. European-style plugs with two round pins are most commonly used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Ashraf Ghani since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Ashraf Ghani since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Important ancient kingdoms of Afghanistan include the Median and Achaemenid Empires. In the 4th century BC Alexander the Great reached the country, leaving behind a Hellenic legacy that would linger for centuries.</p>
<p>The Kushan Empire from the 1st to the 3rd centuries AD found Afghanistan at perhaps its ancient peak, expanding through <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>, and Hinduism and Buddhism became prominent in the country. That was until the 7th century, when Islam reached the country. Although Arab armies made inroads into the country, full-scale conquest was difficult due to the resilience of mountain tribes.</p>
<p>Genghis Khan and Timur were successful conquerors, in the 13th and 14th centuries respectively, while Babur, a descendant of Timur, used Kabul as a base to conquer much of India in the 16th century. The Persians also held sway for a time, until in the 18th century an Afghan tribal leader called Ahmad Shah united much of present-day Afghanistan.</p>
<p>For nearly a century starting in 1838, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Britain</a> attempted to control Afghanistan, but in 1919, the country declared independence. By the 1950s, the Afghan government was courting economic and military assistance form the Soviet Union. In 1963, a constitutional monarchy was declared, leading to destabilising power struggles, then a republic was declared after a coup by Mohammed Daud. The Soviets, however, had other ideas, and ousted him in what became a proxy struggle of the Cold War.</p>
<p>As the Soviet Union attempted to strengthen the new regime, the US-backed Mujahedeen destabilised the country, leading to the Soviet invasion of 1979. By 1985, half of the country's population was displaced by war. Although a peace treaty was signed in 1988, the 1990s saw the civil war continue.</p>
<p>In 1996, the Taliban seized control of Kabul and much of the country. Then, following 9/11, the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> invaded Afghanistan. Elections followed the ousting of the Taliban, but the country remains highly unstable, with whole regions still controlled by warlords. The US has technically withdrawn military forces, but a large number of personnel remain to support the Afghan army and security services.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Human civilisation in Afghanistan dates at least as far back as 4000 BC.<br />
&bull; The territory has always been an important link between the Middle East and civilisations in India, Central and Eastern Asia, making it the victim of various conquering armies.<br />
&bull; In May 2015, representatives from the Taliban and the Afghan government held informal talks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Afghanistan]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(0) 700 102 000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinafghanistan.fco.gov.uk/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(0) 700 102 000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Sun-Thurs 0830-1630.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Wazir Akbar Khan<br/>15th Street Roundabout<br/>Kabul<br/>PO Box 334<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Afghanistan in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 483 6410.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofafghanistan.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 483 6410.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2341 Wyoming Avenue<br/>Washington DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Afghanistan in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>020) 7589 8891/2 (consular section). </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.afghanistanembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>020) 7589 8891/2 (consular section). </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600, 0930-1330 (visa applications).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>31 Princes Gate<br/>London<br/>SW7 1QQ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Afghanistan in the USA - Consular Office]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 298 9125.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofafghanistan.org/page/visa</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 298 9125.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>Suite 216, 2233 Wisconsin Avenue<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An essential stop on the hippie trail in the 1960s, beautiful Afghanistan has been devastated by years of war. Renowned for its epic countryside and rugged mountains, travellers came to interact with local communities, breathe clear mountain air and explore ancient sites such as the giant Buddha statues of Bamiyan. They were happy times.</p>
<p>Sadly, those days are gone. The Taliban destroyed most of the country&rsquo;s monuments, while the US and its allies ruined what was left of Afghanistan&rsquo;s creaking infrastructure. With thousands of peacekeeping troops still operating in the country and pockets of fighting continuing, it will be some time before Afghanistan is restored to its former glory.</p>
<p>Consequently, travellers are advised against visiting Afghanistan. Nevertheless, some adventurous tour companies are offering trips to the country, and there have been reports in some quarters of increased bookings and interest. Afghan authorities put tourist numbers at less than 20,000, though they claim it is slowly increasing.</p>
<p>Tending to take in the historic but war-ravaged city of Kabul, mountain villages, ancient fortifications and some surviving Buddhist sites, tours are generally conducted in small groups and tend to be expensive.</p>
<p>Guides make the point that for many ordinary Afghans, life has continued much the same as it has for centuries. Indeed of the few travellers that do make it to the country, they tell of the surprising normality of Kabul, with little signs of the instability reported by international media. The country also remains a fascinating melting pot of ethnic and tribal groups.</p>
<p>Despite hopes that tourism could return to this historic country, almost every area of Afghanistan remains dangerous as insurgents continue to threaten the fragile democracy. If you do decide to travel to Afghanistan, personal security is recommended, as is a reputable tour company and full travel insurance. Always check foreign office advice before travelling.</p>An essential stop on the hippie trail in the 1960s, beautiful Afghanistan has been devastated by years of war. Renowned for its epic countryside and rugged mountains, travellers came to interact with local communities, breathe clear mountain air and explore ancient sites such as the giant Buddha statues of Bamiyan. They were happy times. 

Sadly, those days are gone. The Taliban destroyed most of the country's monuments, while the US and its allies ruined what was left of Afghanistan's infrastructure. With thousands of peacekeeping troops still operating in the country and pockets of fighting continuing, it will be some time before Afghanistan is restored to its former glory.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
