<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Albania" ColCode="alb" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="al" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Albania]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Albania has a Mediterranean climate, with hot, dry summers and cool, wet winters in the lowlands. In the highlands, snow can fall from November until March; mountain towns are very cold at this time of year.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dependent on the time of year and regions of the country to be visited, and also on the activities planned. For outdoor activities in the mountains, good waterproofs and warm layers should be carried at all times of year. On the coast in summer, long trousers and a light jacket will often be required in the evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no internal flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only internal boat journey is the Komani-Fierza ferry, run by Berisha Ferry (<a href="http://www.komanilakeferry.com" target="_blank">www.komanilakeferry.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The hub of the national railway network is Durr&euml;s. From there, services operate to Tirana, Shkodra, Vlora and Pogradeci. Trains are diesel, infrequent (except between Tirana and Durr&euml;si) and slow.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Successive Albanian governments have invested heavily in highway improvement and the main inter-city routes are of a reasonable standard.</p>
<p>However, Albania is a mountainous country and some towns will be connected by relatively narrow, winding roads for the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>4-wheel drive is not normally required.</p><p>An<strong> </strong>International Driving Permit (technically this should be accompanied with a certified translation) and national driving licence are required. If bringing your own car into Albania, you should ascertain before departure that your insurance is valid there; emergency breakdown cover is also worth considering.</p><p>Speed limits are generally 40kph (25mph) in towns, 80kph (50mph) outside built-up areas, 90kph (56mph) on major roads and 110kph (68mph) on motorways.&nbsp;</p><p>You can hire cars in Tirana from the usual international companies, although they are expensive compared to northern Europe and North America. It may be cheaper, and is certainly less stressful, to arrange a chauffeur-driven car in advance through one of the Tirana-based travel agencies.</p><p>Speed limits are generally 40kph (25mph) in towns, 80kph (50mph) outside built-up areas, 90kph (56mph) on major roads and 110kph (68mph) on motorways.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taxis are plentiful and relatively economical for short journeys within city limits. Urban buses are very cheap but usually very crowded. In Tirana, there is a flat fare for any bus journey; within the city centre, taxis also have a flat fare, which you should agree with the driver before setting off.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Albania</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">shkodra</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Albania</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">korccedila</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Albania</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">gjirokastra</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Albania</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">durreumlsi</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Airways (BA) (<a href="http://www.ba.com/" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) has a year-round direct service to Tirana from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London Gatwick</a>.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/albania/tirana-international-airport-nene-tereza">Tirana International Airport Nene Tereza</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Tirana - 3 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong>&nbsp;Durr&euml;s and Vlor&euml;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no international passenger services at present.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guarded parking is essential; mid-range hotels (and better) usually provide this to guests. If bringing your own car, make sure your insurance covers you for driving in Albania.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>City codes: Tirana 042, Durresi 0522, Elbasani 0542, Shkodra 0222, Gjirokastra 0842, Korça 0822.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage is good, except in the most remote, mountainous areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost every sizeable town in Albania has public Internet access, usually via an Internet cafe. Some hotels, especially in Tirana, have broadband connections in the guest rooms; a few have Wi-Fi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Albania has a good diversity of print and electronic media, although the market is undeveloped which means that all privately-owned outlets are dependent to at least some extent on government advertising. Newspapers are often very partisan; indeed, three widely available papers are published by political parties. Political parties, religious groups and state bodies aren't allowed to own private TV and radio stations. The <em>Albanian Daily News</em> and <em>Tirana Times </em>are English-language newspapers; some Albanian newspapers contain a few pages in English; these include <em>Gazeta Shqiptare</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Albanian postal service is not 100% reliable, although it is not especially bad either. Important documents should be sent by courier. DHL and Federal Express have offices in Tirana and a few other cities. An internal courier service called ACS operates within Albania.</p><p>The central post office in Tirana is open from 0730 to 2000 Mon-Sun.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be on the look out for birds of prey</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pack the binoculars and bird watch in the coastal wetlands of Karavastaja. Part of the Divjake-Karavasta National Park, the lagoon is the westernmost breeding site of the Dalmatian pelican. For further twitching take to Kune-Vaini, the nature reserve bestrides the Drini River and is home to spotted eagles, spoonbills and herons.</p>]]><p><b>Cycle the mountains for unbeatable views</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cycle through the Gramoz mountains from Korça to Përmeti. The moderate ascents are easy on the thighs and the resulting views easy on the eyes. Allow time to enjoy the dramatic landscape of sweeping valleys, rivers and snowy peaks. To refuel, sample the local food in restaurants along the way.</p>]]><p><b>Delve into Tirana's communist past</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For nearly 50 years, Albania was under Communist rule. Although the regime collapsed in 1990, many of Tirana's communist sights remain, including the murals and statues in the city centre; the house where Enver Hoxha lived; and the Pyramid, built as his mausoleum. Take a bus or taxi up to the Martyrs' (Partisans') Cemetery, with its statue of Mother Albania.</p>]]><p><b>Explore ancient archaeological sites</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See interesting and accessible archaeological sites, such as the abandoned ancient Greek city of Apollonia and the steep-sided Roman amphitheatre in Durrësi. Byllis may be a little harder to get to, but the Greek ruins, mountain surrounds and views over the Vjosë River valley make it well worth the effort.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Ottoman architecture of Gjirokastra and Berati</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the well-preserved Ottoman cities of Gjirokastra and Berati with their unique domestic architecture and their imposing hilltop castles. Both listed as World Heritage Sites by UNSECO, the former features unique 17th-century houses, while Berati, with its hillside of neat, whitewashed buildings, was declared a "Museum City" under dictator Enver Hoxha.</p>]]><p><b>Find fantastic frescoes in Voskopoja</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Admire the vibrant colours of the frescoes in Albania's little-known churches. Voskopoja, near Korça, was once the largest city in the Balkans, full of churches and basilicas, and with its own academy where artists were trained. Although the church buildings look a little tired, the fantastic frescoes still flourish.</p>]]><p><b>Hike through the Albanian Alps</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike in Albania's magnificent mountains. The two areas with the best infrastructure, in terms of accommodation and guides, are the Albanian Alps in the far north and the Tomorri massif in the southeast. Outdoor Albania organises hiking, skiing and mountain-biking tours throughout the country.</p>]]><p><b>Meet Albania's national hero at Kruja</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Make the easy day trip from Tirana to the family seat of Albania's 15th-century hero, Skanderbeg. Within the medieval castle's walls are two interesting museums, the larger dedicated to aforementioned heroic noblemen. The restored Ottoman bazaar just outside the castle offers the best souvenir shopping in Albania.</p>]]><p><b>Raft down Albania's rivers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With an impressive network of inland waterways, Albania has an abundance of rafting opportunities. For beginners, the Vjosë River offers a gentle introduction whilst white-water rafting through the spectacular Osumi River canyons offers more in the way of adrenaline. Outdoor Albania has qualified guides, or the Castle Park Hotel in Berati organises rafting weekends.</p>]]><p><b>Reclaim the abandoned city of Butrint</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't miss the UNESCO-listed, ancient city of Butrint, with archaeological remains spanning 2,500 years. Embark on one of the suggested walks through the forest below and seek out the public baths and Roman theatre or explore the ruins of the city abandoned in the Middle Ages at your own leisure.</p>]]><p><b>Set sail on the Lake Komani ferry</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cameras at the ready; take the ferry up the jade waters of Lake Komani. Hemmed in on both sides with rugged and verdant towering cliffs, this peaceful cruise is an enchanting introduction to northern Albania. Wildlife enthusiasts will want to look out for pygmy cormorants, herons and golden eagles.</p>]]><p><b>Stand in awe at the religious art</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The national collections of religious art in Tirana, Korça and Berati contain wonderful icons painted by the 16th-century artist Onufri and his successors in the 18th and 19th centuries. For fans of more modern work, the Tirana Institute of Contemporary Art is a must, whilst Korça's National Museum of Medieval Art is a good counterpoint. </p>]]><p><b>Uncover the legend of Rozafa Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Built before the Roman conquest, this castle in Shkodra was last used for military purposes as recently as 1913. Rozafa was the last fortress in Albania to fall to the Ottomans in 1479 and legend has it the castle was named after a woman who was walled into the bulwark as an offering so the castle would stand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$12.9 billion (2008).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Textiles, asphalt, metals, crude oil and tobacco.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, foodstuffs, textiles and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Italy, Greece, Germany, Bulgaria and Turkey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since 1998, the Albanian economy has stabilised and grown, thanks mainly to the expansion of the construction industry. An increase in tourist activity in many of the seaside resorts has helped to expand the service industry. The agricultural market, which makes up over half of GDP, has grown as production has diversified. The economy is further bolstered by remittances from Albanians abroad, mainly in Greece and Italy, which account for at least 25% of GDP.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Punctuality is expected. Business cards are common and European practices are observed.<br /><br />Anyone considering investing in Albania should bear in mind the prevalence of corruption, the presence of organised crime and the weakness of the judicial system; and seek the advice of the commercial attaché at their embassy in Tirana.<br /></p><p>Civil servants work Mon-Fri 0830-1300 and then 1430-1800 (finishing earlier on Fridays). Private companies tend to keep more traditionally Albanian hours, from 0800 or 0830 to 1500. Offices are closed on Saturdays and Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Tirana Chamber of Commerce and Industry (Dhoma e Tregtisë dhe Industrisë Tiranë)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (04) 230 284
					Website:http://www.cci.al
					Address: ,Rruga e Kavajës 6,Tirana,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Albanian cuisine is a heady blend of Ottoman and Italian influences, with heavy stews, smoked meat and pickled cabbage served alongside Mediterranean-style fish, feta cheese and rice. Visiting vegetarians will find themselves eating a lot of salad; luckily, Albanian tomatoes and cucumbers are always fresh and delicious.</p>
<p>When it comes to drinking, you should try one of Albania&rsquo;s high-quality wines, especially indigenous grapes such as <em>kallmet </em>(red) and <em>shesh </em>(red and white). Grapes are also used to make <em>raki</em>, a clear spirit that will knock your socks off.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Koran:</strong> A species of trout unique to the Ohrid and Prespa lakes.<br />
<strong>Gjize:</strong> A salted curd cheese often used to bulk out dishes.<br />
<strong>Pa&ccedil;&euml; koke:</strong> A thick sheep's head soup.<br />
<strong>Kukurec:</strong> Sheep's innards in a gut casing.<br />
<strong>Jufka:</strong> Handmade pasta created using durum wheat flour.<br />
<strong>Byrek:</strong> A triangular filo pastry usually filled with cheese, spinach or meat.<br />
<strong>F&euml;rges&euml;:</strong> A comforting casserole made with green peppers, tomato, egg and curd cheese.<br />
<strong>Qofte F&euml;rguara:</strong> Fried meatballs combining ground lamb or beef with herbs, feta cheese and bread.<br />
<strong>Flija:</strong> Enormous pie-like pancake consisting of layers of crepes and melted cream cheese.<br />
<strong>Tav&euml; Kosi:</strong> Egg, yogurt and lamb baked with souffl&eacute;-esque results.<br />
<strong>Kafe turke:</strong> Turkish coffee made in the traditional Balkan way, with grounds and sugar brewed together.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>The usual tipping practice is to round the bill up by about 10%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nightclubs in Tirana stay open until very late. The music is sometimes live, especially at weekends. Outside Tirana, clubs of this sort are less common; in the coastal towns during the summer tourist season, music and dancing is laid on in the big hotels.<br /><br />The local cinema chain, Millennium, has branches in all the large towns. They usually screen Hollywood films with Albanian subtitles.<br /><br />Albania has a high standard of classical music. Opera, ballet and concert performances take place throughout the year in Tirana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best place in Albania to shop for traditional crafts is Kruja, less than an hour from Tirana. The bazaar there has felt-makers, rug-weavers and antique dealers. Many of the Kruja shops sell small souvenirs such as Albanian flags, copper plates and ashtrays in the shape of bunkers. Apart from Kruja, there are a few souvenir shops in Tirana, an artisans' co-operative in Gjirokastra and a souvenir stall at Butrint.</p><p>Generally Mon-Sun 0900-1500 and then again for a couple of hours in the early evening (variable according to the time of year). Not all shops open on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As one would expect, the capital city has the widest range of hotels, with accommodation ranging from the luxury end of the market - the Sheraton (<a href="http://www.starwoodhotels.com/sheraton/property/overview/index.html?propertyID=1439" target="_blank">www.starwoodhotels.com</a>) and the Rogner (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hotel-europapark.com/">www.hotel-europapark.com</a>) - through business hotels and cosier, family-run establishments, to budget options including Albania's only Backpacker Hostel (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tiranahostel.com">www.tiranahostel.com</a>), in a 19th-century villa a few minutes' walk from the city centre.<br />
<strong><br />
Grading: </strong>There is a somewhat haphazard grading system, using stars, which does not necessarily correspond to the facilities provided.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Outside Tirana, accommodation is usually in family-run guest houses or in large, communist-era hotels, most of which have been renovated to at least an acceptable standard. There are top-of-the-range hotels at Saranda, Durrësi, Vlora and at a couple of beach resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As one would expect, the capital city has the widest range of hotels, with accommodation ranging from the luxury end of the market - the Sheraton (<a href="http://www.starwoodhotels.com/sheraton/property/overview/index.html?propertyID=1439" target="_blank">www.starwoodhotels.com</a>) and the Rogner (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hotel-europapark.com/">www.hotel-europapark.com</a>) - through business hotels and cosier, family-run establishments, to budget options including Albania's only Backpacker Hostel (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tiranahostel.com">www.tiranahostel.com</a>), in a 19th-century villa a few minutes' walk from the city centre.<br />
<strong><br />
Grading: </strong>There is a somewhat haphazard grading system, using stars, which does not necessarily correspond to the facilities provided.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As one would expect, the capital city has the widest range of hotels, with accommodation ranging from the luxury end of the market - the Sheraton (<a href="http://www.starwoodhotels.com/sheraton/property/overview/index.html?propertyID=1439" target="_blank">www.starwoodhotels.com</a>) and the Rogner (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hotel-europapark.com/">www.hotel-europapark.com</a>) - through business hotels and cosier, family-run establishments, to budget options including Albania's only Backpacker Hostel (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tiranahostel.com">www.tiranahostel.com</a>), in a 19th-century villa a few minutes' walk from the city centre.<br />
<strong><br />
Grading: </strong>There is a somewhat haphazard grading system, using stars, which does not necessarily correspond to the facilities provided.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities (including accident and emergency) are basic and there is a lack of both supplies and doctors. The private or faith-affiliated clinics in Tirana provide the best standard of care. There are also some western-trained dentists in Tirana. Travellers are strongly advised to take out full medical insurance before departure.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is chlorinated and is fine for brushing teeth. However, bottled water is advised for drinking, especially outside Tirana.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Brucellosis and tuberculosis are present in Albanian dairy cattle. Unpasteurised milk and homemade cheese should be avoided; however, in cafes and restaurants the milk is always UHT, and therefore safe.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Rabies is rare in Albania, but medical treatment should always be sought following an animal or bat bite.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tick-borne encephalitis is spread through the bites of infected ticks; the vaccine is usually given only to forestry workers. Hikers should check for ticks at the end of each day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Immunisation against hepatitis B should be considered by those who will be working in healthcare or with children.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations.  During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Lesser Bairam (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Lesser Bairam itself. Lesser Bairam and Greater Bairam (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>Spring Holiday :
							15 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Orthodox Easter Sunday :
							08 April </p><p>May Day :
							01 May </p><p>Beatification of Mother Teresa :
							19 October </p><p>Independence Day :
							28 November </p><p>Liberation (at the end of World War II) :
							29 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Albania without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits with an alcoholic content of 22% or 2L of spirits containing less than 22% alcohol and 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 250ml of eau de toilette or 50ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Personal goods, gifts and souvenirs up to a value of &euro;430 per air or sea traveller and up to &euro;430 per other traveller. Generally up to &euro;150 for children under 15.</p>
<p>Tobacco allowances apply to travellers aged 15 or over. Alcohol allowances apply to travellers aged 18 or over.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include firearms and ammunition, narcotics, and goods which threaten public order.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You need to obtain a permit to export precious metals, ancient coins and scroll, antiques, books or works of art which form part of Albania's cultural and historical heritage.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lek (ALL; symbol Lek). Notes are in denominations of Lek5,000, 1,000, 500, 200 and 100. Coins are in denominations of Lek100, 50, 20, 10 and 5.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency can be exchanged at bureaux de change and banks; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars and Euros can also be changed on the street.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>ATMs are widespread; every town of any size has at least one. Credit cards are accepted only by top-of-the-range hotels and restaurants.</p><p>ATMs are widespread; every town of any size has at least one.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express traveller's cheques can be cashed in Tirana, with a 2% commission charge. Traveller's cheques are not accepted by hotels or restaurants anywhere in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A valid passport or (<strong>1</strong>) ID card is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above to enter Albania.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For visitors who do require a visa, short- and long-term visas are available. Costs vary according to the applicant's nationality; contact the consulate or embassy for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-term visa: up to 90 days within a 180-day period; long-term visa: up to 180 days within a year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section of embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow seven days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[41.110987]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[20.027021]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>28,748 sq km (11,100 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,906,593 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>105.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tirana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parliamentary republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Albania is bordered by Montenegro and Kosovo to the north, the Republic of Macedonia to the east and Greece to the southeast. Italy lies across the Mediterranean to the west; at its narrowest point, close to where the Adriatic and Ionian Seas meet, Italy and Albania are only 75km (47 miles) apart. Albania's highest point is the summit of Mt Jezerca (2,693m/8,835ft), in the Dinaric Alps in the far north. The largest lake in the Balkans, Lake Shkodra, straddles the border between Albania and Montenegro; in the southwest, Lake Ohrid is shared with Macedonia and the Prespa Lakes between Albania, Macedonia and Greece.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Albania is an extremely secular society. The traditional breakdown is 70% Muslim, 20% Orthodox (the autocephalous Albanian church) and 10% Catholic, but at best these figures indicate nothing more than nominal attachment to each faith.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal Albanian etiquette is for people to shake hands the first time they see each other every day, and then again when they part. Between friends, a kiss on both cheeks is exchanged by men as well as women.<br /><br />The usual way to indicate 'yes' is by moving the head horizontally from side to side. 'No' is usually signalled by a slight raising of the eyebrows, sometimes accompanied by a gentle click of the tongue.<br /><br />Albanians usually remove their shoes inside their homes or other people's houses. If you are visiting an Albanian home, you will be offered a pair of slippers or plastic sandals to wear while you are indoors.<br /><br />Smoking is widespread, and it is very unusual to find a non-smoking section in a restaurant, never mind a bar. However, smoking is not allowed on public transport, and this ban is almost always respected. On long journeys, the bus or minibus will stop for a cigarette-break from time to time.<br /><br />Homosexuality is taboo, although not illegal. Public displays of affection by gay couples are likely to be greeted with some hostility.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Edi Rama since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Ilir Meta&nbsp;since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The roots of Albanian culture can be traced back to the ancient Illyrians. The Ardiaei tribe used Shkodra as their capital, and the present-day Albanian language is a rare surviving offshoot of the original Illyrian tongue. The Illyrians lived here first independently, and then alongside the Greeks, until the Romans arrived in the 2nd century BC and assumed control for six centuries.</p>
<p>Next to take over the mantle of leadership were the Byzantines. During their reign, Albania was subject to relentless attacks from Visigoths, Huns and Ostrogoths. A short-lived period of successful Albanian resistance between 1443 and 1468 helped stoke the fire of a burgeoning independence movement, though the country did eventually fall to the Ottomans who stuck around for more than four centuries.</p>
<p>Following the establishment of the nationalist Albanian League and uprisings in 1910 and 1912, the Turks finally gave in to Albania&rsquo;s demands for autonomy. Despite the proclamation of independence, things weren&rsquo;t all fine and dandy. Establishing a coherent state proved difficult and WWI saw the country occupied by a succession of armies, among them the Greeks, Serbian, French, Italian and Austro-Hungarians.</p>
<p>In 1941, soon-to-be-leader Enver Hoxha&nbsp;formed the Albanian Communist Party. Hoxha and his party would keep Albania on a tight leash during a restrictive reign that lasted from 1945 up until the early 1990s. During the early decades of Communist rule, Albania cosied up to China; the two states united by their common enemy, the Soviet Union. But when China severed the partnership in 1978, insular Albania was left extremely isolated; comparisons are often drawn between it and modern-day North Korea.</p>
<p>In 1991, Albania finally shed its one-party system, becoming the last country in Europe to hold multi-party elections. The first year of democracy was turbulent; the country stabilised after the March 1992 elections, but the collapse of pyramid-banking schemes brought Albania to the brink of civil war in early 1997.</p>
<p>Since then, Albania has gradually become more politically stable and economically prosperous. The 2005 parliamentary elections resulted in the first peaceful handover of power from one governing party to another. Albania has been a NATO member since 2009 and the country has been granted official candidate status for EU accession &ndash; meaning a coveted spot in the bloc seems tantalisingly close.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Upon the Mussolini-ordered invasion of Albania in 1939, the country&rsquo;s first and last royal ruler, King Zog, fled his homeland and used gold looted from the Albanian treasury to foot his bill at London&rsquo;s Ritz Hotel.<br />
&bull;	Albania was the first country in the world to be declared an atheist state in 1956.<br />
&bull;	During Communist rule, virtually the only Western films allowed to be shown in Albania were those featuring British comedian Sir Norman Wisdom. Hence, Wisdom became a popular cult figure in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Albania in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(0207) 828 8897.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.albanianembassy.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(0207) 828 8897.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>33 St George's Drive<br/>London<br/>SW1V 4DG<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Albania in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 223 4942.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofalbania.org/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 223 4942.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700 (embassy); Mon-Fri 0900-1200 (consular services).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1312 18th Street<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Albania]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(4) 223 4973.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinalbania.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(4) 223 4973.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0830-1300 and 1400-1700, Fri 0830-1430.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Rruga Skenderbeg 12<br/>Tirana<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Idyllic beaches, warm weather, rich history, spectacular mountain scenery and bargain prices; it sounds like an impossible wish list for a European destination. Yet Albania fulfils all of these criteria and more besides. Over the past quarter of a century, this Balkan land has gradually emerged from its austere communist cocoon and savvy travellers have been taking note.</p>
<p>The capital, Tirana, is a curious and cosmopolitan place. Its countless communist-era apartment blocks have been enlivened with licks of brash, bright paint, and in parts of the city these sit shoulder-to-shoulder with Ottoman and Italian architecture. It is haphazard and disorderly, but wildly alive, with the constant whir of traffic and cacophony of voices adding to the buzz.</p>
<p>Leading down to the Greek border is Albania&rsquo;s greatest asset: the Adriatic coastline (touted as the &ldquo;Albanian Riviera&rdquo;). It would be disingenuous to call it undiscovered; the beaches here draw significant sunbathing crowds during July and August. Even so, these heavenly stretches are fresh to foreign tourists, and among the best in the Med. If you can tear yourself off the towel, there are also interesting remnants of Greek, Ottoman and communist history to be explored in nearby towns. Of particular note are the now deteriorated and occasionally repurposed domed bunkers, paranoid follies ordered by the isolationist ex-ruler Enver Hoxha.<br />
<br />
Further inland, stony hiking trails weave among the lunar, sun-bleached mountains, where remote rural villages offer up a warm welcome to any inquisitive visitors. With unpaved, pot hole-strewn roads and unreliable bus routes, just getting to the country&rsquo;s interior can be an adventure in itself. But when the logistics of travel prove taxing, there&rsquo;s always the dangling carrot of lovingly-prepared meals, tasty wine and ever-hospitable locals to spur you onward.</p>
<p>With its winning combination of sandy beaches, engaging history and affordable prices, Albania's once-unsung charms are now being shouted from the garishly-coloured rooftops.</p><p>Idyllic beaches, warm weather, rich history, spectacular mountain scenery and bargain prices; it sounds like an impossible wish list for a European destination. Yet Albania fulfils all of these criteria and more besides. Over the past quarter of a century, this Balkan land has gradually emerged from its austere communist cocoon and savvy travellers have been taking note. The capital, Tirana, is a curious and cosmopolitan place. Its countless communist-era apartment blocks have been enlivened with licks of bright paint, and in parts of the city these sit shoulder-to-shoulder with Ottoman era architecture. It's haphazard and disorderly, but wildly alive, with the constant whir of traffic and cacophony of voices adding to the buzz.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
