<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Algeria" ColCode="dza" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="dz" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Algeria]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Summer temperatures are high throughout the country, particularly in the south where it is both very dry and very hot. During this time, road travel is difficult and air travel prone to delay because of sandstorms. Northern cities have high humidity, while those along the coast are cooled by sea breezes. In the winter, the oases of the far south are pleasant and attract many visitors. The desert temperature drops dramatically at night. North of the Sahara, temperatures are very mild from September to May and vary little between day and night. South of the Sahara, temperatures are pleasant from October to April, but there are great variations between day and night. Coastal towns are prone to storms from the sea. Rainfall is relatively low throughout the country and in the far south it is virtually unknown.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cotton and linen lightweights are best for winter months and for evenings in desert areas. Woollens and light rainwear are advised for the winter along the coast and the Hauts Plateaux. Remember that desert temperatures can drop very low during the night, so don't get caught out with only flimsy layers. South of the Sahara, from mid-December to mid-January, temperatures drop and warm clothes are necessary both in the morning and the evening. A mountain sleeping bag is also required when camping.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Alg&eacute;rie (<a href="http://www.airalgerie.dz" target="_blank">www.airalgerie.dz</a>) operates frequent services from Algiers domestic airport (adjacent to Algiers International) to the major business centres of Annaba, Constantine and Oran. Less frequent services run from Algiers, Oran, Constantine and Annaba to the other less important commercial centres and gateway oases such as Ghardaia (six hours from Algiers) and Ouargla, as well as important oil towns such as In Amenas and Hassi Messaoud.</p>
<p>Services are generally reliable, but air travel to the far south may be subject to delay during the dry summer months because of sandstorms. Despite this, air is by far the most practical means of transport to the far south for the visitor with limited resources of time; Djanet and Tamanrasset are the oasis gateways to the Tassili N'Ajjer and the Hoggar, respectively.</p>
<p>There is an Air Alg&eacute;rie office in every Algerian town which is served by the airline. You can arrange reservations and itineraries from these offices, but as some of the more isolated offices are not connected by computer or fax, you should confirm reservations well in advance. Offices are very busy in the major towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports are all on the northern coast and include Algiers, Annaba, Arzew, B&eacute;jaia, Djidjelli, Ghazaouet, Mostaganem, Oran and Skikda. Government ferries service the main coastal ports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Soci&eacute;t&eacute; Nationale des Transports Ferroviaires (SNTF) (<a href="http://www.sntf.dz" target="_blank">www.sntf.dz</a>) runs Algeria's railways. Daily (but fairly slow) services operate in the northern part of the country between Algiers and Oran, B&eacute;jaia, Skikda, Annaba and Constantine. The southern routes connect from Annaba to Tebessa via Souk Ahras, Constantine with Touggourt via Biskra and Mohammadia with Bechar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving in Algeria is not for the fainthearted. While driving conditions within the cities are of a reasonable standard, the standards of driving differ hugely, and the distances between cities are large. The N1 (a 1,200km/746-mile motorway) links major cities in the north, from east to west. Security checkpoints outside the major cities are a common sight.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Driving in the desert is not advised without thorough preparation beforehand. It will require a 4x4 and in some cases a permit. It's illegal to drive through the desert alone due to the threat of kidnap and terrorism in the Sahel region.</p>r<p>Road surfaces are reasonably good. All vehicles travelling in the desert should be in good mechanical condition, as breakdown facilities are virtually non-existent. Travellers must carry full supplies of water and petrol. Travel by road (outside Algiers) in northern Algeria should be avoided after dark.</p><p>There is a long-distance bus network around Algeria, with fares and routes operating out of the major cities.</p><p>It's advised not to use public transport other than licensed taxis recommended by established hotels. All taxis are metered and are plentiful in most cities and major towns, though busy during the early evening in the main cities as many people use them to return home after work.</p>
<p>The habit of sharing a taxi is widespread &ndash; a shared taxi is called a <em>louage</em>. Be aware that there are surcharges after dark.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required. A carnet de passage may be required. Cars are allowed entry for three months without duty. You must buy insurance at the border. Proof of ownership is essential.</p><p>Drivers should be aware that drink-driving is illegal. Speed limits are up to 120kph (75mph) on motorways. Children under the age of 10 must sit in the rear of the car.</p><p>You can arrange car hire at the airport on arrival or in most towns. Many hotels can also book this for you.</p><p>Cycling isn&rsquo;t impossible in Algeria but with cycle hire practically non-existent and poor road conditions for cycling, it&rsquo;s not an advisable way of getting around.</p><p>Drivers should be aware that drink-driving is illegal. Speed limits are up to 120kph (75mph) on motorways. Children under the age of 10 must sit in the rear of the car.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Municipal bus and tram services operate in Algiers, its suburbs and the coastal area. You can buy 10-journey carnets and daily or weekly passes. There are also two public lifts and a funicular that lead up to the hill overlooking the old souk in Algiers. The capital also has a one-line metro system (more lines are planned) plus a modern tram line.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Algeria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tlemcen</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Algeria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">oran</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Algeria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ghardaia</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.55</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Algeria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">constantine</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to Algeria are run by several major airlines including Alitalia (<a href="http://www.alitalia.com" target="_blank">www.alitalia.com</a>), Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) and Lufthansa (<a href="http://www.lufthansa.com" target="_blank">www.lufthansa.com</a>). The national airline is Air Alg&eacute;rie (<a href="http://www.airalgerie.dz" target="_blank">www.airalgerie.dz</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/algeria/algiers-houari-boumediene-airport">Algiers Houari Boumediene Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Algiers - 2 hours 25 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Annaba Rabah Bitat Airport </b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 12km (7.5 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Algiers Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.egsa-alger.dz<p>The airport is 20km (12 miles) east of Algiers.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Mohamed Boudiaf International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 9km (6 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Oran Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 10km (6 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports are at Algiers, Annaba, B&eacute;jaia, Oran and Skikda.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no international train service to Algeria from either Morocco or Tunisia. Trains operate within both Tunisia and Algeria so you can take a train to Ghardimaou, cross the border via <em>louage</em> or taxi, and then catch another train from Annaba to Algiers. The closure of the border between Algeria and Morocco means it is no longer possible to catch a train running from Algiers to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/marrakech">Marrakech</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving into Algeria from mainland Europe is a lengthy affair. The simplest drive is to drive through <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>, down to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/marseille">Marseille</a>, and catch a car ferry from there. Alternatively, you can catch a ferry from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tunisia">Tunisia</a>, from where you can drive overland into Algeria. The main border post is at Hazoua.</p>
<p>Note that the border between Morocco and Algeria is closed, so this route is not viable.</p><p>Please note that many desert 'roads' are up to 10km (6-mile) wide ribbons of unimproved desert and are suitable only for well-maintained 4-wheel drive vehicles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>With the advent of mobile phones, the use of landlines (which were never highly used anyway) is in steep decline. Taxiphones (a sort of metered phone booth) are available to make calls from, but mobiles are used as the primary means of communication.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile phone usage across the country has increased greatly, with the main mobile networks giving good coverage across the country. To take advantage of local rates, buy a cheap foreign SIM card for use in your existing phone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafés in all larger towns and hotels in the major cities are more likely to have in-room Wi-Fi available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Algeria's TV and radio stations are state-controlled, but there is a lively private press which is often critical of the authorities. Although there is no overt censorship, legislation sets out prison terms and fines for anyone insulting or defaming the president, MPs, judges and the army. Daily newspapers are printed in Arabic or French, and the main French-language dailies are <em>El Watan</em>, <em>Libert&eacute;</em>, <em>Le Quotidien d'Oran</em> and <em>La Tribune</em>. One of the leading Arabic-language dailies is <em>El Khabar</em>, whilst another daily, <em>Horizons</em>, has an English section.</p>
<p>In terms of TV channels, Enterprise Nationale de T&eacute;l&eacute;vision (ENTV) is state-run. The use of satellite dishes is widespread; some satellite TV stations, such as BRTV, a Berber station based in France, target viewers in Algeria, and European channels are widely watched. Algerian Radio, operated by state-run Radio-T&eacute;l&eacute;vision Alg&eacute;rienne, runs national Arabic, Berber and French networks, and several local stations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mail posted in any of the main cities along the coast takes three to four days to reach Europe; posted elsewhere, it could take much longer. Parcels sent by surface mail may take up to two months to reach Algeria.</p><p>Generally Sat-Wed 0800-1700 and Thurs 0800-1200. The main post office in Algiers (5 boulevard Mohamed Khémisti) is open 24 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire attractive Algiers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Algeria's pretty capital has been a port since Roman times and although commercialised by the French in the mid 19th century, it still has the feel of the Maghreb to it, with many zig-zag alleyways, mosques and a fantastic casbah. It's also evocative of French colonialism with its whitewashed façades and blue painted balconies.</p>]]><p><b>Buy a carpet in gorgeous Ghardaia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Made up of three very different walled towns in this fertile valley surrounded by the Saharan sands, Ghardaia is a unique place. The old towns are ultra-religious and can only be visited with an official guide, but it's well worth doing so. Don't leave without a carpet – those on sale in the main square of Ghardaia are considered to be the best in the country and make superb souvenirs from any trip to Algeria. Haggle with the carpet sellers here to get a good price.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the ‘enchanted oasis’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Deep in the Grand Erg Occidental desert region, lies the oasis town of El Goléa, which is often referred to as 'the pearl of the desert' or 'the enchanted oasis' because of its luxuriant vegetation and abundant water. The town is dominated by an old <em>ksar</em> (fort), whose ruins are well preserved.</p>]]><p><b>Escape the heat in Tlemcen</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tlemcen was an important imperial city from the 12th to the 16th century and stands in the wooded foothills of the Tellian Atlas. A pleasant retreat from the stifling heat of high summer, its sights include the Grand Mosque, the Mansourah Fortress and the Almohad ramparts.</p>]]><p><b>Explore ancient Constantine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated in the east of Algeria, Constantine is a natural citadel lying across the River Rhumnel. Founded by the Carthaginians, who called it Cirta, it is the oldest continuously inhabited city in Algeria. Sights include the Ahmed Bey Palace (one of the most picturesque in the Maghreb) and the Djamma el-Kebir Mosque.</p>]]><p><b>Find the ‘golden key of the desert’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the depths of the Sahara Desert, in southern Algeria, lies the ancient city of Ouargla, which is also known as 'the golden key to the desert'. This ochre-coloured town is well worth visiting for its lovely souks and lofty minarets, which overlook an expansive landscape.</p>]]><p><b>Go dune skiing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>When you see the size of some of the Saharan sand dunes, dune skiing suddenly makes sense. You can bring your own skis (no padding needed) – otherwise quite a few tour agencies offer this unforgettable experience.</p>]]><p><b>Have Djemila all to yourself</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This stunning Roman city near to the city of Sétif is incredibly well preserved but you may well find yourself the only person visiting when you get there. In a stunning setting, surrounded by verdant hills and pine forests, you'll discover huge temples, a formally laid out forum and a superb amphitheatre.</p>]]><p><b>Hike around the Tassili N'Ajjer</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the Tassili N'Ajjer, or 'Plateau of Chasms', a vast volcanic plateau crossed by massive gorges, formed by rivers that have long since dried up. The Tassili conceals a collection of unique rupestrian paintings (rock paintings), which go back at least as far as the neolithic age.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the Turquoise Coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Within easy reach of Algiers are some fine seaside resorts. One of the most famous is Zeralda, a beach town with a holiday vibe and replica nomad village. To the east of Algiers, the Turquoise Coast offers rocky coves and long beaches aplenty. And the Sidi Fredj peninsula has a marina, an open-air theatre and various watersports facilities.</p>]]><p><b>Imbibe Algeirs’ cultural offerings</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Algiers' Bardo Ethnographic Museum and the National Museum of Fine Arts are amongst the finest museums in North Africa. Here you'll find important artefacts and treasures from all eras such as the Roman, Carthaginian and Islamic periods.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Tamanrasset</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Picturesque Tamanrasset, situated at the heart of the Hoggar Mountains, is the unofficial capital of Algeria's Sahara region. Tourists often stay in 'Tam' (as it is sometimes called) and use it as a base for touring the mountains or hiking in the desert. It is also a popular winter holiday destination for Algerians and is regularly visited by the camel caravans of <em>les hommes bleus</em> (the blue-robed Touaregs), who are the ancient nomadic inhabitants of this region.</p>]]><p><b>Sweat it out in the Sahara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Sahara Desert is the most striking and also most forbidding feature of Algeria. The best way to enter is to cross the El Kautara Gorges to the south of Constantine. The sudden glimpse of the Sahara through the El Kautara Gorges is breath-taking. These gorges are said to separate the winter areas from the land of everlasting summer and are called Fouur Es Sahra ('the Sahara's mouth') by local inhabitants.</p>]]><p><b>Tour the Sahara by camel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nothing is quite as evocative of the Sahara's endless sand than the sight of a camel caravan traversing the dunes. Travel agencies in Tamanrasset can organise camel tours of the desert, which allow you to camp overnight in the sands – an unforgettable experience.</p>]]><p><b>Traipse through the ruins of Tipasa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Within easy reach of Algiers, the fascinating ruined city of Tipaza has exceptional Roman, Punic and Christian ruins, and a Numidian mausoleum overlooking a beautiful stretch of the Mediterranean. It's also easy day-tripping distance from Algiers, making it the most accessible Roman ruins in the country.</p>]]><p><b>Trek the Hoggar Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An impressive, jagged range of peaks across Algeria's southern Sahara, the Hoggar Mountains reach as far as Libya and are surrounded by desert on all sides. The massif consists of a plateau made of volcanic rock and eroded cliffs and granite needles form fascinating shapes in pink, blue or black basalt.</p>]]><p><b>Visit holy Beni-Isguen</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The holy town of Beni-Isguen, a fortified city not far from Ghardaia, is a remarkable sight. Set in the Sahara Desert, behind great ramparts, the sprawl of mud brick houses forms a dense warren of narrow streets, and not much has changed since it was first built in the 14th century. Visitors must observe a strict set of rules before entering – dress codes are stringent, no photos are allowed and everyone must be accompanied by a guide.</p>]]><p><b>Wake up in Assekrem</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Camping overnight at this holy retreat with views in all directions to the spectacular surrounding mountains is a wonderful experience. But the unquestionable highlight is getting up just before dawn and ascending the hillside to watch the sun break over the beautiful peaks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$208 billion (2012).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, natural gas and minerals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Foodstuffs and consumer goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Canada, Italy, Spain and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum and natural gas are the most important industries in Algeria and account for all but a small fraction of the country's exports. Most of the country is covered by the Sahara Desert and despite investments in the agricultural sector (the main crops being wheat, potatoes, grapes, cereals and citrus fruits), Algeria is far from self-sufficient in foodstuffs and is vulnerable to drought. <br />
<br />
Most of the fertile land is located in the northern littoral region. The government has recently completed the process of breaking up state agricultural co-operatives and turning the land over to its occupants. Minerals, principally iron ore and phosphates, are the other major export. <br />
<br />
Algeria's principal trading partners are France, the UK, Italy and Spain - it currently supplies around 10% of Europe&rsquo;s natural gas imports to these countries. Plans for the construction of a Trans-Saharan gas pipeline linking coastal terminals to the Saharan gas fields and down into Nigeria, are yet to come to fruition. <br />
<br />
From Europe, Algeria imports most of its industrial equipment and consumer goods. The IMF and other Western donors have provided loans and aid packages, conditional on liberalising economic reforms and the sale of state-owned industrial assets - the government has, by and large, been prepared to meet these.<br />
<br />
As the security crisis has eased in the last few years, economic links between Algeria and the EU have grown. In April 2002, Algeria signed an Association Agreement with the EU, which aimed at boosting both-way trade. Domestic unrest within Algeria in 2011 forced the government to offer $23m in backdated salary increases and more spending on the public sector.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits should always be worn in winter months, shirt sleeves during the summer. Prior appointments are necessary for larger business firms. Businesspeople generally speak Arabic or French and, as a great deal of bargaining is necessary, it is rarely convenient to carry out transactions through an interpreter. Patience is always important. Visitors are usually entertained in hotels or restaurants, where Algerian businessmen are seldom accompanied by their wives. Only rarely are visitors entertained at home. If visiting during Ramadan (and this should be avoided if possible), care should be taken to observe local custom in public places.<br /></p><p>Generally Sat-Wed 0800-1200 and 1300-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre Algérienne de Commerce et d'Industrie</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 965 050 ,966 666
					Website:http://www.caci.dz
					Address: Place des Martyrs,Palais Consulaire,BP 100,6 boulevard Amilcar Cabral,Algiers,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Traditional Algerian food shows the historic influences of Berber, Arab, Turkish, and French tastes. It runs the gamut from mild to very hot, with lots of flavourings used. Algiers and popular coastal towns have a fair selection of good restaurants, serving mainly French and Italian-style food, though even classic dishes will have an unmistakable Algerian quality. Fish dishes are exceptionally good.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Brochettes</em> (kebabs) in French bread and covered in a spicy sauce. <br />
&bull; Couscous (semolina-like pasta made from cracked wheat, is a staple food in Algeria and throughout North Africa). <br />
&bull; Chickpea-cakes (usually added as a side dish to make a cheap and tasty accompaniment for food).<br />
&bull; <em>Shakshuka</em> (stew, often served with vegetables). <br />
&bull; Tajine (stew, usually with lamb or chicken, which is a popular everyday dish). <br />
&bull; Pressed dates or figs, and hard cheese (foods carried by desert people while they&rsquo;re travelling, which keeps for a long time).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol is only available in more expensive restaurants and hotels, as well as from special shops. There are no licensing hours and hotel bars tend to stay open for as long as there is custom. Algeria produces some good wines but very few of them are served in the country itself. Alcohol is generally very expensive and not of great quality – expect non-name brands and a small choice.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is usual in Algiers and larger cities. Elsewhere it is not customary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Algeria&rsquo;s nightlife won&rsquo;t be the main reason you&rsquo;re coming here, but there should be enough options to keep most visitors happy. The main towns of Algiers and Oran offer reasonable options for entertainment, and many hotels will have their own on-site entertainment, such as nightclubs, catering for revellers after a good time. In Algiers, the scene there are a couple of tourist hangouts &ndash; Zeralda, and&nbsp; Sidi Fredj &ndash; where clubs cater to party animals who want to let their hair down. Bear in mind that much of Algeria&rsquo;s nightlife is aimed at men, with women rather less visible in the clubs and bars. Otherwise, try Rue Larbi M&rsquo;Hidi, a pedestrianised area that&rsquo;s quite popular with tourists. If you prefer something a little more sedate, some cinemas show foreign films. <br />
<br />
Strict laws around sale of alcohol mean that it&rsquo;s expensive to drink, whilst many traditional bars have closed down due to the negative effect on business of having liquor licences withdrawn.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Algeria&rsquo;s not as well known as neighbouring Morocco for its shopping credentials but shoppers should find enough to satisfy the urge within the markets and souks of the northern cities. The spread of globalisation has made its mark in the capital Algiers, with shopping centres drawing visitors and locals seeking a &lsquo;Western&rsquo; shopping experience. &nbsp;Don&rsquo;t expect to find the big international brands, but there are plenty of Algerian shops selling everything from jewellery and clothing, to cosmetics and souvenirs.</p>
<p>Possible souvenirs include leatherware, rugs, copper and brassware. Embroidered dresses made locally, known as <em>mejboudi </em>can also make great gifts, although depending where you&rsquo;re buying, they can be expensive. The country is known for its leather in particular, so shoppers can expect to find excellent bags and shoes for excellent value. Berber carpets are beautifully decorated, but rather than buying them in Algiers, go to Ghardaia where the quality will be better and the prices cheaper. Berber jewellery is also highly desirable but many pieces will be made from coral, which while undoubtedly beautiful, is ethically dubious in its origins. From the Sahara comes finely dyed basketwork and primitive-style pottery.</p>
<p>Bargaining is customary in street markets and smaller shops so make sure you haggle, taking care to remain polite at all times. The rue Didouche Mourad is the best shopping street in Algiers; here you&rsquo;ll find small independent boutiques lining the historic street. There are two state-run craft centres with fixed prices., one of which is located at Algiers airport.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0900-1200 and 1400-1900. Some shops open on Fridays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In general, good hotel accommodation in Algeria is limited. The business centres, and in particular Algiers, tend to have either expensive but not particularly high-standard top end hotels or cheaper hotels primarily suited at locals or backpackers. Cheaper hotels tend to be crowded and difficult to get into, even with a confirmed booking.</p>
<p>The hotels in the resorts along the Mediterranean coast have increased in number, and many are of a reasonably high standard. Often, the good hotels in these resorts run their own nightclubs. Winter rates for coastal resorts apply from 1 October to 31 May. <br />
<br />
Good hotels in the gateway oases of the mid-south (such as Ghardaia and Ouargla) are few and far between, and during the season (any time other than high summer, which runs from late June to early September), it is vital to book well in advance. <br />
<br />
Hotels in the very far south are extremely limited. In Tamanrasset there are a few high-standard hotels but room availability remains limited. Many tour agencies run their own Tamanrasset guesthouses, however, so if you book a tour overnight accommodation in one of these will usually be included.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> All hotels are subject to government regulations and are classified by a star rating: deluxe (5-star), second class (4/3-star) and tourist class (2/1-star).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In general, good hotel accommodation in Algeria is limited. The business centres, and in particular Algiers, tend to have either expensive but not particularly high-standard top end hotels or cheaper hotels primarily suited at locals or backpackers. Cheaper hotels tend to be crowded and difficult to get into, even with a confirmed booking.</p>
<p>The hotels in the resorts along the Mediterranean coast have increased in number, and many are of a reasonably high standard. Often, the good hotels in these resorts run their own nightclubs. Winter rates for coastal resorts apply from 1 October to 31 May. <br />
<br />
Good hotels in the gateway oases of the mid-south (such as Ghardaia and Ouargla) are few and far between, and during the season (any time other than high summer, which runs from late June to early September), it is vital to book well in advance. <br />
<br />
Hotels in the very far south are extremely limited. In Tamanrasset there are a few high-standard hotels but room availability remains limited. Many tour agencies run their own Tamanrasset guesthouses, however, so if you book a tour overnight accommodation in one of these will usually be included.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> All hotels are subject to government regulations and are classified by a star rating: deluxe (5-star), second class (4/3-star) and tourist class (2/1-star).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In general, good hotel accommodation in Algeria is limited. The business centres, and in particular Algiers, tend to have either expensive but not particularly high-standard top end hotels or cheaper hotels primarily suited at locals or backpackers. Cheaper hotels tend to be crowded and difficult to get into, even with a confirmed booking.</p>
<p>The hotels in the resorts along the Mediterranean coast have increased in number, and many are of a reasonably high standard. Often, the good hotels in these resorts run their own nightclubs. Winter rates for coastal resorts apply from 1 October to 31 May. <br />
<br />
Good hotels in the gateway oases of the mid-south (such as Ghardaia and Ouargla) are few and far between, and during the season (any time other than high summer, which runs from late June to early September), it is vital to book well in advance. <br />
<br />
Hotels in the very far south are extremely limited. In Tamanrasset there are a few high-standard hotels but room availability remains limited. Many tour agencies run their own Tamanrasset guesthouses, however, so if you book a tour overnight accommodation in one of these will usually be included.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> All hotels are subject to government regulations and are classified by a star rating: deluxe (5-star), second class (4/3-star) and tourist class (2/1-star).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Healthcare facilities are generally of a reasonable standard in the major urban centres of the north with a fairly established network of clinics and hospitals. However, facilities are more limited in the southern Sahara region. Doctors and hospitals usually ask for immediate cash payment for their services. Emergency cases will be dealt with free of charge. Comprehensive travel insurance is essential; make sure your policy covers medical treatment and repatriation.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available and is advised for the first few weeks of stay. Drinking water outside main cities and towns is likely to be contaminated and sterilisation is considered essential. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Powdered or tinned milk is advised. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat, but be careful when eating things like raw dishes like salads and fruits, where ingredients may have been rinsed in tap water. Likewise, avoid drinks with ice in them.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccination against hepatitis B and tuberculosis is sometimes advised. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical help without delay. There is little to no risk of malaria. Algeria's climate is dry and hot, so wearing sunscreen and a hat to shield from midday sun, is advised, as is having drinking water with you.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations.  During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here:</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							05 July </p><p>Anniversary of the Revolution :
							01 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Algeria by persons over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 100 cigarillos or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits or 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 250ml of eau de toilette&nbsp;or 50ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of DZD50,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports to Algeria include arms and ammunition, narcotics and counterfeit goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited exports from Algeria include gold exceeding 150g in weight, firearms, ammunition and narcotics.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dinar (DZD) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of DZD1,000, 500, 200, 100 and 50. Coins are in denominations of DZD100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 centimes. <br />
<strong><br />
Note: </strong>Because of the very strict adherence of the authorities to these regulations, visitors are strongly advised not to be associated with the black market, which tends to concentrate on the Euro and portable electronics.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the past, difficulties have arisen when trying to exchange currency in Algeria, with only one national bank (<em>La Banque Extérieure d'Algérie</em>) able to exchange foreign currency at branches in major business centres. Difficulties are now decreasing and it is possible, for example, to exchange currency at some of the larger hotels. However, the facilities for currency exchange remain quite limited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are generally only accepted in urban areas. Payment in cash is always preferred.</p><p>There are two or three functioning ATMs in Algiers, but they can not be relied upon and there is a thriving black market for currency exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted only in top-class (4-star and above) hotels, government-run craft (souvenir) shops and in certain establishments. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sun-Thurs 0900-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Algeria, a passport valid for at least six months is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To obtain a transit visa, you need to show a valid visa or required documentation for entry to your final destination as well as an onward ticket and sufficient funds for accommodation in Algeria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist/business visa: &pound;85; transit visa: &pound;60. These fees are for British passport holders, but costs vary according to nationality; contact the consulate (or consular section at the embassy) for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry tourist visa: 30 days.</p>
<p>Multiple-entry business visa: 30 days within a 90-day period or 90 days within a 180-day period.</p>
<p>Single-entry transit visa: valid for the number of days required to travel through the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at the embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dependent upon nationality, but allow at least 10 working days for applications made in person, and at least 15 days for postal applications.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[28.214011]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[2.655017]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,381,741 sq km (919,595 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>40,375,954 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>16.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Algiers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Algeria is situated along the North African coast, bordered to the east by Tunisia and Libya, to the southeast by Niger, to the southwest by Mali, and to the west by Mauritania and Morocco. It is Africa's second-largest country, with 1,200km (750 miles) of coastline. Along the coastal strip are the main towns, fertile land, beach <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/algeria/weather-climate-geography">resorts<img height="10" border="0" width="10" alt="" src="file:///C:\Users\JANED~1.COL\AppData\Local\Temp\msohtml1\01\clip_image002.gif" /></a> and 90% of the population. Further south lies the area of the <em>Hauts Plateaux</em><em>,</em> mountains of up to 2,000m (6,600ft) covered in cedar, pine and cypress forests with broad arable plains dividing the plateaux. The remaining 85% of the country is the Sahara  Desert in its various forms, sustaining only 500,000 people, many of whom are nomadic tribes with goat and camel herds.&nbsp;The Sahara region contains two mountain ranges: the dramatic Hoggar massif, rising to almost 3,000m (9,800ft), and the Tassili N&rsquo;Ajjer. Both are scenically stunning and offer some of the best desert landscapes in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>99% of the population adhere to Islam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Courtesy should be adopted with new acquaintances. The provision and acceptance of hospitality are as important a part of Algerian culture as elsewhere in the Arab world. In the main cities, the urban population lives at a frantic pace much akin to European urban dwellers, but in the south and in rural areas people are much more open and friendly. Algerian women are expected to dress modestly in rural areas but this is not necessary in Algiers. Tourist visits should be avoided during Ramadan. Military installations and personnel should not be photographed. Police roadblocks are frequent – slow down and follow their instructions very carefully and respectfully should you be driving around the country. Always carry your passport or identification papers with you.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. The European two-pin plug is standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Ahmed Ouyahia since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Abdelaziz Bouteflika since 1999.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Having won independence from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> in 1962 following a bloody War of Independence that remains the defining event of the country&rsquo;s modern history, Algeria has had a dramatic and rocky first half-century of going it alone. Following a secular, socialist path throughout the 1970s and 1980s to keep the simmering Arab-Berber tensions at bay, the country nevertheless became mired in popular discontent by the late 1980s.</p>

<p>In the 1990s, Algerian politics was dominated by a bloody struggle between the military and Islamic militants that engulfed much of the county and caused huge loss of life. The civil war petered out by 2002, when Abdelaziz Bouteflika, formerly Algeria's long-standing and respected foreign minister, was elected Algeria&rsquo;s president, a role he has held ever since. Bouteflika has run the country with an iron hand ever since, and while being no democrat, he has arguably brought the country something it needs far more in the short term &ndash; stability and peace.</p>

<p>As well as its problems with Islamic militants, the government has also been confronted with agitation from the country's Berber ethnic minority pressing for greater cultural and political recognition, which have resulted in limited concessions to their demands such as Tamazight, the Berber tongue, being recognised as an official national language.</p>

<p>Algeria today is largely stable, with the problems of violence and kidnapping that have plagued it for long now consigned to the past. President Bouteflika won his third term in office in 2009 and while democracy and human rights continue to suffer under his rule, most Algerians are simply glad that the country is a functioning entity and the economy finally growing again.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Algeria in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 2800.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.algerianembassy.org/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 2800.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2118 Kalorama Road<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Algerian Consulate in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7589 6885. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.algerian-consulate.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7589 6885. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Consular services: Tues-Sat 0900-1500. Visa section: Tues-Fri 0930-1200 (visa applications); 1600-1630 (passport collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>6 Hyde Park Gate<br/>London<br/>SW7 5EW<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Algeria in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(0207) 299 7077. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.algerianembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(0207) 299 7077. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1 - 3 Riding House Street<br/>London<br/>W1W 7DR<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Algeria]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(0)770 085 000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-algiers</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(0)770 085 000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Sun-Thurs 0800-1530 (embassy); Sun-Tues and Thurs 0900-1130 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Hydra<br/>3 Chemin Capitaine Hocine Slimane (ex Chemin des Glycines)<br/>Algiers<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For the intrepid traveller, adventure awaits in Algeria. A beguiling blend of cultures, landscapes and traditions, this vast chunk of land contains everything from tranquil fishing ports and bustling cities to the unmatched drama of the Sahara Desert and Hoggar Mountains.</p>
<p>As the largest country in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/africa">Africa</a>, Algeria&rsquo;s terrain is hugely varied yet underexplored: few visitors travel beyond the country&rsquo;s Mediterranean port cities (namely Oran and the capital, Algiers), which lie amidst fertile land and the scattered vestiges of Phoenician and Roman colonies.</p>
<p>Sometimes called &lsquo;Algiers the White,&rsquo; the capital&rsquo;s bustling showpiece is its UNESCO-listed Casbah. This whitewashed medina encompasses both crumbling ruins and newly-renovated spaces and is well worth a visit despite its shady reputation (taking a guide is recommended).</p>
<p>The ancient port city of Oran has a decidedly European vibe: French colonial influences are evident in everything from the soaring Sacr&eacute;-C&oelig;ur Cathedral (now a library) to the richly ornamented Palais de la Culture. The city has long been a popular trading post and remains one of the busiest ports in North Africa.</p>
<p>The Sahara Desert is Algeria&rsquo;s defining feature and one of its biggest drawing cards. It covers more than four-fifths of the country and is the source of myriad myths and legends. Nomadic Berbers still live here, eking out traditional lives in difficult conditions.</p>
<p>The security situation makes independent travel difficult in the Sahara, but under the guidance of reputable tour operators, travellers can visit attractions like the oasis towns of Ghardia and Timimoun, or venture deep into the heart of the desert to view the prehistoric rock art in the Hoggar Mountains and Tassili N&rsquo;Ajjer National Park.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The desert is also home to the world&rsquo;s most remote film festival. FiSahara takes place annually in the Wilaya of Dakhla, a Western Sahara refugee camp, to highlight the plight of the Sahrawi people. <br />
<br />
War and tumultuous politics have deterred many from visiting Algeria &ndash; rerouting them towards <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/morocco">Morocco</a> instead &ndash; but if you&rsquo;re looking for a North African destination with a difference, this country has much to offer.</p><p>For the intrepid traveller, adventure awaits in Algeria. A beguiling blend of cultures, landscapes and traditions, this vast chunk of land contains everything from tranquil fishing ports and bustling cities to the unmatched drama of the Sahara Desert and Hoggar Mountains.</p>
<p>As the largest country in Africa, Algeria&rsquo;s terrain is hugely varied yet underexplored: few visitors travel beyond the country&rsquo;s Mediterranean port cities (namely Oran and the capital, Algiers), which lie amidst fertile land and the scattered vestiges of Phoenician and Roman colonies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
