<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Andorra" ColCode="and" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ad" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Andorra]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Temperate climate with warm summers and cold winters. Rain falls throughout the year.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights for the summer and warm mediumweights during winter. Waterproofing is advisable throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>A good road runs from the Spanish to the French frontiers through Sant Juli&agrave; de L&ograve;ria, Andorra la Vella, Escaldes-Engordany, Encamp and Canillo (about 40km/25 miles between frontiers).</p>
<p>There is a road to El Serrat, and a secondary road from Ordino to Canillo, which is usually closed in winter.</p><p>A valid national driving licence is accepted.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Children aged under 10 must travel in the rear. Speed limits are 40kph (25mph) in towns and up to 90kph (56mph) on major roads.</p><p>International and local firms offer car hire.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Children aged under 10 must travel in the rear. Speed limits are 40kph (25mph) in towns and up to 90kph (56mph) on major roads.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Andorra does not have an international airport. The closest airports in Spain are&nbsp;La Seu d'Urgell, Barcelona, Lleida, Reus and Girona. The nearest airports in France are Toulouse, Carcassonne and Perpignan. Most offer coach or minibus service to Andorra.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>French rail operator SNCF (<a href="http://www.sncf.com" target="_blank">www.sncf.com</a>) runs trains to Gare Andorre L'Hospitalet, just outside the principality. Andorra Bus (<a href="http://www.andorrabus.com" target="_blank">www.andorrabus.com</a>) runs a connecting coach service.</p>
<p>Spanish rail operator RENFE (<a href="http://www.renfe.com" target="_blank">www.renfe.com</a>) offers links to Lleida, from where there's also a bus connection with Andorra Bus. Alternatively, you can travel to Barcelona by train and catch a coach link with Andorra Direct Bus (<a href="http://www.andorradirectbus.es" target="_blank">www.andorradirectbus.es</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile companies. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes are available throughout Andorra.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Andorran media scene has been shaped by the country's proximity to France and Spain. Andorrans have access to broadcasts from both countries, and for many years Andorra was home to Sud Radio: a powerful radio station broadcasting to southwest France. The constitution provides for freedom of speech and of the press. Andorra has two daily newspapers: the <em>Diari d'Andorra</em> and <em>El Periodic</em>. Nacional d'Andorra operates Radio Andorra and music station Andorra Musica; Radio Valira, Andorra 7 and Andorra 1 are commercial stations; TVA is a public service operated by Radio i Televisio d'Andorra.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internal mail services are free; international mail takes about one week within Europe.</p><p>0900-1300 and 1500-1700 in Andorra la Vella, otherwise variable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Caldea</p><![CDATA[<p>Benefiting from its location nestled between Spain and France in the heart of the Pyrenees, Andorra has a world-renowned reputation for its clean mountain air and spa treatments. Built at an altitude of 1,100m (3,600ft) on a site measuring 25,000 sq m (269,100 sq ft), Caldea is the largest spa centre in Southern Europe. Treatments and facilities at the centre include spas, high pressure indoor and outdoor jacuzzis, saunas, hammam, UVA cabins, massages and a whole programme of facial and body treatments. There's also a water bar and a nighttime underwater music and light show. The site also boasts cafes, bars and a gastronomic restaurant. Caldea is open all year round and is a popular place to cool off in the summer and a welcome distraction from the ski slopes in the winter.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bathe in the mountains at Escaldes-Engordany</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ever thought of bathing atop a mountain? Now you can in the spa town of Escaldes-Engordany, adjoining the capital. Enjoyed ever since Roman times, the natural hot springs here are perfect for soothing tired muscles after a day hiking or skiing. The town also boats some beautiful Romanesque architecture.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the stone houses of Encamp</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The small mountain town of Encamp is situated between the capital and the French frontier, and is a good base from which to begin hikes. Encamp is also well liked by tourists for its pretty stone houses and medieval church.</p>]]><p><b>Go bargain hunting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Andorra's wide-ranging shopping opportunities offer prices that are much cheaper than many Europeans can expect at home. Much of this has to do with the tiny state's anti-tax stance – although this has recently begun to be softened under pressure from the European Union. Apart from taking advantage of great deals, there are many traditional local products worth stocking up on such as wine, cheese and, if you smoke, tobacco, which is grown here.</p>]]><p><b>Hike in the Pyrenees</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many visitors to Andorra come to hike in the mountains amongst tumbling rivers, far-reaching lakes and glorious countryside. Easier strolls include the Camí Ral d'Ordino in the La Cortinada parish, and Camí de les Pardines in Encamp. Just remember to wrap up warm – it's cold pretty much all-year-round.</p>]]><p><b>Relax at Europe's largest spa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Caldea is said to be the largest spa centre in Southern Europe. Treatments and facilities include high-pressure indoor and outdoor Jacuzzis, saunas, hammam, UVA cabins, massages and a whole programme of facial and body treatments. There's also a water bar and a night-time underwater music and light show.</p>]]><p><b>Ski on renowned pistes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go skiing at one of Andorra's many resorts; the main centre is Soldeu, but other ski centres can be found at Pas de la Casa-Grau Roig, on the French frontier, and at Ordino-Arcalis and Arinsal-Pal, all north of Andorra la Vella. Try cross-country skiing in the resort of La Rabassa.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the views at El Serrat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Of the many picturesque mountain villages in Andorra, El Serrat is perhaps the finest of all. Many stay here while hiking or skiing nearby, but the breath-taking views of the Pyrenees are worth it alone. The hamlet lies approximately 18km (11 miles) from Escaldes-Engordany, off the main road.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the UNESCO-listed Madriu Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The striking Madriu Valley, which cuts through about a tenth of the principality with its jagged cliffs and dramatic glaciers, is a UNESCO World Heritage Site. As well as stunning views, the region abounds with traditional shepherd's cabins and quaint hamlets, which are the precious remains of an ancient Pyrenees farming culture.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around Andorra la Vella</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nestling in a picturesque valley, at the junction of two mountain streams, Andorra la Vella is the only town in this tiny principality, which, by default, makes it the capital. As well as being the head of government, this tiny town boasts several sights including a fine, 12th-century church and Casa de la Vall, the ancient seat of government.</p>]]><p><b>Watch a game</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Andorra is bursting with spectator sports despite its small size. Watch a game of football – Andorra has a national team and play sits little heart out against bigger teams, even if victories are rarely forthcoming (it currently stands fourth from bottom on FIFA's world rankings). Rugby and basketball are also popular, so are motorbike and car rallies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$3.66 billion (2007).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Tobacco, furniture and leather goods.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Electricity, fuels, food and consumer goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France and Spain.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Andorra's status as a low tax and duty-free zone has led to the development of a major trade in consumer goods. This trade, along with tourism and, more recently, financial services, are now the major components of the Andorran economy.<br /><br />There is a small but thriving agricultural sector farming potatoes, tobacco and livestock. There is also a small mining industry exploiting deposits of lead, iron and alum. The country's hydroelectric power plant supplies about a quarter of domestic needs; Andorra is dependent on imports of electricity and other fuels from France and Spain.<br /><br />Both inflation and growth are around 3%.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits are recommended at all times. Prior appointments are necessary and meetings tend to be formal. Punctuality is important. Lunch is usually after 1330 and can extend through the afternoon. Although English is quite widely spoken, a knowledge of Spanish/Catalan or French is very useful.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700. Some offices open Mon-Fri 0800-1500 (summer only).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Centre de Congressos i Exposicions</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 874 500.
					Website:
					Address: ,Plaça Poble,Andorra la Vella,]]><b>Chamber of Commerce, Industry and Services</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 809 292
					Website:http://www.ccis.ad
					Address: 8,Carrer Prat de la Creu,Andorra la Vella,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>When we talk about Andorran cuisine, we essentially mean Catalan. In the principality, you'll find many pork-based dishes stemming from Catalonia's large-scale cultivation of swine, as well as countless seafood options despite Andorra's distance from the Mediterranean. Sausages and cured hams are eaten almost daily, as is <em>tortilla</em> &ndash; better known as Spanish omelette.</p>
<p>Where there are differences between Andorran and typical Catalan food, they are mostly related to the principality's location in the lofty Pyrenees. Expect plenty of trout, as well as rice dishes based around mountain beasties. The more adventurous visitors might seek out <em>arr&oacute;s amb esquirrol</em> (squirrel) although cultivating or selling these critters for culinary purposes has now been outlawed. Snails are also very popular in Andorra.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Coca</strong>: Flat cakes with a variety of toppings, especially roasted vegetables; also served as a dessert with sweet toppings.<br />
<strong>Trinxat</strong>: A kind of patty made from potato and cabbage.<br />
<strong>Truites de carreroles</strong>: A type of mushroom omelette.<br />
<strong>Formatges i Embotits</strong>: There are many locally produced cheeses and cold cuts.<br />
<strong>Vedella d'Andorra</strong>: Andorran veal.<br />
<strong>Cargols</strong>: Snails, sometimes served with a sauce.<br />
<strong>Escudella i carn c'olla</strong>: Hearty Andorran stew or soup with meatballs, pasta, vegetables and various other meats depending on the chef.<br />
<strong>Arr&oacute;s amb esquirrol</strong>: A kind of paella with squirrel, once traditional in Andorra, but now difficult to find.<br />
<strong>Pa amb tom&aacute;quet</strong>: Served with many meals, bread rubbed with tomato, garlic and olive oil.<br />
<strong>Faves amb pernil ib&eacute;ric</strong>: Broad beans fried with Spanish ham.<br />
<strong>Botifarra amb mongetes</strong>: A large local type of sausage served with white beans.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Service charges are usually included in the bill. Porters and waiters expect a further 10%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Andorra's characteristically safe streets help to create a thriving nightlife. Many bars and hotels provide a variety of evening entertainment. Clubs are open during both summer and winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is duty-free shopping for all goods. Petrol, alcohol, cameras and watches can be purchased at low prices. Electrical goods are excellent value.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0930-1330 and 1600-2000, Sun 0930-1330 and 1600-1900. Department stores: Mon-Fri 0930-2000, Sat 0930-2100 and Sun 0930-1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Andorra has hundreds of hotels and guest houses, principally catering for the summer months and the ski season, although some stay open all year round. Rooms during the summer months (July to August) should be booked well in advance. Hotels and restaurants are registered with the tourist office  and are bound to keep to the registered prices and services. Information on hotels can be obtained from the Andorran Hotel Association (see <em>Accommodation Information</em> below).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Andorra has hundreds of hotels and guest houses, principally catering for the summer months and the ski season, although some stay open all year round. Rooms during the summer months (July to August) should be booked well in advance. Hotels and restaurants are registered with the tourist office  and are bound to keep to the registered prices and services. Information on hotels can be obtained from the Andorran Hotel Association (see <em>Accommodation Information</em> below).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Andorra has hundreds of hotels and guest houses, principally catering for the summer months and the ski season, although some stay open all year round. Rooms during the summer months (July to August) should be booked well in advance. Hotels and restaurants are registered with the tourist office  and are bound to keep to the registered prices and services. Information on hotels can be obtained from the Andorran Hotel Association (see <em>Accommodation Information</em> below).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;For UK citizens, most health costs are covered by reciprocal health agreements but additional insurance is advised. Other nationals are advised to take out comprehensive travel insurance. Visitors should note that as entry to Andorra is usually through France or Spain, the health regulations of these countries should be complied with.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p/><p>&lt;p&gt;Rabies&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical help without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>In July, August and September, parishes have their own public holidays, during which festivals are held.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Constitution Day :
							14 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>St John's Day :
							24 June </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>National Day :
							08 September </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>St Charles' Day :
							04 November </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Eve :
							24 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>New Year's Eve :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Andorra is a duty-free zone, but travellers should check French/Spanish regulations as both these countries maintain customs controls at the borders.</p>
<p>Note that when returning to the EU, there are limits on the quantities of goods you can bring back with you. See <a href="http://www.duana.ad">www.duana.ad</a> for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics, firearms and ammunition, and counterfeit goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You cannot export works of art without permission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although most currencies are accepted, the main currency in circulation is the Euro. Euro (€) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of €500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of €2, 1 and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Andorran banks and bureaux de change will exchange foreign currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros, Pounds Sterling and US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1500-1700, Sat 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Andorra, a valid passport is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above, except (<strong>1</strong>) European holders of a national ID card, providing this is valid to enter Spain or France.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[42.551008]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[1.576007]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>467.8 sq km (180.6 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>69,165 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>183.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Andorra la Vella.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Principality under the suzerainty of the President of France and the Spanish Bishop of Seu d'Urgell.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Andorra is situated in the eastern Pyrenees, bordered by France to the north and east, and Spain to the south and west. It is roughly halfway between Barcelona and Toulouse. The landscape consists of gorges and narrow valleys surrounded by mountains. Much of the landscape is forested, but there are several areas of rich pastureland in the valleys. There are four rivers and several mountain lakes. Ski resorts and the spa town of Les Escaldes are Andorra's main attractions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal social courtesies should be extended when visiting someone's home. Handshaking is the accepted form of greeting. Dress is informal and smoking is very common; customs are similar to those of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a>.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Antoni Mart&iacute; Petit since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Co-heads Joan Enric Vives i Sicilia (Bishop of la Seu d'Urgell) since 2003 and Fran&ccedil;ois Hollande (President of France) since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One of the oldest nations in Europe, the tiny principality of Andorra was established by Charles the Great to act as a buffer state between modern-day France and Muslim Iberia.</p>
<p>As a result of the Paretages (the territory&rsquo;s first constitutional documents) of 1278 and 1288, control of the country was split between the Spanish Bishop of Urgell and a nominee appointed by the King of France (initially the Count de Foix), and subsequently by the French emperors and presidents. This unique power-sharing arrangement lasted until the late 20th century when the present constitution formally enshrined Andorra as a principality.</p>
<p>Administration is in the hands of a general council with 28 members, four from each of the seven parishes, elected by universal suffrage. The council elects a president and a vice-president. Domestic politics are dominated by two parties: the Uni&ograve; Liberal (UL) and the Agrupament Nacional Democr&agrave;tic (AND).</p>
<p>Following a comprehensive victory in the 1997 poll, at which the UL took 18 of the 28 seats on the Conseil G&eacute;n&eacute;ral, a UL government took office under the leadership of Marc Forn&eacute; Moln&eacute;.</p>
<p>Four years later, in 2001, the electorate returned the Moln&eacute; government for a second term, again with an absolute majority. However, in 2005, Albert Pintat of the Liberal Party became prime minister, although not with an absolute majority. Moln&eacute; lost his seat in the 2005 election but, in any case, was barred by the constitution from standing for a new term.</p>
<p>In April 2009, the Social Democratic Party won the parliamentary election and in June 2009 Jaume Bartumeu Cassany assumed office as Head of Government.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; In 1934, a Lithuanian by the name of Boris Skossyreff pronounced himself to be the sovereign prince of Andorra and declared war on the Bishop of Urgell; Boris I was soon arrested and expelled.<br />
&bull; Andorra remained neutral during World War II, though it did provide help to the French resistance.<br />
&bull; Technically, though, Andorra was still at war with Germany since World War I, after its invite to the Treaty of Versailles was lost in the post. The two nations formally declared peace in 1958. Phew.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Principality of Andorra in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 8874 4806.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://visitandorra.com/en/home/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 8874 4806.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Sat 0900-1700 (by appointment only).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>63 Westover Road<br/>London<br/>SW18 2RF<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Permanent Mission of the Principality of Andorra to the United Nations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 750 8064.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 750 8064.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>27th Floor<br/>2 United Nations Plaza<br/>New York<br/>10017<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tucked away in the eastern Pyrenees, the tiny Principality of Andorra is a land of narrow valleys and mountainous landscapes that&rsquo;s popular for skiing and trekking. Its pretty villages and hamlets &ndash; dotted along the main road that traverses the country &ndash; are filled with Romanesque churches and houses, built in a unique, local style and preserved through the country&rsquo;s seclusion.</p>
<p>Tracing its roots back to Ancient Greek times and Polybius&rsquo; mention of Iberian Andosinos, Andorra is not short of history. Tradition has it that Charlemagne rewarded the Andorrans for fending off the Moors by granting them a charter. It&rsquo;s this peculiar independence, somehow enduring over the ages against successive threats, that has allowed Andorra&rsquo;s beautiful architecture to remain so unspoiled.</p>
<p>Liberal snowfalls and an undulating chunk of the Pyrenees make for great skiing conditions; those who love wintersports will find some of Europe's best pistes here. Politicians and royalty of Spain choose Andorra&rsquo;s white peaks for their skiing holidays &ndash; and prices are certainly geared towards the well heeled. During milder spells, Andorra also offers excellent hiking conditions, with sweeping valleys, challenging ascents and charming vistas.</p>
<p>The diminutive nation is administered from the capital city, Andorra la Vella, with two &lsquo;Co-Princes&rsquo; as joint heads of states: the President of France and Bishop of Urgell in Catalonia, a tradition that dates back to the 13th century. The capital might not be to everybody's taste (think chock-a-block traffic barging between more shops than could possibly be required), but just a brief distance away lie some rural gems.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Villages such as Pal, a medieval settlement with an 11th century church, are well worth visiting. The Iron Route &ndash; by foot or bus &ndash; is also popular, taking visitors around the old town of Ordino. Andorra sees an incredible 10 million visitors a year, but wander off the beaten track and you&rsquo;ll find many secluded Pyrenean spots to call your own.</p><p>Tucked away in the eastern Pyrenees, the tiny Principality of Andorra is a land of narrow valleys and mountainous landscapes that&rsquo;s popular for skiing and trekking. Its pretty villages and hamlets &ndash; dotted along the main road that traverses the country &ndash; are filled with Romanesque churches and houses, built in a unique, local style and preserved through the country&rsquo;s seclusion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
