<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Angola" ColCode="ago" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ao" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Angola]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The north of the country is hot and wet during the summer months (November to April); winters are slightly cooler and mainly dry. The south is hot throughout much of the year with a slight decrease in temperature in winter (May to October). Overall, the best time to visit Angola is from June to September when rainfall is low and days are warm and sunny. <br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens throughout the year in the south. Tropical clothing for summers in the north. Nights can be cold, so warm clothing should be taken. Waterproofing is advisable for the rainy season throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>TAAG Angola Airlines (<a href="http://www.taag.com.br" target="_blank">www.taag.com.br</a>) operates flights within Angola. There are scheduled services between major towns. However, aircraft run by this airline may not be properly maintained, and travellers should aim to use flights run by reputable international organisations.</p>
<p>Private jets are operated by some Portuguese, French and Italian business interests (trading most notably in oil and diamonds) in the north of the country, particularly to and from the Cabinda enclave, which is only accessible by air. Sonair (<a href="http://www.sonair.co.ao" target="_blank">www.sonair.co.ao</a>) is recommended. Helicopter access to Cabinda is also possible. Passengers on internal flights must carry official authorisation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rail services are erratic, and tickets hard to purchase. Trains run on three separate routes inland from Luanda: to Malanje (daily) with short branches to Dondo and Golungo Alto; Lobito to Dilolo (the Benguela Railway, daily); and Namibe to Menongue (daily). There are no sleeping cars and no air-conditioned services, though food and drink is available on some journeys.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Car-jacking is a risk.&nbsp;You must carry identity papers.</p>r<p>Driving outside of Luanda may be risky. Unexploded mines remain, driving standards are poor, and conditions are challenging. Much of the infrastructure was destroyed in the civil war, and although some roads have been rebuilt, many are still in a bad state of repair.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is recommended (or translation of national licence), although, in theory, visitors may drive with a national licence for up to 30 days.</p><p>You can find international car hire companies in Luanda; hiring a car with a driver is recommended. Only use a reputable firm.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local buses run in Luanda. A flat fare is charged.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines offering flights to Angola include Emirates (<a href="http://www.emirates.com" target="_blank">www.emirates.com</a>), Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="http://www.ethiopianairlines.com" target="_blank">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>), TAAG Angola Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.taag.com.br">www.taag.com.br</a>) and TAP Portugal (<a href="http://www.flytap.com" target="_blank">www.flytap.com</a>), among others.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Luanda - 11 to 13 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Luanda Quatro de Fevereiro International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 4km (2.5 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Lobito, Luanda, Malongo and Namibe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to significant Chinese investment, the Benguela Railway has been rebuilt. This links the port of Lobito with the border town of Luau, with onward trains to the Democratic Republic of Congo and Zambia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Overland routes to neighbouring countries are generally not open, but conditions are subject to frequent change. Driving outside Luanda is not recommended and can be risky. Travellers should contact an embassy for advice on security along their planned routes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage limited to Luanda and the surrounding area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a few Internet caf&eacute;s in Luanda. Access outside of the capital is limited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Government-controlled media are predominant. Angola's only daily newspaper, Jornal de Angola, and the terrestrial TV service, TPA,<em> </em>are state-owned and carry little criticism of the government. The constitution provides for freedom of expression but the government does not always respect this and the few private media outlets are liable to harassment.<br />
<br />
Private radio stations operate in the main cities but the state maintains a monopoly in radio broadcasting across much of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail between Europe and Angola takes five to 10 days. Surface mail between Europe and Angola takes at least two months. There is a fairly reliable internal service. Most correspondence is by telex.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be enraptured by Kalandula falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Witness the impressive spectacle of the Kalandula Waterfalls, one of the largest by volume anywhere in Africa. Located in the country's north, the falls are spread along 400m (1,312ft) and fall over 100m (328ft) from forested clifftops. The views are particularly mighty at the end of the rainy season when the Lucala River that feeds them is in full flood.</p>]]><p><b>Echo the actions of the early explorers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It was at Soyo that the Portuguese explorer Diogo Cao was the first European to set foot on land in what is now Angola and placed a stone padrao (or standard). Five centuries on, the padrao still stands on the tip of a beautiful peninsula which is also home to sea turtles.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the coastal forts</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The many forts that dot Angola's coastline give a real sense of the country's history as a Portuguese colony. The largest and most famous is Luanda's Fort Sao Miguel, built in 1576 to protect the fledgling city and serve as a slave depot. It now contains the Museum of the Armed Forces.</p>]]><p><b>Grab a towel and head for the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Palmeirinhas beach offers magnificent scenery and a long, deserted beach approximately 45 km (28 miles) south of Luanda, while in the opposite direction Santiago beach is known for its fishing. To swim, the beaches of Luanda's Ilha peninsula are a better bet, and just five minutes from the capital's heart.</p>]]><p><b>Head out on safari</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Kissama (or Quiçama) National Park is currently the only functioning national park in the whole country, and is within easy reach of Luanda. Thanks to a reintroduction programme, the park is home to an increasing variety of wild animals, including elephants and the rare black palanca antelope, which can only be found in Angola.</p>]]><p><b>Relax in Benguela</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Less frenetic than the capital, Benguela maintains its cool colonial charm, making the most of its bay side location. The Governor's Palace, facing the long sandy beach, is one of the best examples of colonial architecture in the country, while plenty of public spaces provide shade for taking in the sights and sounds.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the rails</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The newly refurbished Benguela railway follows an old trade route inland to the Democratic Republic of Congo. Comprising 67 stations and 42 bridges, it is one of the longest rail journeys in Africa, and a great way to see Angola's hinterland while interacting with its people.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the view at Tundavala Gap</b></p><![CDATA[<p>To the south of Angola, close to the city of Lubango, lies Tundavala Gap. Views extend for miles from among the rim of cliffs known as the Serra da Leba escarpment, which marks the end of the Bié plateau that divides Angola into high and lowland.</p>]]><p><b>Take the capital to heart</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ever improving Luanda deserves more than just a quick rest stop on arrival from the international airport. It's the city's atmosphere that draws you in, with a pleasant Atlantic Ocean location and historic churches and architectural gems lining almost every street of the lower city. One of the more curious attractions is the towering Mausoleum of Agostinho Neto, the country's first president: love it or hate it, you can't ignore it.</p>]]><p><b>Understand Angola’s tragic slave past</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gain a historical understanding into Angola's role in the Atlantic Slave Trade at the Museum of Slavery, 25 km (16 miles) along the coast from Luanda. The museum is located near a 17th-century chapel in which slaves were baptised before boarding ships for the New World.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$61.4 billion (2007).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, diamonds, gas, coffee and cotton.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and electric equipment, food product, textiles and medicines.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Portugal, Brazil, France and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Agriculture employs over 50% of the population but production has declined so much that, from being a net exporter, Angola now imports over half its food requirements.<br /><br />Fishing, which almost ceased to exist, is now being rejuvenated with foreign aid. New oil and gas fields off the shore of Cabinda (an enclave in the north of the country) are being developed. However, Angola has only one refinery and so exports most of its oil in the crude form. The only other industry of any size is diamond mining. <br /><br />Angola has successfully reduced inflation from 300% in 1999 to 12% in 2007, with growth at 21%.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits are recommended. Many Angolan businesspeople dress casually, wearing open-neck shirts. Any dark colours can be worn for social occasions. As Portuguese is the official language, a knowledge of this is an advantage in business transactions; French and Spanish are also useful. There are limited translation services. Avoid June to September as Angolans tend to take their holidays at this time.<br /></p><p>Mon-Thurs 0730-1230 and 1430-1830, Fri 1430-1730; some offices open Sat 0830-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Câmara de Comércio e Indústria de Angola (Chamber of Commerce and Industry)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 444 566
					Website:http://www.ccia.ebonet.net
					Address: CP 92,Largo do Kinaxixi 14,1 Andar,Luanda,]]><b>The US-Angola Chamber of Commerce in the USA</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 1100 17,(202) 223 0540
					Website:http://www.us-angola.org
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>There is a noticeable Portuguese influence in Angolan cuisine, particularly in the spicy seafood, which creates a fusion between local ingredients such as cassava and non-natives like onion and garlic.</p>
<p>Meals generally consist of fish or meat stewed in a rich sauce with vegetables such as okra and served with rice or <em>funge </em>(an Angola staple that draws comparisons to polenta). At their most basic, dishes consist of <em>funge </em>and sauce alone.</p>
<p>With its long Atlantic coastline, the seafood is particularly good. Fish or shellfish including shrimp and lobster will often have been caught the same day by local fishermen.</p>
<p>The one downside to Angola cuisine may be the lack of restaurants, especially outside Luanda. Though new restaurants and cafes are popping up all the time, for the moment your hotel is still probably the best bet.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Funge:</strong> Plain carbohydrate made from cassava with a texture like mash potato, generally served with a full-flavoured spicy sauce.<br />
<strong>Calulu:</strong> Dried fish or meat layered with fresh fish or meat, onion, tomatoes, okra and sweet potato leaves.<br />
<strong>Chicken muamba:</strong> Chicken seasoned with palm oil hash.<br />
<strong>Mufete de Cacuso:</strong> Tilapia fish seasoned with pepper and lemon<em>.<br />
</em><strong>Farofa:</strong> Toasted cassava flour with a salty and smoky flavour.<br />
<strong>Caldeirada de cabrito:</strong> Goat stew with rice traditionally served on Independence Day (Nov 11).<br />
<strong>Frango peri-peri:</strong> Grilled chicken in a very hot chilli marinade.<br />
<strong>Feij&atilde;o de &oacute;leo de palma:</strong> Stewed beans in a palm oil sauce.<br />
<strong>Gafanhotos de palmeira:</strong> Toasted grasshopper.<br />
<strong>Mukua:</strong> Dried fruit from the baobab tree, often used for ice cream.<br />
<strong>Kussangua:</strong> Traditional non-alcoholic drink made from cornflour.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Where service charge is not added to the bill, 10% is acceptable, although tipping is not officially encouraged. Tipping can be in kind (e.g. cigarettes).</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are nightclubs and cinemas in Luanda. Angolan music is a fusion of Caribbean, Brazilian and Afro sounds. Cinema seats should be booked in advance. The Lenarius, a gallery and caf&eacute;, is situated behind the Ministry of Defence and is open until late in the evening.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional handicrafts are available in the main cities. Outside of these, shopping is not easy.</p><p>These can vary, but are generally Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many hotels in Angola have air conditioning, a private bath or shower, a telephone, radio and TV. However, there is a general shortage of accommodation, and it is advisable to book well in advance (at least one month prior to departure); accommodation cannot be booked at the airport. Visitors should also note that accommodation in Luanda is expensive but the city does have many hotels. A list of hotels in Angola is provided by the Embassy (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.angola.org">www.angola.org</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many hotels in Angola have air conditioning, a private bath or shower, a telephone, radio and TV. However, there is a general shortage of accommodation, and it is advisable to book well in advance (at least one month prior to departure); accommodation cannot be booked at the airport. Visitors should also note that accommodation in Luanda is expensive but the city does have many hotels. A list of hotels in Angola is provided by the Embassy (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.angola.org">www.angola.org</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many hotels in Angola have air conditioning, a private bath or shower, a telephone, radio and TV. However, there is a general shortage of accommodation, and it is advisable to book well in advance (at least one month prior to departure); accommodation cannot be booked at the airport. Visitors should also note that accommodation in Luanda is expensive but the city does have many hotels. A list of hotels in Angola is provided by the Embassy (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.angola.org">www.angola.org</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Full health insurance is essential and should include medical evacuation insurance. There are some hospital facilities in the main towns but, at the moment, adequate medical facilities are virtually non-existent. However, there are some good private clinics in Luanda. Medical treatment is free although often inadequate, and visitors should travel with their own supply of remedies for simple ailments such as stomach upsets, as pharmaceutical supplies are usually extremely difficult to obtain.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is advised. Avoid dairy products, which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis E is widespread and hepatitis B&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is hyperendemic. Many insect-borne diseases exist all year throughout the country, including urban areas. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Meningitis&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;outbreaks occur. Dengue fever epidemics occur sporadically. Vaccination against tuberculosis is sometimes advised. Rabies&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here:</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Martyrs of the Colonial Repression Day :
							2018<br/>04 January </p><p>Start of Liberation War :
							04 February </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Peace and Reconciliation Day :
							04 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Africa Day :
							25 May </p><p>International Children's Day :
							01 June </p><p>Nation's Founder and National Heroes Day :
							17 September </p><p>All Soul's Day :
							02 November </p><p>Independence Day :
							11 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Angola without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes or 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine and 1L of spirits.<br />
&bull; 3 x 250ml of eau de toilette or 50ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; 3 phones, 1 camera and 1 computer.<br />
&bull; General items for personal use, gifts or souvenirs up to the value of AOA142,560 (around US$860).</p>
<p>Alcohol and tobacco allowances apply to travellers aged 18 and over only.</p>
<p>You must declare brand new electronic items.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted imports include goods which infringe copyright and endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted exports include endangered species and items of historical, artistic and archaeological value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kwanza (AOA) = 100 centimos. Notes are in denominations of AOA2000, 1000, 500, 200, 100, 50, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of AOA5, 2, 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money should be exchanged at official bureaux de change only, which can be found throughout the country, but particularly in Luanda (changing money on the black market is illegal). US Dollars are also widely accepted. Cash withdrawal is not possible.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are not generally accepted. American Express, Diners Club and Visa enjoy limited acceptance. Some larger hotels and resturants in Luanda have started taking credit cards.</p><p>ATMs can be found in major towns and cities, especially in the capital city of Luanda, where there are many major banks and ATM machines. However, many do not accept foreign cards so taking cash is advisable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0845-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Angola, a passport valid for at least nine months after the intended period of stay, and with two blank pages, is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If travelling without one or both parents, a child must carry a notarised travel authorisation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa: &pound;80; short-term visa: &pound;130; business (ordinary) visa: &pound;100. An express service is available for twice the usual fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist and business visas: 30 days and must be used within 60 days from the date of issue.</p>
<p>Short-term visas: up to seven days and must be used within three days of the date of issue.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy), in person, by a third party or agency, or via registered post.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visas: eight days (standard service) or five days (express service).</p>
<p>Short-term visas: eight days (standard service) or three days (express service).</p>
<p>Business visas: 15 days (standard service) or eight days (express service).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa applicants must provide a recent bank statement showing proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visas can be extended once for a further 30 days. Business visas can be extended twice for 30 days each time. Short-term visas can be extended for a further seven days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-12.333032]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[17.539032]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,246,700 sq km (481,354 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>25,830,958 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>15.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luanda.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Angola is bordered by the Democratic Republic of Congo to the north, Zambia to the east, Namibia to the south and the Atlantic Ocean to the west. Mountains rise from the coast, levelling to a plateau which makes up most of the country. The country is increasingly arid towards the south; the far south is on the edge of the Namib Desert. The northern plateau is thickly vegetated. Cabinda is a small enclave to the north of Angola proper, surrounded by the territories of the Democratic Republic of Congo and the Congo. The discovery of large oil deposits off the coast of the enclave has led to it becoming the centre of Angola's foreign business interests. The oil industry is based primarily at Malongo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic (38%), Protestant (15%) and local animist beliefs (47%).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal social courtesies should be observed. Drug trafficking or carrying incurs severe penalties. Homosexuality is illegal.<br />
<br />
<strong>Photography: </strong>It is inadvisable to photograph public places, public buildings or public events. Copies of photography permits should be deposited with your embassy; permits should be carried at all times.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Jo&atilde;o Louren&ccedil;o since September 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Jo&atilde;o Louren&ccedil;o since September 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Much of the land occupied by present day Angola was part of the Kingdom of Kongo, which rose to prominence in the 14th century. It was flourishing a century later, when Portuguese explorers reached the country and set up their first trading post at Soyo in the far north of the country.</p>
<p>Relations between the Europeans and the Kongo kings were good, allowing the foundation of Luanda by Paulo Dias de Novias with one hundred settler families and 400 soldiers in 1575.</p>
<p>The kings' sons were sent to Lisbon for education until the 17th century, after which the transatlantic slave trade soured trust between the two kingdoms. An estimated one million slaves were shipped to Portuguese Brazil between the 16th and 17th centuries from Angola.</p>
<p>The formal abolition of the transatlantic trade in 1836, following Brazilian independence, resulted in the Portuguese intensifying colonisation of its other territories, including Angola. Slavery in Portuguese colonies continued officially until the 1870s and thereafter, barely disguised, until the early 20th century.</p>
<p>It was not until the fascist government took power in Lisbon in 1926 that Portuguese rule was further consolidated with the administrative control of Angola&rsquo;s interior, even despite earlier territorial claims and the importance of the Angolan coast to the Portuguese economy.</p>
<p>Opposition to colonisation remained relatively muted until the 1950s. The war for independence erupted in 1961, and didn&rsquo;t end until Portugal&rsquo;s Marcelo Caetano regime was overthrown in a coup d&rsquo;&eacute;tat in 1974.</p>
<p>However, instead of unification, independence the following year led to an enhancement of the divisions between different liberation movements, laying the foundations for a civil war that consumed Angola for almost three decades.</p>
<p>The half a million Portuguese citizens that had remained in Angola through the independence struggles finally threw in their lot and returned to Europe, creating a massive skills shortage and leaving a country rich in resources struggling with bankruptcy. A ceasefire in 2002 finally stabilised the country, permitting democratic elections.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; President Jose Eduardo dos Santos has led Angola since 1979, making him one of the longest serving leaders anywhere in the world.<br />
&bull; The name Angola derives from the word &lsquo;ngola&rsquo;, meaning king.<br />
&bull; The country&rsquo;s first president, Agostinho Neto, was awarded the Soviet Union&rsquo;s Lenin Peace Prize for 1975-76, despite the outbreak of the Angolan Civil War.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Angola in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 785 1156.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.angola.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 785 1156.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon and Wed 0900-1300, Tues and Thurs 1200-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2100-2108 16th Street<br/>Washington<br/>20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Angola in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7299 9850. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.angola.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7299 9850. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600 (embassy); Mon-Tues 0930-1130, Thurs-Fri 0930-1300 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>22 Dorset Street<br/>London<br/>W1U 6QY<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Its name may be synonymous with strife, but since the civil war ended in 2002 Angola has been enjoying something of a renaissance. Safe and welcoming, this friendly nation transports the laidback, community-orientated lifestyle of southern Portugal to continental Africa &ndash; and travellers are once again discovering its charms.</p>
<p>Most enter the country via the capital, Luanda, which has the dubious and surprising distinction of being the most expensive city in the world. With its gleaming skyscrapers, grand government buildings and palm-lined promenades, downtown Luanda&rsquo;s prosperity probably comes as a revelation to many visitors. But the spoils of Angola&rsquo;s considerable oil wealth soon give way to unofficial shantytowns, proving that not everyone is benefitting from the black gold rush.</p>
<p>It is along Angola&rsquo;s stunning 1,700 km (1,000 mile) coastline, in cities like Luanda, where Portugal&rsquo;s colonial influences are most striking. The faded, art deco splendour of cities like Benguela and Namibe provide a welcome distraction from the country&rsquo;s sandy shores.</p>
<p>Further inland, the landscape becomes one of almost endless plains. Here remote national parks are slowly being restocked with wildlife, while the newly renovated Benguela railway wends through the seemingly endless countryside. One of the world&rsquo;s most evocative rail journeys, riding through the landscape with its people is a great way to delve into the psyche of laughter loving Angolans.</p>
<p>To the north &ndash; and separated from the rest of Angola by a 40 km (25 mile) arm of the Democratic Republic of Congo &ndash; the exclave of Cabinda is Angola in miniature, with empty beaches once popular with expats, elegant towns and virgin rainforest full of wildlife.</p>
<p>Youthful and energetic, Angola, like its people, has its own way of doing things. Fun-loving and eager to impress, it is a country still shaking off its troubled past while looking firmly at the future.</p><p>Its name may be synonymous with strife, but since the civil war ended in 2002 Angola has been enjoying something of a renaissance. Safe and welcoming, this friendly nation transports the laidback, community-orientated lifestyle of southern Portugal to continental Africa &ndash; and travellers are once again discovering its charms.</p>
<p>Most enter the country via the capital, Luanda, which has the dubious and surprising distinction of being the most expensive city in the world. With its gleaming skyscrapers, grand government buildings and palm-lined promenades, downtown Luanda&rsquo;s prosperity probably comes as a revelation to many visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
