<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Anguilla" ColCode="aia" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ai" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Anguilla]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot throughout the year, tempered by trade winds in local areas, particularly early in the year. The average rainfall for the year is 89 cm (35in) and the hurricane season is from July to November.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons throughout the year. Waterproofs are advisable for the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>The road network is good but basic and the main road is asphalt, stretching throughout the 25km (16 miles) length of Anguilla. Unpaved roads lead to beaches.</p><p>Taxis are available at the airport and seaports with fixed prices to the various hotels. Island tours can be arranged on an individual basis.</p><p>Visitors must buy a temporary Anguillan licence. This can be issued by car hire companies or the traffic department in The Valley on presentation of a national driving licence.</p><p>The speed limit on Anguilla is 50kph (30mph).</p><p>Cars are easily available for rent, though they can become booked out in high season over Christmas and New Year, so reserve early. There are numerous rental agencies available, both local and international. Companies generally deliver to your hotel. Most companies require drivers to be over 25 years old to rent a car.</p><p>Bicycles and mopeds, through Boo&rsquo;s Car and Cycle Rentals (tel: +1 264 497 8523).</p><p>The speed limit on Anguilla is 50kph (30mph).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With no direct flights to Anguilla, visitors from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> tend to fly via Antigua (British Airways and Virgin Atlantic) and then make the local transfer by small charter plane. Norwegian runs a direct flight from the UK to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/san-juan">San Juan</a> in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/puerto-rico">Puerto Rico</a>, from where Seaborne (<a href="http://www.seaborneairlines.com" target="_blank">www.seaborneairlines.com</a>) and Tradewind Aviation (<a href="http://www.flytradewind.com" target="_blank">www.flytradewind.com</a>)&nbsp;have daily schedules to the island. From North America most visitors fly to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-maarten">St Maarten</a> (American Airlines, United and Air Canada are among the many airlines serving the route) and then take a boat across to the island. It is also possible to fly via Puerto Rico.</p>
<p>Charter companies that run planes between Anguilla and neighbouring Caribbean islands include Trans Anguilla Airways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.transanguilla.com">www.transanguilla.com</a>) and Anguilla Air Services (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.anguillaairservices.com">www.anguillaairservices.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 to 12 hours (not including time spent in stopovers); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 6 to 7 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$20. Children under 12 are exempt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Clayton J. Lloyd International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is in The Valley.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A regular public ferry operates at least once an hour between Blowing Point in Anguilla and Marigot on the French side of St Martin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international phone companies. Coverage is good. It is possible to purchase a local sim card for the duration of your trip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in most resorts. There are some internet cafes and free Wi-Fi access is available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Anguilla enjoys free press. There is a weekly paper, <em>The Anguillian</em>, and there are many maps and publications designed for visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes from four days to two weeks.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1500 and closed at weekends.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Absorb Anguilla's past at the Heritage Collection Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This simple, but neatly presented museum, has displays on Anguilla&rsquo;s geology, early Arawak past and its British colonial history, right up to the Anguillian revolution and separation from St Kitts and Nevis. The story is told in artefacts such as model boats, shoes made from tyres and local household items such as brooms and irons.</p>]]><p><b>Descend the Pelican Trail to the shoreline below</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Pelican Trail is a wooden stairway that runs down a steep hillside into a tiny enclosed cove known as Pelican Bay. En route you'll find shaded platforms for resting, great views, and snorkelling and glass-bottom kayaking at the bottom.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the island on the Anguilla Heritage Trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Self-guided by map, explore a series of 10 historic sights that are signposted around the island. They include several locations in the Old Valley, with its historic "skirt and shirt" (stone and wooden) homes; the former Court House and basement jail; plus the island's former economic hub, the Old Cotton Gin House.</p>]]><p><b>Find The Fountain in an underground cave</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spend time exploring Anguilla's many grotto-like rock areas and hidden coves, which are dotted all around the island's 30-odd beaches. However, definitely don't miss out on historic landmark The Fountain, a huge underground cave with a constant supply of fresh water at Shoal Bay. Visits can be arranged via the Anguilla National Trust.</p>]]><p><b>Get pampered at a 5-star spa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Several of the major hotels in Anguilla have spas in dedicated buildings, offering an excellent range of treatments, some with products derived from the region. Most permit outside visitors including the Malliouhana Hotel, CusinArt, the Viceroy and Cap Juluca.</p>]]><p><b>Take a day trip to an offshore island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Day trips, with lunch included, are on offer to the beaches of Anguilla's offshore islands. Sandy Island and its beach bar is just 15 minutes from Sandy Ground Harbour and Prickly Pear is 25 minutes away. Scilly Cay, another favourite for lunch, sits in the bay just off the fishing village of Island Harbour.</p>]]><p><b>Test your swing on a championship golf course</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Play a round of golf on a 7063-yard, 18-hole championship golf course designed by Greg Norman. Set overlooking the south coast with lovely views of St Martin, Cuisin Art Golf Club has 13 holes with water features, as well as coastal winds and impenetrable scrub in the rough.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind on beautiful coral beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Anguilla's many idyllic, white coral beaches at a leisurely pace. Many of the best, like Rendezvous Bay, Shoal Bay and Road Bay, offer watersports but Crocus Bay and Barnes Bay can't be beaten for peace, quiet and warm cyan seas. Taxi drivers will happily drop you off and collect you later in the day.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Wallblake House, Anguilla's oldest building</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pop into the impressive Wallblake House, a restored plantation house whose foundations date back to 1787, complete with outside kitchens, stables and workers' quarters intact. The oldest building on the island, it is also the only intact plantation remaining in Anguilla. Tours need to be booked in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$311 million (2014 est).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fish, lobster, livestock, salt, concrete and rum.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fuels, food, manufactured goods, chemicals and trucks.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>North America (mainly USA), the United Kingdom and the Caribbean Region (Caricom, St Martin/St Maarten and others).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Industries include fishing and fish processing, boat manufacture (both traditional and contemporary crafts) and construction. Most of the island's agricultural produce is for domestic consumption.  The service sector, specifically tourism and financial services, is responsible for the great majority of economic output. Tourism accounts for approximately 40% of GDP. GDP has seen an appreciable downtown during the global recession and in 2009 dipped 8.5% on figures from 2008.  The financial sector has been damaged by a series of scandals, which, along with growing competition from other Caribbean micro-states, has put its future viability in question.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Anguilla is a small island with few business opportunities as such; lightweight suits or shirt and tie should be adequate for meetings.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Anguilla Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 497 2839
					Website:http://www.anguillachamber.com
					Address: ,PO Box 321,The Valley,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Unusually for a Caribbean island, Anguilla boasts an exciting array of gourmet, gastronomic dining experiences (by chefs from the excellent hotel dining rooms that have set up independent restaurants) as well Mexican and Italian and of course the informal fare of the beach bars. While most ingredients are imported, local fish, lobster, Anguillian crayfish and some local crops are used.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Salt fish, usually served shredded and tossed with finely chopped onions, sweet peppers, some oil and a bit of hot pepper, is a traditional breakfast.<br />
&bull; Spiny lobster bisque is often served on special occasions. <em><br />
&bull;</em> Johnny cakes, which taste somewhere between bread and cake, are served instead of dinner rolls. <br />
&bull; Tamarind balls are a sweet and sour treat. <br />
&bull; Pigeon peas and rice is a popular side dish.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Normal practice is 10-15%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>16.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Anguilla's nightlife is centred around hotels and small local bars offering live music. Sandy Ground is the 'hotspot' on Fridays and Saturdays, with several restaurants and dance bars. The crowds move to the more touristy Shoal Bay East on Wednesdays and Sundays. Tourists and locals alike dance barefoot.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Art galleries are scattered across the island, offering paintings and occasionally wooden sculpture and carvings. There is a good Arts and Crafts Centre, and the island-built racing boats are world-famous. Souvenirs also include shells and small models of the islands archipelago. In the large resort hotels you will find sophisticated boutiques offering resort clothing and accessories and swimwear, but there are also some good independent clothes shops.  Other shops offer international name brands in bone china, crystal and jewellery. For more extensive shopping, nip across to St Maarten, where the French side offers clothing and accessories and the Dutch side offers duty free purchases of all sorts (cameras, jewellery, souvenirs).</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1700. A few shops open on Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels range from small, boutique properties and beachside cabins to luxury 5-star resorts in architecturally extraordinary buildings. Tourist accommodation is mainly in the west end, though there are some small hotels and apartments around Shoal Bay East and some cheaper guest houses in the Valley and Sandy Ground. The top hotels feature the latest in spa and wellness facilities, services and treatments to further guarantee you unwind. </p>
<p><strong>Note: </strong>A government tax of 10% is levied on all hotel bills as well as a 10% service charge.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Anguilla has a handful of small inns and guest houses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels range from small, boutique properties and beachside cabins to luxury 5-star resorts in architecturally extraordinary buildings. Tourist accommodation is mainly in the west end, though there are some small hotels and apartments around Shoal Bay East and some cheaper guest houses in the Valley and Sandy Ground. The top hotels feature the latest in spa and wellness facilities, services and treatments to further guarantee you unwind. </p>
<p><strong>Note: </strong>A government tax of 10% is levied on all hotel bills as well as a 10% service charge.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels range from small, boutique properties and beachside cabins to luxury 5-star resorts in architecturally extraordinary buildings. Tourist accommodation is mainly in the west end, though there are some small hotels and apartments around Shoal Bay East and some cheaper guest houses in the Valley and Sandy Ground. The top hotels feature the latest in spa and wellness facilities, services and treatments to further guarantee you unwind. </p>
<p><strong>Note: </strong>A government tax of 10% is levied on all hotel bills as well as a 10% service charge.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Primary health services can be obtained from the three private health clinics, where registered nurses provide care for minor emergencies. Family doctors hold clinics twice weekly. Secondary health care can be found at the small hospital located in The Valley. Minor emergency treatment is usually free for UK citizens with proof of UK residence, though you will be expected to pay for drugs. Health insurance is recommended as costs for other categories of treatment are high.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is readily available and is advised. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products (all imported) are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B and dengue fever occur.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are generally observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Anguilla Day :
							30 May </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							11 June </p><p>Separation Day :
							19 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Anguilla without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1.14L of wine or spirits.<br />
&bull; 114ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Gifts to the value of EC$50 per adult and EC$25 per child under 18 (residents of Anguilla returning after at least 72 hours away).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports to Anguilla include drugs, firearms and obscene material.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eastern Caribbean Dollar (XCD; symbol EC$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of EC$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of EC$1, and 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents. <br />
<br />
<strong>Note: </strong>The EC Dollar is tied to the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency may be exchanged in the capital. US Dollars are widely accepted and prices quoted are generally in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express and Visa are widely accepted in hotels and restaurants or shops accustomed to serving tourists.</p><p>ATMs are available in at the airport, several banks in The Valley and at certain shopping malls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1500, Fri 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months after the date of entry into Anguilla is required by all visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British embassies charge &pound;115 for receiving, handling and forwarding visa applications for British Overseas Territories.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Consulate (or consular section at embassy) or High Commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[18.244993]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-63.041979]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>91 sq km (35 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>14,764 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>164 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Valley.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Overseas Territory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Anguilla, the northernmost of the Leeward Islands, also comprises the island of Sombrero, lying 48km (30 miles) north of Anguilla, and several small islets or cays. The nearest islands are St Maarten, 8km (5 miles) south of Anguilla, and St Kitts and Nevis, 113km (70 miles) to the southeast. The islands are mainly flat (the highest point, Crocus Hill, is only 60m (213ft) above sea level) with, arguably, some of the best beaches in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic, Anglican, Baptist, Methodist and Moravian, with Hindu, Jewish and Muslim minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government is anxious to set limits to the commercialisation of the island and visitors will find that social life is centred on the tourist areas. Anguillians will greet anyone they meet, whether they know them personally or not, and expect to be acknowledged in return. The atmosphere is relaxed and English customs prevail. Beachwear should be confined to resorts. Topless and nude bathing is prohibited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without a round, grounding pin) are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chief Minister Hubert Hughes since 2010.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor Christina Scott since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Having first been settled by South American tribes at least 3000 years ago and possibly spotted by Columbus in 1493, Anguilla was named the Spanish (the word means &lsquo;eel&rsquo;) because of the island&rsquo;s shape, but it was the British who first colonised the land in the 17th century when the island was administered in conjunction with the Leeward Islands.</p>
<p>It seems the colonists brought African slaves with them and the island drew the attentions of the French whose efforts to capture it in 1745 and 1796 were repelled.</p>
<p>During the middle of 20th century, Anguilla was incorporated into St Kitts and Nevis, despite opposition from the islanders. Upon St Kitts&rsquo; independence in 1967, the Anguillians refused to accept independent government from there. It led to two &lsquo;revolutions&rsquo; precipitated by referenda in 1967 and 1969 in which the population voted overwhelming against government by St Kitts. After declaring themselves the Republic of Anguilla, a junior minister from the British government arrived to establish an interim government but was quickly expelled. Days later 315 British paratroopers, 40 Metropolitan police officers and two frigates followed, order was duly restored and a new Commissioner installed.</p>
<p>A new constitution was enacted in 1976 and in 1980 Anguilla was formally separated from St Kitts and Nevis and granted the status of a British overseas territory.</p>
<p>Domestic politics have been dominated by the shifting fortunes of the Anguilla United Movement, the Anguilla United Front (which comprises the Anguilla National Alliance and the Anguilla Democratic Party) and the Anguilla Progressive Party, as well as various independent politicians. The current Chief Minister, Victor Banks, took office in 2015.<br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are seven elected seats in Anguilla&rsquo;s assembly &ndash; four assembly members are appointed, three by the governor and one by the ruling party. The assembly is part of the executive council, led by the chief minister who advises the governor, who is appointed by the British monarch, according to the 1982 constitution.</p>
<p>With no tax on profits, estate or capital gains Anguilla has been a popular tax haven for years. In 2011, faced with mounting debts of its own, it introduced its first form of income tax &ndash; the Interim Stabilisation Levy &ndash; at three per cent.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; The national sport is boat racing and there are regattas on pubic holidays.</p>
<p>&bull; It is thought the island&rsquo;s population of Green Iguanas descends from creatures brought from overseas and deposited by hurricanes.</p>
<p>&bull; Anguilla enjoys the reputation of being the &lsquo;culinary capital of the Caribbean&rsquo;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Anguilla in UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 1494 447 033.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 1494 447 033.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>78 Plumber Road<br/>High Wycombe<br/>HP11 2SR<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Governor's Office in Anguilla]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 264 497 2621. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/anguilla</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 264 497 2621. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>PO Box 60<br/>The Valley<br/>AI-2640<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Beyonc&eacute;. Paul McCartney. Denzel Washington. Expect to keep good company if you&rsquo;re holidaying in Anguilla, which has become something of a hangout for the rich and famous in recent years.</p>
<p>Though not the most accessible Caribbean island (geographically and financially speaking), that is precisely why this British Overseas Territory is so appealing for the jet set. There are other reasons, of course. Anguilla also lays claim to some of the finest beaches in the region, as well as some of the most luxurious hotels. Suffice to say, it&rsquo;s not the place to be penny pinching.</p>
<p>That said, some visitors do just that: favourable tax rates have earned Anguilla a reputation as a place to squirrel away the dollars. However, the island&rsquo;s true riches lie below the waves, where you will find spectacular coral reef formations and a staggering diversity of marine life: from stingrays to sharks, turtles to tropical fish, there&rsquo;s as much to see on the seafloor as there is on the shore.</p>
<p>Sailing is another popular pastime in Anguilla and it doesn&rsquo;t take long to navigate the tiny island and its eight largely uninhabited cays.</p>
<p>If it sounds like a playground for the rich that&rsquo;s because it is, but that&rsquo;s not to say more wallet-friendly options don&rsquo;t exist. There are a range of holiday villas and midrange hotels to suit more modest budgets. A night out needn&rsquo;t cost the Earth either: potent cocktails go for reasonable prices in Anguilla&rsquo;s ubiquitous beach bars.</p>
<p>Those who like their food are in for an unexpected treat. The restaurant scene is excellent and there is a surprising range of cuisine, from fine French fare to local dishes. Don&rsquo;t leave without feasting on buttery Anguillian lobster. <br />
<br />
For the culturally minded, Anguilla has many galleries showcasing local art, not to mention a delightfully eccentric museum. Wherever you are though, those beautiful beaches are only minutes away.</p><p>Beyonc&eacute;. Paul McCartney. Denzel Washington. Expect to keep good company if you&rsquo;re holidaying in Anguilla, which has become something of a hangout for the rich and famous in recent years.</p>
<p>Though not the most accessible Caribbean island (geographically and financially speaking), that is precisely why this British Overseas Territory is so appealing for the jet set. There are other reasons, of course. Anguilla also lays claim to some of the finest beaches in the region, as well as some of the most luxurious hotels. Suffice to say, it&rsquo;s not the place to be penny pinching.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
