<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Antigua and Barbuda" ColCode="atg" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ag" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Antigua and Barbuda]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The islands enjoy a very pleasant balmy tropical climate which remains warm and relatively dry throughout the year, with relatively little variance. Temperatures range from lows of 22°C (72°F) to highs of 40°C (104°F) all year round, with October to January being the hottest time of year, staying in the region of 30°C (86°F) to 35°C (95°F). Cooling winds blow in from the south east so the heat rarely feels too unbearable. In general, humidity in Antigua and Barbuda is quite low, meaning you won't be drenched in a sweaty fug during your trip.</p><p>The rainy season runs from around June to November, and during this time daily rain showers are common; there is also a good chance of tropical storms and hurricanes across the islands. Their location in the hurricane zone means the islands are vulnerable to powerful storms every two or three years, whilst hurricanes can hit every two to six years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dress for a tropical climate - lightweight cottons or linens will be appropriate for most of the year, but those visiting the islands from June to September should bring waterproofs so that they're not caught out when the rains come.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A small airstrip at Codrington on Barbuda is equipped to handle light aircraft. Antigua Barbuda Montserrat Air (<a href="http://www.antigua-flights.com" target="_blank">www.antigua-flights.com</a>) operates daily scheduled flights between Antigua, Barbuda and Montserrat.</p>
<p>A helicopter ride and tour is also available from Antigua to Barbuda (<a href="http://www.caribbeanhelicopters.com" target="_blank">www.caribbeanhelicopters.com</a>). Some hotels on Barbuda can arrange private helicopter transfer.</p><p>To fly to other islands from Barbuda it is necessary to transfer back to VC Bird International airport on Antigua.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local boats are available for excursions, and hotels and tour companies can arrange day trips.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is perfectly safe to drive around Antigua by road and this is a good way to explore the country. Main roads are of good quality but may become dirt tracks if you go off the beaten track. A car is not strictly necessary as public transport does exist, but buses, most of which run from St. Johns, tend to serve local rather than tourist routes. Taxis are reliable and plentiful.</p>l<p>Larger roads are all-weather and in reasonable condition, although they often lack road markings. Smaller roads are more rugged and can contain pot holes.</p>
<p>Few streets are lit at night.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p>Taxis are available everywhere with standardised rates. US Dollars are more readily accepted by taxi drivers. Taxi drivers are also qualified as tour guides for sightseeing trips. Taxis are identified by &lsquo;TX&rsquo; on licence plates.</p><p>The national speed limit is 65kph (40mph) and there is a limit of 32kph (20mph) in built-up areas.</p><p>In the event of a breakdown contact your car hire company.</p><p>This can be organised in advance from your home country but is easy to do on arrival. In addition to a valid driver&rsquo;s licence, a permit to drive in Antigua is required. The hire company can assist in getting this temporary licence. There are several reputable car hire companies on Antigua (some of which also hire out mopeds and bicycles). Hire rates are for the day and there is no mileage. Rental cars are identifiable by an &lsquo;R&rsquo; on licence plates.</p>
<p>If travelling with young children, be aware that car hire companies do not provide child or booster seats. It is not a legal requirement to use these, but the conditions of the roads on Antigua make it advisable.</p><p>You can hire bikes from car rental companies or from hotels. Motorcycles are also available for hire at Jolly Harbour.</p><p>The national speed limit is 65kph (40mph) and there is a limit of 32kph (20mph) in built-up areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Antigua and Barbuda</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">vc_birdairport</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Antigua and Barbuda</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">shirley_heights</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Antigua and Barbuda</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">jolly_beach</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Antigua and Barbuda</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">english_harbour</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Antigua and Barbuda does not have its own national airline but many airlines do operate regular direct flights there. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and Virgin Atlantic  (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) fly from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>.&nbsp;Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>) and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) fly from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.</p>
<p>LIAT (<a href="http://www.liatairline.com" target="_blank">www.liatairline.com</a>) operates an inter-Caribbean service to other islands including St. Kitts, St. Maarten, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominica">Dominica</a></a>&nbsp;and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guadeloupe">Guadeloupe</a>.&nbsp;Caribbean Airlines (<a href="http://www.caribbean-airlines.com" target="_blank">www.caribbean-airlines.com</a>) operates connecting flights from Trinidad &amp; Tobago and&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/barbados">Barbados</a>&nbsp;to Antigua as well as international flights.</p>
<p>The best time to travel to Antigua and Barbuda is in the winter between mid-December and mid-April, when the weather is at its driest, but prices outside this period can drop dramatically.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/antigua-and-barbuda/v-c-bird-international-airport">V. C. Bird International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 9 hours;&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;4 hours 20 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cheaper flights are often available which may require connections. VC Bird International Airport is located on the northeast corner of Antigua. Connecting flights are required to travel to Barbuda.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cheaper flights are often available which may require connections. VC Bird International Airport is located on the northeast corner of Antigua. Connecting flights are required to travel to Barbuda.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>V. C. Bird International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.vcbia.com<p>V. C. Bird International Airport is located 8km (5 miles) northeast of St John's, on the island of Antigua.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 268 484 2300</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Main ports of entry to Antigua include English Harbour, Jolly Harbour, Deepwater Harbour and Heritage Quay. Private boaters can enter at St John&rsquo;s Harbour on the west coast, English Harbour and the St. James Club in the south or Crabbs Marina in the north east.</p><p>Bare boat or crewed chartering is available through a number of companies based in St Johns.</p>
<p>Yachts wishing to visit Barbuda must clear in at one of the official ports of entry in Antigua first.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Antigua &amp; Barbuda has an extensive telephone network. Most hotels will have telephone facilities, but it is often cheaper to use VoIP services such as Skype to make international calls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Unregistered roaming is available - visitors with TDMA handsets can make calls without registering, provided they can give a credit card number.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet services are available in the larger cities and resorts, although these may be dial-up rather than broadband connections.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many of Antigua &amp; Barbuda's broadcast media is politically owned or controlled, although this is now changing. The country's first independent radio station Observer Radio launched in 2001 after a five-year struggle to obtain a licence. The daily and weekly press carries a spectrum of opinion, including criticism of the government. Some newspapers have political or governmental associations. All are in English. Following the closure of the <em>Antigua Sun</em>, the main newspaper is <em>The Daily Observer</em>. Cable television is widely available, whilst the local TV station is called ABS (run by Antigua &amp; Barbuda Broadcasting Services). Some radio stations are owned by political or religious factions, such as Crusader Radio, owned by the United Progressive Party. Observer Radio and ZDK are commercial broadcasters as is Sun FM, although it is privately run.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thu 0815-1200 and 1300-1600, and until 1700 on Fridays</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Catch a cricket match</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cricket is played to the highest international standard here – and by legions of enthusiastic amateurs in villages all over the islands. Antigua even produced one of the finest cricketers the game has ever seen, Sir Vivien Richards. Try and catch a game at the country's national stadium in St John's, which is named after the batsman.</p>]]><p><b>Challenge a local to a game of Warri</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You can't avoid Antigua and Barbuda's national game of Warri – an ancient board game (also known as "count and capture") that was traditionally played using shells placed in cups: you see it played on most street corners and may even be asked to join in. A National Warri Festival is held every year.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the past at the Museum of Antigua and Barbuda</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover Antigua and Barbuda beyond the beaches and resorts by visiting the Museum of Antigua and Barbuda, Antigua's oldest building. It is held in the old Court House, built in 1750. Exhibits explore Antigua's geological origins as well as more modern exhibits such as Sir Viv Richards' cricket bat.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a barbecue at Shirley Heights</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The view from Shirley Heights extends across the harbour and out to neighbouring Caribbean islands of Montserrat and Guadeloupe. This collection of gun emplacements and military buildings is the atmospheric, rum-heavy setting for a barbecue with live steel band music every Sunday. Close by is the cemetery, containing an obelisk commemorating the soldiers of the 54th Regiment.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the restored Nelson’s Dockyard</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Antigua's most famous landmarks, Nelson's Dockyard in English Harbour, dates from 1745 and was home to Admiral Horatio Nelson until 1787. It has been lovingly restored after years of decay and today these historic buildings house a museum, craft and souvenir shop, restaurant, hotels and marina.</p>]]><p><b>Feel old-fashioned in Codrington, Barbuda</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the less-developed Barbuda for its wild beauty, deserted beaches and heavily wooded interior abounding in wildlife. The main town, known as the village, is Codrington. It sits on the edge of a lagoon. Laid-back and old-fashioned, visitors share the winding streets with donkeys and goats, instead of fast food outlets and noisy bars.</p>]]><p><b>Follow the road along Fig Tree Drive</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take Antigua's most scenic route, Fig Tree Drive. The 32km (20 miles) of winding roads travel through the lush tropical hills and rainforest and rise to the steep farmlands around Fig Tree Hill before descending to the coast. Fig is the Antiguan name for banana and along the way you'll won't just see bananas but mangoes and coconut groves too.</p>]]><p><b>Get blown away by St John's Cathedral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rebuilt three times because of hurricane damage, the present day St John's Cathedral with its dramatic white towers is an imposing landmark originally erected in 1845. It contains items from its predecessors, whilst the bronze figures of St John the Baptist and St John the Divine are thought to have be taken from a French ship in 1756.</p>]]><p><b>Go wild with watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Antigua and Barbuda offers a seemingly endless range of watersports for those who fancy some exhilaration, including windsurfing, water skiing, surfing and jet-skiing. The island is fantastic for those who wish to snorkel and scuba dive, and with more than 365 beaches, there are plenty of places from which to launch a kayaking, hobie cat or sunfish sailboat.</p>]]><p><b>Haggle at the local markets</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Salivate and haggle over the riot of colourful fruits, vegetables and spices available at one of the best local markets in the Caribbean. Antigua Market is situated in the south end of town at the junction of Valley and All Saints Roads. Head there in the morning to capture the best of the bargains.</p>]]><p><b>Head to Frigate Bird Sanctuary during mating season</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated in the Codrington Lagoon, Frigate Bird Sanctuary is a 40-minute boat ride across the water. It is a spectacular sight even for non-bird watchers. During the mating season (September to April) the Frigate male displays a huge red breast to attract a female mate and they lay just one egg, in a precarious nest atop the mangroves.</p>]]><p><b>Hike up to Highland House</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sitting atop Barbuda's highest point, which at just 38m-high (125ft) won't exactly give you a nosebleed, stand the crumbling ruins of Highland House. A former estate run by Sir Christopher Codrington, it's an impressive sight and offers great views without the vertigo.</p>]]><p><b>Lay claim to the throne at Redonda</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The deserted island of Redonda lies about 56km (35 miles) northeast of Antigua. The island is famous for its unusual monarchy (no less than four people have laid claim to the "throne") and it has an eccentric and amusing history and small population of burrowing owls, a bird now extinct on Antigua. Boat trips to the island are available.</p>]]><p><b>Relax on one of Antigua's many beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are hundreds of beaches on Antigua but some of the best include Half Moon Bay, popular with windsurfers and snorkellers. For those seeking peace and quiet, the southwestern jut off Johnson's Point is tranquil, while Turner's Beach nearby look out to onto Montserrat. For even quieter beaches sneak to uninhabited inlets such as Prickly Pear Island.</p>]]><p><b>Ride a speedboat to Stingray City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A drive to the pretty fishing village of Seatons introduces visitors to the delights of interacting with rays, followed an exhilarating speed boat ride takes you to one of Antigua's off shore islands and a shallow stingray pool where one can touch, play with and feed stingrays in a safe environment.</p>]]><p><b>Sail to a secluded cove</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Antigua hosts many international yachting events and regattas throughout the year, but even inexperienced yachtsmen and women can take the helm. A number of hotels offer sailing lessons and experiences, while seasoned sailors can charter their own yachts. Those preferring to seek out a secluded cove and anchor for a day can do so by hiring a dinghy.</p>]]><p><b>See the rock paintings at Two Foot Bay Caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Caves at Two Foot Bay are popular with visitors to Barbuda and are easily accessible, although a guide is recommended. Bats, crabs and tropical birds can be seen as well as petroglyphs or rock drawings made by Barbuda's early settlers, the Arawaks. Access is through a circular chamber through a hole in the cave roof. </p>]]><p><b>Take the pirate ship to Great Bird Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take an excursion to Great Bird Island, home of the harmless Antiguan racer, from Dickenson Bay. Glass-bottomed boats afford leisurely views of the reef, and a restored pirate ship sails around the island and takes passengers for day or evening trips, with food, drink and entertainment included.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Betty’s Hope, a former sugar plantation</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The islands' colonial history is brought home at partially-restored Betty's Hope, Antigua's pioneer sugar plantation. The surviving structures are two stone sugar mills and a still house, which form an open-air museum and good picnic spot. Originally built by Sir Christopher Codrington, he named it after his daughter Betty.</p>]]><p><b>Witness the power of the Atlantic at Indian Town Point</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The wild side of Antigua can be seen at Devil&rsquo;s Bridge, a limestone arch on the shore of Indian Town Point, where at high tide the Atlantic waves come crashing through boreholes in the rocks near the bridge. Indian Town Point is thought to have been an Arawak campsite before the Europeans colonised the islands.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$1.5 billion (2016)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum products, bedding, handicrafts, electronic components, transport equipment, food and live animals</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food and live animals, machinery and transport equipment, manufactures, chemicals, oil</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Barbados, Spain, UK,&nbsp;USA, China and Canada.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Antigua was one of the first Caribbean islands to actively encourage tourism which continues to dominate the economy, accounting for almost 60% of its GDP.  Tourists from the USA, Canada and Europe account for the majority of arrivals to Antigua and Barbuda and economic growth will depend on their continued support.  However the Spencer Government which came to power in 2004 has made efforts to diversify the economy into other areas such as agriculture and has been successful in reducing the public debt by fiscal reform initiatives.</p>
<p>Antigua and Barbuda&rsquo;s economy was severely affected by the Stanford scandal which rocked the islands in 2009. US citizen and major employer in Antigua Allen Stanford was found guilty of perpetrating a huge fraud scheme and was eventually convicted. His Stanford financial group collapsed with disastrous repercussions for the nation, happening as it did as the region was also suffering from the effects of world recession.  The Bank of Antigua was subsequently taken over by the Eastern Caribbean Central Bank.</p>
<p>In 2013 Antigua and Barbuda Prime Minister Dr Baldwin Spencer officially launched the country&rsquo;s Citizenship by Investment Programme as a way to generate much needed income and employment for the country. Already available on a number of other Caribbean islands, this scheme will offer overseas investors the opportunity to become a citizen of Antigua and hold an Antiguan passport. There are different levels &ndash; amongst the options are a real estate investment of $400,000; a business investment of at least $1.5 million or a $250,000 contribution to Antigua&rsquo;s National Development Fund. The government hoped that this scheme will put the country on the road to recovery as well as attracting international attention to its natural assets. The economy grew by about 2% in 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A lightweight suit is suitable for most business visits. Handshaking is the normal greeting for acquaintances and for formal introductions. Business cards are expected from people who do not live on the islands.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1630.<br />
<br />
Government office hours: Mon-Thurs 1000-1700, Fri 1000-1430.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Investment Authority</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 462 1033
					Website:
					Address: Redcliffe Street,PO Box 80,St John's,]]><b>Antigua &amp; Barbuda Chamber of Commerce and Industry Ltd</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 462 0743
					Website:
					Address: Corner of Popeshead Street and North Street,PO Box 774,St John's,]]><b>Alexander Parrish (Antigua) Ltd (Information on Conferences/Conventions)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 462 0638
					Website:http://www.apalantigua.com
					Address: Travel Department,PO Box 45,Redcliffe Street,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Fresh catches are amongst Antigua's gastronomic specialities with lobster, red snapper, conch, mahi mahi, shrimp and other fish always worth sampling. Most resorts have their own restaurants, but to sample authentic Antiguan fare, head to one of the excellent local restaurants, which are scattered around both the islands. Renowned for their hearty Caribbean dishes, some of these restaurants also offer beach views.</p><p>On Antigua you will find all types of international cuisine including French, Italian and American food as well as local specialities. Meanwhile, delectable street food, such as barbeque chicken, fish and rotis, can be found around St John's and English Harbour.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Seafood:</strong> The waters around the islands abound with delicious fish.<br />
<strong>Fungee:</strong> Cornmeal and okra dumplings.<br />
<strong>Pepperpot:</strong> Hearty vegetable stew with salted meat often served with <em>fungee</em>.<br />
<strong>Roti:</strong> Patties filled with curried potatoes, chicken or beef.<br />
<strong>Ducana:</strong> Grated sweet potato mixed with coconut, sugar and spices and steamed in a banana leaf. Often served with mashed aubergine, okra and saltfish.<br />
<strong>Tamarind balls:</strong> Candy made from tamarind.<br />
<strong>Antigua black pineapple:</strong> Pineapples famous throughout the East Caribbean for their unique, extra-sweet flavour.<br />
<strong>Callaloo:</strong> A dark green vegetable often served as a soup.<br />
<strong>Johnny cakes:</strong> A kind of doughnut, usually served as breakfast with salted codfish and chopped up.<br />
<strong>Ting:</strong> Sparkling grapefruit drink.<br />
<strong>Wadadli:</strong> A light local lager.<br />
<strong>Freshly squeezed juice:</strong> Pineapples, coconuts, guavas, mangoes, lemongrass and tamarind all make delicious juices.<br />
<strong>Rum:</strong> Antigua English Harbour and Antigua Cavalier are the most famous brands.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Antiguan food can be spicy, but locals often add extra heat with a splash of Susie's Hot Sauce, which is present on most Antiguan dining tables.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10 to 15% is included on hotel bills for staff gratuities, plus an 8.5% government tax.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As on most Caribbean islands, you are never far from music and partying on Antigua and Barbuda, with bands playing in bars and on the beaches around the islands.</p>
<p>Most of the nightlife is centred in St John's, although hotels and casinos around the islands usually provide in-house entertainment for both hotel guests and non-residents. The strip on the junction of Falmouth and English Harbour is probably the liveliest location, with a number of bright bars playing live music popular with locals and tourists alike. During Antigua Sailing Week these haunts are full to bursting with yachties and the rum and beer flows.</p>
<p>There are also a number of beach bars along the coast which are lazy by day but jump into life at night with music ranging from jazz and blues to reggae and calypso.</p>
<p>Casinos generally offer more than just gambling; live music, restaurants and bars are standard in most, a wide choice of restaurants and bars around the main tourist areas offer international and authentic Caribbean food.<br />
<br />
Some of the best steel bands in the Caribbean can be found travelling around the hotels along with limbo dancers and calypso singers. They perform nightly during the high season (November to April).<br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p>The best party on the island is at Shirley Heights Lookout. Crowds gather on the terrace of this fortification every Sunday evening from 1600 to 2200 to enjoy unparalleled views over English Harbour with a BBQ, live music, drinks and incredible sunsets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of small supermarkets and shopping centres around the island such as Woods Mall in the North of the island which stock essentials, but for the best souvenirs and luxury duty free shopping head to St John's and its two main shopping areas, Heritage Quay and Redcliff Quay.</p><p>Brightly painted pottery and crafts, spices and of course bottles of rum are the best souvenirs of Antigua, but shops in St John's sell everything from precious gems to pirate outfits.</p><p>Heritage Quay Complex is a shopping and entertainment area with over 50 duty-free shops, restaurants and a casino with a supper club. It forms part of the newest development in central St John's. Brightly stocked stalls of fruit and vegetables are sold at the Public Market, along with a few locally-made crafts.</p><p>Efforts have been made to unclog the public roads of street-vendors so pedestrians and vehicles can move more freely. They now ply their trade of handicrafts, clothing and souvenirs from 150 stalls in the multi-storey Vendor's Mall.</p><p>Saturday morning is the best time to watch the locals buying and selling everything from coconut water to antiques. Arrive early (from 0700 onwards) to catch the best atmosphere and take in a hearty Antiguan breakfast at one of the local cafes afterwards.</p><p>Redcliff Quay is colourful, picturesque shopping district. Overlooking the harbour in St John's, it is located in one of the oldest parts of the town, dating back to the 17th century.  Formerly a trading place for slaves and sugar, today it is home to a number of exclusive shops including jewellers, boutiques and craft shops. There are also art galleries selling work by local artists and potters, and some charming restaurants, coffee shops and wine bars. It is hugely popular with cruise ship passengers so you may want to avoid the area on those days when the cruise ships are in port, as it can get very busy.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1600 Sat 0800-1200. Stores in Heritage Quay and Redcliffe Quay are open on Sundays and public holidays when cruise ships are docked.</p><p>There are only a few small shops at the airport so it is a good idea to buy souvenirs in town before you leave.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to accommodation, Antigua and Barbuda tend to be at the expensive end of the scale. Luxury properties with pools and state-of-the-art facilities abound in the resorts on the beachfronts, as do all-inclusives, but there are less expensive options (albeit more down to earth) to be found too. Boutique hotels such as Keyonna Beach on Antigua Island are gaining in popularity too.</p><p>Hotel rates are considerably cheaper in the summer months (May to November) due to the frequent tropical storms. A government tax of 8.5% is added to hotel bills, plus a service charge of 10%. There is no official grading system but a wide choice of hotels is available on Antigua. Being smaller, Barbuda's accommodation range is more limited, but there are still a few major resorts on the island.<br/><br/><strong>Note: </strong>Accommodation must be booked well in advance during Tennis Week, Antigua Sailing Week and Carnival (contact the tourist office for further information). No special accommodation facilities exist for students and young travellers and camping is not allowed. Sleeping and living on the beaches is also not permitted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guest houses and bed & breakfasts are much cheaper than the hotels and provide basic but clean accommodation, sometimes with meals. There are a number of guest houses and B&Bs on both Antigua and Barbuda. Most are charming, if a little ramshackle, providing a less-cloistered view of life on the islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to accommodation, Antigua and Barbuda tend to be at the expensive end of the scale. Luxury properties with pools and state-of-the-art facilities abound in the resorts on the beachfronts, as do all-inclusives, but there are less expensive options (albeit more down to earth) to be found too. Boutique hotels such as Keyonna Beach on Antigua Island are gaining in popularity too.</p><p>Hotel rates are considerably cheaper in the summer months (May to November) due to the frequent tropical storms. A government tax of 8.5% is added to hotel bills, plus a service charge of 10%. There is no official grading system but a wide choice of hotels is available on Antigua. Being smaller, Barbuda's accommodation range is more limited, but there are still a few major resorts on the island.<br/><br/><strong>Note: </strong>Accommodation must be booked well in advance during Tennis Week, Antigua Sailing Week and Carnival (contact the tourist office for further information). No special accommodation facilities exist for students and young travellers and camping is not allowed. Sleeping and living on the beaches is also not permitted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to accommodation, Antigua and Barbuda tend to be at the expensive end of the scale. Luxury properties with pools and state-of-the-art facilities abound in the resorts on the beachfronts, as do all-inclusives, but there are less expensive options (albeit more down to earth) to be found too. Boutique hotels such as Keyonna Beach on Antigua Island are gaining in popularity too.</p><p>Hotel rates are considerably cheaper in the summer months (May to November) due to the frequent tropical storms. A government tax of 8.5% is added to hotel bills, plus a service charge of 10%. There is no official grading system but a wide choice of hotels is available on Antigua. Being smaller, Barbuda's accommodation range is more limited, but there are still a few major resorts on the island.<br/><br/><strong>Note: </strong>Accommodation must be booked well in advance during Tennis Week, Antigua Sailing Week and Carnival (contact the tourist office for further information). No special accommodation facilities exist for students and young travellers and camping is not allowed. Sleeping and living on the beaches is also not permitted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is strongly recommended as medical treatment is expensive. There are several GPs on the island as well as one hospital and one private clinic. Recompression chambers are on nearby Saba and St Thomas (travel by air ambulance). Please note that the private health clinic, Adelin does not accept medical travel insurance in payment for treatment, and will require a deposit of US$4,000 by credit card before treatment can be given.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available and is advised for the first few weeks of the stay. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption so there is no need to be overly cautious. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Dengue fever may occur. Normal precautions against mosquito bites should be taken and visitors should drink plenty of water to mitigate any risk of heat stroke due to high temperatures.  There is a high prevalence of HIV/AIDS in the Caribbean so appropriate precautions should be taken. Tuberculosis and hepatitis B vaccinations are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are generally observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							07 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Carnival Monday :
							06 August </p><p>Carnival Tuesday :
							07 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							01 November </p><p>National Heroes Day :
							09 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Antigua &amp; Barbuda without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of wine or spirits.<br />
&bull; 170ml (60 zs) of perfume.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include arms and non-prescription drugs. Restricted goods requiring a licence include vehicles, meat, plants, fruits and vegetables, pharmaceuticals, chemicals and firearms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>East Caribbean Dollar (XCD; symbol EC$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of EC$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of EC$2 and EC$1, and 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> currency is accepted almost everywhere. The EC Dollar is pegged to the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although the EC Dollar is tied to the US Dollar, exchange rates will vary at different exchange establishments. There are international banks in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-johns">St John's</a>, and Pound Sterling and US Dollars can be exchanged at hotels and in the larger shops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards including American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted all over the islands.</p><p>ATMs are available on the island, with more found in the major resorts and towns such as St John's.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These can be exchanged at international banks, hotels and larger stores. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars rather than Pound Sterling or Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1500; Fri 0800-1600. The Bank of Antigua also opens until midday on Saturdays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Antigua and Barbuda, a passport valid for at least six months beyond the period of stay and containing one blank page is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit passengers travelling within the same day,  who normally require a visa, do not need a visa for entry into Antigua and Barbuda, provided that they have proof of their onward journey and do not leave the airport transit area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single- and multiple-entry visitor and business visas are available. Costs vary according to the type of visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: valid for a single visit for dates specified on the visa application; multiple-entry visa: valid for multiple entries within one year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All nationals who do require a visa must apply for an e-Visa before travelling (<a href="https://evisa.immigration.gov.ag/agEvisa-app/" target="evisa.immigration.gov.ag/agEvisa-app/">evisa.immigration.gov.ag/agEvisa-app/</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>e-Visa processing usually takes up to seven days, though may take 15 to 30 days in some circumstances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are granted a specific period of stay on arrival. If you wish to extend this, you must apply and pay for an extension at the immigration department.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[17.145978]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-61.820959]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Total: 441.6 sq km (170.5 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>100,963 (World Bank estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>228.42 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St John's.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Antigua &amp; Barbuda is made up of three islands; Antigua, Barbuda and Redonda. Low-lying and volcanic in origin, they are part of the Leeward Islands group in the northeast Caribbean.</p>
<p>Antigua's coastline curves into a multitude of coves and harbours (they were once volcanic craters) and there are more than 365 beaches of fine white sand, fringed with palms. The island's highest point, Mount Obama stands at 402m (1,319ft) high, and its capital is St John's.</p>
<p>Barbuda lies 61.5km (38.2 miles) north of Antigua and is an unspoiled natural haven for wild deer and exotic birds. Its 8km-long (5 miles) beach is reputed to be among the most beautiful in the world. The island's village capital, Codrington, was named after the Gloucestershire family that once leased Barbuda from the British Crown for the price of 'one fat pig per year if asked for'. There are excellent beaches and the ruins of some of the earliest plantations in the West Indies. The coastal waters are rich with all types of crustaceans and tropical fish.</p>
<p>Redonda, the smallest in the group, is little more than an uninhabited rocky islet. It lies 40km (25 miles) southwest of Antigua.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The population is predominantly Christian with the majority denomination being Anglican but there are also Methodists, Roman Catholics, Pentecostals, Baptists, Seventh Day Adventists and others.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to greetings, relatives and good friends generally embrace whilst for acquaintances a handshake will do. Salutations such as 'good morning' and 'good evening' are seen as good manners, and failure to greet others in this way before engaging them in transactional matters or general conversation, may result in being seen as rude.</p><p>Friends tend to drop by unannounced, but an invitation is necessary for acquaintances or business associates. Although gifts will generally be well received, they are normally only given on celebratory occasions. Flowers are appropriate for dinner parties; bring a bottle only when specifically requested.</p><p>In general, because of the warm weather, the dress code in most scenarios tends to be for informal dress, unless formal dress is specifically requested. It is not acceptable to wear revealing clothing or beachwear in towns or villages. Keep in mind that Antigua and Barbuda is a highly conservative country – public nudity (such as topless sunbathing outside of your hotel) will cause offence.</p><p>It is an offence for anyone, including children, to dress in camouflage clothing and those found wearing any military-type clothing will be arrested. Smoking is accepted in most public places. Homosexual acts are illegal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 60Hz. Most hotels have both voltages, and American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without round grounding pin) are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Gaston Browne since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General Rodney Williams since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Originally called Wadadli or Waladli by its Amerindian settlers, Antigua and Barbuda&rsquo;s earliest inhabitants were the Siboney people from around 3100 BC. The Arawak Indians arrived in the first century, followed by Caribs who settled throughout the Caribbean.</p>
<p>Christopher Columbus spotted Antigua on his second voyage to the West Indies in 1493 and without landing named it Santa Maria de la Antigua after a saint.</p>
<p>Sir Christopher Codrington, the first settler on Antigua, arrived in 1684 and introduced sugar cultivation to the islands. By the middle of the 18th century there were hundreds of plantations as Antigua became one of Great Britain&rsquo;s most lucrative colonies, it economy reliant almost exclusively on sugar and, until its eventual abolition in 1834, slavery. Many modern day Antiguans are descended from slaves brought to the island from Africa.</p>
<p>In 1860, Barbuda was annexed to the territory of Antigua, with the small island of Redonda becoming part of Antigua 12 years later.</p>
<p>Admiral Nelson developed British naval facilities at English Harbour in 1784 and Nelson&rsquo;s Dockyard survives as the last example of a Georgian naval dockyard. A strategic port and valuable commercial colony, by the end of the 18th century Antigua was known as the &lsquo;Gateway of the Caribbean&rsquo;.</p>
<p>Until the development of tourism during the last century, Antigua&rsquo;s economy struggled after the demise of the sugar industry. Economic problems contributed to the growth of an independence movement and internal autonomy was achieved in February 1967 when Antigua, Barbuda and Redonda became an Associated State of the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>In 1981, the country became fully independent as Antigua and Barbuda with HM The Queen currently head of state. In Parliament, the populist Antigua Labour Party (ALP) dominated party politics until its historic defeat in 2004, which saw the Caribbean&rsquo;s longest serving elected government toppled.</p>
<p>Prime Minster Gaston Browne returned the ALP &ndash; now the Antigua and Barbuda Labour Party &ndash; to power in the June 2014 elections.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; The highest point on Antigua is Mount Obama, known as Boggy Peak until 2009 before it was renamed in honour of the US President.<br />
&bull; English is the official language although many locals speak Antiguan Creole. The Barbudan accent is slightly different to the Antiguan.<br />
&bull; The national sport is cricket with several West Indian superstars hailing from Antigua including Sir Vivian Richards, Andy Roberts and Richie Richardson.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Antigua & Barbuda in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 362 5122.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 362 5122.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3216 New Mexico Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Antigua & Barbuda High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 020 7258 0070.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.antigua-barbuda.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 020 7258 0070.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 1000-1700, Fri 1000-1430&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2nd floor, 45 Crawford Place<br/>London<br/>W1H 4LP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;We have 365 beaches here &ndash; one for every day of the year.&rdquo; If you were given a dollar every time you heard that in Antigua, your holiday would surely be paid for. It&rsquo;s the national catchphrase and you&rsquo;ll get tired of hearing it.&nbsp;But locals have every right to be proud of Antigua and its dashing twin, Barbuda: with their powdery beaches and swaying palms they&rsquo;re the quintessence of Caribbean island idyll.</p>
<p>Most of the action takes place in Antigua, a glamorous island where expensive yachts float in the harbour, honeymooners frolic in the surf and scuba divers explore colourful coral reefs in crystalline waters. You can see why Giorgio Armani and Oprah Winfrey keep homes here.</p>
<p>Away from the glamour, there are many attractions: from steamy rainforests to historic sites such as Shirley Heights, a military lookout with views over Nelson&rsquo;s Dockyard, the only working Georgian dockyard in the world.</p>
<p>Antigua&rsquo;s highest point, Mount Obama, begs to be climbed. It&rsquo;s also worth checking out the island&rsquo;s national parks and billowing blowholes, such as Devil's Bridge, which are caused by the colliding surf of the Atlantic Ocean and Caribbean Sea.</p>
<p>The buzzing Saturday market in St Johns, the capital, is a must: pick up anything from fresh fruit to local crafts. Antigua springs to life at night, with dozens of places to party including Shirley Heights, which is the setting for Sunday night &ldquo;jump ups&rdquo; (street parties) featuring live music and lots of rum punch.</p>
<p>Antigua&rsquo;s little sister Barbuda is quieter, but no less beautiful. Lying 43.5km (27 miles) to the north, its beating heart is Codrington, which is widely referred to as &ldquo;The Village&rdquo;. Codrington consists of only a handful of streets and offers a glimpse of Caribbean life as it used to be.</p>
<p>Although small, there is much to do in Barbuda. The island is a haven for wild deer and exotic birds, and is home to the Frigate Bird Sanctuary. Important Amerindian rock carvings can be found at Two foot Bay, while sumptuous beaches abound.</p><p>&ldquo;We have 365 beaches here &ndash; one for every day of the year.&rdquo; If you were given a dollar every time you heard that in Antigua, your holiday would surely be paid for. It&rsquo;s the national catchphrase and you&rsquo;ll get tired of hearing it.&nbsp;But locals have every right to be proud of Antigua and its dashing twin, Barbuda: with their powdery beaches and swaying palms they&rsquo;re the quintessence of Caribbean island idyll.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
