<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Argentina" ColCode="arg" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ar" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Argentina]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Argentina's climate ranges from the great heat and extensive rains of the subtropical Chaco in the north, through to the pleasant climate of the central Pampas, and the sub-Antarctic cold of the Patagonian Sea in the south. The main central area is temperate, but can be very hot and humid during summer (December to February) and chilly in winter. <br />
<br />
The most pleasant times to visit <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/buenos-aires">Buenos Aires</a> are September-November and February- March. The city is best avoided in January, when the heat is at its most intense and many of its residents flee to the coast leaving behind a comparative ghost city. Exploring the wilds of Patagonia is best done in the late spring and summer months &ndash; between November and February &ndash; whilst the northern regions are at their most hospitable in the spring, autumn and winter. If heading to Argentina for a ski trip, hit the slopes during mid-June to October.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothing is generally all that is required in the north, whereas warm clothes are certainly necessary in the south, up in the mountains and during winter months in the central area. It is sensible to carry waterproofs in all areas and bring a good sunblock.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Argentina is huge, making air travel the most practical way to get around. However, airlines in Argentina operate a two-tier pricing structure, which means that foreign travellers pay twice, or even three times as much, as locals.</p>
<p>Many flights are inconveniently (and expensively) routed through Buenos Aires, and delays are frequent. National airline, Aerol&iacute;neas Argentinas (AR) (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aerolineas.com.ar/">www.aerolineas.com.ar</a>) serves many domestic destinations from its key hubs in Buenos Aires, Cordoba and Bariloche.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Railway services in Argentina are gradually improving, though trains remain infrequent and slow-going.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Several rail companies operate in Argentina, including Ferrobaires (tel: +54 11 4304 0028; <a href="http://www.ferrobaires.gba.gov.ar" target="_blank">www.ferrobaires.gba.gov.ar</a>), serving destinations such as Mar del Plata and Bahia Blanca. Though notoriously unreliable in terms of scheduling, El Tren a las Nubes (the Train to the Clouds) runs from Salta into the mountains in the north of the country, close to the Chilean border (<a href="http://www.trenalasnubes.com.ar" target="_blank">www.trenalasnubes.com.ar</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving conditions in Argentina are a mixed bag. A 4x4 is recommended if venturing too far outside rural areas. When driving in cities keep windows closed and doors locked, especially when stopping at junctions. It is advisable that only confident drivers tackle Buenos Aires&rsquo; roads.</p>r<p>Major roads are generally in good condition, although rural roads, composed of packed dirt, can become impassable after rain.</p><p>In Buenos Aires the safest option is to telephone a radio taxi; a reputable company is Radio Taxi Pidalo (tel: +54 11 4956 1200; www.radiotaxipidalo.com.ar). Taxis are readily available and can be hailed from the side of the road but make sure the meter is used. It is advisable to used recommended <em>remises</em> (taxis) - which can only be booked by telephone and have fixed prices. Passengers should enquire beforehand.</p><p>Although in theory an international driving licence is required, in practice your driving licence from home is all that is needed, but must be carried with you while driving. You must also carry proof of vehicle ownership, proof of insurance and a receipt for the last tax payment at all times while driving.</p><p>The maximum speed limit on motorways is 130kph (80mph), up to 100kph (62mph) on other non-urban roads and 20-60kph (12-37mph) in built-up areas.</p><p>Autom&oacute;vil Club Argentino - ACA (tel: 0800 777 2894, in Argentina only; <a href="http://www.aca.org.ar" target="_blank">www.aca.com.ar</a>) offers breakdown cover and reciprocal benefits for members of motoring organisations in other countries.</p><p>Visitors aged 21 or over may hire a car in Argentina. Car hire is available in most towns and cities, and many international companies operate out of Buenos Aires and main tourist destinations.</p><p>Buenos Aires runs a bikeshare scheme. Register at <a href="http://www.buenosaires.gob.ar/ecobici" target="_blank">www.buenosaires.gob.ar/ecobici</a> for use of the yellow city bikes. The service is free and operates 24 hours a day.</p><p>The maximum speed limit on motorways is 130kph (80mph), up to 100kph (62mph) on other non-urban roads and 20-60kph (12-37mph) in built-up areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buenos Aires is the only Argentine city with an underground train service, known as the Subte (<a href="http://www.metrovias.com.ar" target="_blank">www.metrovias.com.ar</a>). The Subte is generally clean, safe, fast and efficient. You can buy a one- or two-journey Subtepass tickets at station entrances or use a reloadable SUBE smartcard. Overland urban trains also serve the capital city and its suburbs.</p>
<p>Trains and trolleybuses operate in Argentina's second city, Rosario.</p>
<p><em>Colectivos</em> (local buses) operate on main thoroughfares in all large towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Argentina</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">iguazuacute</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">20.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Argentina</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">coacuterdoba</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">12.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Argentina</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bariloche</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">22.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">36.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Argentina&rsquo;s national airline is Aerol&iacute;neas Argentinas (AR) (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aerolineas.com.ar/">www.aerolineas.com.ar</a>). The cheapest times to fly to Argentina tend to be September, and April to June, although travel to South America from Europe tends to always be quite pricey. Most international flights come into Ministro Pistarini airport just outside <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/buenos-aires">Buenos Aires</a>. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) runs direct flights to Argentina from the UK.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/argentina/buenos-aires-ministro-pistarini-international-airport">Buenos Aires Ministro Pistarini International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours 45 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 11 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Buenos Aires Ministro Pistarini International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aa2000.com.ar<p>Buenos Aires Ministro Pistarini International Airport is situated at Ezeiza, 32km (19 miles) southwest of Buenos Aires.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+54 114852 6900</p>]]><b>Aeroparque International Jorge Newbery</b><![CDATA[http://www.aa2000.com.ar<p>Jorge Newbery airport is situated just 4km (2.5 miles) from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/buenos-aires">Buenos Aires</a> city centre, on the Costanera Norte beside the Rio de la Plata.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+54 11 5480 6111</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Phone centres called <em>locutorios</em> can be found in most towns. Users are given their own phone booth and calls are added up and paid for at the end. Public pay phones are available in shops and restaurants and on some streets. These take 1 peso or 50 and 25 centavos coins. Most public telephones accept international phone cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies, but phones must be tri-band. Coverage is good in most parts of Argentina, but may be lacking in remote and mountain areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in most towns and cities in <em>locutorios</em> (phone centres) and internet caf&eacute;s. Many estancias and rural areas are cut off from both internet and telephone access. Wi-Fi  is increasingly found in upper range hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following the return of democracy, freedom of the press was enshrined in the law, and newspapers, magazines, radio and television generally function free from government interference. However, individual journalists critical of the establishment are often bullied by the powers that be, particularly in the provinces. The <em>Buenos Aires Herald </em>is the leading English-language newspaper in Latin America.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe is slow and generally takes over a week, or even two. Surface mail to Europe takes on average 20 to 25 days but can take as long as 50 days. An express service offers guaranteed 24-hour delivery in Argentina, and one to five days worldwide. The main post office in Buenos Aires is located in Sarmiento 189.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-2000, Sat 0900-1300, with some regional variation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Iguazú Falls</p><![CDATA[<p>The magnificent Iguazú Falls fittingly receive their name from the Guarani Indian word meaning 'great waters'. Surrounded by the virgin jungle of Iguazú National Park, home to 2000 species of flora and 400 species of bird, the Paraná River divides into 275 separate falls. The highest, the Garganta del Diabolo  (Devil's Throat), reaches 70m (230ft) - one and a half times the height of the Niagara Falls.</p>]]><br/><p>Los Glaciares National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Los Glaciares National Park (<a href="http://www.losglaciares.com" target="_blank">www.losglaciares.com</a>) is the second largest in Argentina and runs for 170km (106 miles) along the border with Chile; it is characterised by rugged mountains and clear lakes. The largest glacier is Upsala, but the most popular is the mighty Moreno glacier, where massive chunks of ice shear off and fall into Lago Argentino, the largest lake in Argentina, to form icebergs. Visitors can view the advancing Moreno glacier from catwalks and platforms.</p>]]><br/><p>Nahuel Huapi National Park </p><![CDATA[<p>The park offers trekkers and sightseers many areas of natural beauty, including an extinct volcano called Tronador, alpine meadows and amazing fauna. The sprawling glacial lake, Lake Nahuel Huapi, stretches over 100km (63 miles) to the border with Chile; the lake contains a nature reserve, the Isla Victoria, which can be reached by private or organised boat trips.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Discover vibrant La Boca</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Marvel at the rainbow of painted houses and artistic talents of La Boca – a colourful portside neighbourhood in southern Buenos Aires. One of the area's star attractions is Boca Juniors' home ground, best known as La Bombonera (the chocolate box). This football ground is a fun place to visit by day, but it gets rowdy at night, especially after a match.</p>]]><p><b>Feast on a meaty parilla</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The traditional Argentine <em>parrilla</em> (grill) is the heart and soul of its national cuisine: sample <em>morcilla</em> (blood sausage), <em>chinchulines</em> (intestines) or simply plump for a slap of prime Argentine beef. For a reliably delicious meat experience Buenos Aires has many famous <em>parrilla</em> restaurants or try an open-air barbecue in the Pampas, for an authentic meat feast.</p>]]><p><b>Go wild in the Lake District</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With glacial lakes, towering mountains and dense forests, Argentina's Lake District is certainly one of the country's star attractions. It's the ideal destination if you're looking for tranquil wilderness, and for adrenaline-filled activities, from kayaking to rock climbing and more. Continue on to Lanín National Park, dominated by the extinct, snow-capped Lanín Volcano, which stands at 3,776m (12,386ft).</p>]]><p><b>Have a mountain break in Bariloche</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set in stunning Andean scenery, beautiful Bariloche is enthralling whatever the season. In the summer, you can hike hillside trails, kick back with a fishing rod or hop on a horse or mountain bike. As winter arrives, so do the skiers, with reliable powder attracting snow fanatics worldwide. Last but not least, don't leave without trying its famous locally-made chocolate.</p>]]><p><b>Head north to colonial Salta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This lively university city is peppered with colonial Spanish architecture. Drop in on the nearby pre-Inca ruins at Santa Rosa de Tastil, before travelling through the stunning red gorge of the Quebrada de Humahuaca, scattered with verdant oases. Horse riding treks amid the arid, rose-tinted mountains around Salta are a popular way of taking in the area's distinctive natural backdrop.</p>]]><p><b>Hike around Nahuel Huapi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This superb national park in the Argentine Lake District tempts trekkers and sightseers alike with its many natural beauties, including extinct Tronador Volcano, alpine meadows and amazing fauna. The sprawling glacial lake, Lake Nahuel Huapi, stretches over 100km (63 miles) to the border with Chile; the lake contains a nature reserve, Isla Victoria, which you can visit by private boat or organised excursion.</p>]]><p><b>Raft down the Manso</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Charge down wild rapids on the River Manso, near Bariloche. This thunderous force of nature, shooting through rocky canyons and forests, rises from the glaciers at the foothills of Mount Tronador and wends its way through to Chile. Other top white water rafting options are the River Atuel near San Rafael or the Juramento Rapids near Salta.</p>]]><p><b>Ride like a gaucho in the Pampas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>These flat and fertile lowlands near Buenos Aires provide optimum respite from hectic city life. Head out into the Pampas and stay at an <em>estancia </em>(Argentine-style ranch), many of which offer horse riding around the local beauty spots, open log fires in the winter months and a banquet of fine grilled meat.</p>]]><p><b>Sample Mendoza’s fine wines</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mendoza is one of Argentina's key wine regions, with nearly two thirds of the country's wine produced here, in the Andean foothills. Taste some of the New World's best tipples and learn about winemaking at a traditional <em>bodega </em>(winery). You can tour the region's wineries, from boutique bodegas to major wine labels, many offering guided tours, fine dining and lodging.</p>]]><p><b>Ski down the Andes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>When the snow falls, it's time to zoom down the eastern slopes of the Andes. The best time to go skiing in Argentina is May to September. Bariloche is the most established ski destination, while Las Leñas is a large upmarket resort; this remote, purpose-built ski centre, near Malargüe, offers a well-stocked village and access to world-class advanced slopes.</p>]]><p><b>Take a shower in the Iguazú Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Aptly named 'great waters' by the Guarani Indians, the magnificent Iguazú Falls are set in the lush jungle of Iguazú National Park, packed with exotic birds and plant life. The highest of the 275 separate falls is the Garganta del Diablo, standing nearly twice the height of the Niagara Falls; visitors can get up close via viewing platforms and spray-drenched catwalks.</p>]]><p><b>Tango til dawn in Buenos Aires</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The heady capital city is a vibrant mix of Argentine culture and cosmopolitan city life. This is a full-on, round-the-clock city, with a bustling centre by day, street cafés packed well into the evening, late night feasting at gourmet grills and tango halls that go on way past dawn.</p>]]><p><b>Travel to the ‘Ends of the Earth’ at Tierra del Fuego</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gateway to the Antarctic, Tierra del Fuego is a windswept archipelago of craggy peaks, ancient forests and sprawling estancias, shared by Argentina and neighbouring Chile. A magnet for naturalists and adventurers, the region offers boat safaris through the Beagle Channel, fishing, horse riding, hiking, or exploring Ushuaia, the world's most southerly city.</p>]]><p><b>Watch glaciers calve at Los Glaciares National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This magnificent park runs for 170km (106 miles) along the border with Chile; it is characterised by rugged mountains and clear lakes. The most popular glacier is the mighty Perito Moreno, where massive chunks of ice shear off and fall into Lago Argentino to form icebergs. You can view the advancing Perito Moreno Glacier from catwalks, from boat trips or even by walking on it.</p>]]><p><b>Watch whales in Puerto Madryn</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The beautiful nature reserve Peninsula Valdés situated near the Patagonian town Puerto Madryn is Argentina's prime whale-watching location. From June until December is the best time to spot southern right whales in its temperate waters. Head there in September and October to see the whales with their young, as well as the bulky masses of elephant seals basking on the shoreline.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$583 billion (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Soya beans and oil, cereals, mineral fuels, motor vehicles, beef and leather.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, motor vehicles, chemicals, metal goods and plastics.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Brazil, USA, Chile and China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Argentina is rich in natural resources and has a large and profitable agricultural sector. For all its potential, the economy has been historically blighted by high inflation and a massive foreign debt.<br />
<br />
The Menem government of the mid-1990s made an attempt to tackle these through privatisation, free market economics and cuts in public spending. In addition, the value of the Peso was fixed to the US Dollar. The immediate results were reductions in the national debt and the inflation rate. However, the policy of Peso-Dollar parity eventually led to a sharp fall in exports and government tax revenues, as well as a large increase in government debt. <br />
<br />
With external debt topping US$130 billion in 2001, Argentina was on the point of defaulting on its overseas debts, potentially leading to a complete economic meltdown. At the end of the year, the government was forced to devalue the Peso and freeze bank accounts.<br />
<br />
The government has taken a number of steps to restructure its economy and in 2005 President Kirchner made the bold move of paying off the country's debt to the IMF. The country has battled back from the 2001 crisis and&nbsp;still remains South America's second largest economy, despite suffering a sustained period of stagflation. In 2016, its unemployment rate was just under 10% and inflation as high as 40%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business people in Argentina are very conscious of status and expect to conduct any business dealings with people of an equal footing. Business cards are commonly exchanged by way of introduction. A handshake is standard when greeting a man; a kiss on each cheek when meeting a woman. Smart dress is appropriate as is a high degree of respect.<br /><br />Whenever possible, business in Argentina should be conducted in Spanish although many Argentines do speak English. It's best to allow for plenty of room when organising business meetings as there can be a relaxed attitude towards timekeeping - meetings commonly start 10 or 15 minutes late.<br /><br />Normal business hours are Mon-Fri 0900-1900, or even later, and a siesta doesn't usually feature in the country's business community. In general, conduct is similar to any large European country, with business deals often conducted over lunch.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1200 and 1400-1900, although many workers start late and finish late.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cámara Argentina de Comercio (Chamber of Commerce)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (011) 5300 9000
					Website:http://www.cac.com.ar/
					Address: AAN Buenos Aires,Avenida Leandro N. Alem 36,,C1003]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Argentine cuisine is largely exceptional, although choices can often be restricted to meat, pasta and pizza. Buenos Aires, however, offers a wide selection of culinary genres, with Japanese, Thai and Asian-fusion food becoming increasingly popular.</p><p>Wherever you are in the country, meat is the name of the game, with a wonderful array of carnivorous treats to get stuck into. The traditional <em>parrillada</em> (mixed grill) is the very heart and soul of Argentina's cuisine. Other staples include <em>morcilla</em> (blood sausage), <em>chinchulines</em> (intestines), or the feted Argentine steak.</p><p>Vegetarians may struggle to find many options, particularly outside Buenos Aires, though fruits and salads are widely available. A strong Italian influence means quality coffee and ice cream is popular, and in Buenos Aires the many <em>gelaterias</em> (ice cream parlours) are packed in the summertime.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bife de ancho:</strong><em>&nbsp;</em>Rib eye steak.<br />
<strong>Bife de chorizo:</strong> Sirloin steak.<br />
<strong>Bife de lomo:</strong> Fillet steak.<br />
<strong>Empanadas:</strong> Little pasties typically stuffed with meat, vegetable or cheese, and particularly good in Jujuy and Salta in the northwest.<br />
<strong>Choripan:</strong> Rump steak sandwich.<br />
<strong>Milanesa:</strong> Breaded veal or beefsteak, sometimes topped with cheese, ham or egg.<br />
<strong>Parrillada:</strong> Mixed grill, which might include <em>morcilla</em> blood sausage.<br />
<strong>Alfajores:</strong> Shortbread-type biscuits sandwiched with <em>dulce de leche</em> &ndash; a caramelised milk sauce.<br />
<strong>Chimichurri:</strong> A sauce made from finely chopped parsley and oregano, garlic, olive oil and vinegar, served as a side dish with meat.<br />
<strong>Medialunas:</strong> Small, croissant-like pastries served for breakfast.<br />
<strong>Wine:</strong> Argentina produces some excellent wines. Try a light pinot noir from Patagonia, a silky red from Malbec and Argentina&rsquo;s celebrated white, the aromatic Torront&eacute;s.<br />
<strong>Mate:</strong> An invigorating green tea made from the yerba mate plant and drunk any time, anywhere, as a staunchly Argentine custom.<br />
<strong>Quilmesis:</strong> The national lager.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>If you're baffled by the choice of meat cuts most waiters are more than happy to advise on what to start with and how much per person. Argentines dine late – 2100 is considered early.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A tip between 10% - 15% is acceptable in restaurants as well as bars (unless you were dissatisfied).</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Argentines love to party, and even the smallest of towns in rural areas have late night bars and discos. Nightlife in Buenos Aires is particularly vibrant. Shiny new cocktail bars regularly pop up across the city, and roof terrace gatherings and pool parties are the norm in the spring and summer months.</p>
<p>The city has become a centre for South American clubbing, with a stream of world-famous DJs visiting the solid selection of superclubs. Things rarely get going until gone midnight, and the party keeps pumping well past sunrise.<br />
<br />
The country&rsquo;s older music and dance traditions still stand strong, however. Tango is the traditional music and dance of Argentina, and each night performers showcase this heartfelt art form in clubs across most major cities. Learn and practise the tango at one of the many <em>milongas </em>(tango halls). The San Telmo neighbourhood in Buenos   Aires is a great place to experience the historic tango hall, with its many longstanding venues.</p>
<p>If you have the chance, experience an Argentine Pe&ntilde;a &ndash; a joyous evening filled with live folk music, simple and tasty food and lots of dancing and cheer. Buenos Aires has some great ones on around the time of the annual La Rural agricultural exhibition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From fine wines and leather products, to regional handicrafts and soft alpaca wool clothing, Argentina has some lovely purchases to take home and treasure (or consume, rapidly). Leather goods can be found across the country, and there are some real bargains to be had. Native arts and handicrafts are also easy to come across, and chocolates from Bariloche and wines from Mendoza make particularly welcome gifts.</p>
<p>For an atmospheric shopping experience, visit one of the country's many local <em>ferias</em> (fairs). A huge and lively annual event is La Rural in Buenos Aires, showcasing the best agriculture and livestock the country has to offer, and with craft and produce stalls from regions around the whole country.</p>
<p>Buenos Aires also has some great regular markets. The best place to search for antiques is at the Sunday Feria de San Pedro Telmo flea market at Plaza Dorrego. The Hippie Fair in front of the Centro Cultural Recoleta is a colourful place to browse for handicrafts, jewellery and artwork at weekends. For unique pieces by up-and-coming Buenos Aires designers, head to the clothing boutiques of Palermo, and for cheap and cheerful clothing to top up your holiday wardrobe for a few pesos, the central pedestrianized strip Florida is jam-packed with budget buys. Weekends in riverside Tigre, a 40 minute train ride from Buenos Aires, also see a large market with all kinds of handmade goods.</p>
<p>Beautifully crafted textiles, furniture and clothes are sold by Pasion Argentina (<a href="http://www.pasion-argentina.com.ar" target="_blank">www.pasion-argentina.com.ar</a>), which supports often forgotten indigenous communities. Tierra Adentro in Buenos Aires sells exquisite, fair trade native silver jewellery, textiles and furniture crafted by aboriginals.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0900-2000; Sat 0900-1300. Many shops close for a long lunch, and opening hours can be unpredictable.</p><p>Look out for the 'Tax Free' shopping sign which means foreign visitors can claim back the 21% sales tax on any purchases made in the country. See <a href="http://www.globalblue.com" target="_blank">www.globalblue.com</a>.&nbsp;Since January 2017, foreign tourists staying in Argentina will receive a full refund of the VAT paid on hotel services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Argentina range greatly in standard, from the most luxurious in Buenos Aires to the distinctly rustic in rural areas. In Buenos Aires, the cheaper hotels can mostly be found around Avenida de Mayo. The most luxurious hotels in Buenos Aires are generally considered the stately Alvear  Palace in Recoleta (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.alvearpalace.com">www.alvearpalace.com</a>), and the highly contemporary and high-design Faena Hotel and Universe in Puerto Madero (<a href="http://www.faena.com/buenos-aires" target="_blank">www.faena.com/buenos-aires</a>). If you have the urge to escape the city, and are looking for something really special no matter what the cost, then there are some truly glorious luxury hotel retreats tucked away in Patagonia that offer serene and romantic getaways.</p>
<p>Note that <em>hoster&iacute;as </em>are not hostels, but anything from a budget to a luxury hotel. Most hotels add at least 20% tax to any quoted room price. It is advisable to check correct charges when booking.</p>
<p>Since January 2017, foreign tourists staying in Argentina will receive a refund of the VAT paid on hotel services when&nbsp;using a foreign debit or credit card. The reimbursement will be automatic, you don&rsquo;t have to apply or request the refund.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Ranges from 5-star (highest) to 1-star (lowest). Be aware that this rating system rarely reaches international standards, especially with regard to service. Watch out too for 'design' hotels that may feature the latest in interior design, but tend to disappoint when it comes to staff and attention to detail.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in small family hotels in Buenos Aires and other cities. Maid service is generally included in the price, but laundry service often requires a small extra charge. Bed and breakfast hotels can also offer useful tourist advice.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Argentina range greatly in standard, from the most luxurious in Buenos Aires to the distinctly rustic in rural areas. In Buenos Aires, the cheaper hotels can mostly be found around Avenida de Mayo. The most luxurious hotels in Buenos Aires are generally considered the stately Alvear  Palace in Recoleta (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.alvearpalace.com">www.alvearpalace.com</a>), and the highly contemporary and high-design Faena Hotel and Universe in Puerto Madero (<a href="http://www.faena.com/buenos-aires" target="_blank">www.faena.com/buenos-aires</a>). If you have the urge to escape the city, and are looking for something really special no matter what the cost, then there are some truly glorious luxury hotel retreats tucked away in Patagonia that offer serene and romantic getaways.</p>
<p>Note that <em>hoster&iacute;as </em>are not hostels, but anything from a budget to a luxury hotel. Most hotels add at least 20% tax to any quoted room price. It is advisable to check correct charges when booking.</p>
<p>Since January 2017, foreign tourists staying in Argentina will receive a refund of the VAT paid on hotel services when&nbsp;using a foreign debit or credit card. The reimbursement will be automatic, you don&rsquo;t have to apply or request the refund.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Ranges from 5-star (highest) to 1-star (lowest). Be aware that this rating system rarely reaches international standards, especially with regard to service. Watch out too for 'design' hotels that may feature the latest in interior design, but tend to disappoint when it comes to staff and attention to detail.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Argentina range greatly in standard, from the most luxurious in Buenos Aires to the distinctly rustic in rural areas. In Buenos Aires, the cheaper hotels can mostly be found around Avenida de Mayo. The most luxurious hotels in Buenos Aires are generally considered the stately Alvear  Palace in Recoleta (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.alvearpalace.com">www.alvearpalace.com</a>), and the highly contemporary and high-design Faena Hotel and Universe in Puerto Madero (<a href="http://www.faena.com/buenos-aires" target="_blank">www.faena.com/buenos-aires</a>). If you have the urge to escape the city, and are looking for something really special no matter what the cost, then there are some truly glorious luxury hotel retreats tucked away in Patagonia that offer serene and romantic getaways.</p>
<p>Note that <em>hoster&iacute;as </em>are not hostels, but anything from a budget to a luxury hotel. Most hotels add at least 20% tax to any quoted room price. It is advisable to check correct charges when booking.</p>
<p>Since January 2017, foreign tourists staying in Argentina will receive a refund of the VAT paid on hotel services when&nbsp;using a foreign debit or credit card. The reimbursement will be automatic, you don&rsquo;t have to apply or request the refund.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Ranges from 5-star (highest) to 1-star (lowest). Be aware that this rating system rarely reaches international standards, especially with regard to service. Watch out too for 'design' hotels that may feature the latest in interior design, but tend to disappoint when it comes to staff and attention to detail.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No***]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical insurance is highly recommended as there are no reciprocal health agreements. Medical facilities are generally of a high standard in Buenos Aires, though of varying quality outside the capital. Immediate cash payment is often expected by doctors. To call an ambulance dial 107. Many medicines that require a prescription in North America and Europe can be bought over the pharmacy counter in Argentina, although they may be known under a different name here. If you require a regular medication, bring the packaging into the pharmacy with you to show the pharmacist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Argentina is considered to have a high risk of Zika virus transmission. Pregnant women are advised to postpone non-essential travel until after pregnancy. The mosquito-borne illness can be spread from a pregnant woman to her unborn baby as well as through sexual contact. The World Health Organisation recommends travellers to Argentina protect themselves from mosquito bites and suggests wearing clothes (preferably light-coloured) that cover as much of the body as possible, sleeping under mosquito nets and using insect repellent.  Women who are pregnant, at risk of getting pregnant, or planning pregnancy should seek further advice from their doctor before travelling to Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is generally considered safe in main cities and towns, especially in Buenos Aires, but otherwise bottled water is recommended. If bottled water is unavailable then boil water for over a minute before drinking.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Dengue fever, carried by mosquitoes, is present but not common. Leishmaniasis, a skin disease spread by sandflies, is a low risk. Both can be avoided with sensible precautionary measures such as using mosquito nets and insect repellent in lowland and jungle areas. From around March to October time, Argentine haemorrhagic fever - a viral disease caused by Junin virus &amp;ndash; can be picked up in the pampas. It is transmitted by the corn mouse, by either by breathing in dust contaminated with droppings or by contact with the creature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychoanalysis therapy is incredibly popular in Argentina, especially Buenos Aires; it is said that the Argentine capital has the highest per cent of therapists of any city in the world. Argentina is also known for its affordable cosmetic surgery procedures, and a growing number of people visit for this reason. Standards are erratic, however, and it is incredibly important to make sure you conduct thorough research on medical centres and physicians, and opt for somewhere with an excellent reputation.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Day of Remembrance for Truth and Justice :
							24 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Day of the Veterans and Fallen of the Malvinas War :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>National Day (Anniversary of the 1810 Revolution) :
							25 May </p><p>National Flag Day :
							20 June </p><p>Independence Day :
							09 July </p><p>San Mart :
							20 August </p><p>Day of Respect for Cultural Diversity :
							08 October </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Argentina by travellers over 16 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; US$300 in personal or new goods if arriving by air or sea, plus an additional US$300 of goods purchased in duty-free shops upon arrival.<br />
&bull; US$150 in personal or new goods if arriving by land or waterway, plus an additional US$150 of goods purchased in duty-free shops upon arrival.</p>
<p>Travellers under 16 may import half these amounts.</p>
<p>You should declare upon arrival items that might not be considered part of normal luggage (such as expensive camera equipment or musical instruments) and show the declaration on departure. A licence is required for firearms and ammunition for hunting purposes. You must declare gold.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms (unless under licence from the National Arms Registry), explosives, flammables, narcotics, and goods considered a risk to health or safety.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Peso (ARS; symbol AR$) = 100 centavos. Peso notes are in denominations of AR$500, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 2. Coins are in denominations of AR$2 and 1, and in 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 centavos. <br /><br />US Dollars are accepted in some hotels and tourist centres. Prices in US Dollars are typically marked with US$ to avoid confusion, but sometimes both peso and dollar prices are both preceded by just $, so check if unsure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged in banks and authorised <em>cambios </em>(bureaux de change), which are available in all major cities. Visitors should be aware that due to the instability of the peso, there is a large 'blue' market for dollars, which provides a much more favourable exchange rate of exchange. Whilst it is illegal to exchange currency in from these unauthorised money lenders, the practice is so common so as to make the black market rate the de facto rate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major credit cards are accepted, but not as widely as in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> or Europe; even some major hotels do not have credit card facilities.</p><p>ATMs are available in most cities and have options in English, but it is still best to carry alternative forms of payment as daily withdrawal limits are low and machines don't always work. During national holidays ATMs can run out so it is wise to withdraw in advance. </p>
<p>Foreign tourists who are not resident in Argentina can no longer pay for tourism-related services (air tickets, bus travel, hotel rooms,      all-inclusive tours etc) in Pesos. These services must be paid for with      foreign credit and bank cards, money transfers (in foreign currencies)      from abroad, in cash with foreign money (eg US Dollars) or with      cheques from foreign accounts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is advised to bring traveller's cheques in US Dollars; these can be exchanged at banks, bureaux de change and some hotels. However, it is often difficult to exchange these in the smaller towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 1000-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Argentina, a valid passport is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above. The passport must be valid for the duration of your stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single parents/adults travelling alone with children should be aware that Argentina requires evidence that both parents have given permission for the child to enter/leave the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Passengers staying for less than 12 hours within the airport waiting for connecting international flights do not need to go through immigration control or apply for visas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For nationals requiring a tourist visa, the cost is US$50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa: 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Those applying for a temporary visa have to get an entrance permit (<em>permiso de ingreso</em>) from the Direcci&oacute;n Nacional de Migraciones first. When you have the entry permit, you can apply for a temporary residence visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals requiring visas are advised to allow at least 45 days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa-exempt tourists can apply for a 90-day extension to their visit at the <a href="http://www.migraciones.gov.ar">Direcci&oacute;n Nacional de Migraciones</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets require a certificate issued no more than 10 days before arrival in Argentina showing a clean bill of health. It's a good idea to bring a Spanish translation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-35.629980]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-65.158997]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,780,400 sq km (1,073,518 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>44,022,394 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>15.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buenos Aires.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Argentina is the second largest area of land in South America, separated from Chile to the west by the long spine of the Andes. Its landscape is extremely varied, with the top sub-tropical and sun-baked, and its sub-Antarctic bottom tip glistening with icy waters and glaciers. It has 3,100 miles (4,989km) of coastline. Its eastern border is the Atlantic Ocean, with Uruguay, Bolivia, Paraguay and Brazil to the north and northeast.</p>
<p>Argentina can roughly be divided into four main geographical areas: the spectacular Andes mountain range, the dry North along with the more verdant Mesopotamia, the lush plains of the Pampas and the windswept wastes of Patagonia. Mount Aconcagua soars almost 7,000m (23,000ft), and waterfalls at Iguaz&uacute; stretch out in a massive semi-circle, thundering 70m (230ft) to the bed of the Paran&aacute; River.</p>
<p>Argentina&rsquo;s lowest point is Laguna del Carb&oacute;n in Santa Cruz Province, sitting 105m (344ft) below sea level. In the southwest is the Argentine Lake District with a string of beautiful glacial lakes framed by snow-covered mountains. At Argentina&rsquo;s southernmost tip, and so the southernmost tip of the whole of South America, is Tierra del Fuego (Spanish for Land of Fire), a stunning archipelago split between Argentina and neighbouring Chile.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Argentina's population is more than 92% Roman Catholic, 2% Protestant with small Muslim and Jewish communities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The most common form of greeting between friends is kissing cheeks. It is customary for Argentines to kiss cheeks on meeting and departing, regardless of gender. Dinner is usually eaten well into the evening - from around 2100 onwards. While Argentina is famous for its wonderful wine, Argentinians as a whole do not have the same propensity for drinking large amounts of alcohol as Europeans, and in bars and even nightclubs many will be drinking soft drinks and few will appear noticeably drunk.</p>
<p>Formal wear is worn for official functions and dinners, particularly in exclusive restaurants. A smoking ban was introduced across Argentina in 2011, it prohibits smoking in public areas, including museums, theatres, all forms of public transport, bars and restaurants.</p>
<p>Queuing and waiting for things in public places can seem a little less ordered than in Europe; an example is the Subte in Buenos Aires &ndash; people will continue to board the carriage until the platform is empty, whether there seems to be space in the carriage or not. It can make for a rather crowded and sweaty journey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Plug fittings in older buildings are of the two-pin round type, but most new buildings use the V-shaped twin with earth pin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Mauricio Macri since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Mauricio Macri since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Spanish were the first Europeans to arrive in present-day Argentina in the early 16th century. After becoming a viceroyalty of Spain in the 1770s, the territory achieved independence in 1816. Between the mid-19th century and 1946, Argentina swung from civilian to military rule, and from radical to conservative policies. A coup resulted in the rise of Lieutenant General Juan Domingo Per&oacute;n as president in 1943.</p>
<p>After winning the election of 1946, Per&oacute;n instigated a policy of extreme nationalism and social improvement. At his side throughout his rise to power was his second wife, former actress Eva Per&oacute;n, until her death from cancer in 1952; she remains Argentina&rsquo;s most iconic female figure.</p>
<p>President Per&oacute;n was overthrown in 1955, but he was re-elected in 1973. On his death, a year later, Per&oacute;n&rsquo;s third wife Isabel took office, but she was deposed by a military coup in 1976.</p>
<p>The end of the Peronista period heralded perhaps the darkest period in Argentina&rsquo;s history. Driven by an obsessive fear of communism, the new military regime instituted a reign of terror in which disappearances, torture and extra-judicial murder were commonplace. This brutal era still feels very recent in today&rsquo;s Buenos Aires, and the mothers of those who disappeared during the Dirty War, can be seen silently marching around Plaza de Mayo every Thursday afternoon.</p>
<p>Argentina&rsquo;s invasion of the Malvinas (Falkland Islands) in 1982, led to defeat at the hands of the British. While the topic is still a diplomatic sore point, relations between the two countries have somewhat improved.</p>
<p>Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner succeeded her husband, N&eacute;stor Carlos Kirchner, in 2007, becoming Argentina's first elected female president. She came to power promising more of the same centre-left populist policies that had served her husband so well.</p>
<p>Kirchner&rsquo;s initial popularity waned within a few years, however, with accusations of financial corruption, followed by violent suppression of protesters against her imposed export tax hikes, bringing back horrific memories of former strong-arm governments. In the 2015 elections she lost the presidency to Mauricio Macri of the centrist Cambiemos coalition. Macri&nbsp;reversed some of Kirchner&rsquo;s populist policies, lifting restrictions on foreign currency purchases and&nbsp;reducing export taxes on various agricultural products.&nbsp;The OECD predicts that Argentina will be out of recession by 2018.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
&bull; In 2010 Argentina became the first country in South America to legalise same-sex marriage.<br />
&bull; Nobel Prize winning author Jorge Luis Borges famously compared the Falklands War to &ldquo;two bald men fighting over a comb&rdquo;.<br />
&bull; Lionel Messi and Ernesto Che Guevara were both born in the same Argentinian city, Rosario.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Argentina]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(11) 4808 2200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinargentina.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(11) 4808 2200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Dr. Luis Agote 2412<br/>Buenos Aires<br/>1425<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Argentina in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 238 6400.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofargentina.us</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 238 6400.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1600 New Hampshire Avenue<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Argentine Consulate in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7318 1340.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.argentine-embassy-uk.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7318 1340.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>27 Three Kings Yard<br/>London<br/>W1K 4DF<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Argentina in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>((020) 7318 1300. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.argentine-embassy-uk.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>((020) 7318 1300. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>65 Brook Street<br/>London<br/>W1K 4AH<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Argentina Consular Section]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 238 6460 or 6461.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://embassyofargentina.us</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 238 6460 or 6461.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>Sarmiento Building, 1811 Q Street<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spirited Argentina, with its clamouring capital, vast pampas, rolling wine regions and snowy peaks, is a land bursting with adventure. It&rsquo;s a place where the clich&eacute;s hold true: football is essentially a religion, the beef is phenomenal and there&rsquo;s little point even thinking about starting a proper night out before midnight. Its natural wonders range from Andean plateaux and Patagonian glaciers to subtropical waterfalls and wildlife-rich wetlands. There&rsquo;s an awful lot to love.</p>
<p>Buenos Aires might sit at the very edge of the country, gazing out across the Rio de la Plata, but it&rsquo;s very much Argentina&rsquo;s centrepiece. The city of Evita and Maradona, its tango halls, <em>parillas</em> (grill restaurants) and feisty <em>porte&ntilde;os</em> (BA residents) provide a gutsy introduction to the country. In the high-end neighbourhoods of Recoleta and Palermo you&rsquo;ll find designer boutiques and trendy eateries, while historic San Telmo offers antique stalls, old-world caf&eacute;s and an abundance of live music.</p>
<p>In the north, scorched mountains and otherworldly rock formations characterise the Salta region, where Spanish and Gaucho traditions combine and Argentina&rsquo;s famous white wines flourish. Further west, in the Mendoza region, the grapes are red and the foothills of the Andes offer skiing, while down south, in Patagonia, you&rsquo;ll find an astonishing spread of expansive lakes, jagged peaks and mile upon empty mile of open space.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, try walking in the glistening Lake District, whale-watching off the coast at Puerto Madryn, meeting baby penguins in Punta Tombo or exploring the Jesuit chapels and farmhouses of C&oacute;rdoba. Another of the country&rsquo;s majestic natural beauties is the mighty Iguazu Falls, bordering Argentina and Brazil.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Despite living through a dark military dictatorship and a spectacularly devastating economic crisis, Argentineans still have a vivacious and infectious lust for life. And from its subtropical top to its icy tip, it remains a mesmerising country.</p><p>Spirited Argentina, with its clamouring capital, vast pampas, rolling wine regions and snowy peaks, is a land bursting with adventure. It&rsquo;s a place where the clich&eacute;s hold true: football is essentially a religion, the beef is phenomenal and there&rsquo;s little point even thinking about starting a proper night out before midnight. Its natural wonders range from Andean plateaux and Patagonian glaciers to subtropical waterfalls and wildlife-rich wetlands. There&rsquo;s an awful lot to love.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
