<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Armenia" ColCode="arm" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="am" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Armenia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Armenia is mostly mountainous (more than 90% of the territory is over 900m/2,286ft above sea level), so expect a dry highland climate.</p>
<p>Springs are short with mild temperatures. Temperatures range from 7&deg;C (45&deg;F) to 19&deg;C (66&deg;F) at the capital Yerevan in April. Rains are scarce, but they do fall in springs.</p>
<p>Summers are dry with plenty of sunshine. In Yerevan, temperatures hover around 33&deg;C (91&deg;F) in August. But in the north, temperatures are cooler and they can fall sharply at night too.</p>
<p>Autumns are long and beautiful, with leaves turning gold and red.</p>
<p>Winters are extremely cold, bleak with heavy snow. Temperatures often dip below 0&deg;C (32&deg;F)</p>
<p>May to June and September to October are good times to visit Yerevan, as the weather is warm but mild. If you are travelling to Lake Sevan, June to September are your best bet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Yerevan, you can wear light clothes in summers and autumns, with a light jacket for the evenings. But do bring very warm clothes for springs and winters.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no domestic flights in Armenia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main railway station is the Sasuntsi Davit Station on Tigran Mets Avenue. Trains to places such as Sevan, Gyumri and Vanadzor are slow, overcrowded and poorly maintained. Make sure you secure all belongings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Road surfaces can be very poor, even in the case of major highways, and care should be taken to avoid children and animals on the road.</p><p>An international driving licence is required and the minimum age of driving is 18.</p><p>Local drivers have a tendency to flout traffic regulations and ignore signals.</p>
<p>Visitors should take care when driving or crossing the road.</p>
<p>Seat belts are required by law (although no one seems to use them).</p><p>Local drivers have a tendency to flout traffic regulations and ignore signals.</p>
<p>Visitors should take care when driving or crossing the road.</p>
<p>Seat belts are required by law (although no one seems to use them).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a small underground system in Yerevan (0630-2300). Buses and trolleybuses run in the city.</p>
<p>Taxis are available in the city centre or can be ordered by telephone. Private cars can be flagged down as well as official taxis. Taxi fares should always be negotiated before starting a journey, and visitors should be aware that rates proposed initially are likely to be unreasonably high, in the expectation that foreigners will have unlimited cash and little idea of how much they ought to be paying. It is therefore advisable to make enquiries about 'going rates' per kilometre of travel before entering into negotiations with taxi drivers.</p>
<p>Chauffeur-driven cars are available but are expensive. It is advisable to obtain them through official channels, such as hotels or travel agencies in Yerevan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Armenia<em>&nbsp;</em>(<a href="http://www.armenianairlines.com/" target="_blank">www.armenianairlines.com</a>)<em> </em>is the national airline. If travelling to Armenia from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you can fly to Yerevan via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kiev">Kiev</a> with Ukraine International Airlines (<a href="http://www.flyuia.com" target="_blank">www.flyuia.com</a>) or via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a> with Aeroflot (<a href="http://www.aeroflot.com" target="_blank">www.aeroflot.com</a>).</p>
<p>For political reasons, there are no direct international transport links between Armenia and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/azerbaijan">Azerbaijan</a>; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/georgia">Georgia</a> is sometimes used as a stopover point.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Yerevan - 8 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Zvartnots International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aia-zvartnots.aero<p>The airport  is 10km (6 miles) from Yerevan.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Armenia's rail links to Azerbaijan and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey">Turkey</a> have been closed indefinitely, but an international service still runs to Georgia (every other day). Passengers travelling to Georgia should be aware of the possibility of theft or robbery. The main station is Sasuntsi Davit on Tigran Mets Avenue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>IDD calls can be expensive but in Yerevan some private phone offices offer cheaper Internet calls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. ArmenTel and VivaCell are the local carriers. Both are similar and offer phone coverage to most parts of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in large cities and resorts. There are many Internet cafes in Yerevan. Some are open 24 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Armenian government oversees national TV and radio. Libel and defamation are punishable by prison terms, and journalists have been sentenced under these laws in the past. All print and broadcast media must register with the Justice Ministry. Self-censorship is common. <em>Noyan Tapan</em> is an English-language weekly circulated primarily among the foreign missions and small foreign business community.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International postal services are available to most countries but may be slow and unreliable, although there have been significant improvements in recent years. The main post office is located at Republic Square, Yerevan.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bird watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spot rare species of birds, including eagles, falcons and swans. Armenia is home to 346 of Europe's 550 bird species.</p>]]><p><b>Brandy drinking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sample some of Armenia's excellent brandies, which Winston Churchill always insisted on after first tasting it at the Yalta conference.</p>]]><p><b>Caving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore into some dazzling limestone caverns in Vayots Dzor. Near Goris you can explore cave homes carved into the hillsides.</p>]]><p><b>Cultural sites</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Yerevan's impressive array of cultural sites, including the National Gallery (founded in 1919) and the Yerevan library of ancient manuscripts (<em>Materadaran</em>), which houses over 13,000 texts. Don't miss the State Museum of Armenian History in Yerevan, which houses the country's best collection of historical artefacts.</p>]]><p><b>Debed Canyon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel to the steep-sided Debed Canyon where you can visit the UNESCO-protected monasteries of Haghpat and Sanahin. It is believed that the great Armenian troubadour-poet, Sayat-Nova, was born in Sanahin, and became a monk at Haghpat.</p>]]><p><b>Dilijan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax in Dilijan, a town set amid lovely pine forests with walking trails that ascend to alpine lakes. The town has a number of renovated Soviet-era sanatoriums and a community of retired artists.</p>]]><p><b>Echmiadzin</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience holy Echmiadzin, the capital of Armenia from AD 180-340, and the location of the Cathedral of St Gregory the Illuminator. The cathedral's treasury contains a spearhead believed to have been used to pierce the side of the crucified Christ.</p>]]><p><b>Fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cast a line into lake Sevan, where you can reel into Armenia's famous species of trout, the Salmon trout (<em>Ishkhan</em>), plus many more that swim in Armenia's other lakes and rivers.</p>]]><p><b>Geghard Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Make a pilgrimage to one of Armenia's most dramatic sights, the Geghard Monastery. A monastery has occupied this site since the fourth century AD, and the existing churches, all magnificently carved, date from the 13th century. Take a detour and visit Garni Temple. Earthquakes have destroyed most of the original structure, but the temple's vertiginous position, on a plateau 300m (984ft) above the Azat River, secures its beauty.</p>]]><p><b>Goris</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Journey to Goris, a town that has changed little since it was first planned by a 19th century German architect. The surrounding area is worth exploring for its cave dwellings. Nearby is the spectacular Tatev Monastery.</p>]]><p><b>Hiking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike through Armenia's spectacular countryside, ambling over country roads through timeless villages or up steep mountain passes to catch a gorgeous sunrise.</p>]]><p><b>Horse riding</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Horse ride on Mount Aragats in the spring, when you can traverse Armenia's tallest mountain.</p>]]><p><b>Lake Sevan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Much vaunted for its pure waters, stunning setting and delicious salmon trout, the lake is 70km (43 miles) east of Yerevan and the largest in the Caucasus.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$10.55 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Diamonds, machinery, metal products and food.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Natural gas, petroleum, tobacco products, food and diamonds.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Russia, Belgium, Netherlands, Iran and Israel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Armenian economy is hobbled by the closed borders with Turkey and Azerbaijan, factors that cause high import prices. Nevertheless, GDP growth is a robust 13% and Armenia has been labelled a 'Caucasian Tiger' for its economic advances.<br />
<br />
Mineral deposits including copper, zinc, gold, marble, bauxite and molybdenum have brought some foreign revenue and investment, although this sector is relatively undeveloped. The industrial sector comprises textile and chemical industries, aluminium production and some mechanical engineering. Remittances, which make up 10% of the economy, have triggered some of the growth. In rural areas, many people rely on subsistence agriculture.<br />
<br />
The privatisation programme, launched in the mid 1990s, has been extended to include major parts of the national infrastructure, such as the electricity grid. The volume of foreign investment is growing, despite concerns about widespread corruption and poor financial controls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business is generally conducted formally, and visitors should dress smartly. Appointments are necessary.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Armenian Development Agency</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (10) 570 170
					Website:http://www.ada.am/
					Address: ,17 Charents Street,Yerevan,25]]><b>Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (10) 560 184
					Website:http://www.armcci.am/
					Address: ,11 Khanjyan Street,Yerevan 10,3750]]><b>Ministry of Foreign Affairs</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (10) 544 041
					Website:http://www.armeniaforeignministry.com/
					Address: ,2 Republic Square,Yerevan,10]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Yerevan has a booming restaurant scene, with cuisine available from every corner of the globe. Along Paronyan Poghots (Barbeque Street) you'll find a number of places that serve the famed Armenian dish, <em>khoravats</em> (grilled meats). Crawling between cafes is a popular local activity; many are located in parks and along sidewalks. <br><br>Much Armenian cooking is based on lamb, either grilled and served as <em>shashlik</em> with flat bread, or prepared as soup (the most popular being <em>bozbash</em>, a dish which exists in infinite variations) or stew, often in combination with fruit or nuts. A meal usually starts with a large spread of hors d'oeuvres, which may include peppers and vine leaves stuffed with rice and meat, pickled and fresh vegetables and various kinds of cured meat (<em>basturma</em>).</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Shampours</em> (skewers packed with all kinds of marinated meat and vegetables).<br /><em>&bull; Ghapama</em> (pumpkin stew with rice, raisins, apples and cinnamon). <br /><em>&bull; Khash</em> is a national institution rather than just a dish, with poems and songs throughout the centuries being composed in homage to it. It's a broth made from hamhocks and herbs, served with lots of garlic and bread.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Expected by waiters and doormen in restaurants - sometimes in advance to ensure service.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>There is no minimum.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Yerevan has no shortage of nightclubs and restaurants that host local bands playing everything from soft jazz to hard rock. Some of the biggest clubs play techno and trance until dawn, sometimes with DJs from Europe or Russia. The capital also has a forlorn strip of casinos on the road to the airport. <br />
<br />
Opera, theatre and ballet performances are of a high standard, and tickets are cheap. Folk music, featuring the ubiquitous <em>duduk</em> (a double reed wood instrument) is often organised at traditional Armenian restaurants and other tourist venues. There are often concerts at the Philharmonic, Chamber Music Hall and Opera &amp; Ballet House in Yerevan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Yerevan has several shops selling modern fashions produced by local designers. Souvenir and craft shops are available in shopping plazas and hotels. The <em>Vernisaj</em> flea market in Yerevan attracts sellers of all kinds of goods and is popular with tourists. Shopping is far more limited elsewhere in the country, although Dilijan has a tourist market where you can buy Armenian crafts and artwork.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700. Shops stay open longer in the summer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many of the old Soviet-era hotels have been privatised and upgraded, including the excellent Armenia Marriott Hotel on Republic Square in Yerevan. The Tufenkian Group has established several heritage hotels across the country, notably the Avan Dzoraget Hotel in the Debed Canyon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Armenia has the best network of bed and breakfasts in the Caucuses. Most offer a room inside the family house with shared facilities. Staying in these is a great way to get to know local families. The main tourist office in Yerevan keeps an updated list of bed and breakfasts across the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many of the old Soviet-era hotels have been privatised and upgraded, including the excellent Armenia Marriott Hotel on Republic Square in Yerevan. The Tufenkian Group has established several heritage hotels across the country, notably the Avan Dzoraget Hotel in the Debed Canyon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many of the old Soviet-era hotels have been privatised and upgraded, including the excellent Armenia Marriott Hotel on Republic Square in Yerevan. The Tufenkian Group has established several heritage hotels across the country, notably the Avan Dzoraget Hotel in the Debed Canyon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Travellers are advised to take out comprehensive travel insurance. Power shortages and disrupted medical supplies have undermined normal health services to such a degree that travellers would be well advised to consider a health insurance policy guaranteeing emergency evacuation in case of serious accident or illness, as medical insurance is not often valid within the country.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Doctors and hospitals often expect immediate cash payment for health services and credit or debit cards will not be accepted; most will want treatment paid for in local currency. Travellers are also advised to take a supply of those medicines that they are likely to require (but check first that they may be legally imported) as there is a severe shortage of even the most basic medical supplies, such as disposable needles, anaesthetics and antibiotics.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products should be safe for consumption, however, the incidence of communicable diseases among livestock is increasing because of a breakdown in vaccination programmes.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B and E, tick-borne encephalitis and tuberculosis may all occur. Visitors are advised to take precautions which may include vaccination. There may be a risk of rabies&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;although there has been no reported incidence in animals or humans since 1997. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here:</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Armenian Orthodox Christmas :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Motherhood and Beauty Day :
							07 April </p><p>Genocide Remembrance Day :
							24 April </p><p>Victory and Peace Day :
							09 May </p><p>First Republic Day :
							28 May </p><p>Constitution Day :
							05 July </p><p>Independence Day :
							21 September </p><p>Earthquake Memorial Day :
							07 December </p><p>New Year's Eve :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Armenia by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; Goods up to AMD150,000 (around US$315) in value and not weighing more than 50kg, for personal use only.</p>
<p>It is advisable to declare valuables on arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Live animals and plants, pornography, and objects of historical, cultural and archaeological value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Material containing state secrets, live animals and plants, unlabelled alcohol, pornography, and objects of historical, cultural and archaeological value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Armenian Dram (AMD) = 100 luma. Dram notes are printed in denominations of AMD50,000, 20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of AMD500, 200, 100, 50, 20 and 10.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged at the airports, banks and most hotels and shops during normal opening hours. US Dollars are the most widely recognised foreign currency. Visitors using the national currency are advised to carry plenty of small change as some shops and, particularly markets, may be unable to accept large denominations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are accepted in most cities. There are ATMs in major cities.</p><p>There are ATMs in major cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are accepted in a few shops and hotels. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1500. Exchange offices are open until midnight and also operate at weekends and on public holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Armenia, a passport valid for six months is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign nationals transiting through Armenia must present tickets to a  third country or a visa to a third country and can stay in Armenia for no more than 72 hours except in cases of  emergency.</p>
<p>If leaving the airport, a transit visa may be issued on arrival for a stay of maximum three days, provided the visitor is holding a visa (if required) for the final destination.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is best to apply for an E-Visa. The typical waiting time for an E-Visa is three working days. Please apply at the <a href="http://www.mfa.am/en/visa/">Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Republic of Armenia website</a> before your trip.</p>
<p>A visitor visa (up to 21 days of stay) is US$6 or &euro;5, while a multiple-entry visa (for up to 60 days with a 6 month validity) is US$41 or &euro;37.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry 21-day visas must be used within 90 days of date of issue; single-entry 120-day visas must be used within 180 days of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Embassy (or consular section at embassy). It is also possible to obtain 21-day and 120-day visas on arrival, but expect the costs to be significantly higher than those listed above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least two to three days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are granted for a maximum of 120 days with the possibility of extending for another 60 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[40.291974]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[44.937024]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>29,743 sq km (11,484 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3,026,048 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>102.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Yerevan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Armenia lies on the southern slopes of the Armenian Mountains in the Lesser Caucasus and is bordered by Georgia, Turkey, Azerbaijan and Iran. Its highest peak is Mount Aragats, 4,090m (13,415ft), and even its deepest valleys lie 450 to 700m (1,200 to 1,870ft) above sea level. Its biggest lake is Lake Sevan in the east.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>94% Armenian Apostolic Church, with Catholic and Protestant communities and a Russian Orthodox minority. Armenia is the oldest Christian nation in the world, its conversion dating from the year AD 301.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost all entertaining takes place in private homes, and guests may find themselves subjected to overwhelming hospitality and generosity, as well as being expected to eat enormously and participate in endless toasts. Visitors invited to an Armenian's home should arrive bearing some kind of small gift, such as flowers and alcohol (preferably imported) or chocolates. Handshaking is the normal form of greeting. Business cards are invariably exchanged at any kind of official meeting and not infrequently on first meeting people socially as well.<br /><br />Conversation tends to be highly politicised, and guests may be well advised to avoid expressing strong opinions. Homosexuality is now decriminalised but is still an unacceptable lifestyle for many Armenians. Women tend to be less retiring than in nearby Muslim countries, and can usually dress in normal western-style clothing (especially in the capital), although female visitors may wish to avoid wearing short skirts and shorts.<strong> </strong><strong><br /><br /><strong>Photography:</strong></strong> Refrain from photographing sites such as military bases equipment and installations. Also be aware of cultural sensitivities when photographing churches and other religious sites.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Nikol Pashinyan resigned in October 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Armen Sarkissian since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Before it was incorporated into the Roman Empire in AD114, the Armenian Empire stretched from the Caspian Sea in the east to the Mediterranean in the west. In 301, Armenia became the first country to adopt Christianity as its state religion and by the fifth century, the church had developed an alphabet, which is still used today.</p>
<p>The incorporation of Armenia into the Turkish Seljuk Empire, in the 11th century, resulted in the first of many waves of emigration before the Egyptian Mamluk advance was followed by the Ottoman Turks occupation and a constant struggle with the Iranian Safavid dynasty until the beginning of the 19th century when the Russians moved in and took control.</p>
<p>In 1915 the Turks massacred an estimated 1.25 million Armenians in the first act of genocide of the 20th century. After a brief spell of independence in the aftermath of World War I and following the Bolshevik victory in the Russian civil war Armenia was incorporated into the Transcaucasian Soviet Federated Republic and later became one of three distinct Soviet republics with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/azerbaijan">Azerbaijan</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/georgia">Georgia</a>. In the late 1980s, the Armenians were among the first groups in the Soviet Union to test the limits of glasnost with a series of demonstrations against industrial pollution and repression of the population of Nagorno-Karabakh.</p>
<p>In December 1988, a massive double earthquake struck killing some 60,000 people and destroying nearly half a million buildings. The city of Spitak experienced near total destruction and in Leninakan, Armenia&rsquo;s second city, some 80 per cent of buildings collapsed. The reconstruction process and the simmering Karabakh conflict strengthened the hand of the growing dissident movement leading to the election of Levon Ter-Petrossian, head of the Pan-Armenian National Movement, as President. Independence was formally declared on 23 September 1991 and the Karabakh conflict soon escalated into full-scale war until a Moscow-brokered ceasefire took effect in May 1994.</p>
<p>Although there are still many obstacles, Armenia and Azerbaijan have found sufficient issues of common interest to establish a reasonable working relationship, but diplomatic relations between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey">Turkey</a> were severed in 1992 and remain so. However, Armenia has maintained solid ties with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iran">Iran</a>, as well as the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">United States</a> and the European Union.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>In the wake of the 1988 earthquake, the British music industry launched Rock Aid Armenia to raise money through the release of the album <em>Earthquake</em> and three singles &ndash; covers of <em>What&rsquo;s Going On</em>, <em>Smoke on the Water</em> and Led Zeppelin&rsquo;s <em>Rock and Roll</em>.</p>
<p>The National Art Gallery in the capital Yerevan has more than 16,000 works, some dating back to the Middle Ages.</p>
<p>The apricot is the national fruit of Armenia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Armenia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 319 1976 or 2983 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.armeniaemb.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 319 1976 or 2983 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2225 R Street<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Armenia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7938 5435.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.armenianembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7938 5435.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1800, Fri 0900-1700 (embassy); Mon-Fri 0930-1300 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>25A Cheniston Gardens<br/>London<br/>W8 6TG<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Armenia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(10) 264 301.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinarmenia.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(10) 264 301.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>19<br/>34 Baghramyan Avenue<br/>Yerevan<br/>3750<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It might be a small nation, but Armenia is big on character. Its 20th century history was troubled and relations with neighbouring Turkey are still fractious to put it mildly &ndash; although a visit to the country today is more likely to be dominated by its medieval treasures than its more recent past.</p>
<p>The welcome is rarely anything less than warm &ndash; and usually accompanied by brandy &ndash; and the countryside itself is often breathtakingly beautiful. Tourist numbers are generally low, but you&rsquo;ll find yourself wondering why.</p>
<p>This is a country with serious historical legacy. Christianity arrived in AD 301 and Armenia proudly calls itself the world's oldest Christian nation. Religion still tends to play a large part in visitor itineraries &ndash; from the centuries-old monasteries that stud the hilly Lori region to the mists-of-time bibles at the wonderful Museum of Ancient Manuscripts &ndash; but Armenia is changing.</p>
<p>Since the break-up of the Soviet Union, the country has re-embraced its traditions while moving on. Much of this progress is focused on the capital city of Yerevan. Loomed over on clear days by Mount Ararat across the border, it is the nation's hub of cultural activity and progressive thought, with a lively modern arts scene and plenty of large-scale redevelopment.</p>
<p>Armenia has a large diaspora population &ndash; there are thousands of Armenian Americans &ndash; and a lot of wealth has been brought back into the country as a result. But the passions that underpin life here, from patriotism to religion, chess to cognac, aren&rsquo;t the sort that cost millions. Cafe culture has been perfected and it's de rigueur to spend inordinate amounts of time lingering over a conversation. Armenian food is another treat &ndash; expect mounds of grilled meats and vegetables straight from the nearest garden.</p>
<p>Around the country, travel highlights include the charming little town of Goris and the arty mountain settlement of Dilijan, but exploration anywhere in Armenia is likely to reap rewards.</p><p>It might be a small nation, but Armenia is big on character. Its 20th century history was troubled and relations with neighbouring Turkey are still fractious to put it mildly &ndash; although a visit to the country today is more likely to be dominated by its medieval treasures than its more recent past.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
