<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Aruba" ColCode="abw" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="aw" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Aruba]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With an average temperature of 28°C (82°F), this dry and sunny island is made pleasantly cool throughout the year by constant trade winds. Short showers occur during the months of October, November and December.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothes. Sweaters are useful for air conditioned hotels and restaurants. Some upscale restaurants do not allow shorts and T-shirts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferries depart daily to De Palm Island from the mainland. The crossing takes five minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The road system throughout the island is very good.</p><p>The main taxi office is at Pos Abou. Taxis are not metered. Rates are fixed and should be checked before getting into the cab. There is no need to tip drivers except for help with unusually heavy luggage.</p><p>A valid foreign licence or an International Driving Permit, held for at least two years, are both acceptable. Insurance is recommended.</p><p>Seatbelts must be worn. Right turns on red lights are prohibited. The speed limit is 40kph (25mph) in urban areas and 60kph (37mph) outside towns.</p><p>There are plenty of cars available for hire and touring by car or by 4-wheel drive jeep is one of the most pleasant ways to explore the island. Most major companies have offices in Aruba and there are also many well-established local car hire firms. The minimum age for hiring a car is 21 to 25 (maximum 65 to 70), depending on the firm.</p><p>It's possible to hire scooters, motorbikes and bicycles.</p><p>Seatbelts must be worn. Right turns on red lights are prohibited. The speed limit is 40kph (25mph) in urban areas and 60kph (37mph) outside towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A streetcar connects Oranjestad with the cruise ship port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is<em> </em>Aruba Airlines<em> </em>(<a href="http://www.arubaairlines.com" target="_blank">www.arubaairlines.com</a>). The easiest way to reach Aruba from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> is via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amsterdam">Amsterdam</a> with KLM (<a href="http://www.klm.com" target="_blank">www.klm.com</a>). Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) operates direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;15 hours (including stopover in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amsterdam">Amsterdam</a>);&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;4 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$34.25 (flights outside the USA) or US$37.50 (flights to the USA). Departure tax is normally included in the ticket price.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Queen Beatrix International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airportaruba.com<p>The airport  is 3.5km (2.5 miles) southeast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/oranjestad">Oranjestad</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main port:&nbsp;</strong>Oranjestad.</p>
<p>Boats dock in the heart of town and it's only a five-minute walk to the centre. However, there are also taxis available on the dock itself, plus car hire companies at the port.</p>
<p>Many cruise ships call in on their Caribbean itineraries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Payphones are located all over the island. International phone cards are available from petrol stations, mini markets and supermarkets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a few mobile phone companies. Coverage is average.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many hotels offer connections. Internet cafes are also available. Aruba has several Wi-Fi hotspots (<a href="http://www.wifi-aruba.com" target="_blank">www.wifi-aruba.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Radio stations include Radio Kelkboom, Magic 96.5 and Canal 90; the oldest established newspaper (in Dutch) is <em>Amigoe di Aruba</em>; other papers include <em>Aruba Today</em>, <em>Diario Aruba</em> and <em>Bon Dia</em>; ATV and Tele Aruba are prime TV channels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0730-1200 and 1300-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Climb Hooiberg</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Shaped like a giant haystack, (<em>hooiberg </em>actually means "haystack" in Dutch), this volcano rises dramatically from Aruba's flat interior to the northwest of Santa Cruz. The 165m (541ft) summit is accessed via a series of steps and offers views across to Venezuela on clear days.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy the sights of Bubali Bird Sanctuary</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You don't have to be a twitcher to appreciate Bubali Bird Sanctuary, which is home to herons, egrets, gulls, cormorants and many other species. Viewing platform have been erected throughout the park and provide excellent opportunities for birdwatching.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the underwater world</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A mecca for divers and snorkelers, Aruba has 40 dive sites where visitors can meet the local marine life or explore WWII wrecks. As well as stunning coral formations, bountiful marine life and sunken ships, visitors can enjoy excellent visibility in Aruba's crystalline waters.</p>]]><p><b>Go wild at Arikok National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This enormous park covers one-fifth of the island's landmass and contains a multitude of plants and animals, including flamingos. The park as it's known today was only fully realised in 2000 and is striving to increase the work of conservation and education on Aruba.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The question is: which one? Hadicurari Beach is renowned for its snorkelling, Baby Beach is ideal for children and Palm Beach is well located for a post bathing beer. Feeling more active? Aruba's trade winds offer ideal conditions for windsurfing and kite surfing at Arashi beach.</p>]]><p><b>Lounge under the Divi-Divi trees</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Aruba's unofficial trademark, the distinctive <em>Divi-Divi </em>tree (also known as <em>watapana</em>) stretches out at weird and wonderful angles. Locals use the iconic tree as a natural compass, as they always point in a southwesterly direction due to the trade winds that blow across the island from the northeast.</p>]]><p><b>Make a pilgrimage to the Chapel of Alto Vista</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You can't fail to miss the Chapel of Alto Vista with its bright yellow exterior acting as a beacon to worshippers. Also known by locals as the "Pilgrim's Church", it is located on the north coast and boasts a 100-year-old hand-carved oak altar.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the cave art</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The three best-known caves in Aruba are located in Arikok National Park and contain some fantastic examples of early cave drawings. Arawak Indians, the original inhabitants of Aruba, used to reside in Fontein and their primitive art remains on the walls. The caves at Guadirikiri are a haven for bats, while Huliba Cave is the place for romance, apparently (it's nicknamed the "tunnel of love").</p>]]><p><b>Party hard at the Bonbini Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hedonists are well catered for in Aruba's colourful capital, Oranjestad, which hosts the Bonbini Festival every Tuesday. This weekly shindig takes place in the courtyard of the Historical Museum and offers an insight into local customs, music and cuisine, as well as a chance to get to know the islanders.</p>]]><p><b>Saddle up and go horse riding</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Exploring Aruba on horseback is a highlight for many visitors. There are riding trails throughout the countryside and along the coast. Choose one of the many ranches or horse-riding tours and you'll soon see why it's one of the most popular things to do Aruba.</p>]]><p><b>Shop till you drop</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Duty-free shopping entices many to part with their cash in Aruba. There are shopping malls across the island, specialising in everything from jewellery and homeware to leather goods and designer fashion. The most popular place to melt the credit card is Caya GF Betico Croes in Oranjestad.</p>]]><p><b>Strut your stuff at Carnival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Aruba's annual Carnival kicks off in January and the party keeps rolling until the Tuesday before Ash Wednesday. During these hedonistic weeks visitors can shake their meat to the local beat, admire dazzling costumes and watch colourful processions. The question is: can you keep up?</p>]]><p><b>Tee off for a round of golf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Golfers can enjoy three courses in Aruba of varying size. Aruba Golf Club and The Links at Divi Aruba both offer 9-hole courses that are fine for a swift round. However, if you have, time tee off at Aruba Tierra del Sol's beautiful 18-hole course, which is easily the pick of the bunch.</p>]]><p><b>Unearth artefacts at the Archaeological Museum of Aruba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Archaeological Museum of Aruba has reopened in the restored historic Ecury complex in central Oranjestad. A former family home, the building has been transformed to a state-of-the-art museum that preserves Aruba's Amerindian cultural heritage. This is the perfect place to get up to speed on the rich culture and history of the island.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind in colourful Oranjestad</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Aruba's Dutch colonial history is most evident in the capital, Oranjestad, which abounds with pretty gabled buildings. Also here is Fort Zoutman, the oldest building on Aruba (1796), and home to the Aruba Historical Museum. Fresh fish can be bought straight from the boat at Oranjestad's daily market in the Paardenbaai (Schooner Harbour).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2.2 billion (2008).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil products, animals and animal products, art and collectibles, machinery and electrical equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, food and manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>The Netherlands, The Netherlands Antilles and Venezuela.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Between 1824 and 1916, the economy was based on gold mining. An oil refinery opened in the mid 1920s and was the most important commercial operation on the island until its closure in 1985. However, it was re-opened in 1991 and oil reassumed its central position in the Aruban economy. In the meantime, a sizeable tourism sector grew up. Aruba now receives 1.5 million tourists a year, 75% from the USA. <br /><br />More recently, Aruba has been joined by offshore service industries, including finance and data processing. The country's free-port status, ship bunkering and repair facilities are the island's other main sources of revenue. <br /><br />Light industry is limited to the production of some tobacco products, drinks and consumer goods. Agriculture is confined to small-scale activity, because of poor soil quality. Aruba is classed as an Associated Territory of the European Union.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business dress and etiquette tend to reflect that of the USA. It is usual for men to wear ties to business meetings. Exchanging business cards is the norm. Meetings are usually held during office hours in the workplace.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>De Palm Tours NV</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 582 4400.
					Website:http://www.depalm.com
					Address: ,L G Smith Boulevard 142,Oranjestad,]]><b>Chamber of Commerce and Industry Aruba</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 582 1566
					Website:http://www.arubachamber.com
					Address: PO Box 140,JE Irausquin Boulevard,Oranjestad,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Not much food is grown locally, but the variety in the local cuisine is extensive. There is a very wide range of international cuisine and several of the more famous fast-food chains have premises on the island.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; <em>Keshi yena</em> (Gouda cheese packed with a spicy meat mixture of either chicken or beef and then baked). <br />&bull; <em>Stobà</em> (lamb or goat stew). <br />&bull; <em>Cala</em> (bean fritters). <br />&bull; <em>Pastechi</em> (meat- or cheese-stuffed turnovers). <br />&bull; <em>Ayacas</em> (leaf-wrapped meat rolls).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Hotels add a 15% service charge to any food or beverage bill. Restaurants may add 15% service to the bill; if not, 10 to 15% is normal.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is one drive-in and one indoor cinema screening the latest blockbusters. The highlight of Aruba's nightlife, however, is the casinos; most open from 1100 until the early morning, with a few opening 24 hours. Hotel bars usually offer live entertainment and most hotels run theme nights. Alternatively, there are several cocktail bars and nightclubs in Oranjestad; join one of the party buses for a lively pub tour. Another option is one of the party cruises, usually offering dinner, drinks and entertainment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As a 'free zone', duty on most items in Aruba is so low that shopping here can have obvious advantages. Stores carry goods from all parts of the world and there are some excellent buys, including perfume, linens, jewellery, watches, cameras, crystal, china and other luxury items plus a range of locally made handicrafts. Aloe grows in abundance on Aruba, and skin care products are manufactured locally.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1800; some shops close for lunch between 1200-1400. Shops in malls and shopping centres may open 0930-1800 and may open Sundays when cruise ships are in port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of hotels are in the Palm Beach and Eagle Beach resort area on the southwest coast, offering accommodation of a very high standard. Many of these luxury hotels have beach frontage and swimming pools, plus extensive sport, entertainment and shopping facilities. Rates are much lower in the summer, which is the island's low season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many guest houses are in the Noord area not far from the main hotel area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of hotels are in the Palm Beach and Eagle Beach resort area on the southwest coast, offering accommodation of a very high standard. Many of these luxury hotels have beach frontage and swimming pools, plus extensive sport, entertainment and shopping facilities. Rates are much lower in the summer, which is the island's low season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of hotels are in the Palm Beach and Eagle Beach resort area on the southwest coast, offering accommodation of a very high standard. Many of these luxury hotels have beach frontage and swimming pools, plus extensive sport, entertainment and shopping facilities. Rates are much lower in the summer, which is the island's low season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are excellent medical facilities and many hotels also have doctors on call. There is a modern, well-equipped hospital, as well as a medical centre. In rare circumstances, air evacuation to Curaçao may be necessary. Full medical insurance is advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is considered safe to drink. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Betico Croes Day :
							2018<br/>25 January </p><p>Carnival :
							12 February </p><p>National Anthem and Flag Day :
							18 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							30 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Aruba without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigarillos or 25 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits or 2.25L of wine or 3L of beer.<br />
&bull; Gifts to the value of AWG400.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include unauthorised firearms and ammunition, and narcotics.</p>
<p>Restricted goods which require an import licence include plants, animals, meat and meat products, and medicines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unauthorised firearms and ammunition, and narcotics.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Aruban Florin (AWG; symbol Æ) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of Æ500, 100, 50, 25 and 10. Coins are in denominations of Æ5, 2.5 and 1, and 50, 25, 10 and 5 cents.<br /><br />The Aruban Florin is tied to the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The US Dollar is widely accepted. Other currencies can be exchanged in banks. Currency can also be obtained from ATMs in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/oranjestad">Oranjestad</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are widely accepted by many shops and hotels. They can also be used in ATMs if the card bears CIRRUS or Plus System logos.</p><p>They can also be used in ATMs if the card bears CIRRUS or Plus System logos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Euros. Traveller's cheques can be cashed at banks and at major hotels.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1330-1600. Some remain open at lunchtime.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors to Aruba require a passport valid for the duration of stay.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Schengen visa is not valid for travel to Aruba.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay Caribbean visa: &pound;30.&nbsp;The Caribbean visa allows nationals who do require a visa to make short visits to Aruba, Cura&ccedil;ao, St Maarten, Bonaire, St Eustatius and Saba.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Caribbean visa is a multiple-entry visa. Visa holders may visit any of the countries included under the scheme for a maximum of 90 days within one year. Each continuous period in any one country may not exceed 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dutch Embassy/Consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications for the Caribbean visa are usually processed within 15 calendar days, but processing times vary depending on the country. Applications can be made up to 3 months before the intended travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals who do not require a visa can request an extension of stay up to 180 days at the immigration department (<a href="http://www.dimasaruba.com">www.dimasaruba.com</a>).</p>
<p>You cannot extend the Caribbean visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets may only enter Aruba if they've lived in a country with a low incidence of rabies for at least six months. Your animal needs a microchip, veterinary certificate of good health issued no more than 14 days before travel, and a rabies innoculation certificate issued no more than 30 days before travel.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[12.497997]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-69.936960]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>193 sq km (74.5 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>104,263 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>573.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Oranjestad.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constituent country of the Kingdom of the Netherlands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Aruba is the smallest island in the Leeward group of the Dutch Caribbean islands, which also include Bonaire and Cura&ccedil;ao; they are popularly known as the ABCs.</p>
<p>As the westernmost island of the group, Aruba is the final link in the long Antillean chain, lying 20km (12.5 miles) off the Venezuelan coast. The island is 30km (19.6 miles) long and 9km (6 miles) across at its widest, and has a flat landscape dominated by Jamanota Mountain (188m/617ft).</p>
<p>The west and southwest coast, known as Palm Beach, boasts 11km (7 miles) of palm-fringed powder-white sands while, in contrast, the east coast has a desolate and windswept shoreline of jagged rocks carved into peculiar shapes by the pounding surf.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>82% of the population are Roman Catholic. There are also Protestant, Hindu, Muslim, Confucian and Jewish communities present.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Much of the social activity takes place in hotels where the atmosphere will be informal, often American in feel. The islanders do not wear shorts in town though it is acceptable for visitors to do so. Bathing suits are strictly for beach or poolside. In the evenings people tend to dress up, especially when visiting the casinos. Jackets are not required for men, except for official government functions.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without a round grounding pin) are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Evelyn Wever-Croes since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Willem-Alexander since 2013, represented locally by Governor Alfonso Boekhoudt since 1 January 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alonzo de Ojeda discovered Aruba in 1499, claiming the island for <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a>. He described an 'island of giants' having been struck by the stature of the population. However, the Spaniards did not consider the island worth colonising and left the original Arawak Indian inhabitants to live in virtual peace. Although Spain's lack of interest resulted in the island becoming a haven for pirates and buccaneers, the Spanish hegemony continued unchallenged until 1636, by which time the war with Holland was well into its seventh decade. Dutch war interests then switched to the Caribbean and the Dutch fleet took over the neglected territory with little opposition. In 1643, the Dutch appointed a governor to take charge of Aruba and the rest of the Netherlands Antilles.</p><p>Except for a brief period in the early 19th century, when the British took possession during the Napoleonic Wars, Aruba has remained under peaceful Dutch jurisdiction ever since.</p><p>During World War 2 Aruba was administered by the Dutch government-in-exile in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> and continued to supply oil to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Britain</a> and her allies.</p><p>On 1 January 1986, Aruba achieved internal autonomy, separating it administratively from the rest of the Netherlands Antilles, although it remains a constituent country of the Kingdom of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/netherlands">Netherlands</a>. This was originally conceived as the first step towards independence, for which a 10-year transitional period was planned. In March 1994, however, after consultation with the Dutch government, this plan was shelved. Independence at some later date has not been completely ruled out but it will now require the consent of two-thirds of the population in a referendum.</p><p>The Dutch king Willem-Alexander is Aruba's head of state and appoints the island's governor on a six-year term. The prime minster and deputy prime minister are elected by the Aruban Parlamento, which is made up of 21 members elected by popular vote on four-year terms.</p><p>In recent years increasing <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> tourism has been reflected in the growing popularity of American celebrations such as Halloween and Thanksgiving.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• With low unemployment Aruba enjoys one of the highest standards of living in the Caribbean.</p><p>• With Bonaire and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/curacao">Curaçao</a>, Aruba forms a group known as the ABC Islands.</p><p>• The capital Oranjestad, often referred to as Playa, was built around Fort Zoutman in 1796 and was named after King William I in the 1820s. The artificial Renaissance Island is home to a population of flamingos and has Aruba's only private beaches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Diplomatic Representation]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lean back and take it easy on Aruba, which combines the best that Caribbean sea, sand and sunshine have to offer. Aruba's balmy breezes and relaxed pace are just the tonic for any frazzled visitor; just like the soothing aloe vera plant that is found everywhere on the island.</p><p>The surrounding waters are populated by colourful creatures such as parrotfish splashed with teal and gold, while bright pink flamingos populate the national park. Aruba's capital, Oranjestad, also dazzles – it's great for shopping. Orange facades brightly array the architecture, indicating the island's historical ties with The Netherlands – Aruba's head of state is still the Dutch ruling monarch.</p><p>Favoured by Americans keen to escape extreme weather in winter, Aruba is one of the most popular touristic islands in the southern Caribbean. Sometimes the mob has it right. This island's beautiful beaches, pristine resorts and charming city of Oranjestad are difficult to knock. You'll also find a lively nighttime scene, with glittering casinos, gourmet restaurants and beach-side diners.</p><p>Many come on day-trips as part of a cruise, but it's really worth spending a bit more time in Aruba, soaking up its nature, all rugged coasts and gorgeous beaches. In the interior you'll find rocky deserts, expanses filled with cactuses and the iconic <em>divi-divi</em> tree. It's a good idea to hire a car to really make the most of it. Many tourists don't stray far from Oranjestad, but a drive to the northern and eastern shores comes highly recommended. Look out for the California Lighthouse and Seroe Colorado. Modern road signs are still being developed here, so try not to get lost.</p><p>As for history, Aruba's first inhabitants are thought to be Amerindians from the Arawak tribe. The island was later colonised by the Spanish, before being taken over by the Dutch in the 17th century. Today's Arubans are for the most part an interesting mix of Amerindian and European heritage, with the island boasting the strongest Arawak heritage in the region. There is also a considerable black population, as well as more recent Venezuelan immigrants. Altogether this makes for a lively local scene that's both welcoming and distinct.</p>Lean back and take it easy on Aruba: the best that Caribbean sea, sand and sunshine have to offer.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
