<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="New South Wales" ColCode="nsw" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ns" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[New South Wales]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Warm semi-tropical summers, particularly in lower central area. Mountain areas in the west are cooler, particularly in winter. Rainfall is heaviest from March to June.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens in summer. Warmer mediumweights in mountain areas. Waterproofing is advisable from March to June.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sydney is an international gateway to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>, and flights from Europe, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand">New Zealand</a>, Asia, Africa and the Americas all serve the city. The main domestic airlines operating in New South Wales are Aeropelican Air Services (OT) (<a href="http://www.aeropelican.com.au/" target="_blank">www.aeropelican.com.au</a>), Air Link Airlines (DR) (<a href="http://www.airlinkairlines.com.au/" target="_blank">www.airlinkairlines.com.au</a>), Jetstar (JQ) (<a href="http://www.jetstar.com.au/" target="_blank">www.jetstar.com.au</a>), Qantas (QF) (<a href="http://www.qantas.com.au/" target="_blank">www.qantas.com.au</a>), Rex - Regional Express (ZL)<em> </em>(<a href="http://www.regionalexpress.com.au/" target="_blank">www.regionalexpress.com.au</a>),<em> </em>Tiger Airways (TR) (<a href="http://www.tigerairways.com.au/" target="_blank">www.tigerairways.com.au</a>) and Virgin Blue (DJ)<em> </em>(<a href="http://www.virginblue.com.au/" target="_blank">www.virginblue.com.au</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney</a> is 22 hours, and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a> is 22 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Sydney Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.sydneyairport.com.au<p>Sydney Airport is located 9km (6 miles) south of central Sydney.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+61 2 9667 9111</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sydney (<a href="http://www.sydneyports.com.au/" target="_blank">www.sydneyports.com.au</a>) is a major international port, and cruise lines call from Europe, the Far East and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sydney has through-trains to all other state capitals. The <em>XPT</em> service<em> </em>connects Sydney to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/brisbane-airport">Brisbane</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a>. An internal system of railways runs throughout the state, connecting all the most important towns, tourist resorts and running through to Canberra in the south. The two main rail operators are Cityrail<em> </em>(tel: 131 500; <a href="http://www.cityrail.nsw.gov.au/" target="_blank">www.cityrail.nsw.gov.au</a>) and Countrylink<em> </em>(tel: 132 232; <a href="http://www.countrylink.info/" target="_blank">www.countrylink.info</a>). The main train interchanges are located at Central Station and Town Hall.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>AMP Tower Centrepoint</p><![CDATA[<p>Standing at 305m (1001ft) high, Sydney Tower is the tallest building in Sydney. Located in the Central Business District in the heart of the city, visitors can experience amazing views across Sydney Harbour from the Observation Deck. The tower, which was completed in 1981, also has a revolving restaurant which slowly rotates through 360° views. Visitors can also experience the OzTrek attraction, a simulated journey showcasing Austalia's culture, history and geography. The Sydney Tower itself forms part of the Westfield Centrepoint complex which is home to around 140 shops, as well as the Centrepoint Convention and Exhibition Centre.<br /><br />Address: Sydney Tower, Podium Level, Westfield Centrepoint, 100 Market Street, Sydney NSW 2000</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Aboriginal heritage tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take in Sydney's stunning Royal Botanic Gardens (<a href="http://www.rbgsyd.nsw.gov.au" target="_blank">www.rbgsyd.nsw.gov.au</a>) with an Aborignal tour guide to learn about the heritage of this area and what it meant to the Cadigal, the original inhabitants of the city area. Walking tours take place on Fridays.</p>]]><p><b>Blue Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gaze upon the World Heritage-listed Blue Mountains to the west of Sydney: the Three Sisters (so-named because of dreamtime legend), at Echo Point in the Leura/Katoomba region, rise above the valley floor, and afford sensational views of this rugged wilderness.</p>]]><p><b>Broken Hill</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience unaffected Australian wilderness at the uncommercialised and unpretentious Broken Hill (<a href="http://www.visitbrokenhill.com.au/" target="_blank">www.visitbrokenhill.com.au</a>), featuring ancient landscapes and Aboriginal culture. In recent years artistic pursuits from a growing population of writers, artists and sculptors have flourished providing a unique impression of the outback.</p>]]><p><b>Climb or trek</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rock climbing and mountain walking attract visitors to Warrumbungle National Park whose 'Grand High Tops' track through the remnants of ancient volcanoes ranks high among Australia's most spectacular walks. Trek through rainforest communities in Mount Warning National Park.<strong> </strong></p>]]><p><b>Dolphin watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go dolphin and humpback whale watching; you can spot migrating whales along the coast and good places include Cape Byron between June and August and Hervey Bay between mid July and late October.</p>]]><p><b>Drive</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Grand Pacific Drive (<a href="http://www.grandpacificdrive.com.au/" target="_blank">www.grandpacificdrive.com.au</a>) takes you from Sydney to Wollongong, down to Shoalhaven, through coastal rainforest, villages and across the vast Sea Cliff Bridge. Alternatively, the Greater Blue Mountains Drive (<a href="http://www.greaterbluemountainsdrive.com.au/" target="_blank">www.greaterbluemountainsdrive.com.au</a>) is linked with discovery trails to help you appreciate this World Heritage Area.</p>]]><p><b>Go Skiing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ski, cross-country ski or snowboard in the Great Dividing Range and the Snowy Mountains: the season generally runs from June to October. Thredbo (<a href="http://www.thredbo.com.au/" target="_blank">www.thredbo.com.au</a>) has the longest and best ski runs.</p>]]><p><b>Lord Howe Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It's a two-hour flight from Sydney, but this World Heritage-listed island in the Pacific is the place to really escape to. Only 400 visitors are on the island at any one time and those who are there enjoy snorkelling around the coral reef, strolling the beach forests or venturing up Mt Gower for panoramic views (<a href="http://www.lordhoweisland.info" target="_blank">www.lordhoweisland.info</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Mardi Gras</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Indulge in the queen of all <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/country/194/top_things_to_do/Australia-and-South-Pacific/New-South-Wales.html##" target="_blank">festivals</a>, the world-famous Sydney Gay and Lesbian Mardi Gras (<a href="http://www.mardigras.org.au/" target="_blank">www.mardigras.org.au</a>). Held in February, highlights of the two-week event include the launch, the Oxford Street parade and post-parade event and Harbour party.</p>]]><p><b>National Parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take in as much countryside as you can cope with at New South Wales' many <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/country/194/top_things_to_see/Australia-and-South-Pacific/New-South-Wales.html##" target="_blank">parks</a> and nature reserves (<a href="http://www.nationalparks.nsw.gov.au/" target="_blank">www.nationalparks.nsw.gov.au</a>). The Royal National Park, just 32km (20 miles) outside Sydney, is the oldest park in Australia and the second-oldest in the world. It is rich in Aboriginal history, with Audley a good place to start at.</p>]]><p><b>Skywalk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Step onto the Skywalk (<a href="http://www.skywalk.com.au/" target="_blank">www.skywalk.com.au</a>) at the top of Sydney Tower which enables the brave to literally 'walk across the city skyline', along glass overhangs 268m (880ft) above the ground. Enjoy views as far afield as the Central Coast and the Blue Mountains.</p>]]><p><b>Snowy Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get into some serious mountain country and have your breath taken away at the sight of Australia's majestic highest peak, Mt Kosciuszko. The main visitor centre is at Jindabyne.</p>]]><p><b>South Coast tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the gorgeous south coast where traditional country towns such as Eden, Thathra and Kiama have escaped the onslaught of mass coastal development and interrupt a string of national parks protecting magnificent bushlands and spectacular coastal areas all the way to Sydney.</p>]]><p><b>Surf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Do as the locals do and strut your stuff at world-famous beaches such as Bondi and Manly in Sydney. Surf with the big boys at Bronte, Coogee, Collaroy, Palm and Byron Bay beaches.  Port Macquarie and Coff's coast in the north of the state are great surfing territories with Scott Dillon's Legends Surf Museum the ideal place to visit when on dry land.</p>]]><p><b>Sydney</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the fabulous city of Sydney. The iconic Sydney Opera House (<a href="http://www.sydneyoperahouse.com/" target="_blank">www.sydneyoperahouse.com</a>) has a distinctive shape that echoes the sails of the boats in the equally famous Sydney Harbour. Another must-see is the awesome steel structure of the Harbour Bridge. The observation deck of the 305m- (1,000ft-) high Sydney Tower (<a href="http://sydneytower.com.au/" target="_blank">http://sydneytower.com.au</a>) is a good starting point from which to get your bearings.</p>]]><p><b>Sydney Hobart Yacht Race</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watch the annual yacht race (<a href="http://rolexsydneyhobart.com/" target="_blank">http://rolexsydneyhobart.com</a>) from Sydney to Hobart in Tasmania, starting on 26 December and covering over 2,000km (1,250 miles). The first day at Sydney Harbour attracts huge crowds and spectator craft, generating a great atmosphere as the fleet sets sail.</p>]]><p><b>The Rocks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Step back in time in The Rocks area (the site of Australia's first European settlement), which features cobbled streets, gas lamps, craft shops and small restaurants. This district offers a great introduction to Sydney's maritime history as well as providing some of the best views across to the Opera House and Harbour Bridge.</p>]]><p><b>Watersports in Port Macquarie</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Couple stunning scenery with nail-biting fun by windsurfing, kayaking and white-water rafting in the Great Lakes district; its most popular resort is Port Macquarie, a sophisticated town set in a deluge of greenery with a large koala population.</p>]]><p><b>Willandra Lakes Region</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Look at 370,000 hectares (913,000 acres) of semi-arid country in the Willandra Lakes Region, renowned as one of the world's earliest-known cremation sites. The archaeological discovery of skeletal remains indicated that homo sapiens inhabited the area 40,000 years ago.</p>]]><p><b>Wine tasting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sniff, swirl and sip some exceptional Australian wine in the Hunter Valley wine district (<a href="http://www.winecountry.com.au/" target="_blank">www.winecountry.com.au</a>), famous for wine makers such as Wyndham Estate, Rosemount and McGuigans; the Hunter Valley has over 140 wineries and many restaurants. It is a two-hour drive north of Sydney and is Australia's oldest wine region.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><br />The Sydney Convention and Exhibition Centre at Darling Harbour has facilities for up to 5,000 people. Other major convention centres include Centrepoint Exhibition and Convention Centre, University of NSW, RAS Exhibition Centre, Sydney Opera House, Powerhouse Museum, Sydney Town Hall, University of Sydney, YWCA, Queen Victoria Building, Bankstown Town Hall, Curzon Hall, Film Australia, Hills Centre, Taronga Centre and the NSW Harness Racing Club.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney</a></strong>: In keeping with its distinctly work-hard, play-hard mantra, the protocol in Sydney is typically informal. During the week, business is often conducted over a long lunch, with alcohol included, and the weekend can start as early as Friday lunchtime. As with the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, officewear now errs more on the side of casual (corporate types notwithstanding). Business hours are typically weekdays 0900-1730, although an extended working day is very common in many sectors and it is not unusual for people to be working well into the night or over the weekend.</p>
<p>Australians are a very friendly people and socialising comes easily. Nevertheless, there are a few things that may offend or annoy. The first is the use of the informal &lsquo;G'day' - foreigners trying to emulate this overused greeting is akin to turning up to a business meeting misguidedly wearing a <em>Crocodile Dundee</em> hat in an attempt to culturally integrate &ndash; cringeworthy.</p>
<p>The second is that, while out drinking, a system of &lsquo;rounds' is observed and it is not appreciated when someone skips his or her round by not offering to pay. Gift giving is not a common practice, although a good bottle of Australian wine will be welcome if you&rsquo;re invited to a local house for dinner.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>New South Wales Business Chamber</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (02) 9350 8100 ,132 696
					Website:http://www.nswbusinesschamber.com.au
					Address: 140 Arthur Street,Level 15,North Sydney,]]><b>Business Events Sydney</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (02) 9331 4045
					Website:http://www.businesseventssydney.com.au
					Address: 80 William Street,Level 13,Sydney,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Cuisine in New South Wales, and Sydney in particular, reflects the state's multicultural makeup with Thai, Vietnamese, Japanese, Greek, Italian, African and Indian dishes all represented, and gourmet food and wine trails exist throughout the state. As a harbour city, fresh fish is a staple on most Sydney menus, particularly barramundi and snapper, around Darling Harbour and The Rocks' restaurants.<br />
<br />
Foodies may want to visit Orange, a town in the New South Wales tablelands that prides itself on being the 'foodbasket of the state'. Here, 20 wineries, farmers' markets and an abundance of bistros and caf&eacute;s in the town centre will help you savour the flavours of the region.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Sydney rock oysters are renowned and utterly delicious.  <br />
&bull; Fruits are plentiful due to the pleasant climate: you can find avocados, guavas, passion fruit, pears and berries. <br />
&bull; Fish such as red mullet, yellowfin tuna, whiting, snapper and John Dory.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney</a> is known for being a city that never sleeps, and has a diverse selection of bars, pubs, nightclubs and music venues. Kings Cross in Sydney is an exciting nightlife area attracting a very diverse crowd whilst the famous Sydney Opera House (<a href="http://www.sydneyoperahouse.com/" target="_blank">www.sydneyoperahouse.com</a>) regularly hosts theatre, dance, the Australian Chamber Orchestra and the Sydney Philharmonic Choirs. </p>
<p>Theatre from amateur playhouse to large-scale productions can be found all over the city. Check out the Sydney Theatre Company (<a href="http://www.sydneytheatre.com.au/" target="_blank">www.sydneytheatre.com.au</a>), the city's premier theatre outfit, for upcoming performances. There are also some night-time cruises on Sydney Harbour offering dinner and dancing. If you time it right, the annual firework display from Sydney Harbour Bridge on New Year's Eve makes it a night like no other.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Best buys are opals, precious and semi-precious stones, Aboriginal arts and crafts, woollen and sheepskin goods and fashion by top Australian designers. There's plenty of retail therapy to be had in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney</a>'s central business district, which is chock-a-block full of department stores, speciality shops and high-end fashion boutiques. Pitt Street Mall, which runs off Market Street, and the 120-year-old Strand Arcade are prime shopping locations.<br />
<br />
Woollahra is good for perusing antiques; or if you're after Australiana souvenirs then The Rocks area is your best bet: there's a market there on weekends where you'll find opals, Aboriginal art and other items directed towards tourists. The best weekend market is Paddington Market especially for funky fashions, books and designer jewellery. The Bondi and Glebe markets are top spots for art and jewellery.</p><p>In Sydney, shops open Mon-Fri 0900-1730, Sat 0900-1600 and Sun 1000-1600. Many shops also stay open until 2100 on a Thursday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sydney and other cities offer an excellent choice of hotels for all budgets and tastes. There's plenty of budget backpacker accommodation in central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney</a>, particularly around the Kings Cross area, while more expensive boutique accommodation can be found in The Rocks and Darlinghurst. The state is well travelled by Australians themselves, and so offers an excellent network of accommodation outside the larger cities, mostly of motel or similar class.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are growing in popularity. Accommodation can range from simple rooms in a family house to beachside lodges, rambling country mansions or converted miners' cottages. Many offer quite luxurious facilities and usually include a full cooked breakfast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sydney and other cities offer an excellent choice of hotels for all budgets and tastes. There's plenty of budget backpacker accommodation in central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney</a>, particularly around the Kings Cross area, while more expensive boutique accommodation can be found in The Rocks and Darlinghurst. The state is well travelled by Australians themselves, and so offers an excellent network of accommodation outside the larger cities, mostly of motel or similar class.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sydney and other cities offer an excellent choice of hotels for all budgets and tastes. There's plenty of budget backpacker accommodation in central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney</a>, particularly around the Kings Cross area, while more expensive boutique accommodation can be found in The Rocks and Darlinghurst. The state is well travelled by Australians themselves, and so offers an excellent network of accommodation outside the larger cities, mostly of motel or similar class.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>In addition, New South Wales observes all the Public Holidays observed nationwide.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Queen's Birthday Celebrations :
							11 June </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 October </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-32.831001]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[150.139008]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>800,642 sq km (309,130 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>7.6 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>9.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sydney.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The landscape ranges from the subtropical, rainforest clad regions of the north to the Snowy Mountains in the south, which contain <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>'s highest point, Mt Kosciuszko (2,228m/7,310ft), prominent alongside glacial lakes and stunning valleys.</p>
<p>The southern coastline of New South Wales is home to 30 national parks, an abundance of bays, coves and dazzling beaches, especially around Jervis Bay and the Sapphire Coast. Contrasting that is the rugged outback territory found at Mungo and Mutawintji National Park, where previous settlements and old mining towns unearthed the mineral rich deposits of the area.</p>
<p>There are over 1,300km (800 miles) of coastline and four UNESCO World Heritage sites including Lord Howe Island, the Greater Blue Mountains area, Willandra Lakes and the Gondwana Rainforests.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The oldest and most heavily populated state in the country, New South Wales gives many travellers their first taste of Australia. It tends to be a potent one. Sydney&rsquo;s ravishing waterside setting and cultural vibrancy makes it one of the great world cities and its overall package &ndash; beaches, skyscrapers, Opera House and all &ndash; means it remains very much the centrepiece of the state (even, some might argue, the entire country).</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s a city to enjoy on your own terms. Lose yourself in the markets and coffee houses of the outer suburbs, laze in the open parklands of the centre, catch one of the ferries criss-crossing the water or tick off the big sights, from Bondi to the Harbour Bridge. History is a big draw here too, with much of the architecture harking back to the early days of settlement.</p>
<p>Heading out of town, meanwhile, one of the state&rsquo;s biggest natural draws lies just an hour or two away: the eucalyptus-hazed spectacle of the Blue Mountains. And there&rsquo;s more &ndash; much more &ndash; to enjoy once you travel further afield, from the country music vibe of Tamworth and the surfing outpost of Byron Bay to the winelands of the Hunter Valley and the under-visited national parks of the interior.</p>
<p>Whether you remain in NSW throughout your trip or using it as a springboard to travel elsewhere in the country, the state makes for an absorbing place to explore. And in Sydney, it lays claim to one of those heady, multi-layered cities that draw people back time and time again.</p><p>The oldest and most heavily populated state in the country, New South Wales gives many travellers their first taste of Australia. It tends to be a potent one. Sydney&rsquo;s ravishing waterside setting and cultural vibrancy makes it one of the great world cities and its overall package &ndash; beaches, skyscrapers, Opera House and all &ndash; means it remains very much the centrepiece of the state (even, some might argue, the entire country).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
