<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Austria" ColCode="aut" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="at" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Austria]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best time to visit Austria is June to September for those seeking sunshine and low rainfall, whilst November to March are ideal for those seeking winter sports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>European clothes according to season. Alpine wear for mountain resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vienna is connected to Graz, Klagenfurt, Linz, Innsbruck and Salzburg by Austrian Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aua.com/">www.aua.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A number of operators run cruises along the Danube, and from Switzerland (Bregenz) across Lake Constance. On some cruises, a passport is needed; they last from one to eight days depending on the itinerary. These services run between spring and autumn.</p>
<p><strong>Ferries:</strong> There are regular passenger boat services from mid-May to mid-September along the Danube and on Austria's lakes. The Danube services are run by DDSG Blue Danube Schiffahrt (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ddsg-blue-danube.at/">www.ddsg-blue-danube.at</a>) and private companies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&Ouml;sterreichische Bundesbahnen (&Ouml;BB)<em> </em>(Austrian Federal Railways) (tel: +43 51717; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.oebb.at/">www.oebb.at</a>) runs an efficient internal service. There is a frequent intercity service from Vienna to Salzburg, Innsbruck, Graz and Klagenfurt.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Vorteilscard:</strong><em> </em>offers a 45-50% discount on rail travel within a one-year period. This ID card can be purchased at all Austrian railway stations. The Vorteilscard Family allows four children under 15 to travel free when accompanied by a card-holding adult.<br />
<br />
<strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Austria. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Austria Pass:&nbsp;</strong>offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Austria. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Austria has an excellent network of roads.</p><p>National driving licences issued by EU countries, Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein are accepted, and enable holders to drive in Austria for up to one year. UK licences without a photo must be accompanied by some form of photo ID such as a passport. Car registration papers issued in the UK are also valid in Austria. A Green Card is recommended, but not compulsory if travelling from another EU country.</p><p>Tolls must be paid on all Austrian motorways and 'S' roads. Tourists can purchase either 10-day, two-month or one-year discs which are available at all major border crossings, newsagents, petrol stations, automobile clubs, &Ouml;AMTC and ARB&Ouml;, and at post offices.&nbsp;There will be a digital vignette available as of 2018.</p>
<p>Cars must be driven with lights throughout the year. Seat belts must be worn and children under the age of 12 and under 150cm (4ft 11in) tall may not sit in the front seat unless a special child's seat has been fitted. All cars must have a first-aid kit and a warning triangle. All motorists must also carry high-visibility waistcoats and wear them whenever outside their vehicle on an Austrian roads. Both driver and passenger on a motorcycle must wear helmets, and the vehicle must have lights on at all times.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 100kph (62mph) outside built-up areas and 130kph (80mph) on motorways. The minimum legal age for driving is 18.</p><p>All the major car hire companies are represented in Austria, with offices in most cities, as well as at airports and main railway stations.</p><p>Tolls must be paid on all Austrian motorways and 'S' roads. Tourists can purchase either 10-day, two-month or one-year discs which are available at all major border crossings, newsagents, petrol stations, automobile clubs, &Ouml;AMTC and ARB&Ouml;, and at post offices.&nbsp;There will be a digital vignette available as of 2018.</p>
<p>Cars must be driven with lights throughout the year. Seat belts must be worn and children under the age of 12 and under 150cm (4ft 11in) tall may not sit in the front seat unless a special child's seat has been fitted. All cars must have a first-aid kit and a warning triangle. All motorists must also carry high-visibility waistcoats and wear them whenever outside their vehicle on an Austrian roads. Both driver and passenger on a motorcycle must wear helmets, and the vehicle must have lights on at all times.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 100kph (62mph) outside built-up areas and 130kph (80mph) on motorways. The minimum legal age for driving is 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vienna has an extensive system of metro, bus, light rail<strong> </strong>and tramway<strong> </strong>services. Most routes have a flat fare, and there are pre-purchase multi-journey tickets and passes. The Vienna Card (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.wienkarte.at/">www.wienkarte.at</a>) entitles visitors to 24, 48 or 72 hours of unlimited travel by underground, bus and tram. It also entitles the holder to reductions at several museums and other tourist attractions in the city, as well as shops, cafes and wine taverns. The classic way to travel round the capital is by horse-drawn carriage (<em>Fiaker</em>); fares should be agreed in advance.</p>
<p>There are bus systems in all the other main towns, and also tramways in Linz, Innsbruck and Graz, and trolleybuses in Linz, Innsbruck and Salzburg.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Austria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">salzburg</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.18</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Austria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">klagenfurt</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.25</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Austria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">innsbruck</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.20</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Austria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">graz</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.45</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Austrian Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aua.com/">www.aua.com</a>) is the country's main airline. Other airlines flying to Austria from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and germanwings (<a href="http://www.germanwings.com" target="_blank">www.germanwings.com</a>) and Lufthansa (<a href="http://www.lufthansa.com" target="_blank">www.lufthansa.com</a>).</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/austria/innsbruck-airport">Innsbruck Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/austria/salzburg-airport-w-mozart">Salzburg Airport</a>,  <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/austria/vienna-international-airport">Vienna International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/austria/blue-danube-airport-linz">Blue Danube Airport Linz</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/austria/graz-airport">Graz Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>: to Innsbruck&nbsp;- 2 hours;&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/salzburg">Salzburg</a>&nbsp;- 2 hours;&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vienna">Vienna</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;2 hours 10 minutes.</p>
<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> to Vienna - 8 hours 25 minutes  non-stop.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Vienna International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.viennaairport.com<p>Vienna International Airport is located 16km (10 miles) southeast of Vienna.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+43 1 7007 22233</p>]]><b>Salzburg Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.salzburg-airport.com<p>Salzburg Airport is located 4km (2.5 miles) west of Salzburg city centre, and 2km (1.2 miles) east of the German border.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+43 662 85800.</p>]]><b>Innsbruck Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.innsbruck-airport.com<p>Innsbruck Airport is located 5km (3 miles) to the west of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ski/innsbruck">Innsbruck</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(512) 225 250.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&Ouml;sterreichische Bundesbahnen (&Ouml;BB)<em> </em>(Austrian Federal Railways) (tel: +43 51 717; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.oebb.at/">www.oebb.at</a>) operates a wide network of trains throughout and beyond Austria. International connections from Vienna include direct trains to Bratislava, Prague and Zurich.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Eurostar (tel: 03432 186 186, in the UK only or +44 1233 617 575; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.eurostar.com/">www.eurostar.com</a>)&nbsp;operates direct high-speed trains from London (St Pancras International) to Brussels (Midi/Zuid). From Brussels, you can take a high-speed ICE&nbsp;train to Frankfurt and a second ICE train from Frankfurt to Vienna.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 30 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country<em> </em>Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/montenegro">Montenegro</a>. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 27. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>) and InterRail (<a href="https://www.interrail.eu" target="_blank">www.interrail.eu</a>  or tel: +44 844 248 2481 <a href="http://www.myinterrail.co.uk" target="_blank">www.myinterrail.co.uk</a>). <br />
<br />
<strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 28 countries. Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (travellers aged 12 to 27) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents.&nbsp;Available from Eurail (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.eurail.com/">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>The Channel Tunnel:</strong> Eurotunnel (tel: +44 8443 353 535, in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.eurotunnel.com/">www.eurotunnel.com</a>) runs shuttle trains for cars, bicycles, motorcycles, coaches, minibuses, caravans, camper vans and other vehicles over 1.85m (6.07ft) between Folkestone in Kent, with direct road access from the M20, and Calais, with links to the A16/A26 motorway (Exit 13). All road vehicles are carried through the tunnel in shuttle trains running between the two terminals. The journey takes about 35 minutes from platform to platform and around one hour from motorway to motorway. There are up to four passenger shuttles per hour at peak times, 24 hours per day and services run every day of the year.<br />
<br />
<strong>Car ferry:</strong> There are regular ferry services across the English Channel. The quickest and most practical route from London to Vienna is via the Dover-Calais ferry (crossing time - 1 hour 30 minutes). The distance by road is approximately 1,600km (1,000 miles). It is one day's drive in summer, but can take longer in winter. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/munich">Munich</a> is 4-5 hours from Vienna; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/milan">Milan</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/z%C3%BCrich">Zurich</a> are a good day's drive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Call boxes are grey and found in all areas. International calls can be made from payphones with four coin slots.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is available throughout Austria. There are also many Internet cafes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Austria's public broadcaster, <em>&Ouml;sterreichischer Rundfunk</em>, has long-dominated the airwaves, but now faces growing competition from private broadcasters, particularly in Vienna. This is a relatively new phenomenon to Austria. Some German cable or satellite channels deliberately tailor their content for Austrian audiences. The print market is mainly privately owned, fiercely competitive and popular.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Letters within Europe take two to four days, and to the USA four to six days. Post boxes are yellow or orange; red stripes mean that the box is also emptied weekends and bank holidays.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1400-1800, and Sat various hours. Main post offices and those at major railway stations are open for 24 hours, seven days a week, including public holidays, though some services may be limited. Monetary transactions in all post offices permitted Mon to Fri until 1700, Sat 0800-1000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Belvedere Palace</p><![CDATA[<p>Belvedere Palace, situated right in the heart of Vienna, is Austria's most famous art gallery and home to der Kuss (The Kiss) which was painted by Gustav Klimt. There are two permanent collections – Oberes Belvedere (Upper Belvedere) and Unteres Belvedere (Lower Belvedere) – in the Palace. The palace was built by Lukas von Hildebrandt between 1714 and 1723 as a summer residence for Prince Eugene of Savoy. The two museums house an impressive collection of Austrian art from the Middle Ages through to the 20th century. Today, the Upper Belvedere is home to the Austrian Gallery and works by Renoir, Monet, Klimt, Kokoschka and Schiele, whilst the Lower Belvedere houses the Baroque Museum and the Museum of Medieval Austrian Art.<br /><br /><br /><br /><br />Address: Österreichische Galerie Belvedere, Prinz Engen-Strasse 27, 1030 Vienna, Austria</p>]]><br/><p>Famous Ferris Wheel</p><![CDATA[<p>While in Vienna, see the Ferris Wheel (Riesenrad) in the Prater amusement park, immortalised in the film <em>The Third Man</em>. Also worth a visit are St Stephen's Cathedral, the Chapel of the Hofburg, the Parliament and the Votive Church.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire Austria's architectural beauty</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Soak up Vienna's baroque elegance, notably in the First District (the Innere Stadt), and enjoy Salzburg&rsquo;s splendid Altstadt (old city), which features the Hohensalzburg fortress, a UNESCO World Heritage Site. Other sights in Salzburg&nbsp;include the Peterskirche (St Peter's Abbey, with cemetery and catacombs), the Domkirche (intended to rival St Peter's in Rome) and the Alter Markt (old market square).</p>]]><p><b>Bathe in award-winning lakes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take in the awesome panorama of some of Austria's beautiful lakes: they include Wörthersee, Wolfgangsee, Traunsee, Hallstättersee and Mondsee, one of the warmest lakes in the Salzkammergut region. Known as "Austria's Riveria", Carinthia's lakes reach temperatures of around 28°C (82°F) and are best for bathers having won several awards for their water quality.</p>]]><p><b>Celebrate classical music at Salzburg festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Listen to classical music in the city that produced Mozart. World renowned, the Salzburg Festival provides a varied programme, from singers, actors, orchestras and opera. Enjoy a concert at the House for Mozart or outside in Cathedral Square with its breath-taking baroque backdrop.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the delights of Tyrol</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the Tyrol, Austria's most mountainous province, with forests, pastures, valleys, mountain lakes, alpine villages, churches and castles. Innsbruck, the region&rsquo;s capital, has numerous historical buildings including a 12th-century castle. For spectacular views, take the funicular to Hungerburg and then the cable car to Hafelekar at 2,334m (5,928ft).</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy the country's coolest sculptures</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Witness the magical Eisriesenwelt in Werfen: ice caves, featuring wonderful ice sculptures all year round. These natural caverns are buried deep beneath the mountain wall that flanks the valley south of Salzburg and are accessible by cable car. As well as shimmering walls and impressive icicle displays, the caves offer uninterrupted vistas over the mountains.</p>]]><p><b>Get to grips with Graz on foot</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Graz on foot. Must-sees include the Universalmuseum Joanneum encompassing the Alte Galerie's gothic paintings, the Neue Galerie in the Herberstein Palace, the Cathedral, the Mausoleum of Emperor Ferdinand II, the old quarter, the Schlossberg (Castle Hill) with its Uhrturm (clock tower), and the Glockenturm (bell tower).</p>]]><p><b>Hike high and low in the Alps</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once the snow has melted, hike through the Alps' varied landscapes, ranging from forests and green slopes to glaciers and rocks. The Vorarlberg's alpine pastures provide gentle walks, while the Hohe Tauern National Park has more demanding trekking. For a long distance adventure, sweat the length of the Lech River – Holzgau suspension bridge has unforgettable views.</p>]]><p><b>Hold your nerve at Harakiri, Austria’s steepest ski slope</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Alps are one of Europe's major winter sport destinations, and keen snow freaks can go skiing, snowboarding, tobogganing, sleigh riding, curling and skating across much of Austria. However, only the bravest should test their mettle at Mayrhofen, where the country's steepest ski slope, Harakiri, leans at a vertigo-including 78%.</p>]]><p><b>Look good in leather at the Lederhosen Festival </b></p><![CDATA[<p>Admire traditional Austrian attire at the annual Lederhosen Festival in Windischgarsten.&nbsp;With wood-chopping races, ceremonial dancing and accordion playing, the festival is a celebration of Austrian custom. Although the wearing of the aforementioned costume is optional, drinking good beer and cheering at the election of &ldquo;Miss (or Mr) Lederhosen&rdquo; is compulsory.</p>]]><p><b>Paddle the Danube in the Donau-Auen National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the last major wetlands in Europe, this national park nurtures a diversity of plants and animals. A short drive from Vienna, the vast green space offers the perfect escape to the city with the winding Danube splitting the forest in two. Take a canoe downstream and enjoy the water up close.</p>]]><p><b>Play 18 holes in the Austrian mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Play golf at more than 150 courses in what is one of Europe's fastest-growing golf destinations. Settings to test your swings sway from the grounds of historic castles to alpine valleys and terraces. Check your putting in standout settings such as Schloss Schonborn, known for its manor house 19th hole, and Golf Eichenheim in Kitzbuehel for views across the Kaiser Mountains.</p>]]><p><b>Ride Austria's steepest steam railway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take an old 19th-century steam train and gaze at some picturesque Austrian scenery. Starting at the famous and beautiful village of St Wolfgang in Salzkammergut, Austria&rsquo;s steepest cogwheel rail pulls itself to the top of Schafberg Mountain. At 1,783m (5,850ft), riding the railway is preferable to making it up under your own steam.</p>]]><p><b>Sample the best of Austria's vineyards</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a tasting tour through one of Austria's wine-growing regions, such as Lower Austria or Southern Styria for their elegant Sauvignon blanc and the Burgenland. Most wines, such as the well-known Riesling wine, are white, but there also some good reds from Baden and Burgenland worthy of attention.</p>]]><p><b>See the striking stallions of Austria</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watch the famous Lipizzaner stallions perform finely executed dressage manoeuvres in Vienna. Set to Viennese classical music, the performances are held at the splendid Hofburg Palace. The Spanish Riding School, named after the horses' heritage, is also in the capital, while in Piber, visitors can see the stud farm where they are looked after, trained and ridden. </p>]]><p><b>Take to the lake for floating opera</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Attend the Opera in style: besides the many opera performances in Austria's major towns and cities, journey to Bregenz for a show with a difference. The Upper City is home to St Martinsturm (St Martin's Tower) and the world's largest floating stage for summer opera productions.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind with coffee and cake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax and watch the world go by as you submit to Austria's <em>Kaffeehaus</em> (coffee shop) culture: cakes and puddings (such as torte, of which there are around 60 varieties) can be eaten guilt-free, knowing that it is all in the name of upholding a national institution.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the birthplace of Mozart</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pay homage to Salzburg's most famous son, Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart. His birthplace (Mozart Geburtshaus) is in the Getreidegasse, also the city's main shopping street and is now a dedicated museum. So too is his family home (Mozart Wohnhaus) on the market square, where concerts and lectures are held alongside a permanent exhibition.</p>]]><p><b>Waltz the night away at the Johann Strauss Ball</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dance the hours away at a recreation of a traditional Austrian ball. Find out your most elegant black tie attire for the annual Johann Strauss Ball, which takes place in a beautiful ballroom in the Kursalon Vienna, one of Vienna&rsquo;s most beautiful and historic buildings. Guests are welcomed with a waltz and served fine dining cuisine before finishing the evening with a midnight concert.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$386.4  billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, metals, paper, and pharmaceuticals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cars, vehicle parts, refined petroleum, hormones and packaged medicaments. </p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Italy, Switzerland, USA, Slovakia, France, Czech Republic and China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Austria is one of the most prosperous countries in the world. Manufacturing, including mining, accounts for nearly 30% of GDP. Since WWII, much of the country's industrial capacity has been in state hands and only began to be removed from under the protective wing of the state holding company, OIAG from the 1990s onwards. </p>
<p>Tourism is a hugely important part of the Austrian economy, especially since joining the EU in 1995. Its agriculture industry is also extremely successful, with domestic products meeting 90% of the country's food needs. Austria has moderate deposits of iron, lignite, magnesium, lead, copper, salt, zinc and silver. Although there are some oil reserves and an extensive hydroelectric programme, Austria imports two-thirds of its energy requirements.<br />
<br />
The previously substantial trade with both the USA and the former USSR has fallen proportionally in recent years. Austria met the criteria for membership of the single European currency and joined it upon its inception at the beginning of 1999, adopting the Euro as its currency. Since then, in common with most of the EU, the economy has been sluggish. GDP growth rate was 1.5% in 2016, while inflation is at 2.04% in 2017, up from an average of 0.89% in 2016.<br />
Austria has 31 conference venues, including over 20 in Vienna. The provincial capitals of Salzburg, Innsbruck, Graz, Linz, Bregenz, Klagenfurt and Eisenstadt also offer convention venues, as do several health and spa resorts. Furthermore, there are approximately 70 hotels in Austria which specialise in the conference/convention field. For more detailed information, contact the Austrian National Tourist Office (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Austrians are quite formal in their business dealings. A working knowledge of German is very advantageous. Best times to visit are the spring and autumn months.</p>
<p>The Austrians, especially the Viennese, can be extremely formal to strangers. It is essential to address business contacts by their title, until familiarity is well established. English is commonly used in international business settings, but a few words in German (by way of introduction) will not go amiss. Business dress is not too formal in Vienna and it is possible to go to a business meeting without a tie. It is, however, better for business visitors to err on the side of caution in the first instance. <br />
<br />
Business hours are generally Monday to Friday 0800-1600/1700, with many offices closing slightly earlier on Friday at 1500/1600. Austrians greatly enjoy eating in restaurants and business meetings are often scheduled over a long lunch. Breakfast and brunch meetings are also becoming increasingly popular. However, business visitors should not suggest lunch as a location for a first meeting. <br />
<br />
Austrians tend to keep work and social life separate. Overtime and weekend work is rare. On those few occasions when you are invited to a business contact or colleague's home for dinner, a gift of flowers for the hostess and a bottle of wine for the host are essential, as is punctuality. Visitors to homes should also at least offer to take off their shoes upon entering. Business meals are more for getting to know people, so family and politics should be avoided in conversation.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1230 and 1330-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Austrian Business and Convention</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Wirtschaftskammer Österreich (Austrian Federal Economic Chamber)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 51450
					Website:http://wko.at/wien
					Address: ,Stubenring 8-10,A- Vienna,1010]]><b>Network (ABCN)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 5886 6350
					Website:http://www.abcn.at/
					Address: ,Margaretenstrasse 1,A- Vienna,1040]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Viennese cuisine borrows heavily from its southeastern European neighbours, most notably Hungary, Serbia, Romania and Dalmatia. Broth-based soups, dumplings, cheese spreads, and stewed and breaded meats are all commonplace, but the real star of the show here is confectionary.</p>
<p>Austria&rsquo;s desserts and cakes are renowned, and the lavish patisserie window displays, piled high with towers of tortes adorned with intricate icing, are photograph-worthy. Gourmet culture is particularly evident in Vienna&rsquo;s caf&eacute;s, where coffee-drinking has been raised to a high art.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Wiener Schnitzel:</strong> A traditional dish of bread crumbed and fried veal escalope.<br />
<strong>Tafelspitz:</strong> Boiled beef topside in broth, typically served with horseradish.<br />
<strong>Tiroler Speckkn&ouml;del:</strong> A fried bacon and bread dumpling.<br />
<strong>Palatschinken:</strong> Thin cr&ecirc;pe-like pancakes with savoury or sweet fillings.<br />
<strong>Liptauer</strong>: A paprika-infused creamy spread made from sheep&rsquo;s milk cheese, goat cheese, quark or cottage cheese.<br />
<strong>Apfelstrudel:</strong> Austria&rsquo;s most famous dessert consists of delicate layers of crisp pastry with an apple and raisin filling.<br />
<strong>Salzburger</strong>&nbsp;<strong>Nockerln</strong>: A baked vanilla souffl&eacute; designed to resemble Austria&rsquo;s snow-capped peaks.<br />
<strong>Sacher Torte:</strong> A dense chocolate cake with a layer of apricot preserve, served with a compulsory dollop of whipped cream.<br />
<strong>Mehlspeisen:</strong> The national term for cakes and puddings. There are around 60 varieties of torte, which is often consumed with coffee.<br />
<strong>Stroh</strong>: Potent spiced rum available in several variants, ranging from 40% to a whopping 80% alcohol.<br />
<strong>Gl&uuml;hwein:</strong> A warming mix of hot red wine blended with sugar, orange, lemon, cloves and cinnamon stick.<br />
<strong>Obstler:</strong> Fruit schnapps, usually very strong and relatively cheap.<br />
<strong>Wiener&nbsp;</strong><strong>M&eacute;lange: </strong>A small coffee similar to a cappuccino served with steamed milk and topped with froth.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>The main meal of the day is lunch. All restaurants have waiter service, as do most bars and coffee houses. Bills are settled with the arrival of drinks.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>On restaurant bills, a service charge of 10 to 15% is included, but it is usual to leave a further 5%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>16 (for beer and wine); 18 (for spirits).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Austria enjoys an enduring reputation for music, literature and the arts; visitors are just as likely to find Alpine New Wave punk-rock as they are yodelling. Nightlife is versatile, offering laid-back taverns, beer gardens and excellent <em>apr&egrave;s-ski</em>, trendy clubs and dance venues. Viennese nightlife offers something for every taste: opera,<strong> </strong>theatre and cabaret as well as numerous bars and nightclubs. There are cinemas of all types, some of them of architectural interest, showing films in different languages. A good way to spend a summer evening is in one of the beer gardens found all over Austria, and the wine-growing area around Vienna features wine gardens (<em>Heurigen</em>) where visitors can sample local wines in an open-air setting.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>High-quality goods such as handbags, glassware, chinaware and winter sports equipment are the cream of specialist items found in Austria.</p><p>Shops and stores are generally open from Mon-Fri 0800-1800 (with a one- or two-hour lunch break in smaller towns) and Sat 1200-1700. Big stores and shops in tourist resorts now open Mon-Fri 0800-2100 and Sat/Sun 0800-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of hotels in Austria, from budget bed and breakfasts to a plethora of&nbsp;luxury hotels.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of hotels in Austria, from budget bed and breakfasts to a plethora of&nbsp;luxury hotels.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of hotels in Austria, from budget bed and breakfasts to a plethora of&nbsp;luxury hotels.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;If European visitors or any of their dependants are suddenly taken ill or have an accident during a visit to Austria, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). Full travel insurance is advised for all travellers.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;There's nothing to mark out Austrian produce as particularly risky to general health. The tap water is also safe to drink.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Ticks often live in heavily forested areas during the summer months in some of the more easterly parts of Austria and can create discomfort and, in very rare cases, serious infection to people who are bitten. Tick-borne encephalitis is endemic and travellers likely to find themselves in wooded areas from spring to autumn should take a course of injections.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>National Day :
							26 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Austria is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragrance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices. There are no allowance restrictions on these tax-free items.</p>
<p>If arriving from within the EU, you must prove your goods are for personal use if you bring in more than the following quantities:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% or 20L of fortified wine or spirits up to 22%.<br />
&bull; 90L of wine (including up to 60L of sparkling wine).<br />
&bull; 110L of beer.</p>
<p>However, if you enter Austria from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/">Bulgaria</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia">Croatia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hungary">Hungary</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/latvia">Latvia</a>,&nbsp;Lithuania&nbsp;or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/romania">Romania</a>,&nbsp;the tax-exempt allowance for cigarettes is 300; any cigarettes in excess of this quantity are subject to tobacco duty.&nbsp;</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Austria by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco or a proportional mix of these products.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits over 22% or 2L of fortified wine or spirits up to 22% or a proportional mix of these products.<br />
&bull; 4L of non-sparkling wine.<br />
&bull; 16L of beer.<br />
&bull; Medicinal products sufficient for your visit.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to a value of &euro;430 for airline travellers or &euro;300 for other travellers per calendar day (reduced to &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Restricted imports include plant and animal products and endangered species.</p>
<p>Travellers may not import medicines other than prescribed drugs for personal use.&nbsp;</p>
<p>If bringing a weapon and ammunition into Austria, you must hold a European Firearms Pass. The import of certain weapons, such as knuckle dusters or pump-action guns, is banned.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (&euro;) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;2, 1 and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies and traveller's cheques can be exchanged at all banks, savings banks and exchange counters at airports and railway stations at the official exchange rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are accepted in large cities. However, some smaller hotels may require bills to be paid in cash.</p><p>ATMs are available throughout Austria, especially in the major towns and cities. Most accept all of the major bank cards, including Visa and American Express. In Austria ATMs are called Bankomats and can be identified by a sign with a green stripe above a blue stripe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are widely accepted. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in a major currency (Euros, US Dollars, Pounds Sterling).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon to Wed and Fri 0800-1230 and 1330-1500; Thurs 0800-1230 and 1330-1730. Different opening hours may be kept in the various federal provinces. The exchange counters at airports and at railway stations are generally open from the first to the last flight or train, which usually means 0800-2200 including weekends.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries. However, Romania and Bulgaria are currently in the process of joining the Schengen Area.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Austria is a signatory to the Schengen agreement.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-term Schengen visa: &euro;60/&pound;53.41. Reductions are available for nationals of a few countries and for children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-term Schengen visa: up to 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate or consular section of embassy; appointment required. All applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at the appointment. UK residents requiring a Schengen visa should apply to either the embassy in London or the VFS Global Visa Application Centres in Edinburgh, Cardiff, London and Manchester (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/austria/uk">www.vfsglobal.com/austria/uk</a>), which charge an additional processing fee of &euro;30 (around &pound;22, payable in Pounds Sterling). If applying at the embassy, you have to book an appointment online in advance via email (<a href="mailto:visa.london-ob@bmeia.gv.at">visa.london-ob@bmeia.gv.at</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow two to three weeks for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EU citizens staying longer than three months should register either with the state governor or the administrative district authority authorised by the state governor. See <a href="http://www.migration.gov.at">www.migration.gv.at</a> for details. Non-EU citizens must apply for a residence permit at an Austrian embassy/consulate before travelling if planning on staying in Austria for more than 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet from another EU country, the animal must have a microchip or tattoo, an EU pet passport and a valid rabies vaccination certificate. Animals from outside the EU must also have a microchip or tattoo and rabies vaccination certificate along with a veterinary certificate issued by an authorised veterinarian.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[47.589043]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[14.139993]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>83,871 sq km (32,382 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>8,741,072 (UN estimated statistic 2017)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>106 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vienna (Wien).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mountainous Austria is a landlocked country at the heart of Europe, bordered by Switzerland, Liechtenstein, Germany, the Czech Republic, the Slovak Republic, Hungary, Slovenia and Italy. The diverse landscape can be divided into five sections: the Eastern Alps (62.8%), the Alpine and Carpathian Foothills (11.3%), the Pannonian Lowlands (11.3%), the Vienna Basin (4.4%) and the Granite and Gneiss Highlands or Bohemian Massif (10.1%).</p>
<p>Austria's highest mountain is Grossglockner (3,798m/12,465ft) found in the Alps' Hohe Tauern range, and, on its way from the Black Forest in southern Germany to the Black Sea, the winding River Danube flows for approximately 360km (220 miles) through the country.</p>
<p>Nearly half of Austria is covered with forests, with the lower regions particularly densely wooded. Fir predominates above 488m (1,600ft), and gives way to larch and stone-pine beyond 1,219m (4,000ft); the Alpine foothills consist predominantly of arable land and grassland (above 610m/2,000ft); the Pannonian region is characterised by scrub and heathland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Approximately 64% of the population is Roman Catholic. As of January 2011, 64.1% of the population identified as Catholic. The most recent Church diocese figures indicated that almost 59% of Austrians attend the Catholic Church.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Austrians tend to be quite formal in both their social and business dealings. They do not use first names when being introduced, but after the initial meeting first names are often used. Handshaking is customary when saying hello and goodbye.</p>
<p>It is considered impolite to enter a restaurant or shop without saying <em>Guten Tag</em> (good day) or, more usually, <em>Gr&uuml;ss Gott</em> (common greeting which literally means 'greet God'); similarly, to leave without saying <em>Auf Wiedersehen</em> (goodbye) can cause offence. If invited out to dinner, flowers should be brought for the hostess.&nbsp;The Church enjoys a high and respected position in Austrian society, which should be kept in mind.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chancellor Sebastian Kurz since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Alexander van der Bellen since January 2017.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From the first human settlements in the Danube Valley, to the ensuing Celts, Illyrians, Romans and Bavarians, and then the noble Babenberg and the Habsburg dynasties, Austria is a land that has been ruled by many.</p>
<p>Perhaps the most influential of its rulers, however, was the noble Habsburg family, which used Austria as the cornerstone of their empire for an astounding six centuries. The first of many emperors from the house came to power in 1273, and by the 16th century, the Habsburgs&rsquo; holdings had expanded dramatically across continental Europe both through military conquests and marriages.</p>
<p>In the wake of the French Revolution in the late-18th century, a creeping nationalism spread among the people of Europe and the Holy Roman Empire was dissolved. Despite this new drive for independence among some of the empire&rsquo;s ethnic groups, the Habsburgs managed to hold onto power.</p>
<p>In 1867, the dual monarchy of Austro-Hungary was created in an effort to avoid the secession of an increasingly dissatisfied Hungary. This meant that the Habsburgs agreed to share power with the Hungarian government, divvying up the territory of the old Austrian Empire between them. Though Austria and Hungary was still officially one unit bound by the same ruling emperor, in reality, they had begun to go down increasingly divergent paths.</p>
<p>The Habsburgs&rsquo; 640-year reign was finally ended by WWI. Even before the conflict was officially over, various groups began to declare independence and in 1918, the emperor abdicated. WWII saw Hitler invade and occupy Austria, persecuting the country's Jewish community. Post Holocaust, Austria's Jewish community rebuilt itself, but to this day the Jewish population remains much smaller than before WWII.</p>
<p>After Austria's liberation by the Allies in 1944, foundations were laid for the Second Republic, which was formally established in 1955. Upon becoming an independent nation, the Austrian parliament declared permanent neutrality and, soon after, joined the UN. In 1995, Austria entered into the European Union, and also signed the Schengen Agreement, before adopting the Euro in 1999.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Vienna is home to the oldest zoo in the western world, the Tiergarten Sch&ouml;nbrunn, which began as a royal menagerie for Holy Roman Emperor Francis I in 1752.<br />
&bull; Because of its permanent neutrality, Austria is not a member of NATO.<br />
&bull; Vienna is home to more dead people than living; there are an estimated three million plus buried in the city&rsquo;s Central Cemetery, though the living population only numbers around 1.7 million.<br />
&bull; Austria boasts some strange place names including a town called Egg and a village called Fucking, which has been plagued by spates of signage theft.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Austria]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+43 1 716 130.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinaustria.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+43 1 716 130.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Jauresgasse 12<br/>Vienna<br/>1030<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Austrian Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 020 7344 3250.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.bmeia.gv.at/en/austrian-embassy-london/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 020 7344 3250.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Opening times Consulate: Mon-Fri 0900-1200&lt;br /&gt;
Telephone enquiries Embassy: Mon-Fr 0900-1700&lt;br /&gt;
Telephone enquiries Consulate (passports etc): Mon-Fri 1400-1600&lt;br /&gt;
Visa enquiries: Mon-Fr 1400-1600 (Tel: +44 20 7245 6689)&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Belgravia<br/>18 Belgrave Mews West<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8HU<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Austria in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b> +1 202 895 6700 or 6711 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.austria.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b> +1 202 895 6700 or 6711 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; Mon-Fri 1030-1300 (consular services).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3524 International Court<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite its small size, Austria has a long-established international reputation, which is why most visitors arrive with heads full of Habsburg, Mozart and Alpine visions. Some expectations are delightfully met &ndash; the mountain scenery is breathtakingly real, there are the omnipresent fingerprints of the old empire in Vienna, and home-grown musical icons Mozart, Schubert and Strauss are championed everywhere &ndash; but Austria also has a few surprises up its sleeve in the form of contemporary art, cutting-edge architecture and innovative cuisine.</p>
<p>Austria is frequently cited as one of the best places to live in Europe, and it is not difficult to see why. Remarkably safe and clean, it offers plenty of affordable culture, natural beauty and elegant Baroque and neoclassical architecture, as well as an efficient public transport system.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s also surprisingly varied. You can hurtle down a black run in the skiing paradises of Kitzb&uuml;hel and St Anton, or cosy up with a hot drink in one of Vienna&rsquo;s famous coffee houses. You can skate across icy lakes in winter or seek out wildflower meadows on summertime hikes. You can wonder at the intricate church interiors and the ostentatious opulence of the old Habsburg palaces, or indulge in a more low-key aspect of Mitteleuropa culture over a steaming goulash in a rustic country inn. Or you can ride a horse through pretty wooded tracts, get an eyeful of Rubens, Raphael and Rembrandt, and marvel at Hundertwasser House in Vienna &ndash; a fantastical housing complex characterised by its vivid patterns and mismatched colours.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t try to squeeze it all in though. More than anything, Austria is a place to recline, relax and relish. Its natural beauty is the result of many millennia of natural activity and its grand art, architecture and culture was painstakingly created by many hands over many centuries. These aren&rsquo;t sights to be hurriedly ticked off a list; allow yourself plenty of time to luxuriate.</p><p>Despite its small size, Austria has a long-established international reputation, which is why most visitors arrive with heads full of Habsburg, Mozart and Alpine visions. Some expectations are delightfully met &ndash; the mountain scenery is breathtakingly real, there are the omnipresent fingerprints of the old empire in Vienna, and home-grown musical icons Mozart, Schubert and Strauss are championed everywhere &ndash; but Austria also has a few surprises up its sleeve in the form of contemporary art, cutting-edge architecture and innovative cuisine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
