<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Western Australia" ColCode="was" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="wa" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Western Australia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot summers (December to February), mild winters (June to August). North is tropical. South is subtropical to temperate. Rainfall varies from area to area.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens in summer, warmer mediumweights in winter. Waterproofing is advisable in the wet season in the tropical north.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are international flights to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/western-australia/perth-airport">Perth</a> from Europe and Asia. International airlines serving Perth include Air New Zealand (NZ), British Airways (BA), Cathay Pacific (CX), Garuda Indonesia (GA), Malaysia Airlines (MH), Qantas (QF), Singapore Airlines (SQ), South Africa Airways (SA) and Thai Airways International (TG).<br /><br />There are internal flights from all state capitals. Domestic carriers include Airnorth (TL) (<a href="http://www.airnorth.com.au/" target="_blank">www.airnorth.com.au</a>), Northwest Regional Airlines (<a href="http://www.northwestregional.com.au/" target="_blank">www.northwestregional.com.au</a>), Qantas (QF) (<a href="http://www.qantas.com.au/" target="_blank">www.qantas.com.au</a>), Skywest (XR) (within Western Australia only) (<a href="http://www.skywest.com.au/" target="_blank">www.skywest.com.au</a>), Virgin Blue (DJ) (<a href="http://www.virginblue.com.au/" target="_blank">www.virginblue.com.au</a>) and Tiger Airways (TR) (<a href="file:///C:/Users/ruthd/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/Temporary%20Internet%20Files/OLKCC63/www.tigerairways.com/au/en/)" target="_blank">www.tigerairways.com/au)</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Perth is 20 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Perth Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.perthairport.com.au<p>Perth Airport is located 12km (7.5 miles) northeast of Perth.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+61 8 9478 8888.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Port of Fremantle (<a href="http://www.fremantleports.com.au/" target="_blank">www.fremantleports.com.au</a>) serves Perth. The Fremantle Inner Harbour port  is 19km (11 miles) from Perth.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transwa rail service (tel: (08) 9326 2600; <a href="http://www.transwa.wa.gov.au/" target="_blank">www.transwa.wa.gov.au</a>) serves Western Australia. The Indian Pacific service runs from Perth to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney</a> twice a week and is a three-day trip with beautiful scenery to admire as you <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/country/309/international_travel/Australia-and-South-Pacific/Western-Australia.html##" target="_blank">travel</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Aquarium</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watch rolling surf from wide expanses of white-sand beaches around Perth at Sorrento, Cottesloe, City, Floreat or Scarborough. If you want to see what lives under the waves, the Aquarium of Western Australia (<a href="http://www.aqwa.com.au/" target="_blank">www.aqwa.com.au</a>) at Hillary's Boat Harbour showcases over 4,000 creatures.</p>]]><p><b>Broome</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover Aboriginal culture in the northern Kimberley Region, Western Australia's main outback destination, which features a cliff-lined coast, rugged mountains, dramatic gorges, waterholes and tropical rainforest. The town of Broome is the jewel in the tropical crown.</p>]]><p><b>Darling Ranges</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gaze at the peaks of the Darling Ranges, behind Perth, which are popular with visitors and contain several national parks. At Mundaring, you can step into the Jewel Caves, which feature the longest straw stalactite in any tourist cave.</p>]]><p><b>Diving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go diving off Western Australia's long stretches of unspoilt coastline. Major destinations include Rottnest Island, Exmouth, the Abrolhos Islands (three groups of islands rated amongst Australia's best dive sites), and Dunsborough in the southwest (noted for its famous wreck dive to the HMS Swan).</p>]]><p><b>Feed dolphins</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hand-feed and stroke wild but amazingly friendly dolphins at Monkey Mia beach in the Gascoyne Region (whose nearby Shark Bay is also a UNESCO World Heritage-listed area and a habitat for turtles, manta rays, whales and sharks).</p>]]><p><b>Fremantle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Fremantle, 19km (12 miles) from Perth, a port full of superbly restored historic houses and buildings such as the Court House. The excellent Western Australian Maritime Museum (<a href="http://www.museum.wa.gov.au/maritime" target="_blank">www.museum.wa.gov.au/maritime</a>) is another attraction here.</p>]]><p><b>Guildford</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Glance at Guildford's wonderful old buildings, original homes and quaint antique shops. The town provides the perfect gateway to the wine-producing Swan Valley. <em>Houghton's</em> is a winery here well worth a visit, and great for a spot of lunch.</p>]]><p><b>Kimberley</b></p><![CDATA[<p><em>Australia</em>, the movie, was filmed in this region amid the landscapes of Carlton Hill Station, Cockburn Range, the Bungle Bungle Ranges and Digger's Rest. Take part in a cattle muster and retread the footsteps of the characters in Baz Luhrmann's epic film.</p>]]><p><b>Nambung National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Look at amazing limestone pillars in Nambung National Park: visit the Pinnacles, calcified spires around 30,000 years old, which jut out of the sandy ground and provide the perfect snapshot. The nearby town of Cervantes is popular for its beaches and beach fishing.</p>]]><p><b>National parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk along the challenging but sensational Bibbulmun Track (963km/598 miles, from Kalamunda to Albany) (<a href="http://www.bibbulmuntrack.org.au/" target="_blank">www.bibbulmuntrack.org.au</a>) or around the spectacular red-walled chasms, subterranean pools and waterfalls comprising Karijini National Park in the Pilbara Region.</p>]]><p><b>Perth</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See Perth's colonial buildings such as the Town Hall and Perth Mint in the perennially sunny city. Kings Park gives great vistas over the city and a wide arc of the Swan River, which winds its way down to Fremantle. The Bell Tower (<a href="http://www.ringmybells.com.au/" target="_blank">www.ringmybells.com.au</a>) houses a huge set of historic change ringing bells.</p>]]><p><b>Perth International Arts Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Treat your cultural side at the Perth International Arts Festival (<a href="http://www.perthfestival.com.au/" target="_blank">www.perthfestival.com.au</a>), the oldest of its kind in Australia. Over 300,000 people each year attend its diverse programme of theatre, dance, music, film, visual arts and literature events.</p>]]><p><b>Purnululu National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gawp at the imposing sight of the Bungle Bungle Range in Purnululu National Park, a 350-million-year-old massif with distinctive beehive-like natural domes. From a helicopter, the range is an especially imposing sight: a beautiful world of hidden gorges, pools and palms.</p>]]><p><b>Spot sharks and whales</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Swim with giant whale sharks, the world's largest fish, which make frequent appearances between March and early June at Ningaloo Reef, and whale watch in the Cape to Cape Region.</p>]]><p><b>Surf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Catch waves at some of the best beaches in Australia, many around Perth, such as Trigg, Scarborough and Cottesloe. World-class surfing destinations include Yallingup and Margaret River, whose ominously named beaches, such as Suicide and Grunters, should attract hardcore surfers only.</p>]]><p><b>Walk among the trees</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Step onto the Tree Top Walk at the Walpole-Nornalup National Park, where imposing giant tingle trees in the Valley of the Giants offer the possibility of walking 38m (125ft) above the forest on a specially designed steel-framed walkway.</p>]]><p><b>Wave Rock</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Observe a 2,700-million-year-old granite cliff, which at 15m (49ft) high and 110m (361ft) long with a spectacular overhang resembles a huge tidal wave. You can see Wave Rock at Hyden (<a href="http://www.waverock.com.au/" target="_blank">www.waverock.com.au</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Look out for whales and spouting blowholes in the first European settlement in Western Australia - Albany, founded in 1827. The area includes a natural bridge which has been formed by ocean erosions and provides an impressive-looking arch.</p>]]><p><b>Wineries</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Indulge in gourmet produce including marron (freshwater lobster), and boutique wine in the Margaret River Wine Region. There are also excellent wineries at Mount Barker and the Swan Valley, near Perth. All are open for cellar door sales and tastings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><br />The major convention centres are the Hilton Hotel, Hyatt Regency Hotel, Rendezvous Observation City Hotel, Sheraton Hotel, the Superdrome and also Burswood Resort and Convention and Exhibition Centre, only 3km (2 miles) from the city centre, with seating available for 2,000 for conventions or 21,000 for exhibitions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><br />
Businesspeople in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/western-australia/perth-airport">Perth</a> are generally less formal than in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney</a>. Small talk and humour are welcome and most people prefer to be addressed by their first names from first acquaintance. However, suits (and ties for men) are still expected - even in markedly hot weather.<br />
<br />
Perth people have a good service ethic and 'not a problem' is a frequent reply to any request. Work-related socialising (in the form of picnics, barbecues or cruises) is common and alcohol will flow freely. Similarly, liquid lunches come with the territory. However, smoking in any indoor place should be stringently avoided by visitors; laws came into effect in 2006 banning smoking indoors in public places.</p><p>Normal business hours are weekdays 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chamber of Commerce and Industry of Western Australia (CCIWA)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (8) 9365 7555.
					Website:http://www.cciwa.com
					Address: ,180 Hay Street,East Perth,WA 6004]]><b>Perth Convention Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (08) 9218 2900.
					Website:http://www.pcb.com.au
					Address: ,Level 1, 41 St Georges Terrace,Perth,WA 6000]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>A vibrant pavement coffee culture exists in Perth, and Fremantle's South Terrace is home to the aptly named <em>Cappuccino Strip</em>. There is also an abundance of international cuisine and lots of possibilities for Aussie dining experiences, such as eating fish and chips from a converted tram in Fremantle, sampling the excellent Asian food in Subiaco (Perth), enjoying a seafood barbecue in the bush or partaking in a culinary feast at a waterside restaurant along the Swan River.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Excellent seafood comes from the coast around Perth, including king prawns, rock lobster (locals call this crayfish), dhufish, jewfish or barramundi, and special freshwater lobster called <em>marron</em>. <br />
&bull; Tropical fruits are abundant - especially banana, mango and papaya.<br />
&bull; Pearl meat, a prized delicacy that consists of the shell muscle of pearl oysters.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Find mainstream drinking holes in Northbridge - a large entertainment district just outside <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/western-australia/perth-airport">Perth</a>'s central business district - alongside several nightclubs. Stylish bars and laid-back pubs can be found in Mount Lawley, Leederville, Cottesloe and Subiaco.<br />
<br />
Fremantle has an impressive collection of huge, character pubs. Microbreweries are also well worth a visit here. The six-level Metropolis (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.metropolisfremantle.com.au/">www.metropolisfremantle.com.au</a>) is one of the largest venues and you'll find clubs to cater for all music tastes, including mainstream, hardcore, gay and alternative beats. The substantial Burswood Resort and Casino complex (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.burswood.com.au">www.burswood.com.au</a>) is also only minutes from Perth city centre.<br />
<br />
Perth features lovely old art deco cinemas screen art house movies and, in summer, find outdoor cinemas set in lush parklands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The King Street precinct in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/western-australia/perth-airport">Perth</a>'s West End is full of designer name stores including Gucci and Louis Vuitton. Harbour Town has designer brands at discounted prices, with more to be found at the Colonnade in Subiaco.<br />
<br />
Head to Morely for a browse around the multistorey Centro Galleria, home to 220 retail stores.<br />
<br />
Best buys are Argyle diamonds, opals and Aboriginal art. James Street mall in Perth city is good for boutique shops, alongside Rokeby Road and Hay Street. Subiaco is also good for high-end fashion and decent souvenir hunting.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1800 (Thursday late night opening to 2100) and Sat 0800-1730 in Perth. General retail shops are not allowed to trade on Sundays except those within the central tourism precincts of Perth and Fremantle (shops open 1100-1700).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of hotels and motels in Western Australia, including 5-star<strong> </strong>(luxury), 4-star (deluxe), 3-star (standard) and 2-star (economy). Standards vary, but ensuite, TV, tea and coffee making facilities and a small fridge are usual.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of hotels and motels in Western Australia, including 5-star<strong> </strong>(luxury), 4-star (deluxe), 3-star (standard) and 2-star (economy). Standards vary, but ensuite, TV, tea and coffee making facilities and a small fridge are usual.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of hotels and motels in Western Australia, including 5-star<strong> </strong>(luxury), 4-star (deluxe), 3-star (standard) and 2-star (economy). Standards vary, but ensuite, TV, tea and coffee making facilities and a small fridge are usual.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>In addition, Western Australia observes all the Public Holidays observed nationwide.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Labour Day :
							05 March </p><p>Foundation Day :
							04 June </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-24.413300]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[121.079002]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,529,875 sq km (976,790 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2.6 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Perth.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Western Australia is larger than Western Europe. It has a relatively small population but is growing at its fastest rate in history. Demographers expect the population of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/western-australia/perth-airport">Perth</a> to jump to 2.1 million by 2021. It is bordered in the east by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/south-australia">South Australia</a> and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/northern-territory">Northern Territory</a> and in the west by the Indian Ocean, with the Timor Sea to the north. The west coast is nearer to Bali and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/indonesia">Indonesia</a> than to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney</a>, making Perth a viable stopover destination en route to the rest of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>.</p>
<p>There are vast wheatlands, forests and deserts, and several national parks. Kimberley, in the far north, is one of the oldest geological areas on earth; time and weather have formed deep gorges and impressive mountains, arid red plains and coastal sandstone rich in fossils. In the northwest, Wolf Creek Crater, is an immense hole left in the desert by a giant meteorite 50,000 years ago, while Bungle Bungles is an ancient sandstone massif covering 3,000 sq km (1,160 sq miles). Southeast of Perth, near Hyden, is the 2,700-million-year-old Wave Rock.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The largest state in the country, Western Australia also makes credible claims to being the most handsome. Occupying the entire western third of this vast nation, it stands in stark contrast to its eastern counterparts: coastal development hasn&rsquo;t occurred at the same furious pace as it has on the eastern seaboard, giving full billing to its raw national parks, relaxed coastal towns and rugged outback horizons. Western Australia&rsquo;s vastness is a large part of its appeal &ndash; this is a destination that occupies travellers at length.</p>
<p>State capital Perth is isolated from the rest of Australia&rsquo;s urban centres (and the rest of the world, come to think of it), but its laidback demeanour and ultra-modern skyline is much as you&rsquo;d expect from a prosperous, cosmopolitan city. Close by is the energetic port town of Fremantle, where you can come calling for the weekend markets, excellent seafood restaurants and ubiquitous caf&eacute;s.</p>
<p>Highlights elsewhere in Western Australia are nothing if not diverse. Travellers can sail with whale sharks on Ningaloo Reef, explore the majestic karri forests of Tall Timber Country, head into the stirringly feral lands of the Kimberley, sample the delicious fruits of the Margaret River wine region, take a scenic flight above the Bungle Bungles or gaze out along the never-ending sands of Broome&rsquo;s Cable Beach.</p>
<p>Western Australia as a whole is a vast and physical region, somewhere layered with millennia of human history and endless wraparound panoramas. It&rsquo;s not somewhere you&rsquo;ll want to rush through.</p><p>The largest state in the country, Western Australia also makes credible claims to being the most handsome. Occupying the entire western third of this vast nation, it stands in stark contrast to its eastern counterparts: coastal development hasn&rsquo;t occurred at the same furious pace as it has on the eastern seaboard, giving full billing to its raw national parks, relaxed coastal towns and rugged outback horizons. Western Australia&rsquo;s vastness is a large part of its appeal &ndash; this is a destination that occupies travellers at length.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
