<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Northern Territory" ColCode="nte" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="nt" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Northern Territory]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot most of the year; the Top End has two seasons, dry and wet, whilst the Red Centre has the usual four: summer, autumn, winter and spring. Coastal and some inland areas can receive heavy monsoon rain from October to March. The best time to visit is June to August.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens most of the year. Waterproofing is necessary in the northern areas during the rainy season. A warm sweater or jacket is advised for the centre during winter months, as evenings can be freezing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Northern Territory can be reached by international flights to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/darwin">Darwin</a> from Bali, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brunei">Brunei</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/east-timor">East Timor</a>, Europe, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a> and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>. There are several international carriers operating to the Northern Territory, including <em>British Airways</em>, <em>Garuda Indonesia</em>, <em>Qantas</em>,<em> Tiger Air </em>and <em>Royal Brunei</em>.<br /><br />There are several domestic airlines, including <em>Airnorth </em>(website: <a href="http://www.airnorth.com.au/" target="_blank">www.airnorth.com.au</a>), <em>Qantas </em> (website: <a href="http://www.qantas.com.au/" target="_blank">www.qantas.com.au</a>) and <em>Virgin Blue </em> (website: <a href="http://www.virginblue.com.au/" target="_blank">www.virginblue.com.au</a>), that cover the territory from all capital cities within <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> with connections from most other towns. Smaller commuter airlines connect some of the remoter areas within the territory.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <strong><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> </strong>to<em> </em>Darwin is 20 hours. Connections are available from most Asian airports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Alice Springs Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.alicespringsairport.com.au<p>The airport  is 15km (9 miles) from the city centre (journey time - 25 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Ayers Rock Airport</b><![CDATA[http://ayersrockairport.com<p>The airport is 7km (4 miles) from the Uluru (Ayers Rock) resort.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Katherine Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.ktc.nt.gov.au<p>The airport is 11km (7 miles) from Katherine.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Darwin International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.darwinairport.com.au<p>Darwin International Airport is located 13km (8 miles) from the city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(08) 8920 1811</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main port</strong>Darwin  (website: <a href="http://www.nt.gov.au/dpa" target="_blank">www.nt.gov.au/dpa</a>), the Northern Territory's only large port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main rail service to the Territory is by the <em>Ghan </em>from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/south-australia/adelaide-airport">Adelaide</a>, which travels to Darwin via Alice Springs; see <em>Getting Around</em> in the main <em>Australia</em> section for more information. There is no internal network.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From Alice Springs, the nearest major town in any direction is Tenant Creek, 504km (313 miles) away, and consequently any car or caravan must be in prime mechanical condition. During the tropical summer from November to April, travel in the outback is advisable only in suitable cross-country vehicles, as many conventional roads become impassable for 2-wheel drive cars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Kakadu National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Tumbling waterfalls cascade into crystal-clear rock pools in Kakadu National Park, bordered by the Arnhem Land escarpment. At Ubirr (Obiri Rock) and Nourlangie Rock there are fascinating galleries of Aboriginal rock painting, many dating back over 20,000 years.</p>]]><br/><p>Uluru</p><![CDATA[<p>Behold the intense colours of Uluru (Ayers Rock) (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.environment.gov.au/parks/uluru">www.environment.gov.au/parks/uluru</a>). Uluru is the world's largest monolith and plays an important part in Aboriginal mythology. Note that climbing the rock is considered a gross sacrilege by the indigenous people. The nearby Kata Tjuta, meaning 'many heads' and formerly known as The Olgas, is a series of 36 massive rock domes and a system of gorges and valleys. Visitors can walk through the Valley of the Winds and the Olga Gorge, and also visit the Uluru-Kata Tjuta Cultural Centre, which has exhibitions on local history and geology.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Experience desert life in Alice Springs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There's nowhere quite like Alice Springs, largely because of its back-of-beyond desert location. More than 25,000 people call it home, however, and it retains a cultural appeal thanks to some first-class attractions. Top picks include the School of the Air and the wildlife-packed Alice Springs Desert Park.</p>]]><p><b>Feel small at Uluru</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Little can prepare you for the scale of Uluru, the world's largest monolith and a hugely important part of Aboriginal spirituality. Note that climbing &lsquo;the Rock&rsquo; &ndash; while still possible &ndash; is considered a gross sacrilege by many. As of 26 October 2019 climbing Ayers Rock will be prohibited. The walk around its base is a fine alternative, and gives good insight into its multiple faces.</p>]]><p><b>Get multicultural in Darwin</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take in the tropical, multicultural charms of Darwin, the territorial capital. The city has benefited from recent investment and has some impressive modern developments – including a swimming lagoon and war museum – to offset its bar-heavy, small-town feel. Don't miss the twice-weekly Mindil Beach Night Market.</p>]]><p><b>Get wet in Litchfield</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Swim in one of the territory's many waterholes and waterfalls: recommended are those at Litchfield National Park, which sits a short drive south of Darwin. Crocs can be an issue at certain times of year, but alerts will be in place if this is the case. Otherwise, dive in and enjoy.</p>]]><p><b>Have a cold one at Daly Waters</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Have an ice-cold beer at the quirky Daly Waters Hotel, a historical pub and one of the oldest buildings in the Northern Territory, built in 1893 in a remote spot along the Stuart Highway. The bar is decorated in underwear left by past clientele, and there's often live entertainment in the courtyard.</p>]]><p><b>Head into the MacDonnell Ranges</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spreading east and west of Alice Springs are the rugged MacDonnell Ranges – split, in colloquial terms, into the East Macs and West Macs. Both hold plenty of reward, but it's the West Macs, with remarkable stand-out features such as Ormiston Gorge, that warrant the most time.</p>]]><p><b>Kakadu National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tumbling waterfalls cascade into crystal-clear rock pools in Kakadu National Park, Australia's largest national park. It's been listed by UNESCO for both its natural and cultural value, which neatly sums up the park's sweeping magic.  At Ubirr (Obiri Rock) and Nourlangie Rock there are galleries of Aboriginal rock paintings, many dating back over 20,000 years.</p>]]><p><b>Sail out to the Tiwi Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>By visiting the Tiwi Islands – a small offshore archipelago comprising of Bathurst Island and Melville Island, reachable by ferry – you'll be experiencing Aboriginal islands with a unique culture largely sheltered from the mainland (although that said, the locals are huge Aussie rules fans – try to time your visit with a match).</p>]]><p><b>Soak in natural hot springs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Few things are more appealing to a highway-fatigued road tripper than the prospect of a soak in natural hot springs, making the thermal 'bathtubs' at Mataranka deeply appealing.  The clear waters, with a constant heat at body temperature, surrounded by palm forest, are a recipe for refreshment.</p>]]><p><b>Spot crocs in the Top End</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go on a boat cruise and explore the waterways along Kakadu's South Alligator River or scenic Yellow Water Billabong, spotting crocodiles as you go. A fully grown 'saltie', seen close at hand in the wild, is an unforgettable sight. You may also catch a glimpse of the graceful jabiru (Australia's only stork) wading among the water lilies.</p>]]><p><b>Stop off at The Devils Marbles</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The long drive down the Stuart Highway holds a number of worthwhile detours, including the so-called Devils Marbles, impressively vast boulders strewn across a barren landscape north of Alice. They're close enough to the road to form an easy stop-off. Aboriginal belief holds that they were once serpents' eggs.</p>]]><p><b>Take a helicopter ride</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a scenic helicopter ride above Nitmiluk (Katherine) Gorge, one of Australia's great natural wonders. All 13 of the park's gorges – which follow on from each other in one connecting line – have their own colours and characteristics. Canoe hire and dinner cruises are also available.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Arnhem Land</b></p><![CDATA[<p>East of Kakadu – and utterly dwarfing it in size – lies the near-pristine expanse of Arnhem Land, a permit-only area that remains in Aboriginal hands. Various operators offer tours into the region, ranging from one-day excursions to multi-day fishing trips. It's a special and spectacular part of the country.</p>]]><p><b>Walk the rim of Kings Canyon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Often overshadowed by Uluru to the south, Kings Canyon is another epic natural formation in Australia's outback heartland. Get up early to walk the rim of the canyon itself, which affords stunning views across the landscape. Take a rest at the 'Garden of Eden', a sheltered green waterhole.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the Northern Territory may be little more than bushland, but the state is anything but a no-man's-land for food-lovers. The seafood around Darwin is excellent, and fruit such as mangoes and limes are grown in large quantities in the tropical north.</p><p>The Territory is also a good place to try traditional Aboriginal "bush tucker", which is far tastier than you might expect. Cattle stations are common in the outback, so beef is generally easy to come by.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Barramundi:</strong> A tasty fish found on most menus. <br />
<strong>Kakadu plum jam:</strong> A sweet conserve best eaten on toast. <br />
<strong>Quandong: </strong>A native peach with a delicate flavour, usually served stewed or in ice cream.<br />
<strong>Crocodile meat:</strong> Not especially tasty, but it&rsquo;s there for the curious. <br />
<strong>Mud crabs:</strong> Soft-shell crab, usually cooked with their shells on.<br />
<strong>Damper:</strong> Soda bread traditionally eaten by drovers.<br />
<strong>Mangoes:</strong> Grown in various parts of the Territory. <br />
<strong>Thai food:</strong> Particularly common in multicultural Darwin.  <br />
<strong>Bush tea:</strong> Made from native plants such as leptospermum, referred to as tea tree.<br />
<strong>Paul&rsquo;s Iced Coffee:</strong> Billed as &ldquo;the Territory's own&rdquo;, it is found across the state.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is plenty of nightlife in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/darwin">Darwin</a> with some of the best at outdoor foreshore bars where a beer and a flaming red sunset in tropical heat is unforgettable. The city also boasts the Skycity Darwin<strong> </strong>(<a href="http://www.skycitydarwin.com.au" target="_blank">www.skycitydarwin.com.au</a>), built in an extraordinary modern architectural style. This A$30-million casino complex also encompasses luxury accommodation, restaurants, discos and sporting and convention facilities and is surrounded by lush gardens perched along the shores of Mindil Beach.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Darwin specialities include opals, Aboriginal artefacts and outback clothing, which are also available in Alice Springs. You can also find unique, handcrafted goods in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/darwin">Darwin</a>'s markets, which are great attractions in themselves. Mindil Beach Sunset Market in Darwin is an incredibly popular market open from May to October and a great place to sample the diverse cuisine of the territory.<br><br>Didgeridoos are highly popular souvenir pieces in Alice Springs - and throughout the NT, but make sure you ask for a certificate of authentication and a practical demonstration of the instrument when you buy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Darwin, Alice Springs and Uluru (Ayers Rock) all have international-standard hotels and there's a good standard of hotel and motel accommodation in all the major tourist areas and centres of population.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Darwin, Alice Springs and Uluru (Ayers Rock) all have international-standard hotels and there's a good standard of hotel and motel accommodation in all the major tourist areas and centres of population.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Darwin, Alice Springs and Uluru (Ayers Rock) all have international-standard hotels and there's a good standard of hotel and motel accommodation in all the major tourist areas and centres of population.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>In addition, the Northern Territory observes all the Public Holidays observed nationwide.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>May Day :
							07 May </p><p>Queen's Birthday Celebrations :
							11 June </p><p>Picnic Day :
							06 August </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-18.488300]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[133.501007]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,349,129 sq km (520,902 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>244,500 (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>0.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Darwin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A wilderness stretching roughly 1,670km (1,038 miles) from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/darwin">Darwin</a> and Kakadu in the north to Uluru in the south and 1,000km (620 miles) east to west, the Northern Territory comprises nearly one-sixth of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>; it is the country's Red Centre that extends for miles.</p>
<p>The northern area is tropical with rich vegetation and a varied coastline. Beyond Darwin, 251km (155 miles) east, is World Heritage-listed Kakadu National Park, which is part of the 12,600-sq-km (4,500-sq-mile) area of Arnhem Land - an area of vast flood plains and rocky escarpments steeped in natural and cultural heritage. Aboriginal people have lived here for at least 40,000 years. Katherine township is 314km (195 miles) from Darwin and a further 30km (20 miles) northeast is Nitmiluk (Katherine Gorge) National Park with 13 gorges towering up to 60m (200ft) high.</p>
<p>The southern part of the Northern Territory is centred on the town of Alice Springs, which is almost at the geographical centre of Australia and the starting point of many of the Red Centre's unique and natural wonders, including Uluru (Ayers Rock).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It was as recently as 1869 that the settlement of Palmerston (later to become Darwin) was founded on Australia&rsquo;s north coast, breathing life into the Territory&rsquo;s modern history.</p>
<p>The region, however, was about as far from being new to human settlement as it&rsquo;s possible to get &ndash; indigenous inhabitants had occupied the land for up to 60,000 years. It remains somewhere rich in Aboriginal heritage, and a fitting place to learn more about the traditional landowners&rsquo; ancient if enigmatic culture.</p>
<p>It was actually the state of South Australia &ndash; having recently acquired the country&rsquo;s &ldquo;northern territory&rdquo; &ndash; that settled Palmerston, hoping to turn it into a trading post for the British Empire. Things began well with the 1872 opening of the Overland Telegraph Line (OTL), a remarkable feat of engineering that provided communication links from Australia&rsquo;s south to its north &ndash; and, by consequence, to the outside world.</p>
<p>The line would not have been possible without the pioneering exploits of John McDouall Stuart, after whom the north-south Stuart Highway is now named. More fortuitous was the discovery of gold at Pine Creek by workers erecting pylons for the OTL, which led to a gold rush that saw more settlers descend on the Top End.</p>
<p>By 1911, having survived a cyclone and changed its name to Darwin (a nod to the fact that the HMS Beagle once laid anchor here), the outpost had become a small but efficient government centre. The Northern Territory gained a hard-earned reputation as a place of individual spirit, extreme weather and larger-than-life characters.</p>
<p>Darwin took a battering from Japanese air raids during II, and it was partly a sense of panic over possible invasion that then led to the construction of the aforementioned Stuart Highway, which connected Darwin to another settlement from the OTL era, Alice Springs, and on to South Australia.</p>
<p>The Territory went on to prosper in the decades after war, before Cyclone Tracy rolled in on Christmas Eve 1974 and reduced much of Darwin to rubble. Since then, however, strong links with Asia, a robust mining industry and a growing awareness of the region&rsquo;s super-sized tourism offering (where else can boast the likes of Uluru and Kakadu?) has given it much to be optimistic about.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The Museum of the NT still exhibits a 780kg saltwater crocodile caught in 1979. Its name? Sweetheart. <br />
&bull;	The remote airstrip adjacent to the Daly Waters pub was formerly used by Qantas as a refuelling stop en route to Singapore. <br />
&bull;	On the lookout for aliens? Call in at Wycliffe Well on the Stuart Highway, self-billed as the UFO Capital of Australia.   <br />
&bull;	In WWII more bombs fell on Darwin than on Pearl Harbour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Proud of its muscular individuality, &ldquo;the Territory&rdquo; is where preconceptions of Australia&rsquo;s tough, time-carved wilderness find their fullest shape. From the ancient green plains of the so-called Top End to the natural wonders of the Red Centre, it&rsquo;s a region that deals in physical extremes. Travel here gives a far more untamed feel to the country than a trip along the east coast, and its relative remoteness is a big part of the appeal.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s not to say the Northern Territory is without its home comforts, of course. Capital city Darwin is a laid-back tropical city with an upbeat bar scene, some eye-catching new developments and a thick multicultural flavour. Hang out at beach markets, take a sunset cruise or delve into the city&rsquo;s remarkable history &ndash; more wartime bombs fell here than at Pearl Harbor. Famously, the city is also the gateway to the phenomenal Kakadu National Park, a vast swathe of land with a powerful indigenous heritage and wildlife ranging from crocodiles to sea eagles.</p>
<p>Heading south along the Stuart Highway &ndash; which runs the length of the state &ndash; obvious stop-offs include the likes of Litchfield National Park, known for its waterfalls and swimming holes; Nitmiluk Gorge, one of Australia&rsquo;s most dramatic kayaking spots; Alice Springs, a bold and fascinating city in the middle of the country; and of course the mighty rock formations of the Red Centre, most notably the genuinely breathtaking enormity of Uluru.</p>
<p>Across the Northern Territory, much of the landscape is draped in Dreamtime legend, so you&rsquo;ll also find numerous opportunities for bushwalking, &ldquo;bush tucker&rdquo; tasting or simply learning more about Aboriginal culture.</p><p>Proud of its muscular individuality, &ldquo;the Territory&rdquo; is where preconceptions of Australia&rsquo;s tough, time-carved wilderness find their fullest shape. From the ancient green plains of the so-called Top End to the natural wonders of the Red Centre, it&rsquo;s a region that deals in physical extremes. Travel here gives a far more untamed feel to the country than a trip along the east coast, and its relative remoteness is a big part of the appeal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
