<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="South Australia" ColCode="sta" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sa" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[South Australia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adelaide boasts a Mediterranean climate, perfect for enjoying the great Australian outdoors. Warm and temperate with long hot summers, short mild winters and low rainfall. The north of the state is searingly hot during the day in summer and freezing at night. One of the hottest places in the area is Coober Pedy, 863km (536 miles) northwest of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/south-australia/adelaide-airport">Adelaide</a>, reaching temperatures of up to 50°C (122°F).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens in summer, warmer mediumweights in winter. Waterproofing is advisable throughout most of the year, particularly during May, June and July.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International carriers operating to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/south-australia/adelaide-airport">Adelaide</a> include Cathay Pacific (CX), Malaysia Airlines (MH), Qantas (QF), Pacific Blue (DJ) and Singapore Airlines (SQ). Flights from Europe stop off in the Far East, usually <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malaysia/kuala-lumpur-international-airport">Kuala Lumpur</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangkok">Bangkok</a>. Adelaide is also linked to every other Australian state capital city. For more flight details, see the main <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> section.<br /><br />There is an excellent system of internal flights serving all regional towns, and the majority of flights are run by Rex - Regional Express (ZL) (flights to Kangaroo Island) (<a href="http://www.regionalexpress.com.au" target="_blank">www.regionalexpress.com.au</a>), Qantas (QF) (<a href="http://www.qantas.com.au" target="_blank">www.qantas.com.au</a>), Virgin Blue (DJ) (<a href="http://www.virginblue.com.au" target="_blank">www.virginblue.com.au</a>) and Tiger Airways (TR) (<a href="http://www.tigerairways.com.au" target="_blank">www.tigerairways.com.au</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Adelaide is 22 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Adelaide Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.adelaideairport.com.au<p>Adelaide Airport is situated 6km (4 miles) west of Adelaide city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+61 8 8308 9211</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adelaide (<a href="http://www.flindersports.com.au" target="_blank">www.flindersports.com.au</a>) is an international port, with regular visits from international cruise lines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adelaide, where The Ghan train calls en route to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/darwin">Darwin</a> (a scenic rail journey through a desert landscape), is a major terminal on the national rail network.<br /><br />The Indian Pacific from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/western-australia/perth-airport">Perth</a> also stops in Adelaide, while The Overland travels between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a> and Adelaide. See Getting Around By Rail in the main Australia guide for details.<br /><br />Other tourist services are the Cockle Train (tel: (08) 8552 2782; <a href="http://www.steamranger.org.au" target="_blank">www.steamranger.org.au</a>), a scenic trip on vintage steam locomotives between Goolwa and Victor Harbour on the Fleurieu Peninsula, and the Pichi Richi Steam Train (tel: (08) 8648 6598; <a href="http://www.prr.org.au" target="_blank">www.prr.org.au</a>) which leaves Quorn in the Flinders Ranges on a two-and-a-half-hour round trip.<br /><br />Adelaide's rail terminal is located at Keswick, a few kilometres from the city centre.<br /><br />Adelaide Metro (tel: 1300 311 108; <a href="http://www.adelaidemetro.com.au" target="_blank">www.adelaidemetro.com.au</a>) offers comprehensive suburban rail services across the city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Cage dive with sharks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Put away your fears and come face-to-face with one of nature's supreme hunting machines – a great white shark – by cage diving at Port Lincoln or nearby Neptune Island. It's an area with pedigree where sharks are concerned: scenes from Jaws were filmed here.</p>]]><p><b>Cross the Nullarbor Plain</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Flat, moody and massive, the Nullarbor Plain stretches for some 1,200 km (750 miles) across the bay known as the Great Australian Bight. Catch the train across its middle to understand its size, or ponder the edge of a continent as it suddenly drops 90m (300ft) to form the Bunda Cliffs, which tower above the Southern Ocean.</p>]]><p><b>Delve into the past at the SA Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tracing multiple millennia of local history, Adelaide's South Australian Museum includes exhibits as diverse as 10,000-year-old boomerangs, whale skeletons and gold nuggets. Its Australian Aboriginal Cultures Gallery has a superb collection of artefacts, and there's also an excellent fossils gallery.</p>]]><p><b>Dive with a difference at Mount Gambier</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take the time to visit Mount Gambier, a city built around an extinct volcano. The sights here include sinkholes, limestone coastal area and the Blue Lake, which boasts crystal-clear waters that change in colour with the seasons – for qualified divers, meanwhile, there's also the chance to dive in winding limestone caverns.</p>]]><p><b>Find a gem in Coober Pedy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fossick (sift dirt from working mines) for semi-precious stones at Coober Pedy, which produces 90% of the world's supply of opals. Fortunes have been made and lost in this extraordinary outback town where half the population lives underground to escape the extreme heat.</p>]]><p><b>Go underground in the Naracoorte Caves National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Step into the Naracoorte Caves National Park near the southeast border with Victoria and see stalagmites, stalactites, bats and fossils. The Wonambi Fossil Centre – where you'll need to go to book a tour – also has exhibits that shed light on the underground features. The remains of giant prehistoric wombats have been found in the caves.</p>]]><p><b>Go whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spot whales on the Fleurieu Peninsula around Victor Harbor and on the Nullarbor coast, where large colonies of Southern Right whales breed from June to September. And if you take the horse-drawn tram across the causeway to Granite Island, you'll have the chance to see penguins too.</p>]]><p><b>Head into the Adelaide Hills</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The part of the Mount Lofty Ranges nearest to the city is known as the Adelaide Hills, and a trip here gives the chance to take in wineries, wildlife parks and walking trails – as well as some cracking views. The one-time German settlement of Hahndorf is the main tourist hotspot.</p>]]><p><b>Look out onto Lake Eyre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Australia's lowest natural point is found at Lake Eyre, the enormous salt lake in the north of the state. Given its desert environment it's usually dry, but after heavy rainfall becomes a vast inland sea. Its bright salt crust makes it spectacular at any time.</p>]]><p><b>Meet Kangaroo Island’s fauna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spot wildlife in its natural environment on Australia's answer to the Galapagos: Kangaroo Island. You might see anything from penguins, koalas and wallabies to kangaroos, seals and sea lions. While you're here, try local produce such as marrons (freshwater crayfish) and the honey from Island Beehive.</p>]]><p><b>Sail the Murray River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Strap on some waterskis, jump onto a cruise or take to the tiller yourself – there's no bad way to experience the Murray River, which meanders for 650km (400 miles) through South Australia, having travelled from New South Wales and Victoria. River red gum trees line the banks, and along its length orchards and vineyards flank the waters.</p>]]><p><b>Sip wine in the Barossa Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Barossa Valley attracts around 60% of Australia's wine-tasting tourists – and you'll understand why when you're here. As well as producing a very nice drop (the Shiraz is particularly renowned), it's also a strikingly attractive area, with ample potential for cellar door visits and wine-based road trips.</p>]]><p><b>Step out into the Flinders Ranges</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set eyes on South Australia's immense belt of peaks and bushland, the ancient Flinders Ranges. It's a region of spectacular granite peaks and colourful gorges dotted with eucalyptus trees – there are countless great hikes on offer, with some picturesque villages serving as good bases for walkers.</p>]]><p><b>Take in a festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Indulge in a plethora of world-class festivals in Adelaide, including the Adelaide Festival of Arts, which features everything from jazz to classical theatre, and the diverse Edinburgh-style Fringe Festival. On a similar note, WOMADelaide showcases musicians from around the globe – Jimmy Cliff and Peter Gabriel are among past performers.</p>]]><p><b>Try surfing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Surf excellent waves off uncrowded beaches, particularly at Victor Harbor, Kangaroo Island and the more remote Yorke and Eyre Peninsulas (Eyre's Cactus Beach attracts surfers from all over the world). Elsewhere, Moana Beach is a surfing favourite along the Fleurieu Peninsula, while neighbouring Maslin Beach became Australia's first nudist beach in 1975.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In keeping with a reputation as the more conservative of Australian capitals, business practice in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/south-australia/adelaide-airport">Adelaide</a> is no exception. Business suits are worn by both men and women, and most colleagues greet each other with a handshake; business cards are exchanged between new colleagues. Most businesses and government departments require appointments to be prearranged.</p>
<p>Whilst Australia doesn't have a gift-giving culture, it is standard practice to provide a bottle of wine or a small dessert offering such as chocolate if invited to someone's home.<br />
<br />
Adelaide's major convention centres are the Adelaide Convention Centre and Exhibition Hall, Adelaide Festival Centre, Hilton International Adelaide and the Royal Showgrounds.</p><p>Business hours are from Monday to Friday 0900 to 1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Business SA</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (8) 8300 0000
					Website:http://www.business-sa.com.au/
					Address: Unley,136 Greenhill Road,SA 5061,]]><b>Adelaide Convention &amp; Tourism Authority</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (8) 8303 2333
					Website:http://www.acta.com.au/
					Address: ,Level 1/18 King William Street,Adelaide,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>With fertile lands and a benign climate in its favour – not to mention a now-weighty demand for quality local produce – South Australia has earned a reputation for its food and wine, specifically the latter.</p><p>The Barossa Valley, north of Adelaide, is arguably the best wine region in the country, and enjoys able local support from McLaren Vale, the Coonawarra, Clare Valley and elsewhere. The state's long ocean coastline also means seafood is a speciality.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>German-style delicacies:</strong> German settlers brought with them the likes of <em>mettwurst</em> (spicy cured sausage).<br />
<strong>Seafood:</strong> Try crabs, whiting, oysters, blue fin tuna and crayfish.<br />
<strong>The pie floater: </strong>Meat pie immersed in pea soup.<br />
<strong>Fruit and veg:</strong> Expect citrus, grapes, melons, tomatoes and greens.<br />
<strong>Lamb:</strong> Locally reared lamb is a specialty.<br />
<strong>Cheese:</strong> The Barossa Valley produces good cheeses, as well as wines.<br />
<strong>Chocolate:</strong> The state has numerous artisan chocolate-makers.<br />
<strong>Cooper&rsquo;s Pale Ale:</strong> an iconic beer from the Adelaide area.<br />
<strong>Red wine:</strong> Barossa Valley is particularly renowned for its shiraz.<br />
<strong>White wine:</strong> The Clare Valley produces excellent Rieslings, another German legacy.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The cultural life of the city is rich pickings with the Adelaide Theatre Guide (www.theatreguide.com.au) offering comprehensive pointers to the performance arts. There's always a multitude of entertainment to choose from at the Adelaide Festival Centre (<a href="http://www.adelaidefestivalcentre.com.au" target="_blank">www.adelaidefestivalcentre.com.au</a>).<br /><br />There is also a concentration of nightclubs on or around Hindley Street in the heart of the city, opposite Rundle Mall. Large crowds flock to the cosmopolitan atmosphere of the pubs and cafés in Rundle Street. It's worth a trip up to North Adelaide, which hosts many fine restaurants, bars and pubs along its tree-lined streets. The seaside suburb of Glenelg has a great selection of classy bars and waterside dining options.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rundle Mall provides the central shopping experience in the city; when opened in 1976, it was <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>'s first pedestrian mall. Here, more than 600 retail outlets offering a variety of boutique delights and even a discovery trail are part of the attractions.<br><br><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/south-australia/adelaide-airport">Adelaide</a> is full of antique shops, art galleries and stores that sell Australia's finest opals, handmade chocolates and stockman's hats. The central market, located adjacent to Victoria Square sells all kinds of produce, including fruit, vegetables, fish, cheese, meat, spices and other exotic delights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> has many hotels and motels including 5-star international hotels. Standards vary, but ensuite, TV, drink-making facilities and, sometimes, a small fridge is the norm. In addition, there are numerous holiday flats and apartments for rent. Further information is available from the South Australian Tourism Commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfast, farmstay and cottage accommodation is available throughout the state, particularly in rural areas. This type of accommodation is usually very reasonably priced and spacious.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> has many hotels and motels including 5-star international hotels. Standards vary, but ensuite, TV, drink-making facilities and, sometimes, a small fridge is the norm. In addition, there are numerous holiday flats and apartments for rent. Further information is available from the South Australian Tourism Commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> has many hotels and motels including 5-star international hotels. Standards vary, but ensuite, TV, drink-making facilities and, sometimes, a small fridge is the norm. In addition, there are numerous holiday flats and apartments for rent. Further information is available from the South Australian Tourism Commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Adelaide Cup Day :
							12 March </p><p>Queen's Birthday Celebrations :
							11 June </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 October </p><p>Proclamation Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-32.028900]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[135.001999]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>983,482 sq km (379,725 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1.7 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adelaide.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Except for the state capital of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/south-australia/adelaide-airport">Adelaide</a>, South Australia is sparsely inhabited. It is four times the area of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>. It is the country's driest state, a region of rocky plains and desert landscape broken by the fertile wine-growing areas, which include the Barossa Valley.</p>
<p>South <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> stretches upwards to the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/northern-territory">Northern Territory</a>, eastwards to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland">Queensland</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales">New South Wales</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria">Victoria</a>, and westwards to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/western-australia">Western Australia</a>. The countryside ranges from the beach resorts of the Adelaide suburbs including Henley and Glenelg to the vast expanses of isolated, semi-desert outback; from the craggy mountains of Flinders Ranges to the meandering Murray River. Offshore is the popular Kangaroo Island. Adelaide nestles in the foothills of Mount Lofty Ranges.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Indigenous groups had inhabited the South Australia region for between 40,000 and 60,000 years by the time the region was first recorded by a European &ndash; in this case Dutchman Francois Thijssen, who sighted the coast in 1627.</p>
<p>Almost two centuries later, English cartographer Matthew Flinders became the first to circumnavigate the Australian mainland, and encountered a French survey team in the waters off what is still known as the Fleurieu Peninsula.</p>
<p>It was the Brits who first established a meaningful European presence in the region, however, colonising the area for &lsquo;free settlers&rsquo; (i.e. not convicts) &ndash; locals still take pride in this aspect of their heritage.&nbsp;The colony expanded over the mid-1850s, with wool, wheat, wine and copper-mining industries helping to attract skilled workers, many of them from Germany as well as Britain.</p>
<p>It was in 1901 when, under Queen Victoria, the land of South Australia became an official state of the Commonwealth of Australia. By this time, Adelaide &ndash; which had been chosen as a propitious spot back in the 1830s after Captain Charles Sturt&rsquo;s successful navigation of the Murray River &ndash; was a fully functioning and progressive city, becoming one of the first destinations in the world to grant women the vote.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands of South Australians volunteered to fight in WWI, but the state itself suffered badly during the post-war Great Depression. Its fortunes were brighter after WWII, however, thanks in part to a large-scale migration scheme, which saw more than 200,000 overseas migrants settle here between the 1940s and the 1970s, helping to boost the economy.</p>
<p>The state had a role in the Cold War too, thanks to the establishment of the Woomera rocket range, set up by an Anglo-Australian agreement to test atomic weapons. The same site later figured in the US-led space programme, and Australia&rsquo;s first satellite was launched from the area.</p>
<p>In an illustration of the state&rsquo;s ongoing modern outlook, in 2014, Vietnam-born politician Hieu Van Le was appointed state governor, making him the first person of Asian heritage to hold such a role in Australia. One of his sons is named after South Australia&rsquo;s most famous sporting son, cricketer Sir Don Bradman.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Several scenes from the 1985 movie Mad Max Beyond Thunderdome were filmed in and around Coober Pedy.<br />
&bull;	Mark Twain, once a visitor here, described the Murray River as &ldquo;Australia&rsquo;s Mississippi&rdquo;.<br />
&bull;	The Heysen Trail, running from Cape Jervis to Parachilna Gorge, is officially Australia&rsquo;s longest dedicated walking route, at 1,200km (750 miles) long.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s a mystery why sun-soaked South Australia is so often overlooked by travellers. Endowed with generous helpings of culture, vitality and natural beauty, not to mention some of the best wine in the Antipodes, it&rsquo;s a region that waylays those who do visit for far longer than they anticipated. It&rsquo;s packed with variety too, from the wildlife-clustered greenery of Kangaroo Island to the harsh desert outback of the north.</p>
<p>Arty state capital Adelaide is the natural focal point. Consistently ranked among the most liveable cities in the world, it&rsquo;s renowned for its festivals, museums and live music scene. Locals still semi-jokingly take pride in the fact that it was founded by free settlers (there&rsquo;s no convict past here) and it&rsquo;s a genuinely cultured city, from its characterful cricket ground to its boulevard-style streets.</p>
<p>It is the wider state, however, that holds the most surprises. Visitors can stay in houseboats on the Murray River, hike the mammoth folds of the Flinders Ranges, visit subterranean houses in the wild-eyed desert town of Coober Pedy or take their time evaluating the wines of the Barossa Valley. South Australia&rsquo;s long coastline draws everyone from naturalists to surfers, while the region&rsquo;s much-lauded seafood includes specialities such as oysters, crayfish and prawns.</p>
<p>And while leaving the state isn&rsquo;t likely to be a priority, when you do have to depart it&rsquo;s worth knowing that Adelaide sits on two of the country&rsquo;s most fabled train lines &ndash; catch the Indian Pacific east to Sydney, west to Perth or hop aboard The Ghan and venture through the Red Centre to Darwin. Or just stay a bit longer.</p><p>It&rsquo;s a mystery why sun-soaked South Australia is so often overlooked by travellers. Endowed with generous helpings of culture, vitality and natural beauty, not to mention some of the best wine in the Antipodes, it&rsquo;s a region that waylays those who do visit for far longer than they anticipated. It&rsquo;s packed with variety too, from the wildlife-clustered greenery of Kangaroo Island to the harsh desert outback of the north. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
