<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Queensland" ColCode="qun" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ql" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Queensland]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Queensland straddles the Tropic of Capricorn which accounts for the pleasant climate throughout most of the region. Exceptions are the far north which is tropical and has a wet and dry season, and the arid western outback which is fiery hot in summer. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/brisbane-airport">Brisbane</a> enjoys an average of 7.1 hours of sunshine daily in the winter. The period between November to March is generally humid throughout the state, but sea breezes temper the humidity and make for perfect holiday conditions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens year-round. Waterproofing is advisable in the wet season in the tropical north.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several major air carriers serving <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/brisbane-airport">Brisbane</a> and Queensland, including Air New Zealand (NZ), British Airways (BA), Qantas (QF), United Airlines (UA) and Singapore Airlines (SQ). For more flight details, see Getting There in the general <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> section. Domestic carriers include Qantas (QF) (<a href="http://www.qantas.com.au/" target="_blank">www.qantas.com.au</a>), Jetstar (JQ) (<a href="http://www.jetstar.com.au/" target="_blank">www.jetstar.com.au</a>), Tiger Airways (TR) (<a href="http://www.tigerairways.com.au/" target="_blank">www.tigerairways.com.au</a>) and Virgin Blue (DJ) (<a href="http://www.virginblue.com.au/" target="_blank">www.virginblue.com.au</a>).<br /><br />QantasLink also provides services from Brisbane to assorted towns throughout Queensland.<br /><br />The extensive internal airline system means that Queensland is connected with nearly all major Australian gateways.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From<strong> </strong><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Brisbane is 23 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Brisbane Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bne.com.au<p>Brisbane Airport is located 13km (8 miles) northeast of Brisbane.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+61 7 3406 3000</p>]]><b>Cairns Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.cairnsairport.com.au<p>Cairns Airport is situated 7km (4 miles) north of Cairns city centre, in northern Queensland.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+61 7 4080 6703</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Queensland has its own railway system, run by QR (tel: 131 617; <a href="http://www.qr.com.au/" target="_blank">www.qr.com.au</a>). The main routes are the Sunlander and the Tilt Train which connect coastal towns from Brisbane to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/cairns-international-airport">Cairns</a>. In addition, other services, such as the Inlander (Townsville to Mount Isa), Westlander (Brisbane to Charlesville), and Spirit of the Outback (from Brisbane to Longreach), open up the outback to travellers. The main tourist services are the famous Kuranda Scenic Rail (Kuranda to Cairns) and the Gulflander (Normanton to Croydon). The main railway stations are Central and Roma Street in Brisbane.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sunshine Rail pass:</strong> allows unlimited travel on Queensland's rail routes. Passes are valid for 14, 21 and 30 days in first- or economy-class, offering excellent travel facilities for those intending extensive travel throughout the state.<br /><strong><br /></strong><strong>Wanderer Rail <strong>pass:</strong></strong> travel north of Brisbane or south of Cairns stopping where and when you like as long as you travel in one continuous direction. For more information about rail travel and passes, visit QR online.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Fraser Island</p><![CDATA[<p>Motor over to Fraser Island, the largest sand island in the world and 4-wheel drive to your heart's content. The dense tropical rainforests, gorges and freshwater <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/country/232/top_things_to_do/Australia-and-South-Pacific/Queensland.html##" target="_blank">lakes</a> shelter a diverse ecology. You can often spot whales, sharks, dolphins and turtles offshore. Stretching over 120km (75 miles) from tip-to-tip and covering an area of 165,280 hectares (408,423 acres), Fraser Island is the largest sand island in the world. Characterised by its stunning freshwater lakes, coloured sand cliffs, lush rainforests growing in the sand, secluded creeks and long, white sandy beaches, the idyllic island attracts thousands of visitors each year who come on 4x4-led camping trips or to stay in lodges including the new award-winning eco lodge, Kingfisher Bay, built on the island's west coast. Aside from its swimming holes, creeks and stunning natural beauty, other attractions on the island include the rusting wreck of the Maheno ship which ran aground during a cyclone in 1935 and the former logging camp of Central Station that's now home to an exhibition about the island's unique environment.</p>]]><br/><p>Great Barrier Reef</p><![CDATA[<p>Learn to dive and experience the subterranean splendour of the Great Barrier Reef (<a href="http://www.dive-queensland.com.au/" target="_blank">www.dive-queensland.com.au</a>), with visibility often as deep as 60m (200ft). Heron and Lady Elliot Islands are coral cays renowned as the best diving spots on the reef.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Aboriginal rock art</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Examine excellent examples of Aboriginal rock art among the escarpment country near Laura in the Cape York Peninsula. In Brisbane there are many places to appreciate and buy indigenous art including galleries in New Farm and the city.</p>]]><p><b>Adventure sports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Seize the moment in the adventure sports capital of Australia: you can practise paragliding and parasailing all along the coast; abseiling is possible in Lamington and Carnarvon National Parks; the Sunshine Coast and Mount Tamborine are the main destinations for hang gliding.</p>]]><p><b>Australia Zoo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Steve Irwin's legacy lives on at this unique wildlife park in Beerwah, 60km (37 miles) north of Brisbane. It's home to Asian elephants, a Sumatran tiger and, of course, a few crocs (<a href="http://www.australiazoo.com.au" target="_blank">www.australiazoo.com.au</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Brisbane</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sightsee in Australia's fastest-growing city, Brisbane, with its year-round warm subtropical climate. The Gallery of Modern Art (<a href="http://www.qag.qld.gov.au/" target="_blank">www.qag.qld.gov.au</a>) is superb and sits alongside the Queensland Art Gallery, Queensland Museum (<a href="http://www.qm.qld.gov.au/" target="_blank">www.qm.qld.gov.au</a>) and Queensland Performing Arts Centre at South Bank (<a href="http://www.qpac.com.au" target="_blank">www.qpac.com.au</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Bushwalk and tree climb</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bushwalk around the cooler southern regions: Lamington National Park has a well-maintained, graded track system in the McPherson Range, which features tall rainforests, waterfalls and gorges. Or take a walk on the Mamu Rainforest Canopy Walkway in Wooroonooran National Park.</p>]]><p><b>Daintree Rainforest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This World Heritage-listed tropical rainforest is the place to visit for eco-tours, crocodile cruises, mangrove boating or 4-wheel drive trips. At Cape Tribulation, where the rainforest meets the reef, guided jungle walks bring you into contact with amazing plant and animal species.</p>]]><p><b>Dive in</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Live your waterbaby dream: from surfing (try Surfers Paradise, the Sunshine Coast, and Bribie, Moreton and North Stradbroke Islands) to sailing round the islands and canoeing and sea-kayaking around the Great Barrier Reef, or simply lazing on a perfect tropical beach.</p>]]><p><b>Fraser Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Motor over to Fraser Island, the largest sand island in the world and 4-wheel drive to your heart's content. The dense tropical rainforests, gorges and freshwater <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/country/232/top_things_to_do/Australia-and-South-Pacific/Queensland.html##" target="_blank">lakes</a> shelter a diverse ecology. You can often spot whales, sharks, dolphins and turtles offshore. Stretching over 120km (75 miles) from tip-to-tip and covering an area of 165,280 hectares (408,423 acres), Fraser Island is the largest sand island in the world. Characterised by its stunning freshwater lakes, coloured sand cliffs, lush rainforests growing in the sand, secluded creeks and long, white sandy beaches, the idyllic island attracts thousands of visitors each year who come on 4x4-led camping trips or to stay in lodges including the new award-winning eco lodge, Kingfisher Bay, built on the island's west coast. Aside from its swimming holes, creeks and stunning natural beauty, other attractions on the island include the rusting wreck of the Maheno ship which ran aground during a cyclone in 1935 and the former logging camp of Central Station that's now home to an exhibition about the island's unique environment.</p>]]><p><b>Gold Coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Party hard on the yellow sand along the Gold Coast (<a href="http://www.verygoldcoast.com.au" target="_blank">www.verygoldcoast.com.au</a>). Surfers Paradise is a Miami-style high-rise strip overlooking a crowded beach. Zoom into the Gold Coast hinterland, one of Queensland's best wilderness areas.</p>]]><p><b>Great Barrier Reef</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Be gobsmacked by the beauty and size of the Great Barrier Reef, one of the world's great natural wonders. Stretching for 2,000km (1,200 miles) along the Queensland coast, it offers great views from both above and below, with unique plant and animal life.</p>]]><p><b>Great Barrier Reef</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn to dive and experience the subterranean splendour of the Great Barrier Reef (<a href="http://www.dive-queensland.com.au/" target="_blank">www.dive-queensland.com.au</a>), with visibility often as deep as 60m (200ft). Heron and Lady Elliot Islands are coral cays renowned as the best diving spots on the reef.</p>]]><p><b>Queensland's beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy some of the best beaches in the world. The Sunshine Coast has miles of untouched wilderness and beaches with surf. Mission Beach has 14km (9 miles) of white sand, while the expanse of sand and sea around Fraser Island is heaven sent.</p>]]><p><b>Skyrail adventures</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Skyrail Rainforest Cableway (<a href="http://www.skyrail.com.au/" target="_blank">www.skyrail.com.au</a>) just outside Cairns spans nearly 8km (5 miles) of rainforest, allowing you 90 minutes of canopy cruising with stops at Red Peak, Barron Falls and Kuranda stations.</p>]]><p><b>The Great Barrier Reef</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Great Barrier Reef is the most famous marine-protected area in the world and the largest UNESCO World Heritage area. Covering a geographical area of 35 million hectares (86 million acres) and stretching approximately 2300km (1429 miles) along the coast of northeastern Australia from Bundaberg to Cape York, the Reef is bigger in size than the states of Victoria and Tasmania combined. The Great Barrier Reef is the largest coral reef system in the world and home to approximately 400 different types of coral. It is also an area of outstanding natural beauty and home to around 1500 different species of fish, 4000 types of mollusc and many endangered species. There are also more than 30 historic shipwrecks in the area and a number of archaeological sites which are of Aboriginal origin. In 2005, more coral reefs were discovered in the Gulf of Carpentaria off Australia's north coast.</p>]]><p><b>The McPherson Range</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Appreciate nature in all its glory from lush green mountains to rainforests and scenic wilderness areas. Nature lovers will enjoy Lamington National Park in the McPherson Mountains, the volcanic plateau of Tamborine Mountain and the Currumbin Bird Sanctuary.</p>]]><p><b>Theme parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Unleash your inner child and visit a fun (or tacky, depending on your disposition) theme park (<a href="http://themeparks.com.au/" target="_blank">http://themeparks.com.au</a>), such as Sea World, Movie World, Dreamworld or WhiteWater World , all situated along the Gold Coast.</p>]]><p><b>Wintermoon Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This four-day music extravaganza is held over the long weekend in April/May and promises a unique experience in the foothills of Eungella National Park, watching a wonderful programme of music, dancing, song and verse (<a href="http://www.wintermoonfestival.com" target="_blank">www.wintermoonfestival.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/cairns-international-airport">Cairns</a></strong>: Cairns is a fairly relaxed waterfront town that draws tourists in by the thousands. Business negotiations can be formal, due in part to the city's popularity with Japanese business people and tourists, but there's still an all-pervading, easy-going attitude. Dress sensibly for the tropical weather. Business hours are generally 0900-1700 Monday to Friday.<br />
<br>
<br />
<br />
</br><strong><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/brisbane-airport">Brisbane</a></strong>: Despite the city's laidback demeanour, business in Brisbane is still business. Both men and women usually wear suits and you should arrange appointments in advance. Normal business hours are Monday to Friday 0900-1730, although an extended working day is common in certain sectors. During the week, business may be conducted over breakfast, lunch or coffee. Australian businesspeople are, on the whole, very approachable, quite informal and quick to use first names. Business cards are used. If invited to someone's home, a bottle of wine as a gift is the norm, or flowers and/or chocolates if your host doesn't drink alcohol.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Brisbane Convention and Exhibition Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (07) 3308 3000
					Website:http://www.bcec.com.au/
					Address: South Bank,PO Box 3869,Brisbane,]]><b>Queensland Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (07) 3842 2244
					Website:http://www.cciq.com.au/
					Address: 375 Wickham Terrace,Industry House,Brisbane,]]><b>Cairns Convention Bureau (Tourism Tropical North Queensland)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (07) 4015 1218
					Website:http://www.cairnsconventionbureau.com/
					Address: ,PO Box 865,Cairns,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The food of the area relies to a large extent on the sea and the subtropical climate for specialities in cuisine. In Fortitude Valley, New Farm and the West End, just out of Brisbane city centre, there are a number of European, and Asian restaurants, bars and trendy cafés. There are also excellent places specialising in modern Australian fare, which is usually a fusion of different cuisines, especially Asian.<br><br>Wineries are dotted around Queensland. The largest, Sirromet Wines, has an award-winning restaurant, while the 130-year-old Castlemaine XXXX alehouse brewery in Milton is worth a tour, especially on a hot and thirsty day.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Seafood is supreme in Queensland. Delicacies such as Moreton Bay bugs, mud crabs, king and tiger prawns, mackerel, sea scallops and fresh barramundi.<br />&bull; Delicious range of fruits, such as avocados, mangoes, pawpaws, pineapples, strawberries and bananas.<br />&bull; Native Macadamia nuts are found in all kinds of concoctions including desserts, and in salads.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although much of the tourist activity is centred on the beaches and the Barrier Reef, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/brisbane-airport">Brisbane</a> offers a wide selection of entertainment. Most of the large hotels have dinner and dancing facilities and there are several nightclubs in the city, especially in Fortitude Valley where clubs and restaurants abound. <br />
<br />
The West End of Brisbane is an excellent area for trendy bars, stylish caf&eacute;s and nightclubs. New Farm is also growing in popularity - Brisbane Powerhouse (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.brisbanepowerhouse.org">www.brisbanepowerhouse.org</a>), a performance arts venue with restaurants and a bar, has a magnificent parkland location overlooking the river.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good buys include opals, Aboriginal art and handicrafts, woollen clothing, sheepskin coats and wood products. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/brisbane-airport">Brisbane</a> is very good for Aboriginal art with galleries showcasing a wide range of works, usually for sale. Souvenirs of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> are easy enough to find along Queen Street mall, and you can find boutique designers with the latest fashion on Ann Street in Fortitude Valley. Queen's Plaza is full of designer shops, whilst Tattersalls Arcade and Brisbane Arcade are architectural treats, full of boutique wonders and tea rooms.<br><br>In Cairns, find 170 stores at Cairns Central Shopping centre, while speciality shops can be found at The Pier and Stockland Shopping Centre.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-2100 and Sat 0800-1700, although hours vary depending on the city. Shops in the Gold Coast, Brisbane, Sunshine Coast and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/cairns-international-airport">Cairns</a> are open on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International standard hotels are available in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/brisbane-airport">Brisbane</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/cairns-international-airport">Cairns</a> and the Gold Coast together with a high standard of hotel/motel accommodation throughout the state. You can obtain information regarding price and location of accommodation from Tourism Queensland. Motels are usually in (or on) the outskirts of towns and cities and normally offer self-contained rooms at reasonable rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are growing in popularity in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> and certainly in Queensland. Accommodation can range from simple rooms in a family house to beachside lodges, rambling country mansions or converted miners' cottages. Many offer quite luxurious facilities and include a full cooked breakfast. Eco-lodges and similar types of retreats are popular towards the far north of Queensland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International standard hotels are available in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/brisbane-airport">Brisbane</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/cairns-international-airport">Cairns</a> and the Gold Coast together with a high standard of hotel/motel accommodation throughout the state. You can obtain information regarding price and location of accommodation from Tourism Queensland. Motels are usually in (or on) the outskirts of towns and cities and normally offer self-contained rooms at reasonable rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International standard hotels are available in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/brisbane-airport">Brisbane</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/cairns-international-airport">Cairns</a> and the Gold Coast together with a high standard of hotel/motel accommodation throughout the state. You can obtain information regarding price and location of accommodation from Tourism Queensland. Motels are usually in (or on) the outskirts of towns and cities and normally offer self-contained rooms at reasonable rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>In addition, Queensland observes all the Public Holidays observed nationwide.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Labour Day :
							07 May </p><p>Queen's Birthday Celebrations :
							01 October </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-19.706101]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[145.774002]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,730,648 sq km (668,206 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4.8 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brisbane.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Seven times the size of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, Queensland is known as the 'Sunshine State', priding itself on an average of more than 300 days of sunshine a year. Within its borders lay the Great Barrier Reef, miles of golden sandy beaches, national park forests, vast plains, lush rainforests, forested mountains and extensive wilderness areas.</p>
<p>The coastal plains of the north reach out to the Gulf of Carpentaria. East of the Great Dividing Range there are a range of offshore islands which comprise the Great Barrier Reef and other coral formations such as the Whitsunday Islands.</p>
<p>Tropical islands and national parks lie north of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/brisbane-airport">Brisbane</a> while the Gold Coast reaches south. Further inland the ochre-red outback beckons, with former copper and uranium mining towns on the route west to Mt Isa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Life in Queensland is riddled with all the right sort of Australian clich&eacute;s: lazy barbecues, golden beaches, reef&rsquo;n&rsquo;rainforest, limitless sunshine and cold beer. It&rsquo;s a wonderfully diverse state, full of spirit and diversion and exuding a sense of life being lived at its rightful pace. What with the wildlife, the weather and the seemingly unlimited range of outdoor activities, it&rsquo;s hard not to fall for the place. Bungy-jumper, birdwatcher or beach bum, you&rsquo;ll find plenty to enjoy.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Attention tends to fall, naturally enough, on the coast. The Great Barrier Reef is the headline attraction, stretching along the coastline for 2,300km (1,429 miles) and serving up some of the most spectacular scenery in the country, both above and below the water. It can be experienced in a range of different ways, whether you&rsquo;re joining a yacht in the Whitsundays, learning to dive in Cairns or just taking a road trip up to the tropical north.</p>
<p>To the south, state capital Brisbane is the third largest city in Australia and a lively place to spend time, drawing plaudits for everything from its riverside setting to its food scene. In the surrounding region, meanwhile, Surfers Paradise caters for a party crowd, Noosa is a super-relaxed coastal refuge and Fraser Island lays on 4WD adventures. Heading inland, the craggy drama of the Great Dividing Range and the sweeping scenery of the outback hold highlights of their own.</p>
<p>From the postcard glam of the Gold Coast to the back-of-beyond beauty of its furthest reaches, Queensland continues to be the state that arguably serves up more quintessentially Aussie experiences than any other.</p><p>Life in Queensland is riddled with all the right sort of Australian clich&eacute;s: lazy barbecues, golden beaches, reef&rsquo;n&rsquo;rainforest, limitless sunshine and cold beer. It&rsquo;s a wonderfully diverse state, full of spirit and diversion and exuding a sense of life being lived at its rightful pace. What with the wildlife, the weather and the seemingly unlimited range of outdoor activities, it&rsquo;s hard not to fall for the place. Bungy-jumper, birdwatcher or beach bum, you&rsquo;ll find plenty to enjoy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
