<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Australia" ColCode="aus" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="au" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Australia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Australia is in the southern hemisphere and the seasons are opposite to those in Europe and North America. There are two climatic zones: the tropical zone (in the north above the Tropic of Capricorn) and the temperate zone. The tropical zone (consisting of 40% of Australia) has two seasons, summer ('wet') and winter ('dry'), while the temperate zone has all four seasons.</p>
<p>Spring to summer (October to March): Warm or hot everywhere, tropical in the north, and warm to hot with mild nights in the south. This is the classic tourist season, with northern hemisphere visitors looking to escape winter temperatures and soak up some Antipodean sunshine, although Australia is essentially a year-round destination.</p>
<p>Autumn to winter (April to September): Northern and central Australia have clear warm days and cool nights; the south has cool days with occasional rain but still plenty of sun. Snow is totally confined to mountainous regions of the southeast. At certain times, the southern part of the mainland (as well as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/tasmania">Tasmania</a>) can become seriously chilly, so be prepared to wrap up.</p>
<p>Drought is becoming more widespread with southeast <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland">Queensland</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria">Victoria</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/south-australia">South Australia</a> all badly affected.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights during summer months with warmer clothes needed during the cooler winter period throughout most of the southern states. Lightweight cottons and linens all year in the central/northern states with warm clothes only for cooler winter evenings and early mornings. Sunglasses, sunhats and sunblock lotion are recommended year round in the north and during the summer months in the south.</p>
<p>Should you arrive in the country without the appropriate clothing or equipment, however, it&rsquo;s generally no problem to find high-quality items to purchase &ndash; there&rsquo;s no danger of being left to choose from a substandard selection.   </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Australians rely on aviation to get from place to place in the same way that inhabitants of smaller countries rely on trains and buses. The network of scheduled services extends to more than 150,000km (95,000 miles) and covers the whole continent. Major domestic routes operate between all capital cities. Aircraft can be chartered by pilots who pass a written examination on Australian air regulations and have their licences validated for private operations within Australia.</p>
<p>The major domestic airlines are Qantas/QantasLink (<a href="http://www.qantas.com" target="_blank">www.qantas.com</a>), Jetstar (www.jetstar.com.au), Tiger Airways (<a href="http://www.tigerair.com.au" target="_blank">www.tigerair.com.au</a>), Rex (<a href="http://rex.com.au" target="_blank">rex.com.au</a>)&nbsp;and Virgin Australia (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.virginaustralia.com">www.virginaustralia.com</a>), which serve the major resorts and cities throughout Australia.</p>
<p>In addition,&nbsp;Airnorth (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.airnorth.com.au">www.airnorth.com.au</a>) operates throughout the Northern Territory and also flies to Broome in Western Australia; and several small airlines operate to the islands off Tasmania. Nearly all domestic airlines operate special deals at greatly reduced prices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Australia has 59,736km (37,119 miles) of coastline, including islands, and numerous rivers, lakes, inland waterways and inlets, many of which can be used for touring by boat. Various vessels are available for charter or passenger booking, from paddle steamers along the Murray River to deep-sea fishing cruisers along the vast Barrier Reef.</p>
<p>The Spirit of Tasmania (tel: 1800 634 906, in Australia only or +61 3 6419 9320; <a href="http://www.spiritoftasmania.com.au" target="_blank">www.spiritoftasmania.com.au</a>) is an overnight car-ferry service linking Melbourne with Tasmania daily.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Over 40,000km (24,850 miles) of track cover Australia. Rail travel can be slow and relatively expensive. For further information, contact Rail Australia (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.railaustralia.com.au">www.railaustralia.com.au</a>).</p>
<p>Two services span the continent from coast to coast. The twice-weekly Indian Pacific travels 4,350km (2,704 miles) from Sydney on the east coast to Perth on the west coast, via Adelaide. The journey takes three days and three nights, crossing the famous Nullarbor Plain. The Ghan travels 2,979km (1,891 miles) between Adelaide and Darwin, via Alice Springs. The service runs twice weekly in each direction and takes two nights. Both trains are fully air conditioned, with first- and second-class sleeping cars, a lounge car, bars and good restaurant facilities.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Other express service links (not always daily) from the state capitals are as follows:  <br />
The Canberra XPLORER connects Canberra with Sydney (4 to 5 hours). The Melbourne XPT runs from Melbourne to Sydney, while the Brisbane XPT connects&nbsp;Sydney with Brisbane. The Spirit of Queensland links Brisbane with Cairns in under 25 hours. The Prospector links Perth with Kalgoorlie (6 hours 45 minutes). The Spirit of the Outback runs Brisbane to Longreach via Rockhampton.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Discovery Pass: offers unlimited travel anywhere on the NSW TrainLink regional coach and train network, which covers more than 365 destinations across New South Wales, Victoria, Queensland and the Australian Capital Territory. Passes are available from NSW TrainLink (<a href="http://www.nswtrainlink.info" target="_blank">www.nswtrainlink.info</a>) for 14 days, one month, three months or six months.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Queensland Coastal Pass: allows unlimited stops in one direction between Brisbane and Cairns. Available from Queensland Rail (<a href="http://www.queenslandrail.com.au" target="_blank">www.queenslandrail.com.au</a>) for one or two months.</p>
<p>Queensland Explorer Pass: allows unlimited travel for one or two months across the Queensland Rail network.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s essential for drivers to be aware of the sheer extent of some of the distances involved &ndash; Sydney to Melbourne might not look like much on a map, but the route runs for a total of 1,041 km (650 miles). Sydney to Perth, meanwhile, is a whopping 3,869 km (2,418 miles).</p>
<p>Roads in more remote areas are often unsealed and only negotiable by terrain-equipped 4-wheel drive vehicles. Many see little or no traffic. If planning a journey on a road of this nature, make sure you have enough fuel, water and supplies to cope should anything go wrong. It is also advisable to let other people know about the route you are taking and what your estimated departure and arrival times are before you travel.</p>l<p>The roads between cities and towns are of a high standard. There are few multi-lane highways, but major arteries are generally sealed two-lane roads. Road signs are international.</p><p>Greyhound Australia (1300 473 946, in Australia only; <a href="http://www.greyhound.com.au" target="_blank">www.greyhound.com.au</a>) operates services throughout the country.</p><p>Taxis are generally easy to arrange in all towns and cities, and as a rule offer a safe, reasonably priced alternative to public transport.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required by nationals of countries whose official language is not English. International, foreign or national driving permits are generally valid for three months. An International Driving Permit is only valid in conjunction with a valid national licence. Permits must be carried at all times while driving.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 16 to 18 years, depending on the state. The speed limit is 40-50kph (25-31mph) in built-up areas of cities and towns, unless otherwise signed and 80-110kph (50-68mph) on country roads and highways. Seat belts must be worn at all times and driving licences must be in the driver's possession when driving.</p><p>There are various state automobile clubs which offer roadside assistance. They charge a membership fee, but are generally invaluable in emergencies. The overarching body is the Australian Automobile Association (<a href="http://www.aaa.asn.au" target="_blank">www.aaa.asn.au</a>) while state-specific bodies are the AANT (<a href="http://www.aant.com.au" target="_blank">www.aant.com.au</a>) for the Northern Territories, the NRMA (<a href="http://www.mynrma.com.au" target="_blank">www.mynrma.com.au</a>) for NSW and ACT, the RAC (<a href="http://www.rac.com.au" target="_blank">www.rac.com.au</a>) for Western Australia, the RACQ (<a href="http://www.racq.com.au" target="_blank">www.racq.com.au</a>) for Queensland, the RACT (<a href="http://www.ract.com.au" target="_blank">www.ract.com.au</a>) for Tasmania and the RACV (<a href="http://www.racv.com.au" target="_blank">www.racv.com.au</a>) for Victoria.</p><p>Major international and some local car hire companies are available at all major airports and big hotels to those over 21 years old who have held a licence for a year or more. Surcharges may apply to drivers under 25 years old.</p><p>Bike hire is widely available in towns and cities. It is perfectly possible to cycle between major centres in Australia, although the distance from A to B, and the often unforgiving heat, are factors that may deter some.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 16 to 18 years, depending on the state. The speed limit is 40-50kph (25-31mph) in built-up areas of cities and towns, unless otherwise signed and 80-110kph (50-68mph) on country roads and highways. Seat belts must be worn at all times and driving licences must be in the driver's possession when driving.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Comprehensive public transport systems are provided in all the main towns. The state capitals have suburban rail networks, those in Sydney and Melbourne being particularly extensive; trams run in Melbourne and, to a lesser degree, in Adelaide.</p>
<p>Meter-operated taxis can be found in all major cities and towns. There is a minimum 'flagfall charge' and then a charge for the distance travelled. An extra airport charge is sometimes levied. Taxi drivers do not expect to be tipped. A small additional payment may be required for luggage and telephone bookings. Some taxis accept payment by credit card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Australia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">perth</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">66.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Australia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">melbourne</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">11.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Australia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">brisbane</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">15.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Australia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">adelaide</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">24.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Qantas (<a href="http://www.qantas.com" target="_blank">www.qantas.com</a>) is&nbsp;Australia's flag carrier airline and operates routes between Australia and the UK, USA, China, Japan, Thailand, South Africa, Philippines,&nbsp;New Zealand, Hong Kong, Chile, Singapore and Canada.</p>
<p>A large number of international airlines offer flights to Australia, including British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and Singapore Airlines (<a href="http://www.singaporeair.com" target="_blank">www.singaporeair.com</a>).</p>
<p>The cheapest time of year to fly is generally in the window between the end of Easter and the beginning of July, which coincides with the onset of winter in Australia. Bear in mind that there is only a non-stop flight from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/perth">Perth</a>. For travelling to other destinations in Australia from Europe, your plane needs to stop somewhere en route &ndash; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hong-kong">Hong Kong</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/taiwan">Taiwan</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dubai">Dubai</a> are all commonly used.</p>
<p>Budget airlines such as Tigerair (<a href="http://www.tigerairways.com" target="_blank">www.tigerairways.com</a>) offer flights to Australia from South East Asia.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/brisbane-airport">Brisbane Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/cairns-international-airport">Cairns Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/south-australia/adelaide-airport">Adelaide Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/western-australia/perth-airport">Perth Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brisbane">Brisbane</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> -&nbsp;22 to 24 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a> - 13 hours; <a href=/i/new-york-city">New York</a> - 22 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>
<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/melbourne">Melbourne</a>: from London -&nbsp;22 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); Los Angeles - 14 hours 30 minutes; New York - 23 hours (including stopover).</p>
<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/perth">Perth</a>: from London - 19 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); New York - 25 hours (including stopover); Los Angeles - 22 hours (including stopover).</p>
<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sydney">Sydney</a>: from London -&nbsp;22 hours (including stopover); New York - 24 hours (including stopover); Los Angeles - 15 hours (non-stop).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Adelaide Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.adelaideairport.com.au<p>Adelaide Airport is situated 6km (4 miles) west of Adelaide city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+61 8 8308 9211</p>]]><b>Brisbane Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bne.com.au<p>Brisbane Airport is located 13km (8 miles) northeast of Brisbane.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+61 7 3406 3000</p>]]><b>Melbourne Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.melbourneairport.com.au<p>Melbourne Airport is located 25km (15 miles) northwest of Melbourne.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+61 3 9297 1600</p>]]><b>Perth Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.perthairport.com.au<p>Perth Airport is located 12km (7.5 miles) northeast of Perth.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+61 8 9478 8888.</p>]]><b>Sydney Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.sydneyairport.com.au<p>Sydney Airport is located 9km (6 miles) south of central Sydney.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+61 2 9667 9111</p>]]><b>Cairns Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.cairnsairport.com.au<p>Cairns Airport is situated 7km (4 miles) north of Cairns city centre, in northern Queensland.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+61 7 4080 6703</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cruise liners dock at Sydney (<a href="http://www.sydneyports.com.au" target="_blank">www.sydneyports.com.au</a>), Melbourne (<a href="http://www.portofmelbourne.com" target="_blank">www.portofmelbourne.com</a>), Hobart (<a href="http://www.tasports.com.au" target="_blank">www.tasports.com.au</a>), Perth (Port of Fremantle) (<a href="http://www.fremantleports.com.au" target="_blank">www.fremantleports.com.au</a>), Adelaide (<a href="http://www.flindersports.com.au" target="_blank">www.flindersports.com.au</a>), Brisbane (<a href="http://www.portbris.com.au" target="_blank">www.portbris.com.au</a>) and Darwin (<a href="http://www.darwinport.nt.gov.au" target="_blank">www.darwinport.nt.gov.au</a>).</p>
<p>It's often possible to arrange passage to Australia from the UK or other parts of Europe on cargo freighters, travelling via the Suez Canal. A journey of this type takes between 30 and 40 days. There are fairly low limits on the number of passengers that can be accommodated on a freighter &ndash; usually somewhere around 12 or 15. Meals are often taken with the ship officers, and passengers should (unsurprisingly) expect fewer leisure facilities than would be found on a standard cruise vessel. A good company to contact for further information on travelling by freighter is Strand Voyages in London (<a href="http://www.strandtravelltd.co.uk" target="_blank">www.strandtravelltd.co.uk</a>).</p>
<p>For those travellers already in Asia and looking to arrive by sea, spaces occasionally become available on freighters travelling from Singapore, Indonesia or Malaysia. These sailings are, however, infrequent and notoriously difficult to confirm in advance.</p><p>The season that draws the most cruise ships is the November to February period, which ties in with the Australian summer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Payhone phonecards are available at newsagents, supermarkets and chemists and can be used for local or international calls. Most payphones also accept coins. You can send text messages to Australian mobiles from almost half of all payphones.</p>
<p>Creditphones, which take most major credit cards, can be found at airports, city-centre locations and many hotels. Multimedia payphones are available in parts of Melbourne and Sydney. A touch screen allows you to gain access to information services, including tourist information which can be printed off for future reference. You can buy phonecards for these telephones from nearby shops. You can also make Skype calls from many internet caf&eacute;s.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. US handsets are not compatible. Coverage is good in and around populated areas; access in some of the more isolated, outback and rural areas is limited. In 2014, however, the Australian Government started the Mobile Black Spot Program to improve mobile phone coverage in remote Australia along transport routes, in small communities and locations prone to natural disasters.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available throughout Australia. Internet cafés are prevalent in all capital cities and tourist towns, and individual hotels may also provide facilities. Wi-Fi access is increasing in cities and is mainly found in hotels, bars and cafés. Some public institutions such as universities have also began to offer free Wi-Fi services to the public.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is good freedom of the press. The biggest-selling nationwide newspaper is The Australian (<a href="http://www.theaustralian.com.au" target="_blank">www.theaustralian.com.au</a>), although regional newspapers actually enjoy higher readerships. The most notable of these are The Sydney Morning Herald (<a href="http://www.smh.com.au" target="_blank">www.smh.com.au</a>) and The Daily Telegraph (<a href="http://www.dailytelegraph.com.au" target="_blank">www.dailytelegraph.com.au</a>) (both Sydney-based) and The Herald Sun (<a href="http://www.heraldsun.com.au" target="_blank">www.heraldsun.com.au</a>) and The Age (<a href="http://theage.com.au" target="_blank">theage.com.au</a>) (both Melbourne-based). There are two publicly funded media outlets &ndash; the Australian Broadcasting Corporation (ABC) (<a href="http://abc.net.au" target="_blank">abc.net.au</a>) and the Special Broadcasting Service (SBS) (<a href="http://sbs.com.au" target="_blank">sbs.com.au</a>). They both broadcast on free-to-air television, radio and online. Almost everywhere in the country also receives three commercial television stations &ndash; the Nine Network, the Seven Network and Channel Ten. Increasingly, Australians are getting their news from websites such as news.com.au, Daily Mail Australia, Yahoo7 News, and nine.com.au, in addition to the popular newspapers&rsquo; websites.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are post offices in all the main towns of every state. Stamps are often available at hotel and motel reception areas and selected newsagents.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700; some post office are also open Sat 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Canoe Nitmiluk Gorge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Also known as Katherine Gorge, this spectacular canyon system lies in the Northern Territory and rewards those who make the trip with one of the most memorable canoeing adventures in the country. The gorge is sacred to local indigenous groups. Choose from a few hours' hire to a multi-day trip.</p>]]><p><b>Dive the Great Barrier Reef</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Australia's east coast is brimming with mainstream tourist hotspots, from the brash hedonism of Surfer's Paradise to the 4-wheel-drive-friendly Fraser Island, but for most leisure visitors it's the Great Barrier Reef that remains the must-see sight. It's vast (2,300km/1,430 miles long, to be precise) and is arguably best experienced through diving and sailing trips to the Whitsunday Islands.</p>]]><p><b>Drive the Gibb River Road</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you're looking for outback adventure, there are few better options than this 600km (370-mile) road across the Kimberley. Venerated by enthusiasts for both its rugged scenery and its challenging conditions, it can only be negotiated by 4-wheel drive vehicle. There's a shorter 'tourist loop' at the western end of the road.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Melbourne</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Some cities just get it right. And Melbourne is one of them, giving visitors everything from Victorian-era architecture to cutting-edge counterculture, while also placing plenty of importance on food, festivals, the great outdoors and sport. A month or so here, among the laneway bars and street markets, and you'll be praising the city for life.</p>]]><p><b>Fly over the Bungle Bungles</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Australia knows all about otherworldly landscapes, but the orange-striped beehive domes of the Bungle Bungle Range – high up in Western Australia in Purnululu National Park – is one of the most extraordinary examples in the country.  Take a scenic flight to get a sense of the scale of the domes.</p>]]><p><b>Get arty in Adelaide</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Generally to be found near the top of the list of those "world's most liveable cities" surveys, South Australia's capital is rightly seen as something of an urban gem. Attractive and uncrowded, it's renowned for its parks, its art galleries and its busy cultural calendar, which includes the largest arts festival in the southern hemisphere, the Adelaide Fringe.</p>]]><p><b>Give Tasmania a try</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tasmanians cheekily refer to mainland Australia as 'the north island', and you can forgive the self-confidence. The island state is deserving of as much time as you can spare, cramming in an extraordinary variety of landscapes and outdoor activities. In Hobart, meanwhile, it also boasts a highly liveable capital city.</p>]]><p><b>Go west to Perth</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Western Australia's biggest city is something of a slow-burner. It lacks the immediate wham-bam of Sydney and Melbourne, but for those who take the time to explore its parkland, beaches and laidback urban vibe, it's somewhere that's easy to love. The surrounding region, offering up winelands and character-rich towns, adds to the appeal.</p>]]><p><b>Go wild swimming in Litchfield</b></p><![CDATA[<p>'Litchfield-do, Kaka-don't'. So runs the tongue-in-cheek advice from the Northern Territory's locals when it comes to choosing between their main national parks. Litchfield lacks the epic majesty of Kakadu, but its cascading waterfalls and swimming holes make it a deservedly more popular day-trip from Darwin.</p>]]><p><b>Head to the Blue Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Blue Mountains' proximity to Sydney makes them a near-essential part of any New South Wales itinerary. Their name comes from the bluish haze given off by the eucalyptus trees that carpet the range's huge slopes. A great spot for everything from bush-walking to horse-riding.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the Flinders Ranges</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many visitors never make it down to South Australia, which makes the rolling mountains of the Flinders Ranges all the more special. They play home to national parks, sleepy towns and the kind of true-blue Aussie character that the country's famous for – don't miss the colossal natural amphitheatre of Wilpena Pound.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Kakadu National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wrapped up in endless layers of spiritual significance, Kakadu National Park offers 20,000 sq km (7,700 sq miles) of untamed (and some would say unrivalled) Australian wilderness. There are crocs, creeks, escarpments and waterfalls, as well as an immense collection of ancient Aboriginal rock art.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the Ghan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A north-south alternative to the east-west passage of the Indian Pacific, The Ghan passenger train chugs the full length of the country from Darwin to Adelaide, calling in at Alice Springs and Katherine en route. It's a great way of taking in the breadth of the outback while enjoying Aussie wine, good food and comfortable cabins.</p>]]><p><b>Sink into Sydney</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Where to start with Sydney? It's a toss-up as to whether the locals or the tourists do the most swooning over it, and once you've experienced the surf beaches, the harbour, the skyline and that warm, lazy-day culture, it's not hard to understand why. Give the place as much time as possible.</p>]]><p><b>Travel the Great Ocean Road</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Showcasing arguably the finest surf-pounded coastal scenery in the country, the Great Ocean Road sits within driving distance of Melbourne. It's 250km (155 miles) long, so can be 'done' in a couple of days – far better, though, to take your foot off the gas and experience its towns and beaches at a relaxed pace.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Uluru</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Every bit as magical as the hype would suggest, 'The Rock' is the kind of monumental natural feature for which sightseeing seems too crude a category. Getting there can be time-consuming, but the reward (like Uluru itself) is immense. Take time too to visit nearby Kata Tjuta, in many ways just as epic a landmark.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$1.34 trillion (2015 estimate).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Ores and metals, wool, food and live animals, wheat and minerals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transport equipment, computers and office machines, telecommunication equipment, crude oil and petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Japan, China, USA, South Korea and Singapore</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Australia has a very diverse economy and a high standard of living. The country's service industries account for the major part of the economy. The other major export industry is mining; Australia has vast reserves of coal (of which it is the world's leading exporter), natural gas, nickel, iron ore, bauxite and diamonds, as well as uranium (Australian ore fuels many of the Western nations' nuclear power plants).</p>
<p>Most Australian manufacturing is concentrated in the processing of mineral products and in the iron, steel and engineering industries. The traditional agricultural industry is now less important with long-term drought forecasts. Sheep farming appears to be in long-term decline.</p>
<p>China's demand for raw materials has led to a growth market for Australian exports. Japanese investment in Australia, particularly in property and tourist ventures, has reached the point where most of the eastern seaboard 'Gold Coast' is now Japanese-owned.</p>
<p>The Australian economy is enviably strong despite the global financial crisis of 2008-2009, and a drop in international trade. A fiscal stimulus package, confidence in exports and increased economic links within the Asia-Pacific region have meant that Australia has weathered the global economic downturn better than most advanced nations. Inflation has remained low in 2017 at 1.5% while unemployment stood at 5.7% in the same year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits are usually worn in Sydney and Melbourne. Brisbane businesspeople may wear shirts, ties and shorts; visiting businesspeople should wear lightweight suits for the initial meeting. Prior appointments are usually necessary. Punctuality is important. A great deal of business is conducted over drinks. Best months for business travel are March to November.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Australian Chamber of Commerce and Industry (ACCI)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 6273 2311
					Website:http://www.acci.asn.au/
					Address: Level 3,Commerce House,Australia,]]><b>Association of Australian Convention Bureaux (AACB)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 9326 9133
					Website:http://www.aacb.org.au/
					Address: 80 William Street,Level 13,East Sydney,]]><b>Australian Business in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 0870 890 0720
					Website:http://www.australianbusiness.co.uk/
					Address: ,Swire House,59 Buckingham Gate,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Forget the Vegemite sandwiches. Australia's food and drink is world class these days, with seafood an integral part of the cuisine and quality local produce now increasingly important. Production of organic foods is also rising to meet demand, and there are fine dining restaurants throughout the larger cities.</p><p>Big-name chefs are helping to give Australian cuisine a reputation for bright, creative gastronomy, and regional markets and food festivals are commonplace. Look out for things like farmhouse cheese, speciality sausages and local fruits. Elsewhere, the country's multitude of good wines has earned international acclaim. <br/><br/>'Bush tucker' from Australia's endemic flora and fauna can be delicious; kangaroo meat in particular is growing in popularity. For all the advent of fine dining, however, the humble barbecue remains a quintessential Australian food experience. Steak, prawns and beer tend to feature prominently.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sydney rock oysters:</strong> Small and soft with a distinctive taste.<br />
<strong>Barramundi:</strong> A fish particularly prevalent in the Northern Territory.<br />
<strong>Moreton Bay bugs:</strong> A kind of lobster.<br />
<strong>Macadamia nuts:</strong> Native to New South Wales and Queensland.<br />
<strong>Kangaroo:</strong> Yes, poor old Skippy is also on the menu.<br />
<strong>Meat pie:</strong> A staple on-the-go snack.<br />
<strong>Fruit: </strong>Apples, mangoes and pumpkins are among those grown in large quantities.<br />
<strong>Dagwood dog:</strong> A deep-fried battered hot dog on a stick, popular at fairgrounds and outdoor events.<br />
<strong>Wine:</strong>&nbsp;Regions like the Barossa Valley in South Australia, and Margaret River in Western Australia, are world class.<br />
<strong>Craft beer:</strong> Away from the likes of VB, you&rsquo;ll find some excellent small-batch brewers.<br />
<strong>Sparkling wine:</strong> The bubbly from Tasmania is superb.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In top-quality restaurants, 10% is usual for food and drink waiters, but is optional elsewhere.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Theatre and performance arts are especially good in Sydney and Melbourne; the Sydney Opera House (<a href="http://www.sydneyoperahouse.com" target="_blank">www.sydneyoperahouse.com</a>) regularly hosts the country's top orchestras and opera companies. Melbourne is Australia's cultural city (although you&rsquo;ll find no shortage of Sydneysiders keen to debate the topic) and has a nationwide reputation for its live music scene; venues range from premier music-hosting places such as The Forum (<a href="http://www.forummelbourne.com.au" target="_blank">www.forummelbourne.com.au</a>) to backstreet pubs in Fitzroy, Collingwood and Richmond. Comedy is also popular in Melbourne, a fact borne out by its starring role in the city&rsquo;s annual fringe festival. South Australia is commonly regarded as the 'Festival State'; Adelaide has a multitude of entertainment to choose from at the Adelaide Festival Centre (<a href="http://www.adelaidefestivalcentre.com.au" target="_blank">www.adelaidefestivalcentre.com.au</a>).</p>
<p>Most cities have a healthy clubbing scene pulling top national and international DJs. The venues themselves range from glitzy superclubs to less discerning (but often no less enjoyable) party palaces. Big-name rock and pop acts also tend to take in Australia on their world tours these days, and a there are a good number of music festivals over the course of the year, covering everything from metal to electronica.</p>
<p>Traditional pubs range from huge double-storey monoliths in Western and South Australia, to graceful Victorian edifices in Victoria and New South Wales. Trendy bars attracting the style-conscious are very popular night-time venues. Melbourne's central business district is full of hole-in-the-wall bars.</p>
<p>In rural areas the pub is the standard venue for socialising. Local drinking holes off the beaten track tend to be very simple affairs, and in many cases also very friendly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases include excellent local wines; wool, clothing, leather and sheepskin products; precious or semi-precious stones; and modern art sculpture and paintings. Surfing products are also a big buy around coastal towns and resorts.</p>
<p>Indigenous artworks and artefacts are prolific in some parts of the country and paintings, boomerangs, didgeridoos and other objects are on view and for sale in Darwin, Alice Springs and the state capitals; many depict stories from Australian Aboriginal mythology. Ensure you are purchasing an authentic item, however, as much so-called Aboriginal art is fake, consisting of designs ripped off from the real artists. The best places to buy are outlets supported or owned by Aboriginal communities.</p>
<p>The country's national gemstone, the opal, makes beautiful jewellery and the best places to buy are at or near opal mining towns such as Coober Pedy in South Australia. Towns like Broome in Western Australia grew on the back of pearl diving, and cultured pearls are still sold in large quantities.</p><p>Opening hours for most stores in the cities are Mon-Fri 0900-1730, Sat 0900-1700. Late-night shopping is available on Friday to 2100 in Melbourne, Adelaide, Brisbane, Hobart and Darwin. Late-night shopping is available on Thursday at the same times in Sydney, Canberra and Perth. Major stores in some states are open Sun 1000-1600. Most supermarkets are open until 2000, and are sometimes 24-hour. Corner stores, restaurants and snack bars are open in most cities until well into the night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Every state has a selection of hotels run by well-known and established international chains. More authentic accommodation can be found outside the cities. The highways out of the state cities are lined with motels offering self-contained family units, and often an in-house restaurant service. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong>&nbsp;hotels and motels in Australia are graded from 1 to 5 stars by the Australian Automobile Clubs under the Star Ratings Australia system. The Star Ratings Australia system&nbsp;will cease to operate as of 30 June 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfast in private homes is available throughout Australia, and numbers are on the rise. One of the major attractions of this type of accommodation is the range of properties available. Bed and breakfasts might be found in rambling country manors, boutique urban mansions, restored miners' cottages or faded colonial buildings. Friday to Sunday nights are normally more expensive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Every state has a selection of hotels run by well-known and established international chains. More authentic accommodation can be found outside the cities. The highways out of the state cities are lined with motels offering self-contained family units, and often an in-house restaurant service. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong>&nbsp;hotels and motels in Australia are graded from 1 to 5 stars by the Australian Automobile Clubs under the Star Ratings Australia system. The Star Ratings Australia system&nbsp;will cease to operate as of 30 June 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Every state has a selection of hotels run by well-known and established international chains. More authentic accommodation can be found outside the cities. The highways out of the state cities are lined with motels offering self-contained family units, and often an in-house restaurant service. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong>&nbsp;hotels and motels in Australia are graded from 1 to 5 stars by the Australian Automobile Clubs under the Star Ratings Australia system. The Star Ratings Australia system&nbsp;will cease to operate as of 30 June 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are reciprocal health agreements with the UK, Belgium, Finland, Italy, Malta, Netherlands, Republic of Ireland, Slovenia and Sweden, which allow residents from these countries free hospital treatment as long as citizens carry their Medicare card. Prescribed medicines, ambulances and treatment at some doctors' surgeries must be paid for. Personal insurance for illness and accidents is highly recommended for all visitors, including the nationals of the countries listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some visitors seem to arrive in Australia expecting danger at every turn, which is far from necessary. The standard of health care is in general very high, and despite considerable parts of the country being in the tropics, diseases like malaria or yellow fever are unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture becomes riskier when visiting the country&amp;rsquo;s most remote and unpopulated areas, where it&amp;rsquo;s likely to take considerable time for the emergency services to reach travellers. Self-reliance is an important skill to have, so it&amp;rsquo;s worth looking into wilderness first aid techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attacks by sharks, crocodiles and the like might draw plenty of headlines on the rare occasions they occur, but are by no means a common occurrence.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Standards of hygiene in food preparation are very high. Milk is pasteurised and meat and vegetables are considered safe to eat. Care should be taken, however, if preparing 'bush tucker' in outback areas as some insects and fauna are highly poisonous unless properly cooked.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Outbreaks of dengue fever occur in northern Queensland, especially during the wet season (Oct-Mar), and Ross River fever virus is widespread in Australia. There have been reports of Murray Valley encephalitis in northern Australia and in the northwest of Western Australia. Corals, jellyfish and fresh water crocodiles may prove a hazard to the bather. Insectivorous and fruit-eating bats have been found to harbour a virus related to the rabies virus and should be avoided. Venomous snakes and spiders exist throughout Australia and can be extremely dangerous. You should seek medical assistance immediately if bitten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parts of Australia  regularly experience dangerously high temperatures, so common sense is essential if spending significant time outdoors. Heat exhaustion is a hazard in many parts of the country. Ensure you have adequate sun protection, and heed the now famous government advice to &amp;lsquo;slip, slop, slap&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; that is, slip on a T-shirt, slop on some suncream and slap on a hat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the same note, it&amp;rsquo;s vital to ensure you have an adequate supply of drinking water. This isn&amp;rsquo;t much of an issue when you&amp;rsquo;re kicking back on a busy beach surrounded by shops, of course, but if you&amp;rsquo;re heading off on a long journey (be it by foot, by bike or by motor vehicle) water supply becomes hugely important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inexperienced surfers often see Australia as the ideal place to start learning. Some of the surf spots are world-class, but the surf itself can also be dangerously strong &amp;ndash; watch out for undercurrents and powerful tides. In short, know your limitations, particularly at beaches without lifeguards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few foreigners associate Australia with extreme cold, but it also pays to be aware that parts of the south can become bitterly cold over the winter months. Hypothermia can be as big a risk here as in any other chilly climate. &lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Nationwide holidays only. If these dates fall on the weekend, a day may be given in lieu. Additional holidays are observed by individual states - see individual state sections for details.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Australia Day :
							2018<br/>26 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Holy Saturday :
							31 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>ANZAC Day :
							25 April </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Australia by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 25 cigarettes or 25g of tobacco or cigars.<br />
&bull; 2.25L of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; Personal belongings that you've owned and used for at least 12 months.<br />
&bull; Other goods to a value of A$900 (A$450 if under 18).<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are very strict regulations against the import of non-prescribed drugs, weapons, firearms, wildlife, domestic animals and foodstuffs (including meat, poultry and dairy; plants or parts of plants [including fruit, nuts and seeds]; animal products [including wool, skins and eggs] and any equipment used with domestic animals) and other potential sources of disease and pestilence (such as vaccines or viruses). There are severe penalties for drug trafficking.</p>
<p>For further details on customs regulations, contact the Australian Department of Immigration and Border Protection (<a href="http://www.customs.gov.au">www.customs.gov.au</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The export of protected wildlife and associated products is strictly controlled, including the export of coral, turtle shell, snake or reptile skin, orchids, caviar, ivory products, hunting trophies and traditional medicinal products.</p>
<p>If you plan to export any heritage-listed goods, including works of art, stamps, coins, archaeological objects, minerals and specimens, you need to apply for a special permit.</p>
<p>The export of Australian native animals and plants is either prohibited or restricted.</p>
<p>Also prohibited are firearms, pornography and narcotics.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Australian Dollar (AUD; symbol A$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of A$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of A$2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10 and 5 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchange facilities are available for all incoming and outgoing flights at all international airports in Australia. International-class hotels will exchange major currencies for guests. It is recommended that visitors change money at the airport or at city banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are accepted. Use may be restricted in small towns and outback areas.</p><p>Found in all major towns and cities. However you may have limited or no access to ATMs in small towns and outback areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted in major currencies at banks or large hotels. However, some banks may charge a fee for cashing traveller's cheques. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in a major currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0930-1600, Fri 0930-1700. These hours may vary slightly throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>N/A</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>N/A</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>N/A</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Australia, a valid passport is required by the nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All travellers, regardless of age, require a visa to visit Australia. If your children have their own passport, you should apply for a separate ETA/eVisitor visa for each child entering all the details from their passports. If a child is on a parent&rsquo;s passport, you still need a separate ETA/eVisitor visa, but should apply using the parent&rsquo;s passport details as well as the child&rsquo;s name, date of birth etc, as they appear on the passport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Citizens of the countries listed in the chart above do not need a transit visa if they have onward flights within eight hours of arriving and remain in the transit lounge. Nationals of countries not referred to in the chart above may require a transit visa and should check with the high commission or embassy. Transit visas are free of charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&bull; ETA: free (but a A$20 service charge applies)<br />
&bull; eVisitor visa: free <br />
&bull; Visitor Visa: A$135 for applicants outside Australia visiting once; A$1000 for frequent travelers (this visa is valid for up to 10 years, but it is currently in a trial stage so numbers are limited, though it may be extended to other passport holders in the future).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>ETA/eVisitor: 12 months from the date of issue (or until the passport expires, whichever comes first) and permits multiple entries into Australia for a stay of up to three months on each visit.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Visitor visa: varies according to individual circumstances and will be stated on the visa label in your passport; usually valid for up to three, six or 12 months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>ETA: authorised travel agents or airlines or the nearest Australian High Commission or Embassy; some nationals (including Americans and Canadians) may apply online through the main Department of Immigration and Border Protection (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.eta.immi.gov.au">www.eta.immi.gov.au</a>).</p>
<p>eVisitor visa: apply online (<a href="http://www.border.gov.au" target="_blank">www.border.gov.au</a>).</p>
<p>Visitor visa: Australian embassies, high commissions and consulates; some nationals may apply online.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>ETA applications are usually processed immediately. The processing time for eVisitor visas is between one day and a month. For visitor visas, processing varies according to the nationality of the applicant and can take anything from one day to a month.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Those entering Australia on a working holiday visa are expected to bring sufficient funds to support their initial stay in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Anyone looking to extend their stay needs to apply for a new visa which, if successfully granted, will immediately cancel any other visa held. Those with a &lsquo;Further stay restricted&rsquo; condition on their visa cannot usually extend their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All cats and dogs being imported to Australia, whether it be for the first time or returning, must meet strict import conditions set by the Australian Department of Agriculture and Water Resources (<a href="http://www.agriculture.gov.au/cats-dogs" target="_blank">www.agriculture.gov.au/cats-dogs</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-25.585019]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[134.504009]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>7,692,024 sq km (2,969,907 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>24,127,200 (Australian Bureau of Statistics 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3.1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Canberra.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Australia's great coastline covers 59,736km (37,119 miles); the country is lapped by the Arafura and Timor Seas to the north, the Coral and Tasman Seas of the South Pacific to the east, the Southern Ocean to the south, and the Indian Ocean to the west.</p>
<p>Most of the population has settled along the eastern and southeastern coastal strip, with the notable exception of Perth, one of the most remote cities in the world, on the west coast. Australia is the smallest continent (and the largest island) in the world, and terrain ranges from baking red desert to lush green rainforest, and from world-renowned surfing beaches to snow-clad mountains.&nbsp;</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s partly the extreme diversity of different landscapes that makes Australia such a great travel proposition, in fact &ndash; there aren&rsquo;t many countries that can offer natural features as richly eclectic as Uluru, the Great Ocean Road and the Great Barrier Reef.</p>
<p>In the east lies the Great Dividing Range; there are rainforests in the far northeast (mainly in Queensland); the southeast is a huge fertile plain; and further to the north lays the enormous Great Barrier Reef: a 2,000km (1,200-mile) strip of coral that covers a total area of 345,000 sq km (133,000 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>35% Protestant, 25% Roman Catholic, and smaller minorities of all other major religions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A largely informal atmosphere prevails; shaking hands is the customary greeting. Casual wear is worn everywhere except in the most exclusive restaurants, social gatherings and important business meetings. Most restaurants forbid smoking.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with three flat pins (two of which form an upside-down V) are standard. Outlets for 110 volts for small appliances are found in most hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Scott Morrison&nbsp;since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General Peter Cosgrove since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There were numerous early European explorers to Australia, among them Willem Janszoon, the Dutchman generally credited with being the first outsider to land on Australian soil (doing so in 1606), and his compatriot Abel Tasman, who in 1642 discovered the large island off Australia&rsquo;s southern coast &ndash; hence its modern name, Tasmania.</p>
<p>It was Captain James Cook, however, who landed at Botany Bay in 1770 and changed the fate of the land forever. When he and his men stepped onto Australian shores, they encountered an Aboriginal way of life that went back some 40,000 years.</p>
<p>The first governor, Arthur Phillip, was ordered to encourage a positive relationship with the indigenous locals, although a mixture of disease, malice and mutual suspicion meant this was over-optimistic. The first settlers treated the Aboriginal population with appalling brutality, which gave way to racist policies from subsequent administrations. Tensions still exist between mainstream Australia and the guardians of the Aboriginal way of life.<br />
While the native way of life was being strained, the island&rsquo;s new settlers were putting down firm roots. A British colony had been established not long after Cook&rsquo;s arrival, and by 1868 (recognising the powerful crime deterrent afforded by penal transportation) London had sent more than 160,000 convicts to Australia.</p>
<p>By this time there had also been the mass arrival of free settlers and speculators, many of them pouring into the country in the gold rush of the 1850s. It led to significant economic expansion. By the 1880s the majority of people in the colony had been born and raised in Australia, which in turn was creating a deeper sense of nationalism. The Commonwealth of Australia came into being in 1901.</p>
<p>The nation was deeply involved and affected by both world wars and the Great Depression, but it continued to develop into a modern, versatile nation and grew as both a domestic and international power. Racial reconciliation was given a boost in 2008 when government issued a formal apology to the indigenous population for the past.</p>
<p>Australia remains a constitutional monarchy, with Queen Elizabeth II as its present monarch. The country saw its first ever female prime minister in 2010, when Labor&rsquo;s Julia Gillard won a narrow election victory. Her rule lasted three years, before a political merry-go-round then saw Labor&rsquo;s Kevin Rudd, the Liberal Party&rsquo;s Tony Abbott and current prime minister Malcolm Turnbull all have stints in power before 2015 was up.&nbsp;Turnbull, of the Liberal Party, is currently serving as Prime Minister, having been re-elected in 2016.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Melbourne is said to be home to the most sizable Greek population in the world outside Greece. <br />
&bull;	The country&rsquo;s largest cattle station, Anna Creek in South Australia, is more than three quarters the size of Belgium. <br />
&bull;	Former PM Bob Hawke once held the word record for downing the equivalent of a yard of ale.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Australia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 797 3000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.usa.embassy.gov.au</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 797 3000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1700 (embassy); Mon-Fri 0900-1200 and 1400-1600 (visa office hours).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1601 Massachusetts Avenue, NW<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Australian High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7379 4334.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.uk.embassy.gov.au</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7379 4334.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700 (general); Mon-Fri 0930-1130 (notarial and document services); Mon-Fri 0900-1600 (passport services).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Australia House, Strand<br/>London<br/>WC2B 4LA<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Comission in Australia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+61 2 6270 6666.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinaustralia.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+61 2 6270 6666.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0845-1230 and 1330-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Yarralumla<br/>Commonwealth Avenue<br/>Canberra<br/>2600<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Australia is a land of savage beauty, big adventure and even bigger horizons. There are good reasons why the country finds itself touted as one of the ultimate travel getaways; it has personality in spades, landscapes to die for and more than its fair share of sunshine. And if beaches, rainforest and outback aren&rsquo;t your thing, then its major cities are outstanding destinations in their own right.</p>
<p>In many ways the country breeds extremes. The fiery atmosphere of an Aussie Rules match in Melbourne and the champagne glitz of Sydney Harbour belong to another planet entirely when compared to the quiet expanse of the Red Centre or the surf-bashed coastlines of the west.</p>
<p>Likewise, 40,000 years of Aboriginal culture sometimes seem an unnatural bedfellow for the famed &ldquo;no worries mate&rdquo; BBQ-lifestyle of modern times. When taken as a whole, however, the sum of Australia&rsquo;s contrasts make it a destination that is as fascinating as it is diverse.</p>
<p>Knowing where to go is arguably the toughest part. There are well-travelled paths, with Sydney and the east coast being a perennially popular choice. When you&rsquo;re faced with a country of this magnitude, hwoever, potential itineraries are numberless. The Great Barrier Reef? Uluru? The Great Ocean Road? Kakadu? Hobart? The Kimberley? When the tourist board controversially coined the slogan &ldquo;So where the bloody hell are you?&rdquo; it raised a fair point.</p>
<p>There are iconic Aussie clich&eacute;s by the barrel-load (from cork hats to barbecues, koalas to crocodiles, and cricketers to bush tucker) but the real beauty of the place lies in the stuff you&rsquo;re not expecting; the dusty open road that unfurls to reveal verdant hills; the cold beer at an outback pub that turns into an evening-long session; the stroll to the beach that throws up a street market, open-air concert and implausibly beautiful sunset.</p>
<p>A trip Down Under has long been synonymous with escape, exploration and adventure &ndash; an image that's unlikely to change anytime soon.</p><p>Australia is a land of savage beauty, big adventure and even bigger horizons. There are good reasons why the country finds itself touted as one of the ultimate travel getaways; it has personality in spades, landscapes to die for and more than its fair share of sunshine. And if beaches, rainforest and outback aren&rsquo;t your thing, then its major cities are outstanding destinations in their own right.&nbsp;In many ways the country breeds extremes. The fiery atmosphere of an Aussie Rules match in Melbourne and the champagne glitz of Sydney Harbour belong to another planet entirely when compared to the quiet expanse of the Red Centre or the surf-bashed coastlines of the west.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
