<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Tasmania" ColCode="tas" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bc" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Tasmania]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With four seasons, the summer tends to be warm rather than hot. Winters are wet, cold and stormy, particularly in the east.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens in summer. Waterproof clothes are advisable in the winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sharp Airlines (<a href="http://www.sharpairlines.com" target="_blank">www.sharpairlines.com</a>) flies from Launceston and Burnie to Flinders Island and King Island. Par Avion Wilderness Tours (<a href="http://www.paravion.com.au" target="_blank">www.paravion.com.au</a>) offers flights into the South West World Heritage Area, including a variety of scenic flights and bushwalker access to the remote South Coast Track.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Main ferry services in Hobart include Derwent River sailings from the Brooke Street Pier as well as many tourist cruises (<a href="http://www.hobarthistoriccruises.com.au" target="_blank">www.hobarthistoriccruises.com.au</a>) and water taxis (<a href="http://www.hobartwatertaxis.com" target="_blank">www.hobartwatertaxis.com</a>). For Bruny Island, a car ferry operates on a regular daily schedule from the wharf in Ferry Road, Kettering, 35-minutes drive south of Hobart. For fare and timetable information contact Bruny Island Ferry (<a href="http://www.brunyislandferry.com.au" target="_blank">www.brunyislandferry.com.au</a>; tel +61 (3) 6273 6725).</p>
<p>In the Lake St Clair Cradle Mountain National Park, the Ida Clair takes visitors from Cynthia Bay, at the Lake's southern end, to Narcissus Point at the end of the Overland Track. Booking is essential for the summer and winter service (tel: (3) 6289 1137).&nbsp;</p>
<p>For the east coast Maria Island, there is a daily summer service from Triabunna Wharf 90 minutes drive northeast of Hobart. For bookings and details contact Maria Island Ferry &amp; Eco Cruises (<a href="http://www.mariaislandferry.com.au" target="_blank">www.mariaislandferry.com.au</a>; tel: +61 (4) 1974 6668.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Within this small, compact and sparsely populated island, traffic is rarely a problem. Even in Hobart the capital peak hour lasts for a couple of minutes if that. All major cities, towns and historic villages are linked by major highways and roads. Some of the most splendid mountain, lake and coastal scenery lies off the key routes and are accessed via sealed country roads and minor routes.</p>l<p>Excellent in general. Tasmania has just a handful of well maintained highways including the Midland or Heritage Highway connecting Hobart and Launceston, the Tasman Highway to Port Arthur and Southern Outlet.  Though two-lane roads are also in good condition, some&nbsp;car hire companies have special conditions for use on unsealed roads.</p><p>Coaches are an essential form of tourism transport with daily intercity connections between Hobart and Launceston and to a number of regional centres. Metro Services operate coaches around Hobart and Launceston.</p>
<p>Tassie Link <a href="http://www.tassielink.com.au" target="_blank">(www.tassielink.com.au</a>) and Redline Coaches (<a href="http://www.redlinecoaches.com.au" target="_blank">www.redlinecoaches.com.au</a>) operate the main intra-state service, Hobart-Launceston, to the Huon Valley, Port Arthur, Richmond and the East Coast. Redline also connects Hobart with many North Coast towns and minor rural areas state-wide.</p>
<p>To get to and from Freycinet National Park use Freycinet Connections (<a href="http://www.freycinetconnections.com.au" target="_blank">www.freycinetconnections.com.au</a>), and for other routes try Mersey Bus Link Service <a href="http://www.merseylink.com.au" target="_blank">(www.merseylink.com.au</a>), which runs coaches and commuter buses on the North West Coast around Devonport and Latrobe.</p><p>Royal Automobile Club of Tasmania (RACT, <a href="http://www.ract.com.au" target="_blank">www.ract.com.au</a>; tel: +61 (3) 6232 6300)</p><p>Major car hire companies are Hertz, Thrifty, Avis and Budget and low-cost VroomVroomVroom.  Cars are generally available for pickup at the airport and certain hotels.  Compare rates at <a href="http://www.fetchcarhirehobart.com.au" target="_blank">www.fetchcarhirehobart.com.au</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All direct flights to Hobart arrive from Australian cities including Brisbane, Melbourne and Sydney. There are also direct flights from the mainland to Launceston and the North West coast centres of Devonport and Burnie, King and Flinders Island.</p>
<p>Airlines serving Tasmania include Qantas (<a href="http://www.qantas.com.au" target="_blank">www.qantas.com.au</a>), its low-cost operator Jetstar (<a href="http://www.jetstar.com.au/" target="_blank">www.jetstar.com.au</a>), Virgin Australia (<a href="http://www.virginaustralia.com" target="_blank">www.virginaustralia.com</a>), rural flights with Rex  Regional Express (<a href="http://www.rex.com.au" target="_blank">www.rex.com.au</a>), and Tiger Air (<a href="http://www.tigerairways.com.au/" target="_blank">www.tigerair.com.au</a>) linking to Asian destinations.</p>
<p>Sharp Airlines (<a href="http://sharpairlines.com" target="_blank">sharpairlines.com</a>) flies from Melbourne and Adelaide to Flinders Island. King Island Airlines (<a href="http://www.kingislandair.com.au/" target="_blank">www.kingislandair.com.au</a>), Regional Express and charter company Vortex Air (<a href="http://www.vortexair.com.au" target="_blank">www.vortexair.com.au</a>) operate flights from Melbourne to King Island.  Par-Avion Airlines (<a href="http://www.paravionairlines.com.au" target="_blank">www.paravionairlines.com.au</a>) connects Launceston and Essendon in Victoria with Cape Barren Island in the Bass Strait&rsquo;s Furneaux Group of Islands.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Hobart International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.hobartairport.com.au<p>The airport  lies 16km (10 miles) east of Hobart.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Devonport (<a href="http://www.tasports.com.au/" target="_blank">www.tasports.com.au</a>) on the northwest coast of the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no passenger services in Tasmania, but a couple of notable tourist railways. The West Coast Wilderness Railway (tel: +61 1800 420 155; <a href="http://www.wcwr.com.au" target="_blank">www.wcwr.com.au</a> ) runs between Queenstown and Strahan. Along its 35km (22 miles) journey, it crosses a number of small rivers and passes through restored stations including Lower Landing, Dubbil and Baril (journey time: 5 hours).</p><p>In the northwest, the Don River Railway (tel: +61 (3) 6424 6335; <a href="http://www.donriverrailway.com.au/" target="_blank">www.donriverrailway.com.au</a>) also runs regular excursions using both steam and diesel locomotives. The rail trips usually take half an hour, to Coles Beach and back.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Capture Russell Falls in all its glory</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watch water cascade down the 45m (148ft) high Russell Falls, a pretty display of nature in the Mount Field National Park, and contender for most-photographed waterfall in Australia.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Mt Wellington</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mt Wellington, Hobart's iconic backdrop, looms 1,271m (4,170ft) above the city and its snow-capped peaks glisten white for much of the year. The flanks of the mountain are heavily forested and at the summit there is a lookout point, which has beautiful views across the city, all the way through to Bruny Island and Storm Bay, where the Derwent Estuary opens onto the Tasman.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Freycinet National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Step into Freycinet National Park on Tasmania's east coast and gambol amongst glorious heaths, wildflowers and the white sands of Wineglass Bay, where the azure waters of the Tasman Sea lap gently on the shore. Absolutely stunning.</p>]]><p><b>Hike along Cataract Gorge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cataract Gorge is a slice of Tasmanian wilderness famous for its basalt cliffs and dramatic scenery. Located just 15 minutes by foot from Launceston, the gorge has various hiking trails, as well as a restaurant, swimming pool and chairlift. Resident peacocks roam the gardens of the nearby visitor centre, which is also home to a café.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the slopes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tasmania lays claim to a handful of ski resorts, but the biggest is Ben Lomond, which is home to the Summit Run. If you are planning of skiing there base yourself at the Creek Inn, which has the bragging rights to being Tasmania's highest pub. Even in the winter Ben Lomond is still worthy of a visit; Alpine wildflowers run rampant in spring and summer when bushwalking becomes the main activity. <a href="http://www.skibenlomond.com.au" target="_blank">www.skibenlomond.com.au</a></p>]]><p><b>Imbibe Tasmanian art at MONA</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Described as a &lsquo;subversive adult Disneyland,&rsquo; the controversial Museum of Old and New Art (MONA) has put Tasmania firmly on the cultural map. Its riverside collection boasts 400 works include an Egyptian sarcophagus and a machine that produces, ahem, poo. Located on the Moorilla vineyard, the museum is within staggering distance of a wine bar, microbrewery, restaurant, cinema and fancy guest accommodation, The Pavilions. <a href="http://www.mona.net.au/" target="_blank">www.mona.net.au</a></p>]]><p><b>Meet a Tasmanian devil</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located in the beautiful Cradle Mountain National Park, Devils @ Cradle offers visitors the chance to meet some of Tasmania's most iconic species including the spotted-tail quoll, the eastern quoll and, of course, the iconic Tasmanian devil. The sanctuary was set up to help conserve these endangered species, which are unique to Tasmania. <a href="http://www.devilsatcradle.com/" target="_blank">www.devilsatcradle.com</a></p>]]><p><b>Sail away on the Tasmanian breeze</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sail into Tasmanian bliss on a boat or sailing cruise. It's a popular way to explore the port cities of Launceston and Hobart, and outlying islands. You can explore the southwest coast from Strahan on the west coast.</p>]]><p><b>Study colonial era art</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Study Tasmanian colonial era art and Aboriginal art at the Queen Victoria Museum and Art Gallery (<a href="http://www.qvmag.tas.gov.au/" target="_blank">www.qvmag.tas.gov.au</a>) at its two locations: the Art Gallery at Royal Park in Launceston, and the Museum in Inveresk. The Gallery exhibits include a Chinese temple and joss house.</p>]]><p><b>Take a road trip down the Tasman Peninsula</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Observe the Blowhole, Devil's Kitchen, Tasman Arch, Tessellated Pavement and other coastal splendours on a scenic drive down the Tasman Peninsula. There are terrific views from Eaglehawk Neck over Pirates Bay and beyond.</p>]]><p><b>Trek Cradle Mountain</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gasp at Tasmania's dramatic mountain peaks, situated in the World Heritage Wilderness Area of Cradle Mountain/Lake St Clair National Park. Famous for the 65km (40 mile) Overland Track bushwalk, the mountain bursts with natural wonders including rainforest, alpine heath, glacial lakes and ancient pines.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind in the Royal Botanical Gardens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located on a headland facing the river, a 15-minute stroll from the city, the old worldly gardens are an outdoor lover's joy brimming with century old trees. There's also a Subantarctic Plant House, heritage buildings and a visitor's centre embracing souvenir shop, restaurant and art gallery.</p>]]><p><b>Visit ‘hell on Earth’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A former British penal colony, Port Arthur was described by inmates as 'hell on Earth.' Today its crumbling ramparts are a UNESCO World Heritage Site and the most popular tourist attraction in Tasmania. Between 1833 and 1853 it received the most notorious British criminals, who were the subject of physical and psychological punishment.</p>]]><p><b>Walk on air</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Suspended above a spectacular forest canopy, some 37m (121ft) above the ground, the Tahune AirWalk certainly requires a head for heights. The lofty causeway forms part of the Huon Trail, which includes detours to the Hastings thermal pool, caves and the sheltered bays of the D'Entrecasteaux Channel. Alternatively, the Hollybank Treetops Adventure involves cable 'flights' above Hollybank Forest Reserve.&nbsp;<a href="http://www.adventureforests.com.au/" target="_blank">www.adventureforests.com.au</a></p>]]><p><b>Walk the Walls of Jerusalem</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located in the Tasmanian Central Highlands, the Walls of Jerusalem National Park offer epic landscapes that belie Tasmania's diminutive size. Perfect for hiking, the park's cliffs are thought to resemble the city walls of Jerusalem – hence the name.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around historic Hobart</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a walk through Hobart's historic old town, wandering around Sullivans Cove, through the old warehouses of Salamanca Place and past the Georgian buildings of Battery Point. En route, learn more about the island's history at the Maritime Museum of Tasmania (<a href="http://www.maritimetas.org/" target="_blank">www.maritimetas.org</a>) and the Tasmanian Museum and Art Gallery (<a href="http://www.tmag.tas.gov.au/" target="_blank">www.tmag.tas.gov.au</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Watch the local wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tasmania's national parks are home to a rich variety of animals, many of them unique to the island. They include wombats, duck-billed platypus, wallabies, fairy penguins and the iconic Tasmanian devil, a small, black, dog-like marsupial. <a href="http://www.parks.tas.gov.au/" target="_blank">www.parks.tas.gov.au</a></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Process metal – chiefly zinc and aluminium – and mineral ores are the biggest export earner worth some AU$1.5 billion to the economy each year. Tasmania is widely criticised for exporting its forests, including old-growth forest, as woodchips. The island accounts for about half of all Australia's woodchip, newsprint and writing paper exports. Food exports namely beef, dairy produce and crustaceans are a major economic contributor worth about $300m a year. Other exports include catamarans and poppies; Tasmania is the world's largest producer of opium alkaloids, used as raw material for the pharmaceutical market.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Refined petroleum, fertilisers, animal feed and cars.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, US, Taiwan, India, Japan, Italy, Korea and Mexico.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourism reaps around AU$1.3billion annually with the million visitors a year mark cracked for the first time in 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When conducting business in Tasmania, act as you would in the rest of Australia. A hand shake is the standard greeting. Punctuality, pragmatism and a hard working ethic are deemed important when getting down to business. Connections are valued – bank on a personal introduction as a foot in to developing relationships with an Australian firm. Australians favour directness in communication, and good humour where appropriate, but dislike one-upmanship - don't brag about rank and qualifications. Bargaining is uncustomary.</p><p>Government offices are generally open Mon-Fri 0900-1700 in Hobart and Launceston, closing around 1630 in other regional centres. Shops see shopping.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Tasmanian Convention Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (03) 6224 6852
					Website:http://www.tasmaniaconventions.com/
					Address: 18 Elizabeth Street,Level 3,Hobart,]]><b>Tasmanian Chamber of Commerce and Industry (TCCI)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (03) 6236 3600
					Website:http://www.tcci.com.au/
					Address: 30 Burnett Street,Industry House,North Hobart,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>It may come as a surprise to the casual diner, but over the last few years Tasmania has emerged as one of the Southern Hemisphere's leading culinary destinations. Blessed with rich soil, bountiful seafood and a strong tradition of small-scale production, the Australian archipelago is outshining the mainland when it comes to cuisine.</p><p>Excellent eateries are scattered throughout Tasmania, but the capital, Hobart, boasts the highest concentration of places to eat. Local seafood is plentiful, particularly in the restaurants surrounding the docks, although all dietary requirements are catered for.</p><p>Though not much of it is exported from Tasmania, the local wine is winning plaudits around the world.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Tasmanian Atlantic salmon:</strong> Farmed and famed for its flavour.</p><p><strong>Rye whiskey gravlax:</strong> Brown trout, sea trout or salmon fillets marinated in rye whiskey with brown sugar, pepper and salt.</p><p><strong>Mt Gnomon shredded pork and Dover cherries:</strong> Shredded pork with pickled cherries and rocket served in pastry tartlets.<br/><strong>Beef: </strong>Grass fed on chemical-free pastures Tasmania's wagyu beef cattle are the envy of the world.<br/><strong>Extra virgin olive oil: </strong>Tasmanian olive oil stands comparison with the very finest Europe has to offer.<br/><strong>Wild abalone:</strong> Shellfish noted for its delicate flavour.<br/><strong>Cheese:</strong> Notables examples include Roaring Forties Blue, Ashgrove Mature Cheddar and Wicked's Triple Cream Brie)<br/><strong>Leatherwood honey:</strong> A rainforest honey renowned for its intense floral notes.<br/><strong>Black truffles:</strong> Arguably the finest truffles outside Europe.</p><p><strong>Saffron: </strong>Intensely flavoured and very high quality.<br/><strong>Wasabi:</strong> Exported to Japan and used locally in Ashgrove cheese.</p><p><strong>Lamington: </strong>Chocolate sponge cake rolled in coconut.</p><p><strong>Tasmanian apple cake: </strong>Tasmania was once known as the Apple Isle and this sponge cake can be made with sweet or sour fruit.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>As with mainland Australia, a discretionary 10% will do it.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hobart has a spirited marine atmosphere. Perky sandstone pubs, sailors and a Celtic sense of fun were carried to its ports by convicts and immigrants. Today, revellers still gravitate to the waterfront pubs and clubs, particularly the terraced strip of Salamanca Place where crowds spill outside to alfresco seating whenever weather permits.</p><p>Many night-time haunts are found in Salamanca's old stone warehouses – from historic watering holes such as Knopwoods Retreat (<a href="http://www.knopwoods.com" target="_blank">www.knopwoods.com</a>), named after a tipple-loving colonial clergy, to relative newcomers such as Jack Greene (<a href="http://www.jackgreene.com.au" target="_blank">www.jackgreene.com.au</a>). Most pubs open around 1100 and rock until the small hours of the morning.</p><p>Hobart also boasts Australia's oldest opera theatre, the Theatre Royal (<a href="http://www.theatreroyal.com.au" target="_blank">www.theatreroyal.com.au</a>), while Federation Concert Hall is home to the Tasmanian Symphony Orchestra (<a href="http://www.tso.com.au" target="_blank">www.tso.com.au</a>), widely acknowledged as one of Australia's finest orchestras.</p><p>Though small, the town of Launceston has a lively nightlife with a commendable selection of pubs, clubs and bars to keep the night owls going until the wee hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For authentic Tasmanian souvenirs, the arts and crafts stalls and antique stores of Salamanca Place, Hobart are a good place to start. The celebrated Salamanca Market, held from 0800-1500 every Saturday, brings together 300 stall holders. On top of bric-a-brac and vintage clothing, they sell everything from seasonal vegetables, organic bread and cider to pottery, jewellery and woollen clothing.</p><p>Meanwhile, the venerable Farm Gate Market offers a slice of rural life in the city. Held on the corner of Melville and Elizabeth Streets every Sunday, it features live music and numerous stores which sell everything from local cheese and jam to boutique beer. The market opens at 0900 with the ceremonial ringing of a bell.</p><p>Outside of Hobart, The Penguin Market (<a href="http://www.thepenguinmarket.com" target="_blank">www.thepenguinmarket.com</a>) is the largest undercover bazaar in Tasmania. Taking place in the town of Penguin, it takes place every Sunday between 0900 and <strong>1500. </strong>Also on Sundays is the open-air rural market in the village of Evandale, one of Tasmania's classified historic towns, a 20-minute drive south of Launceston.</p><p>In Hobart's central business district (CBD), Murray and Liverpool Streets are hubs for boutique fashion and gift stores. Similar shops can be found on Sandy Bay Road. In the CBD, chain shops and department stores mingle on Collins and Liverpool Streets, in the Centrepoint shopping centre on Murray Street and the Elizabeth Street Mall.</p><p>Most shops in main centres are open Mon-Thurs 0900-1730, with late night shopping on Friday until 2000, Saturdays 0900-1700 and increasingly prevalent Sunday trading from 1000-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are international hotels in Hobart and Launceston and a wide range of tourist hotels and motels in all the major centres. Standards vary, but ensuite, TV, tea and coffee making facilities and, sometimes, a small fridge is usual. In addition, there are holiday flats and apartments for hire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfast and cottage accommodation is available throughout the state. Accommodation is often quite luxurious.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are international hotels in Hobart and Launceston and a wide range of tourist hotels and motels in all the major centres. Standards vary, but ensuite, TV, tea and coffee making facilities and, sometimes, a small fridge is usual. In addition, there are holiday flats and apartments for hire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are international hotels in Hobart and Launceston and a wide range of tourist hotels and motels in all the major centres. Standards vary, but ensuite, TV, tea and coffee making facilities and, sometimes, a small fridge is usual. In addition, there are holiday flats and apartments for hire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>In addition, Tasmania observes all the Public Holidays observed nationwide.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Royal Hobart Regatta :
							12 February </p><p>Eight Hours Day :
							12 March </p><p>Recreation Day :
							05 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-42.000000]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[147.000000]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>68,401 sq km (26,410 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>517,200 (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>7.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hobart.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The island of Tasmania is located 240km (149 miles) south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a> across the Bass Strait. Roughly heart-shaped, Tasmania is 296km (184 miles) long, ranging from 315km (196 miles) wide in the north to 70km (44 miles) in the south.</p>
<p>The diverse landscape is comprised of rugged mountains (snow-capped in winter), dense bushland (including the Horizontal Forest, so-called because the tree trunks are bent over parallel to the ground), tranquil countryside and farmland. Approximately 40% of Tasmania is protected in national parks and other reserves, over half of this being the World Heritage-listed temperate wilderness in the west of the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Aborigines first inhabited Tasmania some 35,000 years ago, when the archipelago was still connected to mainland Australia. Rising sea levels caused by an increase in global temperatures eventually cut them off, but, despite their isolation, Tasmanian Aborigines clung on to become the most southerly race on the planet.</p>
<p>Despite surviving an ice age and the subsequent thaw, the natives could not endure the Brits, who colonised the islands in 1856 &ndash; approximately 200 years after the Dutch explorer, Abel Tasman, discovered them from the deck of his boat.</p>
<p>Britain's colonisation of Van Diemen&rsquo;s Land &ndash; as it was then known &ndash; was devastating for the aborigines, whose population crashed from 4,000 to just 200 in just three decades.</p>
<p>European illnesses were blamed for most of the indigenous deaths, but some leading historians attribute the demise of Tasmanian Aborigines to the Black War (1828-1832), a conflict between British colonialists and the natives, during which, it is claimed, the Brits committed genocide.</p>
<p>They weren&rsquo;t much kinder to their own countrymen either; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convicts_in_Australia" target="_blank">under British rule Tasmania became a notorious penal settlement</a> for the dregs of British society. By the end of convict transportation in 1853, some 75,000 of an estimated 160,000 prisoners had been banished to Van Diemen&rsquo;s Land. Approximately 12,000 wound up in the notorious prison of Port Arthur, which inmates described as &lsquo;hell on Earth.&rsquo;</p>
<p>Intended for re-offenders, Port Arthur&rsquo;s harsh history was colourfully captured in convict era novels and films &ndash; the most famous being <em>For the Term of His Natural Life</em>, based on the 1874 tome by Australian novelist Marcus Clarke.</p>
<p>In 1856 the name, Van Diemen&rsquo;s Land, was changed to Tasmania, honouring the archipelago&rsquo;s founder, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abel_Tasman" target="_blank">Abel Tasman</a> (some say this was to remove the stigma of its convict past). However, Tasmania remained part of the British Empire until 1901, when Australia gained independence. <br />
<br />
Even with the British gone, controversy has lingered in Tasmania. Since the 1970s the local government has pursued <a href="http://www.abc.net.au/news/2014-04-08/liberals-to-detail-plan-to-dismantle-foresty-peace-deal/5374746" target="_blank">a string of environmentally unfriendly policies</a>, which, critics say, undermines Tasmania&rsquo;s reputation as a wilderness destination. Opposition to such policies led to the formation of the world&rsquo;s first green party.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong> <br />
&bull;&nbsp;<span>Tasmania officially has the cleanest air in the world.</span><br />
<span>&bull;&nbsp;</span><span>The last remaining Tasmanian Aborigine, it is believed, was a woman called Truganini, whose death in 1856 extinguished a race that had been around since the last ice age.</span><span>&nbsp;</span><br />
<span>&bull; The local government&rsquo;s decision to flood Lake Pedder in the 1970s led to the formation of the world&rsquo;s first green party: The United Tasmanian Group.&nbsp;</span>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ever the bridesmaid to mainland Australia, Tasmania is finally stepping out of the shadows. The only question is: how did it take so long?</p>
<p>An archipelago of extraordinary natural beauty, tiny Tassie is similar in size to Ireland, yet it boasts a staggering diversity of landscapes; from snow-capped mountains and sweeping sandy beaches to ancient rainforest and rolling heathland.</p>
<p>Almost&nbsp;a third<strong> </strong>of the island state is set aside in national parks, most notably the Tasmanian World Heritage Wilderness Area, which is home the tallest flowering plants in the world and second tallest trees &ndash; after California&rsquo;s redwoods.</p>
<p>These forests harbour distinctive wildlife, many of which are endemic species found nowhere else on Earth. The sharp-fanged Tasmanian devil &ndash; the largest carnivorous marsupial on the planet &ndash; is perhaps the most famous example. Other favourites include the duck-billed platypus, fairy penguin and wallaby.</p>
<p>Beyond its bountiful natural assets, Tasmania is a destination of increasing cultural significance. In recent years a thriving arts scene has developed in Hobart, which gained a world-class attraction in 2011 with the opening of the Museum of Old and New Art (MONA), the largest privately-funded museum in Australia.</p>
<p>At the same time Tasmania has emerged as one of the most exciting culinary destinations in Australasia, giving the restaurants of Sydney and Melbourne a run for their money. Its success as a gastronomic destination has much to do with the island itself; not only does Tasmania boast the cleanest air in the world, but its fertile soil and pristine oceans have conspired to provide local chefs with some of the purest ingredients available.</p>
<p>It may be hard to believe today, but, for so long, Tasmania was mocked by mainlanders for its isolation and old fashioned ways. But as Australians and international tourists flock to the islands in increasing numbers, there&rsquo;s a feeling that Tasmania is having the last laugh.</p>Lush rainforests, soaring peaks, white-sand beaches and dense bushland characterise Tasmania, Australia's island state.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
