<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Victoria" ColCode="vic" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="vi" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Victoria]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot summers and relatively cool winters. Rainfall is distributed throughout the year. Southern areas can have changeable weather even in summer, often with four seasons' weather in one day.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights during summer months with warmer clothes needed during the cooler winter period, especially in southern areas and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a>. Sunglasses, sunhats and sunblock lotion are recommended for most of the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major international airlines serving <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a> include <em>British Airways</em>, <em>KLM</em>, <em>Malaysia Airlines</em>, <em>Qantas </em>and <em>United Airlines</em>. There are flights from Melbourne to all state capitals and many regional hubs. Domestic carriers include <em>Jetstar </em>(website: <a href="http://www.jetstar.com.au/" target="_blank">www.jetstar.com.au</a>), <em>Qantas </em>(website: <a href="http://www.qantas.com.au/" target="_blank">www.qantas.com.au</a>),<em> Virgin Blue </em>(website: <a href="http://www.virginblue.com.au/" target="_blank">www.virginblue.com.au</a>) and<em> Tiger Airways </em>(website: <a href="http://www.tigerairways.com.au/" target="_blank">www.tigerairways.com.au</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <strong><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a></strong> to Melbourne is 22 hours, 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Melbourne Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.melbourneairport.com.au<p>Melbourne Airport is located 25km (15 miles) northwest of Melbourne.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+61 3 9297 1600</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An overnight passenger/vehicle ferry from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/tasmania">Tasmania</a> to <strong>Melbourne</strong> departs daily (website: <u><a href="http://www.spiritoftasmania.com.au/" target="_blank">www.spiritoftasmania.com.au</a></u><a href="http://www.spiritoftasmania.com/" target="_blank"></a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>V-Line </em>(tel: (3) 9697 2076; website: <a href="http://www.vlinepassenger.com.au/" target="_blank">www.vlinepassenger.com.au</a>) operates state rail services, with links from Melbourne to Ballarat, Bendigo, Echuca, Geelong, Sale, Seymour, Swan Hill, Traralgon and Wodonga. Overnight trains link Melbourne and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales/sydney-airport">Sydney</a> (11 hours), and an overnight train <em>The Overland </em>runs to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/south-australia/adelaide-airport">Adelaide</a> (11 hours). Trains run to other main centres including Canberra (9 hours), <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/queensland/brisbane-airport">Brisbane</a> (34 hours) and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/western-australia/perth-airport">Perth</a> (73 hours).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tickets should be purchased before boarding, or from onboard vending machines (trams only; and coins only).<br><br>Fares are zonal, with travel cards for daily or weekly travel and multi-journey tickets.<br><br>If you purchase a two-hour ticket after 1800, it is valid until services stop that night.<br><br>The Melbourne <em>City Circle</em><em> </em>tram, in distinct burgundy and gold colours, is free.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Aussie Rules</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn to kick the leather off an Australian Rules or 'Aussie Rules' football. The game originated in Victoria and the climax of the season is the Australian Football League Grand Final, played in September at the famous Melbourne Cricket Ground.</p>]]><p><b>Bushwalking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Trek through destinations such as Wilson's Promontory - a three-day circuit that cuts through beautiful stretches of coastline - or the Grampians, which is a spectacular region of sandstone mountain ranges, forests and valleys. For further details, contact Parks Victoria (<a href="http://www.parkweb.vic.gov.au/" target="_blank">www.parkweb.vic.gov.au</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Dandenong Ranges</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Absorb the excellent views over Melbourne from the Dandenong Ranges. At Mount Dandenong check out the haunting carvings of Aboriginal faces - part of the Galeena Beek Aboriginal Culture Centre.</p>]]><p><b>Great Ocean drive</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drive the stunning Great Ocean Road, one of the country's most scenic routes with seemingly impossible twists and turns on a road hewn from sheer cliffs.</p>]]><p><b>Lakes District</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the Lakes District, the largest inland waterway system in the country. The lagoons connect with the ocean at Lakes Entrance, a holiday town with good facilities that has access to Ninety Mile Beach.</p>]]><p><b>Melbourne</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Frequently voted as one of the most liveable cities in the world, Melbourne's attractions include the ultramodern Melbourne Museum (<a href="http://museumvictoria.com.au/MelbourneMuseum" target="_blank">http://museumvictoria.com.au/MelbourneMuseum</a>) and fantastical Federation Square (<a href="http://www.federationsquare.com.au/" target="_blank">www.federationsquare.com.au</a>) - a city block devoted to culture.</p>]]><p><b>Murray River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Indulge in a river cruise (on a paddle steamer or hire a houseboat and have a go yourself) down the beautiful, meandering Murray River at Mildura in the far northwest of the state.</p>]]><p><b>Music Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watch the famed music festival (<a href="http://www.qmf.net.au/" target="_blank">www.qmf.net.au</a>) in Queenscliff, a town which also has Victorian architecture and a historic railway, as well as horse and cart rides. There are some great handicraft and antique shops.</p>]]><p><b>Phillip Island Nature Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spot a huge variety of wildlife at Phillip Island Nature Park (<a href="http://www.penguins.org.au/" target="_blank">www.penguins.org.au</a>), with birds, koalas, fairy penguins (marching up the beach in the evenings) and fur seals. Another famous wildlife area crawling with emus and wombats is Wilson's Promontory National Park.</p>]]><p><b>Ski and snowboard</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whizz down the country's best snowfields on downhill skis or a snowboard through some of Victoria's high country: Mount Buller, Falls Creek, Mount Hotham, Mount Buffalo and Mount Baw Baw all have excellent facilities.</p>]]><p><b>Sovereign Hill</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relive the excitement of the gold-rush at Sovereign Hill (<a href="http://www.sovereignhill.com.au/" target="_blank">www.sovereignhill.com.au</a>), 120km (75 miles) northwest of Melbourne in Ballarat, an old gold mining town, restored to its original condition. For a similar era, try Bendigo with its huge granite, Victorian buildings.</p>]]><p><b>Surf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ride world-class waves at Bells Beach on the Great Ocean Road near Torquay, where the Rip Curl Pro, a world championship surfing contest, is held annually over Easter. Woolamai in Phillip Island offers excellent surfing for the more experienced.</p>]]><p><b>Whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whale watch along the south coast, especially at Warrnambool, where migrating whales can be observed between July and September.</p>]]><p><b>Wine tasting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit some of Australia's best wineries. Outstanding wine-growing regions include the Yarra Valley; the Mornington Peninsula; and the Rutherglen Region in the Grampians. The Victorian Wineries Tourism Council (<a href="http://www.visitvictoria.com/wineries" target="_blank">www.visitvictoria.com/wineries</a>) can provide further details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Melbourne, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>'s second-largest city and gateway to the southern region, has convention facilities to match international standards - the Melbourne Exhibition and Convention Centre is the largest exhibition space in the southern hemisphere with 50 meeting rooms, 10,000 sq m (108,000 sq ft) of exhibition space and three state-of-the-art theatres.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits are a must when conducting business in well-dressed <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a>, the capital of Victoria, and all appointments must be arranged in advance. Like much of Melbourne life, business is conducted over coffee. Breakfast meetings or drinks at a stylish bar are also favoured, although long business lunches are generally a thing of the past. Australian businesspeople are, on the whole, very approachable, quite informal and quick to use first names. Business cards are used. If invited to someone's home, a bottle of wine, flowers and/or chocolates would be appreciated as a gift for the host.</p><p>Normal business hours are Monday to Friday 0900-1730, although many executives work longer hours; government offices may close at 1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Victorian Employers' Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (3) 8662 5333
					Website:http://www.vecci.org.au/
					Address: 486 Albert Street,Industry House,East Melbourne,]]><b>Melbourne Convention and Visitors Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (3) 9693 3333
					Website:http://www.mcvb.com.au/
					Address: IBM Centre,Level 12,60 City Road,]]><b>Melbourne Convention and Visitors Bureau in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01753) 481 540
					Website:http://www.mcvb.com.au/
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Melbourne has a nationwide reputation for its food scene. There is an enormous variety of cuisine available, and restaurants offering specific types can be found in different areas of the city: Lygon Street for Italian, Little Bourke Street for Chinese, Lonsdale Street for Greek, Victoria Street for Vietnamese, Sydney Road for Turkish and Johnston Street for Spanish. Other cuisines that are well represented in the city's restaurants include French, American, Mexican, Lebanese, African, Malaysian, Afghan, Swiss and Mongolian.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Fish is excellent, particularly the signature Murray cod. Also try trout, flathead and yellow perch. <br />&bull; Meats such as beef, lamb and kangaroo. <br />&bull; Cheeses, such as the creamy sheep's milk cheese from Highland Farm.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a> is home to a vibrant and varied entertainment culture. See ballet, classical concerts, opera and plays in Melbourne's ornate theatres.<br />
<br />
Fitzroy is one of the best neighbourhoods for traditional pubs, stylish bars, cafes and live music. The city is well regarded for its live music scene and venues vary from major performance venues to backstreet pubs. Beachside St Kilda has one of the best - The Esplanade Hotel, or Espy, as well as a burgeoning cafe scene. Chapel St in South Yarra is where to head if you fancy mingling with the beautiful people.<br />
<br />
The central business district hosts a plethora of very stylish bars, the best of which are normally tucked away down narrow streets and laneways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional sheepskins and the Australian's answer to the raincoat - the drizabone - can be found here. Iconic Akubra hats are found in shops around Flinders Street train station. Local wines from the Yarra Valley are very popular buys.<br />
<br />
<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a> is a major fashion centre, home to world-famous surfing brand Quiksilver, and shoppers looking for Australian and international designer wear should head for the city arcades - South Yarra or Lygon Street in Carlton. Unusual buys and bargains, as well as a festive atmosphere, can be had at the Queen Victoria Market. For some beautiful, unique and individually crafted jewellery head for the Rose Street Artists Market in Fitzroy.</p><p>Mon-Wed 0900-1730; Thurs and Fri 0900-1730 but some will have a late-night shopping policy and stay open until 1900 or even 2100; Sat and Sun 0900-1730 but some may not open until 1100 or 1200. Most major supermarkets are open 24 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A variety of hotel accommodation is available in Victoria, ranging from 4- and 5-star international-standard hotels in the cities, to basic motels throughout the region. Standards vary, but ensuite, TV, drink-making facilities and, sometimes, a small fridge is the norm. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a> in particular has some very stylish, cutting-edge hotels. Book ahead over summer and holiday periods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These range from quiet lodges and cottages to historic houses, farms and classic guest houses. Farmstays offer the opportunity to stay in a family homestead whilst participating in farm activities. Further information can be obtained from Tourism Victoria (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A variety of hotel accommodation is available in Victoria, ranging from 4- and 5-star international-standard hotels in the cities, to basic motels throughout the region. Standards vary, but ensuite, TV, drink-making facilities and, sometimes, a small fridge is the norm. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a> in particular has some very stylish, cutting-edge hotels. Book ahead over summer and holiday periods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A variety of hotel accommodation is available in Victoria, ranging from 4- and 5-star international-standard hotels in the cities, to basic motels throughout the region. Standards vary, but ensuite, TV, drink-making facilities and, sometimes, a small fridge is the norm. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a> in particular has some very stylish, cutting-edge hotels. Book ahead over summer and holiday periods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>In addition, Victoria observes all the Public Holidays observed nationwide.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Labour Day :
							12 March </p><p>Queen's Birthday Celebrations :
							11 June </p><p>Melbourne Cup Day :
							06 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-38.272689]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[143.261719]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>227,416 sq km (87,806 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>26.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Melbourne.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Victoria is <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>'s most diverse state and its major agricultural and industrial producer. Located in the southeast, bordered by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/south-australia">South Australia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/new-south-wales">New South Wales</a>, its landscape consists of mountains, rainforests, deserts, snowfields, beaches, vineyards, wheatlands and market gardens. The Australian Alps are only three hours away from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria/melbourne-airport">Melbourne</a> and the Great Ocean Road to South Australia is a day's drive. Victoria has 32 national parks, amounting to a third of Australia's total.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Victoria is <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> in miniature: the state crams snow-capped mountain country, epic seascapes, wineries, rainforests and the country's largest inland waterway into its modest borders. Not to mention, of course, the eminently lovable metropolis that is Melbourne. The state capital famously has an intense rivalry with <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/sydney">Sydney</a>, but even a few New South Welshmen would concede Melbourne&rsquo;s claim to being Australia's cultural capital.</p>
<p>The city &ndash; chock-full of galleries, heritage architecture, museums, sporting events and festivals &ndash; has a distinct set of passions, from Aussie Rules football (known universally as &ldquo;footie&rdquo;) to top-tier gastronomy. It&rsquo;s no exaggeration, in fact, to state that Melbourne now stands as a world-class food destination, a status stoked by its vivid multiculturalism.</p>
<p>But you won&rsquo;t need to travel far from the city to experience what else Victoria has to share. Natural features come big and bold down here, from the Great Ocean Road (considered to be one of the best scenic drives in Australia) to the Grampians. The wildlife roster, meanwhile, makes space for wombats, wallabies, emus and everything in between.</p>
<p>Referred to as the Garden State, Victoria ripples with rolling hills and meandering valleys &ndash; its mountains offer some of the best winter sports in the country &ndash; but the state as a whole is also somewhere rich in human history. From the age-old beliefs of the original landowners and the derring-do tales of Ned Kelly to the stirring legacy of the Gold Rush era and the pioneering winemakers of Milawa, the destination holds real rewards for those who travel beyond <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/melbourne">Melbourne</a> and its surrounds.</p>Victoria is Australia in miniature: the state crams snow-capped mountain country, searing deserts, wineries, rainforests and the country's largest inland waterway into its pint-sized borders.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
