<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Azerbaijan" ColCode="aze" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="az" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Azerbaijan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best time to visit Azerbaijan is during spring (March-June) when the weather is warm and the foliage is in full bloom. The summer months (July-September) can be oppressively hot and humid, particularly in the capital, Baku, but they are also the best months to go hiking in the mountains.</p>
<p>Although temperatures along the Caspian coastline remain mild throughout winter (November-February), the mercury dip well below freezing further inland. The mountains at this time of the year are covered in snow and very treacherous. Though downpours do occur throughout the country, most of the rainfall is confined to the west.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Light-weight clothing is fine for low-lying destination in the summer months, but coats and sweaters are advised at other times. Bring warm clothing if you are heading to the mountains, which remain chilly throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Azerbaijan Airlines (<a href="http://www.azal.az" target="_blank">www.azal.az</a>) operates several flights a day between Baku and the Azeri 'exclave' of Nakhchivan, which is cut off from the rest of Azerbaijan by Armenia. There are also connections from Baku to Ganja, Gabala, Yevlakh, Zaqatala and Lankaran.</p>
<p>Although distances appear short on the map, if time is tight air travel knocks several hours off a road journey. Tickets at short notice are widely available throughout the year, except on national holidays when many Baku residents like to visit their family in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rail connections are slow but fares are very reasonable. The main routes from Baku are northwest to the Georgian border and Caucasus Mountains and south to Astara and Iran. Visit <a href="http://www.railway.gov.az" target="_blank">www.railway.gov.az</a> for more details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Azerbaijan's recent prosperity means that the number of cars on the road is in danger of exceeding the road capacity, although new highways are under construction throughout the country.</p>
<p>Visitors should note that many local drivers do not adhere to traffic regulations; it is estimated that almost half of all drivers have not passed a test but obtained their licence through 'connections'.</p>
<p>Self-drive is only recommended to seasoned motorists, but alert and confident drivers may relish the freedom to visit those out-of-the-way beauty spots. Traffic police are numerous and keen to fine visitors and locals alike for speeding offences.</p>r<p>Road conditions away from Baku are often pretty poor and 4-wheel-drive vehicles are recommended for journeys into the mountains. Roads are rarely lit outside major towns.</p><p>Mtrans (tel: +994 12 499 7038; <a href="http://www.mtrans.az/index.php/eng/" target="_blank">www.mtrans.az</a>) runs regular services between Baku and most major towns. The buses are modern, comfortable and a relatively inexpensive way of travelling around Azerbaijan.</p><p>Taxis are widely available in both cities and rural areas. Agree a fare before setting off; meters are not widely used and the initial fares suggested may be high. It is often possible to hire a taxi for a day's sightseeing at prices comparable to self-drive. Drivers are usually competent but are prone to driving alarmingly fast.</p><p>An International Driving Permit or licence issued by an EU country is required. Also carry the vehicle registration document, your passport, proof of insurance and a check-up card that proves the vehicle has passed its annual roadworthiness test.</p><p>U-turns are banned, as is driving while using a mobile phone. Note that left-hand turns across the traffic are forbidden. Seat belts are compulsory. There is zero tolerance for driving under the influence of drink. Speed limits are 40-60kph (25-37mph) in residential zones, 90kph on the open road and 110kph (68mph) on highways.</p><p>Your car hire company may be able to help but there is no official organisation.</p><p>International car hire firms including Hertz and Avis are based in downtown Baku, along with many local firms. The legal minimum age to hire a car is 21. To book a car at Baku airport, contact Tipoa Car Hire (<a href="http://tipoa.com" target="_blank">tipoa.com</a>) or 3 Click Car Hire (<a href="http://www.3clickcarhire.com" target="_blank">www.3clickcarhire.com</a>). &nbsp;</p><p>There are very few push bikes in Baku and local drivers have little experience sharing the roads with bikes. Not recommended.</p><p>U-turns are banned, as is driving while using a mobile phone. Note that left-hand turns across the traffic are forbidden. Seat belts are compulsory. There is zero tolerance for driving under the influence of drink. Speed limits are 40-60kph (25-37mph) in residential zones, 90kph on the open road and 110kph (68mph) on highways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Baku's metro mainly connects the suburbs to the centre and so most visitors use taxis or private cars for trips within the city centre. Buses to the suburbs are cheap but often overcrowded. Public transport is very safe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Azerbaijan Airlines (<a href="http://www.azal.az" target="_blank">www.azal.az</a>) operates regular flights to Azerbaijan from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ankara">Ankara</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/barcelona">Barcelona</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/milan">Milan</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dubai">Dubai</a>, Tehran and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tel-aviv">Tel Aviv</a>. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) also runs direct flights from London to Baku.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/azerbaijan/baku-heydar-aliyev-international-airport">Baku Heydar Aliyev International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 5 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 10 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Heydar Aliyev International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport.az<p>The airport is 25km (16 miles) east of Baku (journey time - 40 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are few options for those wishing to travel to Azerbaijan by boat, although it is not impossible.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Azerbaijan is connected to Tbilisi in Georgia by an overnight sleeper train, which departs from the Georgian capital every night: journey time is 18 hours. Tickets should be bought at the station on Tbilisi.</p>
<p>In theory, you can buy tickets for the trip from Baku back to Tbilisi online via the Azerbaijan Railways website (<a href="http://railway.gov.az" target="_blank">railway.gov.az</a>), which requires you to register before purchasing tickets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Long-distance bus services from Istanbul and other Turkish cities eventually wind up in Baku (with a change in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/georgia">Georgia</a>). Motorists can follow the same route. The most popular way to arrive by road is from Tbilisi in Georgia, via Lagodekhi and Balakan. Coming from  <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iran">Iran</a> the most convenient border crossing is Astara.</p><p>Road routes to and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a> are currently barred to foreigners because of security problems in Dagestan and Chechnya. The border with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/armenia">Armenia</a> is closed due to ongoing tension between the two countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International calls from Azerbaijan may be dialed directly from Baku and some other towns throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is mostly limited to the capital and main towns and is non-existent in many mountain areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in all cities and towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of state-run and public media outlets that compete with private and opposition publications and private broadcasters. Despite official freedom of speech, the Azeri media is tightly controlled and very self-censoring.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International postal services are sometimes disrupted. Delays occur, although letters should normally take 10 to 14 days to arrive. Parcels should be registered or sent by courier services to accelerate the process and ensure against loss.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Baku, Museums</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Baku is home to several excellent museums including the Azerbaijan Carpet Museum, Azerbaijan National Art Museum and National History Museum.</p>
<p><strong>Azerbaijan Carpet Museum</strong></p>
<p>Located in a building modelled on the shape of a rolled carpet, this museum showcases a rich collection of beautiful carpets and artifacts. If you want to purchase a beautiful Azerbaijan carpet, we recommend you to get one from the shop at the Carpet Museum and keep the certificate with you. All carpets must have a certificate stating the price and the age of the carpet. Please note that anything more than 30 years old is subject to an export tax and must be approved by the Ministry of Culture.</p>
<p><strong>Azerbaijan National Art Museum</strong></p>
<p>This extensive collection displays Azeri, Russian and worldwide art from prehistoric times to modern movements, housed in two adjacent buildings. The local modern art is particularly interesting.</p>
<p><strong>National History Museum</strong></p>
<p>Housed in an oil baron's sumptuous Belle &Eacute;poque mansion in central Baku, this informative museum provides a detailed overview of Azerbaijan's history with plenty of striking exhibits from Bronze Age jewellery to Ruritanian military costumes, all with English-language explanations. The no-expense-spared interior design and plush furnishings of the old house are also of interest.</p>]]><p><b>Baku, stroll along Baku Boulevard</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a stroll along Baku's tree-lined promenade for sea breezes, manicured gardens and soothing water fountains. A Ferris wheel offers fine panoramas of the Caspian Sea, while inviting garden caf&eacute;s can be found scattered along the leafy promenade. Typically, the evening is the best time to visit when locals go to walk off dinner.</p>]]><p><b>Baku, the Old City (Icheri Sheher)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the fabulous I&ccedil;eri Seher (or Icheri Sheher), the walled old city of Baku and a UNESCO World Heritage site. The narrow streets, honey-coloured city walls, caravanserais, quaint houses and mosques provide a nostalgic glimpse of old Baku before the oil boom of the 20th century created the modern city. Stop for tea in one of many atmospheric cafes and drink in the views. Famous sights within the Old City include the Maiden Tower and Palace of the Shirvanshahs.</p>
<p><strong>Maiden Tower</strong></p>
<p>Climb the spiral staircases inside Maiden's Tower, which overlooks the Caspian, and marvel at the stunning 360-degree view of the city from 30m up. Informative multi-lingual touch-screen installations provide a fascinating overview of the building's history, from 500BC onwards. It was rebuilt as a fortress in the 12th century.</p>
<p><strong>Palace of the Shirvanshahs</strong></p>
<p>This is the largest monument in Baku's Old City and dates from the 15th century. Painstaking restoration and imaginative new displays give a flavour of the rich and cultured lifestyle of the Persian Sufi ruling dynasty - the music, the paradise gardens, the lovely art and sumptuous costumes. The upper stories were blown away by an early Russian naval bombardment in the 18th century.</p>]]><p><b>Beşbarmaq dağı (Besh Barmag Mountain)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join mystic-minded Azeris on a climb up Beşbarmaq dağı (Five Finger Mountain), which rises dramatically 520m (1,706ft) above the coast just north of Baku and is one of Azerbaijan's most holy animist sites. Rock has been worn smooth by devout kisses and Tibetan-style prayer flags festoon the bushes. Prayers are led by mullahs but the mountain was considered sacred long before the advent of Islam.</p>]]><p><b>Fire Mountain (Yanar Dag)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watch the flames dance at Fire Mountain (Yanar Dag), a 30 minutes' drive from Baku, where a 10m (33ft) wall of fire blazes day and night thanks to underground natural gas. The spectacle is more impressive after dark.</p>]]><p><b>Gobustan National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>About an hour's drive from Baku is Gobustan National Park which is famous for three things: prehistoric rock carvings, mud volcanoes and Gaval Dash (musical stone).</p>
<p><strong>Prehistoric rock carvings</strong></p>
<p>The area is said to have been inhabited continuously for at least 20,000 years and early inhabitants have left striking petroglyphs of giraffes, elephants, aurochs, lions, shamans and tattooed dancers. Archaeologists believe that the first humans to migrate out of Africa also stopped here. It is a UNESCO World Heritage site and contains the earliest known representation of a boat.</p>
<p><strong>Mud volcanoes</strong></p>
<p>Bubbling out of the lonely hills of Gobustan, these enchanting mud volcanoes offer the chance to witness geology in action. The mud is reputed to have therapeutic properties, but don't get too close: it is boiling and from time to time splutters out in a great ball of fire.</p>
<p><strong>Gaval Dash (musical stone)</strong></p>
<p>This big flat stone makes a tambourine-like sound when it is hit with an object, quite a surreal experience.</p>]]><p><b>Kiş, Sheki</b></p><![CDATA[<p>High on a hillside above Sheki, this tiny village serves up a traditional slice of Azeri life. It's also home to a charming 12th century church which captivated the&nbsp;late Norwegian explorer, Thor Heyerdahl, who believed the original Norse gods were Azerbaijanis who migrated to Scandinavia during the Roman period.</p>]]><p><b>Lahıc, Ismailli</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Shop for exquisite copper products in the Persian mountain town of Lahic, where great hiking, charming architecture and natural beauty combine for the ultimate mountain escape. Workshops, smithies and craft shops line the cobbled streets and the tourist office can help arrange homestays with local families.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Shirvanshah Palace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This is the largest monument in Baku&rsquo;s Old City and dates from the 15th century. Painstaking restoration and imaginative new displays give a flavour of the rich and cultured lifestyle of the Persian Sufi ruling dynasty &ndash; the music, the paradise gardens, the lovely art and sumptuous costumes. The upper stories were blown away by an early Russian naval bombardment in the 18th century.</p>]]><p><b>Shaki</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover Shaki, one of Azerbaijan's most beautiful towns, which nestles in the foothills of the Caucasus Mountains. Highlights include Khan's Palace, which is set in ornamental Persian gardens and contains stunning murals and stained glass, and the Karavansarai Hotel, whose faded charm captures the once thriving days of the Silk Road.</p>]]><p><b>Sirvan National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get your binoculars out at Sirvan National Park. Due south of Gobustan, this little-visited slice of coastal wilderness is well worth exploring. The birdlife is outstanding, particularly during the spring and autumn migrations, and is easily viewed from lakeside platforms. Also on display are Azerbaijan's last goitered gazelles and their antagonists: wolves. Wild boar and jungle cats are also common.</p>]]><p><b>Surakhani, Ateshgah of Baku</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Uncover glimpses of the ancient Persian religion of Zoroastrianism at the Ateshgah Fire Temple (also known as the 'Fire Temple of Baku' in Surakhany. Flames lick from torches on the roof of the temple, which was established by the Indian Parsee fire-worshippers who lived in Baku in the 18th century. Zoroastrians still occasionally stage ritual dances here.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the views from Maiden's Tower</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Climb the spiral staircases inside Maiden's Tower, which overlooks the Caspian in the I&ccedil;eri Seher, and marvel at the stunning 360-degree view of the city from 30m up. Informative multi-lingual touch-screen installations provide a fascinating overview of the building&rsquo;s history, from 500BC onwards. It was rebuilt as a fortress in the 12th century.</p>]]><p><b>Travel back to the Stone Age at Gobustan Petroglyphs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The area has been inhabited continuously for at least 20,000 years and early inhabitants have left striking petroglyphs of giraffes, elephants, aurochs, lions, shamans and tattooed dancers. Archaeologists believe that the first humans to migrate out of Africa also stopped here. It is a UNESCO World Heritage site and contains the earliest known representation of a boat.</p>]]><p><b>Xinaliq</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the remote mountain village of Xinaliq, where you can find a unique ethnic group of proto-Caucasians who have inhabited this part of the mountains since the Bronze Age and have preserved their original language, customs and traditions. The best option to Xinaliq is to rent a car or share a jeep with others from Quba; the journey is about 1 hour and 25 minutes. Don your hiking boots as there are several great hikes around Xinaliq including the trail that connects Xinaliq and Laza.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$37.85billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil, gas, cotton, machinery, foodstuffs.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, equipment, metals, chemicals and foodstuffs.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Italy, France, Russia, Germany and Turkey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Azerbaijan's economy is centered on its large oil and gas industry. Most of the reserves are located in the Caspian Sea basin and the Azeri government has signed a number of major deals with a variety of consortia for the exploration and development of various offshore fields.</p>
<p>Construction, banking, tourism and real estate have also shown recent growth.</p>
<p>Literacy for both men and women nudges 100%. The currency unit is the Manat, which is conveniently close in value to the Euro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Doing business in Azerbaijan is quite straightforward but your success often depends on who you know. All documents should be translated into Azeri and you may need a local fixer/translator. Be prepared to take your time and drink lots of chai &ndash; the delicious, low-tannin local tea. Azeris are no pushover and are renowned for their negotiating skills.</p>
<p>Business attire is similar to that in southern Europe for both men and women. A smart look is the norm. Suits are widely worn but in summer a short-sleeved shirt is suffice.</p>
<p>Local businesswomen wear sharp skirts and high heels but you may want to check the uneven pavements before copying. July and August are searingly hot with temperatures in Baku approaching 40C and winters are cold and windy. Dress accordingly.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 370001 ,(12) 928 912
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]><b>US-Azerbaijan Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (202) 333 8702
					Website:http://www.usacc.org/
					Address: NW,1212 Potomac Street,Washington DC 20007,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Azerbaijani food combines Turkish and central Asian elements. While Baku has an excellent selection of international restaurants, from Japanese fusion to Italian, in most rural restaurants the kebab is most definitely king.</p>
<p>Azeris reckon their tomatoes are the best in the world and there is some justification for this. A special place in the cuisine also belongs to lamb kebabs, of which there are many different varieties. Sumac, a purple powder derived from dried berries, adds a zesty citron flavour to plainly grilled meat.</p>
<p>Hand-cut chips, made from locally-grown potatoes, are excellent. Vegetarians will end up eating a great deal of salad and lentil soup as most dishes contain meat. In the <em>chaikhanas</em> (tea houses), men linger for hours drinking sweet black tea out of tiny glasses and playing <em>nard</em> (backgammon).</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Lule kebab:</strong> Spiced, minced lamb pressed on to skewers and grilled.<br />
<strong>Dograma:</strong> A milky potato, cucumber and onion soup served cold.<br />
<strong>Piti:</strong> Mutton and chickpea soup &ndash; a Sheki speciality.<br />
<strong>Qutab:</strong> Pancakes stuffed with spinach, herbs or meat.<br />
<strong>Badimjan dolmasi:</strong> Lamb and herb-stuffed trio of aubergine, tomato and green pepper.<br />
<strong>Dushpara:</strong> Soup made with mutton stock containing small pieces of pasta.<br />
<strong>Toyuk levengisi:</strong> Chicken stuffed with nuts and dried fruits.<br />
<strong>Shirin plov:</strong> Meat and rice pilaf with nuts and dried fruit.<br />
<strong>Monastirski:</strong> Chicken or lamb topped with melted cheese and pomegranate sauce.<br />
<strong>Coban salatasi:</strong> Finely chopped tomatoes, onions, cucumber and herbs.<br />
<strong>Local wine:</strong> Improving all the time and a reasonably priced alternative to expensive foreign imports.<br />
<strong>Xirdalan:</strong> The favoured local beer.<br />
<strong>Shabat:</strong> A soft iced drink made of sugar, various fruits and herbs.<br />
<strong>Chai:</strong> Tea, served black in a glass with lemon and sugar to taste.<br />
<strong>Darchin chai:</strong> Tea, flavoured with cinnamon, ginger and, occasionally, rosewater.<br />
<strong>Su:</strong> Mineral water from the mountains available either naturally carbonated or still.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Although the majority of Azeris are nominally Shia Muslims, alcohol is widely available.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Expected by waiters in most restaurants. 10% is fine.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nightlife in Baku can be quiet or frenetic - take your pick. There are plenty of glitzy clubs (with prices to match) where you can dance until dawn. The names and locations change with dizzying speed. Dress to impress – in this town you can never wear too much bling.</p><p>The downtown area around Fountains Square is where many of the most popular bars and pubs are located. As the names suggest, places like O'Malley's, the Clansman and the Shakespeare, are lively ex-pat hangouts.</p><p>Many bars are in the basement and incredibly hot and smoky. The cafe-bars on the Boulevard are a quieter and classier alternative. Azeri bars are quite simple and serve mainly beer and Russian vodka. The top hotels have their own niche bars and nightclubs and there are a handful of jazz clubs downtown. Baku is a safe city to walk around, even by night.</p><p>If your taste inclines more towards classical productions, catch a performance at the Azerbaijan State Academic Opera and Ballet Theater. The art nouveau-style building is magnificent and tickets are not expensive. The Azerbaijan State Philharmonic Hall holds regular orchestral concerts.</p><p>Outside Baku it is more a case of making your own entertainment. Bars are rare outside hotels and country Azeris love to sit and talk well into the night over endless pots of tea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The top souvenir to bring back from Azerbaijan is undoubtedly a traditional carpet, either woolen or silk. Most are in the sumptuous Persian style, although some are rather plainer and more ethnic. There are seven main centres of carpet manufacture: Baku, Shirvan, Guba, Tabriz, Karabakh, Genca and Gazakh. Each region had its own technology, typical patterns and colours.</p>
<p>If you are in the market for one of these beauties, a visit to the Carpet Museum on Baku&rsquo;s Boulevard is recommended to get an idea of the range of styles and colours. Then it&rsquo;s on to one of the carpet shops in Icheri Sheher, the Old Town. You may be able to haggle about the price over glasses of chai, but the days when you could pick up a bargain are long gone. However, you will return home with a stunning work of art.</p>
<p>Traditional earthenware pottery and ceramics in Oriental blue shades can be found throughout the country. Caviar from the Caspian Sea is no longer the bargain that it once was; pollution and over-fishing mean that the mighty sturgeon which produces these sought-after eggs is now rare. However, it is still approximately half the price of tins in the West.</p>
<p>In Baku, a trip to the Taza bazaar is recommended; it is where locals shop for the freshest fruit and vegetables. If you are the market for a chicken, granny will wring its neck, pluck and draw it before your eyes. There are also plenty of reasonably-priced handicrafts. Unlike many Oriental bazaars it is a friendly place with no aggressive salesmanship.</p>
<p>In the north, Sheki&rsquo;s strategic location on the Silk Road has endowed it with centuries of silk-making expertise. The town's silk factory has a shop attached; both quality and prices are high. Tourist shops also sell silk items; scarves make colourful and highly portable mementos.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-2000.</p><p>Any carpet or artefact more than 30 years old is subject to an export tax and must be certified for export by the Ministry of Culture. Even new carpets require a certificate stating the price and the age of the carpet. Items purchased at tourist shops should already be duly certified and the shop owner should be able to help you with any paperwork. Goods sold at markets or by private individuals may be more problematic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major hotel chains, including Hyatt, Meridian and Radisson  have sprung up across the capital, Baku, in recent years. Most other hotels are privately owned and standards of hygiene, service and catering have improved a great deal since the arrival of multinational hoteliers. Most hotels have Wi-Fi and satellite television.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major hotel chains, including Hyatt, Meridian and Radisson  have sprung up across the capital, Baku, in recent years. Most other hotels are privately owned and standards of hygiene, service and catering have improved a great deal since the arrival of multinational hoteliers. Most hotels have Wi-Fi and satellite television.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major hotel chains, including Hyatt, Meridian and Radisson  have sprung up across the capital, Baku, in recent years. Most other hotels are privately owned and standards of hygiene, service and catering have improved a great deal since the arrival of multinational hoteliers. Most hotels have Wi-Fi and satellite television.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The health service provides free medical treatment for all citizens. However, state-run services in Azerbaijan are limited. All visitors are advised to take out comprehensive travel insurance. It is advisable to take a supply of those medicines that are likely to be required (but check first that they may be legally imported). Travellers are advised to take out an insurance policy which includes emergency repatriation in case of serious illness or accident.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Some parts of Baku have their own water supply from natural mineral springs. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Vaccinations against hepatitis B and tuberculosis are sometimes advised. There may be some risk of meningitis, tick-borne encephalitis and leishmaniasis. Rabies is present in some areas. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following Monday.  Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here:</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							2018<br/>20 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Victory Day :
							09 May </p><p>Republic Day :
							28 May </p><p>National Salvation Day :
							15 June </p><p>Army and Navy Day :
							26 June </p><p>Independence Day :
							18 October </p><p>Constitution Day :
							12 November </p><p>National Revival Day :
							17 November </p><p>Day of Azeri Solidarity :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Azerbaijan by persons over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 600 cigarettes.<br />
&bull; 3L of alcohol.<br />
&bull; Goods up to a value of US$1,500.<br />
&bull; 10kg of food products.<br />
&bull; 125g of caviar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Weapons and ammunition, narcotics, and material inciting violence or terrorism.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Plants, animals and their products must be accompanied by the appropriate import certificate from the State Sanitary Service or State Veterinary Service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Weapons and ammunition, cultural artefacts (unless permission has been granted by the Ministry of Culture), zoological collections, protected plant and tree species, and documents of state importance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Azeri New Manat (AZN)= 100 gopik. Notes are in denominations of 100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 AZN. Coins are in denominations of 50, 20, 10, 5, 3 and 1 gopik.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollars, Pounds Sterling and Euros are the preferred currencies and can be exchanged at the airport, bureaux de change, all hotels, some restaurants and major banks. However, many local hotels, bureaux de change and restaurants will not accept dollar bills dated before 1992 or those which are torn or in any way disfigured. Travellers are advised to take banknotes in small denominations and change small amounts of money as required. Rates offered by banks and bureaux de change are unlikely to vary significantly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some major credit cards are accepted in Baku, at large hotels, restaurants and banks. However, generally, Azerbaijan is a cash-only economy. Credit cards can be used to purchase tickets at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not generally accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Azerbaijan, a passport valid for at least three months after the date of visa expiry is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>No transit visa is needed for onward travel within 24 hours of arrival in Azerbaijan, provided you remain in the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prices vary depending on the type of visa and nationality of the applicant.  Australian, Canadian, UK and US nationals: &pound;18 (single-entry visa); &pound;265 (multiple-entry visa). A service charge of &pound;24 (single-entry visas) or &pound;60 (multiple-entry visas) applies in addition to the visa fee. Prices vary for nationals from the EU; contact the embassy for details.</p>
<p>Visas obtained via the electronic visa system (https://evisa.gov.az/en) pay US$23.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visas: valid for 90 days from the date of issue for stays of up to 30 days.</p>
<p>Multiple-entry visas: valid for 12 months from the date of issue for stays of up to 90 days or 180 days in total, depending on the visa category.</p>
<p>If entering as a tourist, you are only eligible for a single-entry visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).&nbsp;EU and EEA nationals resident in the UK, Ireland, Iceland and Denmark may apply for a visa through the Azerbaijan Visa Centre (<a target="_blank" style="color: rgb(2, 122, 198); text-decoration: none; " href="http://www.visaforazerbaijan.org.uk">www.visaforazerbaijan.org.uk</a>) which processes visas on behalf of the Embassy of the Republic of Azerbaijan (additional application fees apply, see above). You can also apply for an e-visa online through the Ministry of Foreign Affairs website (<a target="_blank" style="color: rgb(2, 122, 198); text-decoration: none; " href="http://evisa.mfa.gov.az">evisa.mfa.gov.az</a>). Some travel agents based in Azerbaijan are able to apply for an e-visa on your behalf; check with the embassy for a current list.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All nationals intending to stay more than 30 days must register for a residence card via the State Migration Service (<a href="http://www.migration.gov.az">www.migration.gov.az</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are issued within 10 working days. An urgent service is available with a processing time of six days for an extra charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For visa extensions (up to three months), contact the State Migration Service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[40.355978]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[47.869031]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>86,600 sq km (33,400 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>9,915,179 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>112.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Baku.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Azerbaijan is bordered by the Russian Federation, Georgia, Iran and Armenia. Much of Southwestern Azerbaijan in the ethnically Armenian region of Nagorno-Karabakh is occupied by Armenian forces following the Armenia-Azerbaijan war (1988-1994). Azerbaijan also includes the exclave of Nakhchivan, which is located between Turkey, Iran and Armenia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mostly Shia Muslim although there are Russian Orthodox and Jewish communities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign women should dress modestly, especially in the rural areas, and cultivate a certain coolness of manner. Both men and women should avoid wearing shorts as this will attract unwelcome attention. Although mostly Muslim in population, Azerbaijan is a largely secular society that views religion as a private matter. Handshaking is the normal form of greeting. Business cards are invariably exchanged at any kind of official meeting, and not infrequently on first meeting socially as well. It's always a good idea to give gifts to people you meet, business contacts. Flowers, post-cards, picture books and alcohol make excellent presents.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Novruz Mammadov since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Ilham Aliyev since 2003.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Over the centuries, Azerbaijan has enjoyed only brief periods of independent statehood, in between longer periods spent incorporated into major regional empires.</p>
<p>Amongst the first to arrive were the Arabs, who marched into The Caucasus in the 7th century and established Islam as the predominant religion. They were followed by the Seljuk Turks who, by the 11th century, had leveraged their growing influence on the region and made Turkish the main language in the territory. Thereafter, Azerbaijan was influenced by both the <a href="http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic/434996/Ottoman-Empire" target="_blank">Ottoman Turks</a>, lying on the border of their empire, and the Iranians, from whom they acquired an adherence to the Shia branch of Islam.</p>
<p>In 1812, the Russians, in the course of their march southwards, took over the northern part of Azerbaijan; the southern part remained a province of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iran">Iran</a>. A series of wars ensued between the two powers, from which <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a> emerged victorious. But then came WWI, which, in 1917, brought about the collapse of the Russian Empire and, consequently, Azerbaijan's freedom.</p>
<p>The years that followed were prosperous for the young nation. A Caspian Sea oil boom brought great wealth to the country and transformed its capital, Baku, into an industrial centre. But this golden era was short lived. In 1920 the Russians returned, marching into oil-rich Azerbaijan to establish a puppet state known as the Azerbaijan Soviet Socialist Republic.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The most prominent politician to emerge during the Soviet period was Heydar Aliyev, successively head of the Azerbaijan KGB, leader of the Republic itself, and then a full member of the Soviet Politburo. He would play a decisive role in post-Soviet Azerbaijan, the seeds of which were sewn when the Soviet Union crumbled towards the end of the 1980s.</p>
<p>During this time the issue of Nagorno-Karabakh &ndash; an autonomous enclave inside Azeri territory with an overwhelming Armenian majority &ndash; proved critical to Azerbaijan's political development.&nbsp;Serious internal problems and a failure to make any progress on Karabakh led to a military coup and paved the way for the return of Heydar Aliyev. He succeeded in tackling the two most pressing issues: stabilising the political situation in the country and negotiating a truce in the Nagorno-Karabakh War.</p>
<p>The 1994 settlement in Nagorno-Karabakh did not favour the Azeris, although they continue to make vigorous diplomatic efforts to address the status of the territory. Aliyev was twice re-elected by huge majorities. Elections in November 2000 gave the party two-thirds of the parliamentary seats.</p>
<p>Ilham Aliyev inherited his father's office in 2003, through an election the international community widely believed to be unfair. While Azerbaijan remains a stable country, it is still mired in corruption, and continues to be a dictatorship in all but name with widespread human rights abuses.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; Hitler said that if he couldn&rsquo;t take over the Baku oilfields, the war would be lost. The German army was on its way there when they were defeated by the Russians in the battle of Stalingrad in 1943.<br />
&bull; The name of Azerbaijan&rsquo;s &lsquo;exclave&rsquo; in Armenian territory, Nakhchivan, means Noah&rsquo;s Colony. Azeris believe survivors of the Great Flood settled here.<br />
&bull; Azerbaijan was the first Muslim country in the world to offer universal suffrage, giving women the vote in 1918.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Azerbaijan in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 337 3500.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.azembassy.us</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 337 3500.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1800 (embassy); Mon, Wed and Fri 1000-1200 (consular services).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2741 34th Street<br/>Washington DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Rebublic of Azerbaijan in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7938 3412.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.azembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7938 3412.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1800.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>4 Kensington Court<br/>London<br/>W8 5DL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The original &lsquo;East-meets-West&rsquo; destination, Azerbaijan sashays between space-age cityscapes and Arabian Nights exotica, taking in some of the most extraordinary landscapes in Caucasia en route.</p>
<p>Sitting at the crossroads between Europe and Asia, this former Soviet Republic is marginally bigger than Ireland, yet boasts an astonishing variety of natural wonders &ndash; from snow-capped mountains and bubbling mud volcanoes to sandy deserts and subtropical forests.</p>
<p>The northern hinterland is arguably the prettiest region thanks to the Caucasus Mountains, which rise to the misty heights of 4,466m (14,652ft). These lofty peaks are home to bears, wolves and leopards, not to mention nomadic shepherds, who move their flocks up and down these mountains in search of fresh pastures, as they have done for thousands of year.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, along the boulevards of downtown Baku, nouveau riche residents butterfly between expensive boutiques. The capital&rsquo;s exclusive shops, modern architecture and luxury hotels &ndash; spoils of Caspian Sea oil &ndash; jar somewhat with the UNESCO old town, not to mention the poorer communities outside Baku. Visitors may feel the black gold bounty is not benefitting everyone.</p>
<p>Though oil has transformed the economy in recent years, Azerbaijan has always been of strategic importance. Nestling on the shores of the Caspian Sea, the camel caravans of the Silk Road once passed through the land, which, over the centuries, has been incorporated into the Persian, Turkish and Russian empires.</p>
<p>Today Azerbaijan is a sovereign state and, although Islamic, the mood is determinedly secular. Alcohol is not only readily available, but proudly produced; grapes have been cultivated here for millennia, and local vineyards are developing some excellent wines. Azeri cuisine is also enjoying a renaissance thanks a profusion of new eateries popping up in downtown Baku.</p>
<p>Sounds like the next big thing, then? Not quite, but the government has ambitious plans to boost tourism to Azerbaijan. Go while it&rsquo;s relatively quiet.</p><p>Azerbaijan is an Islamic former Soviet Republic on the Caspian Sea, an oil rich and strategically important nation that is the key geopolitical power in the Caucasus.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
