<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Bahamas" ColCode="bhs" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bs" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Bahamas]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bahamasair (UP) (<a href="http://www.bahamasair.com" target="_blank">www.bahamasair.com</a>) operates a few domestic routes. Several charter services also run inter-island flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Out Islands are served by leisurely mail boats which leave Nassau several times a week carrying mail and provisions to the islands. Passengers share facilities with the crew. Arrangements should be made through boat captains at Potters Cay.</p>
<p>Bahamas Ferries (tel: +1 242 323 2166; <a href="http://www.bahamasferries.com" target="_blank">www.bahamasferries.com</a>) operates air-conditioned ferries from Nassau to Harbour Island, Eleuthera, Exuma, Andros and Abaco.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving is on the left-hand side of the road in the Bahamas. A toll applies to motorised vehicles wishing to use the bridge between Nassau and Paradise Island.</p><p>Roads across the Bahamas are adequate, if often narrow, but congestion is a problem in the main cities of Nassau and Freeport. Many low-lying parts of the country are also subject to flooding.</p><p>Jitneys (local buses) run all over the bigger islands of the Bahamas; the Family Islands (the smaller outlying islands) have almost no public transport whatsoever. Even in Nassau and Freeport, local buses are not renowned for their promptness, although as on other Caribbean islands, taking a bus for the immersion into local culture is recommended.</p><p>You can pick up taxis at the airport, docks and outside most hotels. Alternatively, you can book one by phone or hail one in the street. Metered rates vary according to the island, but are always reasonable and, whether government-run or privately run, all are controlled by law. Look for the Bahamahost sticker in the taxi; cab drivers with this sticker in the window are not only official, but pride themselves on real Bahamian hospitality. All taxis apply surcharges for groups and extra luggage.</p><p>National licences are valid for up to three months.</p><p>Seatbelts for drivers and passengers are compulsory.</p><p>International car hire firms are represented at the airports and in Nassau and Freeport. You usually need to be at least 21 years old to hire a car. Motor scooter hire is also available; helmets must be worn.</p><p>Rent by the half day, full day or the week in tourist centres.</p><p>Seatbelts for drivers and passengers are compulsory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving in Nassau is notoriously difficult due to the congestion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bahamas</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">marsh_harbour_abaco</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bahamas</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">governorrsquos_harbour_eleuthera</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bahamas</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">george_town_exuma</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bahamas</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">freeport_grand_bahama</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Bahamas' national airline is Bahamasair (<a href="http://www.bahamasair.com" target="_blank">www.bahamasair.com</a>). British Airways (<a href="http://www.britishairways.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) flies to Nassau&nbsp;from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>. Airlines operating direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> to the Bahamas include Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) and JetBlue (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>). Silver Airways (<a href="http://www.silverairways.com" target="_blank">www.silverairways.com</a>)&nbsp;connects <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/fort-lauderdale">Fort Lauderdale</a> with Bimini.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bahamas/nassau-international-airport">Nassau Lynden Pindling International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bahamas/grand-bahama-international-airport">Grand Bahama International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>&nbsp;- 10 hours;&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;3 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Nassau Lynden Pindling International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.nassaulpia.com<p>Nassau Lynden Pindling International Airport is situated 16km (10 miles) west of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nassau">Nassau</a>, on New Providence Island.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 242 702 1010</p>]]><b>Grand Bahama International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.freeportcontainerport.com<p>Grand Bahama International Airport is situated on Grand Bahama Island, 5km (3 miles) north of central Freeport.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 242 352 6020</p>]]><b>Exuma International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Governor's Harbour Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Marsh Harbour Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Treasure Cay Airport</b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A large number of international cruise ships call at <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nassau">Nassau</a>. Nassau also has direct passenger-cargo connections with the USA, the UK, the West Indies and South America.</p>
<p>Travellers arriving in the Bahamas by private boat must pay a customs and immigration fee and arrive at one of the official ports of entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Phone cards are sold island-wide for discounted international calls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a few international mobile phone companies. Coverage is average. Handsets can be hired locally and prepaid SIM cards are sold.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many hotels have Internet access and there are plenty of Internet cafes, as well as a few Wi-Fi hotspots. Only 30% of the population is connected, despite growing e-commerce activities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A US report, entitled <em>Freedom of the Press 2008: A Global Survey of Media Independence</em>, assessed the degree of press freedom in the Bahamas to rank it 37th in the world.<br /><br />Although the constitution of the Bahamas guarantees press freedom, pressure has been applied to the media in the past. Newspapers and magazines are mostly privately owned with the government operating a radio network. It also runs the island's only TV service.<br /><strong><br /></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Postal service to Europe takes up to 10 days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700 and Sat 0900-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bathe on beautiful white sand beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The pale pink sands of Harbour Island are a sight to behold, while the powder-fine alabaster beaches of Paradise Island are home to soaring seabirds and gently rustling palms. Cable Beach, Nassau, is a prime spot for watersports and beach bars, whilst visitors wanting a bit of peace should take a boat to Stocking Island for less-crowded options.</p>]]><p><b>Be drawn by horse and cart around Nassau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the 18th-century forts and pastel-coloured Georgian architecture of the Bahamian capital on foot or, better still, by horse-drawn cart. Get the steeds to stop while you climb the Queen's Staircase, which is carved out of solid rock and offers superb city panoramas. For fascinating history and culture visit the Pompey Museum and its fine collection of island artefacts and exhibits.</p>]]><p><b>Catch a haul in the Abacos Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fishing is possible almost anywhere in the Bahamas but the Abacos has become the angler's choice. On hand are top-quality guides (the incomparable Edward Rolle boasts 20 years' experience) to show you tricks of the trade. For bone-fishing Andros can't be beaten and Bimini boasts the best big game. Try the Tongue of the Ocean for a deep-water haul.</p>]]><p><b>Dance away at the Junkanoo festivities</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With street processions, dance bands and a full-on party crowd, the Bahamian Junkanoo festivities on Boxing Day and New Year's Day are the nation's number one party. Nassau's Junkanoo is the liveliest as revellers in elaborate costumes made from crepe paper and cardboard wheel through the streets. There are other great processions in Eleuthera, the Abacos and Grand Bahama.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Eleuthera's colonial charm</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Eleuthera, the jewel of the Out Islands, is where the first colony on the Bahamas was established, so wandering the streets of its charming colonial villages and rolling pineapple plantations is certainly a scenic trip back in time. There are some memorable seafood restaurants to sample here too.</p>]]><p><b>Dive to the lost city of Atlantis, Abacos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Amongst the wrecks strewn off the coast of the Abacos lies America's first steamship, the San Jacinto. Some of the best dive instructors in the Bahamas are on hand in the Abacos to make your dive experience first class. There are also the stone ruins off Bimini, said to be the remains of the lost city of Atlantis, to explore. </p>]]><p><b>Explore the eco islands of Inagua</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Inagua, the two islands making up the southern-most part of the Bahamas archipelago, is an eco-lovers paradise, with much of Great Inagua being taken up by the huge Lake Windsor. This is an internationally important bird reserve with an 80,000-strong population of West Indian flamingos. Besides birds, there's limestone caves to explore and excellent scuba diving. </p>]]><p><b>Gossip with the locals</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Bahamas' People-to-People scheme helps visitors learn about the cultures, music and oratory traditions of the islanders. Get paired with Bahamian locals of a similar age to enjoy rocking-chair tales, family lunches, church meetings, local bands or just plain out-fashioned <em>sip-sip </em>(local gossip).</p>]]><p><b>Kayak through the Lucayan National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This 16-hectare (40-acre) protected reserve on Grand Bahama secretes one of the world's longest underwater cave systems which (incredibly given the diminutive size of the park) boasts its own unique wildlife including the Remipedia bat. A great way to see the park's highlights is from a kayak as much of it is made up of navigable waterways.</p>]]><p><b>Make friends on Grand Bahama Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Outside fancy Freeport and Lucaya, the smaller settlements of Grand Bahama are surprisingly low-key. With their wide tree-lined streets, restaurants and cruise port facilities, they are also among the friendliest places in the country. Towns like Eight Mile Rock and McLean's Town are fabulous places to get to grips with real Bahamian culture.</p>]]><p><b>Mount Alvernia, Cat Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Climb to the highest point in the Bahamas on Cat Island's Mount Alvernia, 63m (206 ft) above sea level. Straddling the summit is a photogenic medieval-style monastery, a labour of love by one Father Jerome, who had the steps carved out of solid rock. With high cliffs and emerald forests there's plenty of opportunity for solitude seeking on Cat Island too.</p>]]><p><b>Paddle with pigs around Big Major Cay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It is not known exactly how feral pigs came to inhabit Big Major Cay. All we know is that paddling with these water-loving porkies is one of the more surreal ways to spend a day in the Bahamas. The friendly pigs can be visited on boat trips to the island, which is uninhabited by humans.</p>]]><p><b>See the sun go down with a rum cocktails (or two)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are few pleasures in life as simple as sipping rum-laden cocktails (a Bahama Mama is an essential experience) on Abaco Beach at sundown, watching the golden sky turn a dramatic pink-crimson. To add to the magic, fairy lights illuminate the shore as dozens of boats gently bob out in the harbour.</p>]]><p><b>Spend some time shopping in Nassau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dozens of colourful stalls at Nassau's bustling straw market produce a melee of crowds bartering over handcrafted goods. You can join them, or, for a more sophisticated shop, splash some cash in the swish stores at Bay Street, the brightly-coloured buildings are a haven of designer brands.</p>]]><p><b>Swim with dolphins at Blue Lagoon Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At Blue Lagoon Island you can interact with sea lions displaced by Hurricane Katrina and frolic with bottle-nosed dolphins in waist-high pools – many played starring roles in the movie <em>Flipper</em>. Whilst dolphin shows in much of the Caribbean have notoriously dubious ecological credentials, this experience is a class above: it's interaction, rather than getting dolphins to perform.</p>]]><p><b>Test your swing on some fine fairways</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The islands have some memorable golf courses, though the Reef Club is perhaps the prettiest. There are five other world-class courses on Grand Bahama Island to choose from including Exuma's Emerald Reef course which was designed by golfer Greg Norman, and the Abaco Club which boasts a Scottish links-style course. For a cheap round on the beautifully kept fairways, play at twilight.</p>]]><p><b>Visit untouched Andros</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Revel in the natural creeks, bird-filled forests, thick mangroves, and pastel-coloured coral on unexplored Andros – the world's third-longest barrier reef, set amongst the Out Islands. At nearly 6,000 sq km (2,300 sq miles), it is also the largest island in the Bahamas. Whether you snorkel, hike or fish, visitors will delight in this untouched gem.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$7.53 billion (2010 IMF estimate).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Salt, aragonite, pharmaceuticals, lumber, shellfish, fruit and vegetables and rum.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Vehicle parts, hotel, restaurant and medical supplies and electronics. There is also a growing market for products catering to the country's diverse ethnicity, such as ethnic cosmetics.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, EU, Canada, Venezuela and Netherlands Antilles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On a 2010 Heritage Foundation Index of Economic Freedom, The Bahamas billed 47th position in the world. A stable, free-market-orientated government has been heavily reliant on tourism for many decades: the tourism industry currently accounts for approximately 60% of GDP. It is tourism and, following a recent boom, real estate, which attracts the eyes of most foreign investors, a trend actively encouraged by the government. Despite an unemployment problem which has grown alongside the steady economic expansion, the outlook overall is a bright one for Bahamians and outside investment alike, and the country is one of the most affluent nations in the Caribbean.   Lurking behind tourism in the country's economic sustenance is the sizeable offshore banking sector (accounting for around 15% of GDP). Recently the financial sector has come under pressure since the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) instigated a tightening up of monetary laws. Agriculture and fishing account for a mere 5 % of GDP: far lower than other countries in the region.  Conference venues can seat from 15 to 3,000 people. Audiovisual equipment available for hire includes: LCD projector and screen, overhead and slide projectors, TVs, VCRs, and CD players, multiple channel mixers and more. Information may be obtained from the Bahamas Tourist Office or the Bahamas Ministry of Tourism in Nassau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Courtesies follow a similar pattern to the US and UK, ie appointments are made and business cards are exchanged. Business attire is smart-casual, normally trousers or skirt with a collared blouse or shirt. Wait until invited before moving to a first-name basis; whilst extremely friendly, Bahamians are initially more reserved and slower to open up than other Caribbean cultures.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bahamas Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 322 2145
					Website:http://www.thebahamaschamber.com
					Address: Freeport,Shirley Street and Collins Avenue,Grand Bahama,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The Bahamas has a wealth of good restaurants and bars, from local beach-side food joints to upscale diners. Unsurprisingly fish dominates the menu: with boiled whitefish a favourite for breakfast through to dinner-time seafood and steaks. The latter are served with plantain, rice, fries or potatoes. Another popular side-dish is the Johnny Cake (pan-cooked bread made with butter and milk). Fresh fruit from the fertile Out Islands includes sweet pineapple, mango, breadfruit and papaya.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Conch is on every menu, from creamy chowders and fritters to stews and salads. Order it 'scorched' for a ceviche-style dish served with lime juice, hot pepper, chopped tomato and onion, or 'cracked' for deep fried.<br />
&bull; Rock lobster (typically broiled, minced or used in salads).<br />
&bull; Land crabs (usually boiled or baked).<br />
&bull; <em>Souse</em> (a soup consisting purely of onions, water, lime juice, celery, peppers and meat). <br />
&bull; <em>Guava duff</em> (a dessert made with sieved guava pulp and served with <em>Switcha</em> a sauce made with lemon, sugar and water/rum, or, equally, a chilled beer.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Budget for a 15% gratuity as standard, but check the bill as some hotels and restaurants include a service charge. Tip porters B$1 per bag and allow 10-15% for taxi drivers.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A great climate, a wonderfully friendly people and a clutch of renowned celebrity hang-outs: the Bahamas has all the ingredients for a cracking night out, and delivers. Most hotels contain bars, lounges and nightclubs. Live music, beach parties and discos centre on calypso and <em>goombay</em> bands with limbo dancing. Four casinos are spread across Cable Beach, Paradise Island and Grand Bahama (Freeport and Lucaya) with festivals and live entertainment organised locally year-round. At renowned venues like Elvira's Bar on Eleuthera you might find yourself shoulder-to-shoulder with the stars themselves once the party gets started.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In 1992, the Bahamas abolished all import duties. Popular buys include perfumes, crystal, leather, jewellery, linens, watches, cameras and china. Straw goods, ceramics, clothing, seashell jewellery, paintings and woodcarvings are made locally.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0930-1900 and on Sunday mornings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are luxury hotels offering full porter, bell and room service, planned activities, sports, shops and beauty salons, swimming pools and entertainment; some have a private beach, golf course and tennis courts. The small hotels are more informal and while activities are less extensive, they usually offer a dining room and bar.  </p>
<p><strong>Honeymoon Hotels: </strong> Fulfilling its role as a romantic destination, there are ample honeymooning hotspots. Hotel chains like Sandals Luxury Included &reg; offer a wide variety of options for couples, including facilities for lavish and small-scale weddings, privacy and seclusion and often special rates and offers.  </p>
<p><strong>Boutique Hotels:</strong>  Boutique is big on the Bahamas and several of the middle to top-end hotels have garnered a stylish reputation for themselves due to their cutting-edge design, with names as famed as Versace (who designed the Bridge Suite at Atlantis Paradise Island Resort) being involved. Boutique hotels have a particular exclusivity factor on the Bahamas, with many offering only limited rooms (1-30) although many of the larger hotel facilities are still available. </p>
<p><strong>Apartment Hotels:</strong> These consist of apartment units with complete kitchen and maid service. Other hotel facilities (ie swimming pool, sporting activities, restaurant and bar, etc) are normally available on the premises.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[Bahamian guest houses are less expensive than hotels, and offer better opportunities for getting to know Bahamians themselves. Many offer room-only board, but there are plenty of restaurants to choose from. The Out Islands' hotels are small with a casual atmosphere. About 50 small hotels and guest houses are promoted as Small Treasures of the Bahamas by the Ministry of Tourism and are regularly inspected.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are luxury hotels offering full porter, bell and room service, planned activities, sports, shops and beauty salons, swimming pools and entertainment; some have a private beach, golf course and tennis courts. The small hotels are more informal and while activities are less extensive, they usually offer a dining room and bar.  </p>
<p><strong>Honeymoon Hotels: </strong> Fulfilling its role as a romantic destination, there are ample honeymooning hotspots. Hotel chains like Sandals Luxury Included &reg; offer a wide variety of options for couples, including facilities for lavish and small-scale weddings, privacy and seclusion and often special rates and offers.  </p>
<p><strong>Boutique Hotels:</strong>  Boutique is big on the Bahamas and several of the middle to top-end hotels have garnered a stylish reputation for themselves due to their cutting-edge design, with names as famed as Versace (who designed the Bridge Suite at Atlantis Paradise Island Resort) being involved. Boutique hotels have a particular exclusivity factor on the Bahamas, with many offering only limited rooms (1-30) although many of the larger hotel facilities are still available. </p>
<p><strong>Apartment Hotels:</strong> These consist of apartment units with complete kitchen and maid service. Other hotel facilities (ie swimming pool, sporting activities, restaurant and bar, etc) are normally available on the premises.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are luxury hotels offering full porter, bell and room service, planned activities, sports, shops and beauty salons, swimming pools and entertainment; some have a private beach, golf course and tennis courts. The small hotels are more informal and while activities are less extensive, they usually offer a dining room and bar.  </p>
<p><strong>Honeymoon Hotels: </strong> Fulfilling its role as a romantic destination, there are ample honeymooning hotspots. Hotel chains like Sandals Luxury Included &reg; offer a wide variety of options for couples, including facilities for lavish and small-scale weddings, privacy and seclusion and often special rates and offers.  </p>
<p><strong>Boutique Hotels:</strong>  Boutique is big on the Bahamas and several of the middle to top-end hotels have garnered a stylish reputation for themselves due to their cutting-edge design, with names as famed as Versace (who designed the Bridge Suite at Atlantis Paradise Island Resort) being involved. Boutique hotels have a particular exclusivity factor on the Bahamas, with many offering only limited rooms (1-30) although many of the larger hotel facilities are still available. </p>
<p><strong>Apartment Hotels:</strong> These consist of apartment units with complete kitchen and maid service. Other hotel facilities (ie swimming pool, sporting activities, restaurant and bar, etc) are normally available on the premises.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are on a par with the USA, but can be costly. Medical insurance is recommended and should ideally cover the cost of air ambulance.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Bottled water is popular with tourists as the local water is salty to taste - although safe to drink. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;There have been recent outbreaks of tuberculosis and malaria, so as a precaution many travelers prefer to get these vaccinations in any case.  Hepatitis B vaccinations are also sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 June </p><p>Independence Day :
							10 July </p><p>Emancipation Day :
							06 August </p><p>National Heroes' Day :
							12 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into the Bahamas by persons aged over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 454g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of B$100 (visitors), B$300 (residents) or B$500 (residents who have been out of the country for a year or more).</p>
<p>All beer imported into the country is subject to duty.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include indecent or obscene material, counterfeit currency and underwater guns.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Restricted imports include firearms, fireworks and firecrackers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Goods manufactured or produced more than 100 years ago are subject to export restrictions (eg historical and archaeological artefacts or zoological/botanical specimens).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bahamian Dollar (BSD; symbol B$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of B$100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 3 and 1, and 50 cents. Coins are in denominations of 25, 15, 10, 5 and 1 cents.<br /><br />The Bahamian Dollar has parity with the US Dollar and the latter is also accepted as legal tender.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in banks, bureaux de change and hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted. ATMs are available on the major islands in airport terminals, at banks, casinos and at other convenient locations.</p><p>ATMs are available on the major islands in airport terminals, at banks, casinos and at other convenient locations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0930-1500/1600, Fri 0930-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter the Bahamas, you must have a passport valid for at least six months from the date of departure. British and American passport holders can enter with less than six months remaining on their passports if visiting for up to 21 days. All visitors require a return or onward ticket, confirmed hotel booking (or letter of invitation if staying at a private address) and proof of funds to sustain their trip.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unaccompanied children under 16 must carry a letter of authorisation from their parents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: &pound;160; three-month, six-month or one-year multiple-entry visa: &pound;250.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: three months; multiple-entry visa: three months, six months or one year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate (or consular section at embassy or high commission).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A minimum of 48 hours, but processing can take up to six weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are expected to have sufficient funds to cover their stay (around US$200 per day).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Apply to the Immigration Department to extend your stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An import permit is required from the Department of Agriculture; contact the embassy or high commission for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[23.985980]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-77.634996]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>13,939 sq km (5,382 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>392,718 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>23.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nassau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Comprising 700 low-lying islands, mostly islets (cays or keys), atolls and rocks, the Bahamas archipelago extends 970km (500 miles) southeastward from the coast of Florida. Sparkling, clear waters are home to vibrant underwater gardens on the world's third longest barrier reef, which contains about 14.5% of the coral on the planet. Fertile marine plains are split between two oceanic facets, the Little Bahama Bank and the Great Bahama Bank, where visibility of around 60m (197ft) is the norm. Exotic flowers, pine forest, rugged shoreline, barren savannahs, marshlands and sandy beaches typify the landscape, on a bed of limestone and coral rocks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly Christian with Baptist, Anglican and Roman Catholic the main denominations and Methodist, Church of God and other Protestant faiths minority groups.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The chilled-out Bahamian pace of life dominates every convention. 'Island time' is a relaxed approach to time-keeping and also describes the Bahamians' laid-back attitude to life. A slow pace prevails across the board from the banks to the Government offices. Dress is casual, although business attire is worn. Holidaymakers will find beachwear is accepted in the resorts but is frowned upon elsewhere. When dining, dancing or high-rolling in the casinos of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nassau">Nassau</a> or Freeport, dressing up is de rigueur.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>120 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without a round grounding pin) are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Perry Christie since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General Dame Marguerite Pindling since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The original inhabitants, the Lucayan Indians, survived through fishing and a developed trading system with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cuba">Cuba</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/haiti">Haiti</a>, flourishing until 1492 when the Bahamas were first discovered by Europeans under Columbus. San Salvador, near modern-day Cockburn Town, was his first landing place in the New World.</p>
<p>Close to key trading routes, settlers arrived in their droves, most notably the Eleutheran Adventurers, a group of English religious dissidents, in 1647. Adventurers they certainly were, braving food shortages and piracy before establishing a more easily defensible settlement on Harbour Island.</p>
<p>The era of privateering raged on &ndash; the pirate Blackbeard was at one time magistrate of a pirate-controlled <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nassau">Nassau</a> before the archipelago was formally colonised by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Britain</a> in 1717, under Woodes Rogers (himself an ex-privateer). The islands were briefly re-occupied by the Spanish in 1782 but returned to Britain the following year.</p>
<p>A comparatively peaceful, prosperous era ensued. An early haven for freed slaves, the islands lucratively became a trading post for Confederate cotton in the American Civil War. And during Prohibition the port of Nassau had to expand to cope with the surge in the rum trade.</p>
<p>When Cuba closed to tourism in 1962, the Bahamas quickly promoted itself as the bona fide holiday destination for America&rsquo;s wealthy. Internal self-government arrived two years later, followed by full independence in 1973.</p>
<p>The Bahamas is a Commonwealth realm &ndash; one of 16 former British colonies that are members of the Commonwealth of Nations &ndash; and retains HM The Queen as head of state. The head of the government is the prime minister, currently the Rt Hon Perry Christie, who leads the party with the most seats in the House of Assembly, the lower house, which is augmented by a 16-member Senate appointed by the governor general.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull;	Although illegal, <em>Obeah</em>, a form of folk magic, is practised by some Bahamians mainly in the outlying Family Islands.<br />
&bull;	Local heroes, The Baha Men enjoyed a massive worldwide hit in 2000 with <em>Who Let the Dogs Out?</em><br />
&bull;	The uninhabited island of Pig Beach is populated exclusively by feral pigs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Commonwealth of the Bahamas in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 319 2667.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 319 2667.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1730.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2220 Massachussetts Avenue<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Bahamas High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7659 0829.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.bahamas.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7659 0829.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1730.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>10 Chesterfield Street<br/>London<br/>W1J 5JL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The quiet coves and crowd-free beaches of the Bahamas offer visitors the intimacy of a secluded retreat within a paradisiacal expanse of some 700 palm-fringed isles.</p>
<p>Christened baja mar (meaning 'shallow sea') by Christopher Columbus, these islands, with their astonishing hues of sand and sea spanning the colour spectrum from twinkling turquoise to rose pink, are the personification of paradise.</p>
<p>Crystalline waters secrete ancient shipwrecks and a rainbow of coral reefs, while pastel-coloured seashells and vibrant clapboard houses perch atop a tropical landscape that resonates with exotic birdsong.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s the over-riding feeling that the Bahamas has got tourism just right: a range of resorts cater for holidaymakers, including a growing range of eco-hotels, yet their impact on the islands&rsquo; natural beauty remains, by in large, minimal.</p>
<p>The full gauntlet of watersports beckon for the active holidaymaker: from scuba diving and snorkelling to parasailing and sailing, there&rsquo;s more than enough to get the pulse racing here. Then there are the glitzy golf courses, designed by the game&rsquo;s best, whose vistas are enough to compensate for a bad day on the fairways.</p>
<p>Pack your hiking shoes and explore the clutch of nature reserves that are scattered across the archipelago. Pack your binoculars too and look out for the myriad of bird species that call the Bahamas home: from bright pink flamingos to multicolored parrots, you can&rsquo;t miss some of the more flamboyant species.</p>
<p>Come sundown, Bahamian bars and clubs pulsate with island rhythms; discover riotous dance festivals that mix African slave-trade rituals with Bahamian tempo and American hip-hop twists, or head to one of the archipelago&rsquo;s bustling straw markets to haggle over spices, and ceramics.</p>
<p>If it all gets too much, recharge your batteries at one of the wonderful seafood restaurants or with an infamous rum cocktail. Whatever you do, the vividness of the Bahamas never ceases to assault your senses.</p><p>The quiet coves and crowd-free beaches of the Bahamas offer visitors the intimacy of a secluded retreat within a paradisiacal expanse of some 700 palm-fringed isles.&nbsp;Christened baja mar (meaning 'shallow sea') by Christopher Columbus, these islands, with their astonishing hues of sand and sea spanning the colour spectrum from twinkling turquoise to rose pink, are the personification of paradise.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
