<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Bahrain" ColCode="bhr" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bh" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Bahrain]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>June to October, hot and humid (32&deg;C/89&deg;F), December to April, mild (15-25&deg;C/59-77&deg;F). December through to March can be quite cool. Rainfall is slight and occurs mainly in winter.  The best time to visit <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bahrain">Bahrain</a> is between February to April and October to December when the sky is free from heat haze and the weather sunny without being oppressive. The times to avoid, other than the punishing mid-summer months, are Ramadan (when restaurants are closed during the day) and the two Eid holidays (when hotels are in high demand from Saudi visitors).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens from spring to autumn, mediumweight clothes from November to March. Warmer clothes are necessary in winter and on cool evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no internal flights within Bahrain.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transport between the smaller islands is by motorboat or <em>dhow</em>. For details, contact local travel agents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Manama is served by an excellent road system.&nbsp;Road signs are written in English and Arabic.</p><p>You can hire taxis in the street or from stands outside hotels and at major tourist attractions. They are identifiable by their orange side-wings and yellow number plates. Share-taxis which carry up to five passengers are also available. These are recognisable by a yellow circle with the licence number in black painted on the driver's door and by their white and orange number plates. There are several designated pick-up points. Meters are not used and fares should always be agreed beforehand. Radio cabs are also available.</p><p>You can drive using an International Driving Permit for up to a year.</p><p>Speed limits for Bahrain are 60km/h in towns, 80-100km/h on open roads and 120km/h on motorways.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><p>Most of the major international car hire companies operate in Bahrain with representatives at the airport and at big hotels.</p><p>Speed limits for Bahrain are 60km/h in towns, 80-100km/h on open roads and 120km/h on motorways.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline serving <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bahrain">Bahrain</a> is Gulf Air<em>&nbsp;</em>(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.gulfair.com">www.gulfair.com</a>), which operates direct flights from the UK. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) also has a direct connection from London.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bahrain/bahrain-international-airport">Bahrain International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 6 hours 35 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 15 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bahrain International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bahrainairport.com<p>Bahrain International Airport is located 6km (4 miles) northeast of the capital city Manama on the island of Muharraq.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+973 8000 7777</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Khalifa Bin Salman Port is now being used as the main port. Sitra Wharf another port is frequently used. Mina Manama is now being used as a military service port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A car drive to Dhahran (Eastern Province of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/saudi-arabia">Saudi Arabia</a>) takes approximately 1 hour from Bahrain using the King Fahd Causeway. A toll fee is payable by drivers leaving Bahrain. Normal Saudi Arabian visa regulations apply.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Blue phone booths are coin-operated, red booths are phonecard operated and silver booths are operated by both cards and coins. Facilities are provided for video conferencing, digital data networks and mobile links.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is average.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in large towns and resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bahrain's domestic radio and television stations are state-run. Some households have satellite TV. Bahrain is keen to promote itself as a regional media hub, and the London-based pan-Arab satellite broadcaster MBC chose Bahrain as the base for its MBC-2 channel. Journalists have the legal right to operate independently and freely, but can be imprisoned for some offences, which include insulting the king. Self-censorship is practised.<strong><br />
</strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail service to Europe takes three to four days. The main post office is near Bab al-Bahrain in Manama. Efficient one-day international courier services operate out of Bahrain.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0700-2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Barbar Temple</p><![CDATA[<p>Located in the village of Barbar, the most recent of the three Barbar temples was rediscovered by a Danish archaeological team in 1954. A further two temples were discovered on the site with the oldest dating back to 3000BC. The three temples were built atop one another with the second built approximately 500 years later and the third added between 2100BC and 2000BC. It's thought that the temples were constructed to worship the God Enki, the god of wisdom and freshwater, and his wife Nankhur Sak. The temple contains two altars and a natural water spring that is thought to have held spiritual significance for the worshippers. During the excavation of the site many tools, weapons, pottery and small pieces of gold were found which are now on display in the Bahrain National Museum (www.bnmuseum.com).</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Cruise out to the Hawar Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a 40-minute boat ride to the Hawar Islands, an archipelago of desert islands, and look out for the dolphins that play in the calm Gulf seas. It's not all about these playful mammals, though: flamboyant flamingos also stalk the shallow waters. They're much easier to spot.</p>]]><p><b>Dine at the Causeway Restaurant</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Order an egg rollup and coffee at the Causeway Restaurant, which offers stunning views of one of the most impressive engineering feats in Arabia: the King Fahd Causeway; a 25km (16 mile), four-lane bridge that links Bahrain with Saudi Arabia.</p>]]><p><b>Dive into Bahrain’s history</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visitors can learn about Bahrain's once-thriving pearl industry at the Bahrain National Museum, which charts the history of this tiny nation. The museum is located between Manama and the city of Murharraq, a UNESCO World Heritage Site that was built on the pearl industry: listed buildings include the residences of wealthy merchants, shops, storehouses and a mosque. For a more immersive experience you can dive for pearls yourself at Dar Island Resort.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the house of Bait Al Jasra</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located in the rustic village of Al Jasra, this house is the birthplace of the late Emir of Bahrain, Isa bin Salman Al Khalifa, and is an exquisite example of traditional Bahraini architecture. The village itself is also worthy of a wander, with its souks, craft centre and sea views.</p>]]><p><b>Get lost in Bab Al Bahrain souk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Manama's oldest buildings, Bab Al Bahrain is a local landmark. As well as traditional Arabian architecture and lavish water features, it offers visitors the chance to get lost in its souks. Enjoy the nosegays of cardamom, coffee, apricot, sheesha, kebabs and heady incense-laced perfumes as you barter with the local hawkers.</p>]]><p><b>Hang out in hip Adliya</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The bohemian neighbourhood of Adliya is <em>the </em>place to be seen in Manama. Buzzing with lively bars and restaurants, it is vaunted as one of the best places for a night out in Bahrain. As well as chic eateries, cocktail bars and nightclubs, Adliya is home to a collection of art galleries and cafés, where locals and tourists go to socialise.</p>]]><p><b>Hole up in Bahrain Fort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a Portuguese-eyed view of the sea from the strategic Bahrain Fort, which was built in the 16th-century and recently restored to its former no-nonsense grandeur. It gained UNESCO status in 2005 and is one of the country's most popular tourist attractions.</p>]]><p><b>Pretend to be a racing driver</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the latest additions to the F1 calendar, the Bahrain Grand Prix burns rubber once a year at the Bahrain International Circuit. But when the professionals aren't battling it out on the bitumen, amateur petrol heads are: the track is available (at a fee) for anyone who wants to play racing driver. Tours of the circuit are available, which include a lap of the track.</p>]]><p><b>See a performance at the National Theatre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Opened in 2012, the Bahrain National Theatre hosts performances from leading lights in the world of classical music, opera and ballet. Overlooking the sea, near the Bahrain National Museum, the building is beautiful inside and out. As well as an opera theatre, it houses a café, which is a fine place to watch the world go by.</p>]]><p><b>Sit beneath the Tree of Life</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Standing alone in the desert, the Tree of Life has become something of a tourist attraction in Bahrain – by virtue of its loneliness. Thought to be around 400 years old, incredibly the Tree of Life attracts some 50,000 pilgrims annually and is said to be a site for sects practising ancient rites.</p>]]><p><b>Slip inside the Oil Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It might destroy the environment and be the catalyst for wars, but the Bahrain economy was built on black gold and the stuff is jovially celebrated at the Oil Museum near Manama. Telling the story of oil from its beginnings to present day, its grand white building is quaintly at odds with the nodding donkeys and sprawling pipelines of the neighbouring vicinity.</p>]]><p><b>Stock up on bling at Gold City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Barter for bangles in Bahrain's glittering Gold City; a bling-tastic collection of jewellery shops that will bedazzle even the most jaded of shoppers. Located in central Manama, Gold City is a place where many a credit card is melted – you've been warned.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Dilmun Burial Mounds</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Incredibly, roughly 5% of Bahrain's limited landmass is taken up by ancient burial mounds, which dominate the landscape near the town of A'Ali. Thought to be one of the largest cemeteries in the ancient world, there are around 170,000 people buried here.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$31.86 billion (2016)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum and petroleum products, aluminium, gold and textiles.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, machinery and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Saudi Arabia, Japan, UAE and China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Oil dominates Bahrain's economy and, together with gas and petrochemicals, accounts for the bulk of exports and government revenue. That proportion is falling, however, as reserves dwindle. Recognising the need to diversify the economy, the government took early measures to build the banking sector and encourage international investment in large-scale projects such as the Bahrain Financial Harbour in Manama.<br />
<br />
Local tourism (largely from Saudi Arabia) accounts for a robust service industry, and international tourists have been won back through the inauguration of the Grand Prix in April 2004 and high-profile spending in tourist infrastructure, particularly at complexes such as Al-Areen and Durrat al-Bahrain.<br />
<br />
In September 2004, Bahrain signed a Free Trade Pact with the USA but continues to discuss regional economic integration and a proposed single currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Working attire is formal (suits and ties for men, business clothes for women). Commercial interaction is facilitated through personal introduction and greetings and polite conversation are expected before business discussions begin. Bargaining is common practice. Arabs regard their word as their bond and expect others to do the same. The best time to visit is October to April.</p><p>Office hours are usually from 08:30 or 9am to 17:30 or 6pm; Sunday to Thursday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Commercial Arbitration Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (17) 825 540
					Website:http://www.gccarbitration.net
					Address: Adliya,PO Box 16100,Bahrain,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of quality dining options, many but not all of which are to be found in the 5-star hotels. If the ubiquitous Gulf menu of rice, lamb and mezze (hummus, chopped salads and other appetisers) is not to your taste, then try the locally caught prawns and lobster. The fruit juices, such as lemon and mint, are irresistible in summer.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol is widely available for non-Muslim adults over the age of 18 in most top-end restaurants and hotel bars in Manama. Drinking alcohol in public outside these establishments is prohibited.<br />
<strong><strong><br />
National specialities:</strong></strong><br />
<em>&bull; </em><em>Machbous</em>: steamed fish or meat served with rice. <br />
<em>&bull; </em><em>Muchammar:</em> brown, sweet rice served with sugar or dates.<br />
<em>&bull; </em><em>Baba ghanoush:</em> smoked aubergine, pureed garlic, yoghurt and sesame paste.<br />
<em>&bull; </em><em>Shawarma</em>: lamb or chicken carved from a rotating spit and wrapped in flat bread.  <br />
<em>&bull; </em><em>Sambousa</em>: crisp pastry cases filled with meat, cheese, sugar or nuts.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Restaurants, nightclubs and cinemas showing English and Arabic films can be found in the main towns.</p>
<p>Within the capital city, Manama, 'nightlife' generally refers to eating out with friends in some of the city's excellent restaurants, particularly in the Adliya district. Pick up a copy of <em>TimeOut Bahrain </em>for a listing of current favourites. There are also several fashionable nightclubs, mostly attached to hotels, which offer a mix of world music, house, R'n'B, hip hop and even the odd samba club. Live shows are advertised in the 'Nitelife' section of <em>Bahrain This Month </em>and in the English-language newspapers.</p>
<p>For something more 'highbrow', the Bahrain International Exhibition Centre (<a href="http://www.bahrainexhibitions.com">www.bahrainexhibitions.com</a>) features traditional music recitals and the five-star hotels often host quality acts from abroad. All top hotels have attractive bars featuring happy hour and live jazz or piano music.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of modern shopping complexes with imported luxury goods. Pearls are the main local speciality, used in finely wrought gold jewellery. Famous red clay pottery is available from the village of A'ali; hand-woven cloth from Bani Jamrah and textiles from Al-Jasra.<br />
<br />
Manama is a great place for night shopping: just stroll through the labyrinthine streets behind Bab al-Bahrain to discover how locals spend their evenings bartering in the clothes, textiles and gold souks.</p><p>Usually trading hours for malls are 10am to 10pm; Sunday to Wednesday and Thursday, Friday and Saturday; 10am to 12 midnight. Some shops are open for a few hours on Friday evenings in souks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The deluxe hotels are well represented by international chains with some providing a meet-and-greet service from the airport if sufficient notice is given. All the resorts offer an opulent environment with landscaped gardens, pools, clean beach access and fine dining.<br />As Bahrain is a small country, most visitors stay in Manama and the suburbs which offer a choice of hotel accommodation to fit all pockets, ranging from 5-star comfort to family-run hotels and 1-star budget establishments. Visitors ought to be aware that some of the budget hotel accommodation in the city centre may not be suitable for families or women travelling alone as they tend to double as 'evening entertainment' venues for men.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The deluxe hotels are well represented by international chains with some providing a meet-and-greet service from the airport if sufficient notice is given. All the resorts offer an opulent environment with landscaped gardens, pools, clean beach access and fine dining.<br />As Bahrain is a small country, most visitors stay in Manama and the suburbs which offer a choice of hotel accommodation to fit all pockets, ranging from 5-star comfort to family-run hotels and 1-star budget establishments. Visitors ought to be aware that some of the budget hotel accommodation in the city centre may not be suitable for families or women travelling alone as they tend to double as 'evening entertainment' venues for men.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The deluxe hotels are well represented by international chains with some providing a meet-and-greet service from the airport if sufficient notice is given. All the resorts offer an opulent environment with landscaped gardens, pools, clean beach access and fine dining.<br />As Bahrain is a small country, most visitors stay in Manama and the suburbs which offer a choice of hotel accommodation to fit all pockets, ranging from 5-star comfort to family-run hotels and 1-star budget establishments. Visitors ought to be aware that some of the budget hotel accommodation in the city centre may not be suitable for families or women travelling alone as they tend to double as 'evening entertainment' venues for men.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There is a comprehensive medical service, with general and specialised hospitals in the main towns. An emergency health service is provided free of charge or at a nominal fee. Pharmacies are well-equipped with supplies.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice from hotels and public facilities is considered safe by the Bahrain Ministry of Health. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish in the summer months when inadequate storage in the heat can cause problems.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended - consult your doctor for the latest medical advice six weeks before departure. In the summer, it is easy to get sunstroke or become dehydrated. Simple measures such as covering the head, keeping out of the midday sun and regularly sipping water help avoid this.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations.  During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>National Day :
							16 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bahrain/bahrain-international-airport">Bahrain</a> by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes, 50 cigars and 250g of tobacco in opened packets.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic beverages and six cans of beer (non-Muslim passengers only).<br />
&bull; 8 oz of perfume.<br />
&bull; Gifts up to the value of BHD250 (approximately US$660).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include narcotics, indian paan and derivatives, used and reconditioned tyres,&nbsp;cultured pearls, advertisements for cigarettes, radio-controlled model aircraft, children's toy guns, goods of Israeli origin, publications that contradict Islamic teachings, asbestos, raw ivory/ ivory articles and rhinoceros horn, and live swine and ivory.</p>
<p>Restricted imports requiring authorisation include animals, animal products, plants, fruit and vegetables, firearms and ammunition, radioactive chemicals and active isotopes,films and publications, and telecommunications equipment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited exports include fuel, flour, red meat and fresh chicken bearing the trademark 'Delmon'.</p>
<p>Restricted exports requiring authorisation include palm tree seedlings and antiquities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dinar (BHD) = 1,000 fils. Notes appear in denominations of BHD20, 10, 5, and 1, and 500 fils. Coins are in denominations of BHD (500 fils),100, 50, 25, 10 and 5  fils.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency can be exchanged at the airport, at most hotels and in banks and bureaux de change. Rates are more preferential at the bureaux de change than at the airport or at hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted in hotels, major stores and restaurants. Smaller shops may prefer to deal in cash. ATMs are available in major cities.</p><p>ATMs are available in major cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The use of traveller&rsquo;s cheques in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bahrain/bahrain-international-airport">Bahrain</a> is becoming increasingly uncommon. It has become difficult to find a restaurant or a shop that accept traveller's cheques. While the exchange rate for traveller's cheques isn't very satisfying at hotels, banks charge a commission for the service. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sun-Thu 0730-1500. Government offices, businesses and most offices are closed on Friday, which is a weekly holiday.&nbsp;International banks are open from 07:30 to 19:30, and some national banks are open between 8am to 4pm.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Bahrain, a passport valid for at least six months from the date of arrival is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visit visa at port of entry: BHD20; multiple-entry visit visa at port of entry: BHD25; single-entry visit eVisa: BHD29; five-year multiple-entry visa: BHD20 (available to certain nationalities), Visit eVisa: BHD29.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa on arrival: up to three months depending on nationality.</p>
<p>Multiple-entry visa on arrival: two weeks.</p>
<p>Single-entry visa: two weeks to three months depending on nationality.</p>
<p>Multiple-entry visa: up to five years with a maximum stay of four weeks per visit.</p>
<p>eVisas: two weeks to three months depending on nationality and must be used within 30 days of approval; some eVisas are valid for multiple entries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On arrival or online at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.evisa.gov.bh">www.evisa.gov.bh</a>. The UK Foreign and Commonwealth Office advises travellers to obtain visas in advance to avoid delays at the border. Some nationalities not listed in the chart must apply via the embassy and may require a sponsor for travel to Bahrain.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three to five working days when applying online.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend an eVisa once in Bahrain via the Nationality, Passports &amp; Residence Affairs office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[26.093981]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[50.543032]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>765 sq km (295 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,492,584 (August 2017)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,867 per sq km</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Manama.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bahrain is a mostly flat archipelago of desert islands off the east coast of Saudi Arabia. The main island has a supply of fresh water, unique in the region, both on land and offshore. There are extensive date plantations and market gardens near Manama. The strategic 25km-long (16 miles) King Fahad Causeway links Bahrain with Saudi Arabia and a new causeway will in future link Bahrain with Qatar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Islam. Most Bahrainis (60%) are Shi'ite Muslims although there is a sizeable minority of Sunnis, including the Royal family.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bahrain is a tolerant country but visitors will avoid giving offence if they observe a few courtesies, especially with regard to dress. Cover knees and shoulders, except within hotel grounds where more casual clothing is acceptable.<br /><br />At business and social functions, traditional Arabic coffee is served as part of the ritual welcome. Cups are held in the right hand: accept two cups - taking only one cup will embarrass the host; taking more than three will embarrass everybody else. Never pass or receive items with the left hand and avoid pointing with the soles of your feet (for example, when sitting on the ground) as this is considered an insult.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220-240 volts AC, 50Hz (Awali, 110 volts AC, 60Hz). British-style plugs with three square pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Khalifa bin Salman Al-Khalifa since 1971.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Sheikh Hamad bin Isa Al-Khalifa since 1999.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bahrain">Bahrain</a> has a Stone-Age history that dates back to 5000 BC and visible evidence of this early history can be seen around the country in the form of 85,000 burial mounds and chambers that undulate across 5% of Bahrain&rsquo;s land mass. Bahrain is perhaps even more famous, however, as the seat of the lost empire of Dilmun, a powerful civilisation whose influence lasted between 3200 and 330 BC.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s sweet-water springs attracted traders, who took particular interest in the local pearls, and by the 16th century the country began to be of interest to the big naval powers of Europe. In the early 1500s the Portuguese invaded, leaving not much legacy but the distinctive Qala&rsquo;at al-Bahrain fort on Bahrain&rsquo;s northern shore. During the 19th century Bahrain came under the influence of the British in the so-called Trucial system &ndash; a series of treaties signed with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Britain</a> against piracy. The relationship developed into a protectorate agreement, the modern day result of which is a strong tie between the British and the people of Bahrain.</p>
<p>Bahrain regained full independence in 1971 and in 2002, Bahrain became a constitutional monarchy with a fully elected parliament in which both men and women are eligible to vote and stand for office. There is also a system in place to ensure transparency of government finances which has helped Bahrain compete to become the region's leading offshore banking and commercial hub.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Kingdom of Bahrain in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 342 1111. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.bahrainembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 342 1111. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-16530.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3502 International Drive<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Kingdom of Bahrain in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7201 9170.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mofa.gov.bh/london/Home.aspx</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7201 9170.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Knightsbridge<br/>30 Belgrave Square<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8QB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bahrain means 'Two Seas', a fitting name for an archipelago of 33 islands in the Gulf, which defines itself in relation to the water that surrounds its shallow shores.</p><p>Those shallows once harboured a precious trade in pearls, the most important in the world until the 19th century. Now the shoreline is increasingly dominated by ambitious developments, such as the twin 50-floor towers of Bahrain's World Trade Centre and the 2,787,000 sq m (30,000,000 sq ft) horseshoe of man-made islands at the southern tip of the country.</p><p>To those not in the know, Bahrain can seem a formidable place in the heart of the Gulf. But despite being situated just off Saudi Arabia's east coast, it is for the most part a welcoming, open country. Manama is an intriguing capital city, if not quite so glamorous is some of the region's other glittering metropolises. You'll find a decent culinary and artistic circuit, partly buoyed by westerners living here. Expect plenty of craft markets and pottery workshops.</p><p>For history buffs, Bahrain is the location of ancient Dilmun, home to what was an important semitic civilisation in the Bronze Age; Bahrain was later conquered by Babylonians and Persians. There are a number of ruins, burial mounds and forts to explore.</p><p>In the middle of Bahrain, not far from where the Formula 1 racetrack now draws the crowds, is the point where in 1932 the Arab world first struck gold – black gold, that is – and oil has been the mainstay of the country ever since. As visitors travel the modest length of Bahrain, they will run into many reminders of this momentous discovery, not least in the relaxed affluence of Bahrain's multicultural residents. Indeed, there are many signs of Arabian style and influence, along with more cosmopolitan vibes.</p><p>Since 2011, when the Arab Spring swept across the region, Bahrain's fate has been an uncertain one. The initial wave of protests by the largely Shia population against the Sunni rulers were put down with the help of Saudi Arabia, but demonstrations and unrest persist. Check the current situation before travelling.</p>With a name meaning 'Two Seas' it is little wonder that Bahrain, an archipelago of 33 islands in the Gulf, defines itself in relation to the water that surrounds its shallow shores.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
