<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Bangladesh" ColCode="bgd" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bd" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Bangladesh]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot, tropical climate with the monsoon season lasting from late May to October. Temperatures are highest from mid-March to May. Rainfall averages over 2,540mm (100 inches). The cool season is between November and early March. The country is prone to widespread flooding and is also a high-risk earthquake zone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens throughout the year. Warmer clothes are needed in the evenings during the cool season. Waterproofs are necessary during the monsoon season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internal flights in Bangladesh&nbsp;are operated by Biman Bangladesh Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.biman-airlines.com">www.biman-airlines.com</a>)&nbsp;and UBD (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.uabdl.com">www.uabdl.com</a>). Regular flights are run between Dhaka and several other main towns. These are cheap, and most routes are served at least two or three times a week.</p>
<p>Domestic airports include Barisal, Chittagong, Cox's Bazar, Jessore, Rajshahi and Sylhet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Major river ports: </strong>Barisal, Chandpur,<em> </em>Dhaka,<em> </em>Khulna, Mongla and Narayanganj.</p>
<p>The country has more than 8,000km (5,000 miles) of navigable waterways and water transport, if a little slow, is the least expensive method of getting around Bangladesh. Passages should be booked well in advance; for details, contact local port authorities.</p>
<p>River services are operated by the Bangladesh Inland Waterway Transport Authority (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.biwtc.gov.bd">www.biwtc.gov.bd</a>), which runs 'Rocket' ferries and launches on a number of routes. A ferry operates from Dhaka to Khulna six times a week (journey time - 28 hours). Ferries can often be dangerously overcrowded.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A slow but efficient network, operated by Bangladesh Railway (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.railway.gov.bd">www.railway.gov.bd</a>), is divided into two halves, eastern and western by the great rivers that themselves divide the country. River ferries provide through links. Services are being upgraded. However, trains still occasionally derail and passengers have been injured.</p>
<p>The main line is Dhaka-Chittagong (Bangladesh&rsquo;s second city), which offers a good train service with several daily trains, some of which have air-conditioned cars. An intercity express service is available between main towns. There is no train service to Cox&rsquo;s Bazar (Bangladesh&rsquo;s prime beach resort).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>Traffic is chaotic in urban areas and road safety is poor.&nbsp;There are frequent crashes caused by speeding and dangerous driving.&nbsp;Frequent river crossings make cross-country journeys lengthy.</p><p>Available at airports and major hotels. Fares should always be agreed upon first.</p><p>International Driving Permit required. The minimum driving age is 18.</p><p>Not recommended, although you can hire cars at Dhaka Airport or from major hotels. It's better to hire a car with driver.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are bus services, which are usually very crowded and unreliable, in Dhaka, provided by the Bangladesh Road Transport Corporation. The Central Bus Station, known as Fulbaria or Gulistan, is on Station Road in the city centre; there are several other terminals for long-distance services. Buses and bus stations do not generally have signs in English.</p>
<p>There are also an estimated 10,000 independent 'auto-rickshaw' 3-wheeler taxis (avoid night-time use) and cycle rickshaws are ubiquitous. Conventional taxis are also available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bangladesh</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sylhet</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bangladesh</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">rangpur</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">11.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bangladesh</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">rajshahi</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bangladesh</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">chittagong</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline, Biman Bangladesh Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.biman-airlines.com">www.biman-airlines.com</a>), operates flights to Bangladesh. Other airlines flying here include Emirates (<a href="http://www.emirates.com" target="_blank">www.emirates.com</a>), Jet Airways (<a href="http://www.jetairways.com" target="_blank">www.jetairways.com</a>) and Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>).</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangladesh/hazrat-shahjalal-international-airport">Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport</a> and Chittagong Shah Amanat International Airport.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Dhaka: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>&nbsp;is 12 hours 30 minutes (including stopover);&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> is 19 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>BDT350 if leaving overland (included in air fares).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chittagong Shah Amanat International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.caab.gov.bd/adinfo/airports.html]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Osmani International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main seaport is Chittagong. Currently, there no international passenger routes to and from Bangladesh.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The direct Kolkata to Dhaka service is called the Maitree (Friendship) Express and is run by both the Indian and Bangladeshi railways. For other non-direct rail connections, cycle-rickshaw, bus or porter services provide the cross-border connections.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public telephone booths are located at the principal marketplaces and in post offices in the main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage is limited to main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public Internet services exist in the main towns and there are also a few Internet cafes, usually with slow connections. Some hotels in Dhaka and Chittagong offer Internet access (mainly to guests).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main broadcast media in Bangladesh, Radio Bangladesh and BTV Bangladesh Television, the national television channel, are state-owned and favourable to the Government. Little coverage is given to the political opposition, except in the run-up to general elections when a caretaker Government takes control. Although BTV remains the country's sole terrestrial TV channel, private satellite-delivered TV stations have established a presence.<br />
<br />
The constitution guarantees press freedom, but journalists are subject to regular harassment from the police and political activists. Bangladeshi newspapers are diverse, outspoken and privately owned. English-language titles appeal mainly to the educated urban elite. The authorities sometimes withdraw foreign publications from circulation over articles or images considered malicious or offensive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail takes three to four days to Europe; surface mail can take several weeks. Post boxes are blue for airmail and red for surface mail. Post offices are closed on Fridays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Chittagong</p><![CDATA[<p>Chittagong, the second largest city in Bangladesh, is a port city, set against the blue waters of the Bay of Bengal and surrounded by green forests, coconut groves and sandy beaches. Attractions include the Ethnological Museum, the 17th-century Shahi Jama-e-Masjid Mosque, the colourful multi-domed Chandanpura Mosque and the Tomb of Sultan Bayazid Bostami. Foy's Lake, an artificial lake named after the Englishman responsible for its design, is located 8km (5 miles) from Chittagong, and is a popular picnic site. Chittagong is also a good base from which to explore the Rangamati Hill District, famous for its beautiful flora and lakes and the predominantly Buddhist tribal culture.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Experience Dhaka’s historic heart</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The beating heart of the Bengali capital, Old Dhaka is a sprawl of crowded alleyways, unravelling onto the waterfront at Sadar Ghat. As well as famous monuments – Ahsan Manxzil, Lalbagh Fort – the streets are crammed with atmospheric markets selling every imaginable product, and on the edge of the old city is the Baitul Mukarram Mosque, the 10th biggest in the world.</p>]]><p><b>Find peace on the sands of Kuakata</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The long sandy beaches of the far south are better known, but locals claim the finest stretch of sand is at Kuakata, a low-key resort on the edge of the Sundarbans. Close to Barisal, Kuakata offers sparkling sand, swaying palms, ramshackle seafood cafes, laid-back beach resorts, and few of the crowds who mob the sands at Cox's Bazaar.</p>]]><p><b>Follow in the footsteps of the first Bengalis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The archaeological sites of Paharpur, Mahasthanagarh and Sherpur, close to the town of Bogra in the country's northwest, reveal the ancient Hindu and Buddhist origins of Bangladesh. The Somapura Mahavihara was one of the most important Buddhist monasteries of the ancient world and the remains of its vast central stupa dominate the ruins at Paharpur.</p>]]><p><b>Relive a golden age in Sonargaon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>About 25km (15 miles) southeast of Dhaka, sleepy Sonargaon offers respite from the chaos of the capital. This was the capital of eastern Bengal under a string of nawabs and sultans and their faded mansions still line the main road in the village of Painam Nagar. Nearby are ruined mosques and a fine folk-art museum in the historic Sadarbari villa.</p>]]><p><b>Ride a rickshaw through Dhaka</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its crowds, bazaars and rickshaw traffic jams, Bangladesh's capital is famously fast-paced and frenetic. The best place to feel the vibrations of the Bengali capital is Sadar Ghat, where passengers spill from boats day and night in a continuous human tide. More laid-back sights include the uncompleted 17th-century Lalbagh Fort and the stately Ahsan Manzil Palace and Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the Rocket</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Bangladesh's most iconic experiences is the overnight boat trip on the Rocket – the nostalgic paddle-wheel ferry that has piled the waterways between Dhaka and Khulna for more than century. Today, boats travel only as far as Morelganj, but the trip is perhaps the most atmospheric way to experience the pace of life on Bengal's waterways.</p>]]><p><b>Sample the cultural melting pot of Maheskali Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The southern beach resort of Cox's Bazaar attracts local holiday makers in droves, but a more interesting experience can be had off-shore on Maheskali Island, a pilgrimage destination for Muslims, Hindus and Buddhists. Rickshaws wait at Kasturi Ghat to ferry new arrivals up the hill to the Hindu Adinath temple, which offers panoramic views of the island.</p>]]><p><b>See Britain-meets-Bengal in Sylhet</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The divisional capital of Sylhet has grown wealthy from the money sent home by Bengalis working in the UK. Tea is the big local industry, and many workers in the tea plantations are tribal Manipuri and Khasi people. Some estates are within walking distance of the centre and the revered mausoleum of Hazrat Shah Jalal, a 14th-century Sufi mystic.</p>]]><p><b>Sip a brew in Sylhet</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sylhet Division, northeast of Dhaka, is known as 'the land of two leaves and a bud' because of its long tradition of growing fine Indian teas. The best-known estates are found close to the town of Srimangal, which sits amidst a sea of green tea bushes. Many estates offer tours and tastings of the flavoursome local brew.</p>]]><p><b>Spot tigers in the Sundarbans</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The elusive Bengal tiger stalks the rain-soaked waterways of Sundarbans National Park, a vast area of estuarine forest sprawling out into the Bay of Bengal. Spilling over into India, this is the largest mangrove forest in the world, and boat trips offer glimpses of deer, monkeys, exotic birds, and for the lucky, the Bengal tiger himself.</p>]]><p><b>Step into the time of sultans in Bagerhat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the southwest, near Khulna, the town of Bagerhat was the 15th-century capital of the warrior saint Khan Jahan Ali, and the countryside is dotted with the remains of his holy city. The 15th-century Shait Gumbad, the so-called 'Sixty-domed' Mosque, is the most well known structure, but there are more ancient mosques nearby, as well as the mausoleum of Jahan Ali.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll the sand at Cox’s Bar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Bangladesh's far south, close to the border with Myanmar, Cox's Bazaar is where Bangladesh comes to unwind. The world's longest and broadest beach, Inani Beach sprawls south from the city, providing a favourite promenading spot for local holidaymakers. Foreign visitors use the city as a leaping off point for nearby St Martin's Island, perhaps Bangladesh's most perfect beach paradise.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Buddhist villages of Kaptai Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rangamati is the gateway to the Buddhist tribal villages of Kaptai Lake, whose culture owes more to neighbouring Myanmar than to the rest of Bangladesh.</p><p>Boats trips on Kaptai Lake visit Chakma villages and Myanmar-style pagodas, taking in the idyllic green scenery.</p>]]><p><b>Wander the bustling lanes of Chittagong</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The second largest city in Bangladesh, Chittagong is ringed by coconut groves and sandy beaches. This is the gateway to the fascinating Chittagong Hill Tracts, home to Bangladesh's Buddhist hill tribes, and the resort beaches of the far south, but there's plenty to see in the city, including museums and 17th-century mosques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$89 billion (2009).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Garments, jute and jute goods, leather, tea and seafood.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, chemicals, iron and steel, and foodstuffs.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Exports to: USA, Germany, UK and France; Imports from: India, China and Singapore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Overcrowded Bangladesh depends mainly on subsistence agriculture, which suffers frequent and severe damage from cyclones and flooding. Due to a worldwide decline in the demand for jute (formerly an important export), Bangladesh has become more dependant on earning foreign income from the manufacture of textiles. There are reserves of natural gas and low-grade coal, which meet the bulk of domestic energy requirements.<br /><br />Bangladesh continues to rely heavily on foreign aid, which derives from a variety of sources coordinated by the World Bank-led 'Paris Club' of donors. A continuing problem is corruption - Bangladesh is widely recognised to be among the worst offenders.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits or shirt and tie are recommended. Suits are necessary when calling on Bengali officials. Business cards are given and usual courtesies are observed. Visitors should not be misled by the high illiteracy rate and low educational level of most of the population. Given the opportunity, Bangladeshis prove to be good businesspeople and tough negotiators.</p><p>Sun-Thurs 0900-1700 and 0800-1430 (government offices).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Federation of Bangladesh Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FBCCI)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 956 0102
					Website:http://www.fbcci-bd.org/
					Address: ,60 Motijheel Commercial Area,Dhaka-,1000]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The cuisine of Bangladesh straddles the boundary between India and Myanmar, and things get more Burmese and less Indian the further south and east you go.</p><p>For the Muslim majority in Dhaka and northern and western Bangladesh, curry is the national dish, flavoured with the same rich spices found in neighbouring India. Fish features prominently on local menus, alongside <em>biryani</em>, the ubiquitous fried-rice served all over Bangladesh.</p><p>Bengali meals are centred on rice and dal (lentils) – indeed, many Bangladeshis live on these two staples, supplemented by vegetables and the odd bit of fish and meat. Crabs and prawns are popular on the coast, while hilsa, bhekti, butterfish and catfish are served all over the country. In the tribal east, look out for dishes based on bamboo shoots, dried fish, coconut and sour sauces.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Achar: </strong>Pickled vegetables and fruit with mustard and spices<br />
<strong>Dal: </strong>The local name for lentils; dozens of types are served in dozens of different ways.<br />
<strong>Biryani: </strong>Bengali-style fried rice, with curry spices and chicken; a staple for Bangladeshi Muslims.<br />
<strong>Pulao: </strong>Fried rice with vegetables and spices, often served on special occasions.<br />
<strong>Shami kebab</strong>: A grilled, highly spiced kebab made with minced meat.<br />
<strong>Chotpoti</strong>: A stew of chickpeas, potatoes, eggs and spices.<br />
<strong>Mishti doi</strong>: Sweetened yoghurt served as a desert; also called <em>mitha dahi</em>.<br />
<strong>Ilish:</strong> Hilsa fish, frequently served in mustard seed flavoured curries.<br />
<strong>Bhaji: </strong>Vegetables deep fried in lentil flour batter.<br />
<strong>Cha</strong>: Milky sweet tea, made using local grown leaves.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Western food can be found in some hotels and large restaurants in major cities, but elsewhere, Bengali and Chinese food are the only options. The availability of alcohol is extremely limited outside bars in top end hotels.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Locals tend not to tip, but foreigners are often expected to; 10% is appropriate for hotel and restaurant staff.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslims in Bangladesh are prohibited from drinking alcohol, and it is only available to non-Muslims in limited locations. There is no official drinking age.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Leading hotels have bars, but Western-style nightclubs do not exist. The Westin hotel in Dhaka has a bar that offers live music and an open-air terrace. The Pan Pacific Sonargaon hotel offers disco nights and the Balcony Bar which serves imported drinks. The Radisson Water Garden Hotel has the &lsquo;Blaze Entertainment Lounge and Bar&rsquo; which has some offerings of live entertainment and billiards. Some of the international clubs are a good choice for drinks and entertainment, the Nordic Club for example is a good choice, but you need to be a member or to be invited.</p>
<p>Displays of local dance and music are occasionally to be seen, particularly during religious festivals. Traditional theatre can be seen in major cities and the Dhaka City Corporation has opened a modern theatre hall called Dhaka Mahanagor Natya Mancha. Traditional cultural performances may also be seen at Dhaka's Shilpakala Academy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh is famous for its pink pearls. Handloom fabrics, silks, printed saris, coconut masks, bamboo products, mother-of-pearl jewellery, leather crafts, wood and cane handicrafts and folk dolls are popular purchases. Duty-free shops are available in Dhaka and international airports and most hotels have their own shopping arcades.</p>
<p>In Dhaka, the Aarong store (part of a chain of outlets, which is an enterprise of BRAC &ndash; the largest non-governmental development organization in the world) is an excellent one-stop-shop for buying local, ethically produced products. Pottery, brass, Nakshikantha (a traditional form of embroidery) and Jamdani sarees are all for sale. There is also a branch in Chittagong.</p>
<p>There are several malls in Dhaka, Bashundhara City is especially popular, it houses 1,500 shops and has many food outlets and a multiplex cinema.</p><p>Generally Sat-Thurs 0900-2000, Fri 0900-1230 and 1400-2000 (shops in tourist districts often stay open later).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are 4- and 5-star hotels in Dhaka, Chittagong and Cox's Bazar, and a few 5-stars in Dhaka. The Bangladesh Parjatan Corporation manages several modern hotels throughout the country. Bills are usually paid in hard currency or with traveller's cheques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Government-owned and private guest houses are available to hire throughout the country. Enquire at the Bangladesh Parjatan Corporation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are 4- and 5-star hotels in Dhaka, Chittagong and Cox's Bazar, and a few 5-stars in Dhaka. The Bangladesh Parjatan Corporation manages several modern hotels throughout the country. Bills are usually paid in hard currency or with traveller's cheques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are 4- and 5-star hotels in Dhaka, Chittagong and Cox's Bazar, and a few 5-stars in Dhaka. The Bangladesh Parjatan Corporation manages several modern hotels throughout the country. Bills are usually paid in hard currency or with traveller's cheques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is essential. Visitors can also be treated at military hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid all dairy products. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Dengue fever, visceral leishmaniasis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B and E are present. Japanese encephalitis occurs, particularly in rural areas. Humidity and pollution in downtown Dhaka, especially at certain times of the year, can cause problems. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If bitten abroad, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.  Buddhist festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here:</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>International Mother Language Day :
							21 February </p><p>Independence Day :
							26 March </p><p>Bangla New Year :
							14 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>National Revolution and Solidarity Day :
							07 November </p><p>Victory Day :
							16 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Bangladesh by travellers over 18 years old without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 225g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2 bottles of alcoholic beverages of up to 1.25L.<br />
&bull; 250ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Gifts to the value of BDT500.</p>
<p>You can buy duty-free items at Dhaka Airport's duty-free shop on arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms and some animals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh Taka (BDT) = 100 paisa. Notes are in denominations of BDT500, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of BDT5 and 1, and 25 and 50 paisa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All foreign currency exchanged must be entered on a currency declaration form. Hotel bills must be paid in a major convertible currency or with traveller's cheques. Many shops in the cities will offer better rates of exchange than the banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are not generally accepted for payment of goods outside the capital. ATMs (Standard Chartered Bank) are becoming increasingly common and can be found in Dhaka, Chittagong, Bogra, Sylhet and Khulna. HSBC has ATMs in Dhaka and Chittagong.</p><p>ATMs (Standard Chartered Bank) are becoming increasingly common and can be found in Dhaka, Chittagong, Bogra, Sylhet and Khulna. HSBC has ATMs in Dhaka and Chittagong. It is safest to withdraw money from the private booths at Standard Chartered Banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Can be exchanged on arrival at Dhaka Airport. US Dollars are the preferred currency, followed by Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sat-Wed 0900-1500, Thurs 0900-1300. Some banks may close on Saturdays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Bangladesh, a passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh visa prices for Australian nationals: &pound;103 (single-entry, double-entry and multiple-entry for three months).</p>
<p>Bangladesh&nbsp;visa prices for Canadian nationals:&nbsp;&pound;50 (single-entry and double-entry); &pound;101 (multiple-entry for three months).</p>
<p>Bangladesh&nbsp;visa prices for UK nationals: &pound;78 (single-entry, double-entry and multiple-entry for three months).&nbsp;Visa prices for nationals from other EU countries vary according to country.</p>
<p>Bangladesh visa prices for US nationals: &pound;107 (single-entry, double-entry and multiple-entry for three months).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: 30 days.</p>
<p>The maximum stay for a tourist visa is two months; the maximum stay for a business visa is six months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consular section at the embassy or high commission (recommended) or on arrival for certain nationalities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least seven working days for applications submitted in person or at least 10 working days from the date of receipt for postal applications.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your visa, you need to contact the Department of Immigration and Passports (<a href="http://www.dip.gov.bd">www.dip.gov.bd</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[24.309019]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[90.057986]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>143,998 sq km (55,598 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>162,910,864 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,173.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dhaka.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The People's Republic of Bangladesh, formerly East Pakistan, is bordered to the west and northwest by West Bengal (India), to the north by Assam and Meghalaya (India), to the east by Assam and Tripura (India) and by Myanmar (Burma) to the southeast. The landscape is mainly flat. A large part of Bangladesh is made up of alluvial plain, caused by the effects of the two great river systems of the Ganges (Padma) and the Brahmaputra (Jamuna) and their innumerable tributaries. In the northeast and east of the country, the landscape rises to form forested hills. To the southeast, along the Burmese and Indian borders, the land is hilly and wooded. About 7% of the country's area is under water and flooding occurs regularly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>90% Muslim, 9% Hindus and 1% Buddhist and Christian minorities. Religion is the main influence on attitudes and behaviour. Since 1988, Islam has been the official state religion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In someone's home it is acceptable to sit crossed-legged on cushions or the sofa. If a visitor wishes to bring a gift, money must not be given as it may cause offence. Religious customs should be respected by guests. There are severe penalties for possession and trafficking of illegal drugs. Some drugs-related offences are punishable by death. Local women should not be specifically photographed unless it is certain that there will be no objection. Women should wear trousers or long skirts; revealing clothes should be avoided, particularly when visiting religious places. Dress is generally informal for men, though modesty must be maintained. Same-sex relations are illegal.<br />
<strong><br />
Photography:</strong> In rural areas, people are becoming more used to tourists; however, permission should be requested before photographs are taken of individuals. Do not photograph military installations.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Sockets accept a mixture of British-style three-prong plugs, standard European rounded two-pin plugs, rounded three-pin plugs and American-style plugs with two flat pins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina since 2009.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Abdul Hamid since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In ancient history, Bangladesh was ruled by a succession of animist, Buddhist and Hindu empires, including the Pala dynasty in the 8th century, whose kings constructed the vast monastic complex at Paharpur. Hinduism experienced a major revival under the Sena dynasty in the 12th century, but it was soon replaced by Islam, introduced first by Arab traders and Sufi missionaries, and later by conquering armies sent east by the Muslim sultans of the Indian plains.</p>
<p>Successive Muslim dynasties established rival capitals across the country before the Mughals cemented control in 1575, and developed Dhaka as the capital of the province of Bengal. When the British arrived in the 18th century, Mughal control of Bengal had waned and power was devolved to wealthy local families &ndash; the <em>nawabs</em>.</p>
<p>The British East India Company gained ownership of Bengal after the Battle of Plassey in 1757, ruling by proxy through allegiances with powerful <em>nawabs</em>. The division of Bengal into Hindu and Muslim enclaves by the British in 1905 sowed the seeds of rebellion against colonial rule. The Bengal region was divided in 1947 along religious lines in what was known as the Partition of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>, which saw predominately-Hindu West Bengal become a province of India and predominately-Muslim East Bengal become a province of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pakistan">Pakistan</a>, known as East Pakistan.</p>
<p>In the years that followed, the independence movement gathered pace and Bengal continued to be marginalised. Disputes over language and political power came to a head in 1970, when the pro-independence Awami League won an overwhelming majority and West Pakistan sent its armies to suppress the east, plunging the country into civil war. India intervened in 1971 on the side of East Pakistan, but by then perhaps three million Bengalis had been killed by Pakistani forces.</p>
<p>Bangladesh formally came into being on 17 December 1971, but weak governments provided the opportunity for a string of military takeovers. Democracy was finally restored in 1991. Since then, Bangladesh has faced severe challenges: from the devastating 2004 tsunami to a succession of severe cyclones that have flooded large parts of the country. Today, Bangladesh is regarded as one of the nations most vulnerable to the effects of climate change.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong> <br />
&bull;	The Bengal tiger is Bangladesh&rsquo;s national animal, but it&rsquo;s an endangered species with only 440 individuals thought to live in the country.<br />
&bull;	Bangladesh officially has six seasons: summer, rainy, autumn, cool, winter and spring. <br />
&bull;	In Bangladesh, smiling is considered by some people to be a sign of immaturity.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Bangladesh Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 244 0183.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.bdembassyusa.org/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 244 0183.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Consular services: Mon-Fri 1000-1300 (applications), 1500-1700 (collections).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3510 International Drive<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Bangladesh High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7584 0081.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.bhclondon.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7584 0081.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Opening hours (consular services): applications Mon-Thurs 1000-1300, Fri 1000-1230; pickups 1430-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>28 Queen's Gate<br/>London<br/>SW7 5JA<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>India&rsquo;s sleepy eastern cousin, Bangladesh slumbers gently under monsoon skies at the mouth of the Jamuna River, one of the world&rsquo;s great deltas. Formerly East Pakistan, this intriguing backwater gained independence in 1971 after a civil war that still plays a major role in the national psyche.</p>
<p>An influx of tourists was predicted following independence, but this has yet to materialised, meaning visitors have Bangladesh&rsquo;s many and varied attractions to themselves. Those attractions range from Mughal palaces and gleaming mosques to palm-fringed beaches, tea-plantations and jungles full of snarling Bengal tigers.</p>
<p>Bangladesh&rsquo;s frenetic capital, Dhaka, was once the main port for the whole of Bengal, and its rickshaw-crammed streets present a faded mirror to Kolkata across the border. Dhaka is a city of rain-washed colonial buildings, gaudy film posters, docksides thronging with boats and the constant cacophony of car horns and rickshaw bells. It can be a shock for the senses, but the blow is softened by friendly, inquisitive locals and delicious Bengali cuisine.</p>
<p>South of Dhaka, the Jamuna River breaks down into a tangle of jungle-choked waterways as you enter the Sundarbans, one of the last refuges of the Bengal tiger. Here, as elsewhere in Bangladesh, the best way to get around is by river &ndash; legions of boats ply every waterway, from tiny coracles to the paddleboat &lsquo;rockets&rsquo; that chug between Dhaka and Kulna.</p>
<p>The south of Bangladesh is something else again; tropical beaches give way to forested hills that hide a host of Buddhist and animist tribes. Then there&rsquo;s Sylhet, in the heart of tea plantation country, where foreign remittances have built a miniature version of England amidst the monsoon hills.</p>
<p>Above all else, Bangladesh is place to leave the mainstream travel map. Let the crowds mob the beaches of Goa and the forts of Rajasthan; in Bangladesh, you won&rsquo;t have to queue to be amazed.</p><p>India&rsquo;s sleepy eastern cousin, Bangladesh slumbers gently under monsoon skies at the mouth of the Jamuna River, one of the world&rsquo;s great deltas. Formerly East Pakistan, this intriguing backwater gained independence in 1971 after a civil war that still plays a major role in the national psyche.</p>
<p>An influx of tourists was predicted following independence, but this has yet to materialised, meaning visitors have Bangladesh&rsquo;s many and varied attractions to themselves. Those attractions range from Mughal palaces and gleaming mosques to palm-fringed beaches, tea-plantations and jungles full of snarling Bengal tigers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
