<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Barbados" ColCode="brb" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bb" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Barbados]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constant sea breezes cool Barbados's balmy, tropical climate but the island is still sunnier and drier than the other islands. During the so-called wet season (July to November), some brief rain showers are likely. Average sunshine hours per day are eight to 10 from November to March and eight to nine from April to October. Tropical storms and hurricanes may occur between June and November.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons are advised; beachwear is not worn in towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no internal flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>A good network of roads covers the entire island, but many are unpaved and covered in potholes (except for the main highway).&nbsp;Road safety is a national concern, especially after dark.</p><p>Taxis are unmetered but charge fares regulated by the government which are based on the distance travelled. Check the rate before travel - it can be in US Dollars as well Barbados Dollars. Special deals apply for a full-day hire. Licensed minivans, identifiable by their 'ZR' licence plates, operate around the island and can be flagged down. There are no fixed schedules, but service is frequent. Rates are the same as for buses, although minivans tend to be quicker - but can be a tight squeeze.</p><p>A Barbados driving permit is required. You can obtain this from car hire companies, the airport or some police stations. A valid national licence or International Driving Permit and a small registration fee are required.</p><p>Seat belts are compulsory. Speed limits are 40kph (25mph) in built-up areas and 60-80kph (37-50mph) outside urban areas.</p><p>Hiring a car is the best way to explore Barbados, thanks to the fact it&rsquo;s a well-developed, small island measuring just 34km (21 miles) long and 23km (14 miles) wide. You can hire anything from a mini moke to a limousine at the airport, at offices in Bridgetown or at main hotels.</p>
<p>Traffic drives on the left. Drivers must be between 21 and 65 years of age to hire a car in Barbados, with a minimum three years' driving experience. Visitors to the island are easily identifiable on the road by the 'H' number plate. Locals are usually accommodating and make allowances for any confusion.</p><p>Scooter hire is available - you will need to pay a small deposit and wear a helmet, as required by law.</p><p>Seat belts are compulsory. Speed limits are 40kph (25mph) in built-up areas and 60-80kph (37-50mph) outside urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Barbados has a modern, reliable bus network, which operates from 0500 to midnight, while taxis are safe and reliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Barbados</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">speightstown</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Barbados</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">oistins</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Barbados</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">holetown</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Direct flights to Barbados from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> are provided by British Airways (<a href="http://www.britishairways.com">www.britishairways.com</a>)&nbsp;and Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>). If you&rsquo;re looking for cheap flights to Barbados, avoid the peak holiday season between December and March. Cheap Barbados flights are best found between June and October&rsquo;s hurricane season.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/barbados/grantley-adams-international-airport">Grantley Adams international Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>&nbsp;- 8&nbsp;hours 50 minutes;&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>&nbsp;- 4 hours 40 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Grantley Adams International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.gaia.bb<p>Grantley Adams International Airport is situated 13km (8 miles) southeast of Bridgetown.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 246 418 4242</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Barbados's deep-water harbour at <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bridgetown">Bridgetown</a> is a port of call for a number of British, European and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> cruise lines (<a href="http://www.barbadosport.com" target="_blank">www.barbadosport.com</a>). The Bridgetown Cruise Ship Terminal is a multi-purpose marketplace containing shops and restaurants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Cardphones and payphones are located across the island; many make overseas calls. Local calls are free (unless calling from a hotel or business).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with many international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good. Mobile phones can be hired locally.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet caf&eacute;s throughout Barbados. Wi-Fi is increasingly available, especially in hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Press freedom is an established part of Barbadian life with newspapers privately owned and largely unrestricted. Two local daily newspapers are available &ndash; the <em>Barbados Advocate</em> and the <em>Daily Nation</em>. Radio broadcasting benefits from a healthy mix of private and public stations. Although government-owned, the island's sole TV station CBC presents a wide range of political views.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post offices and boxes are found across the island, including at the airport. Airmail to Europe takes around 10 days.</p><p>Variable, but as a general guide Mon-Fri 0730-1700 at the General Post Office; other branches Mon-Fri 0800-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the colonial architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Jacobean St Nicholas Abbey is graced with ornate Persian arches and well-kept gardens. Although now in ruins, Farley Hill is still covered in hibiscus and poinsettias and is one of the island's most storied plantation houses. The George Washington House and Museum is a beautifully restored plantation house, where the former US president stayed on a brief visit to Barbados in 1751.</p>]]><p><b>Admire the local architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tyrol Cot, the grand former home of Sir Grantley Adams, the first premier of Barbados, is a stunning example of local architectural styles. Constructed in 1854, this architectural gem offers an interesting mixture of Palladian and tropical vernacular – beautifully restored by the Barbados National Trust.</p>]]><p><b>Bask on Crane Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The baby-pink sands of cliff-flanked Crane Beach, an idyllic spot that is one of the most beautiful on the island, are perfect for a stroll or some sunbathing. Moderate, foamy waves draw a body-surfing crowd and there are plenty of shaded spots to chill out until the magical sunsets arrive.</p>]]><p><b>Breeze around Bridgetown</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Barbados capital, Bridgetown, is the best place to enjoy the island&rsquo;s colonial history. Visit National Heroes Square, which boasts a statue of Lord Nelson, erected in 1813, well before Nelson's Column was put up in London. Nearby are the neo-Gothic Parliament Buildings, Bridgetown Synagogue (reputed to the oldest in the western hemisphere) and the pretty, pink pastel coloured facades of DaCosta&rsquo;s Mall. When you tire of sightseeing, pop into one of the ubiquitous rum shops or head for a drink at the Waterfront area overlooking the marina.</p>]]><p><b>Discover shipwrecks in Carlisle Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Barbados has several excellent sites for wreck diving. Arguably the most famous is Carlisle Bay, which has more than 200 reported wrecks, and the Stavronikita, a Greek freighter which rests in 37m (120ft) of water, less than 1.6 km (1 mile) from the shore at Folkestone Marine Park.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Harrison’s Cave</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With an abundance of stalactites, stalagmites, streams, lakes and waterfalls, Harrison's Cave is a jaw-dropping spectacle. The caves were first mentioned in historical documents in 1795 and then virtually forgotten for nearly 200 years, until being rediscovered in 1976. Visitors can explore the caves on a 40-minute guided tour in an electric cart. Self-guided walks are also possible.</p>]]><p><b>Get close to nature in Welchman Hall Gully's</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You can also take a self-guided hike amid rare fruit trees in Welchman Hall Gully's magnificent botanic garden or in Andromeda Gardens. Another highlight is the Flower Forest, a vast leafy garden rich in native plants. The Barbados National Trust offers free, guided hikes which are divided into three categories: stop'n'stare, where'n'there and grin'n'bear. Moonlit walks are also held.</p>]]><p><b>Get wet</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The island's rugged south and west coasts boast world-class watersports where windsurfers, jet skiers, parasailers and water skiers enjoy perfect conditions. To ride the waves head to the Soup Bowl, South Point and Rockley Beach, which are Barbados' best surfing spots.</p>]]><p><b>Go scuba-diving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>While there are less pelagic fish off Barbados because of unregulated fishing, divers can enjoy a range of other marine life including sea horses, frogfish and giant sand eels. Hidden caves and shipwrecks provide plenty of underwater nooks and crannies along a shoreline nested by hawksbill turtles.</p>]]><p><b>Go wildlife watching in Barbados Wildlife Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Barbados Wildlife Reserve's resplendent mahogany forest is the roaming territory of green monkeys, tortoises, deer, raccoons, pelicans and otters. A walk-through aviary allows a leafy stroll with peacocks, turkeys, toucans, parrots, flamingos, pelicans, lovebirds and macaws.</p>]]><p><b>Peruse the wares at Chalky Mount Potteries</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Barbados' famous Chalky Mount potters are renowned for their high quality inexpensive art. You can watch the local potters at work at the wheel fashioning centuries-old designs, which is a respected 300-year-old tradition. Buy some of their wares to support the potters' time-honoured profession.</p>]]><p><b>Saddle up and go for a gallop</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Horse riding is a popular activity in Barbados. It's possible to gallop along the beach at sundown or simply trek along inland trails. Dozens of horse-riding events take place on the Garrison Savannah. Polo is also played to a high level by fiercely competitive Barbadian teams.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the views</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lofty Mount Hillaby, the island's highest point at 343m (1,125ft), offers incredible panoramas across the east, west and northern coasts. Dramatic vistas also abound from St John's Parish Church over miles of jagged coastline and moss-covered family vaults dotted with tropical flora.</p>]]><p><b>Take the East Coast Road</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Barbados's East Coast Road, hemmed by crashing Atlantic waves, is one of the island's most exciting drives. A rugged coastal route overlooks treacherous reefs while an inland road weaves through rolling sugarcane to quaint plantation towns topped by church steeples.</p>]]><p><b>Taste the oldest rum in the world</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mount Gay Rum, on the island's west coast, can trace its heritage back to 1703, making it the world's oldest rum producer. Made from the sugar cane that thrived across the island, it was once the favoured tipple of English sailors. Visitors can learn about the refining, aging, blending and bottling process on tastings and tours, which run hourly between Monday-Saturday.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Morgan Lewis Mill</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The aged and charming Morgan Lewis Mill is one of only two of the Caribbean's intact sugar mills, and a noteworthy example of a Dutch windmill from the days of the sugar cane planters. The mill includes an exhibit of the equipment used to produce sugar. Although the old plantation house has seen better days, its crumbling exteriors are very evocative and an important legacy of the island's history.</p>]]><p><b>Watch a game of cricket</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cricket is the national sporting obsession. There&rsquo;s always a game going on somewhere. Choose from barefoot village friendlies to international and local club cups where many of the great names of West Indian cricket are honoured, most notably Sir Garfield Sobers.</p>]]><p><b>Whizz through the rainforest at Walkes Spring</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Aerial Trek Zipline Adventures offers soft adventure thrills as you whizz through the rainforest at Jack-in-the-box Gully, Walkes Spring, in the centre of the island. The scenic ride began operations in 2007 and is proving popular. Advance bookings are recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$4.55 billion (2016 est.).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cotton, chemicals, plants, rum, sugar, molasses and electrical components.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Consumer goods, machinery, food, chemicals, fuel and construction materials.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK, USA, Trinidad &amp; Tobago, St Lucia and Jamaica.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One of the wealthiest countries in the Eastern Caribbean, the Barbadian economy has been growing steadily since 2009. According to a 2017 assessment by the Index of Economic Freedom, Barbados's economy is 54.5% free. Improved investment freedom places it high above the regional average. <br />
<br />
Traditionally relying on sugarcane and other agricultural exports, Barbados has successfully diversified its economic activities. Tourism now represents the largest employer on the island. Cotton, flowers and plants are being developed as export products. The island's other important industry is oil. Exploration efforts have intensified since the mid 1990s. Today, two-thirds of offshore output is exported, with the remainder assigned for domestic consumption. Barbados has also developed an 'offshore' financial industry that now accounts for 15% of GDP. <br />
<br />
Barbados receives some overseas aid from British and US sources and is a member of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/caribbean">Caribbean</a> economic community (CARICOM) which has boosted regional trade. Good transport and communications infrastructure is poised to assist future economic development. Barbados's declared goal is to become the world's smallest developed nation.<br />
Barbados is keen to position itself as the Caribbean's foremost convention destination and offers a number of conference facilities for incentive and business travel groups. All are centred on Bridgetown where meeting space is fully air conditioned and equipped to handle seminars, trade shows and exhibitions, from 15 to 2,500 delegates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bajans favour a more formal approach to greeting and meeting. This is most commonly a handshake between both sexes. When introducing or referring to a Bajan, you should always use a title and surname. Using first names, especially if you have don&rsquo;t have a personal connection to the person, could be considered quite impolite.  Lightweight suits are recommended. European courtesies should be observed, such as presenting business cards.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Barbados Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 426 2056
					Website:http://www.bdscham.com
					Address: Nemwil House,First Floor,Collymore Rock,]]><b>Barbados Conference Services Ltd</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 467 8200
					Website:http://www.bcslbarbados.com
					Address: Two Mile Hill,Sherbourne Conference Centre,St Michael,]]><b>Barbados Investment &amp; Development Corporation</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 427 5350
					Website:http://www.bidc.com
					Address: Princess Alice Highway,PO Box 1250,Pelican House,Bridgetown,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Eating out in Barbados is pricier compared to other Caribbean islands and diners should expect to pay hefty bills even in a mid-range restaurant. There is an eclectic choice of food available, though, with everything from global cuisine served in smart, world-renowned restaurants to Bajan fare available in street markets such as Oistins.</p>
<p>Replica British pubs are popular and serve genuine British bitter and stout &ndash; often with fish-and-chip bar snacks. There are more than 100 rum shops scattered across the island, which are simple, sometimes shabby, but always friendly where policeman and locals sip a mid-afternoon drink &ndash; it&rsquo;s something to be experienced.</p>
<p>A smoking ban in public places was enforced in 2010 and anyone caught breaking it could face a fine or imprisonment. Weirdly, drinking and driving is still legal.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cutters:</strong> Large sandwiches, usually made with flying fish or ham, and doused with hot sauce.<br />
<strong>Conkies:</strong> Cornmeal blended with coconut, pumpkin, raisins, sweet potato and spices steamed in a banana leaf.<br />
<strong>Rice'n'peas:</strong> Rice mixed with local beans and usually flavoured with coconut.<br />
<strong>Sea eggs:</strong> Devilled sea urchin roe.<br />
<strong>Souse:</strong> Pickled pork, typically served with steamed potato.<br />
<strong>Fresh fish:</strong> Overfishing is an issue in the Caribbean, but you will nevertheless find the likes of chubb, marlin, shrimp and kingfish on the menu. Flying fish served with cou cou (steamed cornmeal with okra) and a gravy made with herbs and tomatoes is the national dish.<br />
<strong>Flying fish:</strong> Served with cou-cou (steamed cornmeal with okra) and a gravy made with herbs and tomatoes, this is a national dish.<br />
<strong>Grilled pigtail:</strong> Crispy pork snacks.<br />
<strong>Conch fritters:</strong> Deep-fried snacks made from conch meat.<br />
<strong>Rum:</strong> There are numerous distilleries, but Mount Gay and Cockspur&rsquo;s are the big players.<br />
<strong>Cocktails:</strong> Many typically feature the island&rsquo;s world-renowned rum.<br />
<strong>Banks:</strong> Light and refreshing, this is the local beer.<br />
<strong>Mauby:</strong> Non-alcoholic drink made from the boiled, strained and sweetened bark of a local tree.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10-15%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bajans love to party with nightlife options in Barbados ranging from clubs, beach bars and pubs to rum shops, dinner shows and twilight boat cruises. Music ranges from calypso and reggae to the latest R'n'B.   Most of the main nightlife spots are concentrated around the south and west coasts. St Lawrence Gap is the liveliest nightlife spot on the islands; it&rsquo;s a one-street affair lined with smart pubs, clubs and bars.  If you want to party with the locals, head to Oistins Fish Market on a Friday or Saturday night, where Bajans dance to the early hours in the open air with music ranging from country and western to the latest calypso.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopping in Barbados offers a varied experience. As a duty-free island, prices are typically 30% to 50% less than in Europe and North America. Shoppers must have their airline or passport ticket when purchasing duty free goods. Most of the duty free shops and large, western-style shopping malls offering high quality goods and excellent service are found along Broad Street in Bridgetown. Here you can buy everything from designer clothing to gold and silver jewellery.  Popular souvenirs include local handicrafts, such as straw bags, batiks, paintings, rum and woodwork. Speciality craft and gift shops can be found in Pelican Village, outside Bridgetown, as well as Holetown, Speightstown and St Lawrence Gap. The Crane Village on the south-east coast is the latest upmarket shopping destination, which includes duty-free shops.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700, Sat 0900-1300 or 1400. Some stores are open until 1800 or 2100 on weekdays and until 1530 on Saturdays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the luxury hotels in Barbados can be found on the western Platinum Coast, so called because of their pristine, toothpaste beaches particularly in the parish of St James. Well-known Barbados hotels include Sandy Lane Hotel, Cobblers Cove and Tamarind Cove. Excellent spa facilities are also available in some properties.</p>
<p>More and more boutique hotels in Barbados are also springing up. More affordable options are sprinkled along the southwest coast. There are limited hotels on the east coast of Barbados. There are a wide range of all-inclusive hotels in Barbados from three to five star. Rates are subject to a 7.5% government tax; a service charge between 10 to 15% is also applicable at most hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are small guest houses throughout Barbados, particularly along the south and west coasts. A few are also located on the east coast. Most offer self-catering facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the luxury hotels in Barbados can be found on the western Platinum Coast, so called because of their pristine, toothpaste beaches particularly in the parish of St James. Well-known Barbados hotels include Sandy Lane Hotel, Cobblers Cove and Tamarind Cove. Excellent spa facilities are also available in some properties.</p>
<p>More and more boutique hotels in Barbados are also springing up. More affordable options are sprinkled along the southwest coast. There are limited hotels on the east coast of Barbados. There are a wide range of all-inclusive hotels in Barbados from three to five star. Rates are subject to a 7.5% government tax; a service charge between 10 to 15% is also applicable at most hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the luxury hotels in Barbados can be found on the western Platinum Coast, so called because of their pristine, toothpaste beaches particularly in the parish of St James. Well-known Barbados hotels include Sandy Lane Hotel, Cobblers Cove and Tamarind Cove. Excellent spa facilities are also available in some properties.</p>
<p>More and more boutique hotels in Barbados are also springing up. More affordable options are sprinkled along the southwest coast. There are limited hotels on the east coast of Barbados. There are a wide range of all-inclusive hotels in Barbados from three to five star. Rates are subject to a 7.5% government tax; a service charge between 10 to 15% is also applicable at most hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Both private and state-run medical facilities in Barbados are excellent. Prescribed medicines are provided cost-free for children and elderly patients. All dental treatment bears a cost. Medical insurance is recommended for all nationals.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Barbados's water is said to rank amongst the purest in the world; it is filtered naturally by limestone and coral and pumped from underground streams. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Long-term travellers may be advised to immunise against hepatitis B. A low risk of dengue fever exists. Hay fever and asthma can be exacerbated during the sugar cane harvesting season. Barbados has a high prevalence of HIV/AIDS, particularly amongst the 20 to 45 age group, of which it is the second-biggest killer. All necessary precautions should be undertaken.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Errol Barrow Day :
							2018<br/>21 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>National Heroes' Day :
							28 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Emancipation Day :
							01 August </p><p>Kadooment Day :
							06 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							30 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be brought into Barbados by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 1L of spirits or wine.</p>
<p>All other articles are subject to import duty, other than personal effects required during your visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include illegal drugs and pornography.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include fruit, vegetables, plants and seeds, which may require a permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Barbados Dollar (BBD; symbol BD$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of BD$100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 2. Coins are in denominations of BD$1, and 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.<br /><br />The Barbados Dollar is tied to the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Commercial banks offer the best rates of exchange. The Barbados National Bank and a range of international banks each have an office in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bridgetown">Bridgetown</a> with branches in Hastings, Holetown, Speightstown and Worthing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted in the resorts, but cash is preferred for customs duty payment. ATMs are widely available.</p><p>ATMs are widely available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted by all banks and most hotels. Opt for traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Pounds Sterling to avoid additional charges.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Thurs 0800-1500, Fri 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Barbados, visitors require a passport valid for the duration of stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visitor visa: US$104; multiple-entry visitor visa: US$208.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consular section at embassy or high commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow two weeks for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Animals must have lived in a rabies-free country for at least six months before entry into Barbados. You must also obtain an import permit from the Veterinary Services office; see <a href="http://www.agriculture.gov.bb">www.agriculture.gov.bb</a> for more information and a list of rabies-free countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[13.193887]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-59.543198]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>430 sq km (166 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>284,996 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>663 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bridgetown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As the most easterly of the Caribbean chain, Barbados lies well to the east of the West Indies. A lively surf scene enjoys pounding waves along the rugged east coast where a rocky shoreline kicks up plenty of spray. To the west, fine white sand beaches and natural coral reefs predominate. A handful of gently rolling hills form a ripple to the north while the rest of the island is predominantly flat. Coral filters ensure surrounding waters are among the purest on the planet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Over 100 religious groups practise island-wide, from the Anglican majority to smaller Roman Catholic, Jewish, Hindu, Baptists, Pentecostals, Seventh Day Adventists, Jehovah's Witnesses, Mormons, The Salvation Army, Muslim and Quaker faiths.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many British societal attitudes permeate bureaucratic red tape and architecture, yet when it comes to time-keeping, humour and urgency the laid-back Barbados manner reigns supreme. Barefoot casual attire is de rigour except when dressing up-to-the nines for dinner - or church. As a former slave colony, personal freedom is highly valued.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110-115 volts AC, 50Hz. American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without round grounding pin) are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Mia Mottley since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General Dame Sandra Mason since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Little is known of the early history of Barbados: it was occupied by Arawak Indians from South America as early as 1600 BC before they were wiped out by the cannibalistic Carib Indians around 1200 AD. This war faring tribe was then decimated with the arrival of the Spanish in the 1400s.</p>
<p>While the Spanish, and later the Portuguese, christened the island Los Barbodoes (&ldquo;the bearded ones&rdquo;, after the island&rsquo;s fig trees), it was the British who claimed the island in 1625. By 1663, Barbados was declared a British colony and slaves were brought to the island from Africa to work on the sugar plantations, which rapidly underpinned the entire country&rsquo;s economy. Barbados dominated the industry until 1720.</p>
<p>Slavery was then abolished in 1834 but many freed Bajans returned to work as paid labourers for the former employers. During the early 1900s, the establishment of trade unions gave workers more rights, but the Great Depression of the 1930s led to soaring unemployment, riots and British financial aid.</p>
<p>Gradually, Bajans started to demand their own political rights, leading to the election of Errol Walton Barrow as the island&rsquo;s first prime minister in 1962. Barrow led Barbados to independence four years later. Since then successive governments have tried to help diversify the economy and propel development. However, the country&rsquo;s sugar industry has declined and the agriculture industry has follow suit.</p>
<p>Tourism has picked up the slack. Barbados has a highly developed tourism industry, though it did take a knock after the recession in 2008, reminding islanders of the vulnerability of pinning the economy&rsquo;s hopes on one industry. Meanwhile, the island&rsquo;s offshore banking and financial services sector has grown.</p>
<p>In the 2008 election, David Thompson of the Democratic Labour Party (DLP) assumed office as prime minister from the Barbados Labour Party, which had been in power for 14 years. Thompson pledged to focus on domestic issues, particularly the cost of living, healthcare, and crime. His successor, Freundel Stuart took over in 2010.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong> <br />
&bull;	Drink driving in Barbados is still not illegal.<br />
&bull;	Barbados is known as the &ldquo;land of the flying fish&rdquo; due to the ubiquity of these creatures in its waters. <br />
&bull;	In Barbados it is considered good luck if a mongoose crosses your path.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Barbados in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 939 9200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.foreign.gov.bb/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 939 9200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2144 Wyoming Avenue<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Barbados High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7299 7150.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.foreign.gov.bb</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7299 7150.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1700 (general enquiries); 1000-1600 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Bloomsbury<br/>1 Great Russell Street<br/>London<br/>WC1B 3ND<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fringed by white sandy beaches, sapphire seas and colourful coral reefs, Barbados is the archetypal Caribbean retreat. Off the beaten path this is not: Simon Cowell, Wayne Rooney and Will Smith are amongst the many celebs that have popularised the island, which, alas, has the a-list prices to match.</p>
<p>First time visitors can be forgiven for heading straight for the sand. Barbados is endowed with 113km (70 miles) of glorious beaches, which range from calm coves to surf-pounded shorelines. Most tourists flock to the Platinum Coast to the west, which is lined with luxury resorts, spa hotels, sophisticated restaurants and manicured golf courses, all lapped by the limpid Caribbean Sea.</p>
<p>Never played golf? Not a fan of high-end resorts? Then fear not. The altogether quieter south coast has some of the island&rsquo;s best beaches, while the east coast, pummelled by the Atlantic Ocean, is less developed and attracts mainly surfers, who quench their thirsts in local rum shacks.</p>
<p>Although Barbados&rsquo;s interior is unremarkable compared to some of its Caribbean neighbours there is much to see. And the best way to see it is by hiring a motorbike or a jeep and taking to the road, calling at crumbling sugar mills, rum distilleries and traditional churches that look like they&rsquo;ve been lifted from England. Finish up in the colonial capital, Bridgetown, which, along with the nearby garrison, was awarded World Heritage Site status in 2012.</p>
<p>Combine these attractions with the island&rsquo;s indelible laid-back vibe, its passion for rum (over 1,500 rum shops dot the island) and calypso-infused festivals, and it&rsquo;s no wonder people return to Barbados time and time again.</p><p>Fringed by white sandy beaches, sapphire seas and colourful coral reefs, Barbados is the archetypal Caribbean retreat. Off the beaten path this is not: Simon Cowell, Wayne Rooney and Will Smith are amongst the many celebs that have popularised the island, which, alas, has the a-list prices to match.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
