<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Belarus" ColCode="blr" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="by" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Belarus]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belarus enjoys a seasonal climate with long cold winters and warm, temperate summers. Its presence near the Black Sea means it misses out on the huge temperature fluctuations characteristic of this region of Europe.</p><p>The best time to visit Belarus is during the summer months from May to September. In July and August temperatures can reach highs of 25°C (77°F) although the average is 18°C (64°F). In winter, temperatures can drop quite severely, with the mercury hitting lows of -4C (XXXF).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the winter you'll need to wear medium- to heavyweights in winter – jeans, knits and heavy coats, and good boots at a minimum. In the summer, depending on where in the country you'll be visiting, thinner cottons, linens, shorts and t-shirts will be fine. Waterproofs are advisable throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belavia (<a href="http://www.belavia.by" target="_blank">www.belavia.by</a>) provides domestic flights to all major cities in Belarus including Brest and Vitebsk. Beware of using local airlines, which may have questionable safety standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Services run regularly from Minsk to all other towns. For more information, contact Belarus Railways (<a href="http://www.rw.by" target="_blank">www.rw.by</a>). Keep an eye out for your luggage; numerous cases of theft on trains have been reported.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belarus&rsquo; main highways are halfway decent, but other roads in the country are often hazardous, poorly maintained and thus heavily potholed. It&rsquo;s possible to find fuel in major cities but elsewhere filling up your tank can be more unpredictable. In rural areas beware of pony and trap drivers. There are police checkpoints on all the main routes to and from Minsk.</p>
<p>Belarus has an electronic toll system, which requires drivers to collect an OBU (on board unit) when crossing the border, and top this up with funds as you drive on the country&rsquo;s toll roads. A fine is imposed on drivers who do not have an OBU in the vehicle.</p>
<p>There is also a fee for drivers of foreign vehicles wishing to use Belarus' highways. Payments are collected at border checkpoints and vary according to the length of stay (and often the value of your vehicle).</p>r<p>Many of the minor roads are impassable during the winter months due to potholes and poor maintenance.</p><p>Coach travel within Belarus can be slow due to road conditions.</p><p>These are numerous and inexpensive. Official taxis in Minsk are usually Russian-made Volga sedans, yellow in colour with black and white squares, although this isn&rsquo;t always the case. It's best to arrange a price before your journey whether the taxi is metered or not. It is possible to order a taxi by calling 007.</p><p>It&rsquo;s possible to drive using your national driving licence, but often an International Driving Permit is preferred. When travelling by private vehicle, travellers must be able to produce ownership documents or a letter of 'power of attorney' at customs offices at border crossings; only originals will be accepted. Travellers must have third-party car insurance &ndash; this can be bought when entering Belarus. Drivers should stop when instructed, and have the vehicle documentation ready, otherwise face a fine and delay.</p><p>The speed limit is 60kph (37mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (55mph) outside built up areas and 100kph (62mph) on motorways (Brest-Moscow). Motorists who have held a driving licence for under two years must not exceed 70kph (43mph). Vehicles should have lights on at all times from 1 November to 31 March. All vehicles should be equipped with a first-aid kit, fire extinguisher, warning triangle, winter tyres (between November and March) and OBU.</p><p>This is available from all major hotels in the capital Minsk. Hertz (<a href="http://www.hertz.co.uk" target="_blank">www.hertz.co.uk</a>) Europcar (<a href="http://www.europcar.co.uk" target="_blank">www.europcar.co.uk</a>) and Avis (<a href="http://www.avis.co.uk" target="_blank">www.avis.co.uk</a>) are all available at the International airport in Minsk. Prices are similar to the rest of Europe. It should be remembered when planning to hire a car in Belarus that not unlike neighbouring Russia, driving is not always relaxing, and safety standards are not on a par with Western Europe yet.</p><p>Belarus is not particularly cycle friendly. You may see the occasional local in the countryside on a bike, but not many. Roads in Belarus are not the safest places.</p><p>The speed limit is 60kph (37mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (55mph) outside built up areas and 100kph (62mph) on motorways (Brest-Moscow). Motorists who have held a driving licence for under two years must not exceed 70kph (43mph). Vehicles should have lights on at all times from 1 November to 31 March. All vehicles should be equipped with a first-aid kit, fire extinguisher, warning triangle, winter tyres (between November and March) and OBU.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public transport through Minsk is cheap and efficient. Minsk has an underground metro system with two lines that cover central Minsk, with plans for further expansion with a third line. Trains run between 0530 and 0100, buses, trams and trolleybuses run from 0535-0030. You can buy tickets for buses, trams and trolleybuses at newsstands or kiosks and you must punch them on board. Entry to the underground is by tokens which are obtainable from stations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belarus&rsquo; national airline Belavia (<a href="http://www.belavia.by" target="_blank">www.belavia.by</a>) offers direct flights from a number of destinations, including London, Amsterdam and&nbsp;Berlin. Other airlines flying to Belarus include Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>) and Ukraine International Airlines (<a href="http://www.flyuia.com" target="_blank">www.flyuia.com</a>).&nbsp;Direct flights to Moscow are regularly available with Belavia and Aeroflot (<a href="http://www.aeroflot.ru" target="_blank">www.aeroflot.ru</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/minsk-national-airport">Minsk National Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Minsk: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 3 hours;&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>&nbsp;- 11 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International flights land at Minsk-2 airport (<a href="http://www.airport.by" target="_blank">www.airport.by</a>) which is approximately 40km (25 miles) east of the capital. Most domestic flights and also flights to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kiev">Kiev</a> and Moscow leave from the smaller Minsk-1 airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International flights land at Minsk-2 airport (<a href="http://www.airport.by" target="_blank">www.airport.by</a>) which is approximately 40km (25 miles) east of the capital. Most domestic flights and also flights to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kiev">Kiev</a> and Moscow leave from the smaller Minsk-1 airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Minsk National Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport.by<p>The airport is located about 42km (26 miles) east of the city of Minsk.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+375 17 279 1300</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belarus is a landlocked country with no approaches by water. However with the Baltic States and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a> close by, it could always make a viable extension to any journey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All trains arrive and depart from Minsk-Passazhirsky Railway Station located in the centre of Minsk. There are several lines from Berlin via Warsaw and Brest with connections to Minsk. Another line runs from Vienna via Warsaw and Brest. Further direct trains are available from other cities, including Kaliningrad, Moscow, Odessa, Riga and Vilnius.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belarus does not offer and is not included on any rail pass schemes. However it should be noted that it is possible to travel as close as neighbouring Poland with a European East Pass for rail travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are approximately 10 &lsquo;official&rsquo; road routes into Belarus &ndash; which should be stuck to in order to avoid undue complications. The roads between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vilnius">Vilnius</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lithuania">Lithuania</a>) and Minsk and between Minsk and Bialystok (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/poland">Poland</a>) are probably the most popular. International Driving Permits are required to drive inside Belarus.</p><p>As long as you have the correct visa, entering Belarus by road is (in theory) relatively unrestricted. That said, due to long queues at border crossings, it can be a very time-consuming experience. For the more adventurous traveller, hitchhiking in Eastern Europe is still popular and commonly used &ndash; Belarus is no exception, but of course crossing any border in such a way should be entertained with due caution.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>To make international calls it is necessary to dial 8, wait for a tone, then dial 10. Calls from Belarus to some countries must be booked through the international operator. Public telephones take cards. Grey booths are for internal calls and blue ones for international calls. Prepaid phone cards are available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belarusian mobile phone networks have grown more extensive in their coverage, and are no longer limited to the major cities. There are several international roaming agreements in place; however it&rsquo;s often much cheaper to make calls by either hiring a local handset or using a local sim inside an unlocked mobile phone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a few internet cafes in the major cities, but you're more likely to be able to access the internet from your hotel's Wi-Fi.  Broadband is growing increasingly common but be prepared for slow connection speeds. Access is also available at some post offices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Belarusian authorities have been heavily criticised by human rights and media organisations for suppressing freedom of speech, muzzling the independent press and denying the opposition access to state owned media. The president's administration controls decisions on content and the appointment of senior editors of state media.<br/>Government-controlled newspapers enjoy considerable state subsidies and financial privileges, while many of the opposition print media have faced increased charges, been forced to close down, change name or publish abroad. But some leading privately-owned newspapers survive thanks to popular demand. The English-language paper <em>Belarus Today </em>is published weekly whilst the principal dailies are <em>Narodnaya Hazeta </em>and <em>Respublika</em>, all printed in Belarusian and Russian. <em>Sovetskaya Beloroussiya </em>is a Russian language state-sponsored newspaper. The Belarusian National State Teleradio Company operates domestic radio and TV channels and an external radio service. Some radio stations target Belarusian listeners from outside the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes a minimum of 10 days. The Central Post Office (Minsk, near the railway station) and the Yubileynaya and Planeta hotels in Minsk offer express mail services. DHL Worldwide Express and Federal Express also have branches in Minsk.</p><p>0800-2000 (central office in Minsk).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Belavezha Wood</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belavezha Woodis one of the last sites where rare animals such as bison, bears and wolves can still be seen living in their natural habitat. Long scenic hiking trails are scattered throughout the Nature Reserve of Berezinsky, stretching from the source of the Berezina to Palik Lake. Primeval forests, marshland, deep rivers and a rich fauna and flora dominate this unique region, hence its UNESCO listing as a protected biosphere. This reserve historically provided a great trade route known as the way 'from the Varangians to the Greeks', connecting the Baltic and the Black Sea countries.</p>]]><p><b>Belovezhskaya Pushcha National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the countryside surrounding Brest, time appears to have stood still for centuries; 500-year-old trees can be found in the state national park, Belovezhskaya Pushcha. Wild European (Belovezhskaya) bison roam the area. The park contains 60 types of animal and 900 types of plants.</p>]]><p><b>Braslav Lake District</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Braslav Lake District situated in the north and northeast of the country, near the borders of Lithuania and Latvia, is ideal for boating holidays. Several of the 30 lakes, situated in an atmospheric forest, are connected by canals. Accommodation in the area is usually in small dachas along the lakeshore.</p>]]><p><b>Brest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the highlights of Brest is a tour of its fortress, which was used to repel the German forces during WWII. Inside, a museum chronicles its history back to the 13th century. This history is further illustrated by a fascinating selection of exhibits in the Museum of History and Archaeology. Alternatively, Brest has a famous puppet theatre that is worth seeing and visitors should not miss out on the elegant design of the Belaya Vezha (White Tower), also known as the famous Kamenets Tower,  that was built in the 13th century.</p>]]><p><b>Cross-country skiing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sports enthusiasts can enjoy excellent cross-country skiing in the Raubichy Olympic Sports Complex, 22km (14 miles) from Minsk, while for lovers of mountain skiing, there are two modern resorts (Logoysk and Silichy) situated 30km (19 miles) from Minsk. Skating is also a popular activity.</p>]]><p><b>Dudutki Museum of Material Culture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Dudutki Museum of Material Culture is to be found 40km (25 miles) from the capital city and is the only private museum in Belarus showing traditional crafts and ways of life. It provides a real insight to Belarusian traditions over the years.</p>]]><p><b>Grodno</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Grodno is the fifth-largest city of Belarus. Close to both Lithuania and Poland it has for hundreds of years been a strategic border town, particularly relevant during WWII. The major sites are in the Old Town centre, where the Kalozh-Church and the Old Castle (both from the 11th century) can be found. Dotted with lavish baroque architecture – the Cathedral of St Francis Xavier is probably the highlight – Grodna is well worth a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Khatyn</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In 1943 the entire population of Khatyn village was massacred by a Nazi battalion, consisting of mostly Ukrainian collaborators. Khatyn has become a symbol of a number of mass killings that took place during the war, and the memorial now in place is a sobering yet suitable tribute to the one in four Belarusians that died in the war. Over the past fifty years visitors to the site have included Richard Nixon and Fidal Castro.</p>]]><p><b>Logoysk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The onion-shaped domes of Russian Orthodox churches dominate the landscape throughout the country, but especially around the towns of Logoysk, Krasnoe and Molodechno.</p>]]><p><b>Minsk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Minsk, the capital of Belarus, situated 340km (213 miles) northeast of Warsaw and 120km (75 miles) southeast of Vilnius, was first mentioned in 1067, but little of the old city now survives except a few 17th-century buildings. The city grew to be an important axis of communication and suffered badly during WWII. Modern Minsk is symmetrically designed with wide embankments flanking the Svisloch River.</p>]]><p><b>Minsk Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Not far from Raubichi (10km/6 miles) is the idyllic Minsk Lake, dotted with numerous islets and surrounded by dense pines. It is beautiful all year round; however it's at its best during the summer months – when it is possible to swim and partake in other water sports on the lake.</p>]]><p><b>Minsk museums</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The cultural scene in Minsk is surprisingly diverse, with the Belarusian Ballet and good museums such as the National Museum of Belarusian History and Culture, the National Arts Museum, the Museum of History of the Great Patriotic War and the Museum of Old Belarusian Culture. Other interesting museums deal with the major Belarusian writers, Kolas, Kupala, Bogdanovich and Brovka. Icons form a large part of the National Gallery. Museums generally open Tues-Sun 1000-1900.</p>]]><p><b>Mir Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>120km (75 miles) from Minsk is the small town of Mir where one can see the Jewish Cemetery and the 15th-century Mir Castle, a UNESCO World Heritage Site. Nearby, historic Nesvizh still retains its old buildings. The former residence of the Radzivill family is one of the most attractive palaces in the country. It is surrounded by a large park with numerous lakes and elaborate gardens. Only a short walk away is the imposing Catholic church designed by the 16th-century Italian architect Bernardoni.</p>]]><p><b>Museum of Folk Architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Museum of Folk Architecture is situated in Ozerto, 15km (10 miles) southwest of Minsk), and features original pieces of century-old buildings from different regions in Belarus. This huge open air museum covers some 151 hectares with exhibits from Belarus and further afield.</p>]]><p><b>Novogrudok</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belarus in the 13th century was the nucleus of the great principality of Lithuania and its capital was Novogrudok, featuring a 14th-century castle, Lida, where Adam Mitskevich, the great Belarusian poet, was born.</p>]]><p><b>Pinsk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pinsk is 300km (186 miles) south of Minsk and is the second-largest city in the Brest region. It has an abundance of historical, architectural and cultural monuments. The city and its environs are also renowned for both their natural beauty and as the centre of the Belarusian Polesye, a low-lying land of waters and mists.</p>]]><p><b>Polotsk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The centre of Christianity during the time of Rus (the first Russian state) lay in the Slavic town of Polotsk. Polotsk is the oldest of the Belarusian cities, founded in 862. An excellent example of architecture of the period is the 11th-century Church of St Sophia. Worth a visit are the two castles nearby. There is also a 12th-century convent, St Ephrosinia of Polotsk, and a 16th- to 17th-century Epiphany Monastery.</p>]]><p><b>Raubichi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>About 22km (14 miles) from the capital is the picturesque village of Raubichi, which an interesting ethnographic museum housed in a disused church. However the main draw nowadays is not the village but the Olympic standard sports complex close by. It is home to a specialized educational and sports institution where winter sports athletes are trained. It is possible to join guided tours of the complex and hotel accommodation is available in this beautiful setting.</p>]]><p><b>Troitskoye Predmestye</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For an insight into the way Minsk once looked, the suburb of Troitskoye Predmestye should not be missed. 19th century houses with colourful facades line the streets and there are plenty of excellent examples of baroque architecture, such as the Cathedral of the Holy Spirit, the Cathedral of St Peter and Paul and the Maryinsky Cathedral, which has been rebuilt to its original shape.</p>]]><p><b>Viskouli</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For tourists seeking political history, the village of Viskouli is where leaders of Belarus, Russia and the Ukraine signed the famous agreement stipulating the final disintegration of the USSR.</p>]]><p><b>Vitebsk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Vitebsk, situated 270km (169 miles) from Minsk is the birthplace of the painter Marc Chagall. There is a cultural centre named after him, and his family house has been turned into a museum. One of Belarus' oldest buildings, the Annunciation Church, can also be found here. It dates back to the 12th century.</p>]]><p><b>Zhirovichy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The village of Zhirovichy, 190km (119 miles) from Minsk, is renowned for the beautiful 15th century Monastery of the Assumption. Part of the monastery complex is a convent and a theological seminary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$62.4 billion (2012)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, mineral products, chemicals and textiles.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Energy, mineral products, metals and foodstuffs.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Russia, Netherlands, Ukraine, China, Germany.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite a paucity of natural resources, Belarus enjoyed a relatively high level of prosperity during the Soviet era compared to other ex-Soviet republics. However, the economy has slowed in recent years.<br />
<br />
The main agriculture crops are sugar beet, grain and potatoes; livestock breeding is also substantial. The manufacturing industry is focused on the production of agricultural machinery vehicles and chemicals, most of which have been exported in the past. Apart from a few oil and gas deposits, Belarus has no energy reserves and relies on imports, most of which come from the Russian Federation. <br />
<br />
Like other Soviet republics, Belarus suffered a sharp decline in output and a variety of other problems following the dissolution of the Soviet Union; this was then followed by a period of stabilisation, which took hold during the mid- 1990s as the government and people adjusted to new economic circumstances. <br />
<br />
Up until 2008 Belarus&rsquo; economic growth was relatively strong, with its GDP growing an average of 8.3% annually. Belarus&rsquo; growth was stronger than both Western Europe and Central Asia, largely a result of positive external factors such as strong export demand from neighbouring Russia, and cheap imported energy from Russia.<br />
<br />
Growth slowed after the 2008 global economic crisis and this was followed by a period of instability, with GDP dropping to 0.2% in 2009. Outside help was offered and accepted from the likes of the IMF. However Belarus&rsquo; reluctance to make practical changes as suggested by its benefactors led to a further economic crisis in 2011 and this sent inflation soaring to 109%. Average monthly salaries dropped from $530 to $330.</p>
<p>Since then, the economic situation has gradually improved and stability has been restored. Again Russia has come to the rescue with favourable energy trade agreements. However Belarus&rsquo; economy remains fragile and the situation has revealed big structural problems associated with the country&rsquo;s state-centred economic policies &ndash; which have little changed since Soviet times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For business meetings, visitors should dress smartly. English is widely used in management circles and knowledge of German might also be useful. Appointments should be made well in advance and should be confirmed nearer the time. Business cards should have a Russian translation on the back. Be mindful that business transactions can take quite a long time.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ministry of Foreign Affairs</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 220030 ,(17) 227 2922
					Website:http://www.mfa.gov.by
					Address: ,(Information on Conferences/Conventions),,]]><b>Belarusian Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 220113 ,(17) 226 0473
					Website:http://www.cci.by
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Belarusian cuisine has evolved from the days where the humble potatoes formed the basis for all dishes. However it still shares many similarities with other Eastern and Northern European countries, being closest to Lithuanian cuisine with a strong Polish influence. Meals are largely based on meat and vegetables, and gastronomy is still influenced by the countries of Soviet days past, a period which saw a number of Belarusian culinary traditions being lost. Increasingly, your average Belarussian will take a greater interest in Italian or Chinese cuisine than in their own culinary traditions.</p><p>In addition to Belarusian dishes, there is also a good selection of international and Russian specialities available. The Belarusians love their mushrooms – and mushroom-gathering is a traditional pastime. As a result mushrooms will pop up in a variety of guises on menus across the country. Most popular is Being a landlocked country, don't visit Belarus expecting a wide selection of seafood dishes. Most of the fish available, carp, hake and zander are caught in freshwater (or not so freshwater) lakes.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>• Belarusian borshch (soup made with beetroot, served hot and with sour cream). <br/>• <em>Hribnoy sup</em> (delicious mushroom and barley soup). <br/>• <em>Kotleta pokrestyansky</em> (pork smothered in a mushroom sauce).<br/>• Filet à la Minsk and Minsk cutlet.<br/>• <em>Dracheny</em> (a local tasty potato dish with mushrooms). <br/>• <em>Draniki</em> (potato pancakes served with pickled berries). <br/>• <em>Mochanka</em> (thick soup mixed with lard accompanied by hot pancakes).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Beer and vodka can be bought round the clock from all-night kiosks and food shops. Coffee is generally available with meals and in cafes, although standards vary. Some bars are open until the early hours of the morning, while some close around 2100. In the bigger cities such as Minsk it is possible to get something to eat at any time. In smaller towns be prepared for this not to be the case. N.B food quality and service in restaurants does vary greatly.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is usual. In some hotels in Minsk and other cities a 10 to 15% service charge is added to the bill. Porters expect a tip of US$1-2.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for a wild night out there are a good selection of bars, music venues and clubs in the larger cities. In Minsk, the following shine brighter than the rest: West World Club is one of the biggest, combining a disco with a casino. U Ratushi is a very popular bar and restaurant in the centre of Minsk &ndash; reserve a table as it gets very busy. Alcatraz is a popular dance club with some of the cheapest beer in town. Max Show is an old fashioned disco, in need of redecorating and likely to run out of beer half way through the night, but still good fun, and Reaktor is another big club in the city holding regular concerts. Note that whether you want it or not many venues will put on an erotic show &ndash; but usually after the kitchen has closed.</p>
<p>For something a little more sedate there is a thriving cultural scene with opera, ballet, theatre, circus and puppet theatre to be found in Minsk. Brest also has a renowned puppet theatre. Tickets can be bought in advance at underground stations or at the Central Theatre Ticket Office. Same-day tickets are only available at the venue in question.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopaholics shouldn&rsquo;t venture to Belarus in search of a fix; it is lacking in choice and many of the items that are available are hugely overpriced. That said, Belarus isn&rsquo;t the shopping desert it is often believed to be, and it does have a large selection of indigenous products that make great souvenirs.</p>
<p>Scarina Avenue is the Minsk&rsquo;s main shopping street, where it is possible to buy most of the things that would be available in their Western European equivalents. Podzemka is a bohemian fusion of art gallery and art and craft shop, and is great for souvenirs.</p>
<p>Possible souvenirs include the classic Russian Matryoska Dolls, original samovars, wooden jewellery boxes and spoons. Straw items, decorative plates and other handicraft items are also good buys. Linen items are in abundance, usually in the form of table cloths and tea towels. If nothing else stands out the chocolate made by Belarus&rsquo; two main producers Kommunarka and Spartak, will &ndash; it&rsquo;s delicious. Milavitsa products (quality women&rsquo;s underwear) which were famed throughout the ex -Soviet Union, are also available in a number of western style department stores.</p>
<p>Only Belarusian rubles are accepted, so don&rsquo;t expect to give your plastic a workout. However, nearly every shop has a currency exchange counter. Some shops are closed on Sunday, but tourist shops are usually open every day. Kiosks are still to be found on the street, where light refreshments, tobacco and souvenirs can be purchased.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-2000. In big cities shops are open daily and many open 24 hours a day. In the smaller towns and villages opening times are more random as is product choice.</p><p>Antiquities, valuables, works of art and manuscripts other than those offered for sale in souvenir shops require an export licence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belarus's hotel options are rather thin on the ground. Whilst the capital Minsk, has the lion's share of properties, and other towns such as Gomel, Brest and Vitebsk have accommodation which can cater to the business traveller (international corporate chains such as Hilton and the like), there isn't much choice between these grand business hotels and the basic accommodations available. Room rates will rarely top £100 a night, makng a stay in Belarus a relatively budget bargain, unless you choose to stay at the five star luxurious resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belarus has relatively few B&Bs, with the majority of these located in Minsk. They are less likely to be equipped with facilities, but may make a rather more entertaining stay than the beige surroundings of a corporate hotel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belarus's hotel options are rather thin on the ground. Whilst the capital Minsk, has the lion's share of properties, and other towns such as Gomel, Brest and Vitebsk have accommodation which can cater to the business traveller (international corporate chains such as Hilton and the like), there isn't much choice between these grand business hotels and the basic accommodations available. Room rates will rarely top £100 a night, makng a stay in Belarus a relatively budget bargain, unless you choose to stay at the five star luxurious resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belarus's hotel options are rather thin on the ground. Whilst the capital Minsk, has the lion's share of properties, and other towns such as Gomel, Brest and Vitebsk have accommodation which can cater to the business traveller (international corporate chains such as Hilton and the like), there isn't much choice between these grand business hotels and the basic accommodations available. Room rates will rarely top £100 a night, makng a stay in Belarus a relatively budget bargain, unless you choose to stay at the five star luxurious resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Visitors can expect to pay for prescribed medicines. Medical insurance is compulsory for all travellers to Belarus and if you buy this outside of Belarus, you will be required to prove that you are covered by showing policy documents. If you arrive without insurance, you will be required to buy state medical insurance starting from $1 per day. It is also advisable to carry an adequate supply of prescribed medicines which may be unobtainable in Belarus. Comprehensive travel insurance is advised for all nationals.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;In terms of food and drink, Belarus does not pose much in the way of risks. However, tap water should be filtered and boiled before drinking. Alternatively you may want to drink bottled water. Whilst the risk of contamination from radiation is low, certain foods should be avoided, especially dairy produce, mushrooms and fruits of the forest, as they may contain high levels of radiation as a long-term legacy of the Chernobyl disaster.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;There may be some risk of tick-borne encephalitis. Vaccination against hepatitis B and tuberculosis is sometimes advised. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay. Take care to protect yourself from the sun during Belarus' long hot summers.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Constitution Day :
							15 March </p><p>Orthodox Easter Sunday :
							08 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							09 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							03 July </p><p>Dziady (Remembrance Day) :
							02 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Belarus by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco or an assortment of these weighing up to 250g.&nbsp;<br />
&bull; 3L of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; Goods for personal use up to a value of &euro;1,500 and weighing no more than 50kg.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Weapons and ammunition of any kind, narcotics, and printed and audiovisual material banned by Belarus.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Weapons and ammunition, narcotics, raw precious metals, minerals, wild herbs, wild animals and some wild plants.</p>
<p>Items of cultural value require authorisation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belarusian rouble (BYN; symbol Br.). Notes are in denominations of Br.500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of 1 and 2 roubles and in 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 2 copecks.</p>
<p>The old Belarusian rouble (BYR) will be exchangeable until 1 January 2022.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency should only be exchanged at banks, money-changing kiosks and official bureaux de change, and all transactions must be recorded on the currency declaration form which is issued on arrival. It is wise to retain all exchange receipts. If possible, change money in US Dollars, Euros or Russian Roubles since travellers may encounter difficulties with other currencies. The US Dollar or Euros are the preferred foreign currencies. Some foreign currencies may be hard to exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major international credit and debit cards, including American Express, Cirrus, Electron, MasterCard, Maestro and Visa are accepted in some larger hotels and at foreign currency shops and restaurants.</p><p>ATMs are widespread throughout the country, located in banks, shops, supermarkets and on the street. Most will accept foreign cards, with Mastercard and Visa being the most widely accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>May be accepted at larger banks, but cash is easier to exchange. To avoid exchange rate charges, traveller's cheques should be taken in US Dollars or Euros. Note that American Express cheques are no longer accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes*</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes*</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes*</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes*</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes*</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visitors must hold a passport valid for 90 days after the date of departure from Belarus and with at least two blank pages.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas (single-, double- or multiple-entry) allow travel through Belarus for up to two days and are valid for up to a year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals of Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania and Poland: single-entry transit visa: &euro;10; double-entry transit visa: &euro;15; multiple-entry transit visa: &euro;35; single-entry short-term visa: &euro;25; double-entry short-term visa: &euro;35; multiple-entry short-term visa: &euro;60; long-term visa: &euro;60.</p>
<p>All other nationals: individual visa: &euro;60; group visa &euro;10 per person.</p>
<p>Fees are double if you choose 48-hour processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single- or double-entry short-term tourist visa: 30 days; single-, double- or multiple-entry short-term visitor visa (for visiting friends and relatives): 90 days; single-, double- or multiple-entry short-term business visa: 90 days; long-term visa: usually 90 days within a year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Contact your nearest consulate (or consular section at embassy).   If you live in a country where there is no Belarusian embassy or consulate, you can obtain a visa at Minsk National Airport, but must submit your documentation to the Foreign Admissions Division of the Consular Directorate of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs (<a href="http://www.mfa.gov.by" target="_blank">www.mfa.gov.by</a>) in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least seven days for visa processing. There is also a 48-hour express option.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You may be asked to provide proof of funds to cover your stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your stay, you should contact the local office of the Citizenship and Migration Department.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If importing animals, you must provide a veterinary inspection certificate and vaccination certificate. These should be translated into Russian or Belarusian.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[53.543008]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[28.054981]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>207,595 sq km (80,153 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>9,475,549 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>46.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Minsk.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bordered by Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, Ukraine and the Russian Federation, Belarus is a landlocked, relatively flat country, crisscrossed by thousands of streams and major rivers such as the Dnieper. Its landscape is characterised by uplands and lowlands created by glacial movements during the last Ice Age; these are also responsible for the Belarusian ridge which runs diagonally across the country. Around one third of Belarus is covered by forests, which are rich in wildlife. Straddling the border between Belarus and Poland is Białowieża Forest, one of the last stretches of Europe&rsquo;s primeval forests and home to around 800 bison. The Palyessye plain, a swampy lowland in the southwest of Belarus was severely affected by the Chernobyl disaster and much of the area is off-limits as it is now part of the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christian (majority Eastern Orthodox and Roman Catholic with minority Protestant), and some minority Jewish and Muslim communities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If meeting a stranger, shaking hands is the usual form of greeting. Hospitality is part of the tradition and people are welcoming and friendly, although Belarusians are also known for their brusqueness. If you are invited to someone's house, be sure to bring a small token as a gift. The same goes for power lunches - company gifts are well received. Avoid taking photographs of military or government installations. Take care not to use the 'thumbs up' sign to say 'OK'; in Belarus this gesture this is considered rude. You may see people spitting in public – this is acceptable in Belarus. Belarus is quite a religious and conservative society, and homosexuality, whilst not illegal is kept very low-key so as not to invite unwanted attention.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220V, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Syarhey Rumas since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Alexander Lukashenko since 1994.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The territory now known as Belarus emerged during the 9th to 12th centuries, from the all-encompassing Slavic territory known as Kievan Rus. As Kievan Rus splintered into smaller territiories, Lithuania and then Poland began to expand and acquire Belarusian lands during the 13th century. Over the next two hundred years assimilation was gradual and the Belarusians were allowed a certain amount of autonomy, maintaining their own language and keeping their Orthodox religion. However, they took on the status of serfs. It wasn&rsquo;t until 1596 that the Belarusian church was brought under the authority of the Vatican.</p>
<p>At the end of the 18th century and after numerous wars between Russia and Poland, Belarus was absorbed into Russia and a long period of Russification began. The Russians increasingly saw Belarus as a western Russian state and tried to suppress any sense of a Belarusian national identity, even banning the Belarusian language. During the 19th century the economy developed but despite industrialisation many Belarusians remained in the countryside both poor and illiterate. Their absence from positions of influence and the lengthy dominance by both the Poles and the Russians was beginning to take its toll and the emergence of a distinct Belarusian nationality took time.</p>
<p>However, the early 20th century saw a blossoming of nationalism and a brief period of independence during World War 1, but it was short-lived and the Red Army soon took control after the 1917 Russian Revolution, moving quickly to create the Belarusian Soviet Socialist Republic. The same decade saw the brutal collectivisation of agriculture, industrialisation on a grand scale and purges leading to mass killings, most notably in the Kurapaty Forest outside Minsk.</p>
<p>World War 2 saw even more suffering in Belarus as it found itself on the front line and the location for many battles. Misfortune struck again in 1986, as the Chernobyl nuclear disaster left a quarter of the country contaminated, the effects of which are still being felt to this day. Since 1994 Alexander Lukashenko has ruled Belarus with an authoritarian iron fist, earning it the dubious honour of being widely viewed as Europe&rsquo;s last dictatorship, and although not unpopular within the country, he has lead Belarus down an ever more uncertain path, ruling a country that finds itself increasingly isolated. However, in 2000 Belarus and Russia signed a treaty for greater co-operation.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p> The national dish is draniki, potato pancakes made with flour and egg, topped with savoury or sweet condiments.</p>
<p> With a population of 9.49 million, it is reckoned there are 8.639 million mobile phones in Belarus, 3.718 phone landlines and 3.107 internet users.</p>
<p> Pioneering modernist artist Marc Chagall was born in Belarus in 1887.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Belarus in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 986 1606.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://usa.mfa.gov.by/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 986 1606.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1230.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Belarus in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7938 3677.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://uk.mfa.gov.by/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7938 3677.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon, Tues, Thurs and Fri 0930-1230.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>6 Kensington Court<br/>London<br/>W8 5DL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A land of rusty tractors and tacky fashion; a Soviet state in all but name; Europe&rsquo;s last dictatorship: suffice to say Belarus has something of an image problem.</p>
<p>Though these lazy stereotypes carry some semblance of truth, Belarus is a largely misunderstood country that&rsquo;s had a bit of a raw deal of it in western media.&nbsp;Consequently, those who visit are often surprised to discover a multifaceted destination rich in history, brimming with culture and populated by warm and generous inhabitants, who are gradually pulling themselves from the shadows of their past.</p>
<p>The truth is that Belarus&rsquo; appeal might well be in its isolation. Indeed this is a destination where you can still see what life was like during the days of communism, with an abundance of Soviet iconography, especially in the big cities, allowing anyone with an imagination to visualise how things once were.</p>
<p>In the capital Minsk, with its clean streets and neoclassical Stalinist architecture, a cosmopolitan vibe sits alongside an intense national pride. And well it might &ndash; the Belarusian capital is a survivor, having time and time again, throughout its tumultuous history, refused to say &lsquo;die.&rsquo;</p>
<p>Brest is another city of interest. Nestling on the border with Poland, it is possessed of charm and history in equal measure, and probably the most Western of the Belarusian cities.</p>
<p>Beyond the urban environment travellers will discover wide plains, picturesque villages, ancient castles, monasteries and dense forests, not to mention thousands of lakes. National parks protect some of Europe&rsquo;s oldest untouched woodlands, and some of the continent&rsquo;s largest marshlands. The countryside also offers the chance to see some of the last remaining collective farms in action.</p>
<p>There is no escaping the fact that Belarus is a developing Eastern European country with a somewhat shady past, but for travellers who give this destination the time it deserves, there are a plenty of rewards to be had.</p><p>A land of rusty tractors and tacky fashion; a Soviet state in all but name; Europe&rsquo;s last dictatorship: suffice to say Belarus has something of an image problem.</p>
<p>Though these lazy stereotypes carry some semblance of truth, Belarus is a largely misunderstood country that&rsquo;s had a bit of a raw deal of it in western media.&nbsp;Consequently, those who visit are often surprised to discover a multifaceted destination rich in history, brimming with culture and populated by warm and generous inhabitants, who are gradually pulling themselves from the shadows of their past.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
