<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Belgium" ColCode="bel" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="be" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Belgium]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belgium experiences similar weather to the south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iunited-kingdom/england">England</a> and is best visited in spring and summer, when the days are warmer and the locals are enjoying drinks on the outdoor terraces, and in December when the Christmas markets line the cobblestones. Summer days are long with it often staying light until 2230 and temperatures reaching 25-30&deg;C (77-86&deg;F), intermingled with occasional drizzly days. Heat waves are becoming more frequent in mid-August, so be sure to drink enough water. Winter days are short, with darkness falling around 1700. Winds blowing from the North Pole can be biting, especially on the coast, and can push the temperature down to -5&deg;C (23&deg;F); snow is fairly common in January.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rainfall is common throughout the year so bring a waterproof jacket with a hood, so you don&rsquo;t have to bother with an unwieldy umbrella. Otherwise, pack light clothing, sunscreen, sunglasses and a hat for summer and lots of layers, a hat, scarf and gloves for the winter months. Sturdy walking shoes are best for tackling the cobblestones found in many of the city centres. If you plan to take part in any activities, or rent bikes, be sure to bring a helmet and any specialist sports clothing with you.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As Belgium is such a small country, there are no internal flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belgium's waterways offer a pleasant way to enjoy the country, whether it be on a one-hour canal cruise or an extended voyage between major cities. Numerous operators offer everything from boat hire to luxury cruises - details are available from relevant tourist offices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national Belgian rail network NMBS/SNCB (tel: +32 2 528 2828; <a href="http://www.belgianrail.be" target="_blank">www.belgianrail.be</a>) operates a comprehensive railway network with regular trains on most lines. There are more frequent trains on the main lines.<br />
<br />
<strong>Fares:</strong> First- and second-class, single and return tickets are available. However, a return ticket is double the single fare and is only valid on the day of issue. Children under 12 travel free in second class (restrictions apply).&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Discount travel:</strong> Weekend return fares are available from Friday (after 1900) to Sunday for the outward journey and on Saturday and Sunday for the return journey, giving a 50% reduction. Go Pass 10 offers preferential tariffs for 10 second-class trips within one year to people under 26. The Rail Pass offers preferential tariffs for 10 second-class trips within one year to people over 26. People aged 65 and over benefit from special tariffs. All are available from NMBS/SNCB.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The InterRail One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Belgium. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar (<a href="http://www.eurostar.com" target="_blank">www.eurostar.com</a>) and some ferry routes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belgium has a first-rate highway system linking all the main cities and towns. Queues are uncommon except around Brussels&rsquo; outer ring road during rush hour and the road to the coast during summer.</p>r<p>Thanks to the high taxes, Belgian roads are pothole free and well lit.</p><p>Plentiful in all towns. The tip is included in the final meter price. If there are no taxi stands, you can phone taxi companies for a small extra charge.</p><p>For non-EU nationals, an international driving licence is recommended. Although it's not compulsory, EU nationals taking their own cars to Belgium are advised to take a Green Card.</p><p>The national speed limit is 120kph (75mph) on motorways, 90kph (56mph) on single lane roads and 50kph (31mph) in town. It is compulsory for seat belts to be worn in the front and back of vehicles. Children under 12 are not permitted to travel in the front seat of a car.</p>
<p>A warning triangle must be displayed at the scene of a breakdown or accident. It is compulsory to carry a fire extinguisher, a reflective vest and a first aid kit in all vehicles. Trams always have priority on roads.</p><p>Royal Automobile Club of Belgium (tel: +32 2 287 0911; <a href="http://www.racb.com" target="_blank">www.racb.com</a>).</p><p>Both self-drive and chauffeur-driven cars are available. All the major car hire companies are present in Belgium.</p><p>Bike hire is quick and easy. Many outlets are located near train stations and Brussels has a 24-hour city bike-rental scheme, Villo!, with docking stations dotted all over the city centre.</p><p>The national speed limit is 120kph (75mph) on motorways, 90kph (56mph) on single lane roads and 50kph (31mph) in town. It is compulsory for seat belts to be worn in the front and back of vehicles. Children under 12 are not permitted to travel in the front seat of a car.</p>
<p>A warning triangle must be displayed at the scene of a breakdown or accident. It is compulsory to carry a fire extinguisher, a reflective vest and a first aid kit in all vehicles. Trams always have priority on roads.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good public transport system in all the major towns and cities, with underground, tram and bus services in Antwerp and Brussels, bus and tramways in Charleroi, Ghent and Ostend and bus systems elsewhere.</p>
<p>The public bus system is run by De Lijn (<a href="http://www.delijn.be" target="_blank">www.delijn.be</a>) in Flanders, TEC (<a href="http://www.infotec.be" target="_blank">www.infotec.be</a>) in Wallonia and STIB (<a href="http://www.stib-mivb.be" target="_blank">www.stib-mivb.be</a>) in Brussels. There is a standard flat-fare system, with discounts for five- and 10-journey multi-ride tickets. One-day tickets and multi-mode tourist travelcards are also available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Belgium</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">liegravege</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.22</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Belgium</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ghent</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.28</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Belgium</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bruges</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.53</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Belgium</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">antwerp</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.41</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If flying from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, Brussels Airlines (<a href="http://www.brusselsairlines.com/" target="_blank">www.brusselsairlines.com</a>), British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com/" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>)&nbsp;are the main operators, while travellers coming from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-of-america">US</a> can book direct flights to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brussels">Brussels</a> with American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com/" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>), Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com/" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>). Flights to Belgium don&rsquo;t vary considerably in price throughout the year; the cheapest tickets are those bought in advance.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belgium/antwerp-international-airport">Antwerp International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belgium/brussels-airport">Brussels Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Brussels: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>&nbsp;- 1 hour 10 minutes;&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;7 hours 25 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Brussels Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.brusselsairport.be<p>Brussels Airport is located 12km (7.5 miles) northeast of central Brussels.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+32 2 753 7753</p>]]><b>Brussels South Charleroi Airport </b><![CDATA[http://www.brusselsairport.be/en/<p>The airport  is 5km (3 miles) from Charleroi and 46km (29 miles) from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belgium/brussels-airport">Brussels</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eurostar (tel: 03432 186 186, in the UK only or +44 1233 617 575; <a href="http://www.eurostar.com/" target="_blank">www.eurostar.com</a>) operates direct high-speed trains from London St Pancras (via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lille">Lille</a>) to Bruxelles-Midi/Brussel-Zuid (journey time - 2 hours).</p>
<p>Eurotunnel (tel: +44 8443 353 535; <a href="http://www.eurotunnel.com/" target="_blank">www.eurotunnel.com</a>) runs shuttle trains for cars, bicycles, motorcycles, coaches, minibuses, caravans and campervans between Folkestone in Kent, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, and Calais, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>. It runs 24 hours a day, with up to four departures an hour and the journey takes 35 minutes. Fares are charged according to length of stay and time of year and whether or not you have a reservation. Overnight journeys are cheapest.</p>
<p>Thalys (tel: +49 18 070 707; <a href="http://www.thayls.com/" target="_blank">www.thalys.com</a>) has numerous daily departures from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a> to Bruxelles-Midi/Brussel-Zuid as well as from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cologne">Cologne</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amsterdam">Amsterdam</a>.</p>
<p>NMBS/SNCB (tel: +32 2 528 2828; <a href="http://www.b-rail.be/" target="_blank">www.belgianrail.be</a>), Belgium&rsquo;s national rail service, operates frequent trains to destinations all over Europe, with hourly departures to Luxembourg and Lille.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EU residents can purchase an InterRail (<a href="http://www.interrail.eu/" target="_blank">www.interrail.eu</a>) Pass. There are two types to choose from: the One Country Pass has a Benelux option allowing unlimited travel within and between Belgium, Luxembourg and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/netherlands">Netherlands</a> for a period of three to eight days in a month; while the Global Pass is valid for train travel in up to 29 European countries for five days within 10 days, 10 days within 22 days, or 15 days continuous, 22 days continuous and one month continuous.</p>
<p>Non-European residents need to buy a Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com/" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>) Pass instead. It offers broadly the same freedoms as the InterRail passes, and tickets are valid for five to 10 days of travel within two months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If driving to Belgium from the UK, you need to catch a ferry landing at either Calais or Dunkerque, and then follow the E40 east. The drive takes about two hours.</p>
<p>Travellers coming from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> should follow either the E19 or E42, while visitors coming from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a> should follow the E40 west.</p>
<p>Eurolines (tel: +44 8717 818 178, in the UK; <a href="http://www.eurolines.co.uk/" target="_blank">www.eurolines.co.uk</a>) offers daily bus departures from London Victoria station to Brussels, Ghent, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bruges">Bruges</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/antwerp">Antwerp</a>. The journey takes 6 to 7 hours via the Channel Tunnel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Belgium&rsquo;s international dialling code is 0032. For directory enquiries, dial 1405 (English). There are call boxes in all major towns and country districts, and telecards are available from newsagents, supermarkets, railway stations and post offices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. The main networks are Proximus, Base and Orange Belgium (formerly Mobistar). Coverage is excellent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is widely available and often free in hotels and caf&eacute;s. Designated internet caf&eacute;s are becoming hard to find, although fast food outlets such as McDonalds do offer free Wi-Fi in the cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As a result of its political and linguistic divide, Belgium has two separate public broadcasting organisations: the Dutch-speaking VRT and French-speaking RTBF, each with its own regulations. Cable services, such as Telenet and Belgacom, offer dozens of domestic and foreign channels, including BBC and BBC2. The Bulletin and Agenda are English-language magazines published weekly in Brussels. <em>New Europe</em> and <em>European Voice</em> are English-language papers focusing on EU news. Films are shown in English (marked OV) with Dutch and French subtitles, as well as dubbed French (marked as VF). Country-wide cinema listings can be found at <a href="http://www.cinenews.be/">www.cinenews.be</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belgium&rsquo;s national postal service, bpost (www.bpost.be) became public in June 2013. Airmail takes two to three days to reach other west European destinations. Stamps can be bought at post offices, supermarkets, hotels, campsites, service stations and souvenir shops.</p><p>Hours can vary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Central Square (Grand' Place)</p><![CDATA[<p>The Grand' Place has been at the heart of Brussels' life since the 11th century. Almost totally destroyed by the French bombardment ordered by Louis XIV in 1695, it was later rebuilt in its original architectural style by various workers' guilds. The splendid neo-Gothic and Baroque houses that surround the cobbled square once housed the headquarters of corporations of artists, merchants and tailors; the City of Brussels Museum in the former Maison du Roi (King's Residence) allows visitors to explore the city's illustrious trading history. Other buildings in the Grand' Place which provide insights into Brussels' traditions are the Town Hall, the Museum of Cocoa and Chocolate and the Museum of Brewing.</p>]]><br/><p>In Flanders Fields Museum</p><![CDATA[<p>Some of the most important &minus; and most tragic &minus; conflicts of WWI took place in Belgium. Half a million soldiers lost their lives on the battlefields and in the trenches along the Western Front. There are numerous military cemeteries and memorials in the region commemorating those, of all nationalities, who fell in battle. Almost all can be visited, and although it&rsquo;s possible to see them independently, a booked tour with a qualified history guide is much more rewarding. The historical centre for this region is Ypres, the last major town to remain under Allied control. Its main sites are the Menin Gate and the dynamic In Flanders Fields Museum, where visitors can discover personal mementoes of soldiers, and learn about major events and aspects of the war such as the first gas attack, the Christmas Truce of 1914, and No Man's Land.</p>]]><br/><p>Royal Museums of Fine Arts of Belgium</p><![CDATA[<p>Renovated and reworked into three distinct eras - the Mus&eacute;e Old Masters, Mus&eacute;e Modern, and Mus&eacute;e Fin-de-Si&egrave;cle - Brussels&rsquo; world-famous Mus&eacute;es Royaux des Beaux-Arts spans over five centuries and showcases the work of some of the greatest names in art history, from the Flemish Primitives through to Rubens and Delvaux. It&rsquo;s impossible not to be impressed. And if you haven&rsquo;t had your fill after all that, the unique Mus&eacute;e Magritte is located next door.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Antwerp</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Flanders' 'second capital' is the most dynamic of the northern cities. Famed for its diamond processing, the city is also home to the second-largest harbour in Europe and exposure to numerous nationalities has made it cultured and open-minded. Visit one of the world's oldest zoos, a one-of-a-kind collection of Antwerp-resident Peter Paul Rubens' masterpiece paintings, and shop 'til you drop along the Meir.</p>]]><p><b>Battle of the Bulge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the deadliest surprise attacks launched by German forces against Allied troops during WW II, the Battle of the Bulge took place close to the Luxembourg border and is a key site of remembrance. The nearby Bastogne Historical Centre has a strong collection of memorabilia.</p>]]><p><b>Brussels</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belgium&rsquo;s capital is compact, but boasts myriad personalities thanks to its hotch-potch mix Eurocrats, locals and immigrant Congolese, Turkish and Moroccan neighbourhoods. From the UNESCO-listed Grand&rsquo; Place and cheeky Mannaken- Pis peeing statue, to the gleaming EU buildings and hip Ixelles district there&rsquo;s always plenty to explore. Keep and eye out for Belgium&rsquo;s famous <em>begijnhofs</em> &minus; pious communities founded in the 13th century as sanctuaries for the many women left widowed by the Crusades.</p>]]><p><b>Castles in Wallonia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It's said that Belgium has a higher density of castles per square mile than anywhere else. The castles themselves, which range from manor houses to mighty fortresses, are found across the entire country, but it's in Wallonia that the most attractive constructions are found.</p>]]><p><b>Eat moules frites</b></p><![CDATA[<p>No trip to Belgium would be complete without sampling moules frites (mussels with chips/ French fries). A summer speciality, often served with a light mustard dipping sauce, these plump seashells are best when washed down with a refreshing white beer such as Hoegaarden.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy the original Spa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Wallonian town of Spa is the place from which all spas take their name and, as such, makes for an essential stop-off for those who enjoy a spot of pampering. The modern hilltop spa (<a href="http://www.thermesdespa.com" target="_blank">www.thermesdespa.com</a>) offers a range of different treatments, while the 19th-century-style town is attractive in its own right.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Bruges’ canals</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As the best-preserved medieval city in Europe, UNESCO-listed Bruges is a must-see. Early traders weaved their way through its many canals and it's still the best way to see the city and its legendary historical sights. Numerous canal-boat operators line the banks.</p>]]><p><b>Get lacy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belgian lace is one of the country's most famous products, with its production dating back to the Renaissance. Bruges and Brussels have a handful of shops selling high quality and antique lace, while the Kantcentrum (<a href="http://www.kantcentrum.eu" target="_blank">www.kantcentrum.eu</a>) in Bruges gives regular demonstrations.</p>]]><p><b>Ghent</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Billed as &lsquo;Bruges without the tourists,&rsquo; Ghent boasts almost as many waterways and historic buildings, as well as the &lsquo;buzz&rsquo; provided by its university students. Must-sees are the 15th-century painting <em>The Adoration of the Mystic Lamb</em> in Sint-Baafskathedraal, the Graslei canal, and the foreboding city-centre medieval Gravensteen castle.</p>]]><p><b>Have a few beers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belgium's brewing history reaches back to the Middle Ages, so it would be downright rude not to sample some of its famous ales. There are still well over 100 breweries in the country, producing everything from pale lager to hefty Trappist ales. Bartenders are always happy to talk you through the 800-plus options!</p>]]><p><b>Indulge in chocolate</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visitors with a sweet tooth will already be well aware of Belgium's lip-smacking prowess when it comes to chocolate. Famed for their freshness, you can pick up affordable boxes from the likes of Leonidas and Neuhaus, or splash out of boutique chocolatier Pierre Marcolini. Brussels (<a href="http://www.mucc.be" target="_blank">www.mucc.be</a>) and Bruges (<a href="http://www.choco-story.be" target="_blank">www.choco-story.be</a>) both have chocolate museums.</p>]]><p><b>Join the carnival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belgium has a colourful annual roster of festivals and celebrations, from the UNESCO-listed Binche carnival (<a href="http://www.carnavaldebinche.be" target="_blank">www.carnavaldebinche.be</a>) in Wallonia and Bruges&rsquo; Heilig-Bloedprocessie (<a href="http://www.holyblood.com" target="_blank">www.holyblood.com</a>) in Flanders, to Brussels&rsquo; 500-year-old Ommegang pageant (<a href="http://www.ommegang.be" target="_blank">www.ommegang.be</a>).</p>]]><p><b>La Roche-en-Ardenne</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take to the rivers on kayak, try spelunking, or enjoy a gentle cycle amid the hills of the Ardenne's best base for outdoor activities. An idyllic spot ideal for young families.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about diamonds</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Antwerp has long enjoyed a sparkling reputation as the world's diamond centre, and visitors can discover the city's prominence at the Diamant Museum (<a href="http://www.diamantmuseum.be" target="_blank">www.diamantmuseum.be</a>). The venue features gem cutters and polishers at work, as well as outlining 400 years of history.</p>]]><p><b>Liège</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Built on the back of the steel industry, Liège's charm is perhaps better hidden than other Belgian towns. Those that dig a little deeper, will come across some charming historic quarters and heritage buildings. It has a bohemian spirit and a strong association with folklore - look out for the mischievous character of Tchantchès in the Outremeuse district. Great as a day-trip from Brussels.</p>]]><p><b>Ostend</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once the playground of European aristocracy, the city, beaches and promenade of Ostend possess a faded elegance of days gone by. Visit the restored Mercator Navy ship and dine on fresh shrimp at the daily fish markets.</p>]]><p><b>Take in a museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From Brussels&rsquo; Mus&eacute;es Royaux des Beaux-Arts &minus; the best-stocked art gallery in Europe &minus; to the hyper-modern Mus&eacute;e Herg&eacute; celebrating all things <em>Tintin</em> in Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium is brimming with first-rate museums.</p>]]><p><b>Waterloo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In June 1815, in a muddy field 18km (11 miles) south of Brussels, French Emperor Napoleon went head to head with England's Duke of Wellington and lost. Known as the Battle of Waterloo, this pivotal fight ended 22 years of war and brought peace to Europe. Visits to the historic site are possible, with trains travelling out from Bruxelles-Midi/Brussel-Zuid. Car hire is also popular.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$466.4 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, chemicals, finished diamonds, metal, and food.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, oil, food, chemicals, vehicles, metals, raw diamonds.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Main trade partners: Germany, The Netherlands and&nbsp;France.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The economies of Belgium and Luxembourg have been unified since 1921, when the two governments signed a Convention of Economic Union; this is distinct from the Benelux Union (which includes The Netherlands) and the EU (Belgium being a founder member of both). <br />
<br />
For its size, Belgium is one of the most heavily industrialised countries in Europe, but here like elsewhere, the scale of the worldwide banking crisis had a profound effect. GDP growth was negative in 2009.<br />
<br />
Belgium still imports huge quantities of raw materials, largely to be reworked for export, and manufactured goods and machinery remain a vital part of the economy. Exports are equivalent to roughly two-thirds of gross national product. <br />
<br />
Coal mining, previously a major industry, ceased when the last mine was closed in 1992. Nuclear power accounts for almost two-thirds of Belgium's energy consumption; the remainder is generated from imported fuel products.<br />
There is an extensive range of meeting venues throughout the country. In 2016, Belgium occupied 18th place in the International Congress and Convention Association rankings for numbers of association meetings staged worldwide, while Brussels was 23rd most popular city for such gatherings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A certain degree of business formality is expected in Belgium. It is wise for business visitors to confirm meetings in writing and arrive punctually, armed with business cards and wearing a suit - with a tie for men. Companies are hierarchical, and as many managing directors do not delegate, it is advisable to go straight to the top.</p>
<p>On introduction, you should address colleagues with their surname, respecting any professional or academic qualifications. Language can be tricky: judge carefully whether to use Dutch or French. If you&rsquo;re unsure, it&rsquo;s best to speak English. Personal relationships are important, so relaxed lunch meetings help develop trust - a stage that must be reached before decisions are made. It is common for business colleagues to be invited for an ap&eacute;ritif, followed by dinner at a nice restaurant, although usually not at the first meeting.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Flanders-Brussels Convention Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (02) 504 0435
					Website:http://www.meetingpoint.be/
					Address: ,Grasmarkt 61,B- Brussels,1000]]><b>Brussels Enterprises Commerce and Industry (BECI)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (02) 648 5002
					Website:http://www.500.be/
					Address: ,Avenue Louise 500,B- Brussels,1050]]><b>Belgian-Luxembourg Chamber of Commerce in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 020 7127 4292
					Website:http://www.blcc.co.uk/
					Address: Annie Med Lane HU15 2HG,Westwood House,UK,]]><b>Belgian Foreign Trade Agency</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (02) 206 3511
					Website:http://www.abh-ace.org/
					Address: ,Rue Montoyer 3,B- Brussels,1000]]><b>Belgian-American Chamber of Commerce (BACC) in the USA</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (212) 541 0779
					Website:http://www.belcham.org/
					Address: 8th Floor,c/o KBC Bank 1177 Avenue of the Americas,New York,1003]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Often quoted as having the best cuisine in Europe, Belgium&rsquo;s foodie specialities extend far beyond just waffles, beer and chocolate. For such a small country, it has rich local resources with fish and mussels being harvested from its North Sea coastline; pheasant, rabbit, and venison from the forested hills of the Ardennes; and first-class beef and lamb from the fertile Flemish polders. Butter, cream, beer and wine are used liberally and feature regularly in the cooking. Restaurants run the full gamut: from Michelin-starred to the humble <em>fritkot</em> (chip) stand. Gastronomes won&rsquo;t be disappointed!</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Moules frites: mussels and chips/French fries. <br />
&bull;	<em>Stoemp:&nbsp;</em>mashed potato with leeks and carrots.  <br />
&bull;	<em>Witloof en oven:&nbsp;</em>endives wrapped in ham and covered in cheese sauce. <br />
&bull;	<em>Waterzooi:&nbsp;</em>a fish/chicken and vegetable broth.  <br />
&bull;	<em>Paling in &lsquo;t groen:&nbsp;</em>young eel cooked in a sauce of spinach, thyme, tarragon, sorrel, mint and white wine.  <br />
&bull;	<em>Filet am&eacute;ricain:&nbsp;</em>raw mincemeat mixed with egg, onion and capers. <br />
&bull;	<em>Lapin aux pruneaux:&nbsp;</em>rabbit cooked with prunes and beer. <br />
&bull;	<em>Faison &agrave; la braban&ccedil;onne:&nbsp;</em>pheasant cooked in butter with brussel sprouts and chicory.  <br />
&bull;	<em>Salade li&eacute;geoise:&nbsp;</em>salad containing boiled potatoes, bacon bits and green beans.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Belgians love their meat and vegetarian options can be harder to find in smaller towns, so it&rsquo;s advisable to stock up at the supermarket. Look out for restaurants offering a lunchtime special, known as <em>dagschotel </em>in Flanders and <em>plat du jour</em> in Wallonia, they offer great value for money.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A service charge of 10-15% is usually included in hotel or restaurant bills, although an additional tip may be left at the discretion of the individual. Cloakroom attendants and porters may expect a tip per item of luggage.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>16 for beer and wine, 18 for spirits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belgium&rsquo;s main cities &minus; Brussels, Bruges, Ghent, Antwerp and Li&egrave;ge &minus; offer a broad array of cultural pursuits, from international and local theatre and famous opera, to cosy &lsquo;brown&rsquo; caf&eacute;s, chic cocktail bars and inventive nightclubs. Things can be a little quieter outside the main towns, but you&rsquo;ll always be able to find a port in the storm offering good beer and a warm welcome.</p>
<p>Brussels is a hot spot for jazz bars, try L'Archiduc (<a href="http://www.archiduc.net/" target="_blank">www.archiduc.net</a>), and its Art Nouveau BOZAR (<a href="http://www.bozar.be/" target="_blank">www.bozar.be</a>) theatre complex and historical Th&eacute;&acirc;tre de la Monnaie (<a href="http://www.lamonnaie.be/" target="_blank">www.lamonnaie.be</a>) opera house shouldn&rsquo;t be missed. Performances are available in Dutch, French and some English. In addition, the city has enough bars &minus; cool or cosy &minus; to allow you to drink in a different establishment every night for a year. Everything falls within the city centre and is within easy walking distance.</p>
<p>Ghent and Bruges are better-known for their historical drinking dens, with one or two nightclub options. Antwerp, on the other hand, has a lively club scene, including Belgium&rsquo;s biggest nightclub Noxx (<a href="http://www.noxxantwerp.com" target="_blank">www.noxxantwerp.com</a>), smarter cocktail bars and a handful of jazz dens too. Night-time revelry in Li&egrave;ge centres around the pedestrianised Le Carr&eacute; district, which has numerous bars studded between the boutique shops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopping in Belgium is a joy: from discount diamonds and forward-thinking fashion in Antwerp to antiques from Tongeren and perfumes forged in the vaults of Namur castle. Standard souvenirs are lace, chocolate and beer, but if you&rsquo;re after something more original you could buy a cheeky bottle of <em>jenever</em> from Hasselt, artisan chocolate-dipped moon-shaped <em>halve maantje</em> biscuits from Diest, or a comic book (<em>bandes dessin&eacute;e</em>) by a home-grown cartoon artist from Brussels.</p>
<p>Fashion lovers, both designer and vintage, should make Brussels and Antwerp a priority; beers are best bought from regional breweries, such as Cantillon in Brussels, rather than tourist shops; and chocolate lovers should find plenty of boutique shops in Bruges and Brussels.</p>
<p>Brussels&rsquo; most elegant shopping arcades are the 19th-century glass-vaulted Galeries Royales St-Hubert, Galerie Bortier and Passage du Nord, while high-street fashion shops congregate along Rue Neuve and designer labels can be found lining Avenue Louise. Antiques lovers will find pricey articles on show around the Sablon and cheaper items in the Marolles district.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Antwerp&rsquo;s haute-couture fashion shops centre around Nationaalstraat and Lombardenvest; the high street stores line Meir, which is the arterial street linking the train station and the old city centre. If you&rsquo;re shopping for diamonds, the Jewish district surrounding the station has wall-to-wall dealers.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Markets abound in Belgium, with most taking place in central squares at the weekend between 0700 and 1300. Perhaps the most famous are Brussels&rsquo; March&eacute; aux Puces flea market held on Place du Jeu de Balle (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.marcheauxpuces.org/">www.marcheauxpuces.be</a>) and the sprawling March&eacute; du Midi food market held on Boulevard de l&rsquo;Europe between 0700 and 1300 on Sunday.</p><p>Mon-Sat 1000-1800/1900. Department stores often remain open longer, up to 2100 on Friday. Outside main areas, some shops may close at lunchtime.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Belgium range from luxury 5-star options to privately owned pensions &minus; all of them usually equipped to a high-standard.&nbsp;The narrow medieval street layouts in cities such as Bruges and Ghent have prevented international chain hotels like Radisson and Best Western squeezing in, but they can still be found on the city outskirts. Those in Brussels often offer attractive weekend rates when businesspeople and Eurocrats depart for home. City tax (usually just a euro or so) can be charged as an extra in some establishments. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belgium is particularly strong on quality B&amp;Bs and they offer great value for money. Owners go to a great deal of trouble to make you as welcome as possible from elegant rooms with top-quality fixtures to home-cooked, organic breakfasts. Ghent in particular offers a huge variety. Special rates are often offered to guests staying two or more nights. Local tourist offices can arrange bookings free of charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Belgium range from luxury 5-star options to privately owned pensions &minus; all of them usually equipped to a high-standard.&nbsp;The narrow medieval street layouts in cities such as Bruges and Ghent have prevented international chain hotels like Radisson and Best Western squeezing in, but they can still be found on the city outskirts. Those in Brussels often offer attractive weekend rates when businesspeople and Eurocrats depart for home. City tax (usually just a euro or so) can be charged as an extra in some establishments. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Belgium range from luxury 5-star options to privately owned pensions &minus; all of them usually equipped to a high-standard.&nbsp;The narrow medieval street layouts in cities such as Bruges and Ghent have prevented international chain hotels like Radisson and Best Western squeezing in, but they can still be found on the city outskirts. Those in Brussels often offer attractive weekend rates when businesspeople and Eurocrats depart for home. City tax (usually just a euro or so) can be charged as an extra in some establishments. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;In the event of a medical emergency dial 100. If you are an EU resident and take ill or are involved in an accident during your visit, show your European Health Insurance Card (EHIC) &amp;minus; which should be obtained from your health insurance provider before leaving the UK &amp;minus; to qualify for free or reduced-cost treatment. Travellers from other countries should find out if they are covered by other reciprocal arrangements. Australia, for example, has such an agreement as long as long as citizens carry their Medicare card.&amp;nbsp;Comprehensive health insurance is advised for all other nationals. Belgian hospitals are of the highest standard, while staff at local pharmacies are trained to be able to advise on minor complaints. Pharmacies are recognisable in towns and villages by a green-cross sign outside the door &amp;ndash; the sign flashes when the pharmacy is open.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Restaurants and caf&amp;eacute;s adhere to the highest standards of food preparation &amp;minus; even the famous &lt;em&gt;fritkot&lt;/em&gt; chip stands are well maintained. The tap water is potable, but locals do prefer to buy Spa &amp;minus; the local bottled variety available in still and sparkling. Eating mussels is often a concern for travellers, but it&amp;rsquo;s very rare to contract food poisoning or stomach complaints after eating a pot.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;If walking in long grass check yourself for ticks afterwards; they may carry Lyme disease which manifests as a rash, fever, headache and painful muscles. If you think you&amp;rsquo;ve been bitten, seek medical advice immediately.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re cycling long distances, or hiking in the Ardennes, in warm weather, it&amp;rsquo;s advisable to drink &amp;ndash; and carry &amp;ndash; plenty of water and wear appropriate clothing. Blisters can be another problem for hikers. These can often occur if new walking shoes are being worn across a long distance. Ideally footwear should be worn in before the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re spending time on the coast in summer, be sensible about how long you spend in direct sunlight. It&amp;rsquo;s often windy along the long stretches of beach and the breeze can sometimes mask high temperatures. The usual precautions apply: use a generous amount of sunscreen and wear a hat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been incidences of pick-pocketing in large markets, and around Bruxelles-Midi/Brussel-Zuid train station, as well as the European Union district. In these areas, keep your handbag zipped up, a wallet in a jacket pocket rather than your back pocket, and only take small amounts of cash with you.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Flemish Community Holiday :
							11 July </p><p>Independence Day :
							21 July </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>French Community Holiday :
							27 September </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Armistice Day :
							11 November </p><p>German Community Holiday :
							15 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belgium is within the European Union.  If you are travelling from the <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/united-kingdom/">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22%, 20L of  alcoholic beverages less than 22%, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be  imported into Belgium by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring  customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% or 2L of alcoholic  beverages less than 22%.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of  &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers (reduced to &euro;175 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Restricted imports include firearms, narcotics, plants, animals and their products. Endangered species must be accompanied by a CITES permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belgium switched from the Belgian Franc to the Euro (EUR; symbol &euro;) in 2002. Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;2, 1 and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency exchange can be made in most banks and post offices as well as in some train stations, airports and exchange offices near major tourist sites.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted in the major cities and towns; take cash for smaller villages. Be aware that some petrol stations and local shops only accept a nationwide payment system known as Bancontact or Proton. In these incidences you&rsquo;ll have to use cash or, alternatively, you can buy pre-loaded Bancontact cards from the post office.</p><p>Cashpoints compatible with international banking networks are located in all towns and cities, as well as airports, major train stations and other spots. They usually offer an attractive exchange rate, although be aware that most banks charge a fee for withdrawals made abroad.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers&rsquo; cheques are no longer widely accepted; it&rsquo;s quicker and easier to withdraw cash from an ATM.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1600, Sat 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If visas are needed, a form must be filled out for each individual applicant, including children under 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belgium is a signatory to the 1995 Schengen Agreement.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: &euro;60/&pound;54; short-stay Schengen visa: &euro;60/&pound;54; long-stay visa: &euro;180/&pound;162. Certain long-stay visas require an additional payment; check with the consulate, as this varies from case to case.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay/Schengen visas are valid for up to 90 days. For visits of longer than 90 days, a long-stay visa or residence permit is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate or consular section at the embassy. In the UK, applicants need to apply in person through a VFS Global Visa Application Centre (<a href="http://www.vfs-be-uk.com">www.vfs-be-uk.com</a>), which charges an additional service fee of &pound;24. All applicants aged 12 and over must attend an appointment to submit biometric data.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EU nationals planning to stay longer than 90 days need to apply for a residence permit at the local town hall within eight days of arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three weeks for visa processing. Most applications are completed within 15 days, but applications for some nationalities may take up to several weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If applying for a visa, you&rsquo;ll be asked to detail how you intend to support yourself for the duration of your stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You should address applications for visa extensions to the Immigration Office (<a href="http://dofi.ibz.be">http://dofi.ibz.be</a>). Schengen visa extensions are only granted in exceptional circumstances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets travelling within the EU are permitted if they are accompanied by an up-to-date veterinary certificate, are fitted with a pet microchip and have proof of rabies vaccination.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[50.648970]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[4.641956]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>30,528 sq km (11,787 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>11,267,910 (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>363 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brussels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy. Federal state comprising three autonomous regions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belgium is situated in northwestern Europe, bordered by France to the south, Germany to the east,Luxembourg to the southeast and the Netherlands to the north. There is 60km (37 miles) of North Sea coastline to the northwest. The country is divided into three regions: southern French-speaking Wallonia, northern Dutch-speaking Flanders and Brussels nestled between the two. Both Flanders and Wallonia are then subdivided into ten provinces: within Flanders they are West Flanders, East Flanders, Flemish Brabant, Antwerp and Limburg; within Wallonia they are Hainaut, Walloon Brabant, Namur, Li&egrave;ge and Luxembourg (not to be confused with the neighbouring country of Luxembourg).</p>
<p>Flanders&rsquo; landscape is characterised by low-lying polders near the coast, changing to rolling hills and fertile farming grounds in the Flemish Brabant and finishing with the wooded Hoge Kempen &minus; Flanders&rsquo; only national park &minus;&nbsp;in the east. Flowing across this landscape is the country&rsquo;s largest river the Scheldt, which enters Belgium near Tournai and flows out to sea at Antwerp.</p>
<p>In contrast, landlocked Wallonia is dominated by intensive farming in its northern provinces, watered by the Sambre and Meuse rivers, with the terrain rising to form the hills and gorges of the Ardennes in the south. Belgium&rsquo;s highest point is Signal de Botrange, at 694m (2280ft), located in the far east.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mainly Christian (65%) with a large portion being Roman Catholic (58%, although few attend regular mass), with small Protestant and Jewish communities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Knowing which language to speak where can be tricky. Avoid speaking Dutch in Wallonia and French in Flanders. Most locals are laidback, but it can cause offence if you get it wrong in some circles. If in doubt, speak English.</p>
<p>Outside of business transactions, it&rsquo;s customary to kiss three times on alternate cheeks. Guests should bring flowers, or a small present, for the hostess if they&rsquo;re invited for a meal and it is customary to wish everyone bon appetit/eet smakelijk at the start of a meal. Dress is similar to other Western nations: jeans and a smart top suffices for most occasions, including nights out. Smoking is banned in venues where food is served.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Charles Michel since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Philippe since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belgium's famous Dutch-versus-French language divide was established in the Middle Ages when Roman Emperor Charlemagne was forced to divide his kingdom between his three grandsons. Known as the Treaty of Verdun and signed in AD 843, it effectively split his territories up into the early divisions of France, Germany and the Low Countries. Flanders remained part of the Germanic Frankish lands, while Wallonia belonged to the Roman Empire and its Latin language.  </p><p>Ownership of the area passed between Spanish, Austrian and French kings, with great wealth and high art flourishing during the peaceful years of 1419-1467 and 1579-1620. Cloth-trading towns such as Bruges, Ypres and Ghent became particularly rich. </p><p>Independence only came in 1830 when the citizens staged an uprising against Dutch ruler William of Orange and had their freedom formally recognised by Great Britain and France at the London Conference in 1831. Leopold I was inaugurated as the country's first king and was succeeded by his son Leopold II, who has achieved notoriety in the modern era for pouring the riches he gained from exploitation of the Congo into magnificent buildings like the Royal Greenhouses of Laeken in Brussels. During this time, French was the official language of government and the upper classes, while Dutch remained the dialect of the working classes. The divide created fluctuating friction between Dutch-speaking Flanders and French-speaking Wallonia and it continues to this day.</p><p><br/>The country suffered four years of German occupation during World War 1, seeing some of the most intense conflicts of the entire campaign and emerging in a ruinous condition, an experience repeated during World War 2. However, it experienced rapid economic growth in the post-War era thanks largely to regeneration money granted by the US Marshall Plan. By developing its 'light' industries, Flanders subsequently overtook Wallonia's once-profitable coal industry and continues to support its southern counterpart to the tune of €10 billon a year − a cause of much grumbling among the Flemish. A constitutional monarchy, King Philippe succeeded his father Albert II who abdicated due to ill health in July 2013 and the royal family is credited as a unifying force between the two language communities.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p> Belgium loves a procession and the Carnival of Binches with its famous Gilles and the Processional Giants and Dragons of Ath, Brussels, Dendermonde, Mechelen and Mons are recognised by UNESCO as Masterpieces of the Oral and Intangible Heritage of Mankind.</p><p> Outside of France, Belgians hold the most Tour-de France victories.</p><p> French fries actually originate in Belgium. (French readers may dispute this!)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Belgium in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 333 6900.  </p><p><b>Website:</b>https://diplomatie.belgium.be/en/united_states</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 333 6900.  </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1230 and 1400-1600; Mon-Fri 0930-1200 (visas).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3330 Garfield Street NW<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Belgium]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+32 (2) 287 6211. </p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-brussels</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+32 (2) 287 6211. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700 (embassy); Mon-Tue and Thurs-Fri 0900-1230 (consular).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Avenue d'Auderghem 10, Oudergemlaan<br/>Brussels<br/>1040<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Belgium in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7470 3700 (general enquiries); 0845 730 0118 (visas).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://unitedkingdom.diplomatie.belgium.be/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7470 3700 (general enquiries); 0845 730 0118 (visas).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300 (passports and identity cards); Mon-Fri 1400-1630 (visas).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>17 Grosvenor Crescent<br/>London<br/>SW1X 7EE<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The &ldquo;boring&rdquo; tag is laughable &ndash; Belgium, pretty and creative, is one of Europe&rsquo;s most underrated travel destinations. Beer, chocolate and moules-frites might be the starting points for many first-time visitors, but while you&rsquo;ll eat and drink well, the country&rsquo;s other selling points are no less weighty.</p>
<p>Medieval cities like Brussels, Bruges, Antwerp and Ghent play home to some stunning architecture, while a military legacy that covers everything from Waterloo to WWII holds its own interest. It&rsquo;s compact, easy to travel around and boasts no fewer than 60 UNESCO World Heritage Sites. On top of that it hosts riotous festivals like they&rsquo;re going out of fashion and has a world-class arts heritage, to boot.</p>
<p>What Belgium isn&rsquo;t, however, is straightforward. Divided into three regions &minus; Flanders (the predominantly Dutch-speaking north), Wallonia (the predominantly French-speaking south) and the capital region of Brussels &ndash; it&rsquo;s still very much split down linguistic lines. Even Belgians themselves will often refer to their homeland as an &ldquo;artificial country.&rdquo; In many ways, this only makes the place more fascinating.</p>
<p>Flanders is filled with museums and medieval architecture, its countryside studded with white-washed hamlets and paved with miles and miles of cycling paths. Its North Sea coastline offers opportunities to try land boarding or kitesurfing. Wallonia, meanwhile, follows a slower pace. Steeped in folklore, its main towns have a faded French elegance and are ideal jumping-off points for exploring the rolling hills of the Ardennes. In both halves of the country, there are some genuinely beautiful landscapes.</p>
<p>Brussels itself is a blend of Art Nouveau mansions and gleaming skyscrapers, art galleries and flea markets, &ldquo;fritkot&rdquo; chip stands and Michelin-starred restaurants. Made up of 19 communes &minus; from the chic Ixelles district to up-and-coming Anderlecht &minus; it&rsquo;s a city with many faces. Each quarter offers a different take on the personality of &ldquo;Europe&rsquo;s capital,&rdquo; which is apt in itself: in Belgium, very little matches the monochrome preconception.</p><p>The &ldquo;boring&rdquo; tag is laughable &ndash; Belgium, pretty and creative, is one of Europe&rsquo;s most underrated travel destinations. Beer, chocolate and moules-frites might be the starting points for many first-time visitors, but while you&rsquo;ll eat and drink well, the country&rsquo;s other selling points are no less weighty.&nbsp;Medieval cities like Brussels, Bruges, Antwerp and Ghent play home to some stunning architecture, while a military legacy that covers everything from Waterloo to WWII holds its own interest. It&rsquo;s compact, easy to travel around and boasts no fewer than 60 UNESCO World Heritage Sites. On top of that it hosts riotous festivals like they&rsquo;re going out of fashion and has a world-class arts heritage, to boot.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
