<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Belize" ColCode="blz" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bz" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Belize]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belize&rsquo;s climate is subtropical with a brisk prevailing wind from the Caribbean Sea. Annual temperatures and humidity are high. The temperature stays fairly constant year-round, varying by only about 4&deg;C (7&deg;F) from the hottest times to the coolest. Likewise the humidity remains throughout the year, though the higher you get into the Maya Mountains, the more comfortable the climate becomes.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>The dry season is from January to April and the rainy season is from mid-May until November. This results in overcast weather despite the heat, so it is not the best time to go for a beach holiday. The hurricane season is from June to the end of November &ndash; hurricanes have in the past devastated Belize. January is the coolest month and May is the hottest.</p>
<br />
<br />]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens. A light shell jacket is recommended for the rainy season. Sandals or flip-flops will probably be your most useful footwear, but should you wish to do any hiking in the nature reserves you&rsquo;ll need proper boots to protect your feet. Swimwear will also be necessary; if you plan to go snorkelling, having a top to wear in the water to protect your back from the sun is a good idea too. For generally being outdoors, a hat and sunglasses are required to prevent sunstroke.</p>
<p>Long sleeved shirts and trousers are needed for protection against mosquitoes, which can be ferocious after dusk. Though higher-end places will provide one, it is recommended to take a mosquito net if you&rsquo;re staying in budget accommodation.  </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local airlines connect Belize City with the main towns and cayes. Flights leave from both the international airport and the municipal airstrip. The main carriers are Maya Island Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.mayaislandair.com">www.mayaislandair.com</a>) and Tropic Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tropicair.com">www.tropicair.com</a>). It is best to book in advance to get the best prices. Bear in mind that Belize is small, so internal flights might be considered unnecessary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a frequent scheduled boat service from Belize City to Ambergris Caye, Caye Chapel and Caye Caulker. Boats also depart from Placencia to Honduras and from Punta Gorda to Guatemala. See <a href="http://www.belizewatertaxi.com" target="_blank">www.belizewatertaxi.com</a>&nbsp;for boat schedules and prices from Belize City to Caye Caulker and San Pedro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Roads beyond Belize City are remarkably bumpy and pot-holed &ndash; it is quite normal for Belizeans, when driving on quiet roads, to stick to the smoother side. Local driving standards are extremely poor and road traffic accidents are common.</p><p>Several small bus companies run services across the country, the main routes being from Belize City west to Belmopan, San Ignacio and Benque Viejo del Carmen; north to Orange Walk and Corozal; and south to Punta Gorda, Independence and Dangriga, from where you can get buses to Placencia.</p>
<p>Buses tend to be uncomfortable old American school buses or chicken buses. Roads are largely bumpy and timetables are certainly flexible.</p><p>Most towns and cities are very walkable; however each city has its own taxi system and they are not very expensive. Belizean taxis don&rsquo;t have meters so you should sort out the fare in advance. You can also usually ask your hotel to order a taxi for you if you prefer.</p><p>A national driving licence is acceptable for three months, after which you need to obtain a Belize driving permit from the Department of Traffic.</p><p>The speed limit is 90kph (56mph) on highways and 40kph (25mph) on most other roads. Seat belts are compulsory. You must purchase car insurance. At police checkpoints, officers have the authority to ask to see proof of your insurance and may arrest you if you don't produce the proper documentation.</p><p>There are no official breakdown services in Belize, so ensure that your car hire service comes with the assurance that you&rsquo;ll be picked up if necessary.</p><p>Many international and local firms operate in Belize City as well as in Ladyville (Belize Airport), Dangriga and San Ignacio. Visitors usually need to be 25 years old to hire a car. For excursions south of Belize City, 4-wheel drive vehicles are recommended.</p><p>Belize is pretty flat and not very big, which makes cycling quite a pleasant way to get around. Roads generally aren&rsquo;t brilliant, so you need decent tyres. You can hire bikes in most tourist destinations, and they are also available to buy in the bigger places. Bruce Cycling Club Bike Shop in Belize City&nbsp;is one of the most popular. Make sure you&rsquo;re visible, as drivers have a rather haphazard approach to cyclists.</p><p>The speed limit is 90kph (56mph) on highways and 40kph (25mph) on most other roads. Seat belts are compulsory. You must purchase car insurance. At police checkpoints, officers have the authority to ask to see proof of your insurance and may arrest you if you don't produce the proper documentation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You rarely need to use public transport to get around towns and cities due to their size &ndash; walking is better. If you need to get from A to B in Belize City at night, taxis are preferred. The local chicken buses are slow and uncomfortable, and really only worth it if you can&rsquo;t possibly walk.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Belize</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">san_pedro_ambergris</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Belize</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">punta_gorda</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.55</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Belize</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">corozal_town</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Belize</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">belmopan</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aa.com">www.aa.com</a>) flies from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dallas">Dallas</a> to Belize City. United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) flies from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/houston">Houston</a>. Belize has only two national airlines, the biggest of which is Tropic Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tropicair.com">www.tropicair.com</a>). There are no direct flights to Belize from the UK; passengers can fly non-stop to various US destinations&nbsp;and join a connecting flight. Flights are cheaper during the rainy season (mid-May to November) and slightly more expensive over major holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - at least 20 hours (including an overnight stop in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a> - 2 hours 15 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dallas">Dallas</a> - 2 hours 50 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/houston">Houston</a> - 2 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hurricane season (June to November) in Belize can disrupt flights in and out of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$39.50 when leaving by air, payable in US Dollars, though sometimes this is included in the airfare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hurricane season (June to November) in Belize can disrupt flights in and out of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Philip S W Goldson International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.pgiabelize.com/1.html<p>The airport is 16km (10 miles) northwest of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belize-city">Belize City</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Belize City, Corozal, Dangriga, Punta Gorda and San Pedro (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.portauthority.bz">www.portauthority.bz</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no trains in Belize.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers entering Belize by car from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico">Mexico</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guatemala">Guatemala</a> must obtain a temporary importation permit at the border, valid for one month; drivers need to show all travel documents, insurance papers and proof of car ownership or rental documents.</p>
<p>There are some small bus companies that run into Belize from neighbouring countries. Linea Dorada (tel: +502 7924 8534, in Guatemala; <a href="http://www.lineadorada.com.gt" target="_blank">www.lineadorada.com.gt</a>) runs buses from Flores, Guatemala to Belize City. Mexican operator ADO (tel: +52 1 800 369 4652; <a href="http://www.ado.com.mx" target="_blank">www.ado.com.mx</a>) runs overnight buses from M&eacute;rida, Mexico to Belize City.</p>
<p>When crossing borders by bus, you must alight and walk through with your luggage, and get back on at the other side. The border procedures are generally straightforward. It's also simple to get a bus to the border and find another on the other side.</p><p>Departure tax for travellers staying more than 24 hours in Belize and leaving by land is US$18.75/BZ$37.50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Stay away from the blue and yellow phones in tourist areas. You'll pay close to $US40 per minute for long distance calls.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good along most of the coast and along the main routes to Mexico and Guatemala. Turn your phone local by inserting a SIM chip bought for US$25 and then using pre-paid cards sold throughout the country. You can also get yourself set up with a plan with Digicell (<a href="http://www.digicell.bz/" target="_blank">www.digicell.bz</a>) or with Smart Phones (<a href="http://www.smart-bz.com" target="_blank">www.smart-bz.com</a>).<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafés in urban areas and popular tourist centres offering reliable connections. Larger towns/cities and anywhere that tourists are likely to visit are starting to offer Wi-Fi, including in bars and restaurants, where it's often free when you order food and drink.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belize's constitution guarantees a free press, though exceptions are provided for in the interest of national security, public order and morality.</p>
<p>There are no daily newspapers; most of the weekly papers come out on Friday and are heavily subsidised by political parties. <em>Amandala</em> is the most widely circulated newspaper in Belize and comes out twice weekly; <em>The Reporter</em> is a respected independent weekly; <em>The Guardian</em> is the United Democratic Party&rsquo;s newspaper; and <em>The Belize Times</em> is the People&rsquo;s United Party paper.</p>
<p>All TV channels and radio stations are privately run. Among them are Great Belize Television (known as Channel 5), Tropical Vision and Centaur Cable Network.</p>
<p>Radio stations in Belize include: Love FM, a commercial music and news station; Estereo Amor, a private, Spanish-language station; Krem FM, a commercial station; More FM, a private music station targeted at younger listeners; Wave Radio, affiliated to the United Democratic Party; and Positive Vibes FM, affiliated to the People's United Party.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mail to Europe and the USA takes around a week. The postal service isn't always reliable, so don't be surprised if it takes longer.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800/0830-1200 and 1300-1630. A few open on Saturdays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Climb up Caracol’s ‘Sky Palace’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The archaeological site of Caracol is one of Belize's best-preserved Maya remains, not far from San Ignacio. Thought to be one of the most important Maya cities in the region, Caracol covers a vast area larger than present-day Belize City. Its largest pyramid, Caana, meaning 'Sky Palace', is the largest Maya construction in the country.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Belize’s floral abundance</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn about the flora of Belize at the San Ignacio Botanical Gardens, its manicured grounds filled with orchids, heliconia and many more tropical plants. Or, if you're interested in the healing properties of plants, discover the native herbs of Belize at the Chaa Creek Medicine Trail nearby. And, while you're in the area, visit the ancient agricultural settlements of the Maya at the archaeological ruins of El Pilar.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Mountain Pine Ridge’s epic waterfalls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy fine views and secluded streams in the 121-hectare (300-acre) Mountain Pine Ridge Forest Reserve in the Cayo district. The area contains the Hidden Valley Falls, which plunge 305m (1,000ft) into the valley. With many trails, rivers and waterfalls, the Reserve offers a wealth of outdoor activities, including hiking, horse riding, kayaking and birdwatching.</p>]]><p><b>Dive off the Cayes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belize's most popular destination, Ambergris Caye has everything from diving and snorkelling to golf and even a casino. The reefs and dive sites here are world class; it also has an excellent nightlife and fine seafood restaurants. Ambergris is now often called 'La Isla Bonita', from Madonna's song penned in tribute to its main town San Pedro.</p>]]><p><b>Explore ancient ruins</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wander through Xunantunich, containing some of the most intricate carvings in the Maya world and the most popular Maya site in Belize. The ruins date from AD200 and are found close to the Guatemalan border. Dominating the site is the El Castillo Temple, looming some 40 m (131ft) over the Mopan River; you can climb its steep steps for awesome views over the surrounding jungle.</p>]]><p><b>Get down and dirty in Belize City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An eye-opening alternative to the countryside's natural beauty, Belize City, though tiny, is its gritty capital, showing a different side to Belize. Here, however, is where you'll find real Belizean life, which doesn't depend solely on tourism. It's worth a couple of hours by day to witness its raunchy vibes, but don't expect a Caribbean paradise.</p>]]><p><b>Go underground to discover hidden Belize</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belize's interior hides thousands of caves, providing a rich network of routes to attract cavers and spelunkers. The most accessible cave is Rio Frio Cave in the Mountain Pine Ridge area. Other caves that are easy to visit include Che Chem Ha Cave in Cayo district and Blue Creek Cave in Toledo.</p>]]><p><b>Look out for jaguars in the Cockscomb Basin Wildlife Sanctuary</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Otherwise known as the Jaguar Sanctuary, the 40,500 hectares (100,000 acres) of tropical forest were set aside in the Maya Mountains in 1984 as the world's first reserve for this rare wild cat. You'll be extremely lucky to spot a jaguar, but other residents include jaguarundis, howler monkeys and toucans. There are nature trails and rustic accommodation for visitors.</p>]]><p><b>Plunge into Actun Tunichil Muknal Cave</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Near San Ignacio, Actun Tunichil Muknal Cave is a vast chamber used by the Maya for sacrifice to the gods; offering hardy visitors a full day of jungle hiking followed by wading, swimming and clambering through narrow passages. Not one for the claustrophobic or faint-hearted, but this site is possibly one of Belize's most rewarding adventures.</p>]]><p><b>Scale a Maya temple at Altun Ha</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Altun Ha, a major Maya centre dating from 250BC. A huge quantity of jade was uncovered in the site, including an ornate carved head of a Maya god, which is now a national symbol of Belize. You can explore the plazas and temples dotted around the site, the largest of which is the Temple of the Masonry Altars, where the jade head was found.</p>]]><p><b>See Belize’s amazing animal life</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For its wealth of wildlife, in particular birds, Belize is a natural hotspot. Crooked Tree Wildlife Sanctuary is most notable for its jabiru storks as well as monkeys, coatimundis and reptiles. Alternatively, visit Half Moon Caye Bird Sanctuary between March and August to see the rare red-footed booby with its chicks. The island sanctuary is a day trip from either Belize City or Ambergris Caye.</p>]]><p><b>Snorkel and dive off Belize’s barrier reef</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belize has the longest barrier reef in the Western hemisphere, a wall of coral stretching almost the length of the whole country. You can go snorkelling from cayes such as Ambergris, Caulker and Half Moon Caye; or for one of the world's best dive sites, try the Blue Hole: the vivid blue sinkhole measures 300m (1,000ft) across and over 120m (400ft) deep.</p>]]><p><b>Surf or swim off Caye Caulker</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Its pristine coral cayes are the main reason most people visit Belize, and Caye Caulker is the quiet, laid-back one. Windsurfing or kite-surfing here is magic: the water is so clear, you can spot fish, stingrays and even dolphins from above the waves. The best wind conditions usually occur from February to June.</p>]]><p><b>Swim in St Herman's Blue Hole National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This inland pool is not to be confused with the offshore Blue Hole dive site. The turquoise waters of the Blue Hole, a 7.6m-deep (25ft) collapsed sinkhole, are a popular swimming spot within the national park near Belmopan. The park is home to an abundance of birds, animals, flora and St Herman's Cave, an ancient Maya cave.</p>]]><p><b>Swim with sharks and rays in Hol Chan Marine Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An option off Ambergris Caye for non-divers is to swim and snorkel with the nurse sharks and stingrays in the Hol Chan Marine Reserve. The animals swirl around you in the crystal-clear waters. This protective reserve is also the habitat of some 40 types of coral as well as dolphins, manatee and many tropical fish.</p>]]><p><b>Take a boat trip to Lamanai</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Some 25 miles (40km) by motorboat up the New River from Orange Walk leads through tropical jungle to Lamanai, site of a spectacular Maya citadel. Today, the ruin sits in its own archaeological reserve, home to howler monkeys and many birds. You can climb the High Temple, or visit the museum, the remains of two 16th-century Spanish churches and a 19th-century sugar mill.</p>]]><p><b>Wait patiently for a passing manatee</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belize is one of the world's best places to observe manatees, or sea cows, in the wild. Join a tour at the Swallow Caye Marine Sanctuary: these gentle aquatic mammals are an endangered species, typically growing to about 3m (9.8ft) long. You'll need to have patience – but it'll be worth it.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$1.35 billion (2009, World Bank).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Sugar, citrus concentrates, bananas, papayas, cultured shrimp and fish.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transport equipment, manufactured goods, fuels, chemical products and pharmaceuticals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, UK, Central America, EU (Finland, Spain) and Canada.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The economy of Belize took a real beating due to a disastrous 2008 season. Cane sugar accounts for almost half the country's exports followed closely by orange concentrates. Bananas, fish (farmed shrimp, cobia and tilapia), papayas and grapefruits are also an important secondary industry. With the exception of marine products, growth in these sectors has slowed considerably due to crop failures and the aftermath of several hurricanes. The oil sector grew by 3.4% in 2008 as a result of the sweet crude oil that was discovered in 2006.</p>
<p>The tourism industry, a vital part of the economy, also suffered with a 2.1% decline in overnight tourists and a 19% decline in cruises. The southern region was severely damaged by Hurricane Arthur. Natural catastrophes caused $66 million worth of structural damages, slowing the economy by 1.5% in 2009 with inflation increasing to 4.3% and unemployment hitting just above 12%.</p>
<p>2010, however, showed a weak recovery in economic growth, despite other hurricanes making appearances. Tourism is back up and cruise ships are back in force.  </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits are often worn, although dress is more casual. Ties are rarely worn in business meetings. You should make appointments, and business cards are acceptable. This is a child-friendly culture so it's considered polite to enquire about a colleague's family.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300-1700. Some businesses are open Saturdays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Belize Trade &amp; Investment Development Service (Beltraide)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 822 3737
					Website:http://www.belizeinvest.org.bz
					Address: ,14 Orchid Garden Street,Belmopan,]]><b>Belize Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 227 3148
					Website:http://www.belize.org
					Address: 63 Regent Street,PO Box 291,Belize City,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Belizean cuisine is rather basic, but that's not to say you won't eat well here. A typical meal usually stays true to the time-honoured combination of rice, beans and meat, which is cheap, filling and usually tasty.</p><p>There are exceptions: the more touristy areas such as San Pedro or Placencia have fine restaurants serving excellent food. Along the coast and on the cayes, seafood abounds and is often delicious.</p><p>Dishes recognisable from neighbouring Guatemala and Mexico are also prevalent, as are influences from the Caribbean, Africa and Spain, not to mention international favourites such as Chinese, North American and Latin American.</p><p>Drinks mainly consist of the local beer, Belikin, sweet wine made from cashew fruit, or potent rum-based cocktails.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Rice and beans:</strong> A Belizean staple.<br />
<strong>Tacos:</strong> Corn or flour tortillas, served with shredded chicken, onions, cabbage and cilantro.<br />
<strong>Fry jacks:</strong> Fluffy fried crescents of dough, similar to Mexican <em>sopapillas</em>.<br />
<strong>Conch fritters:</strong> Pieces of conch deep-fried in batter.<br />
<strong>Plantains:</strong> Variety of banana, fried to a sweet golden brown and served with most meals.<br />
<strong>Refried beans:</strong> Served with everything from breakfast to dinner, this is a slightly sweet bean mash.<br />
<strong>Garnaches:</strong> A typical Mestizo dish of fried tortilla topped with refried beans, cabbage, carrots and cheese.<br />
<strong>Ereba:</strong> A dish of bread made from grated cassava and eaten with fish, plantains or gravy.<br />
<strong>Marie Sharp&rsquo;s Hot Sauce:</strong> The leading brand of Belizean hot habanero pepper sauce found on every table in every restaurant.<br />
<strong>Johnnycakes:</strong> Cornmeal flatbreads made from flour and coconut milk, often served with beans and cheese for breakfast.<br />
<strong>Soursop icecream:</strong> A delicious ice cream made from various tropical fruits.<br />
<strong>Juice:</strong> Orange, lime, watermelon or papaya juice are ubiquitous.<br />
<strong>Belikin:</strong> The most popular national beer.<br />
<strong>Lighthouse:</strong> Anorther popular lager. <br />
<strong>Seaweed shake:</strong> Dried seaweed, condensed milk, cinnamon, ice and sometimes a shot of rum.<br />
<strong>1 Barrel:</strong> The most popular rum drunk in Belize, available everywhere, and slightly vanilla flavoured.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>If you are eating street food try to ensure that it has been cooked thoroughly – and recently. There are plenty of rice and beans stalls selling meat, which may well have sat there all day.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Many restaurants and hotels automatically tack on a service charge of 15%. Cab drivers are not tipped unless they have helped you with your luggage. Tour guides are always tipped.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While Belize could not be considered a major clubbing destination, there is no shortage of bars throughout the country. In Belize City, the main spots tend to be the bars in the top-end hotels, which usually have live bands. There is also a casino here.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>San Pedro, on Ambergris Caye, has a lively bar scene and a couple of clubs. You&rsquo;ll also find the odd quite swish beach bar, serving high-quality cocktails. The prices are high in comparison to the rest of Belize and neighbouring countries, but not horrendous. San Ignacio has some excellent music bars. Placencia has a few lovely beachfront bars, and at festival times is extremely lively. Parties at bars in Placencia last through the night, and the quality of the bars is at odds with the tiny, dusty-village vibe of the place.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>Belize has a slightly dodgy reputation for after-hours activity; take care when leaving bars after 2300, especially in Belize City. Some bars which stay open to the small hours of the morning are out of the towns and can only be reached by car &ndash; be aware that many Belizeans will think nothing of driving to and from these bars, regardless of how much they have had to drink, and take extra care on the roads.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belize doesn't have the same traditions with handicrafts as its neighbouring countries, Mexico and Guatemala. Selections will be limited and rather expensive, though if you are travelling only to Belize you will still find typical Latin American indigenous crafts.</p>
<p>The best handmade crafts and jewellery are found in the Ambergris Caye, sold along the beachfront from various stalls. These stalls are set up in the evenings and become quite busy &ndash; pickpockets are about and single women are frequently approached.</p>
<p>Further south you can find hand-woven baskets created by Mayan women, as well as mahogany chairs and other carvings. Locals sell traditional Mayan crafts and jewellery at most of the ruins sites, but bear in mind that they will be cheaper and of higher quality just over the border in Guatemala.</p>
<p>Probably the most distinctive craft available to buy in Belize are the drums created by the Garifuna. They are one of the few options you have of purchasing something truly Belizean. Be careful, however, taking them out of the country, as you may need to declare animal-skin drums at customs. Standard souvenir fare includes slogan T-shirts and Belikin (the country&rsquo;s most famous beer) paraphernalia.</p>
<p>In the Toledo district in the south, market buses run from Punta Gorda to local villages for market days, where you can see the remaining indigenous people of Belize selling their wares. Dangriga Central Market is good not for souvenir shopping but for food, clothes and soaking up the local vibe.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1200, 1300-1630 and 1900-2100. Some shops close on Wednesday afternoons. With Belizean culture being as laid back as it is, don't be surprised if many places don't keep to these hours.</p><p>Travellers should be aware of their home country's rules on importing exotic goods. In the UK, for example, there are restrictions on importing tortoiseshell goods and jewellery made from endangered coral.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belize has an eclectic assortment of high-end, exclusive establishments. Lodges and resorts are almost always comfortable hotels in remote locations. While there are several resort hotels on the Caribbean coast, most accommodation is in simple guest houses or family-run hotels. Expect to pay upwards of BZ$50; anything cheaper is usually not safe or clean. Cabins or cabanas are rustic set-ups, sometimes with or without electricity.</p>
<p>Generally hotels in Belize are of a significantly higher price than those of neighbouring countries, while the quality can be often be lower. Be prepared for extra taxes such as the General Sales Tax (10%), the Hotel Tax (9%) and Service Charge (10-15%) that may be added after the room rate has been quoted. The Belize Tourism Board lists registered accommodation on its website (<a href="http://travelbelize.org" target="_blank">http://travelbelize.org</a>). </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfast places tend to take the form of small guest house-style accommodation, often run by expats. You'll find all sorts of standards available, from the hippie-type bed and breakfast where a laid-back attitude is essential to cope with the basic facilities, to the more homely welcoming sort. It is advised to check the rooms and facilities on arrival to see if you want to stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belize has an eclectic assortment of high-end, exclusive establishments. Lodges and resorts are almost always comfortable hotels in remote locations. While there are several resort hotels on the Caribbean coast, most accommodation is in simple guest houses or family-run hotels. Expect to pay upwards of BZ$50; anything cheaper is usually not safe or clean. Cabins or cabanas are rustic set-ups, sometimes with or without electricity.</p>
<p>Generally hotels in Belize are of a significantly higher price than those of neighbouring countries, while the quality can be often be lower. Be prepared for extra taxes such as the General Sales Tax (10%), the Hotel Tax (9%) and Service Charge (10-15%) that may be added after the room rate has been quoted. The Belize Tourism Board lists registered accommodation on its website (<a href="http://travelbelize.org" target="_blank">http://travelbelize.org</a>). </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belize has an eclectic assortment of high-end, exclusive establishments. Lodges and resorts are almost always comfortable hotels in remote locations. While there are several resort hotels on the Caribbean coast, most accommodation is in simple guest houses or family-run hotels. Expect to pay upwards of BZ$50; anything cheaper is usually not safe or clean. Cabins or cabanas are rustic set-ups, sometimes with or without electricity.</p>
<p>Generally hotels in Belize are of a significantly higher price than those of neighbouring countries, while the quality can be often be lower. Be prepared for extra taxes such as the General Sales Tax (10%), the Hotel Tax (9%) and Service Charge (10-15%) that may be added after the room rate has been quoted. The Belize Tourism Board lists registered accommodation on its website (<a href="http://travelbelize.org" target="_blank">http://travelbelize.org</a>). </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are seven government hospitals - one in Belmopan, one in Belize City and one in each of the other five main district towns, but, generally, medical facilities are limited and there is a shortage of doctors in rural areas. Medical services in rural areas are provided by rural health care centres, and mobile clinics operate in remote areas. Generally, medical standards are not high. Medical insurance is strongly advised, and make sure that it covers you for any adventurous activities you might wish to do, such as scuba-diving, watersports and hiking through caves. Most hospitals and doctors expect to be paid in cash, whether you have insurance or not.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Never drink the tap water and buy only bottled purified water with a proper seal. It is widely available from shops and grocery stores, but in case of being in rural areas with no access to bottled water, carry water purification tablets to treat water. Milk is often unpasteurised and should be boiled, though UHT milk is often available in shops. Avoid ice cream, raw fish and anything from street vendors unless you can see that it has been properly cooked, preferably in front of you. A quick and cheap meal is beans and rice with a piece of meat, usually chicken, and you will find plenty of food stalls or small, local restaurants serving it, but cooked food should never be served lukewarm. Peel or cook all fruits and vegetables. Prevent flies from landing on your food as many carry airborne illnesses, and do not eat at places where the food has been left exposed for long.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes advised, especially if staying for long periods of time or if you might have sexual contact with the local population. Dengue fever occurs throughout Latin America and is on the rise in Belize, so mosquito protection is recommended. If you find yourself with a fever and/or rash, go to a doctor immediately. Malaria also occurs in Belize, so anti-malaria medication such as Malarone or Doxycycline is recommended (except in Belize City).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just over 2.5 % of the population has HIV/AIDS, which is a 25 times higher occurrence than in the UK, but the government has launched a public awareness campaign to try and tackle the problem. Note: Visitors applying for residency will require an HIV test (foreign tests may not be acceptable).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belize is in the tropics so you can burn quickly - sunscreen is a must, and you should protect yourself with a hat and sunglasses. Motor vehicle crashes are the main cause of injury, so take care while on the road and give other drivers a wide berth.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are generally observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Below are listed Public Holidays for the January 2014-December 2015 period.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Baron Bliss Day :
							09 March </p><p>Commonwealth Day :
							12 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Holy Saturday :
							31 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>St George's Caye Day :
							10 September </p><p>Independence Day :
							21 September </p><p>Columbus Day :
							12 October </p><p>Garifuna Settlement Day :
							19 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Belize by travellers aged 18 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 1L of wine or spirits (combined amount).<br />
&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; Personal items, gifts or souvenirs up to a value of BZ$200 if entering via the international airport or BZ$50 if entering via other ports of entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must declare live animals, meat, fruit, vegetables, weapons or ammunition, which all require permits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pre-Columbian articles, marine products, unprocessed coral or turtle shells.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belize Dollar (BZD; symbol BZ$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of BZ$100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 2. Coins are in denominations of BZ$1 and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents. Belize, as part of the Commonwealth, still has Queen Elizabeth II on its notes. American money is eagerly accepted anywhere in the country, and hotel prices are often quoted in US Dollars. Belizean money is worthless outside the country since most exchange houses will not deal with the currency. Exchange your Belize bills before leaving the country.</p><p>The Belize Dollar is tied to the US Dollar at US$1 = BZ$2. Talk of a devaluation is always in the background but it has been that way since 1978 so will likely remain unchanged.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency can be exchanged at most banks, hotels and travel agencies. While not strictly legal, there are also freelance money exchangers who often have a better rate.  Currency exchanged on the border of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guatemala">Guatemala</a> will get a lower rate, and you are also able to exchange US Dollars here if you wish. ATM exchange rates are usually 1% lower than bank rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard and Visa are accepted. Most establishments will add a 5% service charge to the bills of customers using credit cards.</p><p>ATMs in Belize are available in most towns and cities – it's only the really rural areas that you'll have any trouble with. Make sure you've got some cash and a credit card on you to back up your ATM use, just in case. ATMs can also run out of money and might not be restocked for several days. They only give out Belize Dollars, and the exchange rate tends to be a cent or two under the official rate. Many banks also charge a fee to use ATMs and there is a withdrawal limit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These can be exchanged; commission will usually be charged. There are few places accepting cheques so you may have some difficulty cashing them in more remote areas. Cheques with any imperfections will be rejected. In case of being unable to exchange them, it is best to plan your finances and use ATMs in the bigger towns and cities; however, if you are able to use them you will get the full BZ$2 to US$1 rate. US Dollar traveller's cheques are recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1300, Fri 0800-1630. Times may vary according to destination.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Belize, a passport valid for six months beyond the intended length of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adults travelling with children who are not legally their own must have a letter of consent from the children&rsquo;s parents. Children under 18 travelling with only one parent require the written consent of the other parent. Children under 18 travelling alone must have a passport and letter of parental consent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no transit visa for nationals in the above chart. If you are in transit you should not leave the airport, as you will then be liable to the departure tax. If you are staying for fewer than seven days you can get an In Transit stamp and your exit fee will be reduced.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry: &pound;60 plus &pound;7 shipping fee; multiple-entry: &pound;110 plus &pound;7 shipping fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visas are valid for three months from the date of issue; multiple-entry visas are valid for six months from the date of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For nationalities that require a visa, applications should be made to your nearest Belize embassy or high commission. You&nbsp;must show your travel itinerary and accommodation booking confirmation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three to four weeks for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Theoretically, everyone is required to prove they have sufficient funds to cover their stay, which you can demonstrate with bank statements. In practice, you&rsquo;ll almost never be asked.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals stated in the above chart are able to extend their stay by 30 days at any immigration office in the country; you should do this at least two to three days before your original 30-day period expires.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets must come with a vet&rsquo;s certificate issued in their country of origin. Pet owners must also have an import permit for their animal from the Belize Agricultural Health Authority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[17.330014]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-88.629998]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>22,965 sq km (8,867 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>366,942 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>14.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belmopan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parliamentary democracy and member of the Commonwealth.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although Belize is a tiny country, it has an astonishing range of geography. The Great Maya Barrier Reef runs alongside Belize's coast creating hundreds of small islands called cayes (keys) and offshore atolls, perfect for diving or snorkelling.</p>
<p>From the centre of the country, stretching southwest into Guatemala and southeast to the coast are the Maya Mountains, a tropical broadleaf forest that is home to hundreds of different species.</p>
<p>The two most northern districts are Corazol, which is flat terrain eventually turning into the forested hills and wild tropical jungle of Orange Walk. This sector is often referred to as the breadbasket of the country since it's primarily an agricultural area.</p>
<p>The Belize district is home to the Northern Cayes. Ambergris Caye is the most developed and elegant resort area in the country while Caye Caulker has a more laid back atmosphere. Both are famous for their diving and snorkelling. Belize City has a mixed geography: to the north are the savannahs, to the west tropical jungle and to the south lagoons and mangroves.</p>
<p>Western Cayo district is the largest county and is home to the Maya Mountains. Several rivers drop down from the mountain range, heading south, east and north making this a lush forested area filled with waterfalls, caves and Mayan ruins. The spectacular Hummingbird Highway traverses the northern edge of the mountains.</p>
<p>Southern Belize has two distinct areas. Stann Creek rests on the eastern ridge on the Maya Mountain range where there are forested hills and pristine jungle ending at Dangriga on the coast, which gives way to the Central Cayes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The people of Belize are mainly Roman Catholic (approximately 49.6% of the population). Approximately 27% is Protestant with a growing evangelical movement. There are growing Rastafarian communities along with smaller pockets of Islam, Buddhism, Hinduism, and Bahai.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can still see British influence in many social situations. Flowers or confectionary are acceptable gifts to give to hosts if invited to their home for a meal. Dress is casual, although beachwear should not be worn in towns. It may be inadvisable to discuss politics, particularly if of a partisan nature. Time is much more flexible here and any impatience towards the lack of punctuality will not be well received. You'll be asked to get onto Belizean Time. Gay travellers should be aware that male homosexuality is still illegal in Belize, and demonstrable homosexuality from either gender will not be looked upon well and could be dangerous for the traveller.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. American-style plugs with two flat pins are standard; sockets don't usually have holes for a third grounding pin however, so you may need an adaptor if your plug has a third pin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Dean Barrow since 2008.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General Sir Colville Young since 1993.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Maya civilisation that covered much of Central America incorporated Belize from around 2,500 BC to AD 900. The country has some spectacular and remarkably well-preserved ruins from this era and there are still some 30 Maya villages in the south of Belize, which retain a traditional way of life.</p>
<p>Yet it is the British that have given the country its modern shape. They occupied the territory in 1638 and, by the end of the 18th century, had brought African slaves over to cut the country&rsquo;s mahogany. Despite attacks from the Spanish, the settlers remained, although it was not until 1862 that the territory was recognised as a British colony, and named British Honduras.</p>
<p>Belize achieved internal self-government in 1964 and elections the following year brought the leader of the People's United Party (PUP), George Price, to power. He presided over Belizean independence in 1981, but his party lost the 1985 elections to the United Democratic Party (UDP). Price was then returned to office in 1989.</p>
<p>Tensions have long existed between Belize and Guatemala, because, even though the boundary between them was determined in 1859, Guatemala continued to claim sovereignty of Belize. Throughout the 1970s, British troops were sent over to deter Guatemalan invasion threats.</p>
<p>In 1993 the British garrison withdrew and shortly afterwards, Premier George Price called a snap election. Despite expectations he was narrowly defeated by Manuel Esquival, the new leader of the UDP.</p>
<p>The Belizean government has come under pressure from the USA for its alleged laxity in the 'War on Drugs' &ndash; Washington believes that Belize has become a major transit point for shipments into the USA, and for the laundering of drug profits through the country's banking system.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong> <br />
&bull; Belize is the only country in the region with English as its official main language.<br />
&bull; Belize&rsquo;s Barrier Reef is the second largest reef system in the world, running the whole length of its coastline for some 174 miles (280 km).<br />
&bull; Belize is thought to have been named after the British pirate Wallace, who formed the first settlement here.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Belize]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(501) 822 2981/2717/2147.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinbelize.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(501) 822 2981/2717/2147.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1200 and 1300-1600, Fri 0800-1400; Mon-Thur 0900-1100 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>PO Box 91<br/>Belmopan<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Belize in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 9636.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofbelize.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 9636.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1700, Fri 0900-1630.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2535 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Belize High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7723 3603.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.belizehighcommission.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7723 3603.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1800; Mon-Fri 1000-1300 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Third Floor, 45 Crawford Place<br/>London<br/>W1H 5<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sandwiched between Mexico, Guatemala and the shimmering Caribbean Sea, Belize occupies a slice of paradise that is packed with culture, wildlife and a wondrous selection of historical sites. Much of the mainland remains swathed in jungle, where the vestiges of ancient cities punctuate verdant forest canopies. Caracol is the most famous. Its crumbling temples and stone pyramids stand as powerful reminders of the Maya civilisation.</p>
<p>The history is fascinating for sure, but most people visit Belize to see its natural wonders and admirable conservation work; the Cockscomb Basin Wildlife Sanctuary was the first jaguar sanctuary in the world; the island of Half Moon Caye has been entirely dedicated to the conservation of birds; and the protected Belize Barrier Reef harbours an incredible array of marine life. Visitors can swim with sharks and stingrays along colourful walls of coral, or explore the Blue Hole, renowned as one of the world&rsquo;s best dive sites.</p>
<p>Numbering fewer than 335,000, Belizeans have surprisingly diverse roots: the country is a melting pot of Creole, Garifuna, Mestizo, Spanish, Maya, English, Mennonite, Lebanese, Chinese and East Indian heritage. Racial harmony, religious tolerance and a relatively peaceful political culture, have allowed these different elements to blend successfully and have given Belize a reputation as a friendly, laidback destination.</p>
<p>Belize&rsquo;s towns and cities are small and, on the whole, pleasantly unexciting. San Ignacio is a charming enough stop-off for those disappearing into the jungle and Punta Gorda offers insightful home stays with some of the country&rsquo;s last remaining indigenous communities. The somewhat bland capital, Belmopan, however, is hardly worth going out your way for and bustling Belize City, though energetic and ruggedly charming, is used largely as a gateway to the islands.</p>
<p>And what exquisite islands they are. Caye Caulker, Ambergris Caye, Cayo Espanto (to name a few) are everything you expect from the Caribbean and more; swaying palms, pellucid waters, sandy shores, ramshackle beach bars and charming restaurants. All that&rsquo;s missing are the crowds. Go figure.</p><p>Sandwiched between Mexico, Guatemala and the shimmering Caribbean Sea, Belize is packed with culture, wildlife and a wondrous selection of historical sites. Much of the mainland remains swathed in jungle, where the vestiges of ancient cities punctuate verdant forest canopies. Caracol is the most famous. Its crumbling temples and stone pyramids stand as powerful reminders of the Maya civilisation.&nbsp;<span style="line-height: 20.3999996185303px;">The history is fascinating for sure, but most people visit Belize to see its natural wonders and admirable conservation work; the Cockscomb Basin Wildlife Sanctuary was the first jaguar sanctuary in the world; the island of Half Moon Caye has been entirely dedicated to the conservation of birds; and the protected Belize Barrier Reef harbours an incredible array of marine life.<br />
</span></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
