<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Benin" ColCode="ben" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bj" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Benin]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The south has an equatorial climate with four seasons. It is hot and dry from January to April and during August, with rainy seasons through May to July and September to December. The north has more extreme temperatures, hot and dry between November and June, cooler and very wet between July and October.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens. A light raincoat or an umbrella is<br />necessary in rainy seasons and warmer clothes are advised for cool<br />evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Benin's railway service has been mainly limited to freight trains in recent years, but the Cotonou-Parakou line is being upgraded, with plans for an eventual extension to the border at Gaya and on to neighbouring Niger.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>The roads are in reasonably good condition (although some are poorly lit) and many of those which run from Cotonou to Dassa, and Parakou to Malanville, are paved.&nbsp;Tracks are passable during the dry season but often impassable during the rainy season.</p><p>Buses connect the main cities, while bush taxi services run along routes to smaller towns.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>A number of local and international firms are available in Cotonou. It's a good idea to hire a car with a driver rather than attempting to drive yourself.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taxis, especially motorbike taxis,&nbsp;are widely available in the main towns. Taxi fares should be agreed in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main airline is Westair Benin (<a href="http://www.westairbenin.com" target="_blank">www.westairbenin.com</a>). There are no direct flights from the UK or the USA to Benin. You can fly via Paris with Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) or via Casablanca with Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London - 9 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); New York - 19 hours or more (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cotonou Cadjehoun International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeroport-cotonou.com<p>The airport is 5km (3 miles) west of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main port:&nbsp;</strong>Porto Novo. Several shipping lines run regular cargo services from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/marseille">Marseille</a> to Cotonou. Local shipping from Lagos arrives in Porto Novo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Cotonou-Parakou railway line is being upgraded, with plans to connect Benin with Niamey, Niger's capital.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There is an additional charge for calls made from a coin box.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some roaming agreements exist. Coverage is limited. Handsets can be hired locally. Further information can be obtained from the <em>Office des Postes et Télécommunications du Bénin</em> (website: <a href="http://www.opt.bj" target="_blank">www.opt.bj</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public access is available in Cotonou.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The constitution guarantees media freedom although harsh libel laws have been used against journalists. Benin has more than 50 newspapers and periodicals, one state TV channel, a handful of commercial TV channels and more than 30 state, commercial and local radio stations.<br />In 2003, the authorities paved the way for a further expansion of the private media scene, allocating frequencies for five private TV stations and 10 commercial radio stations. The <em>BBC World Service</em> and <em>Radio France Internationale</em> are available on FM in Cotonou.<strong><br /></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail takes three to five days to reach Europe. Surface mail letters or parcels take from six to eight weeks.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Brush up on your history in Porto Novo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The gateway to Benin for most visitors, Porto Novo, Benin's laidback capital, is home to some exquisite examples of colonial and pre-colonial architecture, not least the Brazilian-style Big Mosque. Other attractions of note include the eclectic Musée da Silva, which offers a brief history of Benin, and the Porto Novo Museum of Ethnography. Royalists might want to head to King Toffa's Palace, where the Musée Honmé reveals the secrets of local royalty.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Somba culture in Natitingou</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Natitingou's regional museum provides an impression of life for Benin's Somba communities that primarily inhabit the northeast of the country. Located within an elegant colonial structure previously used by local government, exhibits relate to archaeology, history and art. The habitat room has examples of traditional Somba homes.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Cotonou’s bustling streets</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set between the Atlantic Ocean and Lac Nokoué, Cotonou is Benin's largest and most important city. Its market, the sprawling Dantokpa, covers a whopping 20 hectares (49 acres) and sells everything from toothbrushes to fresh fruit – a great way to experience the city. The nearby Foundation Zinsou, which promotes modern African art, is also well worth a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Feed your brain in Abomey</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The dusty city of Abomey is home to the eponymous Abomey Historical Museum, which offers an insight into the history of the Abomey Kingdom and contains a throne made of human skulls. Whilst you're in town, pay a visit to the opulent royal palaces, swing by the Fetish Temple and peruse the local wares at the Centre Artisanal.</p>]]><p><b>Follow the Route of Slaves in Ouidah</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ouidah was once a major centre for the slave trade, a place where slaves were led from the Portuguese Fort (now a museum) along a 4km (2.5 mile) sandy track to waiting ships that would take them across the Atlantic. Today the track is lined with poignant memorials such as the Tree of Forgetfulness. The path ends at the Door of No Return memorial arch.</p>]]><p><b>Indulge your inner artist at Villa Karo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A cultural centre and artists' residence, Villa Karo in Grand Popo is a Finnish-African project that aims to improve understanding between cultures. The centre puts on a range of events including art exhibitions, film screenings and concerts and is a great way to get involved with the local community, which relies largely on its modest fishing industry.</p>]]><p><b>Journey north for wildlife watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See a wide range of wildlife including cheetahs, hippos and crocodiles at Benin's two national parks. Though celebrated for its diverse landscapes and big game, Pendjari National Park is mostly vaunted for its varied birdlife. The UNESCO-listed W National Park provides a home for some of West Africa's last wild elephants and straddles the frontier between Benin, Niger and Burkina Faso.</p>]]><p><b>Relax by the water</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Although beaches are strung all along Benin's 120km (75 mile) Atlantic coastline, the best quality sands are found at Grand Popo and Ouidah. Facilities for water sports on the coast are limited, though it's possible to sail at the Yacht Club in Cotonou, or hire a dug-out canoe or motorboat on Lac Nakoué.</p>]]><p><b>Take a dip at Kota Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The isolated 20m-high (65ft) waterfalls at Kota provide a relaxed and secluded pool to take a refreshing dip, and an idyllic setting to while away an afternoon with a picnic. Accommodation makes it possible to stay overnight, and enjoy the solitude and romanticism even longer.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the ‘Venice of Africa’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Floating in Lac Nokoué, and only accessible by boat, the stilt village of Ganvie is home to a staggering 20,000 people. A fully-fledged and atmospheric town, it was constructed sometime between the 16th and 17th centuries as a safe haven for the Tofino people against local slave traders.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$4 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cotton, peanuts, coffee and palm oil.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Energy.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria, France, China and India.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since the transition to democratic government in 1991, Benin has undergone a remarkable economic recovery. A large injection of external investment from both private and public sources has alleviated the economic difficulties of the early 1990s, caused by global recession and persistently low commodity prices (although the latter continues to affect the economy).<br /><br />Benin, poor in natural resources, is traditionally a trading nation and its economy is heavily dependent on the success of its much larger neighbour, Nigeria. Benin is hugely dependent on its import/export trade with the latter. A large part of the economy is based on the re-export of goods to Nigeria.<br /><br />Benin's economy is principally agricultural - it is self-sufficient in basic foodstuffs, the main export commodities being cotton, peanuts, coffee and palm oil. The manufacturing sector is confined to some light industry, mainly involved in processing primary products and the production of consumer goods.<br /><br />A planned joint hydroelectric project with neighbouring Togo is intended to reduce Benin's dependence on imported energy (mostly from Ghana), which currently accounts for a significant proportion of the country's imports.<br /><br />The service sector has grown quickly, stimulated by economic liberalisation and fiscal reform. Membership of the CFA Franc Zone offers reasonable currency stability, as well as access to French economic support. <br /><br />Benin is also a member of the West African economic community ECOWAS. The economy remains fragile and largely dependent on international aid. <br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is essential to be able to conduct conversations in French. Normal courtesies should be observed and punctuality is especially important. Lightweight suits should be worn.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1230 and 1500-1830.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie du Bénin</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 312 081 ,314 386 ,311 238
					Website:http://www.ccib.bj
					Address: 01 BP 31,Avenue du Général de Gaulle,Cotonou,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Benin&rsquo;s cuisine is an exotic fusion of European and African flavours. Fish and shellfish are popular choices in the south, close to the country&rsquo;s lagoons and Atlantic coast, while chicken comprises the most common protein in the drier north.</p>
<p>No meal, whether it&rsquo;s a quick snack from a street-side hawker or a full meal at one of Cotonou&rsquo;s finest restaurants, is complete without a rich sauce. Commonly tomato or peanut based, these sauces are the mainstay of Benin&rsquo;s stews and fried foods.</p>
<p>Though desserts are thin on the ground, there is a plethora of freshly-picked tropical fruits including mangoes, oranges and bananas. The small locally-grown pineapples, which can be skinned and chopped on the street for you, are particularly fine.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Aloko:</strong> Deep-fried plantain slices.<br />
<strong>Akpan:</strong> Fried corn dumplings served with a dipping sauce (common street food).<br />
<strong>Smoked fish:</strong> Fish smoked over an open fire.<br />
<strong>Fufu and garri:</strong> Paste formed from either yam or cassava tubers, respectively.<br />
<strong>Moyo:</strong> A sauce served with fried fish, made from tomatoes, onions and peppers.<br />
<strong>Ago glain:</strong> Stew made from shellfish such as crab, tomatoes and chillies.<br />
<strong>Peanut soup:</strong> Made with peanuts, tomatoes and carrots and served with chicken.<br />
<strong>Yovo doko:</strong> Doughnuts, also called beignet.<br />
<strong>Akkara:</strong> Fritters made from skinned black-eyed peas.<br />
<strong>La B&eacute;ninoise:</strong> Benin&rsquo;s favourite lager.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It is normal to tip 10% in hotels and restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cotonou offers several nightclubs, but elsewhere there is little nightlife except during festivals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Cotonou, along the marina, there are many stalls selling handicrafts and souvenirs. The Dan Tokpa market borders the Cotonou Lagoon and is stocked with many goods from Nigeria and elsewhere, as well as traditional medicines and artefacts. Crafts and local goods can be purchased in many towns and villages elsewhere, particularly in markets. Good buys include ritual masks, tapestries, elongated statues and pottery.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1300 and 1600-1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Main towns and urban areas have a variety of hotels. Top-end hotels are, however, mainly found in and around the capital. There are also some campsites in and around Cotonou. There are a few establishments (<em>campements</em>) for game viewing at Porga near Pendjari National Park.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Main towns and urban areas have a variety of hotels. Top-end hotels are, however, mainly found in and around the capital. There are also some campsites in and around Cotonou. There are a few establishments (<em>campements</em>) for game viewing at Porga near Pendjari National Park.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Main towns and urban areas have a variety of hotels. Top-end hotels are, however, mainly found in and around the capital. There are also some campsites in and around Cotonou. There are a few establishments (<em>campements</em>) for game viewing at Porga near Pendjari National Park.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are limited, especially outside the major towns, and not all medicines are available. Doctors and hospitals often expect immediate cash payment for health services. Medical insurance is strongly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid all dairy products. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis E is widespread. Hepatitis B is hyperendemic. Hepatitis C occurs. Meningococcal meningitis is a risk, depending on the area and the time of year. Immunisation against hepatitis B, tuberculosis and meningococcal A and C is sometimes recommended. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. The hot, dusty, windy environmental conditions in November and December may exacerbate respiratory problems. HIV/AIDS is prevalent. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Traditional Day :
							2018<br/>10 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							01 August </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Armed Forces Day :
							26 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>National Day :
							30 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Benin by persons over 15 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 25 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of wine and 1 bottle of spirits.<br />
&bull; 500ml of eau de toilette and 250ml of perfume.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFA (<em>Communauté Financière Africaine</em>) Franc (XOF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of XOF10,000, 5,000, 2,000 and 1,000. Coins are in denominations of XOF500, 200, 100, 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1. Benin is part of the French Monetary Area.<br /><br />Only currency issued by the <em>Banque des Etats de l'Afrique de l'Ouest</em> (Bank of West African States) is valid; currency issued by the <em>Banque des Etats de l'Afrique Centrale</em> (Bank of Central African States) is not. The CFA Franc is tied to the Euro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency can be exchanged at banks and in major hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted on a limited basis. Some banks may advance cash or visa cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1100 and 1500-1700. Some banks may open on Saturday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months beyond your departure date from Benin is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals from the USA are charged US$140 for a Benin visa; this is valid for up to 36 months, and covers both single and multiple entries.&nbsp;</p>
<p>UK nationals are charged &pound;60 for a 15-day single-entry visa; &pound;70 for a 30-day single-entry visa; &pound;80 for a 30-day double-entry visa; &pound;90 for a 90-day single-entry visa; &pound;100 for a 90-day double-entry visa; and &pound;120 for a multiple-entry 180-day visa.</p>
<p>Canadian nationals are charged C$120 for a single-entry 90-day visa and C$140 for a multiple-entry 90-day visa.</p>
<p>Other nationals referred to in the chart above wishing to obtain a visa for Benin should contact their nearest embassy or high commission for the latest fees.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dependent on type of visa (see above).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three working days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[9.623992]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[2.337990]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>112,622 sq km (43,484 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>11,166,658 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>92.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Porto-Novo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Benin is situated in West Africa and is bordered to the east by Nigeria, to the north by Niger and Burkina Faso, and to the west by Togo. Benin stretches 700km (435 miles) from the Bight of Benin to the Niger River. The coastal strip is sandy with coconut palms. Beyond the lagoons of Porto Novo, Nokoue, Ouidah and Grand Popo is a plateau rising gradually to the heights of the Atakora Mountains. From the highlands run two tributaries of the Niger, while southwards the Ou&eacute;m&eacute; flows down to Nokoue lagoon. Mono River flows into the sea at Grand Popo and forms a frontier with Togo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>35% animist/traditional, 35% Christian (mainly Roman Catholic) and the majority of the rest are Muslim.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal courtesies are appreciated; it is customary to shake hands on arrival and departure. However, religious beliefs play a large part in society and these should be respected. Voodoo is perhaps the most striking and best-known practice, and has acquired considerable social and political power. Only priests can communicate with voodoos and spirits of the dead. If travelling, it is advisable to clear itineraries with district or provincial authorities. Casual wear is acceptable in most places.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vacant.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Patrice Talon since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Benin was the seat of one of the great medieval African kingdoms. During the 13th century, the indigenous Edo people were run by a group of local chieftains. However, by the 15th century, a single ruler, known as the <em>oba</em>, had asserted control.</p>
<p>Under the dynasty established by Ewuare the Great, Benin's territory expanded to cover a region between the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/niger">Niger</a> Delta and what is now the Nigerian city of Lagos. The <em>obas</em> brought great prosperity and a highly organised state to Benin.</p>
<p>French colonisation came in 1872 and in 1904 the territory was incorporated into French West Africa as Dahomey. In 1958, it became the R&eacute;publique du Dahomey, self-governing within the French community and gained full independence from France on 1 August 1960.</p>
<p>A succession of military coups brought about many changes of government; the last of these brought to power Major Mathieu K&eacute;r&eacute;kou. The new ruler, who was at the head of a regime professing strict Marxist-Leninist principles, remained in power until the beginning of the 1990s, when the K&eacute;r&eacute;kou government introduced a new democratic constitution and held presidential and legislative elections.</p>
<p>It made Benin the first African country to successfully effect the transition from dictatorship to a pluralistic political system where the president heads the government, the state and the military, and appoints members of the cabinet. K&eacute;r&eacute;kou's principal opponent at the presidential poll, and the ultimate victor, was then Prime Minister Nic&eacute;phore Soglo.</p>
<p>Political newcomer Yayi Boni won the second round of presidential elections in 2006, gaining roughly three quarters of the vote. He went on to win re-election without a runoff vote in 2011, the first president to do so since the reestablishment of democracy in 1991.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Though Benin has been a French colonial possession for much of its recent history, Ouidah&rsquo;s S&atilde;o Jo&atilde;o fort remained Portuguese territory from 1721 until 1961.<br />
&bull; The capital since 1900, Porto Novo actually has three names. It is also known as Adjatche and Hogbonou.<br />
&bull; Benin has never won an Olympic medal, in either the summer or winter games.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Benin in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 232 6656 (general) ; (202) 232 2611 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.beninembassy.us</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 232 6656 (general) ; (202) 232 2611 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2124 Kalorama Road<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Benin in France]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(01) 4500 9882 or 4222 3191 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(01) 4500 9882 or 4222 3191 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>87 avenue Victor Hugo<br/>Paris<br/>75116<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Honorary Consulate of Benin in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 8830 8612.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 8830 8612.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon, Wed and Fri 1030-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Millennium House, Humber Road<br/>London<br/>NW2 6DW<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Direction de la Documentation de Réseau Internet du Gouvernement (DDARIG)]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>306 835.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gouv.bj</p><p><b>Tel:</b>306 835.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>01 BP 120<br/>Cotonou<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In many ways Benin is the perfect introduction to Africa. A land of pristine beaches, bountiful wildlife and hospitable inhabitants, travelling around the country is a doddle thanks to its small size and advanced infrastructure.</p>
<p>The birthplace of voodoo and one of the major departure points for the more than eight million people forced to leave the continent as slaves, the country also has a complex and compelling history that filters down into everyday life to create a jumble of the familiar and the strange.</p>
<p>Stay in the south to experience Benin&rsquo;s major cities, the slightly chaotic yet vibrant commercial hub of Cotonou and the laidback capital Porto Novo. Take some time out from the capital&rsquo;s lagoon-side location and palm-fringed Atlantic beaches to request an audience with the tribal princes of Ajase, Porto Novo&rsquo;s ancestral name, while visiting the palace museum.</p>
<p>Head along the coast to experience the unique lives of the Tofinu people at Ganvi&eacute;, a bamboo stilt village often referred to as the &ldquo;Venice of Africa.&rdquo; Or take advantage of Benin&rsquo;s small size and good roads to explore the country&rsquo;s spectacular countryside, which harbours remote towns and exquisite national parks. Home to lions, hippos and elephants, not to mention myriad bird species, Benin&rsquo;s flagship national park is Pendjari, which serves up spectacular fauna without the crowds.</p>
<p>A thriving arts scene across the country has given rise to stunning public sculptures and fantastic architecture, which complement the elegance of the wooden Afro-Brazilian mansions of Porto Novo and Ouidah. The latter is the beating heart of Benin&rsquo;s voodoo practitioners and an important stop for those interested in the history of the Atlantic slave trade.</p>
<p>Small in size but not in stature, Benin has something to suit every interest, be it the wild landscapes of the north, the bustling metropolises of the south, or the shared religion and history that bind this country and its people together.</p><p>In many ways Benin is the perfect introduction to Africa. A land of pristine beaches, bountiful wildlife and hospitable inhabitants, travelling around the country is a doddle thanks to its small size and advanced infrastructure.</p>
<p>The birthplace of voodoo and one of the major departure points for the more than eight million people forced to leave the continent as slaves, the country also has a complex and compelling history that filters down into everyday life to create a jumble of the familiar and the strange.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
