<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Bermuda" ColCode="bmu" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bm" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Bermuda]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sub-tropical, with no wet season. The Gulf Stream, which flows between Bermuda and the North American continent, keeps the climate temperate. Change of seasons comes during mid November to mid December and from late March through to April, when spring or summer weather may occur and visitors should be prepared for both. Showers may be heavy at times but the skies usually clear quickly. <br /><br />Summer temperatures prevail from May to mid October, with the warmest weather from July to September - this period is occasionally followed by high winds. Visitors should note that such high winds between 1 June and 30 November can (albeit rarely) turn into hurricanes and tropical storms. Since Bermuda is a small target, most storms brush by and only bring elevated surf.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens. Light waterproofs or umbrellas are advisable and warmer clothes for cooler months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferries depart from the terminal on Front Street in Hamilton. Cash is not accepted onboard, only a transportation pass, ticket or token. Ferries run on a regular daily schedule across Hamilton Harbour and to various stops at Sandys, Paget, Warwick and Southampton Parishes. In summer months they stop at the Royal Naval Dockyard before continuing on to the Town of St George (<a href="http://www.seaexpress.bm/" target="_blank">www.seaexpress.bm</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main island has an extensive road network, but foreign visitors may not drive cars in Bermuda. You need to take taxis or use the island's public bus system.</p>
<p>Horse-drawn carriages are available in Hamilton for short rides.</p>l<p>Bermuda's buses are painted with pink and blue stripes. Look for a bus stop with a pink top if you're travelling into Hamilton, or a stop with a blue top if you're heading out of town.</p><p>All taxis are metered with government-set rates, with a 25% surcharge between midnight and 0600, and all day Sunday and public holidays; there is a maximum of four passengers per taxi.</p><p>The speed limit is 35kph (20mph).</p><p>Caution should be taken as many roads are narrow and winding and outside main urban areas, there is also little street lighting.</p>
<p>You can hire scooters (mopeds) throughout the island; a driver's licence is not required for this. Crash helmets must be worn and third party insurance is compulsory. 'Pedal bikes' (bicycles) are also available to hire.</p><p>The speed limit is 35kph (20mph).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bermuda</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">townof_st_george</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bermuda</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">somerset</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bermuda</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">naval_dockyard</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bermuda</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">airport</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bermuda has no national airline. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) operates regular flights to Bermuda from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england/london-gatwick-airport">London Gatwick</a>. American Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aa.com">www.aa.com</a>) flies from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a>.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bermuda/bermuda-international-airport">Bermuda L.F Wade International</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>&nbsp;- 7 hours 45 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 2 hours 10 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bermuda L. F. Wade International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bermudaairport.com<p>Bermuda L. F. Wade International Airport is situated on St David&rsquo;s Island, 5km (3 miles) southwest of St George&rsquo;s and 16km (9 miles) to the northeast of Bermuda's capital city, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hamilton">Hamilton</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 441 293 2470</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The traditional port is the City of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hamilton">Hamilton</a>, the capital, and the most commercial area on the island.</p>
<p>Many ships and private yachts anchor at the Town of St George, where visitors can walk off the vessel into charming narrow lanes with 17th-century buildings and small boutiques.</p>
<p>The West End, Bermuda's third port of call, is becoming trendy; its Royal Naval Dockyard, which was the British Royal Navy's headquarters until 1995, has been beautifully restored as a mini-village.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafes in the Royal Naval Dockyard, City of Hamilton and Town of St George, and connections are provided in most hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The <em>Bermuda Broadcasting Company</em> and <em>VSB</em> are the main broadcasters. Most homes and hotels have access to cable and satellite TV.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most letters will automatically travel by airmail even if surface rates are paid, although paid-for airmail will be given priority. Airmail letters to Europe take five to seven days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700. In addition, the General Post Office in Hamilton is open Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Cruise round the island by ferry</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy a ferry trip round Hamilton Harbour for the best views of the pretty pastel-painted capital. For a longer cruise, take the passenger ferry – it passes through the Great Sound stopping at Somerset Bridge, the rural village of Somerset, and the Royal Naval Dockyard, some of the finest sights on the island.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a picnic and picturesque panoramas at Fort Scaur</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Fort Scaur, a good place to picnic, swim and enjoy the panoramic view of the picturesque Great Sound. Designed so it couldn't be sighted from the sea, the 19th-century fort was built by the British in case of an American attack on the dockyard. Find the weather stone – its forecasts are never wrong.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Fort St Catherine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Fort St Catherine (built in 1614), the largest and most fascinating of the island's fortifications. Perched above the beach in the north west of the island, the stone ramparts and interior are both well preserved. Inside there is a museum dedicated to Bermuda's military history.</p>]]><p><b>Gaze out from Gibbs' Hill Lighthouse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Marvel at the best view of the island from Gibbs' Hill Lighthouse, in Southampton parish, one of the only lighthouses in the world to be made completely from cast iron. With 185 steps to the top, the cafe at the foot of the lighthouse offers the chance to recharge your batteries afterwards.</p>]]><p><b>Go fishing for some wahoo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With grey snapper, barracuda, marlin and wahoo, Bermuda is one of the world's finest fishing centres, especially for light-tackle fishing. Equipment may be rented for shore fishing and there are charter boats for reef and deep-sea expeditions. The best fishing is from May to November.</p>]]><p><b>Guard from invasion at Gates Fort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk to Gates Fort, which dates back to 1620 and is built on a promontory overlooking Town Cut and the sea. Offering a spectacular view of the ocean and harbour, visitors can still see two mounted George III cannons, preparing to defend the channel to the harbour as they were in the 1700s.</p>]]><p><b>Make a wish at the Moongates</b></p><![CDATA[<p>According to oriental legend, honeymooners should make a wish while walking through Moongates. The circles of stone were brought to Bermuda in the 19th century by a sea captain who had seen them on a voyage to China. Unlike those in Chinese gardens, the Moongates at Bermuda are uniquely freestanding.</p>]]><p><b>Open the world's smallest drawbridge, Somerset</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Somerset, on the western end of the island, find the smallest drawbridge in the world, Somerset Bridge. Designed so the yachts with unstayed masts can pass through, the gap is a mere 81cm (32 inches). Captains wishing to sail under must wait for a passer-by to open the timber bridge.</p>]]><p><b>See the best of Bermudan nature at Hamilton Parish</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to Hamilton Parish and investigate the Bermuda Aquarium for its exotic aqua life and try to spot the foureye butterflyfish. There is a Museum and Zoo onsite too. Nearby, the Crystal Caves of Bermuda, made up of sprawling underground systems and crystalline tidal pools, offer the most dramatic views on the island.</p>]]><p><b>Smell the beautiful blooms at the Botanical Gardens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sniff the heavenly scent of Bermuda and see the Double Fantasy flower that inspired John Lennon at the Botanical Gardens in Paget Parish. Walk among the magnolia trees at this impressive 14.5-hectare (36-acre) paradise, the best place to enjoy and identify the island's delightful flora.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the historic Town of St George</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wander the narrow winding lanes of the town of St George, which has UNESCO World Heritage status. Founded in 1612, the garrison town is the earliest English settlement in the New World, its fortifications and landmarks appear much as they did over three centuries ago.</p>]]><p><b>Wander Bermuda's charming capital, Hamilton</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the old charm of Bermuda's capital, Hamilton, taking in The Cabinet Building and the Sessions House. Front Street is Hamilton's main road, which runs along the water's edge, whilst the City Hall and Arts Centre is an architectural gem designed by the delightfully-named Wilfred Onions. For spectacular city views visit the restored 19th-century Fort Hamilton.</p>]]><p><b>Witness the past at the World Heritage Centre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the history of Bermuda's people come to life at the World Heritage Centre, St George. Both light-hearted and enlightening, catch a historical re-enactment while you're there, which includes the dunking of a nagging wench. The centre also runs guided walking tours of the old town.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$5.7 billion (2009).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Semi-tropical produce and light manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Household goods, chemicals, live animals, machinery and transport.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, UK, France, Kazakhstan, Spain and Korea (Rep).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bermuda's economy is dominated by two industries - tourism and international business, including financial, insurance and re-insurance services. Together they account for approximately 90% of GDP, although the contribution from tourism has steadily declined over the years, and now accounts for approximately 30% of GDP.<br /><br />Offshore banking and related services have been the mainstay of the financial sector, although in recent years, insurance has grown to the point where Bermuda is now one of the largest insurance markets in the world. Tax receipts from several thousand offshore companies registered in Bermuda, plus customs duties, go some way to offsetting the island's large annual visible trade deficit of around US$500 million.<br /><br />The small light-manufacturing base in Bermuda is engaged in boat building, ship repair and perfume and pharmaceutical production. There is some agriculture, concentrated in the growing of fruit and vegetables, although most of Bermuda's food is imported along with all its oil, machinery and most manufactured goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits or shirt and tie are acceptable, as are Bermuda shorts, when worn in the appropriate manner. Business cards are usually exchanged. <br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bermuda Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 295 4201
					Website:http://www.bermudacommerce.com
					Address: (PO Box HM 655),1 Point Pleasant Road,Hamilton HMCX,]]><b>Bermuda International Business Association (BIBA)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 292 0632
					Website:http://www.biba.org
					Address: 20 Victoria Street,Cedar House,Ground Floor,Hamilton HM 12,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>There is a vast variety of restaurants, cafes, bars and taverns to suit all pockets. Service will vary, although generally table service can be expected. Hotel cooking is usually international with some Bermudan specialities.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Bermuda lobster (in season from September to mid April). <br />
<em>&bull; Hoppin' John</em> (black-eyed peas and rice). <br />
&bull; Fish chowder infused with sherry, peppers and rum.<br />
&bull; Seafood, including rockfish, red snapper, <em>guinea chick</em> (shiny lobster) and yellowtail. <br />
&bull; Traditional Sunday breakfast is codfish and potatoes, which are served with red sauce, avocado and banana.<br />
&bull; Desserts include sweet potato pudding, bay grape jelly and loquat jam.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>When not included in the bill, 15% is generally acceptable for most services. Hotels and guest houses add a set amount per person in lieu of tips to the bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels offer a variety of entertainment. Dance shows, musical and theatrical performances, cinemas, barbecues and nightclubs are all available. There are also island cruises for entertainment - even the locals attend. African influences can be found in the local dance and music, especially reggae, calypso and the rhythm of the Gombeys' kettledrums. All the latest listings can be found in <em>Preview Bermuda</em> and <em>This Week in Bermuda</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unique local-made items, known as Bermudiana, include handcrafted gold trinkets, cedarwood gifts, perfume inspired by the island's flowers, traditional costumed dolls, rum and artwork. And of course, you can't forget the island's famous Bermuda shorts. Antique shops may have the odd good bargain and shops in the countryside offer many souvenirs. Other good buys are imported merchandise. There is no sales tax or VAT.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1730, with some open later and on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Club resorts are noted for privacy and luxury and are for members or by introduction only. There are club resorts on the main island.<br />Hotels are generally of a high standard. Resort hotels offer a range of facilities and usually have their own beach and pool(s). Hotels offer a choice of meal plans. The Bermuda Department of Tourism provides an online accommodation guide (website: <a href="http://www.bermudatourism.com/" target="_blank">www.bermudatourism.com</a>). Reduced rates are available during the Golf and Spa, or 'low' season, which runs from November to March, and there are many special package tours for special interest holidays. A government tax, called Hotel Occupancy Tax, of 7.25% is added to hotel bills on check-out, and a service or gratuity charge (10-15%) is also added to the final bill. <br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> There is no formal grading system for accommodation. There is a meal plan structure, which grades according to how many meals are included. Smaller hotels are normally less expensive than the resorts, have fewer facilities and are less formal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of these properties are historical homes in lush garden settings, which have been modernised into comfortable guest rooms. Bed & breakfast offers an intimate and traditional setting. Inns offer informal accommodation; most include breakfast; several waterfront units feature swimming pools. Some provide kitchen facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Club resorts are noted for privacy and luxury and are for members or by introduction only. There are club resorts on the main island.<br />Hotels are generally of a high standard. Resort hotels offer a range of facilities and usually have their own beach and pool(s). Hotels offer a choice of meal plans. The Bermuda Department of Tourism provides an online accommodation guide (website: <a href="http://www.bermudatourism.com/" target="_blank">www.bermudatourism.com</a>). Reduced rates are available during the Golf and Spa, or 'low' season, which runs from November to March, and there are many special package tours for special interest holidays. A government tax, called Hotel Occupancy Tax, of 7.25% is added to hotel bills on check-out, and a service or gratuity charge (10-15%) is also added to the final bill. <br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> There is no formal grading system for accommodation. There is a meal plan structure, which grades according to how many meals are included. Smaller hotels are normally less expensive than the resorts, have fewer facilities and are less formal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Club resorts are noted for privacy and luxury and are for members or by introduction only. There are club resorts on the main island.<br />Hotels are generally of a high standard. Resort hotels offer a range of facilities and usually have their own beach and pool(s). Hotels offer a choice of meal plans. The Bermuda Department of Tourism provides an online accommodation guide (website: <a href="http://www.bermudatourism.com/" target="_blank">www.bermudatourism.com</a>). Reduced rates are available during the Golf and Spa, or 'low' season, which runs from November to March, and there are many special package tours for special interest holidays. A government tax, called Hotel Occupancy Tax, of 7.25% is added to hotel bills on check-out, and a service or gratuity charge (10-15%) is also added to the final bill. <br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> There is no formal grading system for accommodation. There is a meal plan structure, which grades according to how many meals are included. Smaller hotels are normally less expensive than the resorts, have fewer facilities and are less formal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is essential as medical costs are very high. The King Edward VII Memorial Hospital, located in Paget Parish (near the city of Hamilton), provides comprehensive medical care to Bermuda residents and overseas visitors.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p/><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations for tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Bermuda Day :
							24 May </p><p>National Heroes Day :
							18 June </p><p>Labour Day :
							03 September </p><p>Remembrance Day :
							11 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Bermuda by persons over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes and 50 cigars and 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits and 1L of wine.<br />
&bull; Other goods to a value of BD$50 (visitors) or BD$200 (residents).<br />
<br />
You may carry prescribed drugs on arrival provided they are for your own personal use, prescribed by your own doctor and in the original pharmacy packaging, bearing the prescription label and containing supplies only sufficient for your length of stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Illegal drugs, offensive weapons, self-defence sprays, stun guns, and indecent or obscene materials.</p>
<p>You must obtain a permit in advance to import firearms and ammunition, live animals and plants, endangered animals and plants, fruit, vegetable and plant products, certain meat and dairy products, and certain radio transmitters.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bermuda Dollar (BMD; symbol BD$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of BD$100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 2. Coins are in denominations of BD$1, and 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.<br /><br />The Bermuda Dollar is at parity with the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollars are generally accepted at parity, although change is almost always given in BD cents. It is illegal to exchange money other than at authorised banks or bureaux de change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard and Visa are accepted at most hotels, shops and restaurants. ATMs are available across the island.</p><p>ATMs are available across the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar cheques are accepted, but they are increasingly difficult to change, with institutions including Butterfield Bank refusing to accept them. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>This ranges between Mon-Fri 0900-1630, with one bank having additional hours of Sat 1000-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above. If you require a visa to travel via Canada, the UK or the USA, your passport must be valid for 45 days beyond the end of your trip. Note that US passport cards are not valid for travel by air to Bermuda.</p>
<p>If travelling via the USA, you may need at least six months' validity on your passport, depending on your nationality; check with your nearest US consulate/embassy.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your stay beyond 21 days, you must apply to the Bermuda Department of Immigration. While not automatic, an extension is usually granted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing your pet, you must apply for an import permit from the Bermuda Department of Environment and Natural Resources (<a href="http://www.gov.bm/importing-animals-bermuda" target="_blank">www.gov.bm/importing-animals-bermuda</a>). Your animal requires a veterinary certificate which should be issued no more than 10 days before arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[32.303030]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-64.752012]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>53 sq km (20 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>65,331 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,324.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hamilton.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parliamentary, self-governing British Overseas Territory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bermuda consists of a chain of some 180 coral islands and islets lying 1,046km (650 miles) off the coast of Cape Hatteras. The seven largest of the islands are linked by bridges and one causeway to form the principal mainland. There are no rivers or streams and the islands are entirely dependent on rainfall for fresh water.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Anglican, Roman Catholic, Seventh Day Adventist and other Christian denominations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many of Bermuda's social conventions are British influenced, and there is a very English feel to the islands. It is quite customary to politely greet people on the street, even if they are strangers. Casual wear is acceptable in most places during the day, but beachwear (including short tops and 'short' shorts) should be confined to the beach. Almost all hotels and restaurants require a smart casual dress in the evenings; check dress requirements in advance. Non-smoking areas will be marked. Drinking alcohol in public outside of a licensed premise is prohibited.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. American (flat) two-pin plugs are standard (with or without round grounding pin).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Premier Edward David Burt since July 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor John Rankin since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bermuda was discovered in 1505 by Spanish mariner Juan de Bermúdez and claimed for the Spanish Empire, although he never actually landed. Shipwrecked Portuguese and other European sailors subsequently left their marks on the land – some kept and released pigs – before the island was claimed in England's name by Sir George Somers in July 1609.</p><p>After colonisation, Bermuda prospered and has continued to do so almost continuously ever since.</p><p>Bermuda is the oldest British colony and there are still elements of British culture and customs in almost every aspect of life on the islands although the tourist industry, which began in Victorian times, caters particularly for the American market.</p><p>In 1949 when Newfoundland became part of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a>, Bermuda became the oldest remaining British Overseas Territory and since 1997, following the transfer of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hong-kong">Hong Kong</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>, it has been the most populous. Established in 1612 its first capital, St George's, is the oldest continuously inhabited English town in the New World.</p><p>In 1968 the island was granted internal self-government with the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> retaining control of defence and foreign policy.</p><p>For many years Bermudan political life was dominated by the United Bermuda Party (UBP), which won a string of election victories from 1964 until 1998, when the Progressive Labour Party displaced it. The PLP held sway until December 2012 when the One Bermuda Alliance (OBA) – formed by a merger of the opposition UBP and Bermuda Democratic Alliance – won the general election. Bermuda's current Premier is the OBA's Michael Dunkley.</p><p>The government's recent agenda has been dominated by three issues: the economy, which relies heavily on financial services and has grown steadily; independence (the most recent plebiscite on the issue took place in August 1995 when a low turnout, produced a vote of 74 per cent against independence and in favour of remaining under British rule); and British citizenship – the British government still has to reach a final decision and it remains the subject of some irritation in the territory.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p> Bermuda was founded by the English Virginia Company, which has established the first permanent English Settlement, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jamestown">Jamestown</a>, in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/virginia">Virginia</a></p><p> The island is the most northerly point of the Bermuda Triangle, an area of sea associated with the mysterious disappearance of a number of aircraft and ships.</p><p> With no corporate income tax Bermuda is a popular location for international businesses seeking to reduce their tax liability.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Diplomatic representation]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bermuda is probably best known for two things: lurid, knee-length shorts and the fabled Bermuda Triangle, a stretch of sea where boats and planes are said to have mysteriously disappeared. However, these lazy stereotypes serve only to distract from what is an exceptionally beautiful destination.</p>
<p>Comprised of around 180 islets, Bermuda looks like your archetypal Caribbean retreat with its fine sandy beaches, colourful coral reefs and swaying palms. But it&rsquo;s nothing of the sort. In fact this lonely archipelago floats 1,030km (640 miles) off the coast of South Carolina, adrift in the Atlantic Ocean, far from anywhere in particular.</p>
<p>A British Overseas Territory, Bermuda has embraced many traditions from the motherland: from sophisticated gents playing cricket to refined ladies supping afternoon tea. There are even red phone boxes.</p>
<p>Discovered by the Spanish in 1505, Bermuda fell into British hands a century later and has remained part of the much-diminished empire ever since. The legendary writer, Mark Twain, popularised the islands in the late 19th century. &ldquo;You go to heaven if you want &ndash; I&rsquo;d rather stay here instead,&rdquo; he cooed. John Lennon was another fan of the archipelago, which was the muse behind his song, Borrowed Time.</p>
<p>For some time Bermuda has been considered a destination for the, shall we say, more mature traveller. And while its scenic golf courses, colonial hotels and genteel vibe do suit elderly travellers, the archipelago has started to attract a younger crowd in recent years. They come for the excellent scuba diving, the cycling and other adventure activities, or just to explore the beauty of the archipelago from the back of a motorbike.</p>
<p>And beautiful it is. Bermuda&rsquo;s coastline is blessed with pink sandy beaches and crystalline waters, while inland visitors will find an abundance of subtropical plants and flowers, interspersed with quaint pastel cottages. There are certainly worse places to disappear.</p>Bermuda is probably best known for two things: lurid, knee-length shorts and the fabled Bermuda Triangle, a stretch of sea where boats and planes are said to have mysteriously disappeared. However, these lazy stereotypes serve only to distract from what is an exceptionally beautiful destination.  

Comprised of around 180 islets, Bermuda looks like your archetypal Caribbean retreat with its fine sandy beaches, colourful coral reefs and swaying palms. But it's nothing of the sort. In fact this lonely archipelago floats 1,030km (640 miles) off the coast of South Carolina, adrift in the Atlantic Ocean, far from anywhere in particular.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
