<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Bhutan" ColCode="btn" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bt" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Bhutan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate varies with altitude, with the highest temperatures and rainfall occurring in the south which bears the brunt of the monsoon between June and September.<br /><br />Temperatures drop dramatically with increases in altitude though days are usually very pleasant with clear skies and sunshine. Nights are cold and require heavy woollen clothing, particularly in winter. Generally, October, November and April to mid June are the best times to visit - rainfall is at a minimum and temperatures are conducive to active days of sightseeing. The foothills are also very pleasant during the winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons in the foothills, also linens and waterproof gear, light sweaters and jackets for the evenings. Upland areas: thick, warm clothing for evenings, particularly during the winter months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Domestic flights between Paro and Bumthang run intermittently.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>The country has a fairly good internal road network with well over 3,000km (1,800 miles) of surfaced road.&nbsp;The average speed is less than 40kph (25mph).</p>
<p>The main routes run north from Phuentsholing to the western regions of Paro and Thimphu, and west-east, across the Pele La Pass and Thrumshing La Pass to the central valleys and eastern regions.&nbsp;The northern regions of the High Himalayas have no roads.</p>
<p>Tour operators arrange all internal travel for tourists, which is usually by road.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bhutan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">punakha</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bhutan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">paro</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bhutan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">prsquosholing</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bhutan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bumthang</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drukair&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.drukair.com.bt/" target="_blank">www.drukair.com.bt</a>) and Bhutan Airlines&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.bhutanairlines.bt" target="_blank">www.bhutanairlines.bt</a>) are the only airlines flying into Bhutan. Between them, they run flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangkok">Bangkok</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/delhi">Delhi</a>, Kolkata, Bagdogra, Bodh Gaya, Dhaka, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kathmandu">Kathmandu</a>, Guwahati, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mumbai-bombay">Mumbai</a>.&nbsp;The Kathmandu-Paro flight has fabulous views of the Himalaya on the left-hand side.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Paro Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bhutan">Bhutan</a>'s only airport, is located in a deep valley, some 2,190m (7,200ft) above sea level, surrounded by hills and high mountains.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The nearest railhead is Siliguri (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only land borders open to tourists are Phuentsholing, Gelephu and Samdrup Jongkhar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The telephone service is reasonable though getting a line can be slow at times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage is extensive but since the mobile network is now superseding the landline service, oversubscription can lead to problems.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Access is growing. There are Internet cafes in large towns and access in major hotels across the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fears of outside influences undermining the country's monarchy, freedom and culture meant that for years Bhutan had a deliberate policy of isolation, including a ban on television. The state-run <em>Bhutan Broadcasting Service</em> <em>(</em><em>BBS</em><em>)</em> launched the first TV service as part of celebrations surrounding King Jigme Singye Wangchuk's silver jubilee in 1999. Radio broadcasting began in 1973 and the first Internet service was introduced in 1999. There are no private broadcasters, but cable television is thriving though 'undesirable and irrelevant channels' have been filtered out.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mail from Bhutan is liable to disruption because of the high value of Bhutanese stamps; they may be steamed off the envelopes en route.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700, Sat 0900-1200 (summer); Mon-Fri 0900-1600, Sat 0900-1200 (winter).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Attend an archery competition</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Archery is a national obsession in Bhutan, and archery competitions are held across the country, with huge crowds admiring, and betting on, the skill of local archers. Traditionally, the Bhutanese used handmade bamboo bows, but these days, high-tech carbon fibre bows are all the rage. Archery competitions are major social events in Bhutan, alcohol flowing freely.</p>]]><p><b>Be beguiled by Bumthang</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Trongsa is the gateway to beautiful Bumthang, where four sacred valleys hide a string of ancient monasteries and captivating country towns. Most visitors head for Jakar, the most substantial settlement, and then roam along the scenic Chokhor Valley, visiting ancient chapels and chortens set amidst sublime mountain scenery.</p>]]><p><b>Be captivated by the colours of Punakha</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Straddling the confluence of the Mo and Pho Rivers, Punakha Dzong was the second Buddhist monastery to be built in Bhutan, founded by the father of the nation, Ngawang Namgyal. Set against a backdrop of trickling water, the fortress is particularly atmospheric in spring, when jacaranda trees burst into pale purple flowers along the riverbanks.</p>]]><p><b>Climb a pass for epic Himalayan views</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travelling from one valley to the next in Bhutan involves climbing over breathless mountain passes, and all offer spectacular views. Crowned by 108 memorial chortens, the 3,100m (10,171ft) Dochu La, between Thimphu and Punakha, offers a breath-taking vista of the eastern Himalaya, while the 3,810m (12,500ft) Cheli La near Paro, is the highest motorable pass in the country.</p>]]><p><b>Explore historic Thimphu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set in a broad valley in the west of the country, Thimphu is Bhutan's only proper city, but the modern and medieval world come together with surprising harmony.  The Bhutanese capital is awash with historic sights: essential stops include the mighty <em>dzong</em> (fortress monastery) of Tashi Chho, Thimphu's bustling weekend market and the towering statue of Buddha that rises above the city.</p>]]><p><b>Heed the calming call of Tashi Yangtse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travellers who roam to the remote valleys of Trashi Yangtse leave the crowds far behind. In this serene part of the world, women spin on the doorsteps and mountain streams burble beside rice fields and ancient chortens. The gateway to this tranquil Shangri La is Tashi Yangtse, the leaping off point for hikes to nature reserves, mountain monasteries and paper workshops.</p>]]><p><b>Scramble up to Drametse Goemba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The views are spectacular as you drive up a rough, vertiginous dirt track to Drametse Goemba. This is the most important monastery in the east of the country, and its chapels are full of memorial chortens, gold Buddha images and curiosities gathered by the monks over the centuries. A massive <em>thondrol</em> (giant thangka painting) is unfurled here every November.</p>]]><p><b>See rare birds in pristine forests</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The mountain valleys and jungle-cloaked hills of Bhutan are home to more than 600 species of birds, including rare black-necked cranes, which winter in the Phobjikha and Bumdeling valleys. Specialist tour operators offer birding tours to sanctuaries across the country, particularly during the crane season from October to February.</p>]]><p><b>See the institutions that drive the world’s happiest state</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Thimphu is the administrative and religious capital of Bhutan, and the focal point of both enterprises is Tashi Chho Dzong, home to the government ministries, the king's throne room and the largest monastery in the country. The monumental monastery is presided over by the Je Khenpo, the chief abbot of Bhutan, and home to over 1,600 monks.</p>]]><p><b>Take in a tsechu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bhutan's Buddhist festivals are some of the most colourful celebrations on Earth. All of the nation's <em>dzongs</em> and <em>goembas </em>(monasteries) host <em>tsechus </em>– animated dance festivals, where monks don rainbow-coloured costumes and fearsome monster masks and dance to the tune of horns, drums and gongs. It's a vital, invigorating introduction to the customs and legends of Bhutanese Buddhism.</p>]]><p><b>Trace royal history at Tongsa Dzong</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many visitors stay close to Paro and Thimphu, but it's worth roaming further afield to Trongsa in central Bhutan, where the nation's largest monastery creates an impressive profile against the surrounding hills. This is the ancestral home of the Royal Family, with nearly two dozen separate chapels and a fascinating museum housed in the watchtower on the hillside above.</p>]]><p><b>Trek into the Bhutanese Himalaya</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There's no better way to experience Bhutan's stunning mountain scenery than to see it as the locals do, on foot, on the walking trails that criss-cross the hills and peaks. The high altitude Snowman Trek (25 days) is the most famous route, but most people opt for shorter, less costly walks, that still offer captivating cultural interactions and magnificent mountain views.</p>]]><p><b>Trek to Taktsang (Tiger's Nest) Goemba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The trek to Taktsang (Tiger's Nest) Goemba tops the list of things to do in Bhutan. This revered monastery clings dizzily to the face of a 900m (2,952ft) precipice in the Paro Valley. According to legend, Guru Rinpoche flew to this site on a magical tiger and meditated in a cave before continuing his journey to spread Buddhism across the Himalaya.</p>]]><p><b>Wander Paro’s monasteries and museums</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Paro is the main port of arrival for most visitors, and a typical bustling Bhutanese country town. Paro Dzong is one of the nation's finest monuments, and the National Museum provides a handy introduction to the culture and history of Bhutan, before you head into the hills to explore more monasteries, ruins and ancient temples.</p>]]><p><b>Wangdue Phodrang</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Right in the centre of Bhutan, Wangdue Phodrang is famous for its castle-like <em>dzong</em>, built in the 17th century atop a curving ridge at the confluence of two rivers. The district is known for its slate carving and bamboo weaving, and for many centuries, this was the seat of one of Bhutan's most powerful <em>dzongpens </em>(regional governors).</p>]]><p><b>Watch ancient arts come to life in Thimphu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The weekend market in Thimphu is crammed with vendors selling Bhutanese handicrafts – delicately embroidered shawls, <em>thangka </em>paintings, fearsome Buddhist masks, rolls of prayer flags – and you can see the artisans at work in the National Institute of Zorig Chusum campuses in Thimphu or Trashi Yangtse. This government enterprise was founded to preserve ancient arts such as embroidery and thangka painting.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$1.3 billion (2007).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Electric power generation and transmission, essential oils and handicrafts.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fuel and lubricants, machinery and parts, vehicles, fabrics and grain.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>India.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost all the working population is involved in agriculture. The economy is therefore mainly one of subsistence. The main products are cereals and wood, though logging is strictly controlled as 60% of the land area is protected forest. There is some small-scale industry, mostly textiles, handicrafts and carpets. <br /><br />Recent economic policy has concentrated on export industries, of which electric power generation and transmission is the major earner. Tourism and stamps are major sources of foreign exchange. Gross National Happiness, which measures the population's physical, emotional and spiritual well-being to help assess the country's 'wealth', is an official part of the constitution.<br /><br />Bhutan is hoping to join the World Trade Organisation in 2009 and is a member of the South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation, which seeks to improve the region's economic and commercial links. The country receives substantial aid from India.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suit or a shirt and tie for the south. In the capital, a full business suit and tie are recommended. The best time to visit for business is October and November.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>BTCL</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Bhutan Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 322 742 ,324 254
					Website:http://www.bcci.org.bt/
					Address: Doebum Lam,PO Box 147,Thimphu,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Bhutanese food is simple and rustic, based on the limited ingredients that can be grown in the challenging environment of the Himalayas. The core of Bhutanese cooking is rice &ndash; both white rice and red rice (<em>eue chum</em>), a nutty-flavoured variety grown for centuries in the Bhutanese hills &ndash; but many farmers also raise buckwheat and maize. Chilli arrived by way of India and China, and it adds punch to many Bhutanese dishes.</p>
<p>Chicken, eggs and dried yak meat are popular sources of protein, as is <em>datshi</em>, traditional unpasteurised cheese made from cows&rsquo; milk, which is melted into soups and stews. Tibetan staples such as momos &ndash; wheat-flour dumplings stuffed with pork, beef, vegetables or cheese &ndash; are commonplace, and many dishes feature apples, asparagus and wild mushrooms from the hills. Tibetan-style tea with salt and butter is sipped everywhere in Bhutan.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Datshi</strong>: Cow's milk cheese, often served in a spicy stew with red chillies (<em>ema datshi</em>).<br />
<strong>Tshoem: </strong>A spicy curry made with beef and mushrooms.<br />
<strong>Eue chum: </strong>Bhutanese red rice, a nutty-flavoured variety unique to Bhutan.<br />
<strong>Phaksha Paa: </strong>Pork cooked with fiery red chillies.<br />
<strong>Sha Kam: </strong>Dried beef, often served in a spicy stew with red chillies, radishes and tomato.<br />
<strong>Hoentoe: </strong>Buckwheat dumplings from Haa, stuffed with turnip leaves, chilli and cheese.<br />
<strong>Jasha Maru</strong>: Spicy minced chicken with garlic, ginger, tomatoes and green chilli.<br />
<strong>Goep: </strong>Tripe, often stewed with chilli.<br />
<strong>Ara:</strong> A rough spirit distilled from fermented rice.<br />
<strong>Chang</strong>: Local beer, cereal-based and generally home-brewed.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Meals are often buffet-style and mostly vegetarian. Meat and fish are now imported from nearby India, and Nepali Hindus living in Bhutan are licensed to slaughter animals. Usual precautions apply.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Not widely practised by locals. Your guides will expect a tip at the end of your trip and US$5-10 per person per day is appropriate.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Markets are held regularly, generally on Saturday and Sunday, and are a rich source of local clothing and jewellery, as well as food. The Handicraft Emporium on the main street in the capital is open daily and offers a magnificent assortment of hand-woven and handcrafted goods. Some hotels have a souvenir shop. Silversmiths and goldsmiths in the Thimphu Valley are able to make handcrafted articles to order. Bhutanese stamps are collectors' items. Shopping is otherwise limited and bargaining is not customary. Phuentsholing has a small department store, the only one of its kind in Bhutan.</p><p>Mon-Sun 0800-2000 for most shops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional hotels, cottages and guest houses approved by the Department of Tourism are usually comfortable with hot and cold running water, electricity and sometimes room telephones though international calls may be via reception. There are a few luxury hotels but these do not come cheap. Accommodation is booked by Tour Operators. Expect a surcharge on the basic rate for upmarket resorts and be aware that at festival time, hotels are booked long in advance so you may need to be flexible. Tourists incorporating a trek in their itinerary may camp. For further information, contact the BTCL (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional hotels, cottages and guest houses approved by the Department of Tourism are usually comfortable with hot and cold running water, electricity and sometimes room telephones though international calls may be via reception. There are a few luxury hotels but these do not come cheap. Accommodation is booked by Tour Operators. Expect a surcharge on the basic rate for upmarket resorts and be aware that at festival time, hotels are booked long in advance so you may need to be flexible. Tourists incorporating a trek in their itinerary may camp. For further information, contact the BTCL (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional hotels, cottages and guest houses approved by the Department of Tourism are usually comfortable with hot and cold running water, electricity and sometimes room telephones though international calls may be via reception. There are a few luxury hotels but these do not come cheap. Accommodation is booked by Tour Operators. Expect a surcharge on the basic rate for upmarket resorts and be aware that at festival time, hotels are booked long in advance so you may need to be flexible. Tourists incorporating a trek in their itinerary may camp. For further information, contact the BTCL (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Full medical insurance is strongly advised. Medical facilities are good but not always close at hand. Officials in Bhutan have reported repeated outbreaks of bird flu during 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Mineral water is widely available. Milk should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis E occurs; hepatitis B is endemic. Giardiasis is common. Meningitis is a sporadic risk and vaccination is advised. Tuberculosis exists. There is a small risk of Japanese encephalitis in southern lowland areas. Altitude sickness may be a problem. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Buddhist festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Birthday of His Majesty the 5th King :
							21 February </p><p>Birthday of the Third Druk Gyalpo :
							02 May </p><p>Birthday of Guru Rinpoche :
							10 July <b>Date to be confirmed </b>yes
							</p><p>Coronation of the Fifth Druk Gyalpo :
							01 November </p><p>Birthday of the Fourth Druk Gyalpo :
							11 November </p><p>National Day :
							17 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Bhutan by tourists without incurring duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 1L of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; Personal effects.</p>
<p>The sale of tobacco is banned in Bhutan. Tourists can import 200 cigarettes or three 50g tins of tobacco for personal consumption, but these are subject to 100% tax.</p>
<p>The following goods may be imported by Bhutanese residents without incurring duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 2 bottles of alcoholic beverages of up to 2L each.<br />
&bull; 50g of gold.<br />
&bull; 1kg of silver.<br />
&bull; 60ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; 10 items of each type of clothing.</p>
<p>The total value of the above items must not exceed US$1,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include narcotics, pornography and antiques.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include arms and ammunition, drugs and pharmaceutical products, used and secondhand goods and equipment, gold and silver in excess of baggage allowance, live animals and their products, plants and chemicals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited exports include narcotics, pornography and antiques.</p>
<p>Restricted exports include arms and ammunition, drugs and pharmaceutical products, used and secondhand goods and equipment, gold and silver in excess of baggage allowance, live animals and their products, plants, chemicals and telecommunications equipment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1 Ngultrum (BTN; symbol Nu) = 100 chetrum (Ch). The Ngultrum is pegged to the Indian Rupee (which is also acccepted as legal tender). Notes are in denominations of Nu500, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of Nu1, and  50, 25 and 20 chetrum. Smaller denomination notes and coins have been discontinued but are still in circulation and are legal tender. US Dollars are also widely accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Leading foreign currencies are accepted but traveller's cheques are preferred and receive a better exchange rate. Major hotels in Thimphu, Paro and Phuentsholing will also exchange foreign currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most cards have limited acceptability. ATMs only accept Bhutanese bank cards.</p><p>ATMs only accept Bhutanese bank cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These can be exchanged in any branch of the Bank of Bhutan or at all BTCL hotels. Travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1500, Sat 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>
<p>It's worth noting that the Bhutan government has been know to refuse entry to those wishing to visit for mountaineering, publicity and other research activities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist: US$40. Tour operators build this into the cost of your trip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas for Bhutan are initially granted for the duration of your arranged trip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Apply through your tour operator.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are usually processed within 72 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[27.416980]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[90.434981]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>38,364 per sq km (14,812 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>784,103 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>19.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Thimphu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bhutan is located in the eastern Himalayas, bordered to the north by China and to the south, east and west by India. The altitude varies from 180m (590ft) in the narrow lowland region to over 7,300m (23,950ft) in the Himalayan plateau in the north, and there are three distinct climatic regions. The foothills are tropical and home to deer, tigers, leopards and the rare golden langur monkey as well as much tropical vegetation, including many species of wild orchids. The Inner Himalaya region is temperate; wildlife includes bear, boar and sambar, and the area is rich in deciduous forests. The High Himalaya region is very thinly populated, but the steep mountain slopes are the home of many species of animals, including snow leopards and blue sheep.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Tantric form of Mahayana Buddhism (<em>Drukpa Kagyu</em>) is the state religion; the majority of Bhutanese people follow the Drukpa school of the Kagyupa sect. Those living in the south are mainly Hindu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The lifestyle, manners and customs of the Bhutanese are in many respects unique to the area. The strongest influence on social conventions is the country's state religion, and everywhere one can see the reminders of Buddhism and the original religion of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tibet">Tibet</a>, Bonism. There are no rigid clan systems and equal rights exist between men and women. The majority of the Bhutanese live an agrarian lifestyle.<br /><br />In 1989, it was made compulsory for citizens to wear national dress and failure to comply at official functions or in government buildings incurs a fine; the men wear a <em>gho</em>, a robe resembling a dressing gown with upturned white cuffs and knee-high socks, whilst the women wear a <em>kira</em>, a sari-like garment that is furnished with ornate brooches, and worn over a blouse. Bhutan has outlawed the sale of tobacco products, and also banned smoking in public places. Healthcare and education are free. The political leaders of the country have also been religious leaders historically.<br /><br />For years the country has deliberately isolated itself from visitors, a policy which is now to some extent being reversed. But Bhutan continues to bear the hallmarks of seemingly peculiar customs borne from legacy and legend. Giant phalluses can often be seen painted onto walls, etc, in order to ward off evil spirits and ensure good crops and healthy children. Climbing some of the Himalayan peaks is banned due to the belief that the mountains are the repository of the gods and all life, animal or plant, is treated with respect as a divine gift.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with two or three round pins are most common.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister&nbsp;Lotay Tshering since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Jigme Khesar Namgyel Wangchuck since 2006.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The ancient history of Bhutan is shrouded in mystery, as few records survive, but early Tibetan manuscripts talk of states called Monyul and Lhomon in the area now covered by Bhutan. The Buddhist history of Bhutan is known with more certainty as a written history was maintained after Mahayana Buddhism was introduced into the country in the 7th century by the Tibetan king Songtsen Gampo.</p>
<p>Widespread conversion to Buddhism followed some time after. According to local legend, the Indian ascetic Guru Rinpoche (Padmasambhava) converted the Bhutanese people after subduing eight classes of demons and converting the local king. For the next thousand years, Bhutan existed as a series of rival monarchies in separate mountain valleys.</p>
<p>Bhutan first became a coherent political entity around the 17th century as Tibetan lamas established a centralised administrative and political structure over the area. Bhutan was officially unified under Ngawang Namgyal, who subdued rival Buddhist sects and founded the first of Bhutan&rsquo;s <em>dzongs </em>(fortress monasteries).</p>
<p>Amazingly, Namgyal&rsquo;s death in 1651 was kept secret for 54 years to prevent the kingdom from fragmenting. His heirs ruled Bhutan until the 18th century, when the British Empire started nibbling away at its southern borders, seizing Bhutanese territory and imposing tithes on the Bhutanese rulers.</p>
<p>In 1907, the Tibetan diarchal system, with power split between equal political and spiritual leaders, was abandoned and a hereditary monarchy was established, with Ugyen Wangchuck elected as the first Druk Gyalpo (Dragon King). His successors introduced some elements of modern government, but it was only when Jigme Dorji came to power in 1952 that Bhutan modernised in any meaningful way.</p>
<p>Tourism to Bhutan began in 1974, after the Bhutanese government agreed to open its formerly restricted territory to outside visitors. In 1991, Bhutan&rsquo;s policy of a daily tourist fee was introduced, allowing visits only on organised trips arranged through local agencies, to protect Bhutan&rsquo;s traditional culture from outside influences.</p>
<p>Bhutan is still nominally a monarchy, governed by the 5th Druk Gyalpo, Jigme Khesar Namgyel Wangchuck, but an elected parliament makes most decisions. The move to democracy was not without problems, and many refugees fled to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nepal">Nepal</a> in the 1990s, where they continue to live in a legal limbo. Bhutan has also become entangled in conflicts between Assamese and Bodo separatist guerrillas and the government of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know? </strong><br />
&bull;	Rather than measuring prosperity in GDP (Gross Domestic Profit), Bhutan measures prosperity by the happiness of its people, or GDH (Gross Domestic Happiness). <br />
&bull;	The Bhutan constitution requires 60% of the country to remain under forest cover. <br />
&bull;	Bhutan was the first country in the world to recognise the rights of the environment in its constitution.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Royal Bhutanese Embassy in India]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(11) 2688 9230 or 9809.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(11) 2688 9230 or 9809.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Chanakyapuri<br/>Chandragupta Marg<br/>New Delhi 110 021<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Closed to the outside world until the seventies, Bhutan may have opened the door to tourism, but it remains something of an enigma to modern travellers. <br /><br />Nestling high up in the Himalayas, Bhutan's mysterious reputation is thanks largely to the government, which requires all visitors to join pre-planned guided tours in a bid to limit the impact of tourism on the country's culture and environment. <br /><br />On one level, this is restrictive; footloose, freewheeling, make-it-up-as-you-go trips are not an option here. The trade-off, however, is that these restrictions have preserved one of the most fascinating cultures on earth, in a pristine mountain environment that has changed little over the centuries. <br /><br />To visit Bhutan every visitor, whether alone or in a group, must make all their travel arrangements through a Bhutanese tour operator, or associated organisation, and pay a fixed daily fee of US$200-250. However, before you baulk, this fee includes all meals, accommodation, transport and guides. <br /><br />Having made this investment, travellers are then free to explore this mesmerising mountain kingdom, known to its people as Druk Yul, or "Land of the Thunder Dragon." <br /><br />Some tour the ancient dzongs (fortress monasteries) in the valleys surrounding the capital, Thimphu. Others seek out snow leopards and yetis – known here as migyur – in remote national parks. Those with the stamina and budget take on the legendary Snowman Trek, a 24-day odyssey over high Himalayan passes.<br /><br />Wherever they go, visitors will encounter exquisite scenery and the famously friendly Bhutanese people, who, though fascinated by foreigners, remain in touch with the value, and values, of their traditional way of life. <br /><br />By subscribing to a "high value, low impact" brand of tourism, Bhutan has made concessions to the modern world, but on its own terms. And that seems to be working for this magical kingdom, which regularly polls as the happiest place in Asia.</p>Closed to the outside world until the seventies, Bhutan may have opened the door to tourism, but it remains something of an enigma to modern travellers. 

Nestling high up in the Himalayas, Bhutan's mysterious reputation is thanks largely to the government, which requires all visitors to join pre-planned guided tours in a bid to limit the impact of tourism on the country's culture and environment. 

On one level, this is restrictive; footloose, freewheeling, make-it-up-as-you-go trips are not an option here. The trade-off, however, is that these restrictions have preserved one of the most fascinating cultures on earth, in a pristine mountain environment that has changed little over the centuries.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
