<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Bolivia" ColCode="bol" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bo" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Bolivia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bolivia has a temperate climate but temperatures can differ dramatically between day and night. The wettest period is November to March, which, in extreme circumstances, may induce landslides in mountainous areas, and cause certain roads to become impassable. The northeast slopes of the Andes are semi-tropical. During the wet season the salt flats become flooded &ndash; it is a beautiful spectacle, as the flats turn into a mirror of the sky above. Winter is perhaps the best time to visit (May-October), especially in the hot and humid lowlands, as it is cooler and drier. In the highlands, it rains much less, remains sunny through the day but gets noticeably colder at night. Visitors sometimes find the highlands (especially La Paz) uncomfortable because of the thin air due to high altitude. The mountain areas can become very cold at night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In terms of clothing, lightweight, natural fabrics and waterproofs are best. Layering is a good idea if taking the tour of the salt flats – it's extremely cold at night and early mornings, but when the sun comes out it warms up quickly. Warmer clothing is necessary at night in the Altiplano, especially in La Paz, Oruro and Potosí. If you need warm clothing, the markets of La Paz and Sucre are a good place to find alpaca wool jumpers and scarves.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internal flights are operated by Boliviana de Aviaci&oacute;n (<a href="http://www.boa.bo/" target="_blank">www.boa.bo</a>). Flights to the Amazon are largely operated by Amaszonas (<a href="http://www.amaszonas.com/" target="_blank">www.amaszonas.com</a>) from La Paz, Cochabamba and Santa Cruz. Because of the country's topography and tropical regions, air travel is the fastest, but not cheapest method of transport, although delays, cancellations and unreliability are common.</p>
<p>La Paz (El Alto), which is the highest airport in the world, and Santa Cruz (Viru Viru) are the principal domestic air hubs. You should book busier routes a few days in advance, and it is important to reconfirm the day before departure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Double-decker passenger boats operate between the various small islands on Lake Titicaca with regular departures from Copacabana to the Isla del Sol. Motorised canoes traverse the many rivers of the Amazon basin with the most regular departures from Rurrenabaque.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bolivia has two separate and unconnected networks - Eastern and Western. The Eastern network's hub is Santa Cruz, from where Ferroviaria Oriental (<a href="http://www.fo.com.bo" target="_blank">www.fo.com.bo</a>) runs trains to the Brazilian borders. The Western line, running from Oruro via Uyuni and Tupiza to Villaz&oacute;n (where you can connect to trains to Argentina) is run by Ferroviaria Andina (<a href="http://www.fca.com.bo/" target="_blank">www.fca.com.bo</a>).</p>
<p>Trains have three to four classes and restaurant cars. Buy tickets in advance from the offices in Santa Cruz and La Paz respectively. There&rsquo;s also a slow but scenic route between Sucre and Potos&iacute;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bolivia&rsquo;s size, geography and lack of basic infrastructure means that travel by road can often be a tumultuous, long and scary ride, yet it is still the first choice mode of transport for travellers and Bolivians alike.</p>r<p>Most major roads are paved but in bad condition. Vehicles often have to take unpaved, dirt tracks.</p><p>Taxis can usually be found anywhere and at anytime in Bolivia, and are the safest mode of transport. Many people work as part-time taxi drivers in cities to supplement their income. Fares tend to be fixed, rarely over Bs15. Tipping is not necessary. In the lowlands moto-taxis are commonly used, while micros (small minibuses) are the main form of urban transport in big cities.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>The national speed limit is 80kph (50mph). The use of seat belts is not enforced, nor is the use of mobile phones prohibited. Vehicles drive on the right-hand side, though this rule is overlooked on some mountain roads when turning &ndash; the vehicle going uphill has priority.</p><p>Breakdown and petrol services on Bolivia&rsquo;s roads are scarce. Fill your tank whenever possible.</p><p>Few travellers rent cars. Virtually no international car hire services are available, but there are local companies in all the major cities.</p><p>Biking is rare in Bolivia. For proper touring you need to bring a bike suitable for mountainous terrain. The country is home to some of the world&rsquo;s best downhill mountain tracks, notably 'Death Road' outside La Paz.</p><p>The national speed limit is 80kph (50mph). The use of seat belts is not enforced, nor is the use of mobile phones prohibited. Vehicles drive on the right-hand side, though this rule is overlooked on some mountain roads when turning &ndash; the vehicle going uphill has priority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taxis are generally the safest mode of transport in Bolivian towns and cities. They are cheap and available anytime. In some cities, fixed-route minibuses, otherwise known as <em>colectivos</em> or <em>trufis</em> are commonly used: there&rsquo;s usually somebody shouting out the route through a window. In rural areas, catching a truck is a cheap but rough form of transport, and moto-taxis are common in the lowlands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bolivia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">uyuni</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">12.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bolivia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sucre</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">16.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bolivia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">santa_cruz</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">24.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bolivia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cochabamba</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>) offers flights to Bolivia direct from Miami, while Air Europa (<a href="http://www.aireuropa.com" target="_blank">www.aireuropa.com</a>) flies from Madrid. There are no direct flights from the UK. The most expensive time to fly is during the high season (July-August, Christmas and Easter). Fares drop during the shoulder seasons (May-June and September-October) and even more during low season (January-April and November-December).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/el-alto-international-airport-la-paz">El Alto International Airport (La Paz)</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 15 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/madrid">Madrid</a> - 11 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 12 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a> - 6 hours 40 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The cost of flights to Bolivia reflects the lack of services and remains comparatively high to other routes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tax on international departures is US$25 to be paid in Bolivianos or US Dollars at a separate kiosk after checking in.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The cost of flights to Bolivia reflects the lack of services and remains comparatively high to other routes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Santa Cruz Viru Viru International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport (Viru Viru International) is 16km (10 miles) from the centre of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/santa-cruz-cruise">Santa Cruz</a> and is the largest airport in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bolivia">Bolivia</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>El Alto International Airport (La Paz)</b><![CDATA[http://www.sabsa.aero<p>The airport is located at Al Alto about 13km (8 miles) southwest of central La Paz.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(2) 215 7300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bolivia is a landlocked country. However, there are several regions &ndash; particularly Lake Titicaca and the Amazon &ndash; where water is the best form of transport. Steamers cross Lake Titicaca to the Peruvian port of Puno from Guaqui, the most important port on the lake. Situated 90km (56 miles) from La Paz, it is accessible by road but the journey is a rough one.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are rail connections from Oruro, through the Altiplano via Uyuni and Tupiza to La Quiaca/Villaz&oacute;n on the Argentinean border. These are all operated by Ferrocaril Andino (<a href="http://www.fca.com.bo" target="_blank">www.fca.com.bo</a>).</p>
<p>The other company, Ferroviaria Oriental (<a href="http://www.fo.com.bo" target="_blank">www.fo.com.bo</a>) runs services between Santa Cruz to Quijarro (Brazilian border) and to Yacuiba (Argentinean border).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can enter Bolivia by land on buses from all five neighbouring countries &ndash; Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Paraguay and Peru. The easiest and most widely used route through Peru is from Puno via the Kasani border. The main crossover in Brazil is at Quijarro &ndash; from here you can travel to Santa Cruz by train.</p>
<p>In Chile, there are three routes: via Tambo Quemado, Calama and the Laguna Verde (where you can plan a jeep trip to the Salar de Uyuni). The Argentinean crossing is at La Quiaca to Villaz&oacute;n or Pocitos. The Paraguayan crossing from Asunci&oacute;n to Santa Cruz is a long journey (approximately 24 hours).</p><p>Luggage is usually stored above or below the coach; the better companies offer a ticket service to retrieve luggage. Keep your hand luggage safe, especially on night buses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>ENTEL, Bolivia's national telephone company has offices in most towns and cities where you can make national and international calls. Local calls are cheap while long-distance are relatively expensive. You can also use a phone card to call home, which can be bought at street stalls, ENTEL offices and shops. Calls to the USA and Europe cost around Bs1 per minute on the cards. You can also use a coin-operated phone box for local calls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a limited number of international mobile phone companies; travellers are advised to check with their mobile phone service provider. Local pay-as-you-go chips are freely available for unlocked phones from companies such as Viva, Tigo and ENTEL. They cost around Bs15 (which you get in credit). Coverage is average.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafés are available in most towns and cities. They charge around 3 to 5 bolivianos per hour. Don't expect the same speed as at home: in many places it is still dial-up. Some internet cafés will also offer net phone or Skype services. Hotels, hostels and cafés may also offer free Wi-Fi access.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Media ownership is highly concentrated. Bolivia's media is dominated by privately run press and broadcasting outlets. Freedom of the press is upheld and self-censorship is usually exercised when dealing with reports of social unrest and political machinations, but attacks on journalists do still occur. Low literacy levels impede upon newspaper readership; radio tends to have precedence and remains the most democratic of media resources in the country. Try Radio Cadena Nacional (RCN), the major national radio station.</p>
<p>The main daily papers published in La Paz are <em>El Diario</em> and <em>La Prensa</em> &ndash; the latter has good foreign coverage. Santa Cruz dailies include <em>El Deber </em>and <em>El Mundo, </em>but these have an extremely regional focus. In Cochabamba, <em>Los Tiempos </em>is particularly good. International press is hard to find, although <em>The Economist, Time </em>and<em> Newsweek </em>can be found in city centres and at international hotels.</p>
<p>Many households in Bolivia do not own a television set. There are seven state channels and other terrestrial channels offering news, popular telenovelas and sport. Big hotels in cities will offer cable with international channels including BBC World and CNN.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe and the USA takes between one and two weeks to arrive, the rest of the world takes longer. Letters cost around Bs10-15. Parcels up to 2kg cost around Bs100 per kilo. You can send letters certified which is more reliable, and there are international courier services such as FedEx and DHL in major cities. Most main post offices offer a <em>poste restante</em> service by which you can receive mail.</p><p>Opening hours are generally Mon-Fri, 0830-2000, Sat 0830-1800, Sun 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Lake Titicaca</p><![CDATA[<p>Take a cruise on Lake Titicaca, the biggest high-altitude body of water in the world, which straddles the Bolivia-Peru border. The enormous azure freshwater lake is home to several small island communities, including the Uros islands made entirely from reeds and Isla del Sol with ancient Inca ruins.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be dazzled by the Salar de Uyuni</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel around the Salar de Uyuni, a high-altitude salt lake, and marvel at its multi-coloured wonders. There's Laguna Colorado, whose fiery red waters harbour pink flamingos, and the stunning Laguna Verde, whose turquoise waters reflect the silhouette of ashen volcanoes. Explore the shimmering lunar landscape on a 4x4 safari and stay overnight in a gleaming salt hotel.</p>]]><p><b>Climb the Cordillera Real</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its ice-capped peaks, condors and hawks, the Cordillera Real is an Andean highlight. You might even catch a glimpse of the spectacled bear; South America's only bear species. The mountain range has six peaks above 6,000m (20,000ft) and many more over 5000m (16,000ft). Climbing excursions (complete with mules, porters and guides) can be booked in Sorata, an Alpine-style village.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise over Lake Titicaca</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The largest high-altitude body of water in the world, Lake Titicaca straddles the Bolivia-Peru border. The enormous freshwater lake is home to several small island communities, including the floating Uros islands made entirely from reeds, and the sacred Isla del Sol with ancient Inca ruins. You can take boat cruises from Copacabana, or stay overnight on the Isla del Sol.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the garden city of Cochabamba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its year-round spring climate, the openness of the locals and its excellent local cuisine, Cochabamba is often hailed as the most welcoming city in Bolivia. For a bird's eye view, climb the 2,000 steps, or take the cable car, up to the imposing statue of Christ on Cerro San Pedro; explore the rambling street markets and sample some local maize beer.</p>]]><p><b>Float down the Amazon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Bolivian Amazon offers safari boat trips, eco lodges and nature trails. Setting out by boat from Rurrenabaque, linked by flights from La Paz, you can choose from a range of tours available to the Parque Nacional Madidi and the Pampas del Yacuma. Typical jungle trips include motorised canoe trips where you can see pink dolphins, guided rainforest walks and rustic accommodation.</p>]]><p><b>Follow in Che Guevara’s final footsteps</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Vallegrande, a quiet market town, was the resting place of Che Guevara. The town's Museo Municipal Ruta del Che Guevara displays photographs of the iconic guerrilla and his comrades; you can also visit various other Che sites, including the hospital where his body was put on display. Die-hard fans take the three-hour trip to La Higuera, the hamlet where Che Guevara died.</p>]]><p><b>Gasp at the wonders of lofty La Paz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Otherworldly, majestic La Paz is the world's highest capital city, sprawled across an Andean basin at 3,632m (11,910ft) above sea level. Overlooked by snow-capped Mount Illimani, the city's chaotic street life reflects its blend of European and Aymaran identities. See colonial palaces, churches and museums, wander the cobbled streets around Plaza San Francisco and listen to haunting panpipes in a folk club.</p>]]><p><b>Have a hell of a time at Oruro’s Carnival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Carnival is celebrated throughout Bolivia, but the annual street party at Oruro, is one of the most faithful traditional expressions of folklore in South America, with its historic 'Devil Dance' procession. This otherwise bleak mining town comes alive once a year with a spectacularly colourful and effervescent popular festival, attracting partygoers from around the world.</p>]]><p><b>Mountain bike down 'Death Road'</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hurtle down the world's most dangerous road on a mountain bike. The adrenalin-fuelled trip starts at the Cordillera Real in the mountains and descends rapidly down twisting roads into the Yungas jungle. At some points the rough track, also know as 'Death Road, is only 3m (10ft) wide with 600m (2,000ft) drops down one side.</p>]]><p><b>Ponder the mysteries of ancient Tiahuanaco</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Near the southern shore of Lake Titicaca, are the impressive stone walls of Tiahuanaco, believed to have once been the capital of a major pre-Inca civilisation, established some three millennia ago. The site is dominated by a series of evocative temples, carved monoliths and a compelling museum of ancient artefacts.</p>]]><p><b>Take the Jesuits Missions Trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dotted along the Jesuit Mission Trail east of Santa Cruz in Chiquitos, are a string of historic colonial churches. In the 18th century, Jesuit priests built these magnificent churches, before being expelled by the Spanish Crown. Six out of the 10 churches still exist today and now comprise a UNESCO World Heritage Site, home to a sacred music festival every other year.</p>]]><p><b>Tour a tin mine in historic Potosí</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Colonial Potosí was once the most important city on the continent and currently the highest city in the world at 4,100m (13,500ft) above sea level. Situated at the foot of Cerro Rico ('Rich Mountain'), Potosi was exploited for its mineral wealth, especially silver, and today is a UNESCO World Heritage Site. Take guided tours to the mines, the striking churches and the former Royal Mint.</p>]]><p><b>Trek through ancient Inca trails</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Bolivian Andes are crisscrossed by Inca trails, which provide a welcome challenge to hikers. Most treks start from La Paz and Sorata, and the most popular is the three-day Choros Trail from La Paz to Coroico. Also a three-day trek, the Taquesi Trail offers a moderate hike from La Paz, while the Illampus Circuit from Sorata is a demanding six-day affair.</p>]]><p><b>Wander through whitewashed Sucre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bolivia's constitutional capital Sucre, otherwise known as 'the white city' is a delightful place in which to unwind from the rigours of the Andes. Revered for its colonial architectural, the UNESCO World Heritage Site is home to beautiful churches, mansions and whitewash buildings. Wander the tranquil squares and market centre, which is known for its traditional weaving.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$24.6 billion (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Natural gas, soybeans and soya products, crude petroleum and tin.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum products, paper, aircraft, prepared foods and insecticides.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Japan, Brazil, Argentina and Peru.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite its wealth of natural resources, notably mineral deposits, oil and natural gas, Bolivia has the second-lowest per capita income in South America. The GNI per capita stands at US$2,040 (World Bank, 2011), and around two-thirds of the nation's population lives below the poverty line. Unemployment stands at 7.9% (2010 estimate). <br />
<br />
Agriculture today accounts for roughly 15% of Bolivia's GDP with soybeans the major cash crop, sold into the Andean Community market, plus sugar and coffee, while beef and hides are valuable export earners. There is also a substantial illegal trade in coca, the plant source for cocaine, which provides a livelihood for many peasants.<br />
<br />
Bolivia's trade with neighbouring countries is growing, aided by preferential trade-agreements with the Andean Community. Bolivia&rsquo;s top trading partners in 2011 in terms of exports were Brazil, Argentina, the USA, Japan, Peru, South Korea, Belgium, China and Venezuela. Bolivia's government remains heavily dependent on foreign assistance to finance development projects.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bolivians tend to be formal in their business dealings. Men should wear suits and ties; women should wear knee-length skirts or trouser suits. Typical business greetings include a firm handshake (don&rsquo;t forget eye contact). Business meals are popular but avoid arranging anything on a Friday evening when restaurants are packed and lively. Major events are usually held at Expocruz in Santa Cruz and Fexbol in La Paz.</p>
<p>The best months for business are April, May, September and October. Avoid the Christmas period, Easter, Carnival week (February) and Independence week (first week of August).</p><p>Businesses are normally open daily 0800-1230 in the mornings and from 1430-1830/1900 in the afternoons. Traditionally, they have a 2-hour lunch break at midday, where people will go home to have lunch with their family. However, many businesses are now switching to the <em>horario continuo</em>, where businesses remain open during the lunch hour (0800-1800 with 1 hour off for lunch). Generally, people do not eat at their desks nor do they stay in the office: they will either go home or eat out.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cámara Nacional de Industrias</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 237 4477
					Website:http://www.bolivia-industry.com/
					Address: Piso 14,Avenida Mariscal,Santa Cruz 1392,Edificio Cámara Nacional de Comercio,La Paz,]]><b>Cámara Nacional de Comercio de La Paz</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 237 8606
					Website:http://www.boliviacomercio.org.bo/
					Address: Pisos 1 and 2,Avenida Mariscal,Santa Cruz 1392,Edificio Cámara Nacional de Comercio,La Paz,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Bolivia&rsquo;s cuisine is as distinctive and varied as its landscape. Local specialities differ depending what region you find yourself in: the highlands and lowlands each have their own flavours. Aymaran cuisine in the Andes and Altiplano is centred on carbohydrates &ndash; especially potatoes, rice and quinoa &ndash; and meat (mutton and llama). Food in the lowlands tends to be more tropical (yucca and plantain are staples) with beef featuring heavily on menus.</p>
<p>You will find a large range of national and international restaurants, especially in La Paz and other large cities. It is possible to find pizzerias, Chinese restaurants (known as <em>chifas</em>) and high-end eateries, as well as more rustic rotisserie chicken restaurants.</p>
<p>Vegetarian options are thin on the ground (though there are a lot of egg-based dishes) outside the main cities. While Bolivia is landlocked, fish is still readily available, including delicious trout available from Lake Titicaca.  For the best deals dine at a local market or plump for a set lunch menu.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Salte&ntilde;as</strong>: Pasties filled with meat, vegetables, sauce, olives and hard-boiled egg.<br />
<strong>Api con bu&ntilde;uelos</strong>: Sweet, hot maize drink with cinnamon, sometimes served with deep-fried pancakes.<br />
<strong>Chu&ntilde;o:</strong> A naturally freeze-dried potato, which is nutty in flavour and often used in a soup called <em>chairo</em>.<br />
<strong>Llajwa:</strong> A hot chilli sauce served with most dishes.<br />
<strong>Chorizos chuquisaque&ntilde;os:</strong> Pork sausages in a spicy sauce.<br />
<strong>Lomomontado:</strong> Fried tenderloin steak served with a fried egg and chopped tomato on top.<br />
<strong>Cu&ntilde;ape:</strong> A pastry made from cheese and yucca flour.<br />
<strong>Surub&iacute;:</strong> A meaty white fish from the Amazonian rivers.<br />
<strong>Picante de pollo:</strong> Southern-style fried chicken, fried potatoes, rice, tossed salad with hot peppers.<br />
<strong>Lech&oacute;n al horno:</strong> Roasted suckling pig served with sweet potato and fried plantains.<br />
<strong>Charquekan:</strong> Llama or beef jerky, served fried with jacket potatoes, cheese and llajwa.<br />
<strong>Mate:</strong> A herbal tea, usually made from the coca leaf which helps with altitude sickness.<br />
<strong>Chicha:</strong> A fermented maize beer available in the Cochabamba region. It&rsquo;s an acquired taste with a bittersweet flavour.<br />
<strong>Singani:</strong> A popular brandy made from fermented grapes. Used in cocktails and great with lemonade.<br />
<strong>Wine:</strong> Bolivia has a fledgling wine industry, but imported wines from Argentina and Chile are also available.<br />
<strong>La Concepci&oacute;n:</strong> A high-altitude wine from Tarija.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tipping is not generally expected in Bolivia, but it is welcomed – 10% would be fine.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For a buzzing nightlife, La Paz should be your port of call. While other major cities boast a growing number of discos and bars, it is in La Paz where you&rsquo;ll find the most variety. The club scene is largely contained to Calles Linares, Tarija and Murillo with bars and clubs playing Latin jazz, pop, R&rsquo;n&rsquo;B, reggae and even 80s music &ndash; Mongo&rsquo;s, Oliver&rsquo;s Travels and Traffic are popular spots amongst travellers. Alternatively, try the designer hangouts of Sopocachi to see where La Paz&rsquo;s elite choose to party. Watch out for Friday nights as these are <em>viernes de solteros </em>(Bachelor Fridays), where most of the male population go out drinking in the city centre.</p>
<p>For a more traditional take on evening fun, try a <em>pe&ntilde;a</em>, a live folk music and dancing show, often accompanied by a late dinner. Pe&ntilde;a restaurants Huari and Marka Tambo both serve traditional Andean food and attract performances by well-known local musicians. International visitors may also be interested in events, shows and performances arranged by local cultural centres.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>La Paz&rsquo;s shopping scene offers a wealth of artisan goods from all over the country, and plenty of memorable souvenirs. Similar products are available at the markets of Sucre and Potos&iacute; so don&rsquo;t worry if you can&rsquo;t decide on the spot as you&rsquo;ll probably find something similar at another market. Pick up llama and alpaca wool scarves, jumpers and socks, Indian handicrafts, woodcarvings, accessories made from traditional materials and gold and silver costume jewellery. Sucre&rsquo;s markets are known for their range of weaved goods available (ponchos, bags and belts) in different styles by the Jalq&rsquo;a and Tarabuco groups.</p>
<p>The streets around the market area, notably Calle Sag&aacute;rnaga, Linares and Illampu, are full of small vendors offering goods at lower prices but quality can be variable. There are, however, only a few places around La Paz where you can buy good-quality products and be sure that a percentage of your money is directly going back into the hands of artisans. For example, the craft shop Ayni Bolivia at the Hotel Rosario supports over 300 artisans from poor, rural communities, and stocks over 300 items across a range of designs and styles.</p>
<p>Head to the Mercado de Hechicer&iacute;a where you can pick up keepsakes such as protective talismans and colourful lucky charms, as well as traditional Aymara remedies (including dried up llama foetuses) and herbal medicines. It&rsquo;s a must-see, just for the insight into ancient Aymaran culture.</p>
<p>For a bit of fun shopping, head to either the Mercado de Buenos Aires or the Feria de El Alto. Mercado de Buenos Aires, situated a few blocks away from Sag&aacute;rnaga, is a vast open-air market selling everything from fruit and coca leaves to smuggled televisions and imitation designer goods. Head to the nearby Calle Max Peredes to see the shops selling traditional clothing &ndash; you can even pick up a bowler hat for yourself. The Feria de El Alto, situated on the rim of La Paz&rsquo;s canyon, is also an interesting experience &ndash; see all kinds of bric-a-brac from live animals to plastic Chinese toys.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0930-1900, usually with a long lunch break from 1200-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Deluxe and first-class hotels in Bolivia are largely contained to the big cities. There is no official accommodation rating system in Bolivia, but some top end hotels will charge around 700 bolivianos per night, where you can expect nice architecture, surroundings and facilities. In smaller towns, the option for top-tier accommodation is difficult to find, and cheaper options are more widely available. There is an assortment of mid-range hotel accommodation available, generally of good value.<br />
<br />
Rates rise at hotels during peak season (July and August) and during any of the regional or national fiestas, prices can double or treble. Haggling is sometimes an option at the cheaper or mid-range hotels, especially if it is quiet or there is a large group. <br />
<br />
In the cold highland cities, heating is only found in the most expensive hotels and the same goes for air conditioning in the tropical lowlands. Most hotels will have hot water, a safety box and luggage storage facilities. Service charges and taxes (amounting to 25-27%) are added to bills. Rates are for room only, except where otherwise indicated.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pensions in major cities provide visitors with comfortable accommodation and food at a reasonable price. If you're in transit and are after a stop gap between places, accommodation near bus stations is usually cheaper in price.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Deluxe and first-class hotels in Bolivia are largely contained to the big cities. There is no official accommodation rating system in Bolivia, but some top end hotels will charge around 700 bolivianos per night, where you can expect nice architecture, surroundings and facilities. In smaller towns, the option for top-tier accommodation is difficult to find, and cheaper options are more widely available. There is an assortment of mid-range hotel accommodation available, generally of good value.<br />
<br />
Rates rise at hotels during peak season (July and August) and during any of the regional or national fiestas, prices can double or treble. Haggling is sometimes an option at the cheaper or mid-range hotels, especially if it is quiet or there is a large group. <br />
<br />
In the cold highland cities, heating is only found in the most expensive hotels and the same goes for air conditioning in the tropical lowlands. Most hotels will have hot water, a safety box and luggage storage facilities. Service charges and taxes (amounting to 25-27%) are added to bills. Rates are for room only, except where otherwise indicated.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Deluxe and first-class hotels in Bolivia are largely contained to the big cities. There is no official accommodation rating system in Bolivia, but some top end hotels will charge around 700 bolivianos per night, where you can expect nice architecture, surroundings and facilities. In smaller towns, the option for top-tier accommodation is difficult to find, and cheaper options are more widely available. There is an assortment of mid-range hotel accommodation available, generally of good value.<br />
<br />
Rates rise at hotels during peak season (July and August) and during any of the regional or national fiestas, prices can double or treble. Haggling is sometimes an option at the cheaper or mid-range hotels, especially if it is quiet or there is a large group. <br />
<br />
In the cold highland cities, heating is only found in the most expensive hotels and the same goes for air conditioning in the tropical lowlands. Most hotels will have hot water, a safety box and luggage storage facilities. Service charges and taxes (amounting to 25-27%) are added to bills. Rates are for room only, except where otherwise indicated.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical insurance is strongly recommended. In case of a medical emergency, La Paz has several reliable, private clinics, such as Clinica Alemana and CEMES. In big cities like La Paz, the pharmacies have a rota system whereby at least one will stay open for 24 hours a day. You can find familiar drugs without prescription here, and often the pharmacists can advise whether you need to see a doctor. In La Paz and Santa Cruz, English-speaking doctors are fairly easy to find. Remember to keep all receipts of treatment so you can claim back costs. In rural areas it is harder to find good medical facilities.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should be boiled or otherwise sterilised (iodine tablets or tincture are good options). It is best to avoid drinking tap water entirely while in Bolivia. Bottled water is purified (though check the seal as they are sometimes refilled in stores). All branded milk products are pasteurised; powdered or tinned milk is also available. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, and vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled. Be wary of street stalls or anything that has been reheated.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations for tuberculosis and hepatitis B are also sometimes recommended. Acute Mountain Sickness (AMS), commonly known as altitude sickness or &lt;em&gt;soroche&lt;/em&gt;, can affect anyone and care should be taken. Symptoms include nausea, dizziness, loss of appetite, breathlessness, headaches and a rapid heartbeat. Drugs can be bought from local pharmacies, or you can try coca tea which the locals swear by. Allow time to acclimatise to high altitude, especially upon arrival in Altiplano cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upset stomachs are common with travellers passing through Bolivia, caused either by contaminated food or water, or adjustment to new bacteria. Drink plenty of liquids and rehydration salts. If it continues for more than five days it&amp;rsquo;s best to consult a doctor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure to bring suntan lotion, especially when visiting Lake Titicaca or the Altiplano. While it may not be hot, the sun up here is strong and many people do not realise they are burning. Lotion can be expensive in the pharmacies, so bring your own from home. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Take extra precautions to prevent against mosquito bites because of the risk of dengue fever in Eastern departments. Affected provinces are Beni, Chuquisaca, Cochabamba, La Paz, Pando, Santa Cruz and Tarija. If you&amp;rsquo;re going into the Amazon, anti-malaria tablets are necessary &amp;ndash; check with your local travel clinic beforehand. Mosquito netting, repellent spray or lotion (with at least 35% DEET content) and electric plugs are the best types of repellent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rabies still exists in Bolivia, so if you&amp;rsquo;re spending time in remote areas or are in contact with animals, it&amp;rsquo;s worth having the vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other health threats include stings and bites from insects which can be treatable by hydrocortisone from a local pharmacy. It is always best to bring a first aid kit with you, especially when travelling to remote areas. Antiseptic cream, insect repellent, waterproof plasters, surgical tape, antihistamine, rehydration salts, paracetamol and water sterilisation tablets are all useful.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Additional holidays are observed by individual provinces and towns.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Carnival :
							12 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							06 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Bolivia by persons over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 450 cigarettes or cigars or 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 3L of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; New articles up to a maximum of US$1,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include illegal drugs, unauthorised guns, explosives and ammunition, knives and deadly weapons, counterfeit money and goods, and pornographic material.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include pharmaceutical and medical products, live animals and animal products, wild products, cheese, milk, raw meat, and other food and drinks. You must declare these, and cannot import them without authorisation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Notes are in denominations of 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5 bolivianos. Coins are in denominations of Bs5, 2 and 1, and 50, 20 and 10 centavos. Bolivianos are sometimes referred to as pesos. <br />
<br />
The Boliviano is tied to the US Dollar. Due to the relative weakness of the Bolivian economy, the boliviano remains vulnerable and so many businesses operate in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars. Most hotels and tour operators quote in dollars and will accept payment in either currency. Smaller shops, stalls and local businesses will only accept bolivianos.</p>
<p>Change and coins are in very short supply in Bolivia, which is something of a vicious circle as local buses, shops and taxis often won&rsquo;t accept big denomination notes. Try to break big notes wherever possible &ndash; namely hotels, restaurants, large stores and bus companies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money can be changed in hotels and <em>casas de cambio</em>. There are also plenty of money street changers if there are no official exchanges available, but be sure to check for forged notes in these cases. The boliviano is the preferred currency with exchange against the euro now preferred to the dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa and MasterCard are the most widely accepted in most mid- to top-range hotels and restaurants, but otherwise have limited acceptance. American Express is rarely accepted. It is best to carry cash with you – there are ATMs in most larger towns and cities.</p><p>There are ATMs in most of the larger towns and cities. Even the smaller towns have at least one bank with an ATM, and there are ATMs available at the larger airports.  Enlace is the nationwide network from which you can withdraw either US dollars or bolivianos. Sometimes in smaller towns, banks will offer international withdrawals for a small fee over the counter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar and Euro travellers' cheques are accepted in the large cities, but outside are useless. Pound Sterling travellers' cheques are not widely accepted. It is best to carry cash with you when travelling to smaller towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1200 and 1430-1700, and Sat 0900-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Europe"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for at least six months beyond the intended length of stay in Bolivia is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bolivia transit visas are only required by those who need a visa to enter the country in the first place.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The cost of tourist and transit visas for Bolivia depends on the nationality of the traveller; enquire at the embassy (or consular section at the embassy). For US travellers, a tourist visa costs US$160 and a specific purpose visa (eg for business) costs US$85. For nationals of Bulgaria, Cyprus, Malta and Romania, the visa is free of charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visas for Bolivia are valid for 30 days from the date of entry. For US citizens only, this visa can be used for up to three trips per year within a 10-year period, up to a maximum of 90 days per year.</p>
<p>Specific purpose visas for all nationalities are valid for 30 days and can be renewed at the immigration office in Bolivia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For temporary stays you will need the following: a valid passport with a specific purpose visa; a notarised document addressed to the Undersecretary of Migration requesting temporary stay; a work contract specifying duration of the stay; criminal record certificate; proof of permanent address; application for temporary residency and a completed application form. The government reserves the right to grant or reject foreigners. Enquire at your embassy or consulate for further details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow seven working days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Showing a credit card will suffice.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend your initial 30-day for a further 60 days. Visa-exempt travellers may only stay for up to 90 days per year. If you wish to stay longer, you should contact your local Bolivian embassy or the Department of Immigration in La Paz.</p>
<p>If travelling on a visa, you have to be able to show the Department of Immigration justifiable cause for an extension.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Bolivia with pets you need a certificate from a licensed vet, ideally issued no more than 10 days prior to travel, and an up-to-date rabies vaccination certificate. It's advisable to take Spanish translations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-16.712016]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-64.666016]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,098,581 sq km (424,164 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>10,888,402 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>9.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>La Paz.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Landlocked by countries (Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Paraguay and Peru), Bolivia is a topological pick and mix of spectacular sights, and remains one of the most bio-diverse countries in the world, despite not having a coast. The geography is largely split into the Andean Altiplano and the Eastern lowlands, and the contrast between them could not be greater. In the West, the parallel mountain chains of the Andes dominate. There&rsquo;s everything from deserts strewn with cacti and soaring rock formations, to magical coloured lakes and the world&rsquo;s largest salt flat, which contains 10 billion tonnes of salt (the remnants of Lake Minchin which evaporated some 25,000 years ago). You can see llama, alpaca, vicu&ntilde;as (rabbit-like animals), puma, and the only bear species in South America at these heights. On top of that, expect volcanic geysers at over 4000m (13,000ft) above sea level, the world&rsquo;s highest lake and the world&rsquo;s highest capital, La Paz, which sits in a mountain valley with the looming Mount  Illimani looking over. The high altitude can take its toll on travellers, so come prepared.</p>
<p>Eastern Bolivia is like a completely different world. The Amazon offers all types of flora and fauna, from over 30 monkey species and giant armadillos to catfish, piranha and pink freshwater dolphins. Visit Rurrenabaque to take tours of the R&iacute;o Tuichi, the Parque Nacional Madidi and the Pampas del Yacuma. The green tropical lowlands of Santa Cruz offer tropical cloudforest &ndash; try the Parque Nacional Ambor&oacute; for lush beauty. The Pantanal, on Bolivia&rsquo;s eastern border with Brazil is the world&rsquo;s largest wetland. Over 200,000 sq km (77,000 sq miles) of ecosystems live here, including swamps, lakes, flooded freshwater grasslands and forest. It is here that you will also find the highest concentration of fauna in all the Americas &ndash; birds, anacondas and giant otters to name a just a few.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Primarily Roman Catholic with a Protestant minority, though indigenous beliefs still hold strong with a large percentage of the population.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal social courtesies in most Bolivian families and respect for traditions should be observed. Remember to refer to rural Bolivians as <em>campesinos</em> rather than Indians, which is considered deeply offensive and racist. Female <em>campesinos</em> still adhere to their traditional dress, while a suit and tie for men and dress for women should be worn for smart social occasions. Casual wear is otherwise suitable, with conservative clothing more appropriate for the highlands. The tropical lowlands are more liberal, especially in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/santa-cruz-cruise">Santa Cruz</a>. Smoking is accepted unless indicated otherwise. Time-keeping is poor. Remember to always ask permission before entering religious ceremonies in church or at festivals.</p>
<p>Remember to always call people Se&ntilde;or or Se&ntilde;ora if they are older than you, and greet people with a formal <em>buenas d&iacute;as</em> (good morning), <em>buenas tardes</em> (good afternoon) or <em>buenas noches</em> (good evening). Use <em>por favor</em>, (please) and <em>gracias </em>(thank you) where possible.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts, 50Hz; some buildings in La Paz also have 110-volt sockets. Plugs are either two-pronged with round prongs (European) and flat-pronged pins (North American).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Evo Morales since 2006.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Evo Morales since 2006.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bolivia was initially inhabited by the ancient Aymara civilisation, which was concentrated in the western highlands. The Aymara were then conquered by the Incas, who were themselves conquered by the Spanish in 1538.</p>
<p>Throughout Bolivia&rsquo;s colonial history, it was known as Upper Peru, where the population faced economic depression, exclusion from high-ranking jobs and regulations preventing trade with any countries other than Spain. This led to the Great Rebellion in 1780-82 by indigenous groups, which culminated in the Independence War in the early 1800s.</p>
<p>Despite being the first country in South America to declare war against the Spanish, it was the last to obtain independence: Venezuelan military leader, Sim&oacute;n Bol&iacute;var, secured a hard-earned victory in 1825 and was rewarded by having the new country named after him.</p>
<p>The Republic of Bolivia faced problems in its early years. War destroyed its infrastructure as well as the economy, and it was ruled by a succession of military dictators who tried, with mixed success, to unite the country's three disparate regions: the central region, the eastern Andes and the Altiplano.</p>
<p>Wars with three neighbouring countries followed, which led to its Pacific coast being taken by Chile. In 1953, Chile declared the port of Arica 'free' and since then, has allowed Bolivia certain privileges in its use. The issue was not fully settled until 1992, when Peru agreed to allow Bolivia free use of the port of Ilo for 100 years.</p>
<p>After an economic crisis, the Chaco War (the result of a border dispute with Paraguay) and a short rule under a military regime influenced by European fascism, Bolivia entered an era of political stability. Much of the credit is due to President V&iacute;ctor Paz Estenssoro, who ruled between 1952-56, and 1960-64 and introduced universal suffrage and a national workers&rsquo; union.</p>
<p>He was elected again in 1985, at the head of a loose coalition of both left- and right-wing parties. By the time Paz Estenssoro ceded office to Jaime Paz Zamora in August 1989, rampant hyper-inflation had been dramatically cut. Both the ADN (Acci&oacute;n Democr&aacute;tica Nacionalista) and Zamora&rsquo;s MIR (Movimiento de Izquierda Revolucionaria), sometimes in coalition, have enjoyed control of the presidency and the national assembly.</p>
<p>Leftist Evo Morales won a decisive victory in the presidential elections in 2005 against a backdrop of political turmoil and social unrest. Morales was inaugurated as Bolivia&rsquo;s first-ever indigenous president in 2006, and he was re-elected in 2009.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; According to witchcraft beliefs a dried llama fetus should be buried in the foundations of new homes, to bring good luck.<br />
&bull; Silver mine city Potosi was once the richest city in the western hemisphere. Its streets were paved with silver and its horses wore silver horseshoes.<br />
&bull; The colourful Diablada Carnival of Oruro is based on Tiw, a devil-like deity who inhabits mines, lakes and rivers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Bolivia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 483 4410 or 232 4827 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.bolivia-usa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 483 4410 or 232 4827 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3014 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Bolivia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 4248.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://bolivianembassy.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 4248.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0935-245.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>106 Eaton Square<br/>London<br/>SW1W 9AD<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Bolivia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(2) 243 3424.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinbolivia.fco.gov.uk/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(2) 243 3424.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0830-1230 and 1330-1700; Fri 0830-1330; Mon-Thurs 0900-1200 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Avenida Arce No.2732, Casilla (PO Box) 694<br/>La Paz<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With its ice-capped Andean peaks, crystalline lagoons, rugged lowlands, Amazonian rainforest, terraced valleys and windswept altiplano, landlocked Bolivia is a virtual showcase of South America&rsquo;s most dramatic landscapes.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Its iconic sights include Lake Titicaca, spiritual home of the Inca creation myth and highest navigable lake in the world; the Salar de Uyuni, highest and largest salt lake on earth; and La Paz, the world&rsquo;s highest de facto capital. The panorama of the city&rsquo;s ramshackle roofs sprawled across the basin beneath the mighty Mt Illamp&uacute; is surely one of the most awesome views in the Americas.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s greatest treasures are the Bolivians themselves. Nearly two thirds of the people are of indigenous origin, preserving the continent&rsquo;s purest cultural roots, which, for visitors, means a dazzling array of colourful festivals, mysterious rituals, haunting folklore music, magical markets and dazzling costumed dances.</p>
<p>While bespoke tourism is emerging, there are also plenty of long bus journeys over precipitous mountain passes, rough-and-tumble jeep trips across empty landscapes and chilly nights at high altitude in budget hostels under llama wool blankets.</p>
<p>Bolivia&rsquo;s cities encapsulate the country&rsquo;s staggering contrasts. La Paz mixes both traditional and modern culture in a frenzy of collisions. Weave your way through the backstreets where cosmopolitan restaurants and lively bars compete with witch markets and speeding minibuses. By contrast, Santa Cruz has a younger vibe: famous for its spirited Carnival, it&rsquo;s the booming hub of the tropical eastern lowlands. Colonial Sucre and Potos&iacute; are chronicles of Bolivia&rsquo;s past &ndash; whitewashed mansions, gilt-lined churches, monumental plazas, and steep cobbled streets. While Tupiza and Uyuni offer something different altogether: the isolated culture of Altiplano towns.</p>
<p>From jungle greenery to vast white salt plains and wildlife-filled wetlands, the sweep of landscapes can be overwhelming: one day you can find yourself walking through a canyon of rock formations, the next volcanic geysers and endless stretches of white salt. It is this smorgasbord of remarkable features which keeps trips to Bolivia varied, alive and unforgettable.</p><p>With its ice-capped Andean peaks, crystalline lagoons, rugged lowlands, Amazonian rainforest, terraced valleys and windswept altiplano, landlocked Bolivia is a virtual showcase of South America&rsquo;s most dramatic landscapes. Its iconic sights include Lake Titicaca, spiritual home of the Inca creation myth and highest navigable lake in the world; the Salar de Uyuni, highest and largest salt lake on earth; and La Paz, the world&rsquo;s highest de facto capital. The panorama of the city&rsquo;s ramshackle roofs sprawled across the basin beneath the mighty Mt Illamp&uacute; is surely one of the most awesome views in the Americas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
