<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Bonaire" ColCode="bon" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="xo" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Bonaire]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot throughout the year, but tempered by cooling trade winds. The average temperature is 28°C (82°F) and the average rainfall is 50cm (20 inches) per year. Bonaire offers good conditions for diving all year round, althought conditions at the south end are generally at their calmest February-April.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights with warmer top layers for evenings; showerproof clothing is advisable throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can hop on a water taxi to visit Klein Bonaire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Roads are reasonably good, although jeeps may be needed for extensive touring of the island.</p><p>A good service exists on the island. Rates are government controlled.</p><p>You need a valid national driving licence. Drivers usually need to be at least 23-25 years old to hire a car (minimum age varies according to hire company and type of car). Drivers under a certain age may also be restricted as to what type of car they may hire, and most cars are manual/standard transmission.</p><p>Numerous car hire firms are located at hotels, the airport and Kralendijk. You should book in advance to get the best rates. Pick-ups and minivans are available for shore divers. Alternatively, it's easy to hire a bike, scooter or motorbike.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>KLM (<a href="http://www.klm.com" target="_blank">www.klm.com</a>) offers direct flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amsterdam">Amsterdam</a> to Bonaire. Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) and United (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">www.united.com</a>) operate direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.&nbsp;There are no direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;13 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>&nbsp;- 4 hours 45 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bonaire International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flamingoairport.com]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no international boat connections to Bonaire. However, Bonaire is regularly visited by cruise ships during high season (December to April).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is average.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet cafes in Kralendijk and varius Internet Access Centres around the island. WiFi is also available between Flamingo Airport, at the southern-most point of Bonaire, to Playa Lechi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The country enjoys freedom of the press and speech as guaranteed under Dutch law. The weekly English-language <em>Bonaire Reporter</em> is an independent publication focusing on news as it relates to the island's residents and visitors. It is distributed free on the island and publishes online (<a href="http://www.bonairereporter.com" target="_blank">www.bonairereporter.com</a>). There is a government-run TV station broadcast from Curaçao.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to and from Europe takes four to six days. Surface mail takes up to six weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Befriend a retired donkey</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The arrival of new agricultural technology made many of Bonaire's donkeys redundant. Cue the Bonaire Donkey Sanctuary, a not-for-profit organisation set up to take care of mules that have long since retired from working on the salt pans. Visitors are encouraged to feed and help care for the ageing animals.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Bonaire National Marine Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bonaire's beautiful National Marine Park is centred on a spectacular coral reef, which has helped the island establish itself as a world-class diving destination. This unspoiled area is maintained and monitored throughout the year by marine biologists, who are blazing a trail for others to follow in the world of coral reef conservation.</p>]]><p><b>Embrace the festival spirit</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bonaire has many festivals to choose from and tourists are always encouraged to join in the celebrations. The most popular jamboree is the colourful Carnival, which comes to a dramatic finale with a firework display and the ceremonial burning of King Momo (an effigy, not a real king). Other festivals to look out for include:  the Simadan (Harvest) Festival in Rincón, with its songs and dances, and Rincón Day, which celebrates the traditions and culture of Bonaire in the island's oldest village.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Bonaire’s darker past</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The bright, white huts on Witte Pan were inhabited by subjugated salt workers until the abolition of slavery in 1863. The eerily small holes on their frontage served as doors, which the slaves would crawl through at night after a gruelling shift. The slave huts serve as a sober reminder of Bonaire's repressive history.</p>]]><p><b>Flock to see the flamingos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bonaire is renowned for its flamboyant flamingo population, most of which inhabit the protected southern areas of the island. Arguably one of the easiest places to spot these ostentatious birds is the beautiful lagoon of Gotomeer, where they gather to feed on brine shrimp. Just be sure not to forget to bring the telephoto lens.</p>]]><p><b>Learn to dive</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The waters around Bonaire are clear, safe and teeming with fish of every size and hue. In short, the island is a diver's paradise and you'd be a fool to forgo the superb scuba diving and snorkelling on offer here. With idyllic learning conditions and some of the best dive instructors in the Caribbean, it's a great place to learn the ways of the underwater world.</p>]]><p><b>Pamper to pleasure on Pink Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Beautiful beaches abound in Bonaire, but Pink Beach has to be one of the finest. Living up to its name, this sandy stretch gets its tinge, most obvious at sunset, from tiny bits of pink coral and crushed seashell. Refreshingly, the beach is not commercialised – there are no ice cream parlours or amusement arcades here – so make sure you take plenty of sun lotion, food and refreshments.</p>]]><p><b>Relax in Rincón</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rincón, Bonaire's oldest village, boasts a sprinkling of bars serving chilled tipples beneath brightly coloured roofs. Rincón translates as the Spanish for 'nook' or 'corner' and is ensconced in the north of the island in an inland valley. One of only two towns on the island, Rincón also used to house slaves who worked on the salt flats.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the wind and waves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bonaire's climate is perfect for wind and kitesurfing, and attracts professionals from around world, who flock to its breezy shores to practice and compete. Calm, shallow waters and regular on-shore winds make it one of the best places in the world to hone your skills and don't take our word for it: Windsurf Magazine voted it best destination in the world to learn to windsurf.</p>]]><p><b>Set sail for adventure</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Half or full day cruises to Klein Bonaire, the island's tiny uninhabited sister isle, can be arranged for wannabe sailors. If you're lucky enough to have your own vessel, there are extensive moorings in Kralendjik harbour, Plaza Marina and Harbour Village Marina. And every second week of October there is a Sailing Regatta, during which there is a carnival atmosphere on the island.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in time at Bonaire Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located just outside Kralendijk, in a restored 1885 plantation mansion, Bonaire Museum displays artefacts depicting the history of the island: from the early days of the Caiquetio Indians and Spanish invaders to the Dutch colonialists and more modern times. It's also home to an impressive collection of seashells.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hike up Mount Brandaris</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bonaire's loftiest point is Mount Brandaris (241m/784ft), which pokes out of the picturesque Washington-Slagbaai National Park in the island's interior. Intrepid explorers are also rewarded for reaching the summit with exceptional views and exotic flora, including the iconic Divi Divi trees, which grow sideways due to the powerful winds that buffet the island.</p>]]><p><b>Trick your eyes at the salt flats</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A trip to Bonaire's salt flats might not sound particularly interesting , but these are no ordinary salt flats: these salt flats change colour before your eyes – from breathtaking fuchsia to subtle pink –  according to fluctuations in the resident algae population. The view is astonishing and with a bit of imagination could even pass as a snow-filled winter scene.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$3.3 billion (Netherlands Antilles; 2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude petroleum, food and manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Venezuela, Mexico, USA, Brazil and Gabon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>During the 1950s, Bonaire began a gradual climb out of chronic economic depression, aided by investment in tourism and the revival of a long-dormant salt industry. The economy gained a further boost in the mid 1970s, when the Bonaire Petroleum Corporation (Bopec) set up an oil transfer depot with a deep-water port, with facilities for transferring oil from ocean-going to coastal tankers. However, plans to build a refinery in Bonaire have been indefinitely shelved.<br /><br />Other economic activities on Bonaire include rice processing and shipping. There is also some agriculture: Bonaire grows a variety of fruit and vegetables; in particular, it is a major producer and exporter of aloes.<br /><br />Bonaire has benefited from the offshore financial industry, which has built up among the island group, although most of the companies engaged in the sector are located on Curaçao and St Maarten.<br /><br />As part of the Kingdom of The Netherlands, Bonaire is an overseas territory in association with the EU; it also holds observer status at the regional CARICOM trading bloc.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>General business practices prevail.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1200 and 1330-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bonaire Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (717) 5595
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The restaurants serve predominantly Creole cooking, particularly seafood dishes, including conch shell meat, grilled spicy fish and lobster. A variety of Chinese, French, Indonesian, Italian and international cooking can also be found. There are several hotels, restaurants and bars in Kralendijk to choose from.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Iguana soup.<br />&bull; <em>Kabrito stoba</em> (goat stew). <br />&bull; <em>Pika Siboyo</em> (a popular sauce made with onions marinated in vinegar and hot peppers). <br />&bull; <em>Pastechis</em> (plump pastries filled with spicy meat, shrimp or fish). <br />&bull; <em>Cocada</em> (sweet cocunut candy).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Restaurants and bars are usually closed by midnight.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>There is typically a 10% service charge in restaurants and a 6% tax.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nightspots are found around the main hotels and restaurants. Evening entertainment includes dancing and listening to reggae groups or calypso steel bands at the many oceanside bars and cafes. The island has two discos and two casinos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The reductions on duty-free imports make the purchase of some perfume, jewellery or alcohol worthwhile. Bonaire prides itself on its unique, specialist stores. Watches, Dutch cheese, fine China and Cuban cigars are usually sold.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800/0900-1200 and 1400-1800. Larger supermarkets are open Monday-Saturday 0730/0800-1900, with some open Sunday 1100-1400. Hours vary widely and those stated above must be treated simply as guidelines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are excellent hotels and resorts on the island with good facilities for the holidaymaker, particularly in the provision of watersports equipment etc. Rates for accommodation will be approximately 20 to 40% cheaper in the off-peak season (mid April-mid December). A small room tax is added to the bill. An additional service charge of 10 to 15% may also be levied.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are excellent hotels and resorts on the island with good facilities for the holidaymaker, particularly in the provision of watersports equipment etc. Rates for accommodation will be approximately 20 to 40% cheaper in the off-peak season (mid April-mid December). A small room tax is added to the bill. An additional service charge of 10 to 15% may also be levied.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are excellent hotels and resorts on the island with good facilities for the holidaymaker, particularly in the provision of watersports equipment etc. Rates for accommodation will be approximately 20 to 40% cheaper in the off-peak season (mid April-mid December). A small room tax is added to the bill. An additional service charge of 10 to 15% may also be levied.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The San Francisco Hospital is equipped to deal with emergencies and has a decompression chamber and an ambulance aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All mains water on the islands is distilled from seawater and is safe to drink. Bottled mineral water is widely available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Outbreaks of dengue fever occur in the area. Vaccination against hepatitis B and tuberculosis is sometimes advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Carnival Monday :
							12 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Queen's Birthday and Rinc :
							30 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Pentecost :
							20 May </p><p>Bonaire Flag Day :
							06 September </p><p>Antillean Day :
							21 October </p><p>Kingdom Day :
							15 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Bonaire by travellers over 17 years of age (tobacco products) or over 18 years of age (alcohol) without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigarillos or 25 cigars or 125g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits over 22% (but no additional wine or beer), or 1L of spirits less than 22% plus 2L of non-sparkling wine and 8L of beer.<br />
&bull; Gifts up to a value of US$500 (or US$150 for children under 15).<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar (USD; symbol $) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of $100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of $1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.</p>
<p>The US Dollar replaced The Netherlands Antilles Guilder or Florin as the currency of Bonaire on 1 January 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major currencies, including US Dollars, Pounds Sterling and Euros, are easily exchanged. ATMs are located around the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, Mastercard and Visa are widely accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1200 and 1400-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for at least six months after departure from Bonaire is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Schengen visa is not valid for travel to Bonaire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay Caribbean visa: &pound;30. The Caribbean visa allows nationals who do require a visa to make short visits to Aruba, Cura&ccedil;ao, St Maarten, Bonaire, St Eustatius and Saba.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Caribbean visa is a multiple-entry visa. Visa holders may visit any of the countries included under the scheme for a maximum of 90 days within one year. Each continuous period in any one country may not exceed 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Contact your nearest Dutch embassy to make an appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications for the Caribbean visa are usually processed within 15 calendar days, but processing times vary depending on the country. Applications can be made up to 3 months before the intended travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You cannot extend the Caribbean visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All pets must be accompanied by a Bonaire veterinary certificate. This should be certified by a licensed practitioner.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[12.201890]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-68.262382]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>290 sq km (112 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>19,408 (CBS value 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>60 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kralendijk.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The National Office for the Caribbean Netherlands acts on behalf of the Government of the Netherlands. The Kingdom Representative for the public bodies of Bonaire, Saint Eustatius and Saba represents the Government of the Netherlands on Bonaire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bonaire is the second-largest island in the former Netherlands Antilles and is located 80km (50 miles) north of Venezuela and 48km (30 miles) east of Cura&ccedil;ao. The landscape is flat and rocky and, owing to low annual rainfall, Bonaire has a fairly barren desert climate. The island has small, beautiful beaches and safe waters.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly Roman Catholic with a Protestant minority. There are many evangelical churches of different denominations, and a new mosque has also been erected on the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dutch customs are still prevalent throughout the islands, although they are increasingly subject to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> influence. Dress is casual and lightweight cottons are advised. Bathing suits should be confined to beach and poolside areas only. Nudity is prohibited on beaches except at Sorobon Beach Resort, a privately owned nudist resort.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>127 volts AC, 50Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without round grounding pin) are most common.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Mark Rutte since 2010, represented locally by Kingdom Representative Gilbert Isabella since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Willem-Alexander since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although discovered by the Spanish explorer Amerigo Vespucci in 1499, Bonaire's earliest inhabitants were Caquetio Indians – noted for their tall stature – who travelled from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/venezuela">Venezuela</a> by canoe about a thousand years ago.</p><p>Spanish colonisation, which started in 1526, was a little half-hearted and although they imported domesticated cows, donkeys, goats, horses, pigs and sheep it's not thought their efforts at farming came to much. From the 1620s the Dutch were regular visitors to the island and abandoned the Spanish and Portuguese prisoners who built the town of Antriol on Bonaire. During the Eighty years War between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a> and The Netherlands, the Dutch conquered Bonaire and built Fort Oranje in 1639.</p><p>The Dutch West Indies Company introduced economic development schemes for which they imported hundreds of slave workers. Even after emancipation free slaves were obliged to do at least dome work for the government, but the abolition of slavery heralded in a long period of economic depression that was only accelerated when the government sold most of the public lands in the 1860s and eventually the vast saltpans, leaving the entire population economically dependent on two private landowners.</p><p>During World War 2 Bonaire became a protectorate of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Britain</a> and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">United States</a> and by 1945 the US Army had built Flamingo Airport, while many German and Austrian citizens were interned on Bonaire.</p><p>An indigenous economy began to emerge in the post-war years as the airport was turned over to civilian use and the former internment camp became the island s firs hotel, paving the way for the modern tourism industry.<br/>After the dissolution of the Netherlands Antilles in 2010, Bonaire held a referendum on independence, but although 84 per cent of those who voted did so to become part of The Netherlands, because the turn out was well below the 51 per cent required, the result was declared void. Bonaire is now a 'special municipality' or public body of The Netherlands but in a referendum in December 2015 65 per cent voted they were not content with Bonaire's current relationship with The Netherlands.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• With Aruba and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/curacao">Curaçao</a>, Bonaire forms part of a group often referred to as the ABC Islands.</p><p>• A giant system of ponds and pools has been created in southern Bonaire to facilitate the production of salt by evaporation. The condensing pools are a natural habitat for brine shrimp on which large flocks of flamingoes and other migratory birds feed.</p><p>• Lac Bay in the south-east of the island is popular with surfers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Office of the Minister Plenipotentiary of the Netherlands Antilles]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(70) 306 6111.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.antillenhuis.nl</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(70) 306 6111.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>PO Box 90706<br/>Antillenhuis,Badhuisweg 173-175<br/>The Hague<br/>2509 LS<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Diplomatic Representation]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Caracas (nearest British Embassy to Bonaire)]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(0) 212 267 1275.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinvenezuela.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(0) 212 267 1275.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1630, Fri 0800-1315.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Avenida La Principal de la Castellana, La Castellana<br/>Torre La Castellana<br/>Caracas<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bonaire is the second-largest island in the former Dutch Antilles, and has desert-like terrain offset by inviting turquoise waters. Beneath the water's surface, rainbow-hued fish drift in between coral, and many believe argue that the diving and snorkelling here is the best in the Caribbean; Bonaire's relative lack of tourism means much of its coral has gone undisturbed. For those seeking sailing or windsurfing, the characteristic windswept postures of the <em>divi divi</em> trees show that Bonaire's warm, dry and breezy climate is ideal for these sorts of activities. </p>
<p>Bonaire is highly eco-friendly and keen not to impair the fragile infrastructure of the coral, nor unsettle the island's serenity with heavy development and glitzy nightlife. Consequently, Bonaire's beautiful beaches and safe waters have remained intact. Flamingos wander the landscape of multi-hued salt plains, and multitudes of birds enjoy this paradisiacal sanctuary.</p>Bonaire was part of the Netherland Antilles until its dissolution in 2010. It is now a special municipality of The Netherlands.Bonaire is the second-largest island in the Dutch Antilles, and has desert-like terrain offset by inviting turquoise waters.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
