<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Bosnia and Herzegovina" ColCode="bih" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ba" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Bosnia and Herzegovina]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dominated by mountainous and hilly terrain, and drained by major rivers to the north (Sava) and east (Drina), Bosnia and Herzegovina has a climate that is as variable as the rest of the former Yugoslav federation, with moderate continental climatic conditions generally the norm (very cold winters and hot summers).<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In winter, heavyweight clothing and overcoat. In summer, lightweight clothing and raincoat required, with mediumweight clothing at times in the colder and wetter north, and at higher altitudes elsewhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Željeznice Federacije Bosne i Hercegovine (<a href="http://www.zfbh.ba" target="_blank">www.zfbh.ba</a>) and Željeznice Republike Srpske (<a href="http://www.zrs-rs.com" target="_blank">www.zrs-rs.com</a>) operate the national railway network. There are connections between the major cities, but note that the Sarajevo-Mostar line is closed for upgrading until late 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travel by road is the usual means of transport in Bosnia and Herzegovina.&nbsp;During winter and spring, block ice and landslides can make driving difficult.&nbsp;Road conditions are varied.&nbsp;The safety and condition of urban roads is generally fair, although rural road maintenance is seriously lacking. Be cautious when driving at night or during winter, and keep to the main roads.</p>
<p>The risk of landmines has decreased in the last few years, as most mines remaining from the war are now clearly marked.&nbsp;However, visitors are still advised to exercise caution when travelling outside main cities and towns.<br />
<br />
The capital, Sarajevo, is the nodal point for all Bosnia and Herzegovina's main communications routes, which go west to Banja Luka, and then to Zagreb, capital of Croatia; north to Doboj, and then to Osijek in Croatia; east to Zvornik, and then to Belgrade in Serbia; south to Mostar, and then the Adriatic Sea; and southeast to Foca, and then to Podgorica, Montenegro.</p>r<p>An International Driving Permit is required. Your insurance should include cover you for the 20km (12-mile) strip of coastline at Neum on the Dalmatian Coast highway.</p><p>Tel: 987.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating flights to Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina include Austrian Airlines (<a href="http://www.austrian.com" target="_blank">www.austrian.com</a>), Croatian Airlines (<a href="http://www.croatianairlines.com" target="_blank">www.croatianairlines.com</a>) and germanwings (<a href="http://www.germanwings.com" target="_blank">www.germanwings.com</a>). There are no direct flights from the UK or the USA.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bosnia-and-herzegovina/sarajevo-international-airport">Sarajevo International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 4 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 11 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$12.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Sarajevo International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.sarajevo-airport.ba<p>The airport is located about 6km (4 miles) southwest of Sarajevo city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+387 33 289 100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rail services link Sarajevo, Mostar, Doboj and Banja Luka to Zagreb, Croatia. However, services are slow.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries.</p>
<p>Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an adult pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to enter the country by car from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia">Croatia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/serbia">Serbia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/montenegro">Montenegro</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is average.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes are on the increase in the larger towns throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since the war in Bosnia and Herzegovina, the media is no longer steeped in propaganda, but it is still only partially free, with journalists under pressure from state bodies and political parties to somewhat censor their content. This is thanks to the 1995 Dayton Peace Accord efforts, although this has had limited success. The most influential broadcasters are the public radio and TV stations operated by the Bosnian Muslim-Croat and Serb entities. New independent commercial channels are now in development. The main newspapers for the Federation of Bosnia and Herzegovina, <em>Dnevni </em><em>A</em><em>vaz</em> and <em>Oslobodjenje,</em> are published in Sarajevo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal post takes approximately one week to reach its destination, while heavier packages could take up to 10 days. Coins, bank notes, precious metals and stones, narcotics, alcohol, firearms and ammunition are not permitted to be sent by mail.</p><p>Generally Monday to Friday 1000-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Cross Mostar Bridge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Mostar to see the elegant bridge that links the two sides of the town across the Neretva River. The original 16th-century Ottoman bridge was destroyed in the 1990s conflict, but has since been reconstructed to the original specifications with Turkish help. In Mostar itself, there are also many well-preserved 16th and 17th-century mosques, medieval buildings and cobbled streets worth visiting.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the history of Sarajevo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Although scarred by war, the Bosnia and Herzegovina capital is a vivacious place once more, with a great café culture and buzzing nightlife. The Ottoman quarter is particularly pretty with its historic mosques and timeworn monuments strewn about aged lanes and bazaars. The history is fascinating, too: visit the site where Franz Ferdinand was assassinated, an event that sparked WWI, and learn about the terrible Bosnian War in the Tunnel Museum and Sarajevo History Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Get the popcorn out for Sarajevo Film Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pop along to the Sarajevo Film Festival, the most popular of all Sarajevo's festivals, which is held annually in August. The jamboree showcases movies from mostly Balkan countries and consistently unearths films of an excellent artistic standard.</p>]]><p><b>Go rafting near Bihac</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See what was historically the westernmost Muslim settlement in Europe, the Bihac pocket in northwestern Bosnia and Herzegovina, close to the Croatian border. As well as being home to the Fathija Mosque, formerly a church, the town is also a superb base for rafting on the Una River.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the hillscapes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bosnia and Herzegovina's undulating landscape provides numerous hill-walking opportunities, although it is imperative to avoid areas where landmines still pose a threat. Bjelasnica Mountain offers the potential for combined hiking, rafting and village tourism. The hills around Sarajevo are also worth trekking into, home as they are to the ruined remains of the bobsled track used in the 1984 Winter Olympics.</p>]]><p><b>Hit Bosnia's only beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For Bosnia and Herzegovina's only beach, head to Neum. The tiny, solitary stretch of coast that divides Croatia's seashore is nevertheless beautiful, with golden sands and emerald waters courtesy of the fabled Adriatic Sea. Climb the hills for incredible views of the Neum corridor, a narrow dagger of sea slicing into the Dalmatian coast.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Bosnian nature in Sutjeska National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't miss the wildlife and unspoiled beauty of Sutjeska National Park. This nature reserve boasts both Maglic Mountain – at 2,368m (7,769ft), the highest point in Bosnia and Herzegovina – and Perucica Forest, one of the last remaining primeval forests in Europe.</p>]]><p><b>Pilgrimage to Medjugorje</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On of Europe's most visited Catholic shrines, Medjugorje, south of Mostar, is where many claim to have seen apparitions of the Virgin Mary. Consequently, hundreds of thousands of pilgrims make their way to this holy town, which sits near the border with Croatia.</p>]]><p><b>Revel at the Winter Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Winter Festival in Sarajevo (usually held in February or March) is an arts festival established long before the war in the 1990s and, indeed, was determinedly held every year during the siege (the festival is usually bi-annual). The cultural festival is a two-month celebration of diversity and talent through assorted performances and workshops.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the rivers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go white-water rafting along one of the country's many mountain rivers. Rafting tours are available along the Neretva, Una and Tara rivers, which offer some of the most exciting locations in Europe for this activity. Kayaking is another water sport for which Bosnia and Herzegovina offers great potential.</p>]]><p><b>See the Dervish house of Blagaj</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Near Mostar, Blagaj is one of the prettiest sights in Bosnia and Herzegovina. With dramatic cliffs, turquoise waterways and mysterious caves, this peaceful village is a feast for the eyes, though the main attraction is the old Dervish house, which looms perilously over the river at the foot of a 200m-high rock face. Blagaj lies just a half-day trip from Mostar.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Bosnia's second city, Banja Luka</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Although most visitors to Bosnia make a beeline for Sarajevo, Banja Luka is definitely worth a visit. The country's second largest city is a hilly, picturesque town with a pleasant snaking river that's lined by many cafes, and willows dipping into the waters. Also check out the Ottoman fortress, originally Roman, and choose between several Orthodox monasteries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$19.36 billion (2008).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Wood, paper, clothing and metal products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, chemicals, fuels and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Croatia, Germany, Italy, Austria, Slovenia and Hungary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Yugoslav civil war that broke out in 1992 brought Bosnia & Herzegovina's economy to a standstill. Most post-war international aid was directed to reconstruction of the Muslim-Croat region. The Republika Srpska got much of its industrial sector working again with support from Milosevic's Yugoslavia but this was set back by its war with NATO in the late 1990s. Since then, the central government has received loans, totalling approximately US$250 million, from the IMF.<br /><br />The growth rate is currently 5.5%, while inflation stands at 1.6%. Unemployment, which officially is around 30%, is currently the biggest problem facing the economy.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Central Bank of Bosnia and Herzegovina</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (33) 278 100
					Website:http://www.cbbh.ba
					Address: ,Marsala Tita 25,71000 Sarajevo,]]><b>Foreign Trade Chamber of Bosnia and Herzegovina</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (33) 663 631
					Website:http://www.komorabih.ba
					Address: ,Branislava Djurdjeva 10,Sarajevo,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Like most of the Balkans, the cuisine of Bosnia and Herzegovina is a product of the colourful interaction between cultures that typifies the region. The Ottoman Turks, who held sway over the area from the 15th century, had perhaps the biggest impact, bringing with them the lamb or beef sausages, filo pastries, spicy meats and kebabs that are consumed en masse in Bosnia and Herzegovina.</p>
<p>Of course, there's more to the country's cuisine than this, with diverse soups and stews also on the menu, while years of Austrian rule have made their mark in the kitchen, too. The Herzegovina region is known for its wines.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Jagnjetina</strong>: Flame-grilled lamb or mutton.<br />
<strong>Bosanskilonac</strong>: Meat stew cooked on an open fire.<br />
<strong>Cevapcici</strong>: Small sausages made from a lamb and beef mix.<br />
<strong>Burek</strong>: Meat or cheese pie made with filo pastry.<br />
<strong>Baklava</strong>: Sweet nuts and honey in pastry.<br />
<strong>BegovaČorba</strong>: Meaning 'Bey's stew', this widely eaten Bosnian soup contains meat and vegetables.<br />
<strong>Filovane paprika</strong>: Fried bell peppers filled with minced meat.<br />
<strong>Ra&scaron;tika</strong>: Meat and rice rolled in kale leaves.<br />
<strong>Pilav</strong>: Rice browned in oil, and then cooked in a seasoned broth, served with various meats and vegetables<br />
<strong>Rakija</strong>: Bosnia's take on the potent cocktail usually derived from plum or apple.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Rounding up is customary for taxi fares. In restaurants, a 10% tip is standard.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>The legal drinking age is 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina's capital, has some of the best nightlife in southeast Europe. In addition to numerous cosmopolitan bars and nightclubs<strong> </strong>there is also a wealth of cinemas and theatres, along with music venues that stage everything from jazz to opera. The city apparently has more cafes per capita than any other European city and a relaxed cafe culture is prevalent. There are also several annual festivals, particularly in the summertime, that showcase jazz, theatre and film.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional purchases include woodcarvings, brass coffee-pots, ceramics, handmade carpets, woollen goods, wines, folk-art, tapestries, embroidery and leather boxes. Souvenirs, particular to Bosnia and Herzegovina and stark reminders of the past Yugoslav War, are the engraved artillery shell casings that are available at the Bascarsija bazaar in Sarajevo.</p><p>0800-2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sarajevo has a wide choice of hotels that range from simple 1-star establishments to luxurious 5-star international. Other cities generally have a narrower choice. In recent years a number of smaller, privately run hotels and motels have also opened up throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These can be found in some of the more touristy areas of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sarajevo has a wide choice of hotels that range from simple 1-star establishments to luxurious 5-star international. Other cities generally have a narrower choice. In recent years a number of smaller, privately run hotels and motels have also opened up throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sarajevo has a wide choice of hotels that range from simple 1-star establishments to luxurious 5-star international. Other cities generally have a narrower choice. In recent years a number of smaller, privately run hotels and motels have also opened up throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Facilities are limited, especially outside Sarajevo and other major towns. All medical and dental care must be paid for in cash at the point of treatment. Tourists are strongly advised to take out full travel and medical insurance before travelling to Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is of good quality and safe to drink. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat, although it is advisable to peel vegetables and fruit and only eat cooked meat and fish. Unpasteurised milk must be boiled. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Immunisation against hepatitis B, tuberculosis and tick-borne encephalitis is recommended. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>In addition to the Public Holidays listed, the government of Bosnia and Herzegovina has decided to allow its citizens two working days per year to fulfil their religious needs. These days are not considered official holidays and the measure has been introduced to respect the religious and ethnic diversity of the country.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>Orthodox New Year :
							2018<br/>14 January </p><p>St Sava Day :
							2018<br/>27 January </p><p>Independence Day :
							01 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Velika gospa (Assumption) :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Statehood Day :
							25 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Bosnia and Herzegovina by travellers aged 17 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits over 22% and 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 60ml of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Gifts and souvenirs to the value of KM200 (around US$113).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must apply for a permit to import sporting or hunting weapons and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Works of art.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bosnia and Herzegovina Konvertibilna Marka (BAM; symbol KM) = 100 feninga. Notes are in denominations of KM200, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 and 50 feninga. Coins are available in denominations of KM2 and 1, and 50, 20 and 10 feninga. Some Euro notes (but not coins) are widely accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Euro and US Dollar are the preferred foreign currencies. The Pound Sterling is rarely used. Some shops will accept Euro cash for payment on a 2KM = 1 Euro basis.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are generally accepted in top hotels and restaurants, and some gift shops. ATMs are becoming increasingly common in cities like Sarajevo, Mostar and Banja Luka, and even smaller towns. However, an emergency supply of cash is still advisable.</p><p>ATMs are becoming increasingly common in cities like Sarajevo, Mostar and Banja Luka, and even smaller towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bosnia and Herzegovina is mostly a cash-only economy and traveller's cheques are exchanged only at select banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the date of departure from Bosnia and Herzegovina is required by all nationals referred to in chart above.</p>
<p><strong>1.</strong> EU citizens may also enter using a valid ID card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If applying for a visa for a child, both parents should sign the form. If one parent can't sign it, they need to provide a notarised letter authorising travel with a copy of their passport.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><font class="v11px_grey">Short-term single-entry visa and transit visa: &euro;31; short-term multiple-entry visa: &euro;57; long-term visa: &euro;72.<br />
</font></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single- or double-entry transit visas: five days; short-term single- and multiple-entry visas: 90 days; single- or multiple-entry long-term visas: over 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to stay longer than 90 days, you must apply to the Border Police for a residence permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three working days for short-term visas and one to three months for long-term visas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers should have at least KM150 for each day of their visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets must be accompanied by a veterinary certificate and rabies vaccination record.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[44.169037]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[17.783028]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>51,129 sq km (19,741 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3,798,672 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>75.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sarajevo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal democratic republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roughly triangular in shape, and the geopolitical centre of the former Yugoslav Federation, Bosnia and Herzegovina shares borders with Serbia in the east, Montenegro in the southeast, and Croatia to the north and west, with a short Adriatic coastline of 20km (12 miles) in the south, but no ports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>45% Muslim, 36% Orthodox, 15% Roman Catholic, 4% Protestant, Jews and other denominations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bosnia and Herzegovina is characterised by its ethnic and religious diversity and visitors should respect the customs and traditions of the various ethnic and religious groups. The main ethnic groups are the Bosniaks (48%, also sometimes referred to as Bosnian Muslims), the Serbs (37.1%) and the Croats (14.3%). Visitors should be aware that drinking alcohol in public may be considered offensive by more orthodox Muslims. Visitors should avoid expressing opinions about the war or other sensitive issues.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are in use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Denis Zvizdić since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chairman of the Presidency Milorad Dodik since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Once part of the Roman province of Dalmatia, modern-day Bosnia was briefly occupied by Goths, until it became an outpost in the Byzantine Empire during the Middle Ages for some six centuries.</p>
<p>From 1180, when Byzantine rule came to an end, and by 1463, when the Ottoman Turks took control, Bosnia was more or less an independent state under a succession of strong rulers who expanded the territory southwards to take in the province of Hum (now Herzegovina).</p>
<p>As a province of the Ottoman Empire, Bosnia and Herzegovina had two distinguishing characteristics: firstly, much of the population converted to Islam; secondly, as a frontier province, it was the first line of defence against incursions into the Ottoman sphere of influence. Consequently, the country suffered from repeated invasions.</p>
<p>Under pressure from the Austrians, Ottoman rule began to weaken during the 18th and 19th centuries, until the Turks were expelled following the Russo/Serbian-Turkish war of 1876, and Bosnia was assigned to the Austro-Hungarian Empire by the Congress of Berlin. The decision by Vienna to annex Bosnia fully in 1908 produced a destabilising chain of events contributing to the First Balkan war of 1912-1913, then to the assassination of the Austrian Archduke Franz Ferdinand in the Bosnian capital, Sarajevo, by a Serb revolutionary, Gavrilo Princip. This assassinating in June 1914 is considered by many the trigger for WWI.</p>
<p>At the end of the war, with the approval of the victorious Great Powers, Serbia annexed Bosnia as part of the new Kingdom of Serbs, Croats and Slovenes, which was renamed Yugoslavia in 1929. Following the Communist take-over in 1945, Bosnia and Herzegovina became a constituent republic of the new Yugoslav federation. The ethnic rivalries characteristic of the region's politics were largely kept at bay during this era, before unravelling tragically in the 1990s.</p>
<p>With a population split almost equally three ways between Serbs, Croats and Muslims, Bosnia became a key battleground as Yugoslavia disintegrated, until NATO forces intervened to stop the ethnic cleansing that was taking place. Peace has largely held since then &ndash; despite rival ethnic nationalists gaining ground in the 2014 general election. However, the country's economic frailty is arguably of more concern to today's population.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Lasting longer than the siege of any other capital city in modern history, the Siege of Sarajevo endured from 1992 to 1996 &ndash; a year longer than the Siege of Leningrad.<br />
&bull; The 1984 Winter Olympics were held in Sarajevo, but during the 1990s the infrastructure (think ski runs, bobsled courses, etc.) was used as target practice by the Serbian Army.<br />
&bull; The 2014 FIFA World Cup was Bosnia and Herzegovina&rsquo;s first major football tournament.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Bosnia and Herzegovina in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7373 0867.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.bhembassy.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7373 0867.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700, Mon-Fri 1000-1300 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>5-7 Lexham Gardens<br/>London<br/>W8 5JJ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Bosnia and Herzegovina in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 337 1500 or 6473 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.bhembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 337 1500 or 6473 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; Mon-Fri 1000-1500 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2109 E Street<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20037<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Bosnia and Herzegovina]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(0) 33 282 200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinbih.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(0) 33 282 200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0830-1700, Fri 0830-1430.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>39a, Hamdije Cemerlica street<br/>71000 Sarajevo<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>After the tragedy of the Yugoslav wars that ravaged the Balkan region in the 1990s, Bosnia-Herzegovina has begun to emerge from that torrid time as a compelling, multi-faceted travel destination. Most notable amongst the country&rsquo;s many charms is its lush, mountainous landscape, best seen from the vantage point of one of its national parks.</p>
<p>Bosnia-Herzegovina still bears the legacy of war, having a fractured infrastructure and parts of its countryside still fraught with mines. It remains one of Europe&rsquo;s poorest countries and some areas of its most afflicted cities have still to be rebuilt.</p>
<p>However, there are plenty of positives to take from the country&rsquo;s urban centres, especially the cosmopolitan capital of Sarajevo. With its rich history and lively nightlife, the diverse city has become one of Europe&rsquo;s most curious, unique capitals. The old town is divided between the evocative Ottoman quarter of historic mosques, little streets filled with cafes and craft workshops, and the trendy Austria-Hungarian quarter built during the late 19th century &ndash; truly a case of east meets west.</p>
<p>Sarajevo also has several museums explaining its history, while climbing the steep hills rewards you with a stirring view of the city. One oddity is the colossal bobsleigh track from the 1984 Winter Olympics that runs through the forests of Trebevic mountain; it was destroyed during the Siege of Sarajevo in 1990s and is now a canvas for local street artists.</p>
<p>Beyond Sarajevo, much of the country is relatively undeveloped, but there are several historic fortresses to see, no shortage of splendid old mosques, and a number of monasteries and Catholic shrines. The second city (at least by reputation), Mostar is also increasingly popular with tourists. Perhaps above all else, it is the city&rsquo;s 16th century Ottoman bridge that symbolises both the past and a positive new beginning for the country. Destroyed during the war, it has since been painstakingly reconstructed, and was declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 2005.</p><p>After the tragedy of the Yugoslav wars that ravaged the Balkan region in the 1990s, Bosnia-Herzegovina has begun to emerge from that torrid time as a compelling, multi-faceted travel destination. Most notable amongst the country&rsquo;s many charms is its lush, mountainous landscape, best seen from the vantage point of one of its national parks.</p>
<p>Bosnia-Herzegovina still bears the legacy of war, but there are plenty of positives to take from the country&rsquo;s urban centres, especially the cosmopolitan capital of Sarajevo. With its rich history and lively nightlife, this diverse city has become one of Europe&rsquo;s most curious, unique capitals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
