<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Botswana" ColCode="bwa" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bw" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Botswana]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The landlocked Botswana is semi-arid and has two main seasons: wet and dry.</p>
<p>The dry season is from May to October. This is peak season for wildlife safari as animals are much easier to spot because the vegetation is less dense, and animals tend to congregate around waterholes. Temperatures are around 25&deg;C (77&deg;F), but they are at least 10 degrees cooler in the south. The Kalahari Desert, in the southwest, may experience cold and frosty early mornings and evenings too.</p>
<p>The wet season is from November to April. November can be very hot and humid, while January and February are the wettest months. Some safari lodges and camps are closed during this period too.</p>
<p>If you are visiting the Okavango Delta and Chobe National Park, the months from June to September are the best time.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Loose, natural fabrics are recommended, with wet-weather gear and warmer clothes according to the season and area visiting.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major areas of the country are linked by air. There are airports in Francistown, Ghanzi, Jwaneng, Kasane, Maun and Selebi-Phikwe. Air Botswana (<a href="http://www.airbotswana.co.bw" target="_blank">www.airbotswana.co.bw</a>) runs domestic flights from Francistown, Kasane and Maun to Gabarone.</p>
<p>Many visitors use charter companies based in Maun to fly to the various lodges in Botswana.&nbsp;These include Mack Air (<a href="http://www.mackair.co.bw/" target="_blank">www.mackair.co.bw</a>), Kavango Air (<a href="http://www.kavangoair.com" target="_blank">www.kavangoair.com</a>) and&nbsp;Kalahari Air Services (<a href="http://www.kalahariair.co.bw" target="_blank">www.kalahariair.co.bw</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An overnight train runs daily from Francistown to Gaborone and Lobatse.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>Botswana has good tarmac roads on major routes; generally roads range from tarmac to either gravel or sand tracks.&nbsp;Visitors should be careful as many drivers ignore safety rules. You should always carry reserve fuel, emergency supplies, and at least 20L of water on longer journeys. Make&nbsp;careful enquiries before setting out.&nbsp;Wildlife and stray livestock may pose a hazard.</p><p>There is a taxi service in all major towns, and it's generally safe. Make sure you agree prices before embarking on a journey.</p><p>To drive in Botswana, you need a valid national driving licence, which you can use for up to six months. If it's not in English, an International Driving Permit is recommended.&nbsp;</p><p>Speed limits are 120kph (75mph) outside built-up areas, and about 60kph (37mph) in built-up areas.</p><p>Major international companies and local firms offer car hire in Gaborone, Francistown, Kasane and Maun. In many areas, you need 4-wheel drive vehicles.</p><p>Speed limits are 120kph (75mph) outside built-up areas, and about 60kph (37mph) in built-up areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public transport within towns consists of share-taxis or minibus services operating at controlled flat fares. Exclusive use of taxis is sometimes available at a higher charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Botswana</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tshabong</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">15.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Botswana</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kasane</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">13.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Botswana</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ghanzi</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.25</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">11.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Botswana</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">francistown</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.35</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Botswana&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.airbotswana.co.bw/" target="_blank">www.airbotswana.co.bw</a>), flies into Gaborone from Harare (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/Zimbabwe">Zimbabwe</a>), Cape Town (South Africa) and Lusaka (Zambia). The quickest route from the UK is to fly to Johannesburg with South African Airways (<a href="http://www.flysaa.com" target="_blank">www.flysaa.com</a>) or Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) and catch a connecting flight from there. South African Airways also runs direct flights to Johannesburg from the USA.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 14 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 19 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Francistown Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Gaborone Sir Seretse Khama International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 15km (9 miles) northwest of Gaborone.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Maun International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.caab.co.bw]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Selebi-Phikwe Airport </b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Botswana Railways (<a href="http://www.botswanarailways.co.bw" target="_blank">www.botswanarailways.co.bw</a>) offers an overnight Francistown-Gaborone-Lobatse service that has first class sleepers, business class seats, standard class seats and a buffet car. Departures take place daily, and tickets can be bought from the website. National Railways of Zimbabwe (<a href="http://nrz.co.zw/" target="_blank">www.nrz.co.zw</a>) used to operate a weekly service between Botswana and Zimbabwe (Francistown-Bulawayo; journey time - 5 hours 30 minutes but this was suspended in 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are very few public phone boxes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies. Coverage is average.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in large cities and resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are claims that there are government limits on ability to broadcast freely but, overall, Botswana welcomes public debate and freedom of expression, as its constitution dictates. State-run television did not appear until 2000 and radio still has more dominance as a medium. Printed media are mostly limited to major cities and towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are post offices in all towns and the larger villages. Airmail service to Europe takes from one to three weeks.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0815-1245 and 1400-1600; Sat 0800-1100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Attraction</p><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Cruise along the Chobe River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The languid and life-giving Chobe River is both exceptionally beautiful and bursting with wildlife. Probably the best place in Africa to see elephants swimming, you'd also be hard pushed to find a better spot for an evening boat cruise and a sundowner or three with hippos belly laughing all about you. To take the experience to another level, book a Chobe houseboat holiday.</p>]]><p><b>Experience the beauty of Moremi Wildlife Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Botswana's Moremi Wildlife Reserve lies in the centre of the Okavango Delta. The reserve encompasses a wide range of habitats – from wetlands, floodplains and reed beds to forests and savannah woodlands. The fauna inhabiting this pristine park is abundant and equally diverse, ranging from exotic birds, zebras, buffalo, wildebeest and giraffes to hippos and lions.</p>]]><p><b>Get lost in Kgalagadi Transfrontier National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Encompassing ancient animal migration routes between Botswana and South Africa, this enormous desert park is bigger than the Netherlands and famed for its big cat population, particularly lion and cheetah. Other attributes include incredible night skies and overpowering stillness. It's still a relatively underexplored park, and a special place for wild camping.</p>]]><p><b>Go on a game drive in Chobe National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Chobe National Park is Botswana's flagship park and easily combined with a visit to Victoria Falls just across the border into Zimbabwe or Zambia. The park itself is vast, wild and home to more than 100,000 elephants, sometimes seen in herds of up to 500. There are also plenty of predators, including leopard, lion and the critically-endangered African wild dog.</p>]]><p><b>Paddle around the Okavango Delta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The oasis of the Okavango Delta is one of Africa's most iconic destinations and not without good cause. Positively teeming with wildlife and birdlife, this region of vast grass flats, low tree-covered ridges and narrow and intricate waterways is best explored in a <em>mokoro</em>, a traditional dugout canoe. This rustic means of transport takes you closer to the delta's staggering biodiversity.</p>]]><p><b>Roar across the Makgadikgadi Pans</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Traverse the world's largest salt pans on a quad bike to make the most of the awe-inspiring vistas and sense of isolation. Come at the right time of year and you'll also see southern Africa's most spectacular zebra and wildebeest migrations. The barren landscape is occasionally punctuated by strange and picturesque islands of palm trees. You might spot the rare brown hyena here.</p>]]><p><b>Sleep with the rhinos at Khama Rhino Sanctuary</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Established in 1992, this community-based wildlife project is a shining example of Botswana's sterling conservation work and its emphasis on sustainable tourism. The peaceful sanctuary provides a safe haven for both white and black rhino, previously wiped out across most of the country, and there are onsite chalets and camping facilities.</p>]]><p><b>Trek in the sacred Tsodilo Hills</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tsodilo Hills is a UNESCO World Heritage Site held sacred by Botswana's San Bushmen. Known to have been inhabited for at least 100,000 years, these dramatic, isolated hills are decorated with thousands of fascinating ancient rock paintings. A number of different hiking trails showcase both the stunning natural beauty and rich cultural heritage of these ancient landscapes.</p>]]><p><b>Venture into Central Kalahari Game Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Remote, enormous and virtually unexplored, the Central Kalahari Game Reserve is a refuge both for iconic wildlife and the country's few remaining Bushmen, nomadic hunter gatherers indigenous to southern Africa. Often referred to as one of Africa's last true wildernesses, roaring lions may be the only sound to puncture the overpowering desert stillness here.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$15.27 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Diamonds, copper, nickel, beef and textiles.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, machinery, electrical goods, vehicles and fuel.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>European Free Trade Association (EFTA); fellow members of the Southern African Customs Union (SACU).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Diamond mining, tourism, financial services and livestock farming are key foreign exchange earners. Botswana is economically connected to South Africa and is a member of the Southern African Customs Union (SACU). It also hosts the Southern African Development Conference, which is the principal mechanism for economic co-operation. <br />
<br />
Prudent management and the successful development of new mineral resources have afforded Botswana consistent economic growth at a rate of around 5% in recent years. The country has been seeking to reduce its economic dependence on diamonds and agricultural products, both of which are vulnerable to price fluctuations, and to increase its focus on high-revenue investment services and upmarket safari tourism. Unemployment is officially around 20%, but many citizens support themselves through subsistence agriculture.<br />
<br />
The HIV/AIDS epidemic, which is extremely serious in Botswana and mainly afflicts the productive, young and middle-aged population, is starting to have a negative effect on the economy.<br />
<br />
<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits should be worn.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700 April-October; 0730-1630 October-April. <br />
<br />
<strong>Government office hours:</strong> 0730-1630 all year round.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Botswana Export Development &amp; Investment Authority (BEDIA)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 318 1931
					Website:http://www.bedia.co.bw/
					Address: The Main Mall,Plot 28,Matsitama Road,Gaborone,]]><b>Ministry of Trade and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 360 1200
					Website:http://www.mti.gov.bw/
					Address: ,P/Bag 004,Gaborone,]]><b>Botswana Development Corporation</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 365 1300.
					Website:http://www.bdc.bw
					Address: ,Moedi,Gaborone,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most of Botswana's safari lodges and camps serve excellent international-style cuisine that incorporates local influences such as game meats or traditional maize or sorghum-based Botswanan staples.</p><p>Good restaurants and bars can be found in most major towns and cities, often in the hotels. In rural villages and less developed areas food is generally more basic, usually consisting of a stiff maize-based porridge (<em>pap</em>) with some form of stew. Goat, beef, chicken and river fish are all common sources of protein for locals.</p><p>There are plenty of locally grown vegetables and fruits available at local markets, including the interesting marula fruit and tasty local wild spinach. Watermelons are also believed to have originated in Botswana.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pap:</strong> A stiff, maize porridge, the main local staple.<br/><strong>Seswaa:</strong> Botswana's national dish, a meat stew made with onions and peppers and served with pap.<br/><strong>Kalahari truffles:</strong> A desert species of mushroom with a rich earthy flavour.<br/><strong>Mopane worms:</strong> Large, protein-rich grubs, boiled, grilled or deep-fried and served as a side or snack.<br/><strong>Morogo:</strong> Wild spinach, often served as a side with pap and stews.<br/><strong>Vetkoek:</strong> A deep-fried dough ball similar to a savoury doughnut, often served with curried mince.<br/><strong>Serobe:</strong> Goat, sheep or cow intestines cooked until soft; trotters are sometimes also included.<br/><strong>Biltong:</strong> Seasoned and dried beef or game meat.<br/><strong>Dikgobe:</strong> A stodgy mixture of beans and maize or sorghum.<br/><strong>Bojalwa:</strong> An opaque, sorghum-based beer.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A discretionary 5 to 10%. In many places, a service charge is automatically added. It is customary to tip the game guide and lodge staff while on safari.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most people get up early in the morning, and even in the capital, Gaborone, nightlife is not very extensive. It's limited to a few bars and restaurants, a cinema and a cultural centre which stages theatrical productions. Some bars host live music sessions at weekends. Despite its steady tourist traffic, Maun is even sleepier, with just a handful of restaurants, a small cinema and a clutch of places to grab a cold beer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Woodcarvings, handcrafted jewellery, textiles and attractive basketry are recommended. The Okavango Delta villages of Etsha and Shorobe are particularly famous for Ngamiland-style baskets. Modern Bushman art and ostrich-eggshell jewellery can be browsed and purchased at D'Kar, 40km (25 miles) north of Ghanzi. There also occasional exhibitions at the National Museum in Gaborone.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1800, Sat 0830-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Botswana's main urban centres - Gaborone, Francistown, Kasane and Maun - all have a number of hotels and motels which generally maintain a reasonable standard. The top-end hotels offer air conditioning, swimming pools and entertainment such as film screenings, live music and dance shows; there are also budget places with fairly basic amenities. Botswana Tourism Department (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>) lists accommodation options online. <br/><br/><strong>Grading:</strong> Botswana operates a standard 5-star rating system for all hotels, lodges and camps.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Botswana's main urban centres - Gaborone, Francistown, Kasane and Maun - all have a number of hotels and motels which generally maintain a reasonable standard. The top-end hotels offer air conditioning, swimming pools and entertainment such as film screenings, live music and dance shows; there are also budget places with fairly basic amenities. Botswana Tourism Department (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>) lists accommodation options online. <br/><br/><strong>Grading:</strong> Botswana operates a standard 5-star rating system for all hotels, lodges and camps.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Botswana's main urban centres - Gaborone, Francistown, Kasane and Maun - all have a number of hotels and motels which generally maintain a reasonable standard. The top-end hotels offer air conditioning, swimming pools and entertainment such as film screenings, live music and dance shows; there are also budget places with fairly basic amenities. Botswana Tourism Department (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>) lists accommodation options online. <br/><br/><strong>Grading:</strong> Botswana operates a standard 5-star rating system for all hotels, lodges and camps.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The dust and heat may cause problems for some people. Visitors should use sun protection, especially due to Botswana's high altitude. The public health system is good. All main towns have chemists, and pharmaceutical supplies are readily available. Health insurance is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is considered safe to drink, although outside main cities and towns, visitors are advised to check first and sterilise water if in any doubt. Bottled water is available in most tourist centres. Milk is pasteurised, and dairy products, local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally safe.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations for tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Hepatitis C occurs. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is endemic; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Tick-bite fever can be a problem when walking in the bush. It is advisable to wear loose-fitting clothes and to search the body for ticks. Rabies is present in animals. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Sir Seretse Khama Day :
							01 July </p><p>President's Day :
							16 July </p><p>Botswana Day :
							30 September </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Botswana without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes and 20 cigars and 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine and 1L of spirits.<br />
&bull; 50ml of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of R500 (South African Rand) from within the SACU zone (<a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/africa/lesotho/" target="_blank">Lesotho</a>, <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/africa/namibia/">Namibia</a>, <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/africa/south-africa/">South Africa</a> and <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/africa/swaziland/">Swaziland</a>) and to the value of R3,000 from outside the zone.<br />
<br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p>Tobacco and alcohol allowances are only applicable to travellers over 18 years old.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include firearms and ammunition, narcotics and pornography.</p>
<p>You may bring in small amounts of fresh food, but you require an import licence for larger amounts. Note that the import regulations on importing meat change regularly according to disease outbreaks in different countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pula (BWP; symbol P) = 100 thebe. Notes are in denominations of P100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of P5, 2 and 1, and 50, 25, 10 and 5 thebe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money should be exchanged in banks at market rates. The main commercial banks include <em>Bank of Baroda</em>, <em>Barclays Bank of Botswana</em>, <em>First National Bank</em>, <em>Stanbic Bank Botswana</em> and <em>Standard Chartered Bank</em> with branches in major towns and villages. Owing to limited facilities in small villages, it is advisable to change money at the airport or in major towns, where credit card cash advances may also be available. There are also bureaux de changes at major border posts. Safari lodges accept payment in US dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted. ATMs are available in most larger cities and towns.</p><p>ATMs are available in most larger cities and towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Pounds Sterling. Traveller's cheques are accepted in some banks in large cities but with a high surcharge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Banks open 0800 and 0900, Mon-Sat, closing between 1615 and 1715 on weekdays and 1045 and 1200 on Saturdays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Botswana, a passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above. Outgoing travel documents and sufficient funds are also required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitor visa: US$107.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Up to 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy or high commission).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 21 working days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your stay beyond 90 days, you must contact the Department of Immigration to request an extension.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-22.188981]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[23.813972]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>581,730 sq km (224,607 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,291,661 (2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gaborone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parliamentary republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Botswana is landlocked, bordered to the south and east by South Africa, to the northeast by Zimbabwe and to the north and west by Namibia. It also touches Zambia just west of the Victoria Falls. The tableland of the Kalahari Desert covers the centre and south. The principal wildlife areas are the Okavango Delta to the northwest, the largest inland delta in the world, which includes the Moremi Game Reserve; Chobe National Park in the north, including Savute and the Linyanti Marshes; and Kgalagadi Transfrontier National Park in the far southwest, co-managed with South Africa. <br />
<br />
The majority of the population lives in the southeast around Gaborone, Serowe and Kanye along the South African border. The vast arid sandveld of the Kalahari occupies much of central and western Botswana. The seasonal rains bring a considerable difference to the vegetation, especially in the Makgadikgadi Pans and the Okavango Delta.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christianity, Roman Catholic and indigenous beliefs. There are numerous small Zionist and Apostolic churches in rural villages, as well as United Reformed (Congregational and Methodist), Dutch Reformed, Lutheran, Methodist and Anglican churches, and predominantly expatriate Muslim, Quaker, Hindu and Bahai congregations in major towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As most people in Botswana follow their traditional pattern of life, visitors should be sensitive to customs which will inevitably be unfamiliar to them. Outside urban areas and safari destinations, people may well not be used to visitors. Casual clothing is acceptable and, in urban centres, normal courtesies should be observed.<br/><br/><strong>Photography:</strong> Airports, official residences and defence establishments should not be photographed. Permission should be obtained to photograph local people.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220-240 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs used are British-style with two flat blades and one flat grounding blade, or South African/Indian-style with two circular metal pins above a large circular grounding pin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Mokgweetsi Masisi since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Mokgweetsi Masisi since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The first people to settle in Botswana were the San Bushmen, nomadic hunter-gatherers whose territories are also thought to have spanned present-day Namibia, Angola, South Africa, Zambia and Zimbabwe. Their influence is still evident in southern Africa, where these indigenous inhabitants eke out traditional lives as hunter-gatherer. Examples of their early rock art are also still visible across the region.</p>
<p>From the 17th century the San Bushmen started to come under pressure from migrating Bantu tribes, who had migrated from sub-Saharan Africa. A further series of migrations followed and by the 18th century these migrants were firmly established in the southern part of Botswana, and had established a powerful military state controlling hunting, cattle-breeding and copper mining.</p>
<p>The 19th century brought another period of upheaval, as inhabitants from the north of the continent, dislocated by slavery and the collapse of their local economies, moved to new territories.</p>
<p>British colonialists and Boer settlers then came along and vied for control of Botswana; the local rulers allied themselves with the British against the Boers, and Botswana was eventually brought under British protectorate control in 1890, remaining so until independence in 1966.</p>
<p>Popular Seretse Khama became the country's first president &ndash; a position he held until his death in 1980 &ndash; and subsequent elections have remained peaceful and democratic.</p>
<p>In the late 1960s, diamonds were discovered in Botswana and became the primary driving factor for the country&rsquo;s economic growth and independence. These riches have, unlike in other parts of Africa, helped the country become a veritable African success story.</p>
<p>During the 1980s and 1990s, Botswana was an important player in South Africa&rsquo;s apartheid struggle, providing refuge for a number of guerrilla fighters and political exiles. Today, Botswana&rsquo;s key domestic priority is to tackle the AIDS pandemic. Botswana's infection rate, estimated at 25 per cent of the total population, is among the world's highest.</p>
<p>For any persisting issues, under current president Ian Khama, first elected in 2008, Botswana continues to be a shining light of peaceful, non-racial, multi-party democracy on the African continent.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; The Jwaneng diamond mine, located in the south of the country, is the world&rsquo;s richest diamond mine.<br />
&bull; The word <em>lekgoa</em>, which locals often use to refer to foreigners, literally translates as &lsquo;spat out by the sea&rsquo;.<br />
&bull; The wife of Botswana&rsquo;s first president, Seretse Khama, and mother of current president, Ian Khama, was an English woman named Ruth Williams.<br />
<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Botswana High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7647 1000</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7647 1000</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>6 Stratford Place<br/>London<br/>W1C 1AY<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Botswana in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 244 4990.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.botswanaembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 244 4990.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon, Wed and Fri 1000-1300 (enquiries); Mon-Thu 0900-1600 (visa drop off); Mon-Fri 1400-1600 (visa collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1531-33 New Hampshire Avenue<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Easily one of best safari destinations in Africa, Botswana is a wild and dramatic land characterised not only by its bountiful wildlife, but also by its extraordinary scenery: from shimmering salt pans and diamond-rich deserts to raging rivers and fertile flood plains, the landscapes here come in many guises.</p>
<p>Nearly half of the country is given over to national parks, reserves and private concessions, which makes for an excellent safari experience. Botswana&rsquo;s policy of favouring low-impact luxury tourism ensures that even the most famous game-viewing areas rarely feel crowded, while its population of just two million adds to the sense of wilderness.</p>
<p>The north of Botswana in particular offers superb wildlife-watching opportunities. It is home to the wondrous Okavango Delta &ndash; the largest inland delta in the world &ndash; where shimmering lagoons and fertile waterways are crammed with more than 400 species of bird. Away from the water zebras and giraffes amble across grass flats and flood plains, keeping an eye out for the numerous big predators that also reside here.</p>
<p>Northeast of Okavango is another jewel in Botswana&rsquo;s crown: Chobe National Park, which has one of the largest concentrations of game anywhere in Africa. The reserve is particularly well known for its vast elephant herds, some 400-strong, which share this wild land with the likes of lions, cheetahs, hippos and many more.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not only in conservation that Botswana is an African success story. Since gaining independence in 1966, it has achieved steady economic growth through good use of its agricultural potential and enviable diamond reserves.</p>
<p>It has not entirely escaped controversy &ndash; the HIV/AIDS pandemic and alleged maltreatment of the Kalahari Bushmen have caused international concern &ndash; but it remains a peaceful and stable nation of remarkable natural beauty and its developed infrastructure makes it much more accessible than some of its neighbours.</p><p>One of best safari destinations in Africa, Botswana is a wild and dramatic land characterised not only by its bountiful wildlife, but also by its extraordinary scenery: from shimmering salt pans and diamond-rich deserts to raging rivers and fertile flood plains, the landscapes here come in many guises. Nearly half of the country is given over to national parks, reserves and private concessions, which makes for an excellent safari experience. Botswana&rsquo;s policy of favouring low-impact luxury tourism ensures that even the most famous game-viewing areas rarely feel crowded, while its population of just two million adds to the sense of wilderness.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
