<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="British Virgin Islands" ColCode="vgb" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="vg" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[British Virgin Islands]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is subtropical and tempered by trade winds. There is little variation between summer and winter. Rainfall is low, varying slightly from island to island. Night-time temperatures drop to a comfortable level. Visitors should note that the British Virgin Islands are susceptible to hurricanes and earthquakes, although these are by no means a frequent occurrence. The primary hurricane season is from June to November.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical lightweights. Dress is generally informal but swimwear is confined to beaches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fly BVI (<a href="http://www.fly-bvi.com" target="_blank">www.fly-bvi.com</a>) and Caribbean Wings-BVI Airlines (<a href="http://www.bvi-airlines.com" target="_blank">www.bvi-airlines.com</a>) run inter-island charter flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Yacht charter is one of the major industries, and you can hire bareboats for cruises. A permit is required for all charter boat passengers. The high season is from December to April.</p>
<p><strong>Ferries:</strong> The main routes are from Tortola to Virgin Gorda, Jost Van Dyke, Marina Cay and Peter Island. A list of operators is available from the British Virgin Islands Tourist Board (<a href="http://www.bvitourism.com/inter-island-ferries" target="_blank">www.bvitourism.com/inter-island-ferries</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good network, although due to steep and narrow mountain roads, plus poor driving standards, conditions may be precarious.</p><p>There are several taxi companies on Tortola and Virgin Gorda. Many drivers double up as tour guides, and you can hire taxis on an hourly or daily basis.</p><p>You can drive on a valid national licence for up to 30 days.</p><p>The speed limit is 64kph (40mph). Seat belts are compulsory.</p><p>There are many local and international companies. Drivers need to be at least 25 years old.</p><p>The speed limit is 64kph (40mph). Seat belts are compulsory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">British Virgin Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">virgin_gorda</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.05</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">British Virgin Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">peter_is</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">British Virgin Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">jost_van_dyke</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">British Virgin Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">guana_is</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The easiest way to reach the British Virgin Islands from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> is via Antigua. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and&nbsp;Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>)&nbsp;offer direct flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Antigua. From Antigua, LIAT (<a href="http://www.liatairline.com" target="_blank">www.liatairline.com</a>) flies to Tortola. Fly BVI (<a href="http://www.flybvi.com" target="_blank">www.flybvi.com)</a> runs chartered flights to an assortment of Caribbean islands.</p>
<p>Travellers arriving from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> can take a connecting flight from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/san-juan">San Juan</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/puerto-rico">Puerto Rico</a>&nbsp;with Cape Air (<a href="http://www.capeair.com" target="_blank">www.capeair.com</a>) or Seaborne Airlines&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.seaborneairlines.com" target="_blank">www.seaborneairlines.com</a>) or fly to St Thomas, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/us-virgin-islands">US Virgin Islands</a> and take a ferry to Tortola. The islands are also accessible via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-maarten">St Maarten</a> and St Kitts.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/british-virgin-islands/beef-island-airport">Terrance B Lettsome International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 14 hours (including stopover in Antigua); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 6 hours (including stopover in Puerto Rico).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>By air: US$20. Children under five years are exempt. By sea: US$20 for foreign visitors and US$15 for residents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Terrance B. Lettsome International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bviaa.com<p>Terrance B. Lettsome International Airport is located 12km (7.5 miles) east of Road Town on the island of Tortola.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 284 852 9000</p>]]><b>Anegada Auguste George Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Virgin Gorda Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 3.5km (2 miles) from Spanish Town on Virgin Gorda.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is excellent. Handsets can be hired.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet access is available in some hotels. There are a few internet cafés and free Wi-Fi hotspots. BVI Marine WiFi (<a href="http://www.bvimarinewifi.com/" target="_blank">www.bvimarinewifi.com</a>) offers a subscription service giving wireless access at the main harbours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no public broadcasters based in the British Virgin Islands; all TV and radio stations are privately run. Cable and satellite TV is widely available. There is freedom in the British Virgin Islands' press to criticise the government. The <em>BVI Beacon</em>, the <em>BVI StandPoint</em> and the <em>Island Sun</em> are newspapers published weekly.<strong><br /></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes up to a week.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Climb Sage Mountain</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Excellent views of the island and its coast can be experienced from Sage Mountain, which kisses the sky at 550m (1,800ft). The mountain sits in a gorgeous national park lined with mahoganies, hanging vines, white cedars and kapok trees. The area is well-marked with trails to explore.</p>]]><p><b>Delve into Dead Chest National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visitors can snorkel amidst the stunning coral gardens of Dead Chest National Park. The island is said to have been named when the infamous pirate Blackbeard put 15 mutinous men ashore with only a bottle of rum between them.</p>]]><p><b>Dive down to the Rhone Marine Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The wreck of the RMS Rhone in the Rhone Marine Park off Salt Island is a mecca for divers. The mail ship sank during the hurricane of 1867 and now lies in two sections in waters between 9m (30ft) and 27m (90ft) deep. The clear water also allows for good snorkelling of the wreck site.</p>]]><p><b>Escape to Fallen Jerusalem National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gloriously untouched by man this uninhabited island is home to the endangered red-billed tropicbird as well as brown boobies, laughing gulls, noddies and brown pelicans, plus sandwich, royal and bridled terns. The island's name is said to derive from the large, volcanic rocks that resemble the destroyed city.</p>]]><p><b>Experience the BVI Spring Regatta and Sailing Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sea lovers can set sail in the annual BVI Spring Regatta and Sailing Festival or take it easy on a luxury charter. The warm water makes for gorgeous sailing conditions, while the parties that take place on dry land are just as hot.</p>]]><p><b>Peer into the caves of Norman Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There is a world of sea-shanties and tales of treasure in Norman Island, the alleged setting for Robert Louis Stevenson's <em>Treasure Island</em>. Popular with cruise boats and tourists, the uninhabited island is well-known for its sea caves that can be explored by curious divers.</p>]]><p><b>Relax on the beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visitors can sink into the sand and gaze upon shimmering aquamarine waters at beaches such as Smugglers' Cove, Long Bay, Brewer's Bay and Marina Cay. The white sand beaches come in all shapes and sizes, but each one provides the perfect backdrop to enjoy a glass of rum.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll around the Botanic Gardens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Joseph Reynold O'Neal Botanic Gardens on Tortola are perfect for a relaxing walk and breathing in the scent of lush, tropical plants native to the British Virgin Islands. Many of the plants in the collection are threatened and endangered and serve to build awareness of conservation on the islands.</p>]]><p><b>Take a dip in The Baths</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Baths in Virgin Gorda is a unique rock formation of dimly lit grottoes and caves most of which can only be reached by foot or boat. Visitors tend to come from adjacent islands such as St Thomas and Tortola and return via the Virgin Gorda airport.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hair-raising ride along Ridge Road</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The drive along the Ridge Road in Tortola offers spectacular panoramic views of Cane Garden Bay. However, the sharp twists and turns of the road are not for the faint-hearted driver. At places it becomes very steep and from a safe vantage point you can take some spectacular photographs.</p>]]><p><b>Take a walk on the wild side</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wildlife abounds on the island of Anegada, which is home to several rare species including the endangered Anegada rock iguana. The local economy is mainly geared towards tourism and fishing, with most of the population residing in the only village on the island, known simply as, The Settlement.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind in Road Town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>West Indian houses and a colourful market can be found in Road Town, the capital of the British Virgin Islands, on the south coast of Tortola. Visitors can see the ruins of Fort Burt or explore Fort Recovery, built in the 1640s. They can also get a taste of the local tipple at the Callwood Rum Distillery.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$840 million.</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Rum, fresh fish, fruit, animals, gravel and sand.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Building materials, cars, food and machinery.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>US Virgin Islands and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourism and financial services are the islands' main economic activities. Tourism employs around one-third of the working population directly or indirectly and accounts for about 45% of GDP. <br /><br />The offshore financial sector, which has been operating since the mid 1980s, has been a spectacular success, by virtue of the British connection, benign legislation and political uncertainty in rival centres (notably Hong Kong and Panama). However, in the last few years, the government has been forced to respond to international pressure to tighten its regulatory regime in order to prevent money laundering.<br /><br />Agricultural production is limited by poor soils, and relies mainly on livestock rearing, but some fruit and vegetables are produced for export. Rum is an important export commodity, and its distilling is the principal industrial activity.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A shirt and tie are required for the summer months; lightweight suits are normally worn at other times. Best time to visit is December to April.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0830/0900-1630/1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>The Government of the British Virgin Islands in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7355 9570
					Website:
					Address: London W1K 7PJ,15 Upper Grosvenor Street,UK,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>There is no shortage of excellent restaurants and inns serving local and international dishes. Most food is imported but local island specialities are often available. In addition to the hotels, eateries can be found on Tortola, Virgin Gorda and Jost Van Dyke.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Seafood dishes, including lobster (the Anegada lobster is reputedly the best in the Caribbean), fish chowder, snapper, whelks, mussel pie, conch stew and shark. <br />
&bull; <em>Roti</em> (flavourful East Indian flat bread, filled with meat or vegetables). <br />
&bull; <em>Pat&eacute;</em> (a dish baked or grilled, containing spiced meat, seafood or vegetables, stuffed into pita bread). <br />
&bull; <em>Fungi</em> (not actually related to the mushroom but instead refers to a delicious mixture of cornmeal and okra, usually served with seafood and probably closest to Italian polenta in flavour and consistency). <br />
&bull; Delicious local fruits such as soursop, papaya, mango, pineapple, guava, sugar apple, passion fruit and tamarind.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>All hotels add a 10 to 12% service charge.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many hotels have special nights with live music or dancing. There are several bars offering live music and/or DJs on both Virgin Gorda and Tortola. A full moon party takes place on the beach at Apple Bay, Tortola every month. There is one cinema (on Tortola). The British Virgin Islands Tourist Board publishes details of all forthcoming events in its publication, <em>The Welcome</em>, which appears every two months (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.bviwelcome.com">www.bviwelcome.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases include carved wooden items, straw-work, jewellery made from conch (pronounced 'konk') shell, rum, local spices and sauces and the attractive <em>batik</em> material, designed and made locally.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A wide range of hotel accommodation is available, from luxury resorts to boutique inns; the British Virgin Islands Tourist Board has a comprehensive list (<a href="http://www.bvitourism.com" target="_blank">www.bvitourism.com</a>). A 7% hotel accommodation tax is added to all bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A wide range of hotel accommodation is available, from luxury resorts to boutique inns; the British Virgin Islands Tourist Board has a comprehensive list (<a href="http://www.bvitourism.com" target="_blank">www.bvitourism.com</a>). A 7% hotel accommodation tax is added to all bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A wide range of hotel accommodation is available, from luxury resorts to boutique inns; the British Virgin Islands Tourist Board has a comprehensive list (<a href="http://www.bvitourism.com" target="_blank">www.bvitourism.com</a>). A 7% hotel accommodation tax is added to all bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There is only one hospital on the British Virgin Islands. Certain cases may be transferred to hospitals in the US Virgin Islands, Puerto Rico or mainland USA. There is a reciprocal health agreement with the &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom"&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt;; treatment for persons aged 70 or over and school-age children is normally free on presentation of proof of UK residence. Other visitors are charged for all services and are advised to take out medical insurance.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available and is advised for the first few weeks of stay. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccination against tuberculosis is sometimes recommended. Outbreaks of dengue fever can occur.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are generally observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>HL Stoutt's Birthday :
							05 March </p><p>Commonwealth Day :
							12 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Territory Day :
							01 July </p><p>August Festival :
							06 August </p><p>St Ursula's Day :
							21 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 230g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 0.95L of wine or spirits.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted goods include firearms, air guns, motorcycles with 125cc engines or bigger, caravans, jet skis, motor vehicles weighing over 5,000kg and video game machines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The list of prohibited and restricted exports is identical to the list of prohibited and restricted imports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar (USD; symbol US$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of US$100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of US$1 and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are accepted in some establishments. There are ATMs in Tortola and Virgin Gorda.</p><p>There are ATMs in Tortola and Virgin Gorda.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted in most places, particularly US Dollar cheques. All cheques are liable to a 10c stamp duty.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0900-1500/1600, Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter the British Virgin Islands, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.<b><br />
</b></p>
<p><strong>1.</strong> Canadian citizens can use an original birth certificate accompanied by valid photo ID, such as a driver's licence, but a passport is preferred.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British embassies charge &pound;115 for receiving, handling and forwarding visa applications for British Overseas Territories.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Embassy/High Commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If planning on bringing your pet to the British Virgin Islands, you must apply for an import permit from the Department of Agriculture before you arrive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[18.492010]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-64.550979]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>153 sq km (59 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>30,659 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>218.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Road Town, Tortola.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Overseas Territory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The 50-plus islands, rocks and cays of the British Virgin Islands, only 16 of which are inhabited, make up the larger part of an archipelago forming the northern extremity of the Leeward Islands in the eastern Caribbean. They are situated approximately 100km (62 miles) east of Puerto Rico, adjoining the US Virgin Islands. The islands are volcanic in origin, with the exception of Anegada, which is formed of coral and limestone and is the lowest lying. The topography is otherwise mountainous, the highest point being Tortola's Sage Mountain, which rises to 550m (1,800ft). There are remnants of a primeval rainforest on Tortola.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mainly Christian, including Methodist (45%), Anglican (21%) and Roman Catholic (6%).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The British Virgin Islands remain linked to the British Commonwealth, and the islanders reflect many British traditions and customs. The development of tourism proceeds with great caution; hence the unspoilt charm of these islands and cays remains the chief attraction. The pace of life is very easygoing. Shaking hands is the customary form of greeting. Dress is informal for most occasions apart from the formal requirements of some hotels. Beachwear should be confined to the beach or poolside.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without a third grounding pin) are used; some sockets may not accept plugs with a third pin however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Premier Orlando Smith since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor Gus Jaspert since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although there is evidence of habitation dating back to 1500 BC, the Islands were first settled by South American Arawaks around 100 BC before being supplanted by the Caribs in the 15th century.</p>
<p>Sighted by Columbus on his second voyage to the New World in 1493 he named them &lsquo;Santa Ursula y las Once Mil Virgenes&rsquo; &ndash; meaning &lsquo;Saint Ursula and her 1100 Virgins&rsquo;.</p>
<p>Over the following 200 years the Spanish, British, Dutch, French and Danish competed for control as the islands became a haven for pirates. The British captured the Dutch settlement on Tortola Island in 1672 and annexed Anegada and Virgin Gorda, which would become part of what we now know as the British Virgin Islands. Meanwhile, the Danes gained control over Saint Thomas, Saint John and Saint Croix.</p>
<p>In time the British established sugar cane plantations worked by slaves brought from Africa and the islands&rsquo; masters prospered until the mid-19th century when the abolition of slavery and a series of hurricanes all but destroyed the industry.&nbsp;In 1917 the USA bought the Danish islands for $25 million to establish the United States Virgin Islands.</p>
<p>The British Virgin Islands were administered as part of the British Leeward Islands with St Kitts and Nevis, before gaining colony status in 1960 and autonomy in 1967. Under its latest constitution, adopted in 2007, HM The Queen remains Head of State with the elected premier, currently Orlando Smith, serving as head of government and presiding over the single chamber parliament.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Although the British Virgin Islands are made up of more than 60 islands and cays, only 15 are inhabited.<br />
&bull;	Fungi, the traditional music of the islands, is named after a cornmeal dish made with okra.<br />
&bull;	Financial services account for more than half the islands&rsquo; income leading some to label the territory as a tax haven.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Her Majesty’s Passport Office in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7901 2334.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.bvi.org.uk/islands/visas</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7901 2334.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0745-1900, Sat 0915-1515 (appointments only).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>London Office, Globe House, 89 Eccleston Square<br/>London<br/>SW1V 1PN<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Diplomatic representation abroad]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sloping hills of green, lush mountainous terrain, extensive coral reefs and famous shipwrecks sum up the thrills and spills of the British Virgin Islands. With myriad nautical pursuits on offer, the 50 idyllic islands are a slice of paradise.</p><p>Norman Island was supposedly the location that Robert Louis Stevenson based <em>Treasure Island</em> on. Today's visitors might not stumble across swashbuckling pirates or half-concealed treasure troves, but they will find a highly prized booty of soft sand and gentle, teal waters. For travellers who prefer to watch the sea rather than get into it, there is the breathtaking chance of spotting dolphins and whales criss-crossing the surface.</p><p>Throughout much of their history, the string of islands and cays were sleepy and unnoticed. Today, colossal cruise ships glide to a halt in the shadow of Road Town on Tortola, the largest of the islands. Smaller ships also take in Virgin Gorda, the second biggest island, docking outside the curiously named Spanish Town. Hardly qualifying as a town, the latter has a few shops and a pretty marina, and is quiet, picturesque settlement. Road Town offers a little more action, with a gleaming harbour and waterfront, as well plenty of pastel-coloured West Indian architecture. Sir Olva Georges Square is a pleasant spot to take a seat and admire the views.</p><p>Although the tourism industry is booming here, you can easily get away from it all. Much of the accommodation beyond Road Town offers utter tranquility, while some of the hotels elsewhere in the territory pretty much have islands to themselves.</p><p>Paradise does come at a cost. Overall, the British Virgin Islands are quite an expensive destination. But, for some, this is the necessary price of saving a Caribbean gem from over-commercialisation. And if that's the intention, the British Virgin Islands are, for now, a resounding success.</p>Sloping hills of green, lush mountainous terrain, extensive coral reefs and famous shipwrecks sum up the thrills and spills of the British Virgin Islands.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
