<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Brunei" ColCode="brn" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bn" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Brunei]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no good or bad season to visit Brunei. You are likely to encounter warm, humid weather and at least some precipitation whenever you come, so whether you're coming for the shopping, the rain forests or the beaches, it's a good idea to bring along lightweight rain gear.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens. Waterproofing is advisable all year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no internal air services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Water taxis ply the Brunei River, linking Bandar Seri Begawan's waterfront with the sultanate's most renowned water village, Kampung Ayer. Be prepared to haggle a bit over the fare. Speedboats link Bandar Seri Begawan with Bangar, the main town in Temburong District.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost all of Brunei's cities, towns and villages are served by excellent paved roads.</p>l<p>Brunei's road network is of international standard.</p><p>Public buses link Bandar Seri Begawan's city centre bus terminal with towns such as Kuala Lurah, Muara, Tutong and Seria.</p><p>Brunei has only a small number of official taxis, all of them operated by independent drivers. The sultanate's only taxi rank is at Bandar Seri Begawan's bus terminal on Jalan Cator. Hotels can arrange cabs and supply drivers' mobile phone numbers. Taxis do not have meters so negotiate the fare before boarding. Tipping is not necessary.</p><p>Driving licences issued by other countries are valid for up to three months.</p><p>Vehicles drive on the left-hand side of the road. All car passengers are required to wear seat belts. Use of mobile phones while driving is prohibited. Speed limits are 100kph (62mph) on dual carriageways, 80kph (50mph) on single carriageways and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas.</p><p>If your car breaks down, roadside assistance is available 24 hours a day from 24-7 Assist (tel: +673 247 0247).</p><p>Self-drive or chauffeur-driven cars are available at the airport and through major hotels. Some companies have a minimum age of 23 and a maximum of 65. Brunei has some of the world's cheapest petrol.</p><p>Vehicles drive on the left-hand side of the road. All car passengers are required to wear seat belts. Use of mobile phones while driving is prohibited. Speed limits are 100kph (62mph) on dual carriageways, 80kph (50mph) on single carriageways and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The confusing public bus system serving Bandar Seri Begawan and its suburbs operates from about 0600-2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to Brunei are served by Royal Brunei Airlines (<a href="http://www.flyroyalbrunei.com" target="_blank">www.flyroyalbrunei.com</a>) ,the national carrier.</p>
<p>The major airport is: Brunei International Airport.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Brunei - 16 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 25 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Br$5 for flights to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/indonesia">Indonesia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malaysia">Malaysia</a> and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/philippines">Philippines</a>; Br$12 for all other destinations. This is payable in local currency in cash, at the airport check-in desk.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main port is Muara. Water taxis link Bandar Seri Begawan with the Malaysian towns of Limbang and Lawas. Car ferries connect Muara's Serasa Ferry Terminal with Menumbok and Pulau Labuan, both in Malaysia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving to Brunei from the Malaysian states of Sarawak and Sabah is a breeze thanks to the excellent Pan Borneo Highway. Bus services to and from Brunei are handled by Jesselton Express (to Sabah, tel: +673 714 5734; <a href="http://www.sipitangexpress.com.my" target="_blank">www.sipitangexpress.com.my</a>) and PHLS (to Miri, tel: +673 277 1668; <a href="http://www.phls38.com" target="_blank">www.phls38.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Coin- and card-operated public telephones are available at post offices and in major shopping areas. Telephone cards are sold at post offices and some shops. Reasonably priced international calls can be made from mobile phones with local SIM cards, public phones and internet cafes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with many international mobile phone companies. Local SIM cards can be purchased from Brunei's two mobile phone operators, DST Communications (<a href="http://www.dst-group.com" target="_blank">www.dst-group.com</a>) and b.mobile (<a href="http://www.bmobile.com.bn" target="_blank">www.bmobile.com.bn</a>). There is good mobile phone coverage in the main cities and towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes are available in Bandar Seri Begawan. Most hotels have internet computers or Wi-Fi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brunei's media are neither diverse nor free. The privately-owned press is either owned or controlled by the sultan's family, or exercises self-censorship on political and religious matters. A press law provides prison terms of up to three years for reporting &quot;false news&quot;. The main English-language newspaper is the <em>Borneo Bulletin</em> (<a href="http://www.borneobulletin.com.bn" target="_blank">www.borneobulletin.com.bn</a>). All local broadcast media are operated by government-controlled <em>Radio Television Brunei </em>(<a href="http://www.rtb.gov.bn" target="_blank">www.rtb.gov.bn</a>) Foreign TV stations are available via a cable network. Access to the internet is said to be unrestricted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Postal services (<a href="http://www.post.gov.bn" target="_blank">www.post.gov.bn</a>) are efficient and reliable. Airmail letters to Europe take two to five days. Courier companies include DHL (<a href="http://www.dhl.com.bn" target="_blank">www.dhl.com.bn</a>).</p><p>Mon-Thu & Sat 0800-1630, Fri 0800-1100 & 1400-1600</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bandar Seri Begawan Waterfront</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The waterfront of Brunei's capital, recently turned into a handsome pedestrian promenade, is a great place for a watery stroll, especially in the evening. Signs point out sights of historical interest, and restaurants offer local and "exotic" food and drink.</p>]]><p><b>Bandar Seri Gegawan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the finest view in Bandar Seri Gegawan, the capital, from the minaret crowning the golden-domed Sultan Omar Ali Saifuddien Mosque, which stands in the middle of its own artificial lagoon.</p>]]><p><b>Billionth Barrel Monument</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Witness the continuing importance of oil to Brunei's economy - the Billionth Barrel Monument near Kuala Belait is a testament to it.</p>]]><p><b>Brunei Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The sultanate's national museum has sections on Islamic art, traditional Bruneian culture and natural history. Highlights include 9th- and 10th-century ceramics and blown glass from the Near East, and a life-size diorama of a Malay wedding.</p>]]><p><b>Empire Hotel &amp; Country Club</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the architectural masterpiece that is the Empire Hotel &amp; Country Club (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.theempirehotel.com/">www.theempirehotel.com</a>), set in acres of tropical gardens at the doorstep of one of the oldest rainforests in southeast Asia. Its golf course has views over the South China Sea and it is Brunei's only beach resort.</p>]]><p><b>Istana Nurul Iman</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Said to be the world's largest residence of any sort anywhere in the world, this 1788-room palace is home to the sultan and his family. The interior can be visited only during the three-day Hari Raya Aidilfitri celebrations at the end of Ramadan but the exterior can be admired from the Brunei River.</p>]]><p><b>Jame'Asr Hassanil Bolkiah Mosque</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Brunei's grandest mosque, built in 1992 to celebrate the current sultan's silver jubilee on the throne, features intricate terrazzo tilework on the outside and spectacular opulence inside. The complex is especially magical around sunset.</p>]]><p><b>Jerudong Theme Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This once-extravagant amusement park has lost most of its rides to bankruptcy but has recently recast itself as a family-oriented theme park with plenty of performances, gardens and fountains - fun for children and adults alike.</p>]]><p><b>Kampong Ayer</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Built on stilts along the banks of the Brunei River, the sultanate's largest water village is an ideal place to get a sense of Bruneians' traditional way of life. After taking a water taxi over from downtown Bandar Seri Begawan, visitors can stroll among colourfully painted houses on wooden boardwalks.</p>]]><p><b>Kampong Labi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the hot springs and waterfalls, along with remote forest communities and more longhouses, in the Belait district, near Kampong Labi. River safaris up the Belait River are the best way to experience these.</p>]]><p><b>Kampung Ayer Cultural &amp; Tourism Gallery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Opened in 2009, this museum offers an interesting look at the history of the water village of Kampung Ayer and the crafts traditionally practiced there. A viewing tower affords panoramic views of the bustling Brunei River and the centre of Bandar Seri Begawan.</p>]]><p><b>Longhouses</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spot the splendid traditional longhouses in the Temburong district, an area with large tracts of virgin rainforest.</p>]]><p><b>Malay Technology Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Just down the hill from the Brunei Museum, this institution illustrates life in both a Malay water village and a Dayak longhouse. The displays are not the newest but are interesting if you'd like to learn more about local culture.</p>]]><p><b>Muara Beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Several stretches of sand suitable for sunbathing are situated not far from Brunei's main commercial and ferry ports. Food stalls make picnicking easy and delicious.</p>]]><p><b>Oil &amp; Gas Discovery Centre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Brunei's main centre of oil and gas production is home to a museum (<a href="http://ogdcbrunei.com/" target="_blank">www.ogdcbrunei.com</a>) dedicated to the extraction of petroleum, source of the sultanate's extraordinary riches. Sponsored by Brunei Shell, the centre has educational programmes featuring science and engineering.</p>]]><p><b>Omar Ali Saifuddien Mosque</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Named after the father of the current sultan, this magnificent mosque boasts dazzling golden domes, a 44m-high minaret, sparkling chandeliers and fine carpets. Completed in 1958, it is surrounded by a lagoon that creates dazzling reflections after sundown.</p>]]><p><b>Pulau Selirong mangrove</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The largest island in Temburong District, much of it covered with mangroves, has been turned into a wildlife sanctuary where visitors can often spot endangered proboscis monkeys. To get there, book a tour in BSB; it takes 45 minutes from Muara by boat. Other wildlife includes macaques, kingfishers and eagles.</p>]]><p><b>Royal Regalia Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The finest, most dazzling royal bling is the draw at this museum, which features the sultan's coronation parade on the ground floor and bejewelled gifts from world leaders upstairs.</p>]]><p><b>Tasek Merimbun lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drive out to Tasek Merimbun, Brunei's largest lake. Located in a hill resort in the Tutong District just over an hour's drive from Bandar Seri Begawan, peaceful picnicking, birdwatching and jungle trails await.</p>]]><p><b>Tomb of Sultan Bolkiah</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Check out the other royal sites, including the ancient Tomb of Sultan Bolkiah, the fifth sultan, known as the 'singing admiral' for his love of both music and conquest, and the Royal Regalia Building in the heart of the capital, home to a collection of ceremonial objects.</p>]]><p><b>Traditional sports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try out traditional sporting activities, such as gasing, a game involving highly polished giant tops, and kite flying.</p>]]><p><b>Twelve Roofs House</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once the colonial-era home of Brunei's British high commissioners, this hillside structure now houses exhibits illustrating the sultanate's "special relationship" with the United Kingdom. The evocative photos include views of Brunei a century ago.</p>]]><p><b>Ulu Temburong National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enlightened conservation practices have left Brunei's Temburong District with one of the largest tracts of unspoilt rain forest anywhere in Borneo. The small section open to visitors has a vertigo-inducing canopy walk. Access to the park is by motorised longboat.</p>]]><p><b>Watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Find more beaches at Muara, Serasa, Kuala Belait and Lumut Beach near Tutong, where watersports are popular.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$11.9 billion (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, natural gas and petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Chemicals, food, machinery and transport equipment and manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Japan, Indonesia, South Korea, Singapore, Australia</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brunei's economy is based on offshore oil and natural gas deposits and investments. Brunei's small population enjoys a very high standard of living and receives free health care and education (through until university). Unemployment is 3.7%, inflation is 2.7%. </p> <p>The economy has grown slowly in recent years due to reduced oil and gas production. Risk also stems from volatility in oil prices. The government is making efforts to reduce dependence on oil and gas in order to ensure that current standards of living remain sustainable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits for men and modest attire for women are recommended. In general, men and women do not shake hands with each other. Do not point with your index finger (use your right thumb). Gifts should be presented with the right hand. When sitting down, do not point the soles of your feet towards anyone.</p><p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1700, Sat 0800-1200. <br />
<br />
<strong>Government office hours:</strong> Mon-Thurs and Sat 0745-1215 and 1330-1630. Shortened office hours operate during the fasting month of Ramadan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>National Chamber of Commerce and Industry of Brunei Darussalam</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 243 321
					Website:
					Address: ,PO Box 115,Bandar Seri Begawan,BS8670]]><b>Brunei Darussalam International Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 226 000
					Website:
					Address: ,PO Box 2285,Bandar Seri Begawan,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Bruneian food is similar to Malay cuisine. Often quite spicy, favourites include satay, broiled fish, BBQ chicken and a variety of rice dishes. Some of the tastiest Bruneian delicacies are available at open-air markets such as Pasar Malam Gadong and Taman Selera in the capital. Restaurants in hotels, shopping centres and downtown BSB serve Chinese, Indian and European food.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Daging masak lada hitam</em> (spicy beef with potato beans).<br />
&bull; <em>Udang sambal serai bersantan</em> (prawns with chilli and coconut milk).<br />
&bull; <em>Serondeng padang</em> (chicken fried with garlic wrapped in pandan leaves).<br />
&bull; <em>Ambuyat</em> (goo made from ground sago tree pith, dipped in sauce).<br />
&bull; <em>Kelupis</em> (sticky rice steamed in a leaf).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol is prohibited, although it may be imported in certain quantities if reported to Customs. Most restaurants are open until 2100 or 2200 although this varies at the weekend.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tipping is not common practice but tourist-oriented hotels and restaurants often add 10% to the bill. Taxi drivers do not expect tips.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>The sale and public consumption of alcohol is forbidden.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The sale and public consumption of alcohol is banned, so Brunei's nightlife is pretty low-key - some would say downright snoozy. In the absence of bars, a night out in the capital usually consists of a meal, possibly followed by shopping or a film, in a suburban district such as Gadong or Kiulap.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopping is one of the favourite pastimes of Brunei nationals. The landmark Yayasan Complex, an upscale mall near the BSB waterfront, boasts the four-storey Hua Ho Department Store, classy boutiques and powerful air-con. Brunei's best-loved shopping district - including its largest shopping mall, The Mall - is in Gadong, 3km northwest of central BSB. Pricey textiles, silverwork, carved wood, ceremonial swords and even brass mini-cannons made by local artisans are on sale at the Arts & Handicrafts Training Centre, on the river east of BSB, but for simple souvenirs you'll get much better prices at Tamu Kianggeh, a sprawling outdoor market just east of downtown.</p><p>Shopping malls: daily 1000-2130. Opening hours of some shops may be shorter during Ramadan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brunei has about three dozen hotels. Accommodation in and around the capital ranges from ultra-luxury (the Empire Hotel &amp; Country Club) to youth hostel bunk beds, with just a handful of international hotels of four-star standard. Serviced apartments combining home comforts with hotel convenience are growing in popularity. Mid-range hotels can be found in major towns, including Kuala Belait, Seria and Bangar. For details, see <a href="http://www.bruneitourism.travel" target="_blank">www.bruneitourism.travel</a></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brunei's small number of very basic homestays are oriented almost exclusively to the domestic market.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brunei has about three dozen hotels. Accommodation in and around the capital ranges from ultra-luxury (the Empire Hotel &amp; Country Club) to youth hostel bunk beds, with just a handful of international hotels of four-star standard. Serviced apartments combining home comforts with hotel convenience are growing in popularity. Mid-range hotels can be found in major towns, including Kuala Belait, Seria and Bangar. For details, see <a href="http://www.bruneitourism.travel" target="_blank">www.bruneitourism.travel</a></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brunei has about three dozen hotels. Accommodation in and around the capital ranges from ultra-luxury (the Empire Hotel &amp; Country Club) to youth hostel bunk beds, with just a handful of international hotels of four-star standard. Serviced apartments combining home comforts with hotel convenience are growing in popularity. Mid-range hotels can be found in major towns, including Kuala Belait, Seria and Bangar. For details, see <a href="http://www.bruneitourism.travel" target="_blank">www.bruneitourism.travel</a></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical insurance that covers medical evacuation is advised. Medical facilities are of a high standard and many doctors are Western-trained. Emergency telephone numbers: ambulance - 991; police - 993; fire brigade - 995.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food is generally safe to eat but raw or undercooked dishes should be avoided. Although tap water in most parts of the country conforms to World Health Organization standards, some embassies advise drinking only boiled or bottled water, which is cheap and widely available.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mosquito-borne diseases such as dengue fever and Japanese encephalitis may occur so protection against mosquito bites is recommended. From July to October, forest fires in Indonesia sometime blanket Brunei with haze, causing health problems for some travellers.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday.<br /><br />Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>National Day :
							23 February </p><p>Royal Brunei Armed Forces Day :
							31 May </p><p>H.M. the Sultan's Birthday :
							15 July </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Brunei by travellers aged over 17 years without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 2 x 1L bottles of alcohol and 12 cans of beer (by non-Muslims for personal consumption only, provided declared at customs upon arrival).<br />
&bull; 60ml of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.</p>
<p>Duty is charged on all cigarettes and tobacco products.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include dangerous drugs (death penalty may apply), guns, ammunition, fire crackers, and cigarettes without a health warning printed on the packet.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include live plants and animals, vehicles, rice paddy (and products) and sugar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You cannot export petrol, diesel, cigarettes or antiques unless you receive authorisation from customs control.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brunei Dollar (BND; symbol B$) = 100 cents. Banknotes are in the denominations B$10,000, B$1,000, B$500, B$100, B$50, B$10, B$5 and B$1. Coins are in the denominations 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 cent. The Brunei dollar is pegged to the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a> dollar; banknotes denominated Singapore dollars are universally accepted in Brunei.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies and travellers cheques can be exchanged at any bank.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are generally accepted by hotels, department stores and major establishments. Credit card purchases may incur a surcharge of 3% to 5%.</p><p>Widely available in cities and towns but not all ATMs accept foreign credit/debit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers cheques can be exchanged for a fee at some banks, but few money changers accept them. Cheques denominated in pounds sterling, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars and Australian dollars are easiest to exchange. Hotels and many department stores cash traveller's cheques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1600; Sat 0900-1100. Shorter hours during Ramadan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Brunei, a passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A transit visa issued on arrival is available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: US$20; multiple-entry visa: US$30.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Up to three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consular section at embassy or high commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To receive an employment visa, you must first obtain a work permit from the Department of Immigration.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing usually takes up to seven working days, but applications which need to be referred to Brunei can take up to one month.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend your visa at any immigration office in Brunei.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brunei is a rabies-free country. Dogs and cats entering Brunei from anywhere other than the UK, Ireland, Australia, New Zealand and the Malaysian states of Sarawak and Sabah must spend 30 days in quarantine, and a further five months in 'home quarantine'.</p>
<p>Required documents include an import permit issued by the Department of Agriculture, a rabies vaccination certificate and a health certificate stating the animal is free of contagious or infectious disease. For details, see <a href="http://www.agriculture.gov.bn">www.agriculture.gov.bn</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[4.569968]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[114.748029]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5,765 sq km (2,226 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>428,874 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>74.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bandar Seri Begawan (popularly known as 'BSB').</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional Islamic monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brunei is on the northern coast of Borneo, the world's third-largest island, just 443km (277 miles) north of the equator. All its land borders are with the Malaysian state of Sarawak, which splits Brunei into two parts. The landscape is mainly pristine equatorial jungle drained by small rivers. Most settlements are situated along estuaries. There are four districts: Brunei-Muara (the capital district), Tutong and Belait (the centre of oil and gas exploitation), in the western part of the country; and non-contiguous, heavily forested Temburong, in the east. The islands in Brunei Bay fall within the Brunei-Muara or Temburong districts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Islam is the official state religion of Brunei, and about two-thirds of Bruneians are Muslims. Buddhists (mainly Chinese) make up about 13% of Brunei's population; Christians are 10%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors should dress modestly. Shoes must be removed when entering mosques and Muslim homes. Some Bruneians do not shake hands with people of the opposite sex.  It is impolite to point with the index finger (the right thumb should be used instead). Food may be served without cutlery: eat using the right hand only. It is widely regarded as discourteous to refuse refreshments or to eat in public during Ramadan.  </p>
<p>Visitors should note that there are severe penalties for all drug offences, and that the legal system in Brunei is partly based on Shariah law and can, occasionally, apply to non-Muslims, including visitors. Dress is informal except for special occasions. Women should ensure that their head, knees and arms are covered.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220/240 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are most commonly used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sultan Hassanal Bolkiah since 1967.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sultan Hassanal Bolkiah since 1967.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A tiny nation on the north coast of the island of Borneo, Brunei is separated into two parts by the Lambang district of the Malaysian territory of Sarawak.</p><p>The country's with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a> dates back at least a thousand years before the kingdom of Brunei was founded in the seventh century. Its kings converted to Islam around the 15th century and the Sultanate of Brunei was the region's dominant force for almost 200 years, winning a brief war with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a> before slipping into decline. The Bruneian Empire crumbled with the loss of much of its territory to the White Rajahs – a dynastic monarchy of the English Brooke family – of Sarawak in the 19th century and Brunei became a British protectorate in 1888.<br/><br/>Oil, discovered in the Seria area in the 1920s, changed Brunei forever. It was black gold that helped fuel Japanese interest in Borneo during World War 2 and just eight days after the attack on Pearl Harbor, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a> landed 10,000 troops on Brunei and occupied the country until June 1945 when Australian forces retook Brunei town.</p><p>Returned to British governance, a new constitution was written in 1959 introducing self-government and in the early 1960s oil – together with the failed Brunei Revolt of December 1962 – made it economically advantageous for the country to remain outside the Federation of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malaysia">Malaysia</a>.<br/><br/>Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah, the country's current absolute ruler and one of the world's richest people, became Brunei's 29th sultan in 1967. He rules under a national philosophy known as Malay Islamic Monarchy, which promotes Islamic traditions and values and loyalty to the sultan. The activities of political parties are severely restricted.<br/><br/>Brunei became self-governing except in foreign affairs and defence in 1971 and became fully independent from Britain in 1984. The country maintains close military, economic and cultural ties with the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>.</p><p>In 2013 Sultan Hassanal Bolkiah declared his intention to impose Sharia Law on the nation's Muslims, about two-thirds of the population, making Brunei the first and only country in the region to incorporate Sharia Law in its penal code.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p> Brunei is the first country in Asia to ban shark finning.</p><p> Under Sharia Law, Christmas decorations are banned in public places but local and foreign Christians are still allowed to celebrate Christmas.</p><p> Brunei has technically been under martial law since the Brunei Revolt of 1962 and Sultan Hassanal Bolkiah also serves as the country's Prime Minister, Finance Minister and Defence Minister.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Brunei Darussalam in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 237-1838 (for consular section ext 353).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.bruneiembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 237-1838 (for consular section ext 353).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3520 International Court<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission of Brunei Darussalam in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7581 0521 (ext 111/137 for consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7581 0521 (ext 111/137 for consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1300 and 1400-1630.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>20 Belgrave Square<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8PG<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission of the UK in Brunei Darussalam]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(673) 222 2231.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinbrunei.fco.gov.uk/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(673) 222 2231.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0830-1700, Fri 0830-1230.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Bandar Seri Begawan<br/>2nd fl, Unit 2.01, Block D, Yayasan Complex, Jln Pretty<br/>Darussalam<br/>BS8711<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to sizeable deposits of oil and gas, the tiny tropical sultanate of Brunei Darussalam has one of the highest standards of living in the world. Its two non-contiguous territories, situated on the northern coast of Borneo in South-East Asia, are home to some of the region's most pristine rain forest habitats.</p>
<p>The country only gained independence in 1984, but has the world's oldest reigning monarchy and centuries of royal heritage. At the helm of the only remaining Malay Islamic monarchy in the world, the Sultan of Brunei comes from a family line that dates back over 600 years. The current sultan, His Majesty Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah, has been on the throne for 43 years and is one of the world's richest individuals.</p>
<p>Visitors to the &quot;Abode of Peace&quot; (the literal translation of <em>darussalam</em>) will find the country surprisingly laid-back and relaxing. In addition to admiring the gilded domes, towering minarets and extraordinary ornamentation of two landmark mosques in the capital, Bandar Seri Begawan, tourists can explore water villages by boat and on foot, learn about local culture in several interesting museums, sample delicious Malay cuising (some of the best can be found at open-air markets), and experience the incredibly biodiversity of the Bornean rain forest in Ulu Temburong National Park.</p><p>Thanks to sizeable deposits of oil and gas, the tiny tropical sultanate of Brunei Darussalam has one of the highest standards of living in the world. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
