<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Bulgaria" ColCode="bgr" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bg" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Bulgaria]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate in Bulgaria varies according to altitude. Summers are warmest with some rainfall, with the south feeling the influence of the Mediterranean. The best months to visit are mid-June to September when the days are long and sunny. Winters are cold with good snowfall in the mountains. January is the best month for skiing in Bulgaria. It rains frequently during spring and autumn.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mediumweights most of the year; warmer outdoor wear necessary in winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bulgaria Air (<a href="http://www.air.bg/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.air.bg</a>) operates some domestic services, connecting Sofia with the Black Sea coast. The journeys from Sofia to Bourgas and Varna take one hour. Air travel is only slightly more expensive than first-class rail travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Private boats and yachts ply the Black Sea coast and the Danube.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Bulgarian State Railway, Balgarski Darzhavni Zheleznitsi (tel: +359 2 932 4190; <a href="http://www.bdz.bg" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.bdz.bg</a>), connects Sofia with main towns. Reservations are essential during peak seasons and first-class travel is advised. A first-class sleeper is a wonderful way to travel long distances, especially at night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass: </strong>offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Bulgaria. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tolls are charged on motorways and main roads out of town. Car-theft and car jacking are both on the increase in Bulgaria.</p>r<p>Road quality is variable and driving standards are generally poor.&nbsp;Night driving can be dangerous owing to poor lighting.</p><p>Available in all towns and also for intercity journeys. Vehicles are usually in good condition. All vehicles are metered, unless they are privately owned. Some drivers may try to drive without putting on the meter; ensure this is done before you leave. Look at the chart on the outside of the vehicle to see what the starting price is and to check the meter is not rigged. A small tip is appreciated.</p><p>All driving licences from EU countries are valid for Bulgaria. If travelling from outside the EU, an International Driving Permit is recommended, as well as a passport. A Green Card is useful, but not compulsory for EU travellers.</p><p>You can buy vignettes at ports, border points, post offices and DZI bank offices.</p>
<p>Speed limits are 120-140kph (75-87mph) on motorways, 90kph (56mph) outside built-up areas and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas.</p><p>UAB (tel: 146), operational only in Bulgarian territory.</p><p>Car hire is available through hotel reception desks, at Sofia Airport, and online in advance. Most of the major international car hire agencies are represented here.</p><p>You can buy vignettes at ports, border points, post offices and DZI bank offices.</p>
<p>Speed limits are 120-140kph (75-87mph) on motorways, 90kph (56mph) outside built-up areas and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bus, tramway and trolleybus services operate in Sofia, along with a small metro system. You can buy tickets from kiosks at major bus stops and newsagents; you must validate these upon boarding.</p>
<p>Buses and taxis operate in all the main towns. There are also trolleybuses in Plovdiv and Varna. Outside Sofia, bus tickets are purchased on board from the conductor.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bulgaria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">varna</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6:30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bulgaria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">plovdiv</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bulgaria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">pamporovo</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Bulgaria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bourgas</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5:30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Bulgaria Air (<a href="http://www.air.bg" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.air.bg</a>). British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>), Ryanair (<a href="http://ryanair.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">ryanair.com</a>) and Wizz Air (<a href="http://www.wizzair.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.wizzair.com</a>) also operate direct flights from the UK. There are no direct flights from the USA.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bulgaria/sofia-airport">Sofia Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bulgaria/burgas-airport">Burgas Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bulgaria/varna-international-airport">Varna International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>&nbsp;- 3 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 11 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Sofia Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.sofia-airport.bg<p>Sofia Airport is located 10km (6 miles) east of Sofia.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+359 2 937 2211.</p>]]><b>Varna International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.varna-airport.com<p>Varna Airport is located 8km (5 miles) to the west of Varna, a Black Sea resort in eastern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+359 52 573 323.</p>]]><b>Bourgas Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bourgas-airport.com<p>The airport  is 13km (8 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Burgas Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bourgas-airport.com<p>Burgas Airport is located 10km (6.2 miles) northeast of central Burgas.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+359 56 870 248</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Bourgas (<a href="http://www.port-burgas.bg" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.port-burgas</a>) and Varna (<a href="http://www.port-varna.bg/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.port-varna.bg</a>) on the Black Sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are frequent services between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sofia">Sofia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/budapest">Budapest</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belgrade">Belgrade</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bucharest">Bucharest</a>. For details contact the Bulgarian State Railway, Balgarski Darzhavni Zheleznitsi (<a href="http://www.bdz.bg" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.bdz.bg</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro. A One-Country Pass cannot be used in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Calls from some remote parts of the country must be placed through the international operator. There are many public telephones in the main towns, from which telephone cards are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is patchy to good in most of the country. It is easy to purchase domestic SIM cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi access is widely available in hotels, restaurants and bars. There are fewer internet cafes in Sofia and Plovdiv than there used to be owing to high rent, but there are a few internet gaming rooms. Varna has several places in the town centre, and the beach resorts have some facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bulgaria enjoys a relatively free press, although most media outlets are aligned to one political party. Bulgaria passed a broadcasting law in 1996, one of the last European countries to do so. National radio and TV were given the status of public services and granted independence. bTV, Bulgaria's first national commercial channel, was launched in May 2000 by Balkan News Corporation (part of Rupert Murdoch's News Corporation) and pulls in more than 35% of the TV audience. Nova TV won the bid for a second national commercial TV licence in 2003. Several privately owned regional television stations are also on the air.  The weekly newspaper, <em>Sofia Echo</em>, is available in English, as is the daily business publication <em>Pari</em> (Money). Both of these are available in print or online versions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes from four days to two weeks. The General Post Office in Sofia, at 6 Gurko Street, is open 24 hours.</p><p>Usually Mon-Sat 0830-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Baba Vida Castle</p><![CDATA[<p>Built on the banks of the River Danube in the town of Vidin in the northwestern tip of the country, Baba Vida Castle occupies a commanding position overlooking the town. The present castle is actually built upon the foundations of a Roman fortress known as Bononia which marked the Danubian Frontier of the Roman Empire from the first to the seventh centuries. Baba Vida Castle was actually built during the 10th century and is the only medieval fortress to have survived intact to the present day. The castle is protected by inner and outer walls and is ringed by a moat filled with water from the Danube. Today, the castle is host to a number of theatre productions during the summer and is often used as a historical film set. There's also an onsite museum with exhibitions about the region's history.</p>]]><br/><p>Rila Monastery</p><![CDATA[<p>Be fascinated by the vast collection of murals, woodcarvings, old weapons and bibles written on parchment at Rila Monastery, 121km (75 miles) from Sofia. Fire has destroyed most of the early 10th-century architecture, and the present buildings date from the 19th century, with the exception of the 14th-century Khrelio's Tower.</p>]]><br/><p>Trigrad Gorge</p><![CDATA[<p>Spectacular Trigrad Gorge is in the Rhodope Mountains close to the town of Trigrad in Southern Bulgaria, and is flanked by walls rising to 250m (820ft). One of the most popular sites at the gorge is Devil's Throat Cave which formed when layers of the mountain collapsed. From here, visitors can travel through a manmade tunnel to see the highest underground waterfalls in Europe which cascade 42m (138ft) into the abyss below. Nearby is the famous Haramiiska Cave where archaeologists discovered evidence of human habitation dating back over 4,000 years. There are over 150 other caves in the region and the area is popular with rock climbers; numerous companies provide guides and tuition. The region is also popular with birdwatchers who come to see Pallid swifts, Crag martins, Rock Partridges and the rare Wallcreeper.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Ancient spas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax in one of Bulgaria's many mineral water spas. The curative properties of the Bulgarian mineral waters have been known and used for centuries. Ancient mineral complexes were built near the mineral springs and there are now plenty of top hotels with spas, especially around the Black Sea coast.</p>]]><p><b>Bachkovo Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated 28km (17 miles) from Plovdiv, the monastery was founded in the 11th century and is home to rare frescoes, icons, manuscripts and coins. Bachkovo lies within the area known in ancient times as Thrace, and many items of archaeological interest have been discovered, including wonderful gold Thracian objects.</p>]]><p><b>Belogradchik</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the age-old town of Belogradchik, nestled in the foothills of the Balkan Mountains in northwest Bulgaria. The main attractions include the Belogradchik Fortress, the ancient Magura Cave on Rabisha Lake, and the Belogradchik Rocks, a wondrous expanse of bizarrely shaped, colourful rock formations, named a Natural Landmark by the Bulgarian government. Visit the local History Museum (<a href="http://www.muzeibelogradchik.com/index_en.html" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.muzeibelogradchik.com</a>)for more information and ticket prices.</p>]]><p><b>Biking tours</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For mountain biking enthusiasts, the Rhodope mountains provide excellent trails, while cycling along the Black Sea coast is a popular family activity.</p>]]><p><b>Climb every mountain</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Organised mountaineering and climbing trips can be arranged in the areas of Vratsa, Veliko Tarnovo, Troyan, Malyovitza and Rusenski Lom. The steep rocks of the Pirin, Rhodope, Rila and Stara Planina are popular with expert climbers, and there are numerous caves and spectacular rock formations, many with ancient cave paintings.</p>]]><p><b>Go hiking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bulgaria has 35,000km (21,748 miles) of way marked paths and one- or two-week trips through the wild mountains can be arranged. Guides are provided and accommodation is usually in mountain chalets, guesthouses or camps.</p>]]><p><b>Inhale the scent of roses</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For centuries Bulgarians have planted roses, and extracted their heavenly essence - attar of roses. The Rose Valley is magically transformed with breathtaking blooms in May and early June each year when The Festival of Roses is celebrated in many towns of the region.</p>]]><p><b>Melnik wine cellars</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the fruits of the vine in Melnik. The tiny town, with 18th- and 19th-century houses perched on strangely shaped limestone and sand pyramids, is famous for its wine cellars. At weekends, Bulgarians flock here for its wonderful mehanas, for traditional food and the local brew.</p>]]><p><b>National parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get back to nature in Bulgaria's national parks. These include the ancient Bailusheva pine forests and limestone rocks in Pirin National Park, the seven lakes and 10th-century monastery in Rila National Park, and the Raiskoto Praskalo waterfall, the highest in Bulgaria and the Balkan peninsula (<a href="http://www.bulgariannationalparks.org/" target="_blank">www.bulgariannationalparks.org</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Plovdiv's old city</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bulgaria's second-largest city is divided by the Maritsa River. Get lost in history around the narrow cobbled streets and quaint houses, and visit the Roman Amphitheatre which is still in use. Test your navigation skills and see if you can visit the ancient monuments that dot the Old Town such as Nebet Tepe and the Eastern Gate.</p>]]><p><b>Rila Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Be fascinated by the vast collection of murals, woodcarvings, old weapons and bibles written on parchment at Rila Monastery, 121km (75 miles) from Sofia. Fire has destroyed most of the early 10th-century architecture, and the present buildings date from the 19th century, with the exception of the 14th-century Khrelio's Tower.</p>]]><p><b>Roman Thermae in Varna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located in the territory of the ancient city Odessus, the magnificent roman baths in Varna are a relic of Roman legacy in Bulgaria. Visit the well-preserved baths, the largest Roman public building in Bulgaria, and then wander through the seaside city of Varna for sweeping views of the Black Sea and endless historical landmarks.</p>]]><p><b>Saddle up</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Horse riding has traditionally been popular in Bulgaria; possible itineraries include the Danube Valley, the Balkan, Rila and Stara Planina mountains and the Valley of Roses.</p>]]><p><b>Sample the folklore</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bulgaria's traditional music festivals are an important part of Bulgarian rural life. Pirin Folk festival features the famous Pirin Folk Ensemble, a major group based in Blagoevgrad. Participants from different countries gather to share traditions, culture and languages on behalf of folklore songs.</p>]]><p><b>Ski the slopes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Quaint Bansko (<a href="http://www.banskoski.com/" target="_blank">www.banskoski.com</a>) is the newest ski area, set in a historical town at the foot of the Pirin Mountains; Pamporovo (<a href="http://www.pamporovoresort.com/" target="_blank">www.pamporovoresort.com</a>), in the Rhodope range, is the best-known in Southeastern Europe; and Borovets (<a href="http://www.borovets-bg.com/" target="_blank">www.borovets-bg.com</a>), in the Rila Mountains, is Bulgaria's oldest and largest mountain resort.</p>]]><p><b>Sofia architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the Greek, Roman, Byzantine and Ottoman architectural styles of the capital, Sofia, boasting museums, monuments, churches, art galleries and opera houses. The stunning gold leaf domed Nevski Memorial Church is the most famous sight, with the sixth-century St Sofia and the Museum of archaeology nearby.</p>]]><p><b>Swim in the Black Sea</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bulgaria has over 370km (230 miles) of glorious coastline with sandy beaches. Try busy resorts Sunny Beach and Golden Sands, picturesque Albena, historical Nesebar, the cultural and historical city of Varna, or the Mediterranean ambience of port city Bourgas.</p>]]><p><b>Trigrad Gorge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spectacular Trigrad Gorge is in the Rhodope Mountains close to the town of Trigrad in Southern Bulgaria, and is flanked by walls rising to 250m (820ft). It&rsquo;s one of the most popular sites at the gorge is Devil's Throat Cave. Visitors can travel through a manmade tunnel to see the highest underground waterfalls in Europe, which cascade 42m (138ft) into the abyss below. Nearby is the famous Haramiiska Cave where archaeologists discovered evidence of human habitation dating back over 4,000 years.</p>]]><p><b>UNESCO wonders</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover Bulgaria's ten UNESCO-listed World Heritage Sites, including the perfectly preserved fourth-century murals in the Thracian Tomb of Kazanlak, the Thracian Tomb of Sveshtari near Razgrad, the 13th-century Boyana Church on the outskirts of Sofia, and the Ivanovo Rock Monasteries near Ruse.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Valley of the Thracian Kings</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stroll amongst the ancient burial mounds in the valley of Kazanlak. As well as the famous Kazanlak tomb there are interesting tombs at the villages of Krum, Maglizh, the Koprinka Dam and many others.</p>]]><p><b>Veliko Tarnovo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the ancient museum town of Veliko Tarnovo, capital of the Second Bulgarian Empire (1185-1396), situated on three hills circled by the River Yantra. It contains extraordinary collections of historic works of art, including church relics.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$152.4 billion (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, tobacco, wine, clothing, footwear, iron and steel, chemicals, IT components, electronics and machinery.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, fuel products, minerals, raw materials, chemicals, metals and ores, machinery and equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Russia, Germany, Italy, Turkey, Romania, France, Poland and Greece.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In general, Bulgaria has suffered the usual problems experienced by centrally planned economies adjusting to market conditions. Successive governments have followed the path taken by other former Communist governments, under which most industry and agriculture was privatised, trade liberalised and reforms of the fiscal and banking systems instituted. However, some key privatisations (tobacco, telecoms, banking) have already experienced difficulties, possibly threatening the stability of the government.<br />
<br />
The value of the Bulgarian Lev was fixed to the Deutschmark by the currency control board created in 1997; it is now linked to the Euro. The economy declined slightly to -4.9% in 2009, following a large increase in previous years. However, inflation has been brought down to single figures and in 2006 was 1.6%.<br />
<br />
In 1990, Bulgaria joined the IMF, which has had a major influence on the country's economic policy, along with the World Bank and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development. Bulgaria became a member of the European Union in January 2007.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business visitors to Bulgaria should request meetings well in advance and arm themselves with documents detailing interest and position. Bulgarian people with senior positions are likely to be former Communist party members, so be prepared for some officiousness. Otherwise most meetings are more relaxed, often followed by lunch or dinner.</p>
<p>Dress code is standard suit and tie for men, although this could well be more relaxed especially in warmer weather. Women are expected to wear similarly formal attire &ndash; revealing clothing is generally unacceptable.  Conservative but stylish is preferred, but dress code depends on the industry and working environment.</p>
<p>English is generally well understood, although employing an interpreter can help. Interpreters can be organised through tourist agencies. If arranged in advance through foreign trading organisations, services are free. Note that in Bulgaria, nodding of the head means 'no', while shaking the head means 'yes'.</p>
<p>Standard office hours are 0900-1800 and punctuality is important - even if locals tend to be a little late. Bureaucracy is often slow and complicated, so patience is essential. However, after-hours socialising with Bulgarians is lively, with a prodigious intake of food and alcohol - foreigners are advised not to attempt to keep up. Inviting business contacts to lunch or dinner is a common practice, and dinners often last for a few hours. Lunch usually begins at noon and dinner at 1900 or later. Favourite topics of conversation are sports and new economic and political changes. Gift giving is a delicate matter as corruption is still widespread, so it is better to give an &lsquo;original&rsquo; gift rather than an expensive one, which could be perceived in a number of ways.  Alcohol or branded office materials are customary.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bulgarian Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (02) 987 2631
					Website:http://www.bcci.bg
					Address: ,ulitska Iskar 9,Sofia,1058]]><b>British-Bulgarian Chamber of Commerce in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 8464 5007
					Website:http://www.bbcc.bg/
					Address: Bromley,PO Box 123,BR1 4ZX,]]><b>North American-Bulgarian Chamber of Commerce in the USA</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 1 800 269 2152
					Website:http://www.nabcc.org
					Address: Suite 200,851 Irwin Street,San Rafael,9490]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Dinner is a social occasion, with traditional music and dancing in many restaurants, especially in resorts and in some Sofia eateries. Food is hearty and good. Meals usually start with a salad, from which there are many to choose from on the menu. <br />
<br />
There are a wide variety of national dishes, as well as Western European standard dishes, which can be chosen on the spot at any restaurant. All good hotels have restaurants and there are many attractive folk-style restaurants and caf&eacute;s throughout the country.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Tarator</em>&nbsp;- cold soup made from cucumber, walnuts and yoghurt<br />
&bull; <em>Shopska salata</em>&nbsp;- huge salad starter with tomatoes, cucumbers, peppers and white cheese<br />
&bull; <em>Kavarma</em>&nbsp;- individual casseroles of pork or veal, onions and mushrooms<br />
&bull; <em>Sarmi</em>&nbsp;- stuffed vine or cabbage leaves stuffed with meat<br />
&bull; <em>Kebapche</em>&nbsp;- small, strongly spiced, minced meat rolls</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Apart from the top hotels, restaurants rarely add service charge so a 10% tip is customary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some restaurants have folk dancing and music. Opera is performed at the State Opera House in Sofia, as well as in Plovdiv and other cities. You can also listen to classical concerts performed by local orchestras or the National Folk Ensemble. <br />
<br />
Bulgaria has a thriving nightclub and bar scene, with Sofia, Bourgas, Plovdiv and other resorts pumping out great music including the locally popular chalga (home-grown gypsy/dance/techno music) and international sounds. Good 'what's on' guides on major cities and resorts can be found in tourist offices and hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main shopping area of Sofia is on both sides of bulvard Vitosha Boulevard. Bulgarian products, clothes, shoes, handicrafts, wines, spirits and confectionery can all be purchased. Graf Ignatiev Street and Pirotska Street are busy streets with local clothes and electrical stores.</p><p>General shops Mon-Sat 1000-2000; shopping malls Mon-Sun 1000-2200.</p><p>Many supermarkets are open all day, everyday.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There has been a vast increase in the number of hotels in Bulgaria, mostly in cities and tourist resorts, and notably more guest houses in Sofia. Advance booking is advisable especially when travelling in high season to major resorts, and to Sofia. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are classified according to the European star-grading system, with 1 to 5 stars displayed outside, and although standards are comparatively low, they are improving. Special care has been taken in most hotels to conform to international standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation in Bulgaria is available in small villas with private rooms, particularly near the coast, but also in small towns and villages inland in older houses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There has been a vast increase in the number of hotels in Bulgaria, mostly in cities and tourist resorts, and notably more guest houses in Sofia. Advance booking is advisable especially when travelling in high season to major resorts, and to Sofia. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are classified according to the European star-grading system, with 1 to 5 stars displayed outside, and although standards are comparatively low, they are improving. Special care has been taken in most hotels to conform to international standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There has been a vast increase in the number of hotels in Bulgaria, mostly in cities and tourist resorts, and notably more guest houses in Sofia. Advance booking is advisable especially when travelling in high season to major resorts, and to Sofia. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are classified according to the European star-grading system, with 1 to 5 stars displayed outside, and although standards are comparatively low, they are improving. Special care has been taken in most hotels to conform to international standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;If European visitors or any of their dependants are suddenly taken ill or have an accident during a visit to Bulgaria, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). All nationals are advised to take out comprehensive travel insurance.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is generally safe and drinkable, but there have been reports of contamination in some rural areas so some travellers may prefer to drink bottled water for the first few weeks of their stay. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. All food is prepared with a good level of hygiene.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B is endemic. Hepatitis C may occur. Tick-borne encephalitis exists. Immunisation against tuberculosis is sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>National Day (Day of Liberation) :
							03 March </p><p>Orthodox Easter :
							06 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>St George's Day (Day of Bulgarian Army) :
							06 May </p><p>St Cyril and Methodius Day (Day of Culture and Literacy) :
							24 May </p><p>Unification Day :
							06 September </p><p>Independence Day :
							22 September </p><p>Day of the Bulgarian Revival Leaders :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Eve :
							24 December </p><p>Christmas :
							25 December </p><p>New Year's Eve :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bulgaria is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/united-kingdom/">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragrance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Bulgaria by persons over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco (if arriving by air).<br />
&bull; 40 cigarettes or 20 cigarillos or 10 cigars or 50g (if arriving overland).<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lev (BGN; symbol лв) = 100 stotinki. Notes are in denominations of лв100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 (this is rarely used). Coins are in denominations of лв1 and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 stotinki.<br />
<br />
<strong>Note:</strong> (a) The Lev is tied to the Euro at a fixed rate; &euro;1 = лв1.955. (b) Notes dated 1997 and earlier are now out of circulation. Euro coins will replace the lev once the convergence criteria are fulfilled.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are advised to exchange money at banks, at large hotels and at independent currency exchange offices, where the rates are clearly displayed. Travellers should not be tempted by a 'better rate' offered at unofficial sources on the street. It is illegal for commission to be charged when changing money at official offices. No store, bank or bureau de change will accept mutilated, torn or excessively dirty foreign currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted in large cities, in larger hotels and car hire offices, and in some restaurants and shops, mainly in <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/bulgaria/sofia/">Sofia</a>. However, Bulgaria is still a country that operates mainly on cash.</p><p>ATMs are widespread, although it is best to check with the relevant bank/card provider prior to travel. Not all Bulgarian bank machines accept every overseas credit or debit card; it may take more than one attempt to withdraw cash successfully.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted in major hotels and restaurants, although cash is far more common. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars, Pounds Sterling or Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Bulgaria, a passport valid for at least three months beyond the length of stay is required by all nationals referred to in chart above, except (1) EU nationals holding a valid national ID card.</p>
<p>EU nationals are only required to produce evidence of their EU nationality and identity in order to be admitted to any EU member state. This evidence can take the form of a valid national passport or national identity card. Either is acceptable. They are not required to show possession of a return ticket, a certain length of validity on their document or sufficient funds for the length of their proposed visit.</p>
<p>For non-EU nationals, possession of a return ticket and sufficient funds for the length of the proposed visit are required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas are available to travellers passing through Bulgaria for no more than 24 hours en route to another country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Those who do require a visa must show proof of sufficient funds to support their stay in Bulgaria when applying for the visa. This is equivalent to &euro;100 euros per day. If you don&rsquo;t have return airfares arranged beforehand, proof of having &euro;300 euros to cover the cost of leaving Bulgaria is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay visa: &pound;52.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay visas are valid for 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The processing time for transit and short-stay visas is 15 working days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Those who do require a visa must show proof of sufficient funds to support their stay in Bulgaria when applying for the visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet from another EU country, your animal requires a pet passport, microchip and rabies vaccination certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[42.766997]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[25.281992]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110,879 sq km (42811 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>7,101,510 (UN estimate 2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>64.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sofia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bulgaria is situated in Eastern Europe and bordered to the north by the River Danube and Romania, to the east by the Black Sea, to the south by Turkey and Greece and to the west by Serbia and the Republic of Macedonia. The Balkan Mountains cross the country reaching to the edge of the Black Sea and its golden beaches.</p>
<p>The land is heavily cultivated, covered with forests and crossed by rivers. Although Bulgaria lies in the very southeast corner of Europe, the climate is temperate &ndash; cold, damp winters and hot, dry summers. The Black Sea resorts have some of the largest beaches in Europe and offer sunbathing from May until October, while in winter heavy falls of snow are virtually guaranteed in the mountain ski resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the population are Christian, the main denomination being Bulgarian Orthodox Church with a membership of 59.4% of the population. Eastern Orthodox Christianity is considered to be the traditional religion in Bulgaria. There is also a significant Muslim minority (7.8%) and a small Jewish community.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal courtesies should be observed and handshaking is the normal form of greeting. Dress should be conservative but casual. If invited to the home, a small souvenir from one's homeland is an acceptable gift, and something for their children is always welcome. Do not give money. Remember that a nod of the head means 'No' and a shake means 'Yes'. <br />
<br />
<strong>Smoking: </strong>Bulgarian restaurants, caf&eacute;s and nightclubs have zones for smokers and non-smokers. There is no smoking in public places.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220-240 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bojko Borisov (Prime Minister) since April 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Rumen Radev since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bulgaria is the oldest surviving state in Europe to have kept its original name &ndash; since 681CE &ndash; and most of the population are descendants of the Bulgar invasion of the south Danube around that time.</p>
<p>On two occasions during the medieval period - between the 7th and 11th centuries and again between the 12th and 14th centuries - the Bulgarians managed to establish empires, which existed in a state of armed conflict with Byzantium.</p>
<p>The rising power in the Balkans, the Serbs, overran Bulgaria&rsquo;s territory in Macedonia. However, their dominance was short-lived as the Ottoman Turks arrived in the 1350s and within 40 years, the country had been completely absorbed into the Ottoman Empire.</p>
<p>Following an uprising in 1876, Bulgarian volunteer forces, with strong Russian support, defeated the Turks and established an independent state.</p>
<p>King Ferdinand was the dominant figure in Bulgarian politics up to World War I, although he was discredited thereafter due to his support for the Germans. The popular Agrarian leader, Aleksandur Stambolyiski, imprisoned by Ferdinand, formed a reformist government that lasted until 1923 when it was overthrown in a right-wing coup.</p>
<p>The government of Alexander Tsankov, which replaced Stambolyiski&rsquo;s administration, established a royalist-militarist government with King Boris as head of state.</p>
<p>Soviet forces entered the country in 1944, the monarchy was abolished, and a republic was declared.</p>
<p>By the end of 1947, the Communist Party had completed its takeover of the country.</p>
<p>Bulgaria&rsquo;s dominant political figure was Todor Zhivkov, under whose leadership Bulgaria became the staunchest of Moscow&rsquo;s allies.</p>
<p>In 1989, Zhivkov resigned and the first multi-party elections for 44 years were held in June 1990 with the ruling Communists restyling themselves the Bulgarian Socialist Party (BSP) and winning an absolute majority.</p>
<p>Throughout the first half of the 1990s, Bulgaria was wracked by instability and plunged into economic crisis with a range of personality-lead parties such as former King Simeon II&rsquo;s populist liberal NDSV and the ruling centre-right GERB Party emerging to oppose the BSP.</p>
<p>In recent years Bulgarian politics have stabilised and the country is considered to have a good record on freedom of speech and human rights.</p>
<p>Bulgaria became a NATO member in 2004, and joined the EU in 2007.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong></p>
<p>
&bull; Swiss-born gymnast Charles Champaud competed for Bulgaria in the first modern Olympics in Athens in 1896, the year after he brought football to the capital Sofia.<br/>
&bull; To welcome spring each year martenitsa, small red and white dolls made of yarn, are traditionally worn from 1 March until the wearer first sees a stork, swallow or blossoming tree.<br/>
&bull; Estimated to be over 1670 years old, the Granit Oak &ndash; a common oak tree named after the village in which it is found &ndash; may be the oldest living oak tree in the world.<br/>
</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Bulgaria in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 387 0174 or 7969 (consular office: Mon-Fri 1400-1700 only).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.bulgaria-embassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 387 0174 or 7969 (consular office: Mon-Fri 1400-1700 only).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1730; Mon-Fri 0900-1230 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW, Dimitar Peshev Plaza<br/>1621 22nd Street<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Bulgaria in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7581 3144 or +44 20 75849400 or  +44 20 7589 3763 (visa section; individual enquiries; Mon-Fri 1300-1600 only).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.bulgarianembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7581 3144 or +44 20 75849400 or  +44 20 7589 3763 (visa section; individual enquiries; Mon-Fri 1300-1600 only).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1330 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Kensington<br/>186-188 Queen's Gate<br/>London<br/>SW7 5HL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bulgaria's spectacular mountains, golden beaches and vibrant cities have begun attracting hordes of eager-eyed tourists over the past few years, and with them much has been transformed in this crossroads between the Mediterranean and Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>The country's mammoth changes have seen its cities and resorts undergoing construction booms galore, tempting buyers from Western Europe with relatively cheap property and stunning landscapes.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's beautiful beach and ski resorts are expanding quickly as a result and have lured visitors away from more expensive European destinations with low-priced lift passes and accommodation options. The main cities have shrugged off their weary Communist-era image and have become vibrant and attractive, with well-kept boulevards, varied shopping and lively nightlife. In contrast, many towns and villages have preserved the authentic Bulgarian spirit and hospitality -  the country is especially proud of its rich folklore traditions.</p>
<p>Hikers will find a variety of mountain ranges covering much of the country, with plenty of extraordinary wildlife to be glimpsed along the way. The walking trails are well mapped, taking hikers through forests, past lakes and waterfalls, with the chance to glimpse bears, wolves and lynx.  Those keen on caving and kayaking will also find plenty to entertain them, while skiing and snowshoeing is also popular here.</p>
<p>Of course, the attraction that brings most visitors to Bulgaria is its remarkably unspoiled beaches strewn along the Black Sea coast. Less-visited, less-developed and with lots of facilities for water sports, Bulgaria's sandy beaches are the equal to almost any of the more popular coastal spots in the Mediterranean. What&rsquo;s more, you&rsquo;ll find many aged seaside towns complete with cobbled streets and historic buildings. Indeed, those interested in history will find Bulgaria a haven of Byzantine heritage, with a long tradition of Orthodox Christian churches and religious art. There are also a number of intriguing, secluded monasteries that are worth visiting especially for their detailed murals.</p><p>Bulgaria's spectacular mountains, swathe of golden beaches and vibrant cities have begun attracting hordes of eager-eyed tourists over the past few years - a dramatic change to how the country was a mere 10 years ago. In fact, Bulgaria has been through mammoth changes in the last few years, with many of the cities and resorts undergoing construction booms galore, tempting buyers from Western Europe with relatively cheap property and stunning landscapes. Bulgaria's beautiful beach and ski resorts are expanding quickly as a result and have lured visitors away from more expensive European destinations with low-priced lift passes and accommodation options. The main cities have shrugged off their weary Communist-era image and have become vibrant and attractive, with well-kept boulevards, varied shopping and lively nightlife. In contrast, many towns and villages have preserved the authentic Bulgarian spirit and hospitality -  the country is especially proud of its rich folklore traditions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
