<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Burundi" ColCode="bdi" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bi" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Burundi]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A hot equatorial climate is found near Lake Tanganyika and in the Ruzizi River plain. It is often windy on the lake. The rest of the country is mild and pleasant. Burundi has two rainy seasons - the major one from February to May, with a minor rainy season between September and November, and two dry seasons: the long dry season from June to August and the shorter dry season between December and January.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens with waterproofs for the rainy season. Warm clothes are recommended for the evening.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no scheduled internal flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are main roads east from Bujumbura to Muramvya (once the royal city of Burundi) and south to Gitega.  Both journeys can be completed without too much strain during the dry season, but any road travel can be difficult in the rainy season. Avoid&nbsp;travelling by road outside Bujumbura after dark.&nbsp;</p>r<p>Few roads are paved, and even these are not always in great condition.</p><p><em>Tanus-tanus</em> (truck taxis) are usually available but they are often crowded.</p><p>You can drive on a valid national driving licence for up to six months.</p><p>Car hire is available from local companies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Air Burundi (<a href="http://www.flyairburundi.com" target="_blank">www.flyairburundi.com</a>). If travelling from the UK, options include flights with Kenya Airways (<a href="http://www.kenya-airways.com" target="_blank">www.kenya-airways.com</a>) via Nairobi or Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="http://www.ethiopianairlines.com" target="_blank">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>) via Addis Ababa. Travellers coming from the USA usually need to make at least two stopovers.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 23 hours (including stopovers).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$20.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bujumbura International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 11km (7 miles) north of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage mainly in the west of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in some areas. There are a few Internet caf&eacute;s in Bujumbura.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Burundi's media are self-censored and also receive occasional government censorship. Nevertheless, a range of political views are sometimes aired. There is a high turnover rate for newspapers. The sale of newspapers is quite low due to small print runs and low levels of literacy. The main source of information for many Burundians is therefore the radio. The only radio station with national coverage is government-owned, as is Burundi's only TV station.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main office in Bujumbura is open Mon-Fri 0730-1200 and 1400-1730, Sat 0830-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the flora and fauna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For a small nation, Burundi has a diverse series of habitats, ranging from savannah to blooming fields and mountain forests that are home to myriad species of both plant and animal life. Just 15km (9miles) from the capital, Rusizi National Park provides a wetland habitat for hippos, while Ruvubu National Park also contains a sizable population of leopards.</p>]]><p><b>Be beguiled by Gitega</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gaze across the beautiful vistas of Burundi's central plains from the mountaintops of the Congo-Nile range in Gitega before exploring the second city's exquisite charm, from the history of the <em>ibwani</em> (or Royal Court) and National Museum, to the natural beauty of the Chutes de la Kagera waterfalls.</p>]]><p><b>Echo Stanley’s famed words</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Around 10km (6miles) south of Bujumbura is a large stone that is said to mark the historic first meeting between Stanley and Livingstone in 1871. Having pushed through equatorial Africa from the coast to locate the lost missionary and explorer David Livingstone, Stanley is supposed to have been mortified when all he could muster was 'Dr Livingstone, I presume?'</p>]]><p><b>Experience drumming rituals</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located on a hilltop outside the town of Gitega, Gishora Drum Sanctuary was founded by King Mwezi Gisabo at the end of the 19th century to protect the ritual drums of the royal court. Today, a reconstructed palace houses the retinue drums used to announce important events, and two important unplayed drums named Ruciteme and Murimirwa.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the capital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On Lake Tanganyika's northern shore, Bujumbura is a bustling city of 200,000 people. Growing in size after German colonisation in the 19th century, the city centre still includes a number of colonial-era buildings, including the Postmaster's House. Other attractions include an excellent market, the Islamic Cultural Centre, and the <em>museé vivant</em>, a reconstructed open-air village displaying Burundian culture.</p>]]><p><b>Go birdwatching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located around&nbsp;Kirundo, in the far north of Burundi, Cohoha, Rweru and Rwihinda lakes are known locally as the best places in the country to settle down to some&nbsp;birdwatching. Rwihinda is even nicknamed 'Birds Lake' because of the sheer quantity of birds that settle there. Another popular birding spot is&nbsp;Kibira National Park.</p>]]><p><b>Play the locals at urubugu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Compete with locals in the ancient game of <em>urubugu </em>(also known as <em>mancala</em>). Similar to draughts, the aim is to capture an opponent's pieces or block any legal move. It is traditionally played with pebbles, seeds or seashells on a board of hollows scooped out of the ground, or with expensive and elaborately carved wooden boards.</p>]]><p><b>Reach the source of the world’s longest river</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As far as Burundians are concerned (Rwandans hail it to be a narrow stream in Nyunge Forest National Park), the southernmost source of the Nile bubbles out of the ground at Kasumo, just 115km (70 miles) southeast of the capital, where a stone pyramid marks the spot.</p>]]><p><b>Take to the waters of Lake Tanganyika</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whether you want to relax on its sandy beaches, kick back in waterside cafes and restaurants, become seduced by its natural beauty or take the opportunity to take to the water, Lake Tanganyika is the place to be. Thought to be the second largest freshwater lake in the world, it laps against the shores of Burundi's capital, Bujumbura.</p>]]><p><b>Try your hand at traditional arts</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A great way to get under the skin of Burundian culture is to explore its traditional arts and crafts at the Craftwares Village at Giheta. Leatherwork, ceramics, and woodcarvings are all for sale, while sculpture, wickerwork and painting can be practiced in the town's Art School.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$1.5 billion (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Coffee, tea, sugar, cotton and hides.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Capital goods, petroleum products and foodstuffs.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Switzerland, Germany, Belgium, Thailand, USA, Italy, Japan, Kenya, Tanzania, Uganda, France, Rwanda and Zambia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Subsistence agriculture employs 90% of the workforce and accounts for approximately half of the total economic output. Cassava and sweet potatoes are the main subsistence crops, while coffee (the country's leading export), tea and cotton are the main cash crops. Hides and skins also produce valuable income.<br /><br />The country's small mining industry produces gold, tin, tungsten and tantalum. Deposits of vanadium, uranium and nickel (perhaps 5% of known global reserves) have also been located and are due to be exploited in the near future. Oil deposits are believed to be present, although the quantities are unknown. Manufacturing is confined to small textile concerns.<br /><br />Burundi has economic cooperation agreements with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/rwanda">Rwanda</a> and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/congo">Democratic Republic of Congo</a> through the Economic Community of the Great Lakes Countries and is a member of the Common Market for Eastern and Southern Africa (COMESA) and of the International Coffee Organisation. Burundi is also a member of the African Union (AU) and the World Tourism Organisation.<br /><br />As one of the poorest countries in the world, with an annual per capita income of just US$100, Burundi remains heavily dependent on foreign aid, principally from France, Germany, Belgium (these three are also its major sources of imports), the EU and the World Bank.<br /><br />Burundi's major export markets are the countries of the CFA Franc zone, which take approximately one-third of the total.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits are necessary. April to October and December to January are the best times to visit.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1200 and 1400-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intercontact</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 226 618.
					Website:http://www.intercontactservices.com
					Address: ,19 rue de l'Industrie,Bujumbura,BP 982]]><b>Chambre de Commerce et de l'Industrie du Burundi</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 222 280
					Website:
					Address: ,BP 313,Bujumbura,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The choice of food in Burundi can appear limited at first, but the cuisine is in fact both varied and flavoursome. Most food is boiled, stewed or roasted over a wood fire. Staple ingredients include plantains, sweet potatoes, cassava, peas and maize.</p><p>Stewed beans are traditionally eaten at least once a day, while meat (mainly chicken and goat) is only rarely consumed. Close to the shores of Lake Tanganyika, fish is popular and prepared in similar ways to meat. Snacks include fruit such as bananas and pineapples, as well as cane sugar and peanuts.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ibiharage</strong>: Red kidney beans stewed simply with onion and chilli.<br />
<strong>Boko boko harees</strong>: Chicken cooked with bulgur wheat, onion and turmeric.<br />
<strong>Ndizi</strong>: Sliced plantain fried in palm oil, making a delicious snack or side.<br />
<strong>Ndagala</strong>: Small locally-caught fish eaten whole.<br />
<strong>Muk&eacute;k&eacute;</strong>: Another locally-caught fish, often steamed over an open fire and served with a tomato and onion sauce.<br />
<strong>Spicy carrots</strong>: Side dish of carrots mixed with mustard seeds and chilli peppers.<br />
<strong>Bugali</strong>: Plain tasting carbohydrate staple served at almost every meal.<br />
<strong>Brochette</strong>: Skewers of barbequed meat, often goat.<br />
<strong>Renga renga</strong>: Potato-leaf and peanut stew.<br />
<strong>Nyama</strong>: Meat stew with tomato.<br />
<strong>Urwarwa:</strong> Homemade banana wine drunk during celebrations.<br />
<strong>Impeke:</strong> Beer brewed from sorghum, and often drunk through straws.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several nightclubs, restaurants and bars in Bujumbura.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local crafts, particularly basketwork, make excellent buys.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1200 and 1500; Sat 0830-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost all the hotels in Burundi are situated in the capital, Bujumbura, although there are a few in Gitega, Kirundo, Muyinga and Ngozi. Elsewhere in the country there is virtually no accommodation for visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost all the hotels in Burundi are situated in the capital, Bujumbura, although there are a few in Gitega, Kirundo, Muyinga and Ngozi. Elsewhere in the country there is virtually no accommodation for visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost all the hotels in Burundi are situated in the capital, Bujumbura, although there are a few in Gitega, Kirundo, Muyinga and Ngozi. Elsewhere in the country there is virtually no accommodation for visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Full medical insurance, including repatriation, is essential. Medical supplies are limited. In the event of a serious accident, evacuation by air ambulance may be required.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advise. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Avoid food from street vendors. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis E and dysentery are widespread. Hepatitis B is hyperendemic. Meningitis is present all year and vaccination is sometimes advised. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. HIV/AIDS is prevalent. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Unity Day :
							05 February </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							01 July </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Rwagasore Day :
							13 October </p><p>President Ndadaye's Day :
							21 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Burundi without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 1,000 cigarettes or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic beverages.</p>
<p>A deposit may be required for items such as cameras, video recorders and laptop computers. You should declare currency and cameras upon arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Burundi Franc (BIF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of BIF5,000, 1,000, 500, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of BIF10, 5 and 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All exchange transactions must be conducted through one of the main banks in Bujumbura or Gitega.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are not generally accepted; there is limited use in some major hotels.</p><p>There are a few ATM cashpoints around Bujumbura, the capital. A few of them accept foreign Visa cards. However, if you are travelling outside of Bujumbura, it's best to carry cash with you.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Euros. Commission rates are usually high.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri, mornings only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for at least six months, and with at least one blank page, is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Multiple-entry visa: &pound;60.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One month.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). You can no longer obtain visas on arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 14 days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-3.365015]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[29.887018]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>27,816 sq km (10,740 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>11,552,561 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>386.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bujumbura.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Burundi is a land-locked country in the heart of Africa, a little south of the equator, on the eastern shore of Lake Tanganyika. It is bordered by Rwanda to the north, by the Democratic Republic of Congo to the west and by Tanzania to the south and east. The interior is a broken plateau sloping east to Tanzania and the valley of the River Malagarasi. The southern tributary of the Nile system rises in the south of the country. The landscape is characterised by hills and valleys covered with eucalyptus trees, banana groves, cultivated fields and pasture. In the east, the fertile area gives way to savannah grassland, and tea and coffee are now grown on mountainsides.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>77% of the population are Christian, the majority of which are Roman Catholic; there are Anglican and Pentecostal minorities. 22% adhere to animist beliefs. There is also a small (1%) Muslim community.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal social courtesies apply. However, outside the cities people may not be used to visitors, and care and tact must be used in respect of local customs. Inhabitants of major towns generally have a more modern way of life. Dress should be reasonably conservative.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are usually used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Pierre Nkurunziza since 2005.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Pierre Nkurunziza since 2005.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Hutu and Tutsi ethnic groups have occupied the area now known as Burundi for many centuries, but in the early 19th century the region became part of German East Africa and was ruled by the Germans until the end of WWI.</p>
<p>The Belgians took over after the war and continued what the Germans had started: namely a perverse programme of ethnic segregation. The minority Tutsi were given the highest positions in society, dominating the army, civil service and higher reaches of the economy, while the majority Hutu were largely discriminated against and excluded from positions of power. This segregation precipitated the 1994 genocide in neighbouring Rwanda, which was also ruled by Germany and Belgium, and has led to chronic instability in Burundi. The antagonism has occasionally flared up into mass violence and the massacre of tens of thousands, especially in 1972 and 1988.</p>
<p>Multiparty elections for a National Assembly were held in 1993, which resulted in President Pierre Buyoya replaced by the Hutu banker Melchior Ndadaye, who was killed later that year in unsuccessful military coup. Things continued in that violent vein in 1994 when President Cyprien Ntaryamira, another Hutu, was killed with Rwandan president, Juv&eacute;nal Habyarimana, when their plane was shot down over Kigali.</p>
<p>The incident is widely seen as the trigger for the Rwandan Genocide in which some one million Rwandans died. Burundi narrowly avoided the same fate, although tensions between Tutsis and Hutus sharply increased, and the civil war that followed claimed 300,000 lives.</p>
<p>Two years later, Buyoya took over once again in another coup. The guerrilla war between Hutu rebels and the Tutsi-dominated army intensified. However, mediation efforts by Tanzania and personal intervention by Nelson Mandela served to pacify things in 2000, with a final settlement in 2001. A transitional government, jointly led by Buyoya and FRODEBU leader Domitien Ndayizeye, held power until 2003, when Ndayizeye became the country's sole leader.</p>
<p>In 2005, Pierre Nkurunziza was elected president, but his leaderships has failed to bring stability to the country &ndash; in fact Burundi witnessed extreme violence after the 2015 elections, which saw Nkurunziza win a controversial third term. Since then the country&rsquo;s long-suffering citizens have endured hunger, disease and violence, pushing Burundi towards what the UN describes as a major crisis.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Burundi remained one of Africa&rsquo;s few kingdoms until four years after independence. The last king was Ntare V.<br />
&bull;	Its two national parks, Kibira and Ruvubu, were founded in 1982.<br />
&bull;	The first Europeans to visit the area were the British explorers John Hanning Speke and Richard F Burton in 1858.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Burundi in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 342 2574.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.burundiembassydc-usa.org/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 342 2574.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1700, Fri 0900-1400.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>Suite 212, 2233 Wisconsin Avenue<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Burundi in Belgium]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(02) 230 4535.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(02) 230 4535.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>46 square Marie-Louise<br/>Brussels<br/>1000<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For all its wondrous landscapes (think undulating mountain ranges, dense rainforests and shimmering lakes), travellers are advised to steer clear of Burundi right now &ndash; the scenery might be beautiful, but the political situation is decidedly ugly.</p>
<p>Civil unrest, an abortive military coup and controversial elections have dominated the headlines in Burundi recently, which is a great shame given what this country has to offer.</p>
<p>The vibrant if tumultuous capital, Bujumbura, has a prime location on the shores of Lake Tanganyika and just outside the city are some of the best inland beaches in Africa, plus a number of idyllic beachfront bars and resorts.</p>
<p>The city itself has some interesting examples of French architecture and has developed a reputation for its vibrant nightlife, but infrastructural development has been hindered by decades of sporadic conflict that culminated in 1994 and left more than 300,000 dead.</p>
<p>Further beyond the city limits, the four beautiful waterfalls at Chutes de la Karera are well worth a visit, as are a few of the largely unexplored and underdeveloped national parks.&nbsp;Parc National de la Rusiza is the most accessible, just 15km (9 miles) from Bujumbura, while Parc National de la Kibira is the largest rainforest in Burundi and is home to rare colobus monkeys and chimpanzees.</p>
<p>An advantage of Burundi&rsquo;s small size is that if you have your own vehicle or hire a driver, it&rsquo;s generally easy to visit any of these highlights and return to Bujumbura within the same day; public transport, however, is limited outside the city.</p>
<p>Burundi has made tentative progress towards peace and stability since a power-sharing government was set up in 2001 and most rebel groups agreed to disarm, but in 2015 President Nkurunziza&rsquo;s bid to change the constitution and stand for a third term sparked mass protests and a violent response from the state.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of Burundians have fled into neighbouring Tanzania, fearing the collapse of the country&rsquo;s fragile democracy and a return to civil war. Watch this space.</p><p>For all its wondrous landscapes (think undulating mountain ranges, dense rainforests and shimmering lakes), travellers are advised to steer clear of Burundi right now &ndash; the scenery might be beautiful, but the political situation is decidedly ugly.</p>
<p>Civil unrest, an abortive military coup and controversial elections have dominated the headlines in Burundi recently, which is a great shame given what this country has to offer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
