<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Cambodia" ColCode="khm" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="kh" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Cambodia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Being located in the tropical zone north of the equator, Cambodia has a monsoon climate. Monsoon season runs May - November, meaning that the most pleasant season for visitors is generally the dry season, stretching from November/December - April. Immediately after the monsoon, the blanketing green of the countryside can be stunningly beautiful. <br />
<br />
In the north, winters are generally colder, while throughout most of the country temperatures remain fairly constant. The average year-round temperature in Cambodia is 27.7&deg;C (the highest monthly average being 35&deg;C, the lowest monthly average being 21&deg;C). There is often seasonal flooding in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/phnom-penh">Phnom Penh</a> and the rest of Cambodia in late July and early August, and, because the majority of roads are dirt, travel may be disrupted at these times. At the peak of the wet season it can rain as often as two in every three days.<br />
<br />
While the rain may affect certain outdoor activities when travelling (many hiking, biking or boat cruise companies will cancel excursions), the temperature is pleasant and in the larger cities the rainfall acts as a burst of refreshment for the dusty roads. Do bear in mind when hiking during the region in monsoon season that leeches are plentiful; leech socks and regular leech checks en route are advisable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothing is worn all year. Gumboots, umbrellas and raincoats are advisable during the monsoon season - because when it rains, it pours. Rain may continue solidly for days on end.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cambodia Angkor Air (<a href="http://www.cambodiaangkorair.com" target="_blank">www.cambodiaangkorair.com</a>) and Bassaka Air (<a href="http://www.bassakaair.com" target="_blank">www.bassakaair.com</a>) operate internal flights between Phnom Penh and Siem Reap for Angkor (journey time - 45 minutes). Siem Reap Airport, the main gateway for visitors going to see the ancient temples at Angkor, is a 10-minute taxi ride from the city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Government-run ferries depart from the Phnom Penh port near Street 104 and go to Siem Reap, a route popular with travellers. You can buy tickets in person at the dock or through a travel agent. Travel can be difficult in the dry season when the water level is very low, and often boat services are suspended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cambodia&rsquo;s defunct railway system is slowly being rehabilitated, but there are currently no passenger services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Roads vary from excellent to very poor and there are numbered routes from Phnom Penh with Route 1 leading to the Vietnamese border. Take care while driving, as accidents are relatively frequent. You can't always rely on other vehicles to use headlights at night.</p><p>You can hire taxis in main cities, although they are not metered so the price has to be fixed in advance. Tips are appreciated.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is not recognised in Cambodia, and as car hire does not exist, visitors are advised to hire a car with a driver.</p><p>These are few and far between. In most areas, drivers of broken-down vehicles have to take a bus, taxi or moto to the nearest town to hire a tow to a local garage.</p><p>It is really only possible to hire a car with a driver. You can arrange car hire by private negotiation with a taxi waiting outside the hotels or through tour operators.</p><p>Given the predominant use of motorcycles for urban public transportation, you should ensure that any insurance policies provide coverage for riding as a driver or passenger.&nbsp;Cattle often stray onto the roads. In Siem Reap, it's easy to find companies hiring motorbikes, despite a local ban to protect tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a limited public bus service in Phnom Penh, but none in Siem Reap. Taxis wait outside hotels and restaurants but, as they are unmetered, the fare should be fixed before leaving. <em>Cyclos </em>(tricycles) or <em>motodops </em>(motorcycle taxis) are an efficient and inexpensive way to get around and some of the drivers, especially those found outside main hotels, speak a little French or English.&nbsp;Siem Reap also has motorised tuk tuks<em>.</em></p>
<p>In terms of the greatest risks (particularly in Phnom Penh, Siem Reap and Sihanoukville), the greatest danger faced by visitors is from road-traffic accidents, armed robbery after dark, bag snatching and, in remote areas, landmines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cambodia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sihanoukville</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cambodia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">siem_reap</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cambodia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kompong_cham</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cambodia Angkor Air (<a href="http://www.cambodiaangkorair.com" target="_blank">www.cambodiaangkorair.com</a>) is the national airline and operates flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/thailand">Thailand</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> to Cambodia.</p>
<p>Most long-haul flights to Cambodia require a stop-over in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangkok">Bangkok</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hong-kong">Hong Kong</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a> first. Air Asia (<a href="http://www.airasia.com" target="_blank">www.airasia.com</a>), Bangkok Airways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.bangkokair.com/">www.bangkokair.com</a>) and Thai Airways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.thaiair.com/">www.thaiair.com</a>) fly between Cambodia and Thailand.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/phnom-penh-international-airport">Phnom Penh International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/phnom-penh">Phnom Penh</a>: from Bangkok - 1 hour; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 14 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 21 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Siem Reap International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.cambodia-airports.com<p>The airport is 8km (5 miles) from Siem Reap.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Phnom Penh International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.cambodia-airports.aero/<p>Phnom Penh International Airport is located approximately 10km (6 miles) from the city centre in Phnom Penh, Cambodia.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+855 23 862 800</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Phnom Penh and Sihanoukville are the main ports. You can reach Phnom Penh via the Mekong Delta through Vietnam. This route is served by regular passenger ferry services from Chau Doc in Vietnam, with tickets available through travel agencies or at the dock. You can reach Sihanoukville from Thailand through the border crossing at Hat Lek and the boat from Koh Kong. Tickets are sold at the dock in Sihanoukville.</p><p>There is also a more sketchy border crossing from Cambodia on the Mekong River to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/laos">Laos</a>. Tourists travelling to Laos have to obtain a visa beforehand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cambodia's rail network is being reconstructed after decades of neglect, but there are currently no passenger services. Plans for a new line connecting Cambodia with the Vietnamese border is likely to be years away from completion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to drive from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/phnom-penh">Phnom Penh</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ho-chi-minh-city">Ho Chi Minh City</a> in a day but there are formalities involved regarding the use of the same vehicle all the way. Right-hand drive vehicles (quite common in Cambodia) are not allowed entry to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vietnam">Vietnam</a>. You must obtain Vietnamese visas in advance, but you can obtain Cambodian visas at the border.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Prepaid telephone cards are available in post offices, hotels and shops for public phones around Phnom Penh and Siem Reap.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with many international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good in major towns and cities and patchy elsewhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in most areas. Internet cafes are available in Phnom Penh, Siem Reap and all other major towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Much of Cambodia's media depends on support from political parties. Press freedom is not guaranteed, but Prime Minister Hun Sen has declared his public support for press freedom. There are no restrictions on satellite dish ownership, and neighbouring foreign radio broadcasts are easily received. </p>
<p>Newspapers <em>The Cambodia Daily</em> and <em>The Phnom Penh Post</em> (fortnightly) and are printed in English. National Television Kampuchea (TVK) is a state broadcaster, while Aspara TV and TV3 are commercial stations, and CTN, CTV9, Bayon TV and TV5 are private broadcasters. National Radio Kampuchea (RNK) is a state broadcaster; FM 95 (operated by Bayon Radio and TV News Agency), Radio FM 97 (operated by Aspara Radio and TV Radio) and Radio FM 103 are all commercial broadcasters. There are 11 TV stations nationwide, and 18 radio stations including French, Thai and Vietnamese broadcasts. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes at least a week, and longer to the USA. The main post office in Phnom Penh is located on the western side of 13 Street between 98 Street and 102 Street, open 0630-2100.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0730/0800-1700/1730, sometimes closed for lunch.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Angkor</p><![CDATA[<p>Angkor, the former capital of the ancient Khmer Empire, is one of the greatest and most spectacular Hindu religious sites in the world. Construction of this elaborate temple complex - built in honour of the god Vishnu - began in AD 879 during the reign of King Suryavarman II and was completed in 1191. It lay concealed for many years, however, until the site was discovered by Frenchman Henri Mahout in 1860. The central complex, Angkor Wat, features an elaborate, unmortared 66-metre (215-foot) central tower surrounded by four smaller towers. Stretching around the outside of the temple complex is an 800m-long (2625ft) bas-relief, the longest in the world. This is Cambodia's most iconic sight, and particularly popular at sunset among tour groups. The temple is so synonymous with the country that it dominates the national flag, and to visit it today is to marvel at the scale of its ambition, built as it was in the 12th century.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be awestruck by Angkor Wat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Angkor, the former capital of the ancient Khmer Empire, is one of the greatest and most spectacular religious sites in the world. Construction of this elaborate temple complex – built in honour of the Hindu god Vishnu – began in AD 879 but the site was lost to history for centuries before being rediscovered by Frenchman Henri Mahout in 1860.</p>]]><p><b>Be bowled over by the Bayon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Angkor Wat takes centre stage at Angkor, but the Bayon is perhaps the most magical of all the structures here. From its monumental towers, a series of colossal stone faces, depicting the Buddhist deity Avalokitesvara, gaze out serenely across the temples and jungles. The atmosphere is mesmerising, particularly at dawn, when the faces loom dramatically out of the mist.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise the Mekong</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The boat trip from Phnom Penh to Siem Reap is one of Asia's legendary traveller journeys, and by far the most atmospheric way of reaching the Angkor temples. On the journey along the Mekong River and out onto Tonle Sap lake, you'll absorb some of the spirit of Cambodia's life-giving waterways. The trip upstream to Battambang is even more scenic.</p>]]><p><b>Cycle to Angkor’s outlying temples</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Angkor complex sprawls for miles through the jungle, but roaming to outlying temples is part of the magic. Hire a bike and spend magical days exploring the temples, shrines and palaces, from the famous spires of Angkor Wat and the magnificent Bayon, to overgrown Ta Phrom and the remote temples of Bantaey Srei.</p>]]><p><b>Dive into Cambodia’s Water Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As in neighbouring Thailand, the changing seasons in Cambodia are marked with major festivals, and the biggest of all is Bom Om Touk, held in October or November, when the flow of the Tonle Sap River changes direction. Alongside three days of merry-making, rainbow-coloured boats race each other along the Tonle Sap.</p>]]><p><b>Encounter the wild in Cambodia’s national parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Large areas of Cambodia have been set aside as national parks, and several are easily accessible from Phnom Penh. Kirirom National Park, southwest of the city, has walking and mountain bike trails and cascading waterfalls, while Phnom Tamao Wildlife Sanctuary provides a safe home for tigers, elephants, gibbons and other animals rescued from poachers and traffickers.</p>]]><p><b>Feast on fresh seafood</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cambodia's coastline offers the full sun, sea and sand experience, but for many visitors, the big appeal is Cambodia's ocean-fresh seafood. The stretch of coast around Kampot and Kep is famous for just-caught crab, and all along the coast menus are graced by fresh fish, prawns, squid and lobster.</p>]]><p><b>Fire some artillery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Firing a weapon of war is probably not your standard tourist activity, but then Cambodia's not your standard tourist destination. For a price, visitors can take control of high-grade weaponry on countryside shooting ranges all over the country, from machine guns and hand grenades to rocket launchers.</p>]]><p><b>Go dolphin spotting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The claim to fame of the Mekong town of Kratie is its population of Irrawaddy river dolphins, one of the rarest of all aquatic mammals. Various tour operators organise early-morning boat trips to observe these peaceful creatures in their natural habitat, but time is running out for these graceful animals – only 80 are thought to survive in the Mekong River.</p>]]><p><b>Imbibe history at Bokor Hill Station</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An abandoned French hill station in the south of the country, Bokor was built originally as a weekend sanctuary for settlers stuck in stifling Phnom Penh. Like a Wild West ghost town, it's best known for its derelict hotel, which stands as an eerie reminder of the extravagant final years of French Indochina.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Kampot</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A sprawl of shophouses on the riverbank, the southern town of Kampot provides a gateway to Cham villages, national parks, cave temples at Phnom Chhnork and Phnom Sorsia and the lush green countryside of the Gulf coast. Travellers love Kampot for it's laid-back atmosphere and relaxing pace of life.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Khmer art in the National Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Staggering amounts of Khmer art were looted during the Khmer Rouge years and sold on the international art market, but some of the finest examples of Khmer artistry now take pride of place in the National Museum in Phnom Penh. Amongst the impressive collection are statues and sculptures and ceramics. The building was constructed by the French in 1917.</p>]]><p><b>Move to Khmer rhythms</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Classical Khmer dance is one of Asia's great dance traditions and displays have become a popular tourist attraction. Many international hotels around Siem Reap stage tourist shows, but you can see spontaneous dances across the country during monastery feast days. Also listen out for the haunting psychedelic rock of Ros Sereysothea, who vanished during the conflict.</p>]]><p><b>Pay your respects at Tuol Sleng</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set in the former Phnom Penh high school that would later become the notorious S-21 detention centre, Tuol Sleng today acts as a haunting memorial to the genocide of the Khmer Rouge era. Torture instruments remain in some rooms and the walls are lined with photos of the tens of thousands of victims who passed through before vanishing in the Killing Fields.</p>]]><p><b>Relax on the sands of Sihanoukville</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cambodia's main port city was already a backpacker beach hangout when the Khmer Rouge was active. It still retains its relaxed beach atmosphere, a laid-back counterpoint to the more visited beaches of neighbouring Thailand. It takes its name from King Norodom Sihanouk, one of the main agitators for independence from France.</p>]]><p><b>Shop for silver</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Prized across Southeast Asia since the 11th century, silver is one of the most sought-after Cambodian souvenirs, and it is made into a remarkable range of objects, from anklets and jewellery to elegant bowls and betel nut storage tins. Most items are decorated with intricate designs, applied using the repousse technique, with tiny hammers and punches.</p>]]><p><b>Swing by Phnom Penh’s Royal Palace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Phnom Penh's showpiece attraction was built in the 1860s, and it cuts a handsome figure on the skyline, crowned by a series of stupas and towering spires. The royal family were driven from the palace during the Khmer Rouge era, but the monarchy was restored in 1993. The adjoining Silver Pagoda houses a number of ancient and revered Buddha statues.</p>]]><p><b>Take a heart-rending journey through history</b></p><![CDATA[<p>To get a clearer understanding of Cambodia's darkest hour, visit the Killing Fields outside Phnom Penh. It makes for a sobering experience that will stay with you long after you leave the country. Most people also visit the Tuol Sleng Genocide Museum, set in the former school used as a brutal prison by the Khmer Rouge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$12.9 billion (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Timber, footwear, fish, rubber, tobacco and clothing.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum products, cigarettes, gold, construction materials and machinery.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Thailand, China, Vietnam, Singapore, South Korea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Cambodian economy was all but destroyed by the war in southeast Asia and the rule of the Khmer Rouge between 1975 and 1979. Since the ousting of the Khmer Rouge from power by the Vietnamese in 1979, Cambodia has undergone a slow process of recovery. Restoration of agriculture (the foundation of the Cambodian economy and the main source of employment) has been slow but steady with rice as the staple. The timber industry has also grown quickly but at the expense of worrying deforestation. <br /><br />The effects of the 1997 currency crisis on the economy were transitory, given the relatively undeveloped state of the Cambodian economy. Cambodia aspires to the status of an Asian 'tiger' economy and has joined the Association of South-East Asian Nations (ASEAN), now the principal regional economic co-operation body.<br /><br />GDP growth stood at 6.7% in a 2011 estimate, with inflation running at 5.5%.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most senior staff in large and international companies will speak English but it is not common in smaller companies. It is essential to make appointments for business meetings and to exchange business cards. Cambodian hosts are quite likely to present their guests with gifts, so visitors should take along a gift typical to their own country of origin in order to reciprocate.<br /><br />Cambodian businesspeople are generally quite formal so protracted niceties are inevitable before getting down to business.<br /><br />Cambodian businesspeople are gradually becoming more formal in their dress, as contact with international business increases. However, because of the extreme heat, it is quite acceptable, and practical, to dispense with the wearing of a suit jacket. <br /><br />Offices tend to open early between 0730 and 0800 and close around 1700 or 1800 with a long lunch break between 1130 and 1400, a legacy from the French. Many offices are also open on Saturdays but always check to see if this is the case.</p><p>Offices tend to open early between 0730 and 0800 and close around 1700 or 1800 with a long lunch break between 1130 and 1400, a legacy from the French. Many offices are also open on Saturdays but always check to see if this is the case.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Cambodian food draws on the same rich culinary traditions as neighbouring Thailand and Vietnam, with a noticeable leaning towards fish – as you might expect from a nation at the delta of the mighty Mekong River.</p><p>Cambodian pepper and cardamoms join more familiar Southeast Asian ingredients such as curry pastes (<em>kroeung</em> in Khmer), lemongrass, chilli, kaffir lime leaves, Asian basil and galangal as flavourings for stir fries, stews and soups.  <em>Prahok </em>– a pungent seasoning made from fermented fish – is another much-loved seasoning.</p><p>The foundation of any Khmer meal is rice, either sticky rice, or the fragrant jasmine rice grown in paddy fields across the nation. Vietnamese influence manifests itself in the form of noodle soups such as <em>kuy teav</em>, while the French legacy is obvious from the popularity of coffee and the <em>nom pang </em>(baguette sandwiches with pork) served as snacks across the country.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Balut</strong>: Fertilised duck eggs, served as a snack; you&rsquo;ll see them sold all over the country, but with a whole chick inside. It&rsquo;s an acquired taste.<br />
<strong>Prahok</strong>: Fermented fish paste, used as a seasoning for stir fries, but never for soups.<br />
<strong>Fried tarantula: </strong>A speciality of Skuon in North Cambodia, and a popular dining dare for travellers.<br />
<strong>Amok trey</strong>: Fish in a thick coconut curry sauce, wrapped in banana leaves and steamed.<br />
<strong>Babor: </strong>Rice porridge with chicken broth often served with an omelette or dried small fry.<br />
<strong>Kuy teav</strong>: Rice noodle soup with pork stock, thought to originate from China. It comes topped with all sorts of vegetables, garnishes and meat cuts and is a popular breakfast.<br />
<strong>Bai chha</strong>: Khmer fried rice with sausage, pork, garlic and herbs.<br />
<strong>Kralan</strong>: Sticky rice flavoured with sugar, beans and grated coconut, steamed inside a bamboo pole.<br />
<strong>Lok Lak: </strong>Stir-fried beef in a lime, salt and pepper sauce, often served with fried potatoes and an egg.<br />
<strong>Mee katang</strong>: Cantonese-style wide rice noodles cooked with meat and vegetables in oyster sauce.<br />
<strong>Nom banh chok</strong>: Curry-style noodles often served with shredded fish, turmeric root, lemongrass, citrus, mint, and chilli.<br />
<strong>Pleah sach ko</strong>: Beef ceviche with peanuts and garlic, in a lime and palm sugar dressing.<br />
<strong>Fresh coconut juice:</strong> A refreshing and popular beverage.<br />
<strong>Green tea:</strong> China&rsquo;s influence again.<br />
<strong>Rice wine: </strong>Often served infused with spices as <em>sombai</em>.<br />
<strong>Beer:</strong> Angkor and Anchor are the lagers to look out for.<br />
<strong>Golden muscle wine:</strong> Made from herbs and deer antlers (yes, really).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Hygiene is something travellers should be aware of when travelling to Cambodia. Roadside street food stalls and restaurants are fun to try but may not have the strictest cleanliness habits. Stick to busy stalls and restaurants serving piping hot foods.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Locals rarely tip but travellers often like to and around 10% is appropriate, particularly in hotels and restaurants where no service charge has been added.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are no age restrictions on drinking in Cambodia, but a new minimum age of 21 is being debated.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's not difficult to find vibrant nightlife in Cambodia, particularly in heavily visited destinations such as Phnom Penh and Siem Reap (which neighbours the Angkor Temple Complex). Bars and restaurants are plentiful, ranging from down-and-dirty drinking holes to smart cocktail bars. Outright nightclubs are few and far between, although girlie bars are anything but rare. Be sure to check a venue out before handing over a cover charge, as you may end up in a seedy environment. In Phonm Penh you can&rsquo;t go wrong with the bars in the restaurants on the riverfront, which offer laidback family atmospheres. <br />
<br />
Most major hotels offer entertainment of their own, with properties in Siem Reap especially good at hosting traditional dance performances during high season. Gambling is a major pastime in Cambodia and there are several casinos in Sihanoukville and on the border with Thailand. This same beach town is also a raucous backpacker haven. Steer clear of Victory Hill, unless you enjoy an up all night go-go dancing atmosphere (reminiscent of Khao San Road, Bangkok).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors to Cambodia have a tendency to leave with bulkier luggage than on arrival: the country's markets are heavy with potential souvenirs, ranging from silks, textiles and statues to carvings, silverwork and Buddhist artworks. Unique to Cambodia is the omnipresent <em>krama</em> (a unisex checked scarf usually made of cotton), while silk can be bought either by the length, or in the form of scarves and other garments. Jewellery, ceramics, clothing, CDs and DVDs are widespread in city markets. </p>
<p>Try Phnom Penh Central Market or Angkor Night Market as a starting point - go prepared to haggle. Alternatively peruse the trendy, fairtrade boutiques in the nation&rsquo;s capital. Areas such as Street 240 and Street 178 offer art dealerships, which have popped up in handfuls in recent years. Silk shops selling everything from scarves to daintily embroidered cushions, a and antique traders selling furniture and memorabilia are also common here. Bookshops selling tomes of the region can be bought on Norodom Boulevard or 178 Street for your onward journey.</p><p>Daily 0800-2000.</p><p>The trade of rare animal furs is illegal, it's advised to avoid purchasing fur or jewellery made from endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Cambodia are inexpensive, and standards have vastly improved in recent years, especially in Phnom Penh, Siem Reap and Sihanoukville, which offer a variety of hotels and hostels, and numerous international hotel chains. Elsewhere, there is usually one good standard hotel in town, although facilities are often limited.&nbsp;Take star ratings with a pinch of salt; there is no official grading of hotels in Cambodia. Price is often the only guide to the quality, but not often the best guide. Ask to be shown your room before you hand over your credit card for a week&rsquo;s stay, to avoid disappointment. <br />
<br />
Phnom Penh, Siem Reap and Sihanoukville have some superb hotels with major five-star brands such as Raffles, InterContinental and Sofitel offering all the facilities and services expected in international-standard properties. There is also a good selection of mid-range hotels and quirkier luxury abodes such as floating river lodges (complete with air conditioning, televisions and room service), jungle bungalows (hidden in the forests, for ultimate seclusion) and private islands (such as Song Saa, set on Koh Ouen  Island, Sihanoukville).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a variety of good guesthouses and boutique lodges available in the capital and in most towns around Cambodia. Facilities range from well equipped to very limited, but most will include air conditioning or a fan and a restaurant. Boutiques of note include the minimal 60s cool d&eacute;cor of Amansara (<a href="http://www.amanresorts.com" target="_blank">www.amanresorts.com</a>) and Hotel Be Angkor (<a href="http://hotelbeangkor.com" target="_blank">http://hotelbeangkor.com</a>) in Siem Reap. Do note that some boutiques and guest houses have shared bathrooms. Some budget guesthouses do not have restaurants, so guests have to buy breakfast in a local cafe. Budget hotels and hostels are plentiful, although they tend to be very basic and are best suited to backpackers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Cambodia are inexpensive, and standards have vastly improved in recent years, especially in Phnom Penh, Siem Reap and Sihanoukville, which offer a variety of hotels and hostels, and numerous international hotel chains. Elsewhere, there is usually one good standard hotel in town, although facilities are often limited.&nbsp;Take star ratings with a pinch of salt; there is no official grading of hotels in Cambodia. Price is often the only guide to the quality, but not often the best guide. Ask to be shown your room before you hand over your credit card for a week&rsquo;s stay, to avoid disappointment. <br />
<br />
Phnom Penh, Siem Reap and Sihanoukville have some superb hotels with major five-star brands such as Raffles, InterContinental and Sofitel offering all the facilities and services expected in international-standard properties. There is also a good selection of mid-range hotels and quirkier luxury abodes such as floating river lodges (complete with air conditioning, televisions and room service), jungle bungalows (hidden in the forests, for ultimate seclusion) and private islands (such as Song Saa, set on Koh Ouen  Island, Sihanoukville).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Cambodia are inexpensive, and standards have vastly improved in recent years, especially in Phnom Penh, Siem Reap and Sihanoukville, which offer a variety of hotels and hostels, and numerous international hotel chains. Elsewhere, there is usually one good standard hotel in town, although facilities are often limited.&nbsp;Take star ratings with a pinch of salt; there is no official grading of hotels in Cambodia. Price is often the only guide to the quality, but not often the best guide. Ask to be shown your room before you hand over your credit card for a week&rsquo;s stay, to avoid disappointment. <br />
<br />
Phnom Penh, Siem Reap and Sihanoukville have some superb hotels with major five-star brands such as Raffles, InterContinental and Sofitel offering all the facilities and services expected in international-standard properties. There is also a good selection of mid-range hotels and quirkier luxury abodes such as floating river lodges (complete with air conditioning, televisions and room service), jungle bungalows (hidden in the forests, for ultimate seclusion) and private islands (such as Song Saa, set on Koh Ouen  Island, Sihanoukville).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance, including emergency evacuation, is absolutely essential. Doctors and hospitals expect cash payments for any medical treatment. The cost of medical evacuation is high. The hospital in Phnom Penh is reliable. Visitors should bring adequate supplies of any essential personal medication, since particular medications may not be available in Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Boil or sterilise water for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice. Bottled water is widely available. Milk is also unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is an advisable alternative to fresh produce. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;When travelling on the wild side go with a reliable and experienced guide. Though tens of thousands have been removed, there are still landmines left over from years of war. There are still an estimated 4m undetonated mines in the country. As a result of the continual mine problem Cambodia has approximately 40,000 amputees, victims of unexploded ordinances. Supposedly, the Cambodian government spends around $30m each year on demining operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drugs such as marijuana, ecstasy, opium, cocaine and heroin are readily available in Cambodia, but drugs penalties are harsh, and being a foreigner will not give you any protection. Also overdoses are rife, it&amp;rsquo;s common for dealers to cut drugs with poisonous substance and simply swap cocaine orders with heroin (as heroin is much cheaper).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cholera may be a serious risk in this country and precautions are essential. Up-to-date advice should be sought before deciding whether these precautions should include vaccination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is advisable to take anti-malarials if you are travelling to affected areas. It is possible to buy anti-malarials at pharmacies in the larger cities. However, depending on the brand you may need to start the course before you arrive in a malaria zone, so it&amp;rsquo;s advisable to purchase anti malarials before you travel. Be aware that resistance to anti-malarial Lariam has been reported in Cambodia. Affected areas include Kapot, Sihanoukville, Piopet and Stung Treng, plus others whilst there is little risk of malaria in Phnom   Penh, Siem Reap and Angkor Wat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Giardiasis, dysentery, typhoid fever and dengue feverare common throughout Cambodia. Dengue fever is particularly prevalent in Phnom Penh, Kampong Cham, Kompong Thom and Siem Reap. Hepatitis Bis hyperendemic. Japanese encephalitisoccurs in rural areas from May to November, and is relatively common in the highlands where there are rice fields and pigs, as both are needed for the disease to occur. The vaccine is only usually given for people travelling in rural areas for four weeks or more. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Epidemics of avian influenza (bird flu) were reported in Asia in 2004 and again in 2005, and some human cases were confirmed. The last confirmed cases were in 2012, there were three. Visitors should avoid bird farms or markets, where contact with poultry might occur. HIV/AIDS is endemic and safe sex practices are essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following Monday.<br /><br />Buddhist festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Victory Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Cambodian New Year :
							13 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>King Sihamoni's Birthday :
							13 May </p><p>Former Queen's Birthday :
							18 June </p><p>Constitution Day :
							24 September </p><p>Coronation Day :
							29 October </p><p>Former King Sihanouk's Birthday :
							31 October </p><p>Independence Day :
							09 November </p><p>International Human Rights Day :
							10 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Cambodia by travellers aged 18 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 200g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 350ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following are subject to licensing: arms and ammunition, pesticides and fertilisers, artificial sweeteners, cultural items above US$10,000, gold, silver and precious stones, pharmaceuticals and medical materials, vehicles, machinery for military purposes, and wood products (see <a target="_blank" href="http://www.customs.gov.kh">www.customs.gov.kh</a> for updates).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arms and ammunitions, fireworks and fire crackers, illicit drugs, live pigs and poultry meat, politically sensitive printed materials, right-hand drive vehicles, and used motorcycle tyres (check <a target="_blank" href="http://www.customs.gov.kh">www.customs.gov.kh</a> for updates).</p>
<p>You must obtain a permit to export cultural artefacts or plants and animals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Riel (KHR; symbol CR) is the country's official currency but locals prefer to use dollars. Riel notes are in denominations of CR100,000, 50,000, 20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 2,000, 1,000, 500, 200, 100 and 50. Dollars notes (not coins) are widely accepted, yet visitors in small villages and shops vendors may not have change for high notes (including $10+). It is advisable to keep hold of small Riel change wherever you can as it is very useful.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollars are widely exchangeable and can often be used as payment in their own right. Thai Baht can be easily exchanged close to the Thai border, but other currencies are generally only recognised at banks and airports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are now more widely accepted in upmarket hotels, shops and restaurants catering to visitors. There are ATMs in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/phnom-penh">Phnom Penh</a>, Siem Reap and Sihanoukville. It is always best to carry cash (US Dollars if necessary) in small denominations.</p><p>There are plenty of ATMs in Phnom Penh, Siem Reap and Sihanoukville that accept international cards including Cirrus, Plus, Maestro, Visa and MasterCard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Limited acceptance. Traveller's cheques are generally not recommended. Traveller's cheques in US Dollars can be changed at banks and some hotels, but can be difficult to change outside major cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1500. Some banks are open on Saturdays 0800-1130.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months is required for entry into Cambodia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist (single-entry): &pound;25; business (single-entry): &pound;30; tourist e-Visa (single-entry): US$36.</p>
<p>To obtain a visa on arrival, bring two passport photos and US Dollars (US$30 for a tourist visa or US$40 for a business visa).</p>
<p>Visitors can apply for an electronic visa (e-Visa) online through the <a href="https://www.evisa.gov.kh" target="www.evisa.gov.kh">Cambodian Ministry of Foreign Affairs &amp; International Cooperation</a>.&nbsp;It&rsquo;s advisable to apply for this at least two weeks before your departure. It is possible to change a departure date after you have applied for a visa, as long as it is before the visa expiry date. You can only use an e-Visa at certain border crossings, so check in advance that it will be valid at your port of entry.</p>
<p>If you apply for an ACMECS visa from the Cambodian Embassy, you pay the usual tourist visa fee for Cambodia then pay Thailand's tourist visa fee at the international border.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visas are valid for 30 days and must be used within three months of the date of issue.</p>
<p>The ACMECS visa is valid for 90 days from the date of issue, allowing up to 60 days in Thailand and up to 30 days in Cambodia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section of embassy), online (see above) or on arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas for Cambodia typically take five working days if you apply in person or six working days for postal applications. e-Visas are issued within three working days, with the visa delivered electronically to the applicant's mailbox.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Extensions of up to one extra month for tourist visas, or one, three, six or 12 months for business<em>&nbsp;</em>visas (which can be multiple-entry) may be granted by the Immigration Department in Phnom Penh.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[12.569997]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[104.813995]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>181,035 sq km (69,900 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>15,827,241 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>86.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Phnom Penh.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bordered to the west by Thailand, to the north by Laos and to the east by Vietnam, Cambodia is a roughly circular country with a southern coastline giving onto the Gulf of Thailand. The landscape comprises tropical rainforest and fertile cultivated land, with lush highlands rising in both the northeast and southeast. Rivers are a central feature of its make-up, with Phnom Penh situated at the confluence of the Bassac, the Tonle Sap and the mighty Mekong. A large inland lake, also called Tonle Sap, sits close to the Angkor Temple Complex in the north. There are numerous beaches and offshore islands along the southwest coast.</p>
<p>However, Cambodia&rsquo;s main landscape is its jewel, comprising tropical rainforest and fertile cultivated land, with lush highlands rising in both the north east and south east. This rich, nutritious land also includes a wealth of nature, including rare and endangered species such as Indochinese tigers, Asian elephants and freshwater Irrawaddy dolphins.</p>
<p>Unfortunately Cambodia suffers from high rates of illegal trading in endangered wildlife and logging, and man is fast wiping out these incredible creatures and their habitat. Around Cambodia visitors can find various eco-camps and rainforest preservation trips offering excursions, education and an alternative form of income to locals previously involved in illegal trade.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>95% of the population are classified Buddhist (Theravada), the remainder are Muslim and Christian. Buddhism was reinstated as the national religion in 1989 after a ban on religious activity in 1975.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sensitivity to politically-related subjects in conversation is advisable. Avoid pointing your foot at a person or touching someone on the head, as it&rsquo;s considered insulting. Women should keep their shoulders covered and should not wear shorts when visiting pagodas.<br />
<br />
<strong>Photography:</strong> Permitted, with certain restrictions such as the photography of military installations, airports and railway stations. It is considered polite to ask permission before photographing Cambodian people, especially monks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Many hotels and guest houses have universal sockets which accept European-style plugs (with two round pins), North American-style plugs (with two flat pins) and British-style plugs (with three square pins). Power cuts are frequent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Hun Sen since 1985.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Norodom Sihamoni since 2004.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Little is known of the early history of Cambodia, although there is evidence of habitation in parts of the country dating as far back as 4000 BC. It is also known that Chinese and Indian traders exchanged goods with people living on the coasts of present-day Cambodia and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vietnam">Vietnam</a> as early as the AD 1st century.</p>
<p>According to Chinese chroniclers, a Hindu kingdom known as Funan flourished between AD 300&ndash;550, but the power of this trading empire declined for reasons unknown and their territories were claimed by the Chenla dynasty, which was divided into two parts &ndash; Land Chenla and Water Chenla &ndash; in the 8th century. During this period Cambodian power spread westwards into parts of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/thailand">Thailand</a>.</p>
<p>Cambodia&rsquo;s golden era came with the arrival of the Khmer dynasty, which ruled from the 9th to the 15th centuries and made the kingdom of Kambuja (from where modern-day Cambodia gets its name) one of the most powerful in Asia. The Khmer established their most famous capital at Angkor, founded as a Hindu spiritual centre but later converted to Buddhist worship.</p>
<p>A long period of decline followed, before the country fell under French colonial control in the 1800s. Independence was finally achieved in 1953, coinciding with the French being driven from Vietnam, after which Norodom Sihanouk was appointed king. His first reign lasted until the 1970s, when a coup d&rsquo;etat by the prime minister led to Cambodia being caught up in the Vietnam War. American air raids on Cambodia played a direct role in the rise of Pol Pot and the Khmer Rouge, who seized control after a brutal insurgency in 1975.</p>
<p>During the four years of Khmer Rouge rule, tens of thousands of people were executed in a systematic campaign of genocide, targeting academics, the wealthy, the educated, city dwellers and even people who wore glasses. In 1979 the Vietnamese army captured <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/phnom-penh">Phnom Penh</a> and occupied Cambodia, which was renamed the People's Republic of Kampuchea.</p>
<p>Following UN intervention, Sihanouk returned to the throne in 1993, before abdicating in 2004 in favour of his son, Norodom Sihamoni.<strong> </strong>In the subsequent elections, the left-wing Cambodian People&rsquo;s Party came to wield most of the power, led by prime minister Hun Sen. The most important ongoing issue facing Cambodia is the clearance of land mines and unexploded ordnance left behind from American bombing and the civil war, which continue to kill hundreds of people every year.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The Cambodian flag is the only national flag to feature a building &ndash; Angkor Wat. <br />
&bull;	There are an estimated four million unexploded landmines still scattered around the Cambodian countryside<br />
&bull;	Cambodia is one of the only countries in the world that has never had a McDonalds restaurant.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Cambodia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(0) 23 427 124.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukincambodia.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(0) 23 427 124.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0815-1645, Fri 0815-1315 (office); Mon-Fri 0830-1130 (consular).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Sangkat Srah Chak, Khan Daun Penh<br/>27-29 Street 75<br/>Phnom Penh<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Cambodia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 726 7742/7824. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofcambodia.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 726 7742/7824. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1200 and 1400-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>4530 16th Street<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20011<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Royal Embassy of Cambodia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 8451 7850.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.cambodianembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 8451 7850.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1630 (general); Mon-Fri 0930-1230 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Willesden Green<br/>64 Brondesbury Park<br/>London<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It might be one of Southeast Asia's smallest countries, but Cambodia can compete with the big boys when it comes to must-see sights. Once the preserve of trailblazing backpackers, this formerly war-torn nation is now firmly established on the Asia travel circuit. That luxury yachts ply their trade on Tonle Sap, Southeast Asia's largest freshwater lake, is a mark of just how far Cambodia has come.  <br /><br />Carving the country in two is the mighty Mekong River, which remains the lifeblood of Cambodia, running as it does from the bustling capital, Phnom Penh, to Vietnam's Mekong Delta. A journey down this iconic waterway is one of the great pleasures of Southeast Asia – boats of all shapes and sizes drift, chug and spray their way along the Mekong, carrying piglets, clay pots, bananas, motorcycles, you name it.  <br /><br />Away from the water, the ravages of war have become unlikely tourist attractions in Phnom Penh and other cities. Crowds gather at former prison camps and the notorious Killing Fields to contemplate Cambodia's darkest hour, a period of unimaginable suffering that took place under the brutal regime of Pol Pot. <br /><br />The crumbling remains of the Khmer Empire are the biggest draw in Cambodia, though. After building up a kingdom that stretched into neighbouring Thailand and China, the Khmers fell, leaving behind an extraordinary collection of temple complexes, most notably Angkor Wat, which owns the bragging rights to being the largest religious monument in the world. <br /><br />Then there are more typical Southeast Asian attractions – frenetic cities crammed with rickshaws, strange and exotic food, blissful beaches, tropical jungles teeming with wildlife, and a densely-forested hinterland full of tribal villages. <br /><br />There are few places that have been through as much as Cambodia, but this optimistic nation has belied its tumultuous history and emerged as one of the warmest, most welcoming destinations in Southeast Asia.</p>It might be one of Southeast Asia's smallest countries, but Cambodia can compete with the big boys when it comes to must-see sights. Once the preserve of trailblazing backpackers, this formerly war-torn nation is now firmly established on the Asia travel circuit. That luxury yachts now float on Tonle Sap, Southeast Asia's largest freshwater lake, is a mark of just how far Cambodia has come. Carving the country in two, the mighty Mekong River remains the lifeblood of Cambodia and a journey down this iconic waterway is one of the great pleasures of Southeast Asia.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
