<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Cameroon" ColCode="cmr" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="cm" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Cameroon]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The south is hot and dry November-February. The main rainy season is June-October. Temperatures in the north vary. On the Adamaoua Plateau, temperatures drop sharply at night; the rainy season is May-October. Grassland areas inland are much cooler than the coast with regular rainfall. The best months to visit are January- April.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cotton clothes, canvas or light leather shoes or sandals. Waterproofs are advised for coastal areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>This is the most efficient means of national transport. Camair-Co (<a href="http://www.camair-co.cm" target="_blank">www.camair-co.cm</a>)&nbsp;runs services to a number of destinations within Cameroon including Douala, Yaound&eacute;, Garoua and Maroua. You can also arrange private charter jets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Camrail (<a href="http://www.camrail.net" target="_blank">www.camrail.net</a>) is the national service provider. Services are good, if relatively slow, but it is still much quicker to go by train than by bus. There are daily overnight services from Yaound&eacute; to Ngaound&eacute;r&eacute;, with couchettes and first- and second-class seats.&nbsp;</p>
<p>There is a rail route running from Douala to Nkongsamba, with a branch line leading off from Mbanga to Kumba. Daily trains also run from Yaound&eacute; to Douala. Trains usually have a restaurant car. Tickets must be booked on the day of travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>There are paved roads from Douala to Yaound&eacute;, Limb&eacute;, Bu&eacute;a, Bafoussam and Bamenda and between main centres.&nbsp;Other roads are generally poorly maintained and become almost impassable during the rainy season.&nbsp;Many vehicles are poorly lit and badly driven.&nbsp;Night driving is not recommended.</p>
<p>Carjackings and violent muggings are increasingly common, particularly in the three most northern provinces.&nbsp;Driving on the Yaound&eacute;/Douala trunk road should be avoided; accidents happen frequently.</p><p>You can drive on your own national licence when you first arrive, but need to obtain a Cameroonian licence from the Delegation of Transport as soon as you can.</p><p>This is expensive and limited to Douala, Yaound&eacute; and Limb&eacute;. Cars are available with or without a driver. Roadside assistance is non-existent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taxis and share-taxis are available at reasonable fixed rates (none are metered). A 10% tip is optional. City taxis do not generally comply with basic security norms and seat belts are often absent. Violent assaults on taxi passengers are not uncommon, so the choice of taxi must be considered carefully. However, they are cheap and fast.</p>
<p>Petty theft is common on trains, coaches and bush-taxis, and visitors to Cameroon who rely on public transport are urged to remain vigilant.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cameroon</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ngaoundeacutereacute</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">12.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cameroon</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">maroua</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">24.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cameroon</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kribi</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cameroon</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">garoua</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">18.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cameroon</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">douala</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no direct flights to Cameroon from the UK or USA. Options include flights with Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) via Paris, Brussels Airlines (<a href="http://www.brusselsairlines.com" target="_blank">www.brusselsairlines.com</a>) via Brussels, or Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>) via Casablanca.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 16 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFA10,000 (children included in parents' passports are exempt as are holders of diplomatic passports).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Douala International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is situated 10km (6 miles) southeast of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Yaoundé Nsimalen International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport airport is situated 25km (15.5 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cargo boats from Douala to Malabo (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/equatorial-guinea">Equatorial Guinea</a>) sometimes accept passengers. Speedboats and cargo boats ply the coastal route between Idendao (northern Cameroon) and Oron (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nigeria">Nigeria</a>). However, these services are not regulated.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no international rail services from Cameroon to neighbouring countries due to the different line gauges.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International calls can be made from Camtel offices. Telephones can usually be found in post offices and restaurants, and there are telephone booths in the towns. Phonecards are available. The phone service is often unreliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a number of international mobile phone companies. Coverage is patchy but better in the south.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Main towns will have Internet cafés. Charges are significantly higher outside Yaoundé and Douala. The service is often slow and unreliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Media is highly government controlled. However, a general liberalisation of media in 2000 led to Cameroon's first private TV station, TV Max, being launched in 2001, with a spate of others quick to follow. <br /><br />Nevertheless, libel laws inhibit journalists and some have even been jailed in the past. This is regarded as a genuine problem by the international community, who believe that Cameroon is becoming one of the most repressive countries worldwide in regards to freedom of expression.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Stamps can only be obtained from post offices. Mail usually takes at least a week to reach Europe.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Drive through the central highlands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hop in a 4-wheel drive and explore the splendid scenery of the central highlands. Starting in Douala, the drive to Nkongsamba rises to reveal vibrant, verdant valleys and breath-taking waterfalls. As dusk falls, ready the camera to capture the striking orange and purple skylines.</p>]]><p><b>Find colonial architecture in Foumban</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In this culture-rich town, discover many traditional buildings dating from Cameroon's period of German colonisation. Completed in 1917, a beautiful Sultan's Palace contains a museum on King Ibrahim Njoya, whilst nearby the Musée du Palais, the Musée des Arts et des Traditions Bamoun and the market are all well worth a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Go on a gorilla safari in Lobéké National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lobéké National Park is home to elusive families of western lowland gorillas. For the best chance of viewing these graceful giants, visitors can spend the night in a specially built watchtower. Equally exciting but easier to spot are elephants, buffalo and the giant forest hog, though visitors should keep their eyes peeled for red river hogs and bongo antelope.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about the local fauna at Limbé</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This pleasant port town (formerly Victoria) boasts a beautiful botanical garden. Founded in 1892 by Cameroon's German colonisers, the gardens were originally set up to trial exotic crops such as coffee, cocoa and rubber. Today, conservation is at the heart of the scent-filled gardens, which offer trails and insights into Cameroonian botanic culture.</p>]]><p><b>Make for Maroua for hiking and rock climbing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head north to Maroua for some exertion. Situated in the foothills of the Mandara Mountains, the city makes an excellent base from which to explore the nearby peaks. Lower reaches offer moderate hiking trails and fine views whilst Le Dent de Mindif, south of the city, is a highly regarded rock climbing spot.</p>]]><p><b>Reserve some time for nature spotting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to Cameroon's northern reaches to see monkeys, snuffling warthogs and an abundance of antelope in the Kalamaloué Reserve. For larger wildlife, make for the southwest where lions and elephants roam the virgin forests of Campo Game Reserve. Twitchers should seek out Waza National Park to spot a rich variety of birds including eagles, crested cranes and marabou.</p>]]><p><b>Scale an active volcano</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At 4,095m (13,435ft) Mount Cameroon is the highest mountain in West Africa and Africa's highest active volcano, making it a popular destination for mountaineers. Make your base Buea, a pretty colonial town complete with Cameroon's first post office. From here, the climb takes three to four days.</p>]]><p><b>Spot the rare black rhino in Bouba Ndjidah National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated on the banks of Mayo Lidi River, in the far north of the country, this park is a popular location to see lions, elephants, élan and buffalo. Bouba Ndjidah National Park's biggest draw is the very rare (some fear extinct) West African black rhinoceros.</p>]]><p><b>Wade waist-deep through Korup National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Africa's oldest and most biologically diverse rainforest offers the chance to see a wide variety of primates including the short-tailed drill monkey. Ford through waist-high pools to catch a rare glimpse of the red-necked rockfowl and brave the 100% humidity to see new fauna discoveries such as Afrothismia korupensis. </p>]]><p><b>Wander the hills of Yaoundé</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Straddling seven hills, Cameroon's bustling capital is pleasantly green. On top of Mont Fébé sits the Benedictine Monastery's Musée d'Art Cameroonais, which houses traditional arts and crafts including an enviable collection of masks. The newer National Museum of Yaoundé is also worthy of a visit. Make the most of the exhibitions with a guided tour.</p>]]><p><b>Witness crab sorcery at Rhumsiki</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This village features a maze of paths linking the small farms known as the Kapsiki; the Kirdi live here, whose customs and folklore, including crab sorcery, have changed little for centuries. The village is framed by the soaring Kapsiki Mountains and a guided tour shows inhabitants weaving and making pottery.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$22 billion (2010 est.).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil and petroleum products, timber, cocoa, cotton, aluminium and coffee.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, electrical and transport equipment, and food products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Italy, Nigeria, Spain, China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Because of consistent agricultural performance and the growth of its modest oil industry, Cameroon has enjoyed broad economic success since independence, although it is vulnerable to changes in world commodity prices.<br /><br />The main agricultural products are cocoa, coffee, palm oil, wood and rubber. There are some offshore oil deposits, and sizeable but largely unexploited deposits of iron ore, copper, uranium and other metals. Hydro-electric projects supply most of the country's energy, while oil and gas are largely exported. <br /><br />During the 1990s, the government opened up much of the economy to competition. Since then, an IMF structural adjustment programme has set the ground rules for the country's economic policy. Cameroon became eligible for debt relief under the Heavily Indebted Poor Countries Initiative (HIPC) in 2000, which meant significant relief from debt upon completion in 2006. Since 2002, Douala has hosted one of sub-Saharan Africa's few stock exchanges.<br /><br />The main hindrances to Cameroon's further economic development include corruption, inefficiency and an excess of red tape. The IMF continues to press for reform in all these areas, and for privatisation of key institutions and services, as a means to poverty reduction.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0730-1800.<br /><br /><strong>Government office hours</strong>: Mon-Fri 0730-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce, d'Industrie, des Mines et de l'Artisanat du Cameroun</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 32 42 98 81
					Website:http://www.ccima.net
					Address: ,PO Box 4011,Douala,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Local food is excellent, but luxury items can be extremely expensive. There are many restaurants in big towns and cities, with good service. Douala and Yaoundé have by far the greatest variety, with many different styles of cuisine represented, including Lebanese, Asian, African and European. Cheap and tasty Cameroonian food is served in <em>chantiers</em> and chop houses. The coastal area offers excellent fresh fish and prawns. Most international hotels have bars.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; <em>Feuille</em> (manioc leaves). <br />&bull; West African peanut soup.<br />&bull; Banana bread.<br />&bull; <em>Zom</em> (spinach with meat).<br />&bull; Fried sweet potatoes or plantains. <br />&bull; Beef with pineapple or coconut.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Although vegetarianism is rare in Cameroon, it is possible for to get by on egg dishes, vegetables, pizza, bread and tropical fruit. Many dishes are served with rice, couscous, mashed manioc or chips made from potato, yam or plantain.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>The average tip for porters and hotel staff should be about 10%, otherwise service charges are usually included.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Douala and Yaound&eacute; particularly, nightclubs and casinos can be found independently or within most good hotels. Both Douala and Yaound&eacute; have a few sophisticated restaurants which double as live music venues and attract the expat crowd. <br />
<br />
There are also plenty of basic bars and clubs, some of which host live bands at weekends. The music on offer varies from local sounds to reggae, rap and rock. There are no licensing hours, and hotel bars stay open as long as there is custom. Every large town also has at least one cinema.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local handicrafts include highly decorated pots, drinking horns, jugs, bottles and cups, wood carvings, great earthenware bowls and delicate pottery, dishes and trays, mats and rugs woven from grass, raffia, jewellery and camel hair, cotton and beadwork garments. These are sold in the <em>march&eacute;s artisanales</em> (tourist or craft markets) found in large towns and tourist areas. <br />
<br />
Some stallholders offer items which they describe as antique: in many cases they're merely distressed. Special permission must be obtained from the Delegation Provinciale de Tourisme in Douala or Yound&eacute; to take genuine antiquities out of the country. The main markets in most towns sell fresh produce, cheap clothing and household essentials rather than souvenirs, but can be good places to find African-style printed cotton fabric.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0730-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good accommodation of international standard is available in Bamenda, Douala, Garoua, Maroua and Yaoundé. Cheaper accommodation, catering principally for local travellers, is available in every town. Rates quoted by hotels and lodges are generally for the room rather than per person. <br /><br />The good hotels (government-rated 2-star and above) have rooms with showers and air conditioning; the better places also have sports facilities and swimming pools. Prices in Douala and Yaoundé are rather high. Some large hotels will accept major credit cards. Hotel facilities are in heavy demand; it is advisable to book in advance and obtain written confirmation of your booking.<br /><br />Mid-range and cheap hotels, including <em>auberges</em> (guesthouses) and <em>campements</em> (country lodges), can be excellent value, although it's wise to inspect the room, checking that it has running water and electricity, before committing yourself. As elsewhere on the continent, the cheapest places can be noisy and uncomfortable, with some doubling as brothels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good accommodation of international standard is available in Bamenda, Douala, Garoua, Maroua and Yaoundé. Cheaper accommodation, catering principally for local travellers, is available in every town. Rates quoted by hotels and lodges are generally for the room rather than per person. <br /><br />The good hotels (government-rated 2-star and above) have rooms with showers and air conditioning; the better places also have sports facilities and swimming pools. Prices in Douala and Yaoundé are rather high. Some large hotels will accept major credit cards. Hotel facilities are in heavy demand; it is advisable to book in advance and obtain written confirmation of your booking.<br /><br />Mid-range and cheap hotels, including <em>auberges</em> (guesthouses) and <em>campements</em> (country lodges), can be excellent value, although it's wise to inspect the room, checking that it has running water and electricity, before committing yourself. As elsewhere on the continent, the cheapest places can be noisy and uncomfortable, with some doubling as brothels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good accommodation of international standard is available in Bamenda, Douala, Garoua, Maroua and Yaoundé. Cheaper accommodation, catering principally for local travellers, is available in every town. Rates quoted by hotels and lodges are generally for the room rather than per person. <br /><br />The good hotels (government-rated 2-star and above) have rooms with showers and air conditioning; the better places also have sports facilities and swimming pools. Prices in Douala and Yaoundé are rather high. Some large hotels will accept major credit cards. Hotel facilities are in heavy demand; it is advisable to book in advance and obtain written confirmation of your booking.<br /><br />Mid-range and cheap hotels, including <em>auberges</em> (guesthouses) and <em>campements</em> (country lodges), can be excellent value, although it's wise to inspect the room, checking that it has running water and electricity, before committing yourself. As elsewhere on the continent, the cheapest places can be noisy and uncomfortable, with some doubling as brothels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are a number of district and private hospitals in Cameroon, although health facilities are not recommended to foreign travellers. Sanitation levels are low, even in the best hospitals and clinics. Facilities outside Yaoundé and Douala are extremely limited. International travellers are strongly advised to take out full medical insurance before departure.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Bottled water is readily available. Powdered or tinned milk is advised. Milk is unpasteurised: avoid dairy products made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B is hyperendemic. Hepatitis E, dysentery, dengue fever and typhoid fever are widespread. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Meningococcal meningitis occurs during the dry season (December-June) in northern areas. HIV/AIDS is prevalent. Rabies is present; for those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Djoulde Soumae (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Djoulde Soumae itself. Djoulde Soumae and Eid al-Adha (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Youth Day :
							11 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>National Day :
							20 May </p><p>Sheep Festival :
							21 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Cameroon without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes or 125 cigars or 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits and 3L of wine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlicensed arms and ammunition; game-hunting weapons require a permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Endangered flora and fauna, unless licensed. You must also obtain permission to export artworks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFA (Communaut&eacute; Financi&egrave;re Africaine) Franc (XAF; symbol CFA) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of CFA10,000, 5,000, 2,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of CFA250, 100, 50, 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1.<br />
<br />
Cameroon, together with CAR, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chad">Chad</a>, Congo-Brazzaville, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/equatorial-guinea">Equatorial Guinea</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/gabon">Gabon</a>, belongs to an economic and monetary community sharing a common currency, the Banque des &Eacute;tats de l'Afrique Centrale (Bank of Central African States) CFA Franc, which is pegged to the Euro. The CFA Franc issued by the Banque des &Eacute;tats de l'Afrique de l'Ouest (Bank of West African States), used in the ECOWAS countries further west, has the same value but is not legal tender in Cameroon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euros are the easiest currency to exchange. US Dollars are the next most acceptable. Travellers should bring cash in preference to traveller's cheques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are accepted on a very limited basis (some airline offices and hotels will take them). Cards cannot be used in banks to obtain cash advances.</p><p>ATMs are rare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros, although it is possible to exchange Sterling traveller's cheques. Commission rates tend to be high.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0730-1530 or from 0800-1700 at certain branches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for a minimum of six months is required by all nationals referred to in chart above to enter Cameroon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist  and business: &pound;89 (three months) or &pound;178 (six months).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Usually up to three or six months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Passports are usually available for collection 48 hours after drop-off at the high commission/embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When applying for your visa, you need to supply a bank statement showing a balance of at least &pound;1,000. This is waived if a travel agent or tour operator is organising your trip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[5.684972]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[12.722998]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>475,442 sq km (183,569 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>23,924,407 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>49.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Yaound&eacute;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Situated on the west coast of Africa, Cameroon is bordered to the west by the Gulf of Guinea, to the northwest by Nigeria, to the northeast by Chad (with Lake Chad at its northern tip), to the east by the Central African Republic and to the south by Congo-Brazzaville (Republic of the Congo), Gabon and Equatorial Guinea.</p>
<p>The far north of the country is a semi-desert broadening into the vast Maroua Plain, with game reserves and mineral deposits. This is bordered to the west by the lush Mandara Mountains; the Benue River rises here and flows westwards into the Niger.</p>
<p>The country to the northwest is particularly striking: volcanic peaks covered by bamboo forest rise to over 2,000m (6,500ft), with waterfalls and villages scattered over the lower slopes. Further to the south and west are savannah uplands, while dense forest covers the east and south. The highest peak, at 4,095m (13,434ft) is Mount Cameroon, which lies close to the coast. The humid coastal strip is tropical, with a mixture of rainforest and farmland.</p>
<p>The River Wouri, which flows southwest into the Gulf of Guinea, inspired the country's name after 15th-century Portuguese sailor Fernando Po's spoke of the Rio dos Cameroes (river of shrimps).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the population hold Christian (mainly Roman Catholic) or traditional animist beliefs. The sizeable remainder are followers of Islam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the customary form of greeting. In the north, where the population is largely Muslim, Islamic traditions should be respected. Visitors should never step inside a Muslim prayer circle of rocks. In other rural areas, where traditional beliefs predominate, it is essential to use tact.<br /><br /><strong>Photography:</strong> Cameras should be used with discretion, particularly in rural areas. Always ask permission before taking a photograph. Do not photograph airports, military establishments, official buildings, or military personnel in uniform.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Phil&eacute;mon Yang since 2009.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Paul Biya since 1982.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the first century, the Sao people settled around Lake Chad and it is from them that much of the country's remarkable sculpture originates.</p><p>Present-day Cameroon was at the heartland of an area that extended into Nigeria, under the control of the Duala people. An estimated 200 distinct ethnic groups live in the region, the largest of which is the Bamileke, a tribe occupying the west and centre of the country.</p><p>Equatorial Bantu live in the area between the Congo basin and the plateaux of the interior, while small hunting bands of pygmies dwell in the remote southern forests.</p><p>The Portuguese arrived in the 15th century; later, in the 1880s, the area became a German protectorate. But after Germany's defeat in World War 1, Cameroon was divided between Britain and France.</p><p>French Cameroon achieved independence in 1957, under the control of the principal pro-independence party, the Union Nationale Camerounaise (UNC). In 1961, the northern provinces voted to become part of Nigeria, while the south opted for union with French Cameroon. A centralised political and administrative system was introduced with the veteran northern politician, Ahmadou Ahidjo, as President.</p><p>In 1975, Paul Biya became Prime Minister and when Ahidjo stepped down in 1982, he was succeeded by Biya who as head of the UNC and its successor party, the Rassemblement Démocratique du Peuple Camerounais (RDPC), Biya has since achieved complete political domination over Cameroon.</p><p>In recent years Cameroon's English-speaking territories have become increasingly isolated from Biya's government with some politicians from these regions calling for greater devolution, even secession. However, the country is generally quite stable in social and political terms, allowing the development of infrastructure and industry.</p><p>Cameroon joined the Commonwealth in 1995 and the UN Security Council in 2002, as one of three African representatives (with Angola and Guinea). It is also a member of la Francophonie. Its record on human rights is considered flawed but has been generally improving.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p> The two most popular types of music in Cameroon are makossa, a blend of highlife, soul, folk and Congo music; and bikutsi, the dance music of the Ewondo people heard of Paul Simon's 1990 album, <em>The Rhythm of the Saints</em>.</p><p> Although French and English are the official languages, Cameroon his home to some 1738 language groups.</p><p> in May 2014, following the Chibok schoolgirl kidnapping, Cameroon joined Chad in declaring war on the Boko Haram and deployed troops on the border with Nigeria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Cameroon in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 8790.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.cameroonembassyusa.org/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 8790.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3400 International Drive<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Cameroon High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7727 0771.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.cameroonhighcommission.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7727 0771.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1630.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>84 Holland Park<br/>London<br/>W11 3SB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While referring to Cameroon as &ldquo;Africa in miniature&rdquo; has become a bit of a clich&eacute;, this statement certainly rings true: everything you would expect from the African continent seems to be consolidated here, in this enticing and eclectic land.</p>
<p>The beautiful south is characterised by tropical rainforests and deserted golden beaches, which would be chock full of bathers in a more developed destination. There&rsquo;s a hearty appetite for independence in the English-speaking south, but, despite the best efforts of local pressure groups, it has yet to break free from the rest of the country.</p>
<p>In contrast to the south, the dramatic landscapes of northern Cameroon are dominated by great expanses of desert, lakes and savannah. Traditional villages still cling on in this unforgiving land, which is perhaps the most culturally diverse region in Cameroon, home as it is to some 50 ethnic groups. Though largely peaceful, the region has been rocked by attacks from extremists in recent years. Keep abreast of the latest news.</p>
<p>Pack your hiking gear if you&rsquo;re heading to western Cameroon, which is dominated by volcanic mountains. Looking out across these rugged ranges you could be forgiven for thinking you were on Mars, such is their otherworldly appearance. It&rsquo;s not all about the landscapes, though. Scattered across the country are a handful of game reserves, which offer ample opportunity to observe impressive wildlife, including elephants and lions.</p>
<p>Cameroon really should be one of Africa&rsquo;s leading destinations, but poverty blights much of its infrastructure, meaning transport and accommodation are chronically underdeveloped. Outstanding border disputes haven&rsquo;t helped, either &ndash; travellers are advised to steer clear of the frontiers with Nigeria, Chad and the Central African Republic, which are considered unstable.  </p>
<p>Aside from certain no-go areas, Cameroon has much to offer adventurous travellers. From its verdant rainforests to its iconic wildlife, the country is bursting with life. Go and you shall be handsomely rewarded.</p><p>While referring to Cameroon as &ldquo;Africa in miniature&rdquo; has become a bit of a clich&eacute;, this statement certainly rings true: everything you would expect from the African continent seems to be consolidated here, in this enticing and eclectic land.</p>
<p>The beautiful south is characterised by tropical rainforests and deserted golden beaches, which would be chock full of bathers in a more developed destination. There&rsquo;s a hearty appetite for independence in the English-speaking south, but, despite the best efforts of local pressure groups, it has yet to break free from the rest of the country. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
