<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Alberta" ColCode="aba" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ab" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Alberta]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Summer, between June and September, is warm, while winters are cold, with particularly heavy snowfalls in the Rockies. Spring and summer evening temperatures can be cool.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Light to medium-weight clothing during warmer months. Heavyweight clothing and durable footwear is required in winter, with alpine wear in mountains. Waterproof wear is advisable throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Air Canada (AC) </em>(<a href="http://www.aircanada.com/" target="_blank">www.aircanada.com</a>) operates flights to Alberta. Many other airlines also serve the province from worldwide destinations.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From Edmonton/Calgary to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a><em> </em>is 8 hours 30 minutes, to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/los-angeles-international-airport">Los Angeles</a><em> </em>is 3 hours and to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a><em> </em>is 4 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Calgary International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.yyc.com<p>Calgary International Airport is located 17km (10.5 miles) northeast of Calgary.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 403 735 1200</p>]]><b>Edmonton International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flyeia.com<p>The airport  is 28km (17 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>VIA Rail </em>(tel: +1 888 842 7245; <a href="http://www.viarail.ca/" target="_blank">www.viarail.ca</a>) serves Edmonton and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ski/jasper">Jasper</a>. The Western transcontinental train (<em>The</em> <em>Canadian</em>) crosses the province several times a week, originating from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/ontario">Ontario</a>, in the east and going via Edmonton and Jasper, to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vancouver/vancouver-international-airport">Vancouver</a> in the west and vice versa. This train connects with <em>The <em>Skeena </em></em>train at Jasper with a regular service to Prince Rupert, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/british-columbia">British Columbia</a>. The Skeena trip requires one or more overnight off-train stays en route.<br />
<br />
The seasonal <em>Rocky </em><em>Mountaineer</em><em> </em>(tel: +1 877 460 3200 <em>or</em> +44 0800 0606 7372, in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>; <a href="http://www.rockymountaineer.com/" target="_blank">www.rockymountaineer.com</a>) is the only other rail service operating into the province with routes from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/alberta/calgary-international-airport">Calgary</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ski/banff">Banff</a> or Jasper to and from Vancouver and <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/seattle">Seattle</a>, running between mid April and mid October.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Jasper National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Jasper National Park was established in 1907 and is the largest of Canada's Rocky Mountains  parks, spanning 10,878 sq kilometres (4200 sq miles). The spectacular scenery is characterised by glaciers, rugged mountains, forests and meadows carpeted with alpine flowers. The park protects a range of fragile mountain ecosystems - elk, moose, bear, bighorn sheep and mule deer are regular sights - and is home to the threatened woodland caribou. Maligne Lake, 48km (30 miles) southeast of Jasper is surrounded by snow-capped mountains and its crystal clear waters are popular for boating and fishing.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Alpine diving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Horseshoe Lake, Patricia Lake and Lake Annette are three of the more popular alpine diving locations. Divers should be experienced and employ the 'buddy' system as the water is cold and often cloudy. The local Rangers Station supplies permits, maps and other information.</p>]]><p><b>Ancient fossils</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You can study dinosaur remains on the banks of the Red Deer River, on the 48km (30-mile) Dinosaur Trail near Drumheller. Also near downtown Drumheller is the Royal Tyrrell Museum of Palaeontology, with hands-on exhibitions and one of the world's largest collections of dinosaur remains.</p>]]><p><b>Banff Summer Arts Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Alberta's biggest showcase of the arts (with dance, theatre, film, music and art) takes place over four months annually, all amidst the stunning backdrop of the Rocky Mountains.</p>]]><p><b>Calgary Stampede</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Canada's biggest rodeo is billed as the 'Greatest Outdoor Show on Earth'; it is held over 10 days in July each year (www.calgarystampede.com) and attracts many competitors and spectators with stage shows, parades, concerts, rodeo and agricultural exhibits.</p>]]><p><b>Calgary Tower</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Calgary's most recognisable feature, the 191m (626ft) Calgary Tower<strong>,</strong> offers panoramic views of the city, local towns and the Rocky Mountains. Sky 360, the rotating restaurant at the top, is a popular treat (<a href="http://www.sky360.ca" target="_blank">www.sky360.ca</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Cowboy country</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The heritage of ranching is alive and well in the town of Cochrane, west of Calgary. Country-and-western-themed shops pepper the downtown area and genuine cowboys still live and work in the region.</p>]]><p><b>Historic site</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You'll find Alberta's oldest surviving structure, the historic log cabin of Father Lacombe, in the town of St Albert, 30km (19 miles) northwest of downtown Edmonton. At one time it was the centre of a thriving French-speaking Métis settlement (people of mixed native and European heritage).</p>]]><p><b>Jasper National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Jasper National Park was established in 1907 and is the largest of Canada's Rocky Mountains  parks, spanning 10,878 sq kilometres (4200 sq miles). The spectacular scenery is characterised by glaciers, rugged mountains, forests and meadows carpeted with alpine flowers. The park protects a range of fragile mountain ecosystems - elk, moose, bear, bighorn sheep and mule deer are regular sights - and is home to the threatened woodland caribou. Maligne Lake, 48km (30 miles) southeast of Jasper is surrounded by snow-capped mountains and its crystal clear waters are popular for boating and fishing.</p>]]><p><b>Lovely lakes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Alberta boasts characteristic Canadian views: stunning lake scenery in Waterton Lakes National Park, joined to Glacier National Park in Montana to form the Waterton-Glacier International Peace Park; and Banff National Park in the heart of the Canadian Rockies.</p>]]><p><b>National parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The great outdoors is the main attraction in the southern part of the Rockies; Banff and Jasper national parks are obvious starting points.</p>]]><p><b>Native heritage</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The name sounds horrific but the prairie views are unparalleled at Head-Smashed-In Buffalo Jump, west of Lethbridge. This cliff-top is an ancient jump site, used for 10,000 years to drive buffalo to their deaths, thus providing native people with food, shelter and clothing.</p>]]><p><b>On the slopes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Skiing, both cross-country and downhill, is a major pastime in the Rockies in the winter. Snowboarding is also very popular.</p>]]><p><b>Scenic drive</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Icefields Parkway (Highway 93), running through Banff and Jasper national parks, affords magnificent views of the lakes, forests and the glaciers of the Columbia Icefield. It also provides access to wilderness trails in the area.</p>]]><p><b>West Edmonton Mall</b></p><![CDATA[<p>North America's largest entertainment centre and mall, the West Edmonton Mall (<a href="http://www.wem.ca" target="_blank">www.wem.ca</a>), boasts theatres, restaurants, nightclubs, miniature golf course, ice rink, swimming pool, water park and amusement park, skateboard park, aquariums and bungee jump.</p>]]><p><b>Winter sports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are myriad ways to enjoy the wonderful mountain scenery, including dog sledding (trekking along mountain trails with teams of huskies under the supervision of experienced guides), ski-joring (being pulled along on skis by teams of huskies), wildlife tracking, snowmobiling and snowshoeing.</p>]]><p><b>Wonderful wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Elk Island National Park (<a href="http://www.pc.gc.ca/elkisland" target="_blank">www.pc.gc.ca/elkisland</a>), which traces its roots to 1906, is home to over 44 different kinds of animals (including elk, moose, coyote and beaver), as well as massive herds of plains bison.</p>]]><p><b>Wood Buffalo National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Vast expanses of boreal plains are yours to discover at Wood Buffalo National Park (<a href="http://www.pc.gc.ca/woodbuffalo" target="_blank">www.pc.gc.ca/woodbuffalo</a>) (Canada's largest national park, bigger than Switzerland), granted World Heritage status by UNESCO in 1983. It provides the perfect habitat for many rare species of wildlife, including the world's largest free-roaming bison herd.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Situated to the east and north of the Rocky Mountains, Alberta&rsquo;s business etiquette falls somewhere between the legendary laid-back attitude of the west coast and the well-known conservatism of the east. Canadians from Alberta are immensely friendly, hard-working and punctual. Both men and women dress 'business conservative' in the office, while formal dress is expected at business meetings. </p>
<p>During the Calgary Stampede, however, many of the city's business professionals express their civic pride by dressing in cowboy hats, boots, jeans, etc.  The working day typically begins as early as 0800 and ends at 1700. During formal introductions, it is common to shake hands and address individuals by their surnames. On a day-to-day basis, however, both superiors and co-workers are normally addressed on a first-name basis. </p>
<p>Most entertainment takes place in bars and restaurants and it is unusual for a business visitor to be invited into someone's home. Gift giving is uncommon in business situations, although a token gift is acceptable after a project or deal has been completed (but not before). Although <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a> is officially bilingual, English is almost always the language of business in Alberta.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Calgary Convention &amp; Visitors Bureau (Information on Conferences/Conventions)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (403) 263 8510 ,1 800 661 1678
					Website:http://www.tourismcalgary.com/
					Address: 238 11th Avenue SE,Suite 200,Calgary,]]><b>Alberta Chambers of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (780) 425 4180
					Website:http://www.abchamber.ca/
					Address: 10025-102A Avenue,1808,Edmonton,]]><b>Jasper Tourism and Commerce (Information on Conferences/Conventions)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (780) 852 3858
					Website:http://www.jaspercanadianrockies.com/
					Address: Jasper,PO Box 98,Alberta T0E 1E0,]]><b>Edmonton Economic Development Corporation/Edmonton Tourism</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (780) 426 4715 ,1 800 463 4667
					Website:http://www.edmonton.com/
					Address: 9990 Jasper Avenue,Third Floor,World Trade Centre Edmonton,Edmonton,]]><b>Banff/Lake Louise Tourism Bureau (Information on Conferences/Conventions)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (403) 762 8421.
					Website:http://www.banfflakelouise.com
					Address: Banff,,Alberta T1L 1B3,PO Box 1298]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alberta's prairie is ideal for cattle rearing and its Western beef is world famous. There's a strong emphasis on sustainable eating here, with chefs creating inventive dishes using seasonal, locally grown produce. Apart from traditional foods, Alberta's towns and cities offer an excellent range of international cuisine.  Eating out in Alberta might involve sharing Asian small plates, tucking into a tender hunk of steak, savouring fine French fare or enjoying the latest farm-to-table creations.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>• Beef is barbecued, braised, grilled, minced and skewered with different complements such as onions, mushrooms, green peppers, rice, sauces and beans; Alberta beef is renowned worldwide and is extraordinarily succulent.<br/>• Stew (combination of diced steak, garden vegetables and biscuits cooked in rich gravy).</p><p>• Game meats and wild fish, combined with garden-fresh vegetables.</p><p>• Bison is served in a variety of cuts, including steaks, burgers and sausages.</p><p>• Root vegetables such as beetroots and carrots.</p><p>• Taber corn, sold at roadside stands in and around the southern Alberta town of Taber. It's famed for its sweet taste thanks to the area's abundant sunshine.<br/>• Wild berries and nuts are used in desserts.<br/>• Honey is made from alfalfa and clover nectar and is a widely used sweetener and breakfast food.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>In Alberta, alcohol is sold in privately owned liquor stores.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It's customary to tip between 15% and 20% at bars and restaurants in Alberta. Tips are also given to tour guides, and for taxi service, spa treatments, porters and haircuts.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Both Edmonton and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/alberta/calgary-international-airport">Calgary</a> have a rich variety of nocturnal entertainment. Nightclubs, cabarets, taverns, lounges and pubs combine to provide constant local and international entertainment. Calgary and Edmonton boast full-scale orchestras.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alberta is the only Canadian jurisdiction (apart from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/northwest-territories">Northwest Territories</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/nunavut">Nunavut</a> and Yukon) that does not apply an extra sales tax on all purchases over and above the federal goods and services tax of 5%. Artwork available in the province includes pottery, ceramics, sculptures and paintings. There are numerous malls in Edmonton, including the huge West Edmonton Mall. Speciality shops can be found in the Old Strathcona district, from boutiques to a farmer's market. The trendy Kensington Village district in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/alberta/calgary-international-airport">Calgary</a> has over 100 excellent shops, restaurants and services.</p><p>Mon-Sat 1000-1800 (hours vary widely; many large stores and malls are open until 2100 Mon-Fri, and Sun 1200-1700).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation ranges from top-quality hotels to motorway motels, lodge estates, camping and hostels. A basic room tax of 4% is levied on all accommodation. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ski/banff">Banff</a> also has a 2% tourism improvement fee.&nbsp;Some cities in Alberta levy an additional Destination Marketing Fee (DMF) up to 3 per cent.<br />
<br />
Banff National Park is famous for its two landmark chateau-style hotels, built when the railways were driven across <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a> and offering approximately 1,300 rooms. <em>Canada</em><em> Select</em> star ratings (1 to 5 stars) is an&nbsp;optional rating programme. However, much of Alberta's accommodation is inspected by the Alberta Hotel &amp; Lodging Association. Look for the 'Approved Accommodation' sign.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfast and ranch stays are available throughout Alberta.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation ranges from top-quality hotels to motorway motels, lodge estates, camping and hostels. A basic room tax of 4% is levied on all accommodation. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ski/banff">Banff</a> also has a 2% tourism improvement fee.&nbsp;Some cities in Alberta levy an additional Destination Marketing Fee (DMF) up to 3 per cent.<br />
<br />
Banff National Park is famous for its two landmark chateau-style hotels, built when the railways were driven across <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a> and offering approximately 1,300 rooms. <em>Canada</em><em> Select</em> star ratings (1 to 5 stars) is an&nbsp;optional rating programme. However, much of Alberta's accommodation is inspected by the Alberta Hotel &amp; Lodging Association. Look for the 'Approved Accommodation' sign.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation ranges from top-quality hotels to motorway motels, lodge estates, camping and hostels. A basic room tax of 4% is levied on all accommodation. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ski/banff">Banff</a> also has a 2% tourism improvement fee.&nbsp;Some cities in Alberta levy an additional Destination Marketing Fee (DMF) up to 3 per cent.<br />
<br />
Banff National Park is famous for its two landmark chateau-style hotels, built when the railways were driven across <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a> and offering approximately 1,300 rooms. <em>Canada</em><em> Select</em> star ratings (1 to 5 stars) is an&nbsp;optional rating programme. However, much of Alberta's accommodation is inspected by the Alberta Hotel &amp; Lodging Association. Look for the 'Approved Accommodation' sign.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>In addition, Alberta observes all the Public Holidays observed nationwide.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Below are listed Public Holidays for the January 2014-December 2015 period.</p>]]><p>Heritage Day :
							06 August </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[53.933271]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-116.576504]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>661,848 sq km (255,541 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4.1 million (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5.77 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Edmonton.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alberta is the most westerly of the 'prairie and plains' provinces, bordered to the west by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/british-columbia">British Columbia</a> and the Rockies, and to the south by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/montana">Montana</a>. In the north, along the border with the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/northwest-territories">Northwest Territories</a>, there is a wilderness of forests, lakes and rivers. Mt Columbia on the western Rocky Mountains border is the highest point, rising to 3,747m (12,293ft). Alberta also has significant icefields. They release meltwaters which supply the Mackenzie River flowing into the Arctic Ocean, and the North Saskatchewan River flowing into Hudson Bay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>First inhabited by the Paleo-Indians more than 10,000 years ago, the first European settlers arrived in Alberta circa 1750. The native population and the new arrivals, mostly either British or French, helped establish the area as a centre for the North American fur trade and trading opportunities ballooned with the arrival of the Canadian National Railway in Alberta in 1883. Within ten years, Alberta's non-native population swelled from about 1,000 to almost 17,500. Alberta was officially declared a province of Canada on 1 September 1905, named after Princess Louise Caroline Alberta (1848-1939), the fourth daughter of Queen Victoria and wife of the Marquess of Lorne, former Governor General of Canada. Edmonton was named its capital city.<br /><br />The early twentieth century was a period of boom and bust for Alberta as its fortunes followed the seismic economic shifts of the times. After World War II, the region was transformed forever with a major crude oil discovery Leduc, near Edmonton. The oil industry now became the main source of the province's economic prosperity and fuelled the region's urbanisation, as Edmonton and Calgary grew into centres of business and finance.<br /><br />Alberta has hosted a number of international sporting events over the years, including the 2005 Grand Prix in Edmonton and the 1988 Winter Olympics in Calgary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hulking great mountains, sprawling ice fields and emerald lakes are Alberta&rsquo;s star attractions, but equally thrilling are its dinosaur-strewn Badlands and cowboy heritage.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;d swear they&rsquo;ve added a drop of dye to the lakes in the Rocky Mountains. Could they really be such a startling colour? Yes they could, and you need to supercharge your camera battery if you&rsquo;re going to capture every snap-worthy scene that comes your way.</p>
<p>Whether you&rsquo;re spotting grizzlies and elk alongside the Icefields Parkway, soaking in Banff&rsquo;s hot springs, hiking around Maligne Lake or skiing fresh powder at Lake Louise, you&rsquo;d have to be a Martian not to be bowled over.</p>
<p>This pristine nature sits uneasily next to the controversial oil sands of Alberta&rsquo;s north, whose modern-day gold rush has fuelled the province&rsquo;s booming economy. This wealth is evident in cities like Calgary and Edmonton, home to shiny new skyscrapers, flashy restaurants and ever-expanding suburbs.</p>
<p>While much of Alberta beyond the Rockies seems to be an endless vista of prairies topped with a generous sprinkling of lakes, the Badlands pop out like a Christmas cracker surprise. Stripy hills and sandstone hoodoos like giant mushroom stalks conceal many dinosaur bones &ndash; in its day this must have been the Cretaceous equivalent of Tokyo or Delhi.</p>
<p>Get your own bones rocking at Edmonton&rsquo;s summer fiesta, K Days, a 10-day jamboree featuring whirring fairground rides and big-name bands. Or join the cowboy extravaganza that is the Calgary Stampede, when chuckwagon races, bull riding and dazzling stage shows make you <em>yee-haw</em> till you&rsquo;re hoarse.</p><p>Hulking great mountains, sprawling ice fields and emerald lakes are Alberta&rsquo;s star attractions, but equally thrilling are its dinosaur-strewn Badlands and cowboy heritage.&nbsp;You&rsquo;d swear they&rsquo;ve added a drop of dye to the lakes in the Rocky Mountains. Could they really be such a startling colour? Yes they could, and you need to supercharge your camera battery if you&rsquo;re going to capture every snap-worthy scene that comes your way.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
