<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Manitoba" ColCode="man" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mb" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Manitoba]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A winter visit to Manitoba will give you a true Arctic winter experience complete with doses of icy winds, driving snow storms and cool, calm starry nights (not to mention periodic displays of the northern lights). July or August is the ideal time to visit for warm, sunny days and pleasantly cool nights. <br />
<br />
The scenery and tourist opportunities are at their best in the summer months. This is also the best time for walking, canoeing, fishing or even hunting in the vast tracts of Manitoba wilderness. Festival season is in full swing through the summer with almost endless quirky and more mainstream events, from the Boissevain Turtle Derby, the Morris Stampede and the Morden Corn and Apple festival to the Winnipeg Fringe and Folk festivals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Light- to medium-weight clothing during warmer months, heavy-weight clothing in winter. Waterproofing is advisable throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Canadian flag-carrying airline <em>Air Canada (AC) </em>(<a href="http://www.aircanada.com/" target="_blank">www.aircanada.com</a>)<em> </em>runs inter-provincial and international flights to the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a>. Other airlines also provide such a service to Manitoba.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Winnipeg James Armstrong Richardson International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.waa.ca<p>The airport  is 10km (6 miles) northwest of the city centre (journey time - 20 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only major coastal port is Churchill (<a href="http://www.portofchurchill.ca/" target="_blank">www.portofchurchill.ca</a>) on Hudson Bay, which operates from mid-July to October.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Winnipeg is the most central hub of <em>VIA Rail</em> (tel: +1 888 842 7245; <a href="http://www.viarail.ca/" target="_blank">www.viarail.ca</a>) in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a>. <em>The Canadian</em> takes four days to connect <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vancouver/vancouver-international-airport">Vancouver</a> in the west to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a> in the east, passing through Winnipeg several times a week in each direction. <em>The Hudson Bay</em> service runs northwards within Manitoba from Winnipeg to The Pas (the interchange station for services to Pukatawagan), Thompson and Churchill.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Canoeing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Seal River in the north is one of the most challenging canoe routes in Canada. Whiteshell Provincial Park, a couple of hours from Winnipeg, offers a variety of routes from an easy afternoon paddle to a multi-week wilderness adventure. The Mantario trail is a four-day paddle through a beautiful system of lakes straddling the Manitoba-Ontario border.</p>]]><p><b>Fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Several of the northern lakes are only accessible by air, and remote fly-in lodges are the answer to an angler's wilderness dream. Fish for trout, northern pike, walleye, channel catfish and Arctic grayling.</p>]]><p><b>Folklorama</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Canada's primary cultural celebration, Folklorama (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.folklorama.ca/">www.folklorama.ca</a>) takes place in Winnipeg each late July to mid-August. Go and be entertained and educated by a rich and diverse spread of food, music, dance and history from around the world - in particular, Canada's ethnic communities.</p>]]><p><b>Icelandic Festival of Manitoba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Icelandic Festival of Manitoba, in Gimli, is the largest Icelandic gathering outside Iceland itself; the province has strong historical connections to the country. It is a surreal experience eating Icelandic food and watching people wearing Icelandic garb in typical Canadian land.</p>]]><p><b>Lake Winnipeg</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On the eastern edge of the Interlake Region, Lake Winnipeg has good sandy beaches and boats for hire. The western shore was once New Iceland, a self-governing area settled by thousands of Icelanders fleeing volcanic eruptions in their homeland.</p>]]><p><b>Manitoba's national parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The province's national parks allow you to get close to some stunning scenery. The vast recreational area of Riding Mountain National Park is prime black bear-spotting country. Wildlife viewing, biking, backpacking and horse riding are all available.</p>]]><p><b>Mennonite culture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get a close-up view of early Mennonite life in the German-speaking Mennonite town of Steinbach.</p>]]><p><b>Northern Lights</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Manitoba's wide open skies and cool, calm starry night are perfect for viewing the <em>Aurora Borealis</em> (Northern Lights) in winter. Churchill is a good spot in which to do so.</p>]]><p><b>River Souris suspension bridge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk across the River Souris on Canada's longest free suspension foot bridge. It is over 100 years old and is a massive 177m (582ft) long.</p>]]><p><b>Wapusk National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A remote area with a severe sub-Arctic climate, Wapusk National Park is home to one of the world's largest known polar bear den sites, in addition to hundreds of thousands of waterfowl and shorebirds.</p>]]><p><b>Watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The province's two huge lakes, Lake Winnipeg and Lake Manitoba, are very popular for watersports. The best-known spot is Grand Beach on Lake Winnipeg. Backed by high, grass-topped sand dunes, it's a favourite swimming spot among locals, owing to its shallow water and easy access. Sailboarding, windsurfing and sailing are on offer.</p>]]><p><b>Western Region</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You can see moose and wood bison in the Western region's densely wooded parklands. The Spirit Sands, a 5-sq-km (1.9-sq-mile) tract of sand dunes towering over 30m (100ft), are also well worth seeing. Minedosa is the region's flourishing tourist centre with shopping areas, a beach, restaurants and nature trails.</p>]]><p><b>Whales</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Beluga whales congregate at the mouth of the Churchill River by the thousand in summer. Churchill, a sub-Arctic seaport in the far northeast, is best reached by air across the vast flatlands running into Hudson Bay. It is known for its birdwatching and as a centre for polar-bear-watching tours in autumn.</p>]]><p><b>Whiteshell Provincial Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Soak up the flat, moss-wrapped terrain of Whiteshell Provincial Park, with its gorgeous lakes and forests.</p>]]><p><b>Winnie the Pooh</b></p><![CDATA[<p>AA Milne's hugely popular children's character <em>Winnie the Pooh</em> was named after Winnipeg. A statue commemorates the bear in Assiniboine Park and the only known oil painting of Winnie hangs in the Pavilion Gallery.</p>]]><p><b>Winnipeg</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Canada's most culturally and racially diverse cities, Winnipeg is Manitoba's capital. Visit the Legislative Building with Manitoba's symbol, the Golden Boy, balancing on its dome; Manitoba Museum; St Boniface Cathedral Basilica; and Forks National Historic Site, a large park with river walks, historic port, market, theatrical tours, restaurants and concerts.</p>]]><p><b>Winnipeg paddle steamer</b></p><![CDATA[<p>While in Winnipeg, catch a paddle steamer through the city on the Red and Assiniboine rivers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Winnipeg has a vibrant dining scene with a huge choice of global cuisines thanks to the city's diverse cultures. You might dine on Manitoba beef in an upscale eatery, chomp into bison burgers in a local diner or munch pierogies and cabbage rolls in a corner café.<br/><br/>Chefs produce creative dishes using Prairie-grown produce such as wild berries and wild rice. Numerous festivals showcase the region's food and culture, including Folklorama and the Icelandic Festival of Manitoba.<br/><br/>Rural Manitoba also offers a wide choice of restaurants, from high-end bistros to roadside grills and bakeries selling organic treats.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>• Traditional First Nations foods, such as bison, game, fish, wild fruit and grain.<br/>• Bannock: flat bread cooked over an open fire, first brought by fur traders.<br/>• Smoked fish and meats – try some delicious smoked Lake Winnipeg goldeye, or another favourite, pan-fried pickerel (a small pike).<br/>• Culinary imports include sushi, Ukrainian<em>borscht</em>or a delectable<em>vinarterta</em>dessert from Iceland, consisting of thin cake layers sandwiched together with a cardamom-scented prune filling.<br/>• French-Canadian dishes, such as pea soup,<em>tourtière</em>and sugar pie.<br/>• Pierogies: eastern European dumplings stuffed with fillings such as potato and cheddar or bison and prosciutto.<br/>• Schmoo torte: cake layered with whipped cream, nuts and caramel.<br/>• Apple jacks: an apple-filled pastry sold at Gunn's Bakery in Winnipeg.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Off-licence alcohol is generally available only from government-owned and privately run liquor stores, although some hotels sell beer to take off the premises.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It is customary to tip waiters 15 to 20% of the bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Winnipeg's nightlife is vibrant. Many cinemas, theatres, clubs, restaurants and bars also provide entertainment. Winnipeg is home to a mixture of performing arts: the Royal Winnipeg Ballet, the Winnipeg Symphony Orchestra, Manitoba Opera and several theatre, dance and music companies. The city also offers dining and moonlit dancing cruises aboard riverboats on its scenic Red and Assiniboine rivers. The main stages at Club Regent and McPhillips Street Station casinos also feature entertainment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several nationally known department stores in Winnipeg, with branches throughout Manitoba. Winnipeg also has a number of shopping districts such as Academy Road, Corydon Avenue and The Exchange District<em><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a>. The Forks Market</em> sells many fresh and speciality foods and has over 50 shops all housed in an old horse stable.<br><br>There are also shopping malls: Garden City<em>,</em> 20 minutes drive from the centre, Grant Park Shopping Centre and Polo Park Shopping Centre with 200 shops, a cinema and a bowling alley.<br><br>North of The Pas is a Native American handicraft shop where visitors can watch Native American women making moccasins, <em>mukluks</em>, jackets and jewellery. At the Rock Shop in Souris, you can buy costume jewellery made from rock from a local quarry, and you can obtain a permit to collect your own rock.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0930-2130, Sat 0930-1800 and Sun 1200-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Manitoba has a wide selection of accommodation, ranging from first-class hotels in Winnipeg to guest houses and farm holiday camps. Farm holidays are controlled by their own association, ensuring high standards. Bed & breakfast accommodation is available at a reasonable price. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> The national <em>Canada Select</em> programme operates in Manitoba, rating accommodation from<strong> </strong>1 to<strong> </strong>5 stars on a voluntary basis.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Manitoba has a wide selection of accommodation, ranging from first-class hotels in Winnipeg to guest houses and farm holiday camps. Farm holidays are controlled by their own association, ensuring high standards. Bed & breakfast accommodation is available at a reasonable price. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> The national <em>Canada Select</em> programme operates in Manitoba, rating accommodation from<strong> </strong>1 to<strong> </strong>5 stars on a voluntary basis.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Manitoba has a wide selection of accommodation, ranging from first-class hotels in Winnipeg to guest houses and farm holiday camps. Farm holidays are controlled by their own association, ensuring high standards. Bed & breakfast accommodation is available at a reasonable price. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> The national <em>Canada Select</em> programme operates in Manitoba, rating accommodation from<strong> </strong>1 to<strong> </strong>5 stars on a voluntary basis.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[53.760861]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-98.813876]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>647,797 sq km (250,116 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,278,365 (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Winnipeg.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Manitoba is bordered by the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> states of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/north-dakota">North Dakota</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/minnesota">Minnesota</a> to the south, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/saskatchewan">Saskatchewan</a> to the west, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/ontario">Ontario</a> to the east, and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/northwest-territories">Northwest Territories</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/nunavut">Nunavut</a> to the north. It is the easternmost of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a>'s three Prairie Provinces, and also known as Heartland Canada as well as the 'Land of 100,000 Lakes'. The landscape is diverse, ranging from rolling farmland to sandy beaches on the shores of Lake Winnipeg, and from the desert landscape in a small corner of the south to northern parkland covered by lakes, forests and sub-Arctic tundra.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Overlooked by many, Manitoba could be Canada&rsquo;s best-kept secret, spanning Arctic tundra and sprawling prairies, a classy capital and vast swathes of wildlife-packed wilderness.</p>
<p>At one extreme, there&rsquo;s the sub-Arctic coastline at Churchill on Hudson Bay where you can spy frolicking beluga whales in summer or roaming polar bears in the autumn. At the other, there&rsquo;s cosmopolitan Winnipeg, crammed with thrilling museums and fascinating historic districts.</p>
<p>In between, there&rsquo;s not much at all other than a phenomenal landscape of sweeping farmland, flowering prairies and some 100,000 lakes, which support a range of wildlife including elk, black bears, wolves, muskox, moose and various migratory birds.</p>
<p>No wonder outdoor adventurers are in heaven, paddling the historic Hayes River, or camping at spots like Paint Lake Provincial Park for a hike to Kwasitchewan Falls.</p>
<p>If all that open space overwhelms you, head for the city. Winnipeg is usually either blisteringly hot or bitingly cold, but don&rsquo;t let the weather put you off. The city boasts Canada&rsquo;s oldest public gallery as well as the Canadian Museum of Human Rights, opened in 2014 and the first national museum built for nearly 50 years.</p>
<p>For a city plonk in the middle of the prairies, Winnipeg boasts a seriously impressive cultural line-up, including a professional ballet, symphony orchestra, theatre and opera. And who&rsquo;d have thought it? Every single Canadian coin in your pocket was minted in Winnipeg.</p>
<p>Manitoba is a huge province with comparably few residents, but the people that do live there are renowned for their friendly, hospitable natures and embrace of diversity. Winnipeg is the centre of the cultural festival Folklarama, a celebration of Canada's ethnic communities. Manitobans themselves are a vibrant international mix, and include Icelandic, Japanese and Italian.</p><p>Overlooked by many, Manitoba could be Canada&rsquo;s best-kept secret, spanning Arctic tundra and sprawling prairies, a classy capital city and vast swathes of wildlife-packed wilderness. At one extreme, there&rsquo;s the sub-Arctic coastline at Churchill on Hudson Bay where you can spy frolicking beluga whales in summer or roaming polar bears in the autumn. At the other, there&rsquo;s cosmopolitan Winnipeg, crammed with thrilling museums and fascinating historic districts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
