<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Ontario" ColCode="ont" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="on" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Ontario]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Summers can be very warm, while spring and autumn are cooler. Winters are cold with occasional snowfall.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Light- to medium-weight clothing during warmer months, heavyweights in winter. Waterproofing is advisable throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Canadian flag-carrying airline <strong>Air Canada</strong> (<em>AC</em>)&nbsp;(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aircanada.com/">www.aircanada.com</a>; +1 514 393 3333) operate inter-provincial and international flights from Ontario. Many other international airlines offer direct services into <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a>. Charter airlines often offer an economical alternative to the scheduled airlines. Local air services are run by a number of operators.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Toronto Pearson International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.torontopearson.com<p>Toronto Pearson International Airport is located 27km (17 miles) northwest of Toronto city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 416 247 7678</p>]]><b>Ottawa International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.yow.ca<p>Ottawa International Airport is located 10km (6 miles) south of central Ottawa.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 613 248 2125</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only port on James Bay with rail links to the south is Moosonee, which is also the base for a limited local air service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>VIA Rail<em> </em>(tel: +1 888 842 7245; <a href="http://www.viarail.ca" target="_blank">www.viarail.ca</a>) connects Toronto to western <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a>. Several corridor services connect Toronto, Windsor and Ottawa with Montr&eacute;al and Qu&eacute;bec City in Qu&eacute;bec. Links to the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> are with Amtrak<em> </em>(tel: +1 215 856 7952; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>) and VIA Rail. Services run from Toronto to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a> via Niagara Falls. VIA Rail also serves most of the major cities of the province, mainly in the southern region, which is home to most of the population. <br />
<br />
Ontario Northland<em> </em>(tel: +1 705 472 4500; <a href="http://www.ontarionorthland.ca" target="_blank">www.ontarionorthland.ca</a>) runs rail services from Toronto to Timmins, Cochrane, Kapuskasing, Hearst and Moosonee, with stops along the way.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Niagara Falls</p><![CDATA[<p>A must-see; Niagara Falls are a legacy of the Ice Age, gushing out half a million gallons of water every second. The falls are made up of two separate parts, Horseshoe Falls on the Canadian side and American Falls  on the USA side. Although not the highest waterfall in the world they move a staggering 168,000 cubic metres (219,600 cubic yards) of water per minute over a drop of 51m (167ft), making them one of the natural wonders of the world. The city of Niagara Falls itself is stuffed with wax museums and theme restaurants, but just to the north lies the storybook village of Niagara-on-the-Lake. Southwest of the falls, the north shore of Lake Erie is dotted with small resorts and good beaches; Port Stanley is particularly popular.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Behold the great butterfly migration</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Beautiful and unique (to Ontario) monarch butterflies stop off at Point Pelee on Lake Erie in September during their annual migration to the mountains of central Mexico. These colourful insects cover the trees, providing an amazing spectacle.</p>]]><p><b>Canada's capital city</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Canada's capital city, you can admire the imposing gothic-style Parliament Buildings, Peace Tower, Confederation Square (site of the National War Memorial), and the Rideau Canal, a UNESCO World Heritage Site. Among the city's many museums and galleries are the National Gallery of Canada, the Canada Science and Technology Museum and the Canadian Museum of Nature. Just across the Ontario River in Quebec, the Canadian Museum of History is also worth a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Canoeing across Ontario </b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ontario is particularly well known for canoeing, and has more canoe routes than any other region in the world - more than 5,400km (3,355 miles) of routes in northwestern Ontario alone. Good locations include Killarney and Algonquin Provincial Parks in southern Ontario, the latter being within three hours' drive of Toronto.</p>]]><p><b>Climb CN Tower</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Thrill seekers can hurtle up to the top of the CN Tower in Toronto (<a href="http://www.cntower.ca/" target="_blank">www.cntower.ca</a>): Canada's national tower was until recently the world's tallest freestanding structure. From the public observation deck in its SkyPod, 447m (1,465ft) above the ground, you can see Niagara Falls on a clear day.</p>]]><p><b>Flip some pancakes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Sandy Flat Sugar Bush and Pancake House in Warkworth hosts the annual Maple Syrup Festival in March. Amongst the many demonstrations, races and contests is also the chance to sample lots of this sweet and sticky fluid liberally poured onto anything from pancakes to sausages. The maple trees and their sap are unique to eastern North America and Ontario is very proud of its culinary links to the syrup.</p>]]><p><b>Get closer to nature in Algonquin Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nature lovers are drawn to the protected wilderness of Algonquin Park, Ontario's oldest provincial park; 7,600 sq km (2,934 sq miles) of forest and lakeland provide the perfect environment for outdoor recreation. For campers and day visitors, Highway 60 is the centre of the park, offering campgrounds, walking trails, conducted hikes and access to public wolf-howling sessions. In winter, cross country skiing trails are popular. Visitors can also soak up the history of the park in the Logging Museum, or in the Algonquin Gallery, which focuses on the Canadian artist Tom Thomson's (1877-1917) famous group of painters, the Group of Seven.</p>]]><p><b>Get your skis on</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Midland commands a spectacular view of the Muskoka-Georgian Bay lake district and is a popular resort, mainly because of the various minor ski resorts located around Georgian Bay.</p>]]><p><b>Hiking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From hiking trails on the Bruce Peninsula, the views are spectacular.</p>]]><p><b>National Gallery of Canada</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The National Gallery of Canada was founded in 1880 by the Governor General, the Marquess of Lorne and since then has grown to become an internationally-renowned art museum. The permanent collections reflect Canada's diverse history, and includes works by European masters such as Monet, Turner and Di Cosimo, as well as avant-garde Canadian paintings from the 1960s and religious sculptures from Qu&eacute;bec. The museum also contains a large collection of Inuit art, including prints, drawings and whale bone sculptures, many of which portray the cultural and social issues that have affected Canada's indigenous population since WWII.</p>]]><p><b>Niagara Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A must-see; Niagara Falls are a legacy of the Ice Age, gushing out half a million gallons of water every second. The falls are made up of two separate parts, Horseshoe Falls on the Canadian side and American Falls  on the USA side. Although not the highest waterfall in the world they move a staggering 168,000 cubic metres (219,600 cubic yards) of water per minute over a drop of 51m (167ft), making them one of the natural wonders of the world. The city of Niagara Falls itself is stuffed with wax museums and theme restaurants, but just to the north lies the storybook village of Niagara-on-the-Lake. Southwest of the falls, the north shore of Lake Erie is dotted with small resorts and good beaches; Port Stanley is particularly popular.</p>]]><p><b>See artwork in the rocks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lake Superior Provincial Park has many beautiful ravines, lakes and waterfalls. In particular, its Agawa Rock Pictographs are highly famed. These are one of the largest collections of Indian rock art in Ontario. The pictographs remain one of Superior's most sacred spots.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Toronto</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Canada's largest city is also the provincial capital. The CN Tower has glass-fronted elevators rising to indoor observation decks that afford a 160km (100-mile) panoramic view on a clear day. Yorkville, the hip part of town in the 1960s, now caters to the tastes of the city's upwardly mobile, but is a good spot to go window shopping or enjoy a cup of coffee. Queen Street West attracts a younger, more style-conscious crowd. In the eastern suburbs, the spectacular Ontario Science Centre and the Toronto Zoo are both worth seeing.</p>]]><p><b>Watch Shakespeare in the summer</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Stratford Shakespeare Festival focuses mainly (but not exclusively) on the Bard's plays, while the Shaw Festival in Niagara-on-the-Lake highlights the works of George Bernard Shaw and his contemporaries, and the Blyth Festival presents Canadian plays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Ontario has an eclectic food and drink scene. There's a wide range of global cuisines and a strong focus on farm-to-table dining. Toronto's diverse neighbourhoods and cultures mean you can taste everything from Italian and Greek to Indian and Chinese. Ottawa's international population helps feed a dynamic selection of laid-back restaurants featuring high-end dishes.<br/><br/>Beyond the major cities, you can explore apple orchards and vineyards, load up on fresh produce at farmers' markets, or follow local food trails, such as Stratford's Bacon and Ale Trail (<a href="http://www.visitstratford.ca/stratford-bacon-and-ale-trail" target="_blank">www.visitstratford.ca/stratford-bacon-and-ale-trail</a>). Popular Ontario food and drink festivals include the TO Food Fest in Toronto (July) and the Niagara Wine Festival (September).</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Maple syrup can accompany everything, from waffles and toast to pancakes and even baked beans!<br />
&bull; Ontario&rsquo;s huge range of artisanal cheeses include Guernsey milk cheeses, cheddar and Dutch Gouda cheese.<br />
&bull; Try one of the dazzling varieties of fish from the countless lakes and rivers.<br />
&bull; BeaverTails (fried pastries topped with sweet treats) originated in Ottawa and are now sold in stores across the country.<br />
&bull; Butter tarts: small pastries filled with baked butter, sugar, syrup and egg.<br />
&bull; Wild blueberries grow in northern Ontario; peak picking time is July and August.<br />
&bull; Pickerel is a small pike commonly found in northern Ontario&rsquo;s lakes.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Beer, wine and spirits are sold in government-run liquor stores. An increasing number of supermarkets also sell beer, cider and wine.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It's customary to tip 15 to 20% at bars and restaurants in Ontario.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>19</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ontario's two main cities, Toronto and Ottawa, have establishments offering all forms of entertainment, from quiet clubs featuring a lone pianist, through Latin American combos to dance and rock bands and big-name international entertainers. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a> is recognised as the third most important theatre centre after London and New York, and cabaret/dinner theatres are also especially popular in Toronto. Toronto is also known as a good jazz and blues town. Both Toronto and Ottawa host jazz festivals in the summer. Theatres with classical entertainment are also found in Ottawa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Toronto offers everything from antiques to luxury lingerie, if you have the money and time to spend. There are large suburban shopping centres (including Vaughan Mills, one of the province's newest mega-malls, with almost 200 shops). The Eaton Centre, a glass-domed galleria in the heart of the city, is linked to 4.8km (3 miles) of interconnecting underground shopping malls with hundreds of retail outlets. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a>'s villages are full of colourful streets of renovated Victoriana, with garment shops, art galleries, antique stores and open-air cafes in summer. Kensington Market and its surrounding neighbourhood is a popular jumble of food stalls, vintage clothing shops, décor stores and quirky restaurants.<br /><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><br /><br />Ottawa also has a wide choice of shops and handicraft centres. The Byward Market is a popular area of craft shops, farmers' market stalls and cafes. The Glebe, Wellington Village and Westboro are charming neighbourhoods that are home to a selection of independent retailers selling everything from art glass to yoga clothing.</p><p>Shops are open daily 1000-1800 in most parts of Ontario (Thurs-Fri until 2100, Sun from 1200). Many city and suburban shops are open until 2100 Mon-Fri.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Both Ottawa and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a> have international-standard hotels. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Accommodation is graded on an entirely voluntary basis through the Canada Select programme (<a href="http://www.canadaselect.com" target="_blank">www.canadaselect.com</a>)  programme, which grades hotels in, which grades hotels in Ontario  according to a 5-star system, ranging from 5-star (deluxe) to 1-star  (basic).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For help with bed &amp; breakfast accommodation, contact the Federation of Ontario Bed &amp; Breakfast Accommodation (<a href="http://www.fobba.com" target="_blank">www.fobba.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Both Ottawa and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a> have international-standard hotels. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Accommodation is graded on an entirely voluntary basis through the Canada Select programme (<a href="http://www.canadaselect.com" target="_blank">www.canadaselect.com</a>)  programme, which grades hotels in, which grades hotels in Ontario  according to a 5-star system, ranging from 5-star (deluxe) to 1-star  (basic).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Both Ottawa and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a> have international-standard hotels. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Accommodation is graded on an entirely voluntary basis through the Canada Select programme (<a href="http://www.canadaselect.com" target="_blank">www.canadaselect.com</a>)  programme, which grades hotels in, which grades hotels in Ontario  according to a 5-star system, ranging from 5-star (deluxe) to 1-star  (basic).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[51.253775]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-85.323214]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,076,395 sq km (415,598 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>13.5 million (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>14.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Toronto.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ontario is an eastern-central province bordered by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/manitoba">Manitoba</a> and Qu&eacute;bec, with a northern coastline on James Bay and Hudson Bay; it also shares the shores of the Great Lakes with the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>. The two most populated areas, around <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a> and Ottawa, are in the southern spur, and the north remains a landscape of forests and lakes. The province contains the Niagara Falls, one of the most spectacular sights in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Energetic cities, sprawling forests and more than half a million lakes are just some of the reasons why Ontario pulls in the crowds.</p>
<p>Most start their Ontario adventure in buzzing Toronto, a jewel in the province&rsquo;s crown, whose multicultural inhabitants lend the city a genuinely cosmopolitan edge. You can cheer on the Maple Leafs in their quest for the Stanley Cup, glug the latest craft brew in historic pubs and stuff your face with mini doughnuts from a foodtruck. And what&rsquo;s the point looking out the windows of the CN Tower when you can skirt its roof on the vertigo-inducing EdgeWalk?</p>
<p>In Canada&rsquo;s capital city, Ottawa, knowing whether to say &ldquo;bonjour&rdquo; or &ldquo;hello&rdquo; is always a quandary, so just say both. Skate the world&rsquo;s largest ice rink, the Rideau Canal, or gen up on all things Canadian in the city&rsquo;s fabulous museums.</p>
<p>You don&rsquo;t have to travel far to find nature. Equidistant from both cities, Algonquin Provincial Park is a quintessentially Canadian landscape of maple-blanketed hills splashed with thousands of lakes. It dishes up quintessentially Canadian experiences, too: wilderness hiking, 2,100km (1,300 miles) of canoeing routes, and the chance to land the biggest trout of your life. Also a short drive from Toronto are the booming Niagara Falls, one of the Seven Natural Wonders of the world.</p>
<p>And then there are the lakes. Ontario borders four of the five Great Lakes, most notably Lake Huron, home to Fathom Five National Marine Park and its extraordinary shipwrecks. Elsewhere there are lakes for fishing, lakes for canoeing, lakes for swimming and lakes for diving. Come on in, the water&rsquo;s lovely.</p><p>Energetic cities, sprawling forests and more than half a million lakes are just some of the reasons why Ontario pulls in the crowds. City slickers make a beeline for buzzing Toronto, a jewel in the province&rsquo;s crown, whose multicultural inhabitants lend the city a genuinely cosmopolitan edge.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
