<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Canada" ColCode="can" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ca" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Canada]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re planning on skiing or enjoying winter sports, the best time to visit Canada is between December and April, though some resorts open as early as November and extend their seasons as late as June (or even July on Whistler&rsquo;s glacier). If you want to enjoy the great outdoors without the snow, travel between May and September. Be aware however, that if there&rsquo;s been heavy snowfall during the winter, some high-altitude hiking trails may be closed well into July. May, June and September are typically cheaper than July and August, but you&rsquo;ll get the best of the weather in the latter two months.</p>
<p>Summer thunderstorms are common throughout Canada. Occasionally, these may become severe. Tornados also occur throughout Canada, with May to September being prime months. The peak season is June and early July in southern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/ontario">Ontario</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/alberta">Alberta</a>, southeastern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/quebec">Quebec</a>, and a band stretching from southern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/saskatchewan">Saskatchewan</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/manitoba">Manitoba</a>, through to Thunder Bay. The interior of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/british-columbia">British Columbia</a> and western <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/new-brunswick">New Brunswick</a> are also tornado zones. Earth tremors occur in the western mountains. Forest fires can occur at any time, regardless of the season, particularly in the grasslands and forests of western Canada.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Note:</strong> These general guidelines apply mainly to the settled areas of southern Canada. Travellers heading to northern areas, such as the Yukon, the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/northwest-territories">Northwest Territories</a>, Nunavut and Labrador, should bring warm clothing for all but the summer months (and even in summer, at least a lightweight jacket is advisable). See the individual provinces and territories sections for more details.</p>
<p><strong>Dec - Feb:</strong> Winter temperatures. Winter  clothing is necessary (eg overcoat, hat, boots and gloves). Heavy  snowfall in most provinces, with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vancouver">Vancouver</a> being the main exception in  that it usually rains instead.<br />
<strong>Mar - May:</strong> Moderate temperatures. Medium weight clothing with a waterproof topcoat or umbrella is the recommendation.<br />
<strong>Jun - Sep:</strong> Warm. Lightweight summer clothing with some medium weight clothing for cool evenings.&nbsp;<br />
<strong>Oct - Nov:</strong> Cool, with the first frost in the air.&nbsp;Medium- to heavyweight clothing is recommended, particularly with the first signs of snow in November.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Canada (<a href="http://www.aircanada.com" target="_blank">www.aircanada.com</a>) and WestJet (<a href="http://www.westjet.com" target="_blank">www.westjet.com</a>) serve destinations throughout Canada. Other carriers include Yukon-based Air North (<a href="http://www.flyairnorth.com" target="_blank">www.flyairnorth.com</a>) and a host of small outfits serving remote communities and wilderness areas.</p>
<p>Canada is so vast, domestic flights can save you many hours and even days versus driving or taking the train and are sometimes essential if visiting isolated lodges or settlements. Flights are generally cheaper if booked in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Canada has many thousands of miles of navigable rivers and canals, a vast number of lakes and an extensive coastline. The whole country is well served by all manner of boats and ships, particularly the east and west coasts, where ferries are fast, frequent and good value. The St Lawrence Seaway provides passage from the Atlantic Ocean to the Great Lakes.</p>
<p>One of the largest ferry operators is BC Ferries (tel: +1 888 223 3779; <a href="http://www.bcferries.com" target="_blank">www.bcferries.com</a>). It runs a number of services linking British Columbia's mainland with its coastal islands, as well as a route to Haida Gwaii (the Queen Charlotte Islands) and another through the Inside Passage.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>VIA Rail Canada (tel: +1 888 842 7245;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.viarail.ca"> www.viarail.ca</a>) operates extensive services across Canada.</p>
<p>VIA Rail operates a western transcontinental service (the Canadian) between Toronto (Ontario) and Vancouver (British Columbia), running three times weekly east and west. Passengers are drawn to this route by the spectacular scenery of the many mountain ranges passed en route, including the Rockies. The journey takes four days.</p>
<p>Rapid intercity services are available between Quebec City, Montreal, Toronto, Windsor and Ottawa. VIA Rail also operates an overnight eastern transcontinental service (the Ocean) between Montreal (Quebec) and Halifax (Nova Scotia).</p>
<p>The Rocky Mountaineer (tel: +1 877 460 3200; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.rockymountaineer.com">www.rockymountaineer.com</a>) runs from mid-April to mid-October and offers the opportunity to travel from Vancouver to Jasper or Banff (and vice versa) during daylight hours.</p>
<p>For visitors seeking a route into the Canadian wilderness, the Polar Bear Express (tel: +1 800 461 8558; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.polarbearexpress.ca">www.polarbearexpress.ca</a>) runs between Cochrane and Moosonee (with connections to Toronto).</p>
<p>Other notable tourist routes include Ontario's Agawa Canyon Tour Train (tel: +1 800 242 9287; <a href="http://www.agawatrain.com" target="_blank">www.agawatrain.com</a>) and the White Pass &amp; Yukon Route Railroad (tel: +1 800 343 7373;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.wpyr.com" target="_blank">www.wpyr.com</a>) between Skagway, Alaska and Carcross, Yukon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Canrailpass - System: allows seven or 10 one-way trips or unlimited travel anywhere on the VIA network within a 60-day period.</p>
<p>Canrailpass - Corridor: gives seven or 10 one-way trips or unlimited travel on VIA Rail in Quebec and southern Ontario within a 10-day period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Canadian road network covers huge distances as the country is over 5,500km (3,400 miles) as the crow flies from west to east and 4,600km (2,800 miles) from north to south. The Canadian Automobile Association (CAA) (tel: +1 800 222 4357; <a href="http://www.caa.ca" target="_blank">www.caa.ca</a>) is affiliated with most European organisations, giving full use of facilities to members.</p>r<p>Getting around Canada by road is easy, though drives can be long owing to its size. Road quality is generally excellent, but routes to remote destinations may be unpaved. Winter roads formed of snow and ice serve northern communities in winter. On country roads, you should be mindful of wild animals, such as deer or moose.</p><p>Greyhound (tel: +1 800 661 8747; <a href="http://www.greyhound.ca" target="_blank">www.greyhound.ca</a>) is Canada&rsquo;s main coach line and runs a comprehensive network across Canada. Smaller, regional operators also offer services within individual provinces.</p><p>It&rsquo;s easy to hail a cab on the street or pick up a taxi from your hotel or a designated rank in all Canadian towns and cities.</p><p>Visitors may drive on their national driving licences for at least three months in all provinces.</p><p>Right turns on red lights are legal in Canada except in Montreal. Generally, speed limits are 100-120kph (62-75mph) on motorways (depending on province/territory), 80kph (55mph) on rural highways and 50kph (30mph) in cities. Seat belts are compulsory for all passengers and child car seats must be used by small children.</p>
<p>Radar detection devices are strictly prohibited in many provinces and studded tyres are illegal in southern Ontario. If you&rsquo;re driving in the interior of British Columbia or Quebec between December and March, you must fit your car with winter tyres. Many provinces require drivers to keep headlights on during the day.</p><p>CAA (tel: +1 800 222 4357; www.caa.ca).</p><p>Available in all cities and from airports to full licence holders over 21 years of age, except in Saskatchewan which has a minimum age of 18. For some car hire companies, drivers may need to be at least 25 years old.</p><p>In towns and cities, cycling is usually pleasant given the courtesy (and risk aversion) of drivers. There are many excellent car-free cycle paths making for a fun half-day ride. On highways between towns, cycling can be a bit unnerving with enormous lorries thundering past. Where the country really excels is in the wide network of off-road routes, often in tranquil and challenging forest settings.</p><p>Right turns on red lights are legal in Canada except in Montreal. Generally, speed limits are 100-120kph (62-75mph) on motorways (depending on province/territory), 80kph (55mph) on rural highways and 50kph (30mph) in cities. Seat belts are compulsory for all passengers and child car seats must be used by small children.</p>
<p>Radar detection devices are strictly prohibited in many provinces and studded tyres are illegal in southern Ontario. If you&rsquo;re driving in the interior of British Columbia or Quebec between December and March, you must fit your car with winter tyres. Many provinces require drivers to keep headlights on during the day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Canada&rsquo;s major cities have excellent public transport systems, with a mixture of buses, trams, light rail systems and underground trains. If you&rsquo;re visiting Toronto, Vancouver, Montreal or Ottawa, you can easily get around without a car. Public transport is safe and generally offers good value for money, with transfers usually available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Canada</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">winnipeg</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">32.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">32.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Canada</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">vancouver</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">62.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">75.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Canada</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">toronto</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Canada</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">montreacuteal</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Canada (<a href="http://www.aircanada.com" target="_blank">www.aircanada.com</a>) is the country&rsquo;s flag carrier airline and currently operate routes between Canada and 81 international destinations.</p>
<p>Airlines flying from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> to Canada also include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), Air Transat (<a href="http://www.airtransat.co.uk" target="_blank">www.airtransat.co.uk</a>) and WestJet (<a href="http://www.westjet.com" target="_blank">www.westjet.com</a>). Most major US carriers fly from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>. Fares increase significantly in July and August, as well as during the ski season (December to April) if you&rsquo;re flying to western Canada.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/alberta/calgary-international-airport">Calgary International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vancouver/vancouver-international-airport">Vancouver International Airport </a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/halifax/halifax-stanfield-international-airport">Halifax Stanfield International Airport</a>, Ottawa International Airport , <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/ontario/toronto-pearson-international-airport">Toronto Pearson International Airport </a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/quebec/montreal-pierre-elliott-trudeau-international-airport">Montreal Pierre Elliott Trudeau International Airport </a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>: to&nbsp;Calgary - 9 hours 20 minutes; to Halifax - 7 hours; to&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/montreal">Montreal</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;7 hours 30 minutes; to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;8 hours; to&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vancouver">Vancouver</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;9 hours 35 minutes.</p>
<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>: to Montreal - 1 hour 30 minutes; to Toronto - 1 hour 30 minutes; to Vancouver - 6 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Calgary International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.yyc.com<p>Calgary International Airport is located 17km (10.5 miles) northeast of Calgary.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 403 735 1200</p>]]><b>Halifax Stanfield International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.halifaxstanfield.ca<p>Halifax Stanfield International Airport is situated 35km (22 miles) north of central Halifax.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 902 873 4422</p>]]><b>Montreal-Pierre Elliott Trudeau International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.admtl.com<p>Montréal-Pierre Elliott Trudeau International Airport is located 20km (12 miles) west of Montréal.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 514 633 3333</p>]]><b>Toronto Pearson International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.torontopearson.com<p>Toronto Pearson International Airport is located 27km (17 miles) northwest of Toronto city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 416 247 7678</p>]]><b>Billy Bishop Toronto City Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.torontoport.com]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(416) 203 6942</p>]]><b>Ottawa International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.yow.ca<p>Ottawa International Airport is located 10km (6 miles) south of central Ottawa.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 613 248 2125</p>]]><b>Quebec City Jean Lesage International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeroportdequebec.com<p>Quebec City's airport lies 20km (12 miles) west of Old Quebec and handles primarily domestic flights, although there are a few flights from destinations in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> as well as charters to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> and the Caribbean.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(418) 640 3300</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Canada has many ports served by international shipping lines. Montreal (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.port-montreal.com">www.port-montreal.com</a>) is a popular port for cruise ships.  The port of Vancouver (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.portmetrovancouver.com">www.portmetrovancouver.com</a>), Canada's busiest port, is on the west coast and is a common start point for cruise ships travelling to Alaska. Toronto's port (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.torontoport.com">www.torontoport.com</a>) is on the northwestern shore of Lake Ontario.</p>
<p>Halifax, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/nova-scotia">Nova Scotia</a>&nbsp;(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.portofhalifax.ca">www.portofhalifax.ca</a>), Saint John, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/new-brunswick">New Brunswick</a> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sjport.com">www.sjport.com</a>) and St John's, Newfoundland (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sjpa.com">www.sjpa.com</a>) are the principal ports on the Atlantic coast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Canadian rail system connects to the USA at several points. US rail operator Amtrak (tel: +1 800 872 7245; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amtrak.com">www.amtrak.com</a>) runs the following international routes: New York-Albany-Montreal (the Adirondack), New York-Albany-Buffalo-Toronto (the Maple Leaf) and Eugene-Portland-Seattle-Vancouver (the Amtrak Cascades).</p>
<p>The Rocky Mountaineer train (tel: +1 604 606 7245; <a href="http://www.rockymountaineer.com" target="_blank">www.rockymountaineer.com</a>)  also runs the 'Coastal Passage' tourist route from Seattle to Vancouver.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no international rail passes covering trains into Canada. Amtrak&rsquo;s USA Rail Pass does not include routes north of the US border.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only road access to Canada is through the southern border with the USA or from the west through <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/alaska">Alaska</a>. There are numerous road crossings between the two countries.</p>
<p>Greyhound (tel: +1 800 661 8747; <a href="http://www.greyhound.ca" target="_blank">www.greyhound.ca</a>) runs several coaches between the USA and Canada. Some of the most popular are New York to Montreal, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/detroit">Detroit</a> to Toronto/Hamilton, and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seattle">Seattle</a> to Vancouver. Note there is no coach service at all between the two countries west of southeastern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/ontario">Ontario</a> until you reach Vancouver.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Most public telephones charge 50 cents a call, which can be paid with any combination of five-, 10- and 25-cent coins. Public telephones are becoming harder to find, due to the growing popularity of mobile phones. Many telephone companies offer a reduced long-distance rate Mon-Fri 1800-0800 and Sat 1200 to Mon 0800. For long-distance calls, telephone cards are available. You can find credit card telephones in larger centres. If you're near an internet café, you can use Skype too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good in major urban areas, but spotty in remote locations. Roaming rates can be high, so you should check with your provider before leaving home.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available throughout Canada, as are internet cafes (although the latter are not as common as they are in many other countries). You can often find pay-per-use Wi-Fi hotspots in coffee shops, fast-food outlets and airports; in some cases it's free as long as you buy a drink or something to eat. Free public Wi-Fi is easiest to find in public libraries. Some hotels provide free Wi-Fi too, but others continue to charge exorbitant daily fees.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC) is Canada&rsquo;s national broadcaster. It was set up in the 1930s and broadcasts in both French and English via TV, radio, internet and satellite. The main national daily newspapers are <em>The Globe and Mail</em> and <em>The National Post</em>. French-language dailies are published in Montreal, Ottawa and Quebec City. Regional English-language daily newspapers are also published in individual provinces.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All mail from Canada to outside North America is by air. Stamps are available at post offices and in many hotels, pharmacies and convenience stores, among other locations. Letters sent by regular mail take four to six working days to reach the USA and four to seven working days to reach other countries.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0930-1700, Sat 0900-1200, but times vary according to province and location; city offices will have longer hours. Canada Post (<a href="http://www.canadapost.ca" target="_blank">www.canadapost.ca</a>) has a full list of locations and hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Drive the Cabot Trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the world's most scenic drives, the Cabot Trail loops 300km (186 miles) round Nova Scotia's Cape Breton Island, hugging the coastline and traversing Cape Breton Highlands National Park. Take in pretty fishing villages and picturesque beaches, enjoy spectacular hiking and horse-riding trails, paddle hidden coves and revel in the region's Celtic musical heritage.</p>]]><p><b>Experience the tundra of Baffin Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Canada's largest island is a pristine wilderness of fjords, mountains, glaciers and tundra. Sledge across frozen Frobisher Bay, spot whales, seals and polar bear cubs from the floe edge, gawp at colossal icebergs, encounter caribou, musk-ox and migrating birds, kayak amid jaw-dropping scenery, and discover Inuit traditions.</p>]]><p><b>Gaze down on Toronto</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Canada's largest metropolis curls along the rim of Lake Ontario. Steel your nerves and gaze through glass floors from 342m (1,122ft) up on the CN Tower, explore the vibrant cafés, boutiques and galleries of the Distillery District's beautifully restored Victorian industrial architecture, or grab an ice-cream and some rays on the beach.</p>]]><p><b>Get soaked under Niagara Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Thunderous, mighty and mesmerising: the spectacle of up to 170,000 cubic m (6 million cubic ft) of water roaring down the equivalent of a 13-storey building is truly awesome. Sail to the base of the Canadian Horseshoe Falls aboard the classic Maid of the Mist tour, soar overhead on a helicopter or crank up the adrenaline on a nail-biting jetboat trip through Niagara Gorge.</p>]]><p><b>Have an adventure in Banff National Park </b></p><![CDATA[<p>Picture Canada and you might imagine dramatic, jagged mountains criss-crossed by glacier-fed rivers and peppered with vivid, emerald lakes. Look no further than Banff National Park. Canada's oldest national park sits at the heart of the Canadian Rockies; highlights include stunning cerulean Lake Louise and the striking peaks and shimmering glaciers of the Icefields Parkway.</p>]]><p><b>Kluane National Park and Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A UNESCO World Heritage site since 1979, Kluane National Park in the Yukon is a vast expanse of vertiginous mountains, gigantic glaciers and extraordinary wildlife. At its heart is Canada's highest peak, 5,959m (19,550ft) Mt Logan. Raft, hike or canoe through this exceptionally beautiful backcountry, home to eagles, grizzlies, wolves and moose.</p>]]><p><b>Learn the history of Quebec City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>UNESCO-listed Old Quebec is North America's only remaining walled city, its charming 17th- and 18th-century houses a world away from the glitzy skyscrapers elsewhere. Gaze up at the impressive Château Frontenac, explore the star-shaped citadel, or track down local arts and crafts and pause at tantalising bistros in the Petit-Champlain district.</p>]]><p><b>Roam the Prairie provinces</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Comprising Alberta, Saskatchewan and Manitoba, the Prairies' expansive grasslands in the south give way to parkland and coniferous forests further north. Swim, sail or waterski in one of Saskatchewan's 100,000 lakes, spy polar bears and beluga whales in Churchill, Manitoba or hunt for fossils in Alberta's Dinosaur Provincial Park.</p>]]><p><b>Say bonjour to Montreal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Romantic yet cutting edge, North American with a distinctly French flair, the nation's second biggest city dazzles and enchants. Wander the elegant, cobbled streets of Old Montreal, potter among the quirky stores, funky cafés and colourful houses of bohemian neighbourhood Le Plateau, or soak up some serious tunes during the world's largest jazz festival in June and July.</p>]]><p><b>See whales off the Bay of Fundy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This 270km-long (170 miles) bay stretches between the Atlantic provinces of New Brunswick and Nova Scotia and possesses the world's highest tidal range – sometimes 15m (49ft) or more. Witness the inter-tidal zone's incredible changes, go whale watching, then take an exhilarating rafting trip on the Shubenacadie River tidal bore or a thrilling jetboat ride on Saint John's Reversing Falls.</p>]]><p><b>Spot an iceberg off the Twillingate Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Newfoundland's Twillingate Islands are considered the best place in the world to see icebergs. Hop aboard an ocean cruise between May and August to glimpse hunks of ice the size of a five-storey house as well as humpback whales, dolphins and an astonishing array of seabirds.</p>]]><p><b>Sunbath on Prince Edward Island's glorious beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>PEI's shoreline encompasses over 800km (500 miles) of gloriously sandy beaches with enormous mobile dunes, distinctive red sandstone cliffs and surprisingly warm water for its latitude. Listen out for the 'singing sands' at Basin Head, dig for clams at Teahill or stargaze at Cavendish in PEI National Park.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Vancouver</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nestled beneath the towering Coast Mountains on the shores of the Pacific Ocean, Canada's gorgeous west coast city exudes an easygoing, cosmopolitan vibe. Ski or hike Grouse Mountain, cross the dizzying Capilano Suspension Bridge, bike or blade round the Stanley Park seawall, or hit Chinatown for some top-notch dim sum.</p>]]><p><b>Whistle down the side of Whistler</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Two mountains, 3,307 hectares (8,171 acres) of terrain, 1,609m (5,280ft) of vertical and over 10m (33ft) of annual snowfall: Whistler beats its rivals hands down. This is the place to ski or snowboard in North America, thanks to an abundance of powder-filled bowls, magical gladed runs, gnarly chutes and cruisy slopes, alongside a lively pedestrianised village.</p>]]><p><b>Witness the Northern Lights</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ethereal lights of the Aurora Borealis are frequently visible in the Northwest Territories. To observe this magical, kaleidoscopic phenomenon, join a tour from Yellowknife and travel by dogsled across a frozen lake or splash out on a trip to a fly-in lodge where you could also try snowshoeing, ice fishing or snowmobiling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$1.55 trillion (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Motor vehicles and parts, machinery and equipment, crude petroleum, natural gas and high-technology products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, industry goods, motor vehicles and parts, fuels and oils, and plastics.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, France, Germany, Japan, South Korea, Mexico, UK and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Canada is one of the world's leading trading nations and a member of the G8 group of major industrial economies. The country has immense natural resources and a high standard of living.</p>
<p>Agriculture and fisheries are particularly important; Canada exports much of its agricultural produce (principally grain and oil seeds) and is the world's sixth-largest exporter of fish. Timber is another important sector, given that more than 40% of the land area is forest.</p>
<p>As a mineral producer, Canada exports crude oil and natural gas, copper, nickel, zinc, iron ore, asbestos, cement, coal and potash. Energy requirements are met by a mixture of hydroelectric, nuclear, coal and oil-fired generating stations. Manufacturing covers a wide range of industries from heavy engineering and chemicals to vehicle production and agro-business to office automation and commercial printing.</p>
<p>Almost 80% of the country's trade is with the USA, making this the world's largest single bilateral trade relationship.</p>
<p>The 1989 free trade agreement signed with the USA formed the basis for the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA); Mexico joined as the third signatory in 1994. The future of NAFTA remains uncertain as US President Donald Trump seeks to re-negotiate the terms &nbsp;of the agreement.</p>
<p>Canada&rsquo;s prudent economic policies have allowed it to weather the worst of the global economic downturn, with growth recovering to 3.1% in 2010. This is in part thanks to its increasing population due to immigration. Nonetheless, some economists predict Canada&rsquo;s housing bubble will soon burst; house prices have rocketed in the past decade, with low interest rates encouraging consumers to borrow ever-increasing amounts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Usual courtesies are observed in Canada, including exchanging business cards and making appointments. Men and women wear business suits and rarely drink alcohol at lunch, although drinking at lunchtime is starting to become more common. Younger corporate workers enjoy a few after-work drinks too. Entertaining is usually confined to restaurants and bars, rarely in private homes. You might be taken to an ice hockey match if the company has box seats.</p>
<p>Toronto has often been ridiculed as a conservative, uptight city - Toronto the Good, as its detractors say. But while this perception is about 20 years out of date, its legacy survives in the city's approach to business. Torontonians are hard-working, efficient employees. A little chit chat here and there is welcome but generally people like getting to the point. The giving of gifts in business situations is unusual and might be treated suspiciously. In the workplace, it is common to answer the telephone by stating one's first and last name. Around the office, however, people (both superiors and co-workers) are usually addressed by first name.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Canadian Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (613) 238 4000
					Website:http://www.chamber.ca
					Address: 360 Albert Street,Head Office,Suite 420,Ottawa,K1R 7X7]]><b>Canada-United Kingdom Chamber of Commerce in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 020 7258 6578
					Website:http://www.canada-uk.org/
					Address: ,38 Grosvenor Street,London W1K 4DP,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Whether you're craving a monster-sized burger and fries, a juicy rare steak, freshly caught seafood or Oriental stir-fry, Canada has a panoply of eateries to sate your appetite. The French influence in Quebec is easily discernible. Areas where particular groups of immigrants have settled have their own distinct specialties. Look for German-style cuisine in southwestern Ontario, Ukrainian dishes on the Prairies and Asian foods in Vancouver, for instance.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>• Fresh seafood such as mussels, salmon, lobster, prawns, crab and scallops.<br/>• Steak (the central plains produce first-class beef).<br/>• Game (try venison, elk, bison or caribou).<br/>• Poutine (fries smothered in cheese curds and gravy).<br/>• Maple syrup (often liberally doused on pancakes or French toast).<br/>• Nanaimo bar (super sweet chocolatey biscuit bar layered with vanilla or custard buttercream and topped with chocolate).<br/>• Montreal smoked meat (cured beef usually piled high in a sandwich accompanied by mustard).<br/>• BC roll (British Columbian speciality sushi roll made with rice, seaweed, grilled salmon and cucumber).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>In most provinces, you can only buy spirits from specially licensed liquor stores. In Quebec, wine and beer are also available in convenience stores and supermarkets. Beer is sold in some Ontario grocery stores, and a limited number of BC supermarkets sell alcoholic drinks.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Normal practice is usually 15 to 20% of the bill. Tipping your server is standard practice in restaurants, bars and nightclubs.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Either 18 or 19, depending on the province or territory. In Nunavut, alcohol is prohibited in some communities.<br />
<font color="#222222" face="arial, sans-serif" size="2"><br />
<span style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);">&bull; </span></font>19 years of age in the provinces of British Columbia, New Brunswick, Newfoundland and Labrador, Northwest Territories, Nova Scotia, Nunavut, Ontario, Prince Edward Island, Saskatchewan, and Yukon.</p>
<p><font color="#222222" face="arial, sans-serif" size="2"><span style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);">&bull; </span></font>18 years of age in Alberta, Manitoba and Quebec.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Canadian nightlife isn&rsquo;t solely oriented around boozing. But if you&rsquo;re up for a few drinks, most cities have a pleasant selection of casual brewpubs and hipster lounges. In many cases, the most popular bars are connected to stylish hotels. The major cities have at least a handful of nightclubs playing music to suit most tastes. Live music&rsquo;s popular too &ndash; try Nova Scotia for traditional Celtic music with a Canadian slant or Alberta for boot-stomping cowboy tunes.<br />
<br />
A night out in Canada is just as likely to be centred around eating, and the country&rsquo;s considerable ethnic diversity means you&rsquo;re in for a treat, with an enormous variety of food available. Vancouver is the place to head for sushi, while Montreal is renowned for poutine - a stodgy dish of fries smothered in cheese curds and gravy.<br />
<br />
Canadians also love hanging out at coffee bars and these tend to stay open late, making a nice alternative to sitting in the pub.<br />
<br />
Montreal, Ottawa, Toronto, Vancouver, Calgary and Winnipeg are centres for ballet, opera and classical music, with visits from leading orchestras and internationally renowned performers.<br />
<br />
Entertainment in the more remote towns is scarce, but it&rsquo;s always worth having a few beers in the local bar where you&rsquo;re likely to encounter a few characters.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You&rsquo;ll have no trouble buying large vats of maple syrup or cuddly polar bears galore. If you&rsquo;re looking for something more original, check out the extensive range of fine Canadian crafts available, such as art woodcarvings, leather goods, pottery, jewellery and native artworks.</p>
<p>Sports lovers might enjoying kitting themselves out in an ice hockey strip: take your pick from NHL teams the Montreal Canadiens, Toronto Maple Leafs, Ottawa Senators, Winnipeg Jets, Calgary Flames, Edmonton Oilers or Vancouver Canucks.</p>
<p>Outdoors enthusiasts meanwhile will find a vast selection of stores selling all the must-have gear and clothing. Mountain Equipment Co-op (MEC) has branches across the country, sells everything you could possibly need for trips into the backcountry, and is something of a Canadian institution.</p>
<p>Canada boasts a strong tradition of microbreweries, and a few bottles of the local ale make for a unique and consumable gift. Edible treats include salmon candy (chewy strips of smoked salmon steeped in honey and spices), fireweed honey and a smorgasbord of specialist chutneys, pickles and sauces.</p>
<p>This being North America, shopping malls are everywhere; if you&rsquo;re a mall fanatic, make a pilgrimage to the country&rsquo;s (and previously the world&rsquo;s) largest, the West Edmonton Mall in Alberta. With more than 800 shops, a water park, ice rink, amusement park, aquarium, cinemas, restaurants, clubs and even two hotels, there are no shortage of outlets to splash your cash.</p>
<p>There are three different forms of sales tax throughout Canada; these are added onto the price of goods at the till. A 5% goods and service tax (GST) is levied on most goods and services in Canada. In addition, most jurisdictions (except Alberta, the Northwest Territories, Nunavut and the Yukon) levy a provincial service tax (PST) of 5 to 10% in shops, restaurants and short-term accommodation.</p>
<p>In the provinces of Newfoundland and Labrador, Prince Edward Island,&nbsp;Nova Scotia, New Brunswick and Ontario, a harmonised sales tax (HST) of 12 to 15% has replaced the GST and PST. Note that visitors may no longer reclaim GST or HST on accommodation and any goods purchased and taken out of the country.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1800, with late-night shopping in some stores Thurs-Fri, up to 2100 (malls in large cities are often open until 2100 Mon-Fri). Some shops and stores are also open on Sunday, and some are open 24 hours a day.</p><p>Some countries have restrictions against the import of endangered animal species products, such as products made from polar bear, seal, walrus or whale, so you should check entry regulations in your home country before departure; some of these products may also require a Canadian export certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Canada cover every budget: all the major North American chains are represented across the country, from luxury brands such as Fairmont, Westin and Four Seasons to more affordable options including Days Inn and Comfort Inn. Toronto, Vancouver and Montreal have all seen a slew of new luxury hotels opening in the past few years and design-led boutique hotels have become something of a trend in all the major cities.<br />
<br />
There&rsquo;s certainly no shortage of clean, modern hotels to suit smaller budgets however. Hotels generally have a variety of room types: you can often squeeze four into a room with two double beds or go for a super king-size bed or a one-bedroom suite if you&rsquo;re travelling with kids.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> The voluntary Canada Select accommodation grading system (<a href="http://www.canadaselect.com" target="_blank">www.canadaselect.com</a>) operates across the country. In many cases, non-profit groups or industry associations assess the properties, such as the CAA (Canadian Automobile Association), which grades participating properties on a 1- to 5-diamond rating (<a href="http://www.caa.com" target="_blank">www.caa.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfast accommodation is widespread in Canada. You can find an excellent source of listings at <a href="http://www.bbcanada.com" target="_blank">www.bbcanada.com</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Canada cover every budget: all the major North American chains are represented across the country, from luxury brands such as Fairmont, Westin and Four Seasons to more affordable options including Days Inn and Comfort Inn. Toronto, Vancouver and Montreal have all seen a slew of new luxury hotels opening in the past few years and design-led boutique hotels have become something of a trend in all the major cities.<br />
<br />
There&rsquo;s certainly no shortage of clean, modern hotels to suit smaller budgets however. Hotels generally have a variety of room types: you can often squeeze four into a room with two double beds or go for a super king-size bed or a one-bedroom suite if you&rsquo;re travelling with kids.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> The voluntary Canada Select accommodation grading system (<a href="http://www.canadaselect.com" target="_blank">www.canadaselect.com</a>) operates across the country. In many cases, non-profit groups or industry associations assess the properties, such as the CAA (Canadian Automobile Association), which grades participating properties on a 1- to 5-diamond rating (<a href="http://www.caa.com" target="_blank">www.caa.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Canada cover every budget: all the major North American chains are represented across the country, from luxury brands such as Fairmont, Westin and Four Seasons to more affordable options including Days Inn and Comfort Inn. Toronto, Vancouver and Montreal have all seen a slew of new luxury hotels opening in the past few years and design-led boutique hotels have become something of a trend in all the major cities.<br />
<br />
There&rsquo;s certainly no shortage of clean, modern hotels to suit smaller budgets however. Hotels generally have a variety of room types: you can often squeeze four into a room with two double beds or go for a super king-size bed or a one-bedroom suite if you&rsquo;re travelling with kids.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> The voluntary Canada Select accommodation grading system (<a href="http://www.canadaselect.com" target="_blank">www.canadaselect.com</a>) operates across the country. In many cases, non-profit groups or industry associations assess the properties, such as the CAA (Canadian Automobile Association), which grades participating properties on a 1- to 5-diamond rating (<a href="http://www.caa.com" target="_blank">www.caa.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There is no reciprocal health agreement with the UK, but doctors will continue medication for prescriptions issued in Europe. Private health insurance is absolutely essential as hospital charges are very high. Health facilities are excellent. Travellers to more remote northern areas should carry personal first-aid kits. Dial 911 for emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is safe to drink and food safety standards are high. If camping in the backcountry, you should be aware of the risks of giardia, where water in streams or lakes has been contaminated by animal waste. This can cause diarrhoea, vomiting and headaches. Ensure you boil, filter or purify water first; purification tablets are easy to buy in any outdoor equipment store. You should also be aware of the dangers of eating shellfish directly from the sea, which can cause paralytic shellfish poisoning, resulting in illness or death. Check locally before you travel.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Summer can bring extremely high temperatures, so you should guard against the problems of heat and sunstroke. Wear sunscreen to prevent sunburn, particularly on days when the widely publicised UV rating is high. (Remember that sunburn can be a risk in winter too, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re skiing, when the high altitude and reflection from the snow can be a potent combination.) In winter, on the other hand, temperatures can be bitterly cold and frostbite is a real risk; ensure you wear multiple layers and a hat, and cover your face when outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rabies is present in animals. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An outbreak of hepatitis A was reported in Vancouver Island in 2011, but most cases have been confined to one cultural group on the island. Vaccination against hepatitis A is not advised unless you&amp;rsquo;re visiting the outbreak area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If walking in tick-infested woodland and brush areas, you should be aware of the risk of Lyme disease. Ensure you cover bare skin (tucking in all clothes), use insect repellent containing DEET and remove any attached ticks using tweezers. The disease is transmitted from the bites of the western blacklegged tick in British Columbia and the blacklegged or deer tick in other parts of Canada. Since 2010, there has been an increased risk in southern Quebec due to newly discovered populations of ticks carrying the bacterium that causes Lyme disease. The first symptom is usually a circular rash, accompanied by fatigue, chills, fever, headache, muscle and joint pain and swollen lymph nodes. You should seek treatment as soon as possible as symptoms can worsen if left untreated, though fatalities are rare.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are often observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here:</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Victoria Day :
							21 May </p><p>Canada Day :
							01 July </p><p>Labour Day :
							03 September </p><p>Thanksgiving Day :
							08 October </p><p>Remembrance Day :
							11 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Canada without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes and 50 cigars and 200g of loose tobacco and 200 tobacco sticks per person over 18 years of age.<br />
&bull; 1.5L of wine or 1.14L of spirits or 8.5L of beer or ale per person over 18 years of age if entering <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/">Alberta</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/">Manitoba</a> and Qu&eacute;bec, and over 19 years if entering <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/british-columbia">British Columbia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/new-brunswick">New Brunswick</a>, Newfoundland and Labrador, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/northwest-territories">Northwest Territories</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/nova-scotia">Nova Scotia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/nunavut">Nunavut</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/">Ontario</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/prince-edward-island">Prince Edward Island</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/">Saskatchewan</a> and Yukon.<br />
&bull; Non-residents can bring gifts to the value of C$60 per gift (excluding advertising matter, business-related materials, tobacco or alcoholic beverages).<br />
&bull; Canadian residents can bring goods to the value of C$200 for trips out of the country of 24 hours or more (excluding alcohol and tobacco) and C$800 for trips of 48 hours or more (including alcohol and tobacco).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The import of firearms, explosives, endangered species of animals and plants, animal products, meat, dairy, and food and plant material is subject to certain restrictions and formalities.&nbsp;Check the Canada Border Services Agency website (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.cbsa.gc.ca">www.cbsa.gc.ca</a>) for further details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some products made from endangered animals may require an export certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Canadian Dollar (CAD; symbol C$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of C$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of C$2 and 1, and 25, 10, 5 cents. Although the 1c coin (or penny) remains legal tender, as of 2013 it is being phased out of circulation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can easily exchange currency at any bank or bureau de change. Hotels sometimes change money too, but their exchange rate is likely to be less favourable. If you're travelling to smaller communities, ensure you have a good supply of Canadian Dollars in cash, as you may not be able to change foreign currency at all and might not have access to an ATM.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are widely accepted. Use of debit cards is widespread, although many stores impose a C$5 to C$20 minimum per debit card purchase, and service charges may apply.</p><p>ATMs are easy to find in populated areas but are less common in remote regions such as rural parts of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/northwest-territories">Northwest Territories</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/nunavut">Nunavut</a> and Labrador. Use a machine affiliated with a major bank to reduce service charges; independent machines in locations such as casinos and convenience stores may carry high charges and do not always accept international cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Canadian Dollars; these are negotiable primarily in banks, hotels and tourist facilities. Their use has declined somewhat in recent years as more visitors rely on ATM cards, but travellers should bring at least some emergency currency in traveller's cheques in case their ATM cards do not work.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally, Mon-Fri 0930-1700 with extended hours in some locations, particularly on Thursday and Friday evenings. Some branches open as early as 0800 and many now open on Saturdays and Sundays too, usually until 1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>N/A</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>N/A</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>N/A</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>2</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes/1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Canada, a valid passport is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above, except the following:</p>
<p><strong>1.</strong> Citizens of France who are residents of, and entering from, the French overseas territory Saint Pierre and Miquelon; and persons entering from Saint Pierre and Miquelon.</p>
<p><strong>2.</strong> Citizens of the&nbsp;USA&nbsp;holding a birth certificate, certificate of citizenship or naturalisation, US&nbsp;permanent resident card, or certificate of Indian status along with photo ID. However, it is recommended that you carry a valid passport. US citizens re-entering the USA&nbsp;from Canada via air, land or sea require a valid passport or passport card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If travelling with children under 18 of whom you are not the legal parent or guardian, you are advised to bring a signed letter authorising entry into Canada from the child's parent or guardian. If you are the child's only parent or guardian, it's recommended that you bring documents showing this.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas are necessary for all nationals who require a visitor visa and who are stopping in Canada for fewer than 48 hours on the way to another country. However, certain nationalities travelling to the USA&nbsp;via Canada may be eligible for the Transit Without Visa programme; check online at <a href="http://www.cic.gc.ca">www.cic.gc.ca</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single- or multiple-entry visitor visa: C$100; family visitor visa: C$500 maximum; transit: free; study permit: C$150.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: up to six months; multiple-entry visa: up to six months at a time for up to 10 years. All applicants are considered for a multiple-entry visa.</p>
<p>The determination regarding length of stay in Canada can only be decided by the examining officer at the port of entry. It is usually six months, but in some cases the officer may limit the permitted time in Canada depending on the purpose of your trip.</p>
<p>Visitors must leave Canada on or before the date authorised by the examining officer on arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy or high commission). Some applicants are eligible to apply online (<a href="http://www.cic.gc.ca">www.cic.gc.ca</a>). Applicants living in the UK either need to apply online or through VFS Global's Canada Visa Application Centre (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.ca">www.vfsglobal.ca</a>) which charges a &pound;21.49 processing fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In addition to the visas listed above, parents and grandparents of Canadian citizens or permanent residents may apply for a Parent and Grandparent Super Visa, which allows stays of up to two years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing time varies according to your nationality and your country of residence. In the UK, applications for visitor visas are usually processed within 12 days if you apply online or through VFS Global. This can vary according to the time of year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visitors must have enough money to cover their stay; the amount varies depending on individual circumstances, length of stay and whether you&rsquo;re staying with friends and relatives or in a hotel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your stay as a visitor, you must apply to the nearest Canada Immigration Centre or online at least 30 days before the expiry of the visitor visa. The cost to extend a visitor visa is C$100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For information on importing pets into Canada, visit the website of the Canadian Food Inspection Agency (<a href="http://www.inspection.gc.ca" target="_blank">www.inspection.gc.ca</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[52.961875]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-98.613281]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>9,984,670 sq km (3,855,102 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>36,428,310 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ottawa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Canada is the second largest country in the world after Russia, covering an area of 9,984,670 sq km (3,855,103 sq miles). It is bordered to the west by the Pacific Ocean and Alaska, to the east by the Atlantic Ocean, to the northeast by Greenland (across the Nares Strait), and to the south by the 'Lower 48' states of the USA. The polar ice cap lies to the north.</p>
<p>Canada stretches 4,634km (2,879 miles) from its northernmost point on Ellesmere Island, Nunavut to its southernmost point on Middle Island, Lake Erie, Ontario. The longest distance east to west is 5,514km (3,426 miles) from Cape Spear, Newfoundland and Labrador to the Yukon-Alaska border. Canada also has the world&rsquo;s longest coastline at 202,080km (125,566 miles). The country&rsquo;s highest mountain, with a peak at 5,959m (19,550ft), is Mt Logan in the Yukon Territory.</p>
<p>The landscape is diverse, ranging from the Arctic tundra of the north to the great prairies of the central area. Westward are the Rocky Mountains, and in the southeast are the Great Lakes, the St Lawrence River and Niagara Falls. The country is divided into 10 provinces and three territories.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Around 70% of the population belong to the Christian faith; over half are Roman Catholic, followed by the United Church of Canada and Anglican denominations. There are numerous other active denominations and religions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking predominates as the normal mode of greeting. Close friends often exchange kisses on the cheeks, particularly in French-speaking areas. Codes of practice for visiting homes are the same as in other Western countries: flowers, chocolates or a bottle of wine are common gifts for hosts, and dress is generally informal and practical according to climate. It is common for black tie and other required dress to be indicated on invitations. Exclusive clubs and restaurants often require more formal dress. Smoking has been banned in most public areas. <br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>120 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style flat two-pin (with or without round grounding pin) plugs are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Justin Trudeau since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented by Governor General Julie Payette since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The first Europeans to reach Canada were descendants of Norse seafarers who had settled in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iceland">Iceland</a> and in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greenland">Greenland</a> during the ninth and 10th centuries; the second wave of European arrivals, led by the Italian navigator Giovanni Caboto (better known as John Cabot), were seeking a passage to Asia, in 1497. Over the next 100 years, attracted by rich fishing grounds, English and French commercial interests flocked to Newfoundland.</p>
<p>During the 17th century, the French accelerated trading with the New France Company. The creation of England's Hudson's Bay Company initiated a long period of rivalry, culminating in the Anglo-French war of the early 1760s; this ended with the surrender of the French Canadian capital, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/quebec-city">Quebec</a>, to the English forces. The Treaty of Paris, in 1763, gave all French territories in northeast America to the British.</p>
<p>Within two decades, however, the English had been ousted from their American colonies following defeat in the American War of Independence. Eastern Canada was then settled by loyalists from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> holding allegiance to the defeated British Crown. In 1791, Canada was divided between regions occupied by the English-speaking and the longer-established French-speaking community, but the arrangement did not work and was replaced by a unified system.</p>
<p>In the mid-19th century, Canada was granted the status of a Dominion of the British Empire, with an autonomous government but with the British monarch as head of state. From 1968 to 1984, politics were dominated by the charismatic figure of Pierre Trudeau. Brian Mulroney was elected in 1984, and the Quebec issue came to the fore once more. A 1995 referendum in Quebec resulted in an extremely narrow vote in favour of remaining inside Canada, although in 2006 the Canadian parliament agreed the Quebecois should &lsquo;form a nation within a united Canada&rsquo;, a largely symbolic gesture.</p>
<p>In 2015, Justin Pierre James Trudeau followed in the footsteps of his father and was named 23rd prime minister of Canada. As leader of the Federal Liberal party, Trudeau Jr. built a cabinet from an equal number of men and women, starting a trend towards a new liberal form of politics. Virtually every Trudeau initiative, from tax policy to legalising marijuana, has been at odds with the previous Conservative administration.&nbsp;</p>
<p>2017 marks the 150th anniversary of the Canadian Confederation and the country will celebrate this sesquicentennial with a series of special events planned over the course of the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Canadian Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 682 1740. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.washington.gc.ca</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 682 1740. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; 0900-1200 (consular services).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>501 Pennsylvania Avenue<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20001<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Canadian High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7258 6600. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.unitedkingdom.gc.ca</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7258 6600. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon, Wed and Fri 0800-1030 (immigration and visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>38 Grosvenor Street<br/>London<br/>W1K 4DP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Canada]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 613 237 1530.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/canada</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 613 237 1530.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>80 Elgin Street<br/>Ottawa<br/>K1P 5K7<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Whether you&rsquo;re a hardcore adrenaline junkie, a wildlife enthusiast or a city slicker looking for cutting-edge culture, Canada ticks all the boxes. The world&rsquo;s second largest country racks up an astonishing diversity of landscapes; vast prairies rise abruptly to glacier-topped mountains; rugged, unspoiled coastlines give way to immense forests and emerald lakes; and Arctic waters lap upon frozen tundra. Incredibly, this wilderness is also home to cosmopolitan cities, quirky towns and remote indigenous settlements.</p>
<p>Canada&rsquo;s people are as varied as the landscapes; from the Arctic Inuit and the Francophone Quebeckers to the British expatriates and burgeoning Asian community, this is a multicultural land where around 20% of the population are foreign-born.</p>
<p>Canadian cities are progressive, vibrant and regularly feature on lists of &ldquo;best places to live.&quot; Toronto, a veritable patchwork of charming neighbourhoods, has an idyllic beachside location on the shore of Lake Ontario, while Canada&rsquo;s capital city, Ottawa, contains a clutch of fantastic museums and the pretty Rideau Canal for ice skating in winter. Montreal&rsquo;s skyscrapers belie its French heritage, but look closer and you can stumble upon historic, cobbled streets and centuries-old customs.</p>
<p>A stone&rsquo;s throw from the Canadian Rockies, booming Calgary flashes its oil wealth and flaunts its cowboy traditions during the annual boot-stomping Stampede. Chilled-out Vancouver, meanwhile, seems to have it all: mountains, beaches, an incredible downtown park and a cosmopolitan dining scene. And across the Georgia Strait, Vancouver Island is just the tonic if the city life gets too tough. Not that it ever does here.</p>
<p>For something wilder, ski steep chutes in British Columbia, kayak secluded bays with whales in Nova Scotia or learn to lasso at an Albertan ranch. Capture grizzlies on camera in the Yukon, watch mammoth icebergs drift past the Newfoundland coast, or soar over Niagara Falls by helicopter. Tour vineyards, dig for clams or feel giddy gazing at the Northern Lights. In Canada, it seems, the options are endless.</p><p>Whether you&rsquo;re a hardcore adrenaline junkie, a wildlife enthusiast or a city slicker looking for cutting-edge culture, Canada ticks all the boxes. The world&rsquo;s second largest country racks up an astonishing diversity of landscapes; vast prairies rise abruptly to glacier-topped mountains; rugged, unspoilt coastlines give way to immense forests and emerald lakes; and Arctic waters lap upon frozen shores. Incredibly, this wilderness is also home to cosmopolitan cities, quirky towns and remote indigenous settlements.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
