<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="British Columbia" ColCode="bco" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="bc" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[British Columbia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The southern coast of British Columbia is one of the mildest regions in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a>, with warm summers and relatively mild winters - hence Vancouver Island's coastal rainforests and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria">Victoria</a>'s palm trees. Summers in the province's interior are hot. Heavy snowfalls occur in the mountains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights for most of the summer, with warmer clothes sometimes necessary in the evenings. Mediumweights are worn during winter, with Alpine wear in the mountains. Waterproof clothing is advisable throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Canada (AC) (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aircanada.com">www.aircanada.com</a>) serves British Columbia, and many other airlines from worldwide destinations also serve the province.&nbsp;Vancouver International (<a href="http://www.yvr.ca/" target="_blank">www.yvr.ca</a>) is the second busiest airport in Canada and serves BC with non-stop flights to Asia, Europe, Oceania, Mexico and the USA.&nbsp;Across the Strait of Georgia, Victoria International Airport (<a href="http://www.victoriaairport.com" target="_blank">www.victoriaairport.com</a>)&nbsp;served more than 1,800,000 passengers in 2016, offering a number of internal routes alongside&nbsp;international flights to Mexico and the USA.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Kelowna Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.kelownaairport.com<p>The airport  is north of Kelowna.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Victoria International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.victoriaairport.com/<p>The airport  is 22km (14 miles) north of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria">Victoria</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vancouver (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.portmetrovancouver.com">www.portmetrovancouver.com</a>) is an international passenger port, with regular sailings to the Far East and ports on the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>'s northwestern coast as well as up to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/alaska">Alaska</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>VIA Rail (tel: +1 888 842 7245; <a href="http://www.viarail.ca" target="_blank">www.viarail.ca</a>) train routes to and within British Columbia are: The Skeena service from Prince Rupert to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ski/jasper">Jasper</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/alberta">Alberta</a>) with connections to Edmonton (requires at least one overnight off-train stay en route);&nbsp;and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vancouver/vancouver-international-airport">Vancouver</a> to Edmonton via Kamloops and Jasper, and on to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a> three times a week (The Canadian).<br />
<br />
The seasonal Rocky Mountaineer train (tel: +1 604 606 7200;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.rockymountaineer.com" target="_blank">www.rockymountaineer.com</a>) is a two-day, all-daylight tour between Vancouver and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ski/banff">Banff</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/alberta/calgary-international-airport">Calgary</a> or Jasper and between Whistler and Jasper, operating between mid April and mid October.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Canrailpass - System: allows seven or 10 one-way trips anywhere on the VIA network (from British Columbia to Nova Scotia) within a 60-day period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Ancient history</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fossil hunters can see specimens dating back 50 million years at Driftwood Canyon Provincial Park.</p>]]><p><b>Bear facts</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many visitors are eager for a close encounter of the furred kind with foraging black bears; prime viewing areas include Wells Gray Provincial Park and rural roads nears Kamloops and Merritt. Learn about bear safety first, and keep a safe distance. Never approach or feed them.</p>]]><p><b>Downtown Vancouver</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gastown, the city's reconstructed old centre, is a pleasant array of cobblestone streets, caf&eacute;s and shops. Museums and galleries include the University of British Columbia's Museum of Anthropology, Science World and the Vancouver Maritime Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Salmon is especially plentiful around Vancouver Island, and the Kootenay Rockies offer the best bass fishing in the province. Other fish include halibut, cod, trout, whitefish and turbot. There are more than 200 lakes within an hour of Kamloops. Licences are required.</p>]]><p><b>Glaciers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>More than 400 glaciers continue to sculpt the dramatic Columbia Mountains and to feed the crystal-clear rivers in the spectacular Glacier National Park.</p>]]><p><b>Hiking trails</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Vancouver, stroll through Stanley Park. Long-distance hiking trails include the beautiful West Coast Trail in Pacific Rim National Park and the Juan de Fuca Marine Trail, both on Vancouver Island. You can see giant trees in the old coastal rainforests on the island's Pacific coast.</p>]]><p><b>Lakes and deserts</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Vineyard views and their vinous produce abound in British Columbia's 'playground' around Lake Okanagan. The northern tip of Mexico's Sonora Desert ends in this rich countryside and azure-blue waters. Autumn wine tours attract many visitors. Shuswap Lake offers resort-like summer weather and excellent boating opportunities.</p>]]><p><b>Other winter sports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you tire of straightforward skiing, there's also snowboarding, glacier skiing (in summer), heli-skiing or cat skiing. Cross-country skiing is widely practised, and ski touring through backcountry forests is popular.</p>]]><p><b>Pioneer sites</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Historic towns are dotted along the Cariboo Gold Rush route. Common stops include 100 Mile House, which recalls the days when Cariboo pioneers measured journeys by the distance from the Gold Rush town of Lillooet, otherwise known as 'Mile 0'.</p>]]><p><b>Ranches and lodges</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Vast tracts of untamed lakeland, forest and wilderness define the Cariboo. The arid, desert-like terrain is best known for its guest ranch accommodation and winter lodge facilities.</p>]]><p><b>Royal British Columbia Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Royal British Columbia Museum in BC's capital city, Victoria, is home to exceptional collections of First Nations masks and totem poles, as well as other items from the province's history. After exploring the museum, take in the sights of charming Victoria, whose stately buildings and red pillar boxes give a pronounced British feel.</p>]]><p><b>Scenic drive</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Silvery Slocan Circle Driving Tour meanders past numerous historic landmarks, such as the historic logging town of Kaslo, which populates the hills and shoreline of Kootenay Lake, and the town of Nelson, home to hundreds of heritage buildings.</p>]]><p><b>Sensational views</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Also in Vancouver, the Grouse Mountain Skyride on the North Shore offers views of the city and fjords of the Pacific coast. You'll find more breathtaking city and coastal views in Vancouver's eastern suburbs at Burnaby Mountain Park.</p>]]><p><b>Skiing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Rocky and Coast Mountains offer superb skiing. One of Canada's best-known ski resorts is Whistler, which will co-host the 2010 Winter Olympics. Other well-known centres include Fernie, Red Mountain (home to several of Canada's Olympic ski medallists), Kimberley, Sun Peaks, Kicking Horse and Big White.</p>]]><p><b>Victoria</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located on the southern tip of Vancouver Island on the Pacific coast, British Columbia's capital city of Victoria boasts a population of 78, 000. Named after the UK's Queen Victoria it is one of the oldest cities in the Northwest and home to a number of historic buildings like the British Columbia Parliament Buildings and the Empress Hotel. Visitors can also enjoy a number of museums here such as the Royal BC Museum and the Maritime Museum of British Columbia, plus a wealth of natural scenic beauty and a beautiful temperate climate.</p>]]><p><b>Volcanoes and natives</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Nisga'a Memorial Lava Bed, a sacred Aboriginal site about 100km (62 miles) north of Terrace, is a unique volcanic landscape where you can learn about Nisga'a culture and legends. The Queen Charlotte Islands are also inhabited by several Aboriginal communities, and are accessible by boat or floatplane.</p>]]><p><b>Watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Excellent sailing, canoeing and white-water rafting are all available in British Columbia, with its ample lakes and rivers, and long Pacific coast. The sheltered Inside Passage from Vancouver Island to Prince Rupert is particularly popular. Expect beautiful views of the fjord-indented coastline and snow-capped Coast Mountains.</p>]]><p><b>Whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You might spot orca (killer), humpback, grey or minke whales on whale-watching cruises. In March, the Pacific Rim Whale Festival celebrates the yearly migration of Pacific grey whales. Watch for whales in remote towns Tofino and Ucluelet, near Pacific Rim National Park, which is full of sandy beaches and wilderness.</p>]]><p><b>Winery tours</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Okanagan Wine Route winds through the vineyards of the Thompson Okanagan Valley, the oldest wine-producing region in British Columbia. There are more than 100 wineries in the region, and the valley holds four wine festivals each year.</p>]]><p><b>World Heritage Site</b></p><![CDATA[<p>More than one million seabirds and animals populate one of Canada's many UNESCO World Heritage Sites, the Gwaii Haanas National Park Reserve.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><br />There are convention centres in Penticton, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vancouver/vancouver-international-airport">Vancouver</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria">Victoria</a> and Whistler as well as over 200 hotels throughout the province which can offer meeting facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal business courtesies should be observed in British Columbia, although businesspeople here are less formal than Europeans and tend to use first-name terms after initial introductions have been completed.  Business cards are usually exchanged on meeting a colleague for the first time - and a compliment on British Columbia's beauty is sure to be well received. Both men and women generally wear suits, although short-sleeved shirts are acceptable in summer. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a> </p>
<p>Appointments and punctuality for business meetings are expected. Business hours are usually Monday to Friday 0900-1700, although may start or end an hour earlier or later, depending on the company. Lunch meetings are more common than breakfast meetings, however, these are rarely alcohol-fuelled affairs.  Most business entertainment takes place in bars and restaurants and it is unusual for a business visitor to be invited into someone's home. If you are, a token gift (alcohol, flowers or chocolates) would be a nice gesture. Anything more expensive may be deemed unacceptable.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Tourism Vancouver</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (604) 682 2222
					Website:http://www.tourismvancouver.com/
					Address: 200 Burrard Street,Suite 210,Vancouver,]]><b>The Greater Victoria Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (250) 383 7191
					Website:http://www.victoriachamber.ca/
					Address: 852 Fort Street,Suite 100,Victoria,]]><b>Tourism Victoria</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (250) 953 2033 ,1 800 663 3883
					Website:http://www.tourismvictoria.com
					Address: Victoria,812 Wharf Street,British Columbia V8W 1T3,]]><b>Ministry of Small Business, Technology and Economic Development</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:http://www.gov.bc.ca/tted
					Address: Station Provincial Government,PO Box 9324,Victoria,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>British Columbia has a dynamic food and drink scene, with a huge variety of international influences and a strong focus on farm-to-table menus. Restaurants dish up everything from fresh salmon and sushi to raw foods and tapas.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>• The Pacific Ocean yields a great variety of seafood, including king crab, oysters, shrimp and other shellfish, as well as cod, haddock and salmon (coho, spring, chum, sockeye and pink), which is smoked, pan-fried, breaded, baked, canned or barbecued, and complemented by local vegetables.<br/>• Fruits grown in the province include apples, peaches, pears, plums, apricots, strawberries, blackberries, the famous<em>Bing</em>cherries, cranberries and loganberries. <br/><em>•</em> Victoria creams, a famous chocolate delicacy derived from a recipe dating back to 1885, come in multiple flavours, including raspberry, ginger and maple. The original confectioners shop, Rogers' Chocolates, is in Victoria on Vancouver Island<em>.</em></p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Spirits, beer and wine can be served in licensed restaurants, dining rooms, pubs and bars. In many jurisdictions, bars and pubs are open until 0200, but hours vary, since they are set by local governments. Alcohol is sold in privately and provincially owned liquor stores as well as in some grocery stores (where there is no nearby liquor store). You can also buy craft beer direct from the brewery, many of which also offer tours.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It's customary to tip between 15% and 20% at bars and restaurants in BC. Tips are also given to tour guides, and for taxi service, spa treatments, porters and haircuts.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>19. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major cities and towns have top-class restaurants, nightclubs and bars, sometimes in pub style. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vancouver/vancouver-international-airport">Vancouver</a> has an active theatre life. Good nightspots are often found in hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vancouver is a shopper's paradise. Robson Street offers fashion boutiques, souvenir and speciality shops. Yaletown is the shopping ground of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vancouver/vancouver-international-airport">Vancouver</a>'s young and aspirational, with designer fashions, art galleries and trendy home decor shops. Other popular areas include Chinatown, Gastown and Granville Island. Indoor shopping downtown includes the Pacific Centre, Royal Centre and the Sinclair Centre, while Metropolis at Metrotown is a large suburban mall in Burnaby (with about 500 shops and food outlets). Popular handicrafts include Pacific Northwest and Inuit arts and crafts: soapstone sculptures, carved masks, totem poles, pottery, jewellery and prints.</p><p>In the larger areas shops are generally open daily 0930-1800 (Thurs-Fri until 2100, Sun from 1200).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation ranges from top-class hotels in cities and resort areas and motels beside highways to simple cabins high up in the mountains. Cottages and cabins are widely available. Ranch holidays are popular in the Cariboo Chilcotin Coast tourism region of central British Columbia. Tourism British Columbia has an annual guide listing all the agencies providing accommodation in the province. Tourism BC oversees standards and approved hotels display a white <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a>'Approved Accommodation' sign to indicate that Tourism BC's standards of courtesy, comfort and cleanliness have been met.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation ranges from top-class hotels in cities and resort areas and motels beside highways to simple cabins high up in the mountains. Cottages and cabins are widely available. Ranch holidays are popular in the Cariboo Chilcotin Coast tourism region of central British Columbia. Tourism British Columbia has an annual guide listing all the agencies providing accommodation in the province. Tourism BC oversees standards and approved hotels display a white <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a>'Approved Accommodation' sign to indicate that Tourism BC's standards of courtesy, comfort and cleanliness have been met.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation ranges from top-class hotels in cities and resort areas and motels beside highways to simple cabins high up in the mountains. Cottages and cabins are widely available. Ranch holidays are popular in the Cariboo Chilcotin Coast tourism region of central British Columbia. Tourism British Columbia has an annual guide listing all the agencies providing accommodation in the province. Tourism BC oversees standards and approved hotels display a white <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a>'Approved Accommodation' sign to indicate that Tourism BC's standards of courtesy, comfort and cleanliness have been met.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[53.726668]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-127.647621]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>944,735 sq km (364,764 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,648,055 (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Victoria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Columbia is <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a>'s most westerly province, bordered to the south by the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> (Washington, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/idaho">Idaho</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/montana">Montana</a> states), to the east by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/alberta">Alberta</a>, to the north by the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada/northwest-territories">Northwest Territories</a> and the Yukon, and to the west by the Pacific Ocean and the 'Alaska Panhandle'. It is mainly covered by virgin forests, and encompasses the towering Rocky Mountains (rising to 3,954m/12,972ft), vast expanses of semi-arid sagebrush, lush pastures on Vancouver Island's east coast, farmland in the Fraser River delta, and fruitland in the Okanagan Valley. The highest mountain is Fairweather at 4,663m (15,298ft). Between the eastern and coastal mountains is a lower central range. The coastal range sinks into the Pacific, with larger peaks emerging at Vancouver Island and Haida Gwaii (Queen Charlotte Islands). The Columbia River flows from the Rockies into <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/washington-state">Washington State</a> and out into the Pacific Ocean.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One colossal mountain range after another, gigantic fjords biting chunks out of a wild coastline, and temperate old-growth rainforests hiding cougars, bears and wolves: British Columbia is nature at its best.</p>
<p>That said the cities are pretty special too. Clutching onto the edge of the Coast Mountains and Pacific Ocean, Vancouver may lack world-class museums, but who needs those when you&rsquo;ve got beaches to flop on, food trucks to munch at and Canada&rsquo;s biggest city park to play in? Not to mention an elaborate web of hiking and ski trails in the city&rsquo;s backyard.</p>
<p>And forget what you&rsquo;ve heard about Victoria replicating ye olde England. BC&rsquo;s bijou capital buzzes with floatplanes, kayakers, one of the finest gardens in the nation and a resident orca population offshore.</p>
<p>Take a road trip past mineral hot springs and glacial lakes in the Kootenay Rockies or peach trees and vineyards in the Okanagan. Venture into Canada&rsquo;s only desert at Osoyoos, home to rattlesnakes, scorpions and prickly pear cacti. Spot grizzlies in Northern BC, whose sprawling wilderness is twice the size of the UK.</p>
<p>The opportunity for adventure in this province is unremitting. Get out and surf Pacific swells at Tofino or ski fathomless powder in Whistler. Explore the Gulf Islands and Haida Gwaii archipelagos by kayak or paddle the Kicking Horse River by raft. Hike up and down ladders on Vancouver Island&rsquo;s West Coast Trail or follow the wagon wheels of pioneers and bike the Gold Rush Trail north from Lillooet.</p>
<p>Wherever you go, unspoiled beauty will be just around the corner.</p><p>One colossal mountain range after another, gigantic fjords biting chunks out of a wild coastline, and temperate old-growth rainforests hiding cougars, bears and wolves: British Columbia is nature at its best.&nbsp;<span style="line-height: 20.3999996185303px;">That said the cities are pretty special too. Clutching onto the edge of the Coast Mountains and Pacific Ocean, Vancouver may lack world-class museums, but who needs those when you&rsquo;ve got beaches to flop on, food trucks to munch at and Canada&rsquo;s biggest city park to play in?<br />
</span></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
