<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Quebec" ColCode="que" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="qc" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Quebec]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Summer months (June to August) are hot and often humid, with cooler evenings. Autumn and spring are cooler and winters are very cold and snowy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights during summer, with warmer clothes sometimes necessary in the evenings. Medium-weight clothing are advisable during autumn and spring, with warm clothing for the cold winters and Alpine wear in the mountains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>National carrier <em>Air Canada</em> (AC) (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aircanada.com/">www.aircanada.com</a>) and other international carriers fly into Montr&eacute;al and Qu&eacute;bec City. Commuter services between Montr&eacute;al and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/quebec-city" target="_blank">Qu&eacute;bec City</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a> also exist. Local air services operate between the cities in the south and float planes serve the lakes and parkland of the north.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Montreal-Pierre Elliott Trudeau International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.admtl.com<p>Montréal-Pierre Elliott Trudeau International Airport is located 20km (12 miles) west of Montréal.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 514 633 3333</p>]]><b>Quebec City Jean Lesage International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeroportdequebec.com<p>Quebec City's airport lies 20km (12 miles) west of Old Quebec and handles primarily domestic flights, although there are a few flights from destinations in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> as well as charters to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> and the Caribbean.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(418) 640 3300</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Qu&eacute;bec City (tel: +1 418 648 3640;&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.portquebec.ca/">www.portquebec.ca</a>) and Montr&eacute;al (tel: +1 514 283 7011;&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.port-montreal.com/">www.port-montreal.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>VIA Rail (tel: +1 888 842 7245; <a href="http://www.viarail.ca/" target="_blank">www.viarail.ca</a>) connects Montr&eacute;al and Qu&eacute;bec City to Toronto and Ottawa with fast, regular services. It also offers services to Halifax from Montr&eacute;al and Qu&eacute;bec City. Links to the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> are with Amtrak (tel: +1 800 872 7245; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>). Amtrak operates one daily train to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York City</a>, with connections to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/philadelphia">Philadelphia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/baltimore">Baltimore</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/washington-dc">Washington, DC</a>. VIA Rail services connect the major cities in the south of the province, with frequent daily services from Montr&eacute;al to Qu&eacute;bec.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire stain glass artwork in Lower Town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Québec City's 'Lower Town' is a thicket of 17th-century streets centred on Place Royale. For art lovers, the Notre-Dame de Québec Basilica houses a unique collection.</p>]]><p><b>Culture in Montréal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Place des Arts is the home of the Montréal Symphony Orchestra and several theatres offering year-round drama, music, ballet and opera. Both the Montréal Museum of Fine Arts and the Museum of Contemporary Arts of Montréal have good collections.</p>]]><p><b>Cycling</b></p><![CDATA[<p>La Route Verte (the 'Green Circuit') boasts over 4,000km (2,485 miles) of marked paths and roadways. The St Lawrence River Valley is good for moderate cycling, while the hilly Laurentians region is more challenging. Mountain bike enthusiasts head for parks and nature reserves, especially Parc de la Jacques-Cartier and Mont-Sainte-Anne, both within easy reach of Québec City.</p>]]><p><b>Feel festive at the Winter Carnival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Qu&eacute;bec City's Winter Carnival (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.carnaval.qc.ca">www.carnaval.qc.ca/en</a>), held in late January to mid February, is one of the largest Lenten festival in the world. It is a thrilling spectacle of parties, ice baths, dog sled races, ice palaces, sculptures and snowmobile races.</p>]]><p><b>Gaspé</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the Gaspésie region, highlights include the Rocher Percé ('the pierced rock', a massive, arched sandstone rock rising from the Atlantic), and Gaspésie Provincial Park, which protects herds of caribou in a beautiful landscape of woods, lakes and streams.</p>]]><p><b>Montréal architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cosmopolitan metropolis Montréal has an unusual underworld - a series of underground shopping and recreation complexes, linked by walkways and the metro, and centred on Place Ville-Marie. Other architectural highlights include the Biodôme (the former Olympic velodrome, now an exotic indoor zoo), and the fascinating Canadian Centre for Architecture.</p>]]><p><b>Old Montréal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Vieux-Montréal, the historic waterfront section, has been carefully restored and contains many beautiful buildings and gathering places including Place Jacques-Cartier; the former French governor's residence, Château Ramezay; the city's oldest chapel, Notre-Dame-de-Bonsecours; and Pointe-à-Callière, the Montréal Museum of Archaeology and History.</p>]]><p><b>Québec City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Old city walls and green copper roofs are the defining characteristics of Québec City. The provincial capital is the only fortified city in North America and is one of the most 'European' cities on the continent, with a 95% Francophone population. A UNESCO World Heritage Site, it celebrated its 400th anniversary in 2008.</p>]]><p><b>Skiing and snowboarding</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Qu&eacute;bec boasts outstanding winter sports facilities, a long season, plentiful snow and around 80 ski centres. The main regions are the Laurentians, the Eastern Townships and the Greater Qu&eacute;bec/Charlevoix area. Cross-country skiing is very popular, as are snowmobiling, snowshoe trekking, ice fishing and ice climbing.</p>]]><p><b>Taste treats</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Québec is home to countless food and drink festivals, such as the many events celebrating the maple syrup harvest from March until mid April. <em>Érablières</em> (maple farms) and <em>cabanes à sucre</em> (sugar shacks) are sprinkled through the province. You can watch the harvest and sample maple toffee (made by pouring molten syrup onto fresh snow).</p>]]><p><b>The marvellous Magdalens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Miles of white sandy beaches and a host of unspoilt fishing villages await intrepid travellers in the Magdalen Islands, 215km (134 miles) east of the Gaspé Peninsula in the Gulf of St Lawrence.</p>]]><p><b>Upper Town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>While in Qu&eacute;bec City, you can wander through the cobblestoned streets and shaded squares of the 'Upper Town', which has fine 18th- and 19th-century architecture, notably the Place D'Armes and the iconic Fairmont Le Ch&acirc;teau Frontenac hotel (<a href="http://www.fairmont.com/frontenac" target="_blank"><span style="color: windowtext;">www.fairmont.com/frontenac)</span></a>. Energetic tourists climb 310 wooden steps to the Citadel, which affords incredible views across the river.</p>]]><p><b>Vikings and geology</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Duplessis region (part of a bigger, largely rural area called the Côte-Nord) is the site of some of the earliest landfalls in the New World, made by the Vikings. The bizarre geological formations of nearby Mingan Archipelago are best explored by boat.</p>]]><p><b>Watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you're an outdoorsy type, you can enjoy a variety of watersports, from white-water rafting (especially on the Rivière Rouge) to gentle boating. Canoes, kayaks and sailboards are available to hire in many provincial and national parks. The St Lawrence River has excellent facilities for sailing.</p>]]><p><b>Whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From May to October, whale-watching tour passengers can see up to 12 species including humpbacks in the St Lawrence. In early March, thousands of harp seals give birth on the ice floes of the Magdalen Islands. You can take a helicopter ride over the area. Be forewarned that this is also the season of the controversial seal hunt, so you may encounter both hunters and activists.</p>]]><p><b>Wild western Québec</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Outaouais region of western Qu&eacute;bec, near Ottawa, is home to aerial parks where you can walk or zip line through the forest canopy, white-water rafting spots, caves, bungee jumping sites, unspoiled Gatineau Park and Omega Park (<a href="http://www.parc-omega.com" target="_blank"><span style="color: windowtext;">www.parc-omega.com</span></a>), as well as one of the largest log buildings in the world (now the Fairmont Le Ch&acirc;teau Montebello hotel).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montréal is a major meeting and convention centre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In both <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/montreal">Montreal</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/quebec-city">Quebec City</a>, although there is more English spoken in the business world than on the streets, a few words of French before switching to English will always be appreciated. Whether documents should be translated into French depends on the industry, but a translation of the executive summary would be considered a <em>beau geste</em> (good gesture). Due to the touchy political situation, it is best to avoid discussing issues of language rights or the sovereignty movement.</p>
<p>Normal business courtesies should be observed, although Canadians are generally less formal than Europeans and usually use first-names after initial introductions have been completed. When speaking French, it is best to use &lsquo;vous' until the other party uses the less formal &lsquo;tu'; after that, lapsing back into &lsquo;vous' is considered bad form.</p>
<p>Business cards are usually exchanged either at the beginning or at the end of the first meeting. Both men and women generally wear suits but short-sleeved shirts are acceptable in summer. Business hours are generally 0900-1700 weekdays but often extend to 1800 or 1900; Montrealers are not early risers, as a rule.</p>
<p>In Montreal business meals and entertaining can range from a formal hotel breakfast meeting to a night out on the town. Many Montreal business deals are clinched in a more informal social setting. In Quebec City breakfast and lunch meetings are more common than evening meetings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Québec City Tourism (Information on Conferences/Conventions in Québec)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (418) 641 6654 ,1 877 783 1608
					Website:http://www.quebecregion.com/
					Address: Québec City,399 St-Joseph Street East,Québec G1K 8E2,]]><b>Board of Trade of Metropolitan Montréal</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (514) 871 4000
					Website:http://www.ccmm.qc.caand/
					Address: 380 St Antoine Street West,Suite 6000,Montréal,]]><b>Tourisme Montréal (Information on Conferences/Conventions in Montréal)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (514) 873 2015 ,1 877 266 5687,0800 051 7055
					Website:http://www.tourisme-montreal.org/
					Address: Montréal,CP 979,Québec H3C 2W3,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Qu&eacute;bec proudly reflects a tradition of French culture, never more so than in the restaurants and cuisine of the province. As well as typically French dishes (with a Qu&eacute;becois twist), you can enjoy a wide range of global cuisines, from Italian and Greek to Vietnamese and Chinese.<br />
<br />
You might pick up a smoked meat sandwich in a corner caf&eacute; or savour fresh seafood from the Gulf of St Lawrence in a high-end bistro. In summer, food trucks cluster in pockets of Montr&eacute;al, serving everything from cr&ecirc;pes and waffles to pierogies and tacos.<br />
<br />
Many farms across the province offer tours, where you can explore vineyards, orchards and sugar bushes and enjoy the flavours of the latest crop.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Pork dishes such as<em>rago&ucirc;t de boulettes&nbsp;</em>(pork meatballs with seasoning),&nbsp;<em>cretons du Qu&eacute;bec</em> (chilled minced pork), and beans and pork baked in maple syrup.<br />
&bull; Poutine (French fries with cheese curds and gravy).<br />
&bull; Game, such as wild boar, venison, caribou and wapiti (deer).<br />
&bull;<em>Tarte au sucre</em> (maple sugar pie).<br />
&bull; <em>Galettes de sarasins</em> (buckwheat cakes).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Bars and other licensed venues can stay open daily until 0300. Government-run liquor stores (SAQ) sell a wide range of beer, wine and spirits. Beer and wine are also available in grocery stores, convenience stores (<em>d&eacute;panneurs</em>) and other retail locations. Look out for &ldquo;<em>apportezvotrevin</em>&rdquo; (&ldquo;bring your own wine&rdquo;) signs on restaurants where you can drink your own wine or beer.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It's customary to tip between 15 and 20% at bars and restaurants in Québec.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Qu&eacute;bec City and Montr&eacute;al offer some of the best nightclubs and cabarets in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a>. In Montr&eacute;al, the action seldom begins before 2200 and usually continues until 0300 the next morning. Nightlife is concentrated in the western part of the downtown area along Crescent and Bishop Streets and around Ste-Catherine Street, where there are many bars, restaurants and clubs of all kinds. For a particularly French flavour, try the many clubs, bars, restaurants, cafes and bistros further east around Saint-Laurent (often known simply as 'The Main') and Saint-Denis. In Qu&eacute;bec City, the wide boulevard called Grande All&eacute;e, just outside the old city walls, hums with activity in clubs and bars until late at night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Qu&eacute;bec City and Montr&eacute;al have excellent shopping facilities, both in large department stores and small street markets. Specialities include furs, Native American crafts, haute couture, antiques, specialist fashion boutiques and discount retail outlets.<br />
<br />
In Montr&eacute;al, Sainte-Catherine Street is home to international fashion retailers and elegant department stores, while the Plateau Mont-Royal neighbourhood is known for chic d&eacute;cor shops and quirky boutiques. In the suburbs, Carrefour Laval is one of the larger malls. In Qu&eacute;bec City, don't miss Petit-Champlain Street, a narrow, cobblestone street that is one of the oldest shopping thoroughfares in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/north-america">North America</a>. For street caricaturists and art galleries, head to Tr&eacute;sor Street.</p><p>Generally, Mon-Wed 0900-1800, Thurs-Fri 0900-2100 and Sat 0900-1700, but hours vary. Most shops are open on Sunday afternoons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the population lives in the south of the province, where all the large cities offer an extensive choice of hotel accommodation. Some of the best hotels in the country are in Montr&eacute;al and Qu&eacute;bec City, with small boutique hotels one of the fastest-growing sectors. Outside the cities, accommodation takes on a more rural flavour; lakeside lodges and cabins are very popular. Accommodation is often possible in private homes. There are also many resort properties, including several luxury casino resorts - and you can even stay in the famous Ice Hotel, just outside Qu&eacute;bec City, in winter.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> The Corporation de l'Industrie Touristique de Qu&eacute;bec, a non-profit organisation, classifies and rates accommodation (<a href="http://citq.qc.ca" target="_blank">citq.qc.ca</a>). Accommodation is awarded 1 to 5 stars according to its facilities and level of comfort, while bed &amp; breakfast establishments (<em>g&icirc;tes</em>) are awarded 1 to 5 suns for their atmosphere, architecture and welcome. The precise definition of the star allocation system varies according to the type of accommodation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous organisations in Qu&eacute;bec that provide information regarding bed &amp; breakfast accommodation, including <em>R&eacute;seau des G&icirc;tes Classifi&eacute;s</em> (<a href="http://www.gites-classifies.qc.ca" target="_blank">www.gites-classifies.qc.ca</a>) and <em>L'Association de l'Agrotourisme et du Tourisme Gourmand du Qu&eacute;bec</em> (<a href="http://www.inns-bb.com/" target="_blank">www.inns-bb.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the population lives in the south of the province, where all the large cities offer an extensive choice of hotel accommodation. Some of the best hotels in the country are in Montr&eacute;al and Qu&eacute;bec City, with small boutique hotels one of the fastest-growing sectors. Outside the cities, accommodation takes on a more rural flavour; lakeside lodges and cabins are very popular. Accommodation is often possible in private homes. There are also many resort properties, including several luxury casino resorts - and you can even stay in the famous Ice Hotel, just outside Qu&eacute;bec City, in winter.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> The Corporation de l'Industrie Touristique de Qu&eacute;bec, a non-profit organisation, classifies and rates accommodation (<a href="http://citq.qc.ca" target="_blank">citq.qc.ca</a>). Accommodation is awarded 1 to 5 stars according to its facilities and level of comfort, while bed &amp; breakfast establishments (<em>g&icirc;tes</em>) are awarded 1 to 5 suns for their atmosphere, architecture and welcome. The precise definition of the star allocation system varies according to the type of accommodation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the population lives in the south of the province, where all the large cities offer an extensive choice of hotel accommodation. Some of the best hotels in the country are in Montr&eacute;al and Qu&eacute;bec City, with small boutique hotels one of the fastest-growing sectors. Outside the cities, accommodation takes on a more rural flavour; lakeside lodges and cabins are very popular. Accommodation is often possible in private homes. There are also many resort properties, including several luxury casino resorts - and you can even stay in the famous Ice Hotel, just outside Qu&eacute;bec City, in winter.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> The Corporation de l'Industrie Touristique de Qu&eacute;bec, a non-profit organisation, classifies and rates accommodation (<a href="http://citq.qc.ca" target="_blank">citq.qc.ca</a>). Accommodation is awarded 1 to 5 stars according to its facilities and level of comfort, while bed &amp; breakfast establishments (<em>g&icirc;tes</em>) are awarded 1 to 5 suns for their atmosphere, architecture and welcome. The precise definition of the star allocation system varies according to the type of accommodation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Quebec observes all the Public Holidays observed nationwide (see the general <em>Canada</em><em> </em>section).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[46.802071]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-71.244926]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,542,056 sq km (595,391 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>8.16 million (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Qu&eacute;bec City.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The province of Qu&eacute;bec is in the east of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a>, with coasts on the North Atlantic and Hudson and James Bays. The St Lawrence Seaway, the major shipping channel of the Canadian east coast, cuts through the populous south; the cities of Qu&eacute;bec and Montr&eacute;al (Canada's second-largest city) stand beside it. In the north, the Laurentians resort area has snow-covered mountains in winter and scenic lakes. The far north is a spread of forest and lakes forming one of the largest areas of wilderness in Canada.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chic cities, eye-catching landscapes and welcoming people, passionate about their heritage: Qu&eacute;bec has created a French-North American cocktail, and it tastes good.</p>
<p>Canada&rsquo;s largest province encompasses vast tracts of barren mountains, 13,323km (8,279 miles) of coastline, looming canyons and craggy fjords. Thrilling sights grab you at every turn as you explore this mainly French-speaking region, where you can swim with beluga whales in Saguenay Fjord, visit 400-year-old clifftop houses on the Chemin du Roy and spot herds of caribou roaming the Parc National des Grands-Jardins.</p>
<p>Alternatively, you could don the Lycra and pedal around La Route Verte, an immense 5,000km (3,100 miles) network of cycle trails, which take riders through the pretty villages of the Eastern Townships, along the stunning coast of Lac Saint-Jean and down the disused Laurentides railway.</p>
<p>Qu&eacute;bec is a giant water park: there are countless sandy beaches, lakes and rivers for swimming; the St Lawrence River is a magnet for kayakers, who also have a phenomenal number of inland waterways to choose from, such as the Bonaventure River in the Gasp&eacute; Peninsula.</p>
<p>Hikers can enjoy 100km (62 miles) of mountainous trails on the Travers&eacute;e de Charlevoix or trek Qu&eacute;bec&rsquo;s portion of the International Appalachian Trail. In winter, skiers rip up the slopes at Mont Tremblant.</p>
<p>Craving city action? Hip and happening Montreal is an alluring blend of glitzy skyscrapers and historic cobblestone quarters, with cosmopolitan neighbourhoods and a buzzing cultural scene. As for UNESCO-listed Qu&eacute;bec City, you can have a ball diving in and out of tiny eateries and bijou boutiques tucked among the fortified city&rsquo;s 17th-century alleyways.</p><p>Chic cities, eye-catching landscapes and welcoming people, passionate about their heritage: Qu&eacute;bec has created a French-North American cocktail, and it tastes good.&nbsp;Thrilling sights grab you at every turn as you explore this mainly French-speaking region, where you can swim with beluga whales in Saguenay Fjord, visit 400-year-old clifftop houses on the Chemin du Roy and spot herds of caribou roaming the Parc National des Grands-Jardins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
