<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Cayman Islands" ColCode="cym" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ky" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Cayman Islands]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Cayman Islands enjoy a very warm, tropical climate throughout the year, with temperatures that can reach highs of up 33°C (91°F) during the summer, moderated by trade winds. The best time to visit is during the dry months of December to April, when temperatures are generally cooler than in summer, hovering between 22°C (72°F) and 27°C (80°F).  The rainy season is from May to October but showers are generally short and sharp (ie lasting hours rather than days); these can provide temporary respite from the hot summer sun. July and August are the hottest months, whilst the hurricane season is from June to November. Since the islands are low-lying, there is a high risk of flooding if a storm hits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>During the dry season, wear lightweight, natural fabrics; temperatures rarely dip below 21°C (70°F), so you shouldn't need anything much heavier than this. A good strategy is to take layers, so that you can be ready for cooler conditions should the trade winds blow strongly. During the rainy season, bring a light raincoat or umbrella. Warmer clothes may be needed on cooler evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Grand Cayman is connected to Cayman Brac and Little Cayman by internal flights run by Cayman Airways Express (<a href="http://www.caymanairways.com" target="_blank">www.caymanairways.com</a>) and the charter company Island Air (<a href="http://www.islandair.ky" target="_blank">www.islandair.ky</a>). Services to the Sister Islands are regular and fares are kept low as a result. Travel between Grand Cayman and the Brac/Little Cayman is around 30 minutes and about 10 minutes between the Brac and Little Cayman. Blink and you&rsquo;ll miss it. It is virtually impossible to travel to the Sister Islands except by air.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to sail round the islands to your destination. Leisure trips to Stingray City and Rum Point by sail or motor boat are privately run. Anyone can navigate on the water, with the exception of shipping lanes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving on-island can be a hairy experience; with so many different nationalities present in Cayman (over 100), that means over 100 different experiences of road rules and a Wild-West feel. Keep your wits about you, drive at your own pace (and on the left) and you&rsquo;ll be OK. The worst thing about car drivers on-island is that both left-hand drive and right-hand drive vehicles are present. Even the police have their driving seats on the &lsquo;wrong&rsquo; side of much of their fleet!</p>l<p>By Caribbean standards, the roads throughout Cayman are of excellent quality. Beware of potholes on smaller roads. The roads often flood during Caribbean downpours but are astonishingly well drained and within hours will be dry again. Everywhere is accessible by car.</p><p>Grand Cayman does have a number of bus routes to all points on the island, nearly all during the daylight hours. These are operated by individuals and run to and from the bus depot in the centre of George Town. There are bus stops, but you can often pick up a bus anywhere just by hailing them down as you would a taxi. Indeed, the drivers ask you via a quick beep of the horn whether you require their services &ndash; and it&rsquo;s not unknown for an empty bus going in the wrong direction to pick you up and go back on themselves.</p><p>There are taxis operating on Grand Cayman from all resorts, the cruise dock at George Town and the international airport. They offer a fixed rate per vehicle or per person to all points on the island. A sign with current rates is posted at the cruise ship dock in George Town. Taxis in Cayman Brac are limited, and best pre-booked.</p>
<p>Be wary of rogue operators; if you are staying in one of the major hotels, ask them to book in advance and agree a price before going anywhere. Most taxis are extremely reliable and the operators honest, but horror stories of $100 journeys are not unknown either.</p><p>A temporary local driving licence is required, which is issued from the police station or car-hire agency at a nominal charge on presentation of a valid licence from your country of origin.</p><p>Drivers must be over 21 years of age. Strictly enforced speed limits are generally 40-48kph (25-30mph) in built-up areas, 64kph (40mph) outside these, and - on Grand Cayman - 80kph (50mph) in rural areas east of Bodden Town. The National Roads Authority (<a href="http://www.caymanroads.com" target="_blank">www.caymanroads.com</a>) has further information.</p>
<p>Seat belts must be worn at all times. Full insurance is required and must be arranged with the car-hire company; some companies will not insure drivers under 25. It is an offence to use a mobile phone to call or text while in control of a vehicle. Hands-free sets are, however, allowed. Do not use your phone at a red light &ndash; even if you have stopped there you will be ticketed.</p><p>Cayman&rsquo;s Auto Club (<a href="http://www.autoclub.ky" target="_blank">www.autoclub.ky</a>) offers 24-hour roadside assistance for members &ndash; otherwise it&rsquo;s going to be a pricy garage callout. There are numerous garages on island for everything from major repairs to replacement tyres.</p><p>In Grand Cayman, most major car-hire companies are represented at the airport or in George Town. Private limousine services are available for special events and airport transfers. You can also hire cars on Little Cayman and Cayman Brac. Insurance is a must. Cars range from the smallest compacts to large SUVs and, increasingly, electric vehicles. There are also classic cars available for special occasions.</p>
<p>As with most things on-island, rates are higher in the winter high season which runs roughly from mid-November to early May. You must be over 21 and hold a valid driving licence. You may need a special visitor permit which will be charged at the hire office.</p><p>Mopeds, scooters and bicycles are available for hire on all three islands. Motorcyclists are required by law to wear a helmet at all times. On Cayman Brac and Little Cayman, most hotels have bicycles available for complimentary guest use.</p>
<p>Bicycles aren&rsquo;t generally the preferred method of travel on Grand Cayman, although a number of brave souls do take their future in their hands amidst the enormous motor vehicles prevalent on the island.</p>
<p>The Sister Islands are arguably best-seen by bike &ndash; but remember, in Little Cayman, iguanas have right of way!</p><p>Drivers must be over 21 years of age. Strictly enforced speed limits are generally 40-48kph (25-30mph) in built-up areas, 64kph (40mph) outside these, and - on Grand Cayman - 80kph (50mph) in rural areas east of Bodden Town. The National Roads Authority (<a href="http://www.caymanroads.com" target="_blank">www.caymanroads.com</a>) has further information.</p>
<p>Seat belts must be worn at all times. Full insurance is required and must be arranged with the car-hire company; some companies will not insure drivers under 25. It is an offence to use a mobile phone to call or text while in control of a vehicle. Hands-free sets are, however, allowed. Do not use your phone at a red light &ndash; even if you have stopped there you will be ticketed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cars rule the roost on Grand Cayman, with buses up and down the popular Seven Mile Strip entertainment and bar district particularly numerous. Walking in the height of the day under the blazing sun is not recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cayman Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">west_bay</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cayman Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">rum_point</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cayman Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">little_cayman</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cayman Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cayman_brac</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Cayman Airways (<a href="http://www.caymanairways.com" target="_blank">www.caymanairways.com</a>).  Services include <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/havana">Havana</a>, La Ceiba, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a> and&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tampa">Tampa</a>, plus seasonal flights to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chicago">Chicago</a>.</p>
<p>British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) flies to the Cayman Islands via Nassau. Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>), JetBlue (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>), United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) and Air Canada are other major carriers to Cayman, many of whom also run seasonal flights. Inter-island travel is handled by Cayman Airways Express.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 4 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saturdays can see significant congestion at the airport due to its relatively small size compared to the amount of flights; be prepared to wait (bring water, sunscreen and a hat &ndash; sometimes the lines can stretch outside, which isn&rsquo;t much fun at 1400 under a blazing Caribbean sun).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saturdays can see significant congestion at the airport due to its relatively small size compared to the amount of flights; be prepared to wait (bring water, sunscreen and a hat &ndash; sometimes the lines can stretch outside, which isn&rsquo;t much fun at 1400 under a blazing Caribbean sun).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cayman Brac Charles Kirkconnell International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.caymanairports.ky<p>The airport is 3km (2 miless) from the main tourist accommodation in the southwest.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Grand Cayman Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.caymanairports.com<p>The airport is 2km (1 mile) east of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/george-town">George Town</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Grand Cayman is one of the most popular Caribbean ports and a busy port of call for leading international cruise lines operating from North America, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico">Mexico</a> and Europe. Grand Cayman&rsquo;s port (<a href="http://www.caymanport.com" target="_blank">www.caymanport.com</a>) is situated in the capital, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/george-town">George Town</a>. By day it handles cruise ships, then by night it switches over to cargo only.</p>
<p>Ships may also dock at the Royal Watler cruise terminal, which is a rather gaudy mess of tourist shops, tour operators peddling their wares and often steel band music to welcome visitors. However, in contrast to other Caribbean destinations, it's kept free of hawkers and unlicensed operators (outside the terminal is a different matter, of course).</p>
<p>Occasionally you will see mega-yachts anchored off shore; these huge ships are more than capable of handling the choppy waters over the reef. Sailing trips to Cayman are rare, mostly because of the deep water, but private boats are very well served.</p>
<p>The George Town Barcadere marina (<a href="http://www.barcadere.com" target="_blank">www.barcadere.com</a>) is a brand new, world-class and environmentally-friendly marina located on the North Sound coastline and adjacent to the airport. There are more than 80 slips and it can handle ships up to 40m (130ft) in length, with a maximum draft of 2.4m (8ft). A chandlery, showroom, boatyard, restaurant (with Wi-Fi) and more are available.</p><p>Ships currently tender passengers to shore but conversations have been ongoing for nearly 20 years about potential development of a cruise dock to enable the country to handle the largest Oasis-class cruise ships.</p>
<p>There are sometimes long waits to re-board the tenders for the cruise ships which the country is addressing by providing additional shade.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Land lines are in use on the island, and it's also possible to buy pre-paid phonecards to make calls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a few international mobile phone companies and coverage is surprisingly good on Grand Cayman – it may waver a little on Little Cayman and Cayman Brac. Buying sim cards from local vendors at the malls is relatively simple, and usually much cheaper than paying for international calls on your domestic tariff.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many internet cafes throughout the Cayman Islands and most hotels also offer internet facilities; although this may be dial-up rather than a broadband connection. Wi-Fi access is also available in some hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The <em>Cayman Net News </em>and <em>Caymanian Compass </em>are published daily. Four TV stations are on the air in the Caymans, two of them run by religious organisations. Cayman 27 is a private TV station, whilst cable and satellite are also popular with the islanders. Private radio station Z99 and government-owned Radio Cayman, which operates two networks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It takes from 7 to 10 days for mail sent from the Cayman Islands to arrive in the UK via airmail. For mail sent to the US takes 5 to 8 days. Blue mail collection boxes are at key points around Grand Cayman. The main post office is on Edward Street and Cardinal Avenue in George Town. There are various branches across the islands, including at the West Shore Centre on West Bay Road. Stamps are available in most shops and hotels.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1530, Sat 0830-1130.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Camana Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Restaurants, events, shopping, movies, music, business, fashion, sports, school – it's all here at a bespoke-built new town of Camana Bay (<a href="http://www.camanabay.com" target="_blank">www.camanabay.com</a>) which is ever growing. The 200 hectares (500 acres) of this extraordinary project are beautifully-designed from scratch. The effect is of a high-end, safe small US town where everything is within walking distance. You won't believe you're in the Caribbean when you stroll along the Paseo. The master plan is a multi-decade, multi-million pound project by Dart Realty.</p>]]><p><b>Cayman Brac caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Bluff that runs along the centre of Cayman Brac is riddled with caves, many of them with tales to tell about the islanders who have sheltered there during hurricanes. One of the popular ones is Bat Cave, which for obvious reasons, is a photo opportunity in the making.</p>]]><p><b>Cayman Motor museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Believe it or not, Grand Cayman is home to the original Batmobile – one of nearly 90 cars at the privately-owned Cayman Motor museum (<a href="http://www.caymanmotormuseum.com" target="_blank">www.caymanmotormuseum.com</a>). There's also one of the first cars ever produced, an 1886 Mercedes-Benz. Well worth a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Cayman Turtle Farm</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At this commercial turtle farm visitors can watch sea turtles at various stages of their development. There's also an artificial predator reef, a snorkelling lagoon, an aviary, a crocodile and a cultural centre. The farm has come under much fire for its high levels of government subsidy each year and there have also been doubts cast over the living conditions for the turtles. Ironically, even whilst you admire these noble, ancient creatures, you can do so from the Turtle Farm's own bar and restaurant – which serves turtle steaks, turtle burgers and turtle stew.</p>]]><p><b>Experience the Atlantis Submarine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Delve beneath the deep completely wetsuit-free with the Atlantis Submarine (<a href="http://www.atlantisadventures.com/" target="_blank">www.atlantisadventures.com</a>), which offers hour-long trips to view the spectacular reefs. The submarine is fully kitted out for tourists and is unsinkable, fully-pressurised and suitable for all ages. It's a great way to get under the water without the hassle, expense and restrictions of gaining your PADI dive qualification.</p>]]><p><b>Go Booby-spotting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Booby Pond on Little Cayman, which hosts the world's largest colony of red-footed boobies. A natural, land-locked saltwater lagoon, it also has Magnificent Frigatebirds nesting around and was designated as a Wetland of International Significance in 1994. The visitor's centre is built in traditional Cayman style and is home to the National Trust. Over on the Brac, there's the Parrot Reserve which is home to the endangered Cayman Brac parrot. The Sister Islands are also home to the equally-endangered Rock Iguana.</p>]]><p><b>Go fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The deep waters surrounding Grand Cayman are prime fishing grounds, offering various species of large fish. The annual International Fishing Tournament (<a href="http://www.fishcayman.com/" target="_blank">www.fishcayman.com</a>) takes place in April.</p>]]><p><b>Hell</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go to Hell and back - literally. The peculiar rock formations of this area of Grand Cayman have evolved from shells and corals solidified by salt and lime deposits. A close examination reveals petrified forms of sea life that could be up to 20 million years old. There is a post office there which has one of the most unique local area stamps you will find. Look out for the devil himself – aka local shop owner, Ivan Farrington, replete in flame-red costume.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the Mastic Trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike through the mangrove swamps and ancient forest along Grand Cayman's Mastic Trail (<a href="http://www.nationaltrust.org.ky/" target="_blank">www.nationaltrust.org.ky</a>), linking Frank Sound to Old Man Bay. The trail dates back to the 18th century and passes through a variety of flora and fauna. This protected area represents some of the last remaining examples of Caribbean subtropical forest.  You may spot a native Cayman Green Parrot, Caribbean Dove, West Indian Woopdpecker, butterflies, lizards, frogs and more. Special tours are available and the trail takes approximately three hours. You will need to be reasonably fit to join this pedestrian route.</p>]]><p><b>Miss Lassie’s House</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This remarkable traditional Cayman home was the dwelling of one Gladwyn 'Miss Lassie' Bush, who began painting at age 62 after she had experienced a vision. Walls, windows, canvas are adorned with her intuitive art, which includes Biblical scenes as well as purely abstract patterns. The South Sound house is free to visit and tours of the wattle and daub house are available.</p>]]><p><b>Mission House</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In historic Bodden Town, which was Cayman's first capital, lies Mission House. It now serves as a museum portraying the history of the house, which was instrumental in bringing missionaries, teachers and more in the early years of the country. A historic – and beautiful - building in its own right, it is kept beautifully by the National Trust. Tours are available.</p>]]><p><b>National Gallery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Local, American and British art is on display at the National Gallery of the Cayman Islands (<a href="http://www.nationalgallery.org.ky/" target="_blank">www.nationalgallery.org.ky</a>) in George Town. Now situated in an impressive multimillion pound new building, the gallery also puts on numerous events, openings, films, lectures and more.</p>]]><p><b>National Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn the history of the islands in The Cayman Islands National Museum (<a href="http://www.museum.ky/" target="_blank">www.museum.ky</a>), George Town, where there are interactive exhibits and a good shop. The museum itself is a listed building which has over the years been used as a government house, prison and schoolhouse.</p>]]><p><b>Pedro St James</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This early 19th century plantation great house (<a href="http://www.pedrostjames.ky/" target="_blank">www.pedrostjames.ky</a>) and is set in beautiful grounds by the sea in Savannah. The oldest building in the Cayman Islands, it was the site of the 1831 proclamation ending slavery in the islands. It is also the 'birthplace of democracy' where the first governments sat. Pedro St. James is very popular for weddings and special events, including live music.</p>]]><p><b>Reef diving the Kittiwake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cayman's offshore reefs and walls - including Little Cayman's Bloody Bay Wall - are world renowned for diving (<a href="http://www.divecayman.ky/" target="_blank">www.divecayman.ky</a>). Various locations also offer wreck diving, particularly Cayman Brac, where a Russian warship was intentionally sunk in the late 1990s.</p><p>At the top end of Seven Mile Beach/North West Point lies the<em> Kittiwake</em>, an extraordinary 77m- (251ft-) vessel deliberately sunk in 2011 to serve as a dive site and artificial reef. The site is run by the Cayman Islands Tourism Association. It's both diver- and snorkeller-friendly, with excellent dive-throughs of the hyperbaric chambers, muster decks, crew quarters and a sense of grandeur. Ironically, the<em> Kittwake</em> originally served as a submarine rescue vessel.</p>]]><p><b>Seven Mile Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The turquoise waters of Grand Cayman's West Bay are backed by the long, sandy Seven Mile Beach, and, while this is the main tourist centre and highly developed, this glorious stretch of coast retains its idyllic charms. As with all beaches in the Cayman Islands, the land up to the high water mark is public. Beware, therefore, of bars or restaurants asking for fees to use their beach. Hiring their loungers, yes. Paying for public beach? No deal. Snorkelling is wonderful in the stretch outside the Marriott hotel.</p>]]><p><b>Snorkelling at Stingray City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Snorkel alongside southern stingrays at Stingray City in North Sound on Grand Cayman. These shallow waters are home to a profusion of stingrays and visitors can get right up close with these otherworldly, gentle creatures. As the story goes, when fishermen of yore cleaned their catch, they'd throw the unwanted innards overboard. Over a number of years, the stingrays came to associate the noise of the returning boats with a free feed and as a consequence both Deep Stingray City (near the reef) and the Sandbar have become popular sites for tourists. The stingrays aren't tame but are very used to visitors. They do have a barb which can sting if they are scared or provoked. Be aware that lifting them out of the water is considered cruel; stroke them gently along their fins and you'll get on just fine. They don't bite, but might leave you with a hard-to-explain hickey if you get too close. It is possible to feed them by hand.</p>]]><p><b>Surfing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Need to polish up your board skills before hitting the beach? Learn to surf in a wave tank at Black Pearl Skate and Surf (<a href="http://www.blackpearl.ky" target="_blank">www.blackpearl.ky</a>), in Grand Harbour. Waves aren't going to be six-footers in Cayman because of the reef, but there are plenty of spots in the right weather.</p>]]><p><b>Wander Queen Elizabeth II Botanic Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wander around the Queen Elizabeth II Botanic Park (<a href="http://www.botanic-park.ky/" target="_blank">www.botanic-park.ky</a>), a 26-hectare (65-acre) heritage garden boasting a vivid array of cacti, shrubs and native flowers. The park has become the focus of a highly successful conservation programme to protect the endangered Cayman blue iguana which is constantly threatened both by new development leading to habitat loss and the invasive, non-indigenous, bigger, brasher green iguana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$2.6bn (2012)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Financial services, turtle products, salt, rum products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, food, fuel.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, UK, Canada and Caribbean Community (CARICOM) countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Cayman Islands have no direct taxation and have become important as an offshore financial centre. Good communications and infrastructure have also helped the islands become the world's fifth-largest banking centre. A key agreement on information exchange signed with the US government has spared the Cayman Islands many of the problems (money laundering and large-scale tax avoidance) that have bedevilled other aspirant offshore financial centres. Cayman continues to sign similar agreements with other destinations.<br/><br/>Tourism is the islands' other main source of revenue. There is little agriculture, and most food for the islands is imported. Staples such as breadfruit, beef, tomatoes, chillies, calaloo, mangoes (in season) and seasoning peppers are always available. Exports of rum cake, rum and some of the local beer (Caybrew) contribute to the economy. Construction is a growth industry and medical tourism is expected to grow into the third pillar for the economy.</p><p>A Special Economic Zone – Cayman Enterprise City - has been initially established for technology, finance and education investments. It is currently situated in George Town but a bricks-and-mortar bespoke city in the Savannah area is planned. The Cayman Islands have associate membership of at the Caribbean Common Market (CARICOM).</p><p>The standard of living on the islands is one of the highest in the world, and the per capita income is the highest in the region. The healthy state of the economy and the rapid development of tourism have attracted migrant workers from all over the world including Jamaica, Europe,  the Philipines and North America.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business suits are recommended when calling on senior officials and local heads of business and also for semi-formal or formal functions. Exchange of business cards is usual. It is generally easy to gain access to offices of senior government officials, politicians and business executives. Civil servants are excluded from accepting gifts, except for diaries or calendars at Christmas. Monetary gifts or expensive presents are not encouraged in the private sector.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700. Some establishments are open on Saturday mornings, but virtually nothing is open on Sundays aside from petrol stations, a number of smaller mom and pop stores and hotel shops. Note that liquor stores are open for limited hours, although this has changed recently. It is however possible to buy off sales from most bars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cayman Islands Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 949 8090.
					Website:http://www.caymanchamber.ky
					Address: ,Macdonald Square, 2nd Floor,Grand Cayman KY 1-1102,PO Box 1000]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>For a Caribbean island, the food and drink options available in Cayman are extraordinarily varied, ranging from jerk chicken stands (try the one on Shedden Road) to five-star international dining and everything in between. The islands have for a while striven to be named the 'Culinary Capital of the Caribbean' and it seems as though the ploy is working.</p><p>As there are over 100 nationalities resident in Cayman, this is also reflected in the varied cuisine available. There are two major food festivals at the start of the year and during special events there are always local stands serving a wide range of eats. Look out also for low-season offers and seasonal produce of extremely high quality. Magazines covering the foodie scene are <em>Flava</em> and <em>Food and Drink</em>, which come out roughly quarterly.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>• Jerk chicken (chicken marinated in spices which may or may not be head-blowingly hot – and barbecued.)<br/>• Rice and peas.<br/>• <em>Moros y cristianos</em> (black beans and rice).<br/>• Fried plantain.<br/>• Conch, including fritters, stew, ceviche and chowder (often it's best served  in a fresh ceviche as out of season, some places may use frozen, rubbery conch in the fritters which is pretty awful).<br/>• Lobster.<br/>• Turtle stew and turtle steaks.<br/>• Dolphin (this is the local name for mahi-mahi, a firm white fish).<br/>• Fresh fish (local varieties include wahoo, snapper, tuna and red lionfish).<br/>• Local mangoes (there are seven varieties in season).<br/>• Seasoning pepper (these have all the flavour of Scotch Bonnet chillies but none of the heat).<br/>• Cayman Gourmet Pepper Jelly (a delicious sauce made in small batches by hand, and delicious).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>An unusual menu item is often the Red Lionfish, which is an invasive species that threatens the delicate ecosystem of the reefs due to its lack of natural predators. A programme of culling is under way and luckily the fish is rather delicious, a kind of firm white fish that lends itself to many different dishes.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Restaurant bills usually include a 10-15% charge in lieu of tipping. Of course, extras are always welcomed by the staff who often are on a very low hourly rate, making their money up by tips. At a bar, aim to give CI$1 per drink/round to bartenders. You won't lose out; most bars don't have measuring cups so being nice to the person serving your drinks will more often than not, have you drinking generous measures before long.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Seven Mile Strip is the most lively part of Grand Cayman for the visitor, with numerous bars, clubs, restaurants and beach bars catering for tourists. Locals tend to go to the George Town bars for their entertainment, which can make for an interesting experience. A comedy and variety club is situated in the Strand. Most bars have DJs and/or live music at the weekends and often midweek too. Keep an eye out for pub quizzes in aid of the Cayman Islands Humane Society, usually taking place at the excellently-named Irish pub Fidel Murphy's.</p><p>Music is varied and clubs offer everything from live DJs to salsa, reggae, calypso and disco. Concerts and theatre productions (<a href="http://www.artscayman.org/" target="_blank">www.artscayman.org</a>) are staged at the Harquail Theatre, off West Bay Road, and the Prospect Playhouse, Red Bay. There is also a multi-screen cinema in Camana Bay.</p><p>Dinner cruises onboard a replica pirate ship or a 19th-century tall ship can be booked through local watersports operators. On Cayman Brac there are occasional weekend dances with local bands and community events, such as talent shows and other stage productions, at the Aston Rutty Center.</p><p>Local publications with nightlife information include <em>Key To Cayman</em>, <em>What's Hot</em>, <em>What to Do</em>, <em>Destination Cayman</em> and Friday's edition of the <em>Caymanian Compass</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>George Town is a mecca for those in search of duty-free goods, and also offers numerous small boutiques. Local products such as jewellery made of Caymanite (the islands' semi-precious stone), hand-woven baskets, hats and fans, colourful paintings and underwater photographs make excellent souvenirs.  Local foods, including tropical fruits, can be bought or sampled at the Farmers' Market every Wednesday at Camana Bay, other days around the island, stalls along the roads toward the East End and particularly Saturday mornings at the Agricultural Grounds in Lower Valley.</p><p>The Tortuga Rum company specialises in rum and rum cake plus a range of delicious hot sauces of various styles. The Cayman Spirits Company is a relatively new addition to the rum world, being behind Seven Fathoms (which is apparently matured at a secret location seven fathoms under the sea) and the Governors' range of spirits. Blackbeard's also has its own range of spirits including Cayluha – a witty pun on the famous chocolate liquor.</p><p>Camana Bay is the main place that offers North American and European fashion brands, furnishings and household goods. Many luxury goods and essential food products are duty-free but duty of up to 20% is charged on other items. George Town still has boutiques and lots of duty-free stores.</p><p>Local art and crafts are available from a number of places including Cayman Craft Market, situated on the waterfront in George Town, the Royal Watler Cruise Terminal and Pure Art Gallery & Gifts, a lovely traditional Cayman house to the south of the capital.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1700. During peak tourist season, many shops open later and also open on Sundays. Supermarkets and liquor stores are closed on Sundays.</p><p>Turtle products cannot be imported, even by persons in transit, into any country which has signed the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species. This includes the USA, Canada and the UK. Caymanite cannot be taken out of the country in its raw form.</p><p>Enterprising stores taking advantage of Cayman's confused licensing laws have pushed the boundaries between bar, liquor store and hotel shop, which obviates the need to stock up before 1900 on a Saturday for wine and beer. Supermarkets do not have liquor licenses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The leading hotels are located on the coast. Some of the best-known overlook Grand Cayman's Seven Mile Beach: a dazzling stretch of fine powdery sand said to be one of the world's most beautiful beaches. Hotels providing accommodation with 100 rooms are considered large in the Cayman Islands, and are generally only found only on Grand Cayman. Visitors don't have to stay in a behemoth luxury resort however; there are more boutique retreats available too.<br/><br/>Prices are seasonal; the high season begins in mid-December and usually runs through to mid-April. During that time, visitors should expect to pay up to 50% more for a room, peaking over the Christmas and New Year period. A 10% government accommodation tax is payable to the hotel on departure. Most also add a service charge of around 10%.<br/><br/><strong>Grading: </strong>A government board of control monitors accommodation standards. Hotels vary in standard, from luxury (very comfortable, with some outstanding features) to tourist class (budget hotel).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are very few B&Bs or guesthouses on the islands, as the majority of visitors opt for hotel accommodation. The Shangri-La on Grand Cayman is one of the most luxurious examples on the islands, whilst Walton's Mango Manor is the only B&B on Cayman Brac. The standard varies from charmingly rustic to low-key luxury, and are perfect for a relaxing break – just don't expect the same in terms of facilities and mod-cons as at the larger hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The leading hotels are located on the coast. Some of the best-known overlook Grand Cayman's Seven Mile Beach: a dazzling stretch of fine powdery sand said to be one of the world's most beautiful beaches. Hotels providing accommodation with 100 rooms are considered large in the Cayman Islands, and are generally only found only on Grand Cayman. Visitors don't have to stay in a behemoth luxury resort however; there are more boutique retreats available too.<br/><br/>Prices are seasonal; the high season begins in mid-December and usually runs through to mid-April. During that time, visitors should expect to pay up to 50% more for a room, peaking over the Christmas and New Year period. A 10% government accommodation tax is payable to the hotel on departure. Most also add a service charge of around 10%.<br/><br/><strong>Grading: </strong>A government board of control monitors accommodation standards. Hotels vary in standard, from luxury (very comfortable, with some outstanding features) to tourist class (budget hotel).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The leading hotels are located on the coast. Some of the best-known overlook Grand Cayman's Seven Mile Beach: a dazzling stretch of fine powdery sand said to be one of the world's most beautiful beaches. Hotels providing accommodation with 100 rooms are considered large in the Cayman Islands, and are generally only found only on Grand Cayman. Visitors don't have to stay in a behemoth luxury resort however; there are more boutique retreats available too.<br/><br/>Prices are seasonal; the high season begins in mid-December and usually runs through to mid-April. During that time, visitors should expect to pay up to 50% more for a room, peaking over the Christmas and New Year period. A 10% government accommodation tax is payable to the hotel on departure. Most also add a service charge of around 10%.<br/><br/><strong>Grading: </strong>A government board of control monitors accommodation standards. Hotels vary in standard, from luxury (very comfortable, with some outstanding features) to tourist class (budget hotel).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Modern medical facilities are available on Grand Cayman and Cayman Brac, including government- and privately-operated hospitals. There is also an island-wide, 24-hour 911 (or 555) emergency service. There are pharmacies across on Grand Cayman and Cayman Brac; however, these may be limited in the range and volume of supplies, so if you require certain drugs it's generally best to stock up before travelling. Private dental clinics are also available, and Cayman has a nascent medical tourism industry; however caution is strongly advised before proceeding down this route. There is no national health service, and even the most remedial medical treatment is expensive. Private insurance is recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;In general, eating and drinking on the Cayman Islands doesn't require any special precautions. As in most of the Caribbean, seafood is practically a staple, so take care to ensure that any dishes you eat are being made with fresh, hygienically prepared ingredients; dishes such as ceviche are generally fine if made with very fresh ingredients, but can be harmful if not. Be aware that some tropical fish may contain toxins and in particular, barracuda should never be eaten. It is fine to drink tap water in the Cayman Islands as the water is perfectly sterilised. Eating tropical fruit and vegetables is part of the delight of being in the Caribbean, but take care to stick to ripe, fresh fruits.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations for tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Occasional cases of dengue fever have been reported.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Ash Wednesday :
							14 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Discovery Day :
							21 May </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							11 June </p><p>Constitution Day :
							02 July </p><p>Remembrance Day :
							12 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into the Cayman Islands by persons over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits or 4L of wine or 1 case of beer (up to 8L).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include illegal drugs, obscene publications or articles, any goods or items depicting or referring to marijuana, counterfeit money, gambling devices, turtles, turtle meat and turtle products, firearms and ammunition (unless licensed by the Commissioner of Police), bows, pellet guns and catapults, and spear guns.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include plants, fruit, vegetables and meat, which require an import permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lobster, conch or conch meat (unless in transit), and turtles, turtle meat and turtle products.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cayman Islands Dollar (KYD; symbol CI$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of CI$100, 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.<br/><br/>The Cayman Islands Dollar is tied to the US Dollar at a fixed rate of CI$1 = US$1.2 although bank charges for currency exchange may result in minor fluctuations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollars circulate freely and are the best currency to exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are widely accepted. ATMs accepting Visa, MasterCard and cards with Cirrus affiliation are located at banks on Grand Cayman and Cayman Brac. Take care to inform your bank that you will be using your card abroad, before you travel.</p><p>ATMs are widespread and most cardholders shouldn't have too much trouble withdrawing cash. Grand Cayman has the most extensive network of ATMs. Fees for foreign currency transactions may be charged; these vary from bank to bank so ask yours before travelling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Readily accepted. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0900-1600, Fri 0900-1630. Some banks are open on Saturday mornings. Hours may be shorter on Little Cayman and Cayman Brac.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals referred to in the chart above require a<strong>&nbsp;</strong>passport valid for six months beyond the length of stay in the Cayman Islands, except:</p>
<p><strong>1. </strong>Canadian citizens,&nbsp;who can instead present proof of citizenship, such as a birth certificate together with a photo driver's licence, plus a return or onward ticket. If travelling via the USA however, you must carry a passport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single- and multiple-entry visas are available. British embassies charge &pound;115 for receiving, handling and forwarding visa applications for British Overseas Territories.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: three months; multiple-entry visa: one, two or three years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Consulate (or consular section at embassy), Embassy or High Commission. UK residents requiring a visa (this does not include British nationals) should apply to the Home Office in the UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least 14 days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[19.511030]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-80.604983]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>260 sq km (100 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>60,764 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>215.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>George Town.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British overseas territory and parliamentary democracy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Cayman Islands are situated in the Caribbean, around 440km (270 miles) northwest of Jamaica, 390km (240 miles) south of Cuba and 640km (400 miles) south of Miami. At around 197 sq km (76 sq miles) Grand Cayman is the largest and most populous island in this British overseas territory. Little Cayman and Cayman Brac lie around 130km (80 miles) northeast of Grand Cayman and are separated from each other by a channel about 16km (10 miles) wide.</p>
<p>The islands are peaks of a very deep subterranean mountain range called Cayman Ridge, which extends from Cuba towards the Gulf of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/honduras">Honduras</a>. All three islands are situated in some of the deepest waters in the Caribbean; the Cayman Trough which separates them from Jamaica reaches a depth of 6.4km (4 miles). The islands themselves are relatively low-lying, with the highest point on Grand Cayman reaching only 18m (60ft) above sea level. The Bluff, a magnificent limestone peak on Cayman Brac is the highest point on all three islands, reaching an elevation of 43m (140ft).</p>
<p>The beaches on the Cayman Islands are considered some of the very best in the Caribbean, the most notable one being Seven Mile Beach on Grand Cayman. Casuarinas and sea-grape trees line many of the beaches, many of which are protected offshore by a fringing reef.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christianity is the predominant religion with the denominations of Anglican, Catholicism, Baptist, and Presbyterian all represented on the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Life on the Cayman Islands is a blend of local traditions and of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> and British patterns of behaviour. Handshaking is the usual greeting; hugging and kissing is for friends and family only. Because of the large number of people with a similar surname (such as Ebanks and Bodden), a person may be introduced by his first name (such as Mr Tom or Mr Jim). Flowers are acceptable as a gift on arrival or following a visit for a meal.</p><p>Most modes of dress are acceptable, although it is normal to prescribe a dress code on invitations. Save your beachwear for the actual beach however, as wearing skimpy clothing, or going without a shirt, in restaurants or bars will be frowned upon. Topless bathing is prohibited.</p><p>Caymanians tend to be churchgoers, and island society is relatively conservative in terms of attitudes to LGBT rights; the government has been known to make anti-gay comments before, although homosexuality was decriminalised in 2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style (flat) two-pin plugs (with or without round grounding pin) are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Premier Alden McLaughlin since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, is represented by Governor Martyn Roper since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The two smaller Cayman islands &ndash; Little Cayman and Cayman Brac &ndash; were discovered by Columbus in 1503, who named them Las Tortugas (Spanish for turtles) after the vast numbers of turtles populating the islands. The Cayman Islands&rsquo; turtles remain a talking point for visitors to the islands. This is due to the unique fact that Cayman retains the right to eat the turtles, farmed at a special facility in West Bay that is also open to the public. So you can snorkel with the beautiful creatures then, erm, eat them.</p>
<p>During the early 16th century, the islands&rsquo; name was changed to Cayman after the Carib word for a kind  of crocodile which, although long gone, once was prevalent throughout  the islands. Britain&rsquo;s Sir Francis Drake explored the area in 1586, but it was 1670 before the islands came under full British rule. Many of the original settlers&rsquo; descendents can be seen in the islands&rsquo; surnames including Bodden, Ebanks and Kirkconnell.</p>
<p>Grand Cayman was settled from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jamaica">Jamaica</a> by 1672; Little Cayman and Cayman Brac were settled some time later, and maintained a separate administration until 1877. The surrounding waters were the backbone of the Cayman Island&rsquo;s industries right up until the late 1900s; shipbuilding was a key source of income for the islands, as were fishing and turtling.</p>
<p>Today, it is tourism that brings in much of the riches. Grand Cayman suffered a setback when it was battered by Hurricane Ivan in 2004, and the island all but shut down for numerous months while it was restored.  Things have now recovered and it continues to attract high-end tourism to the country due to a combination of excellent infrastructure, top class hotels and of course the world-famous beaches and diving.</p>
<p>The Governor of Jamaica held administrative responsibility for the islands until 1962, when Jamaica itself became independent. Since 1971, the Cayman Islands have had their own Governor appointed by the British crown. There is a directly elected Legislative Assembly which is responsible for the implementation of law in the Cayman Islands. The Governor has the power of veto which is rarely exercised.</p>
<p>A constitution was passed in 2009 and occasional flirtations with financial problems have meant closer scrutiny by the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>. Independence is not likely in the near future as the island continues to recover from the financial crisis, which hit government coffers badly.</p>
<p>The island continues to discuss modernisation in a series of public-private partnerships with potential cruise industry, airline industry and investment partners as Cayman does not have the resources to embark on capital projects any more.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Important Address]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ask people to define their idea of paradise and they may well describe the Cayman Islands, a Caribbean archipelago renowned for its beautiful beaches, world-class diving and incredible food.</p>
<p>Mere specs in the Caribbean Sea, the Caymans are made up of three islands in all: Grand Cayman, Cayman Brac and Little Cayman. These British Overseas Territories are home to around 50,000 people, a significant number of whom are British expatriates working in everything from finance and property to scuba diving and services.</p>
<p>A trip to the Caymans is all about switching off. The extraordinary beaches on all three islands are perfect for whiling away lazy days, whilst the surrounding waters are a treasure trove of marine life, making them a hit with divers.</p>
<p>The financial industry looms large over the islands and there&rsquo;s no income tax, leading many to believe that paradise really does exist here. Still, the high duty on consumer goods, food and fuel makes the cost of living sharply felt.</p>
<p>If you've got the cash, there&rsquo;s an exceptional selection of high-end restaurants scattered across the archipelago &ndash; more than 200 on Grand Cayman alone. Island cuisine is also celebrated at Cayman Cookout, an annual culinary jamboree that attracts chefs from around the world. If that&rsquo;s a bit highfalutin for you, then drop in at Taste of Cayman, which is a far more accessible food festival.</p>
<p>The jamborees come thick and fast throughout the winter months. Pirates Week celebrates local culture and the archipelago&rsquo;s swashbuckling history, while Heritage Days allow visitors to sample local food, entertainment and history of the island in even more detail.</p>
<p>Another noteworthy jamboree is Batabano &ndash; the Cayman Islands&rsquo; own version of Carnival, complete with floats, extravagant costumes, steel bands and all the dancing you can muster. So pour out a glass of the local brew, Swanky, grab a spot on Seven Mile Beach, sit back and enjoy the show.</p><p>Ask people to define their idea of paradise and they may well describe the Cayman Islands, a Caribbean archipelago renowned for its beautiful beaches, world-class diving and incredible food.</p>
<p>Mere specs in the Caribbean Sea, the Caymans are made up of three islands in all: Grand Cayman, Cayman Brac and Little Cayman. These British Overseas Territories are home to around 50,000 people, a significant number of whom are British expatriates working in everything from finance and property to scuba diving and services.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
