<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Central African Republic" ColCode="caf" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="cf" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Central African Republic]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot all year with a defined dry season. Especially hot in the north, with greater humidity in the south. The rainy season is mainly from May to October, while the driest months are January and February. Heavy rainfall is typical in the southwestern forest areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Light, linen and tropical, waterproof clothing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Scheduled flights sometimes operate to Berb&eacute;rati. However, most domestic flying is limited to chartered planes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Incidents of roadside theft and robbery occur regularly, and armed gangs are known to operate in the outlying areas of Bangui. Road closures are frequent during the rainy season.</p>r<p>Good roads connect the few main towns (although few are paved), but the majority are often impassable during the rainy season and travellers should expect delays.&nbsp;Most roads require a 4-wheel drive vehicles to render them passable.&nbsp;Outside urban areas, motor vehicles are rare and spare parts virtually impossible to find.</p><p>International Driving Permit required. Identification (eg residence permit or certified copy of passport) must be carried at all times. Failure to do so can result in detention by police.</p><p>Self-drive or chauffeur-driven cars are available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Limited bus services run in Bangui. Taxis are only available in the urban areas; they do not have meters and fares must be negotiated. Minibuses serve Bangui and other major towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main airlines serving the Central African Republic are Kenya Airways (<a href="http://www.kenya-airways.com" target="_blank">www.kenya-airways.com</a>), Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>) and TAAG (<a href="http://www.taag.com" target="_blank">www.taag.com</a>). There are no direct flights from the UK or the USA.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours (including stopover); <a href="new-york-city">New York</a> - 26 hours (including stopovers).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>XAF10,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bangui M’Poko International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 7km (4 miles) southeast of Bangui of the city (journey time - 30 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is sometimes possible to hire a boat, although this is expensive and services are unpredictable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a few international mobile phone companies. Coverage is limited to the capital, Bangui.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet access is available in some towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is journalistic freedom in the Central African Republic to the extent that private newspapers criticise Government policies and allegations of corruption, but these are likely permitted because most of the populace both cannot afford them and cannot read them (there is a high rate of illiteracy in the country). Televsion stations include Television Centrafricaine (state-run) and Tropic RTV (private); newspapers include the state-owned Centrafrique-Presse; and radio stations include the UN-backed Radio Ndeke Luka. State run radio and TV stations provide little to no coverage of the political opposition. It was only until 2004 that prison terms for press offences were abolished.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a post office in each prefecture. Local postal services are unreliable. Both postal and telecommunications services are in the process of being developed. Airmail services to Europe take approximately one week, although it is often much longer; surface mail can take up to three months.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1130 and 1430-1630; Sat 1430-1830; Sun 0800-1100, open for stamps and telegrams only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire traditional wooden houses in Zinga</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See some rare examples of beautifully constructed wooden houses in the friendly town of Zinga on the Ubangi River, one of the Congo's largest tributaries. The most atmospheric way of reaching the town is by motorboat or traditional canoe from Bangui, which lies some 100km (60 miles) north of Zinga.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the riverside capital, Bangui</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Shaded by tropical greenery, Bangui's city centre is a fine place to while awaya day or two. Star attractions include the tomb of the emperor-president Jean-Bédel Bokassa, which lies in the Berengo palace grounds, and a colourful central market renowned for its malachite necklaces. The Grande Corniche leads to the banks of the River Ubangi and provides a picturesque view of the fishermen's round huts and traditional canoes.</p>]]><p><b>Go on safari</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the dry season, take a 4x4 and spot wildlife in the Central African Republic's national parks. The three most important are Manovo-Gounda St Floris, known for its high concentration of hippos, Bamingui-Bangoran in the north and Dzanga-Sangha in the southwest. The game population of the parks is impressive.</p>]]><p><b>Relax beside Boali Waterfalls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At 250m (820ft) wide and 50m (165ft) high, the plunging Mbali River waterfalls near the charming village of Boali are a wonderful spectacle. Those wishing to linger and enjoy the views should grab a seat at the riverside restaurant, before paying a visit to the nearby hydroelectric power plant, which harnesses the energy of the cascading water.</p>]]><p><b>Shoot some hoops</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Basketball is the country's most popular sport and a good way to forge connections with the people of the Central African Republic. Almost every town has some sort of space for playing, while league teams meet regularly to fight for the title. International games are often screened in bars and cinemas.</p>]]><p><b>Shop for handicrafts at Bangui’s artisans’ market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A great place to pick up a souvenir in a relaxed atmosphere, the capital's artisan market displays a range of traditional products from across the country. Handicrafts for sale include woven products, pottery, musical instruments, such as the xylophone-like <em>balafon</em>, and other hardwood carvings from the country's forested tropical belt.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in time to ancient Africa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Around the town of Bouar, in the east of the country, 70 groups of upright megaliths called <em>tajunu</em> mark the locations of ancient burial mounds. Standing up to 5m (16ft) high, they are thought to date from Neolithic times, making them roughly the same age as England's Stonehenge.</p>]]><p><b>View gorillas and elephants at Bayanga</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Dzanga-Sangha Reserve near Bayanga provides the opportunity to get up close and personal to several groups of habituated lowland gorillas while taking advantage of the good quality accommodation on offer. The platforms overlooking Dzanga and Sangha bais almost guarantee sights of shy forest elephant in search of a mud-bath.</p>]]><p><b>Visit indigenous forest tribes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See indigenous forest tribes, including Pygmy people, living in encampments of small, low huts made of lianas and roofed with leaves in the Lobaye Region, 100km (60 miles) from the capital. The region is also known for producing coffee and visitors can visit plantations on the fringe of the forest, outside urban centres such as M'Baïki.</p>]]><p><b>Witness nature at its most spectacular</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Close to Kembé, a traditional village with mud-brick huts bearing thatched roofs, the Kotto River is churned white as it cascades over a spectacular V-shaped waterfall. Villagers use the river for washing and bathing, while children play in its strong currents most days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2.113 billion (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Diamonds, timber, cotton, coffee and tobacco.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, textiles, petroleum products, machinery, electrical equipment, motor vehicles, chemicals and pharmaceuticals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Belgium, Italy, Spain, Indonesia, USA and Cameroon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Agriculture, upon which most of the population depends, is concentrated on subsistence crops plus coffee, cotton and wood as cash crops for export. Livestock and tobacco are also exported. The main cash earner is timber, which has been heavily exploited with little government restriction.<br /><br />The country's mining industry is largely devoted to diamonds; a small quantity of gold is also produced. Other deposits, including uranium, copper, manganese and iron ore, are yet to be exploited.<br /><br />The small manufacturing sector is devoted to the processing of primary products to produce food and drinks, wood products and textiles.<br /><br />The overall economic development of the Central African Republic has been limited by an adverse climate, poor infrastructure and low world commodity prices. With a per capita annual income of just US$700, the Central African Republic is one of Africa's poorest countries. The GDP growth rate was 3.7% in 2010.<br /><br />The Central African Republic is a member of the Central African Economic and Monetary Union (CEMAC), the main regional trading organisation. France provides extensive economic and financial aid and is the country's main trading partner.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A knowledge of French is essential. Interpreter and translation services may be available at large hotels. Business cards should be in French and English. Formal wear is expected (suits and ties for men). The best months for business visits are between November and May.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie (CCI)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 611 668
					Website:
					Address: BP 823,Boulevard Charles de Gaulle,Bangui,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Local food can be basic, though full of flavour. Meals centre around large portions of starch such as <em>chiwangue </em>served with sides of vegetables and meat, all topped with rich sauces that often include peanuts.</p><p>Many dishes contain <em>gombo </em>(okra), tomato and onion, although other popular ingredients include rice, bananas and cassava. The most commonly eaten meats are chicken and goat, with bushmeat hunted in more rural areas. Meat is generally well-marinated before being grilled or steamed over open braziers.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Makara</strong>: Bread made from cassava flour.</p><p><strong>Chicken and cumin stew</strong>: With additional flavours from onion, tomato and garlic.</p><p><strong>Chikwangue</strong>: Traditional starch made from manioc and often serves as batons.</p><p><strong>Egusi</strong>: Blood-red sauce made from the seeds of gourd or pumpkin as well as tomato, onion and chilli.</p><p><strong>Capitaine</strong>: Fish caught in the Bangui River and smoked. Also called Nile perch.<br/><strong>Moambe</strong>: Soup or sauce made from palm butter.</p><p><strong>Karkanji</strong>: Drink made from hibiscus flowers.<br/><strong>Shrimps:</strong> Eaten with boiled yams or sweet potatoes.</p><p><strong>Kanda ti nyma</strong>: Spicy beef meatballs.<br/><strong>Spinach stew</strong>: Might also include tomatoes, peppers, chillies, onions and peanut butter.</p><p><strong>Chichinga</strong>: Skewered pieces of barbequed goat meat.</p><p><strong>Ginger beer: </strong>A refreshing fizzy drink made using ginger.</p><p><strong>Palm wine:</strong> A potent liquor made from the sap of palm trees.</p><p><strong>Banana wine:</strong> A similarly strong tipple made from bananas.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is appropriate in expensive hotels and restaurants. Bargaining is normal.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[The few hotels in Bangui have clubs catering for tourists and businessmen; local nightlife is centred on the district known as 'Kilom&egrave;tre Cinq'.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bangui has reasonable shopping facilities, including the Marché Central (Central Market) notably for ebony, gold jewellery, butterfly collections and objets d'art made from butterfly wings.  However, one of the best methods of finding bargain souvenirs is by bartering with villagers outside the urban areas for their handmade goods.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1200 and 1600-1900. Some shops close on Monday. The market in Bangui is open 0730-dusk.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a range of good hotels in Central African Republic. Travellers will find the more exclusive and expensive hotels in Bangui. The better hotels have air conditioning and swimming pools. Pre-booking is essential (ideally several weeks in advance). Outside Bangui, accommodation of any standard may be difficult to find, although guest houses exist in smaller towns, principally Bangassou, Boali, Bambari and Bossangoa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guest houses exist in smaller towns, principally Bangassou, Boali, Bambari and Bossangoa as well as in the capital Bangui.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a range of good hotels in Central African Republic. Travellers will find the more exclusive and expensive hotels in Bangui. The better hotels have air conditioning and swimming pools. Pre-booking is essential (ideally several weeks in advance). Outside Bangui, accommodation of any standard may be difficult to find, although guest houses exist in smaller towns, principally Bangassou, Boali, Bambari and Bossangoa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a range of good hotels in Central African Republic. Travellers will find the more exclusive and expensive hotels in Bangui. The better hotels have air conditioning and swimming pools. Pre-booking is essential (ideally several weeks in advance). Outside Bangui, accommodation of any standard may be difficult to find, although guest houses exist in smaller towns, principally Bangassou, Boali, Bambari and Bossangoa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Full health insurance is essential, and should include air evacuation to Europe in case of serious accident or illness. Medical facilities are severely limited outside the major centres and visitors should travel with their own supply of remedies for simple ailments such as stomach upsets: pharmaceutical supplies are usually very difficult to obtain.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis E is present and hepatitis B is hyperendemic. Diarrhoeal illnesses are common. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Meningococcal meningitis is particularly prevalent during the dry season in December, especially in the north of the country. Vaccination is strongly recommended. There is also a high incidence of HIV/AIDS; sensible precautions should be taken. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Anniversary of the Death of Barth̩lemy Boganda :
							29 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Independence Day :
							13 August </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>National Day :
							01 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported by visitors over 18 years of age into the Central African Republic without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 1,000 cigarettes or cigarillos or 250 cigars or 2kg of tobacco (for women, cigarettes only).<br />
&bull; 5 bottles of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; 5 bottles of perfume.</p>
<p>You must declare firearms before entering.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFA (Communauté Financière Africaine) Franc (XAF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of XAF10,000, 5,000, 2,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of XAF500, 100, 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1.<br /><br />The Central African Republic is part of the French Monetary Area. Only currency issued by the Banque des Etats de l'Afrique Centrale (Bank of Central African States) is valid; currency issued by the Banque des Etats de l'Afrique de l'Ouest (Bank of West African States) is not. The CFA Franc is tied to the Euro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency can be exchanged at banks in Bangui and Berbérati.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are not generally accepted, except in major hotels.</p><p>There are no international ATM machines and few estabilshments accept major international credit or debit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros. Even so, commission rates can be very high.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0700-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months after entry is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above to enter the Central African Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay visa: &euro;75; long-stay visa: &euro;155.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay visa: up to 30 days; long-stay visa: up to three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Usually two days, unless the application is referred to the authorities in the Central African Republic. Allow extra time if you need to post your application to an overseas consulate (eg UK nationals must apply to the embassy in Paris).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[6.574017]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[20.487016]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>622,984 sq km (240,535 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,998,493 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>8.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bangui.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Central African Republic is bordered to the north by Chad, to the east by Sudan, to the south by the Democratic Republic of Congo and the Republic of Congo, and to the west by Cameroon. It is a large, landlocked territory of mostly uninhabited forest, bush and game reserves. The Chari River cuts through the centre from east to north; towards the Cameroon border the landscape rises to 2,000m (6,560ft) west of Bocaranga in the northwest corner, while the southwest has dense tropical rainforest. Most of the country is rolling or flat plateau covered with dry deciduous forest, except where it has been reduced to grass savannah or destroyed by bush fire. The northeast becomes desert scrubland and mountainous in parts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>25% of the population is Protestant. 25% is Roman Catholic. There is a small Islamic minority of 15% and 35% of the population have indigeneous beliefs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dress is informal. Care should be taken to dress modestly in Muslim areas, and Muslim customs should be respected and observed; visitors should not, for instance, show the soles of their feet when sitting. Shorts are also generally frowned upon, and women are expected to dress modestly. It is customary to shake hands. Women are strictly segregated, especially in towns. In Muslim areas, visitors should not smoke or drink in public during Ramadan.<br /><br /><strong>Photography:</strong> Film is expensive and should be sent abroad for developing. Show caution and discretion when photographing local people; ask for permission. Do not photograph military installations or government buildings.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Simplice Sarandji since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Faustin-Archange Touad&eacute;ra since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The territory we now know as the Central African Republic has been settled since at least the 7th century and incorporated into a number of regional empires including the Kanem and Wadai empires. In the 16th and 17th centuries, prior to French colonisation of central Africa in the 1880s, many tribes fled to the region in order to escape the slave trade.</p>
<p>In 1910, the area, then known as Ubangi-Chari, became incorporated into French Equatorial Africa, however, after WWII, the territory was granted its own assembly, as well as representation in the French National Assembly. Internal self-government followed in 1958, with the leading nationalist politician, Barth&eacute;lemy Boganda, serving as prime minister. Boganda died the following year and his nephew, David Dacko, took the country to full independence in 1960.<br />
<br />
In 1965, with the country facing bankruptcy and political chaos, Dacko was overthrown by army chief Jean-Bedel Bokassa, and the already impoverished country was further damaged by the disastrous and profligate rule of the self-styled emperor. The 1977 'coronation' of Emperor Bokassa I is estimated to have used up over a quarter of the country's annual income. The regalia alone is estimated at the time to have cost US$5m. Under his rule, the Central African Republic was renamed the Central African Empire.<br />
<br />
Bokassa was deposed just two years later by Dacko and exiled to France, with the country reverting to its previous name, Central African Republic. The two dominant figures in the country&rsquo;s more recent history have been Andr&eacute; Kolingba, another former army commander, who took charge after ousting Dacko in a 1981 military coup, and Ange-F&eacute;lix Patass&eacute;, who later emerged as Kolingba's principal opponent.<br />
<br />
Following a transitional period, which led to presidential and parliamentary elections in 2005, Fran&ccedil;ois Boziz&eacute; was elected as president in place of Patass&eacute; and was subsequently elected for a second term, beating Patass&eacute; to the leadership once again. In 2016&nbsp;Faustin Archange Touad&eacute;ra was inaugurated as president.<br />
<br />
<strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The Central African Republic has the least light pollution of any country on Earth.<br />
&bull;	Bokassa&rsquo;s coronation robe contained 785,000 pearls and more than 1.2 million crystal beads.<br />
&bull;	The constitution was suspended temporarily in 2003 since it permitted religious freedom but declared witchcraft a criminal offence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Central African Republic in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 483 7800.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 483 7800.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1618 22nd Street<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Central African Republic in France]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>01 4524 4256.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>01 4524 4256.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>30 rue des Perchamps<br/>Paris<br/>75016<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One of the least visited countries in Sub-Saharan Africa, the Central African Republic ranks amongst the poorest nations on the planet and has struggled to find its feet since gaining independence from France in 1960. Suffice to say few tourists venture out this way.</p>
<p>A country of contrasts, the Central African Republic is a place where the Sahara Desert meets tropical Africa, where the pastoral traditions of Africa&rsquo;s tribespeople rub shoulders with the colonial architecture of imperial France.</p>
<p>The French influence is particularly strong in the capital, Bangui, which retains its colonial aesthetic and is scattered with patisseries serving fresh baguettes and &eacute;clairs. Vibrant stalls around the central market provide cheap and tasty local cuisine, which ranges from fish straight out of the Ubangi River to fried plantain and <em>fufu</em>, a sour-tasting starch prepared from manioc flour which is a staple of the region.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s frenzied markets are perfect places to interact with and better understand the culturally diverse tribespeople that make up the population. The shortest interaction with these people shows them to be inquisitive, warm and generous beyond their means.</p>
<p>Geographically, much of the Central African Republic is composed of rolling grasslands, dusty deserts and steamy jungles. The northern reaches of the country are dominated by the seemingly infinite Sahara. With so little light pollution here, the night skies gleams with millions of stars.</p>
<p>The far south is home to equatorial rainforests, which are considered some of the best places in Africa to see forest elephants and western lowland gorillas. The jungle is also home to pygmy tribes, which live off the land in remote pockets of central Africa. Visits to these tribes are possible and offer an insight into their extraordinary lives.</p><p>One of the least visited countries in Sub-Saharan Africa, the Central African Republic ranks amongst the poorest nations on the planet and has struggled to find its feet since gaining independence from France in 1960. Suffice to say few tourists venture out this way.</p>
<p>A country of contrasts, the Central African Republic is a place where the Sahara Desert meets tropical Africa, where the pastoral traditions of Africa&rsquo;s tribespeople rub shoulders with the colonial architecture of imperial France.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
