<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Chile" ColCode="chl" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="cl" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Chile]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Due to its long coastline, clearly Chile&rsquo;s weather is extremely diverse and unpredictable although it is seasonal in much of the country. Summer runs from December to February, and winter from June to August.</p>
<p>It is difficult to pinpoint temperatures ranges for the country as a whole as they&rsquo;re so variable.  There&rsquo;s the dry, arid Atacama desert in the north where temperatures reach a maximum of 32&deg;C (90&deg;F) and can drop to -2&deg;C (28&deg;F). Chile&rsquo;s central region has a Mediterranean feel with a cold, wet season from May to August, while it is usually always cool and damp in the south. Easter Island has its own humid sub-tropical temperatures, while much of the south, from Region VII down has a very high annual rainfall.</p>
<p>Arica, Iquique, Antofagasta, La Serena and Coquimbo are the principal summer beach hubs in the north for local tourists, while Puc&oacute;n in the south sees high tourism numbers from January to March. Due to its proximity to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/santiago">Santiago</a>, Vi&ntilde;a del Mar and Valpara&iacute;so beach areas see plenty of sunshine and beach bums during the summer, often filling up with neighbouring Argentinians.  As Chile is in the southern hemisphere, the ski season takes place between June and August.</p>
<p>In terms of visiting Patagonia and south, the summer months from December to March are ideal as it is warmer for trekking and other outdoor activities. November and April are quieter times in terms of tourism but the weather is less dependable. It isn&rsquo;t advisable to visit the south from the end of autumn to the end of winter - May to September - as many trails close due to bad weather and strong winds and waterways ice over.  However, places in the north, such as the Atacama, can be visited all year round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[If visiting the cities, bring lightweight, natural fabrics that can wick away sweat easily. During the wet season, you'll need to bring waterproofs – aim for breathable materials so you don't overheat. More substantial waterproofs and warm weather clothing are often needed in the south and at altitude.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are frequent services between main cities. The southern part of the country relies heavily on air links and reservations are essential. Flights are operated by LATAM (<a href="http://www.latam.com" target="_blank">www.latam.com</a>), and by Sky Airline (<a href="http://www.skyairline.cl" target="_blank">www.skyairline.cl</a>), as well as a number of air taxi companies such as Aerov&iacute;as Dap (<a href="http://www.aeroviasdap.cl" target="_blank">www.aeroviasdap.cl</a>), which flies around the Magallanes region and Antarctica.</p>
<p>There are regular flights with LAN from Santiago to Easter Island (journey time - 5 hours). Flights fill up quickly so it's essential to book in advance throughout the year.  An air taxi runs a summer service to the Juan Fern&aacute;ndez Islands from Santiago, run by Aerol&iacute;neas ATA&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.aerolineaata.cl" target="_blank">www.aerolineaata.cl</a>). Sky Airline flies south to Punta Arenas and north to Antofagasta amongst other routes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From Puerto Montt there are various ferry operators that travel south. The main one is Navimag (tel: +56 2 2869 9900; <a href="http://www.navimag.com/" target="_blank">www.navimag.com</a>). The most popular routes are from Puerto Montt to Chacabuco, running inland to the spectacular San Rafael glacier, and between Puerto Montt and Puerto Natales.</p>
<p>Cargo boat services running from Valpara&iacute;so to Robinson Crusoe Island (part of the Juan Fern&aacute;ndez Islands) occasionally have cabins available. Enquire in Valpara&iacute;so.</p>
<p>To experience the fjords of Chilean Patagonia on a personalized luxury ship, Nomads of the Seas (tel: +56 2 2414 4690;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.nomads.cl" target="_blank">www.nomads.cl</a>) provides memorable nature and fishing expeditions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All tickets are bought from Central Station in Santiago or from the Metro Universidad de Chile. One major rail route heading south to Valpara&iacute;so, Vi&ntilde;a del Mar and Limache is with Metro Valpara&iacute;so (tel: +56 32 252 7500; <a href="http://www.metro-valparaiso.cl" target="_blank">www.metro-valparaiso.cl</a>). Fesub travels to the city of Concepci&oacute;n (tel: +56 41 286 8015; <a href="http://www.fesub.cl" target="_blank">www.fesub.cl</a>).</p>
<p>There aren&rsquo;t any major rail services connecting the capital with the north of the country. A modernised system of southbound trains runs frequently from Santiago through Talca and Chill&aacute;n to Temuco. Empresa de Ferrocarriles del Estado (tel: +56 225 855 050;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.efe.cl/" target="_blank">www.efe.cl</a>) has more information. Painfully slow services crawl to Talcahuano near&nbsp;Concepci&oacute;n&nbsp;and to Talco, stopping at Curic&oacute; and Parral.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chile has a large network of good roads, with the exception of the fjord-filled south of the country which is not always connected to central Chile by road. Crossings have to be made at times through Argentina, and water transport also plays a part there.</p>
<p>There is around 80,000km (50,000 miles) of highway in the country, half of which is paved. Foreign drivers should feel comfortable driving in Chile, as in general, traffic rules are obeyed here more than in other Latin American countries &ndash; although you can often find horses, bicyclists, and pedestrians on the highways, so keep aware! Most highways are well-marked.</p>
<p>There is a toll for using the highway, with rates differing according to distance and section. Outside Santiago, you&rsquo;re expected to pay in Chilean Pesos. In Santiago, the toll is automatically charged via the TAG-system - a little sensor that is fixed onto the windscreen of each car, mandatory for driving on Santiago&rsquo;s city highways.</p>r<p>Chile generally has good roads and somewhat enforced speed limits. The Pan American Highway is in great shape and threads right down most of the country from north to south. It runs for over 3,455km (2,147 miles) from the Peruvian border to Puerto Montt.</p>
<p>Chile&rsquo;s  Carretera Austral, a (mostly) unpaved road running southwest down through Patagonia, covers 1,240km (771 miles) from&nbsp;Puerto Montt&nbsp;to&nbsp;Villa O&rsquo;Higgins. Although a bit of a rough road, it&rsquo;s the best way to access the Aysen region&nbsp;and the southern part of Los Lagos.</p>
<p>It's advisable in more remote areas to carry plenty of water, spare petrol and an additional spare tyre; tyres should be hard-wearing. On gravel roads, the most common type of trouble is rocks hitting the windscreen, so when renting a car, it&rsquo;s best to opt for the insurance which covers you for this.</p><p>Long-distance bus travel in Chile has a great reputation for punctuality, efficiency and comfort, and prices are a bargain compared to North American and European standards. Most major cities have a central bus terminal with destinations, schedules and fares prominently displayed. The majority of highways are paved (except for large parts of the Carretera Austral). Long-distance buses generally have toilet facilities and often serve coffee, tea and meals on board. <em>Cama</em> service means that the seat will recline greatly, <em>semi-cama, </em>not so much.</p>
<p>Chile's biggest bus company is TurBus (tel: 600 660 6600, in Chile only; <a href="http://www.turbus.cl" target="_blank">www.turbus.cl</a>), offering services throughout the country.  Its main competitor is Pullman (tel: 600 320 3200, in Chile only; <a href="http://www.pullman.cl" target="_blank">www.pullman.cl</a>), which also has extensive routes.</p>
<p>A bus service specifically aimed at backpackers is Pachamama by Bus (tel: +56 2 688 8018; <a href="http://www.pachamamabybus.com" target="_blank">www.pachamamabybus.com</a>). It's a hop-on, hop-off service with two long routes exploring the north and south respectively, visiting many out-of-the-way national parks and other attractions.</p><p>Taxis are black with a yellow roof and an orange licence plate. In some tourist towns, such as Vi&ntilde;a del Mar, taxis may cost twice as much as elsewhere.</p>
<p>Most should have meters, but, if you can, find out roughly what the fare should be before climbing in. Fares for long journeys should be agreed beforehand. Minicabs may not bear the standard colours but still carry the orange licence plate. Tipping is not expected.</p><p>Drivers need to carry their passport and it's recommended that you carry an International Driving Permit, although many car hire companies don't ask for this.</p><p>Seat belts are mandatory for the driver and passenger. Smoking, using a mobile phone or a personal music player with headphones is prohibited for the driver. In towns and cities the limit is generally 60kph (37mph), and up to 100kph (62mph) on rural roads, if not indicated differently. The speed limit on highway throughout Chile is 120kph (75mph). It is recommended to follow these limits, since Chilean<em> carabineros</em> (policemen) often patrol with radar.</p><p>Get 24-hour roadside assistance by calling +56 600 464 4040.</p><p>Drivers must be over 22 years old, although some car hire companies make exceptions for drivers as young as 18 upon request. Self-drive cars are available at the airport and in major city centres. A 20% tax is added and a credit card is required as guarantee. The Autom&oacute;vil Club de Chile in Santiago can supply road maps (tel: +56 600 464 4040; <a href="http://www.automovilclub.cl" target="_blank">www.automovilclub.cl</a>).</p><p>You can find quality bicycles with front suspension and decent brakes in adventure activity destinations such as the Lake District and San Pedro de Atacama. Leisurely biking around Chile&rsquo;s wine regions is a great way to enjoy the countryside.</p>
<p>Bike Santiago (<a href="http://www.bikesantiago.cl" target="_blank">www.bikesantiago.cl</a>) is the capital's bikeshare scheme.</p><p>Seat belts are mandatory for the driver and passenger. Smoking, using a mobile phone or a personal music player with headphones is prohibited for the driver. In towns and cities the limit is generally 60kph (37mph), and up to 100kph (62mph) on rural roads, if not indicated differently. The speed limit on highway throughout Chile is 120kph (75mph). It is recommended to follow these limits, since Chilean<em> carabineros</em> (policemen) often patrol with radar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Santiago has South America&rsquo;s most extensive metro network (<a href="http://www.metrosantiago.cl" target="_blank">www.metrosantiago.cl</a>). It also has bus and shared <em>colectivo</em> (taxis with fixed routes) services, although the modernisation of the city's transport infrastructure seems to have overcome its teething problems. Metro fares increase at peak travelling times. You can pay for the metro and buses with a pre-paid bip! card (so-called because of the sound it makes when you push it up against the orange machine).</p>
<p>Taxis are plentiful, and can be flagged down in the streets. It's a safe city in general in which to use public transport although usual precautions should be taken. For long-distance travel within Chile, buses in are inexpensive and actually quite comfortable.  Meal service, movies, and reclining seats make the journey an easy one.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Chile</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">puerto_montt</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">14.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Chile</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">easter_island</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Chile</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">concepcioacuten</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Chile</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">arica</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">28.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chile's main airline LATAM (<a href="http://www.latam.com" target="_blank">www.latam.com</a>), connects both Europe and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> with Chile. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) also flies to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/santiago">Santiago</a> via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sao-paulo">Sao Paulo</a> in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brazil">Brazil</a>&nbsp;(the second leg is operated by LATAM), Air France flies from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a> (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>), and Air Canada arrives from London via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/toronto">Toronto</a> (<a href="http://www.aircanada.com" target="_blank">www.aircanada.com</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chile/santiago-arturo-merino-benitez-international-airport">Santiago Arturo Merino Benitez International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 17 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 10 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>At the airport upon arrival in Chile, visitors are issued a <em>tarjeta de turismo</em> (tourist card) by the immigration authorities. Travellers must retain this document and present it to immigration upon leaving the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>At the airport upon arrival in Chile, visitors are issued a <em>tarjeta de turismo</em> (tourist card) by the immigration authorities. Travellers must retain this document and present it to immigration upon leaving the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Santiago Arturo Merino Benítez International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeropuertosantiago.cl<p>Santiago Arturo Merino Benítez International Airport is located 15km (9.5 miles) northwest of central Santiago.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+56 2 2690 1752.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shipping lines such as Compa&ntilde;&iacute;a Chilena de Navegaci&oacute;n Interoce&aacute;nica (CCNI) (<a href="http://www.ccni.cl" target="_blank">www.ccni.cl</a>) and Compa&ntilde;&iacute;a Sud Americana de Vapores (CSAV) (from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a> and European ports) (<a href="http://www.csav.com" target="_blank">www.csav.com</a>) operate in Chile. The country's biggest port is San Antonio.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A sporadic service used to exist between Chile and Bolivia (although it was mostly used for freight). There is talk of reviving that line, although that may be years before it happens.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chile shares a northern crossable border with Peru and Bolivia, and Argentina is to the east.  There are more than 30 border crossings accessible by road with Argentina, although in winter months many are closed due to snow (remember, the daunting Andes separate the two countries).</p>
<p>The&nbsp;two most commonly used border crossings by road are the Paso Internacional Los Libertadores, also called&nbsp;Cristo Redentor, a&nbsp;breathtaking mountain pass in the&nbsp;Andes between&nbsp;Mendoza, Argentina and&nbsp;Santiago, Chile, reaching elevations of 3,200m (10,500ft) and including some intense switchbacks. The other popular crossing is the Pajaritos crossing (also known as Paso Cardenal Antonio Samor&eacute;) between Villa La Angostura, Argentina and Osorno, Chile.</p><p>Many border crossings are paved highways, although some, especially towards the far south of Chile or the far north in Atacama, are gravel roads.  Many are not accessible by public transportation, and close for the winter due to snow.  It's best whenever possible to check ahead of time with either the nearest tourism office or gendarmeria (border police) office to make sure that the crossing is open.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public phone boxes are unreliable, and visitors will find it cheaper to use phones in <em>centros de llamadas </em>(call centres) in towns, or at internet cafes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good in built-up areas, less so outside of the towns. It is also cheap and easy to buy your own if you are in the country for any length of time, although calls are not especially cheap.</p><p>Pre-paid SIM cards can be used in unblocked phones allowing cheaper calls within Chile. For all-round country coverage, Entel (www.entel.cl) and Movistar (www.movistar.cl) are Chile's largest networks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafés are open all hours in the main towns and tourist areas. Many hotels and hostels will have access to the internet which is relatively cheap at around US$1 for 30 minutes, while free Wi-Fi is also becoming increasingly popular, with many hotels offering this.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chile enjoys a reasonable level of press freedom, which is now enshrined in the constitution. There is, however, a heavy conservative tilt to the media, which has never quite redressed the imbalance of the Pinochet-era restrictions. The <em>Santiago Times </em>is the only English language daily in Chile whilst Spanish dailies include <em>El Mercurio,</em> La<em> Tercera,</em> conservative evening newspaper <em>La Segunda</em>, business newspaper <em>El Diario</em>, and government-run <em>La Nación</em>. The <em>Patagonia Times </em>concentrates on news in the country's south.</p><p>Television was introduced in 1957 and national broadcasters include Canal 13, which is part-owned by the Catholic church, UCV Televisión, Chilevisión (owned by Sebastián Piñera, the Chilean politician and businessman widely tipped to become the next president), TVN, Mega, RED TV and Telecanal. Although state-owned, National Television of Chile is not under direct government control. Radio stations include Radio Nacional de Chile, news-based national commercial network Radio Cooperativa and music-based Radio Horizonte. Santiago Radio is a fledgling English-language online station.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The postal service, Correos de Chile (<a href="www.correos.cl" target="_blank">www.correos.cl</a>), is reasonably reliable. Airmail to Europe and the USA takes anything from four days to a week.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1900; Sat 0830-1300. The central post office in Santiago is located at Plaza de Armas 559. Post offices in villages are likely to have reduced opening hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>La Sebastiana</p><![CDATA[<p>The Valparaiso home of famous Chilean poet Pablo Neruda is open for exploration.  Visitors can wander around La Sebastiana at will, lingering over the chaotic collection of ship's figureheads, glass, 1950s furniture and artworks by his famous friends.  Notable is the inspiring view of the ocean from Neruda's crow's nest study.</p>]]><br/><p>Pre-Colombian Art Museum</p><![CDATA[<p>Santiago's small but magnificent Pre-Colombian Art Museum is a moving testament to the sophistication and artistry of the cultures that thrived in South America 4,500 years before the arrival of the plundering conquistadores. A fascinating collection of ceramics, textiles and Chinchorro mummies, which outdate their Egyptian counterparts, awaits.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Discover Chile’s northern delights</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Northern Chile offers a dazzling plethora of attractions: visit the fishing village of Los Choros to spot bottle-nosed dolphins and sea otters off shore. World surfing championships are held at Arica and Pichilemu, but Punta de Lobos is the best surf spot for beginners. Explore the eerie mining ghost town of Humberston; and see flamingos and rheas on the salt plains of the Parque Nacional Lauca.</p>]]><p><b>Get the sand between your toes in the Atacama Desert</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Let the uniquely arid landscape of the Atacama Desert sweep you away with its broad, stark vistas of volcanoes, salt flats, aquamarine lakes and the abandoned homes of the indigenous Aymara people. The world's driest desert, there are areas of Atacama that haven't seen rain for more than 400 years.</p>]]><p><b>Get up close to the San Rafael Glacier</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The star attraction of the superb San Rafael National Park is its eponymous glacier. Witness giant icebergs from a glacier cruise, or kayak out to accessible parts. Longer cruises follow a spectacular route through the Beagle Channel and around Cape Horn, passing glacial valleys, fjords and huge icebergs; with stop-off points en route, notably at Puerto Natales and Tierra del Fuego.</p>]]><p><b>Go whale watching in Francisco Coloane Marine Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located in the historic 560km-long (350mile) Strait of Magellan, this is the only site in the southern hemisphere outside of Antarctica where humpback whales can be found feeding. Boat safaris are available from Punta Arenas, from December to April, during the summer months when these majestic cetaceans head north to warmer waters.</p>]]><p><b>Haggle in La Vega Central Market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Raspberries, quinces, figs, peaches, persimmons, custard apples, wine, spices… if it's from Chile, you'll find it at Santiago's La Vega Central Market and Bazaar. Get there early for the best selection and to see the more than 500 enthusiastic vendors in full swing. It's loud, chaotic and crowded, which is all part of the authentic Chilean shopping scene.</p>]]><p><b>Hike up fiery Volcán Villarrica</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the world's most active volcanoes, Volcán Villarrica near Pucón is safer than it sounds – it is also one of the world's most monitored, so you should have plenty of warning of any imminent eruption. You can hike up Villarrica in a day, with local tour operators running guided walks, and shoot back down on a thrilling toboggan ride.</p>]]><p><b>Kayak through the Chiloé archipelago</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Chiloé islands, which are separated from Chile by the Chacao Channel, have a quirky range of attractions, including colourful old wooden churches, precarious waterfront houses on stilts, and a notable colony of penguins on the main island of Chiloe. Perhaps the most unforgettable experience, however, is a sunrise kayak ride through a petrified forest with one of several local agencies.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Chile's lake district</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ideal for watersports, trekking and fly-fishing, this area is heaven for lovers of the great outdoors. The Llanada Grande Valley is great for fishing, as well as many family friendly activities. See millennia-old larch trees in the lush, temperate rainforests of Patagonia at Pumalín Park, a vast nature reserve. Huilo Huilo, an incredible biological reserve, has bundles of activities as well as great accommodation options.</p>]]><p><b>Mingle with the penguins in Antarctica</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Voyage to the world's last undiscovered wilderness, Antarctica, from Chile's southernmost city, Punta Arenas. Where else could you find penguins, vertiginous icebergs and live out the fantasy of being Scott of the Antarctic for a few days? Local tour operators in Punta Arenas can help get you there, offering everything from skiing and mountain climbing expeditions to luxury cruises.</p>]]><p><b>Quaff Chile’s fine wines</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A short hop from Santiago lieChile's leading wine regions, with tasting tours available for keen oenophiles. The Rapel Valley has earned international recognition for its Carménère and Syrah wines. Concha y Toro, one of Chile's oldest winemakers, is famous for its Carménère. Further south of the capital are the Curicó and Maule valleys, also home to some of Chile's oldest and finest vineyards.</p>]]><p><b>Raft down the rapids</b></p><![CDATA[<p>White-water rafting down the country's many rapids is a popular way to experience nature – at high speed. Specialist operators offer up to week-long trips down the Maipo near Santiago, the Trancura near Pucón, as well as the Bio-Bio River in Region VIII. For hard-core rafters looking for an adrenaline rush, however, the impressive Futaleufu River in the south is the ultimate challenge.</p>]]><p><b>Remember Robinson Crusoe on the Juan Fernández Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Retrace the footsteps of the real-life Robinson Crusoe in the little known Juan Fernández Islands 650km (403 miles) west of Valparaíso, accessible by plane from Santiago. Scotsman Alexander Selkirk was marooned here in the early 18th century, forming the inspiration for Daniel Defoe's novel <em>Robinson Crusoe</em>. Today, you can visit various sites, including Selkirk's cave and his hilltop lookout.</p>]]><p><b>Search for Valparaíso’s poetic spirit</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the most atmospheric port cities in Latin America, Valparaiso is a place of sinuous hills, a labyrinth of precipitous streets and bright clapboard houses. Its slightly offbeat charms inspired Pablo Neruda. Chile's best-known Nobel Prize-winning poet, his home, La Sebastiana, is open to visitors. Colour, culture and bohemia sum up this coastal haven located just a little more than an hour from Santiago.</p>]]><p><b>Ski in the Darwin Mountain Range</b></p><![CDATA[<p>World-class backcountry skiing can be found in the Darwin Mountain Range at Chile's southernmost tip, where the ski season runs from June to September. For the slightly less adventurous, the famous Portillo resort hosts many national ski teams. Portillo's powder snow is a perfect match for boarders. Other slopes in the area include Farellones-El Colorado, La Parva and Valle Nevado.</p>]]><p><b>Stare at the statues of Easter Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A lonely volcanic island in the Pacific Ocean, Easter Island is famous for its mysterious stone statues, or <em>moais</em>. Around 300 statues and other stonework form an almost unbroken ring around the coast, still puzzling scientists how and why they were made. Other sites to investigate include the volcano crater Rano Kau, the Orongo rock carvings and the museum in Hanga Roa.</p>]]><p><b>Stargaze in Chile’s clear skies</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Glimpse faraway galaxies at one of several powerful observatories situated in the northern Coquimbo region, which is famed for its remarkably clear skies. The best of the best is ALMA (Atacama Large Millimeter/Submillimeter Array), the world's largest astronomical project, on the Chajnator Plateau in northern Chile. Or set your sights on the powerful Schmidt Cassegrain telescope in the Collowara Observatory, atop Cerro Churqui near La Serena.</p>]]><p><b>Tackle Santiago’s lofty hills</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Perched atop Cerro San Cristóbal is the giant statue of the Virgin Mary, a popular spot for city hikers to enjoy a spectacular panorama over Santiago's vast sprawl. Reward yourself for your efforts by stopping off at the foot of the hill in Barrio Bellavista, to visit the eccentric La Chascona, once the Santiago home of poet Pablo Neruda.</p>]]><p><b>Trek through Torres del Paine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The jagged peaks of Torres del Paine are a defining sight of the far south. Its two trekking circuits, the Grande or the W, provide a taste of Patagonian wilderness; and catch the impressive Southern Ice Fields, a trip best made in summer. For the most southern trek in the world, take on the Dientes de Navarino, located further south on Isla Navarino.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$240.8bn (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Copper, fruit, fish products, paper, chemicals, wine.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, vehicles, natural gas, excavating machinery, electrical and telecommunications equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, USA, Argentina, Brazil, Japan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With well-developed industrial and service sectors, Chile has one of Latin America's strongest economies. However, it still depends on export of primary commodities (metals and ores, fruit, fish and wood) for a large proportion of its export earnings. With commodity prices dropping recently, harsher times look likely for the Chilean economy, in line with the straitened financial times across the world.<br/><br/>However, Chile's industrial base has grown substantially over the last decade and includes steel manufacturing, oil production, ship building, and the production of cement and consumer goods. The mainstay of the export economy is still metals and ores: Chile is the world's leading exporter of copper and also produces zinc, iron ore, molybdenum, manganese, iodine and lithium.<br/><br/>The service sector has developed rapidly, especially financial services. Chile's economic performance has been strong since 2000; unemployment was estimated at roughly 6% in early 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business life in Chile remains formal both in dress code and conduct. When meeting an associate, greeting them with a firm handshake accompanied by a smile and direct eye contact, is appropriate for a business setting. Business cards are immediately exchanged, and titles and surnames should be used until otherwise invited. Chileans may stand quite close to each other when speaking.</p><p>In a business environment, <em>usted</em>, the polite Spanish form of address, should be used instead of the more familiar <em>tu</em>. Failure to observe this linguistic etiquette could be construed as disrespectful or even arrogant. Some Chilean executives speak reasonably competent English, but any attempt to use Spanish, however faltering, will be greatly appreciated.</p><p>Like their counterparts in North America and Europe, members of Chile's business community make good use of the working lunch. Meanwhile, Chile's international hotels, especially in the capital Santiago, have benefited in recent years from the increased popularity of the 'business breakfast'. The best months for business visits are April to December. The summer months of January and February are slower, as Chileans tend to holiday then. Chileans are generally very hospitable and it is not unknown for foreign business travellers to be invited to dinner at home.</p><p>Be careful when inviting an important business client for coffee. There are many cafés spread throughout Santiago, especially close to Plaza de las Armas, which offer more than just coffee. Known as a 'café con Piernas' baristas here are typically 20-something women wearing some form of bikini or lingerie ensemble. These cafés can be recognized by the fact the all windows facing the outside are heavily tinted or covered with advertisements.</p><p>Usually Mon-Fri 0900-1800, although Chilean business workers are known for working long hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cámara Nacional de Comercio de Chile</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 365 4391
					Website:http://www.cnc.cl/
					Address: ,Merced 230,Santiago,]]><b>Santiago Convention Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 333 8085
					Website:http://www.scb.cl/
					Address: ,(Information on Conferences/Conventions),,]]><b>Cámara de Comercio de Santiago de Chile AG</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 360 7000
					Website:http://www.ccs.cl/
					Address: ,Monjitas 392,Santiago,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>With its fertile landscape and temperate climate, Chile is blessed with an abundance of natural produce. Its cuisine is likewise fresh and hearty, less spicy than most of Latin America, and with a mix of Spanish, French and German influences.</p>
<p>Outside of Santiago, where international cuisine abounds, options are limited for vegetarians. Seafood, red meat (including excellent lamb), and chicken dominate the menu. For carnivores, a leisurely <em>asado</em> (barbeque) or <em>curanto</em> (shellfish stew) is an opportunity to participate in a cherished Chilean tradition.</p>
<p>With its long coastline, seafood is plentiful in Chile. The fish market at Angelm&oacute;, near Puerto Montt is renowned for its exotic produce; try <em>congrio</em> (conger eel), <em>centolla</em> (king crab) and, if you&rsquo;re feeling adventurous, <em>picorocos</em> (barnacles) and <em>erizos</em> (sea urchin), which taste much better than they look.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Empanada:</strong> A pasty stuffed with a combination of meat, chicken or fish, with vegetables, eggs, raisins or cheese.<br />
<strong>Seafood:</strong> Including clams, sole, sea bass and oysters.<br />
<strong>Curanto:</strong> A seafood stew from the island of Chiloe, where heated rocks line the bottom of a large hole, and the food, wrapped in large leaves, is buried to slow-cook.<br />
<strong>Cazuela de ave:</strong> Soup with rice, vegetables, chicken and herbs.<br />
<strong>Bifea lopobre:</strong> Steak with fries, onions and eggs.<br />
<strong>Parrillada:</strong> A selection of meat cuts grilled over hot coals, often including delicacies such as intestines, udders and black pudding.<br />
<strong>Pastel de choclo</strong><em>: </em>A typical, hearty Chilean casserole dish made of ground corn, usually with chicken and basil.<br />
<strong>Pebre:</strong> A simple salsa often served with bread as a starter.<br />
<strong>Wine:</strong> Chilean wine is very good, especially the Carmen&egrave;re, Syrah, Cabernet Sauvignon and Malbec varieties, with the Central and Colchagua valleys being the best wine-growing areas.<br />
<strong>Pisco:</strong> A powerful brandy distilled from grapes after wine pressing and used to make pisco sours &ndash; a potent lemon-based cocktail that Peru also claims as its own.<br />
<strong>Chicha:</strong> A traditional maize beer, which can also be made from grapes, apples or other fruits.<br />
<strong>Beer:</strong> Local brews include Cristal, Kross, Kunstmann, and Escudo.<br />
<strong>Cola de mono</strong><em>: </em>Meaning 'monkey's tail' this is a coffee and chocolate-based liqueur, similar to eggnog, that's very popular at Christmas.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It is customary to add 10% to the bill. Some restaurants and bars automatically do this.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While many restaurants and hotels offer entertainment, there are also a number of nightclubs. Santiago is lively on the weekends, especially in Pablo Neruda's former neighbourhood haunt, Bellavista, where the caf&eacute;s and bars spring into action, and in Barrio Brasil, the bohemian area to the west of the centre which is teeming with cool restaurants.</p>
<p>Those who want to pack as much into one night as possible should look into the boho Happy End Tours (<a href="http://www.happyendingtour.com" target="_blank">www.happyendingtour.com</a>) taking in the city's best bars, clubs and restaurants.  Santa Luc&iacute;a is also packed with great eateries, while Providencia and Nu&ntilde;oa provide good bar action. Lastarria, an area just to the west of Bellas Artes metro station, is perhaps the most refined area for going out. Even if jazz isn&rsquo;t your thing, swing by South America&rsquo;s most renowned venue of the genre, the aptly named Club de Jazz (<a href="http://www.clubdejazz.cl" target="_blank">www.clubdejazz.cl</a>).</p>
<p>Bands and acts frequently perform; listings sections can be found in&nbsp;<em>La Tercera</em>&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.latercera.com" target="_blank">www.latercera.com</a>) and <em>El Mercurio</em>&nbsp;(<a href="http://elmercurio.com" target="_blank">www.elmercurio.com</a>) as well as in the weekend cultural section of The Santiago Times.  Santiago's club scene caters to the 18-35 year-old crowd, and don&rsquo;t expect anything to start until around midnight. If you show up much earlier, you may be the only one there.  Visitors should be aware that the English word 'nightclub' translates as 'brothel' in Chile.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases include textiles such as colourful hand-woven ponchos, vicuna rugs, alpaca jumpers and copper and silver work.  Most small towns and villages throughout Chile will have a local market or stores which will offer handcrafts at prices much lower than what you&rsquo;d find in Santiago.  Negotiation of prices at markets is possible and can be attempted, although not aggressively.  A genuine smile and a &lsquo;please&rsquo; in Chile can go far when it comes to lowering prices.</p>
<p>Chile is particularly known for its lapis lazuli jewellery, but jade, amethyst, agate and onyx can all be purchased. Increasing numbers of small boutique stores selling well-crafted jewellery and handmade wares are cropping up in Cerros Alegre and Concepci&oacute;n in Valpara&iacute;so. Camping and other outdoor equipment can be bought in Santiago, although you are advised to buy essential equipment before arriving.</p>
<p>Big spenders should head to Alonso de Cordova Street and shopping malls such as Parque Arauco and Alto Las Condes in Santiago to pick up luxury brands. For an impressive array of wines from the local wine regions, look no further than the Wine Tasting Room located in Santiago&rsquo;s hip W Hotel, which features thousands of bottles from around the world.   A great souvenir that you can pick up anywhere in Chile is a bottle or two of pisco, Chile&rsquo;s national alcoholic drink.</p>
<p>Foodies should definitely take back some of Chile&rsquo;s traditional spices, including a smoked <em>aji</em> (pepper) called <em>merken</em>. High quality sea salts can be found all along the coast at incredibly low prices.</p><p>Mon-Fri 1000-2000, Sat 1000-1400. Large shopping malls are open daily 1000-2100.</p>
<p>As a general rule, most places are closed on Sundays and in rural areas, some shops could be closed for siesta after the lunch hour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Several luxury hotel chains have set up shop in Santiago and there are also various boutique hotels that meet exacting Western standards in the capital. Advance bookings are essential in resort areas during the high season. The cost of accommodation in Santiago is higher than in the provinces, with rates increasing during the summer holidays from January to March, particularly in coastal resorts.</p>
<p>Members of foreign motoring organisations can often obtain discounts at hotels by joining the Autom&oacute;vil Club de Chile. A tax of 19% is levied on all hotel bills, except those paid in foreign currencies by visitors, for which an export bill is required.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Chile are graded from 5 (luxurious rooms) to 2 stars (basic commodities).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Several luxury hotel chains have set up shop in Santiago and there are also various boutique hotels that meet exacting Western standards in the capital. Advance bookings are essential in resort areas during the high season. The cost of accommodation in Santiago is higher than in the provinces, with rates increasing during the summer holidays from January to March, particularly in coastal resorts.</p>
<p>Members of foreign motoring organisations can often obtain discounts at hotels by joining the Autom&oacute;vil Club de Chile. A tax of 19% is levied on all hotel bills, except those paid in foreign currencies by visitors, for which an export bill is required.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Chile are graded from 5 (luxurious rooms) to 2 stars (basic commodities).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Several luxury hotel chains have set up shop in Santiago and there are also various boutique hotels that meet exacting Western standards in the capital. Advance bookings are essential in resort areas during the high season. The cost of accommodation in Santiago is higher than in the provinces, with rates increasing during the summer holidays from January to March, particularly in coastal resorts.</p>
<p>Members of foreign motoring organisations can often obtain discounts at hotels by joining the Autom&oacute;vil Club de Chile. A tax of 19% is levied on all hotel bills, except those paid in foreign currencies by visitors, for which an export bill is required.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Chile are graded from 5 (luxurious rooms) to 2 stars (basic commodities).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Getting access to quality medical care in Chile is possible in the larger cities such as Valparaiso and Santiago. Travellers are advised to take out comprehensive health insurance before travelling. Emergency services can be dialled free - call 131 for an ambulance. For medical emergencies, private services may deliver more modern equipment and a faster response. &lt;em&gt;Cl&amp;iacute;nicas&lt;/em&gt; (private hospitals) can be contacted directly in the case of a medical emergency. If bringing medication, then make sure to have a signed note from the doctor stating medical conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Standards of hygiene are generally reasonable in Chile, and should not cause visitors any undue concern. Tap water in the cities is fine to drink but it does have a high mineral content and may taste different to what you're used to. Bottled water is easily available should you prefer to stick to that. When it comes to eating out, use common sense – only eat food that has been freshly cooked and looks to have been prepared in hygienic conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. When travelling to rural parts of Chile, care should be taken to avoid the hantavirus, a potentially fatal condition that is spread by rodents. In particular, avoid resting near tall grasses or haystacks, don't leave food sources lying around and make sure rustic cabins are well aired out and free from any sign of rodents.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Holy Saturday :
							31 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Navy Day :
							21 May </p><p>Feast of Saints Peter and Paul :
							29 June </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>National Unity Day :
							03 September </p><p>Independence Day :
							18 September </p><p>Army Day :
							19 September </p><p>Discovery of Two Worlds Day :
							12 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Chile without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes and 500g of tobacco and 50 cigars.<br />
&bull; 2.5L of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; Gifts to the value of US$300.<br />
&bull; Items bought on arrival in the duty-free shop to the value of US$500.</p>
<p>Alcohol and tobacco allowances apply to travellers aged 18 and over only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Used cars and motorbikes, asbestos and pornography.</p>
<p>Restricted imports requiring authorisation include firearms and ammunition, food, plants, animals (and their products), drugs and pharmaceutical products.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chilean Peso (CLP; symbol CH$) = 100 centavos. The local symbol is simply $. Notes are in denominations of CH$20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 2,000 and 1,000. Coins are in denominations of CH$500, 100, 50, 10, 5 and 1, although the latter is no longer in circulation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign exchange transactions can be conducted through commercial banks, <em>casas de cambio,</em> or authorised shops, restaurants, hotels and clubs. <em>Casas de cambio </em>are open daily 0900-1900 (Mon-Sat) and 0900-1400 (Sun). Ask to be given smaller denomination bills as these will be easier to spend, and you may run into trouble trying to get change from larger notes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa and Mastercard are commonly accepted &ndash; Diners Club and American Express slightly less so - in towns and cities, where ATMs are also largely available. Outside of the larger, more tourist-centred towns, currency exchange can be tricky.</p><p>Credit/debit cards (Visa, Diners Club, MasterCard and sometimes American Express) are widely accepted in towns and cities, where ATMs (also known as <em>redbancs</em>) are also largely available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government does not regulate the market of foreign currency in Chile, making it possible to exchange money and traveller's cheques at any <em>casa de cambio </em>at market-driven exchange rates. However, exchanging traveller's cheques in Chile has been reported to be problematic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Chile, a passport valid at least six month beyond the stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Children under 18 who are leaving Chile alone, with only one parent, with friends or family, or with a group must obtain an official authorisation to travel from a Chilean <em>notaria</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Costs for travellers requiring single- or multiple-entry visas vary according to nationality; check with the consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The validity of visas varies between one and 90 days, depending on the applicant's nationality.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you do require a visa, you should apply at least 20 days before your trip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-39.116989]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-72.441024]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>756,102 sq km (291,932 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>18,131,850 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>24 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Santiago.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chile is situated in South America, bordered to the north by Peru, to the east by Bolivia and Argentina, to the west by the Pacific Ocean and to the south by the Antarctic. The country exercises sovereignty over a number of islands off the coast, including the Juan Fern&aacute;ndez Islands and Easter Island. Chile is 4,329km (2,690 miles) long and nowhere more than 180km (112 miles) wide.</p>
<p>The Andes and a more westerly coastal highland range run parallel with each other for much of the country's length. The coastal range forms high, sloped cliffs into the sea from the northern to the central area. Between the ranges runs a fertile valley, except in the north where transverse ranges join the two major ones, and in the far south where the sea has broken through the coastal range to form an assortment of archipelagos and channels.</p>
<p>Wide variations in soil and a vast difference in climate are reflected in an uneven population distribution, and in a wide range of occupations. The Atacama desert, the driest in the world, is in the northern part of the country, which is also the main mining area. The central zone is predominantly agricultural, and is often referred to as the breadbasket of Chile. This is where the two-thirds of the population reside. Below Concepci&oacute;n, there are large tracts of forested land, although the area also has some agriculture. Chile is prone to frequent powerful earthquakes as the Liquine-Ofqui Fault lies just under the northern Patagonian Andes and runs for 1000km (621 miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christian (mostly Roman Catholic) majority with small but notable Mormon and Bahá'í Faith minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chileans are often seen as more formal than others in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-america">South America</a>. Handshaking is the customary form of greeting between men. On informal, social occasions, women usually greet friends with a single kiss on the cheek.  It is very common to entertain at home and it is acceptable for invitees to give small presents as a token of thanks.</p><p>Most Chileans consider themselves Catholic, and undertake baptism and first communion although they may not practise as adults. People believe in marriage and even if they are not practising Catholics, a wedding will still take place in a church. Co-habitation does exist between younger couples although it is not very common; however it is accepted. Chile was one of the last countries in the world to make divorce legal in 2004. Chileans also adhere to Catholic death rites.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with with either two circular pins or three pins in a line are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Sebasti&aacute;n Pi&ntilde;era since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Sebasti&aacute;n Pi&ntilde;era since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although today Chile is a democracy with a stable economy, partly thanks to its strong trade ties with the US, its history hasn&rsquo;t always been harmonious. A conquered nation, like its neighbours, Chile went through colonisation in the north at the hands of the Spaniard Pedro de Valdivia, who then founded the capital Santiago in 1541.</p>
<p>In the south, it took European conquerors more than 300 years to colonise the resisting Mapuche Indians. With civil unrest developing due to Spain&rsquo;s firm trade control and domination of farm estates, Chile was finally liberated in 1818 thanks to the Argentine Jos&eacute; de San Mart&iacute;n and Bernarndo O&rsquo;Higgins. The latter ruled Chile for six years and established Catholicism as the nation&rsquo;s religion.</p>
<p>The regime seed had been sown, right from Chile&rsquo;s birth. Generals have led military coups over the years, but the most prominent was General Pinochet, whose rule lasted 17 years until 1990. Imposing his extreme right-wing policies, Pinochet overthrew elected President Salvador Allende, killing and torturing thousands of Marxist Allende&rsquo;s supporters and forcing others into exile.</p>
<p>However, Pinochet brought economic stability and in the 1989 elections he stepped down as leader. Patricio Aylwin won with 55% of the votes and so began the slow path to democracy. Since then, ruling parties have tended to be socialist and Chile voted in its first female president, socialist Michelle Bachelet, in 2006. Her successor, Sebasti&aacute;n Pi&ntilde;era, was from the right-wing Coalition for Change party, but his presidency didn&rsquo;t last long: in 2014, Bachelet regained the country&rsquo;s top job.</p>
<p>Chile has taken some hard knocks. An earthquake measuring 8.8 on the Richter scale hit in 2010 caused mass devastation. Nearly six months later, the trapping of 33 miners from a San Jos&eacute; copper mine, and their subsequent rescue after 69 days, became a global news story.</p>
<p>Chile staved off recession in 2009, becoming an OECD member that same year. It remains one of South America&rsquo;s most stable and prosperous nations despite slow economic growth, which has averaged less than 2 per cent since the leftist government of Michelle Bachelet took power in 2014.&nbsp;With presidential and congressional elections scheduled for November 2017, Bachelet's left-leaning coalition has a fight on its hands to retain power against the conservative opposition.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; The Atacama Desert, in northern Chile, is the driest non-polar desert on Earth, with some parts never having had any recorded rainfall.<br />
&bull; In the far south of the country lies the Cueva del Milodon, where 10,00 year-old remains were found of the huge, bearlike Mylodon, now extinct.<br />
&bull; Chile is one of the world&rsquo;s biggest producers of edible seaweed, with the long, tubular <em>cochayuyo</em> one of its most popular varieties.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Chile in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7222 2361.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.chileabroad.gov.cl/reino-unido/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7222 2361.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1730.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>37-41 Old Queen Street<br/>London<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Chile in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 785 1746.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://chile.gob.cl/estados-unidos/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 785 1746.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1330.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1732 Massachussets Avenue<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Chile]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+56 2 2370 4100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.chile-usa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+56 2 2370 4100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1300 and 1400-1730, Fri 0900-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Las Condes<br/>Avenida El Bosque Norte 0125<br/>Santiago<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A narrow slither of land wedged between the Pacific and the Andes, Chile stands as a nation apart in South America &ndash; both literally and figuratively. The mountains cut the country off from Argentina and Bolivia to the east, while the expansive Atacama Desert separates it from Peru to the north. And to the south, beyond the country&rsquo;s infamous Cape Horn headland, lies nothing but ocean and Antarctica. But far from being a curse, this isolation has created a very special destination indeed.</p>
<p>Whether you fancy road-tripping the endless Carretera Austral, climbing the peaks of Torres del Paine National Park or surfing the brutal waves of Punta de Lobos in Pichilemu, Chile is deserving of its reputation as one of the world&rsquo;s best destinations for adventure tourism. It&rsquo;s not just for thrill-seekers, though. From its incredible night skies and Mapuche Indian heritage to its vibrant arts scene and vertiginous vineyards, this is a country that caters for travellers of all hues. The Chileans themselves, meanwhile, tend to be warm and open, so absorbing what the country has to offer is generally a joy.</p>
<p>The country hasn&rsquo;t always had it easy, of course, and the tribulations of the Pinochet era can be explored in the dynamic capital, Santiago. The city&rsquo;s buzzing boulevards and arty neighbourhoods feel a million miles away from Chile&rsquo;s more famous attractions, and this in itself tells you how broad the country&rsquo;s offering is &ndash; this is a land that not only includes vast swathes of Patagonian wilderness and the glacier-threaded waterways of Tierra del Fuego, but also incorporates the remote, statue-studded landmass of Easter Island.</p>
<p>Whether you&rsquo;re seeking solitude as a leisurely backpacker or taking on the big sights in unbridled luxury, consider yourself warned &ndash; once you&rsquo;ve experienced the myriad attractions Chile has to offer, you may find other destinations fall somewhat short.</p><p>A narrow slither of land wedged between the Pacific and the Andes, Chile stands as a nation apart in South America &ndash; both literally and figuratively. The mountains cut the country off from Argentina and Bolivia to the east, while the expansive Atacama Desert separates it from Peru to the north. And to the south, beyond the country&rsquo;s infamous Cape Horn headland, lies nothing but ocean and Antarctica. But far from being a curse, this isolation has created a very special destination indeed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
