<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="China" ColCode="chn" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="cn" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[China]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>China&rsquo;s extreme size means it has a great diversity of climates, but being located entirely in the northern hemisphere means its seasonal timings are broadly comparable to those in Europe and the US.</p>
<p>The northeast experiences hot and dry summers and bitterly cold harsh winters, with temperatures known to reach as low as -20&deg;C (-4&deg;F). The north and central region has almost continual rainfall, temperate summers reaching 26&deg;C (79&deg;F) and cool winters when temperatures reach 0C (32&deg;F). The southeast region has substantial rainfall, and can be humid, with semi-tropical summer. Temperatures have been known to reach over 40&deg;C (104&deg;F) although this is highly unusual, but during summer temperatures over 30&deg;C (86&deg;F) are the norm. Winters are mild, with lows of around 10&deg;C (50&deg;F) in January and February.</p>
<p>Central, southern and western China are also susceptible to flooding, and the country is also periodically subject to seismic activity.</p>
<p>Early autumn around September and October, when temperatures are pleasant and rainfall is low, is generally seen as an optimum time to visit. Spring is also popular, for similar reasons, and the many tourists visit in March or April.</p>
<p>Be aware that if visiting during Chinese New Year a large number of businesses will be closed and public transport, in particular rail routes, can be enormously busy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If arriving in winter, heavyweight clothing and boots are recommended to cope with what can be extreme cold. Likewise, lightweight clothing should be packed for a visit at the height of summer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>China's airlines operate about 1,000 domestic routes, serving over 150 cities. Routes are served by the three major state-owned groups of Air China (<a href="http://www.air-china.co.uk" target="_blank">www.air-china.co.uk</a>), China Southern Airlines (<a href="http://www.csair.com/en" target="_blank">www.csair.com/en</a>) and China Eastern Airlines (<a href="http://uk.ceair.com">http://uk.ceair.com</a>).</p>
<p>International airports in Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou have undergone massive upgrades with stylish new terminals added. Tickets are normally purchased by guides and the price will be included in any tour costs.</p>
<p>Independent travellers can also book through the local Chinese International Travel Service (CITS), which charges a small commission, popular online agent Ctrip.com (<a href="http://english.ctrip.com" target="_blank">http://english.ctrip.com</a>) or buy tickets in booking offices or at some hotel travel desks. It's advisable to buy internal air tickets well in advance if travelling during April, May, September or October.</p>
<p>There are multiple daily connections to Hong Kong from Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou, as well as other cities. You can also fly directly to Taiwan from numerous cities on the mainland. Flights are always overbooked so you must confirm seats before travel.</p>
<p>Note: Safety records have improved greatly in recent years, and Chinese airlines now almost exclusively operate aircraft from Western companies such as Boeing and Airbus with average fleet ages of six to eight years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major rivers are served by river ferries, especially the Yangtze. Coastal ferries operate between Dalian, Tianjin (Tientsin), Qingdao (Tsingtao) and Shanghai. There are regular ferry services between mainland China and Hong Kong, conditions on which vary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Railways provide the principal means of transport for goods and people throughout China, with the network standing as one of the busiest and most comprehensive worldwide. The routes are generally cheap, safe and well maintained. Routes operate between major cities; services include Beijing to Guangzhou, Shanghai, Harbin, Chengdu and Urumqi.</p>
<p>There are three types of train, of which Express is the best. There are four types of fare: hard seat, soft seat (only on short-distance trains such as the Hong Kong to Guangzhou line), hard sleeper and soft sleeper (the priciest option). Children under 1m (3ft) tall travel free and those under 1.3m (4ft) pay a quarter of the fare. Rail travel is usually comfortable but time-consuming due to the vast distances between destinations. High-speed intercity trains travelling up to 350kph (218mph) link Beijing with Tianjin, and Shanghai with Suzhou and Hangzhou.</p>
<p>The Qinghai to Tibet railway which is a 1,142km (710mile) route from Golmud in Qinghai to Lhasa in Tibet is the most elevated rail route in the world, reaching an altitude of 5,072m (16,640 ft). Services operate to Lhasa from Beijing, Xi'an, Chengdu, Chongqing, Guangzhou and Shanghai.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Be aware that it's not possible to drive in China without a Chinese driving licence. Obtaining this can be a complicated process and in most cases it's preferable and relatively inexpensive to hire a car with a driver. China&rsquo;s road infrastructure itself is generally of a high standard, particularly between major centres. Police road blocks are not uncommon, and standards of driving can be erratic.</p>
<p>Distances should not be underestimated and vehicles should be in prime mechanical condition as away from the cities, China is still very much an agricultural nation without the mechanical expertise or services found in the West. From Beijing to Shanghai is 1,461km (908 miles), and from Beijing to Nanjing is 1,139km (718 miles).</p>r<p>As part of its economic drive, China has undergone rapid expansion of its road network and it is now possible to reach 80% of settlements by road, although a high percentage of roads are simple gravel tracks rather than tarmacked surfaces. A superhighway links Beijing and Tianjin, and a 138km (86-mile) four-lane toll highway links Hangzhou and the port of Ningbo in the Zhejiang province.</p><p>There is an extensive intercity network of long-distance buses which tourists can use as an alternative to air or train travel. These are much cheaper than trains and most have air-conditioning, toilets, and depending on the length of the journey, may have sleeping berths. Seats can generally be booked in advance at the coach station.</p><p>Taxis are available in large cities from most hotels and shopping districts, and are generally permitted to stop at the passenger's signal. It's best to check if the taxi is metered. If not, then it's important to agree a fare beforehand (especially at railway stations), before getting into the taxi. Drivers are not normally tipped.</p>
<p>You should have your destination written down in Chinese characters before starting any journey as most drivers do not speak English. Hotels often provide cards with the hotel address and that of several key attractions or points in the city. Taxis can be hired by the day.</p><p>A Chinese driving licence is required to drive in China; International Driving Permits aren't recognised.</p><p>The maximum speed limit in China is 120kph (75mph) on expressways.  This drops to 100kph (62mph) on city roads and 80kph (50mph) on national highways.</p><p>Available, but a three-month residency permit and examination are required to gain a local licence which makes self-drive car hire all but impossible in practice for short-term visitors. Cars with a driver can be hired on a daily or weekly basis.</p><p>Within the major urban centres, motorised forms of transport dominate, and cycling is tantamount to taking your life into your own hands. Motorbikes and e-bikes are more common although still require caution. However, cycling in more rural areas is certainly doable, although it may be more difficult to hire bicycles outside the cities.</p><p>The maximum speed limit in China is 120kph (75mph) on expressways.  This drops to 100kph (62mph) on city roads and 80kph (50mph) on national highways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are metro systems in Beijing, Shanghai and several other cities including Tianjin, Guangzhou, Shenzhen, Chengdu, Nanjing, Xi'an, Harbin and Qingdao. Hong Kong has its Mass Transit System, and tramways and trolleybuses operate in a number of other cities. Most cities have public transit systems, usually bus.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">China</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">shanghai</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">11.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">China</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kunming</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">40.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">China</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">guangzhou</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">21.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">China</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">chengdu</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.25</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">26.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to China are served by Air China (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.airchina.co.uk">www.air-china.co.uk</a>).  British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) also run direct flights to China from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>. Autumn, when tourist numbers are down but the weather in many regions remains pleasant, is a good time to find flights. Fares can be higher in and around peak holiday seasons such as Chinese New Year.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/shanghai-hongqiao-international-airport">Shanghai Hongqiao International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/shanghai-pudong-international-airport">Shanghai Pudong International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/beijing-capital-international-airport">Beijing Capital International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/xiamen-gaoqi-international-airport">Xiamen Gaoqi International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/chengdu-shuangliu-international-airport">Chengdu Shuangliu International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/guangzhou-baiyun-international-airport">Guangzhou Baiyun International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Beijing: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 14 hours.</p>
<p>Flights are often overbooked, so you're strongly advised to re-confirm your return flight reservations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Shanghai Pudong International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.shairport.com<p>Shanghai Pudong International Airport is located 30km (19 miles) southeast of central Shanghai, in eastern China.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+86 21 96990</p>]]><b>Beijing Capital International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://en.bcia.com.cn<p>Beijing Capital International Airport is situated 32km (20 miles) northeast of Beijing&rsquo;s city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+86 10 96158</p>]]><b>Hong Kong International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.hongkongairport.com<p>Hong Kong International Airport is located 34km (21 miles) northwest of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hong-kong">Hong Kong Island.</a></p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+852 2181 8888</p>]]><b>Shanghai Hongqiao International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://en.shairport.com<p>Shanghai Hongqiao International Airport is situated 13km (8 miles) southwest of Shanghai city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+86 21 96990</p>]]><b>Guangzhou Baiyun International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.gbiac.net<p>Guangzhou Baiyun International Airport is located 28km (17 miles) north of Guangzhou city centre. It straddles the border of the northern Renhe Town in the district of Baiyun and Xinhua Town in the district of Huadu.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+86 20 3606 6999</p>]]><b>Macau International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.macau-airport.com]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(853) 5988 888</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>China has a huge number of ports. More than 120 of them are open to foreign ships, but these are almost exclusively used for the import and export of goods and containers. International cruise ships do make use of the most prominent ports, though, with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/shanghai">Shanghai</a>, Qingdao and Tianjin among the most popular stop-off points.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International services run from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/beijing">Beijing</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a> on both the Trans-Mongolian Railway (via Ulaanbaatar in Mongolia) and the Trans-Manchurian Railway (via northeastern China). The Trans-Siberian route runs from Moscow to Vladivostock, and from here you can also cross into China, although the other two routes are more direct. Non-stop, the journey by train takes around one week. Allow more time if coming from London or other locations in Western Europe. Train timetables can be found at Man at Seat 61 (<a href="http://www.seat61.com" target="_blank">www.seat61.com</a>).</p>
<p>From Vietnam to China it is possible to take a train which travels from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hanoi">Hanoi</a> to Beijing. There is also a daily overnight train service between Hanoi and Nanning, in Guangxi province.&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are also four weekly services from Beijing to Pyongyang in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/north-korea">North Korea</a>. Owing to demand, it may be necessary to book up to two months in advance. A regular train service runs from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hong-kong">Hong Kong</a> to Guangzhou (Canton). There are several trains daily.</p>
<p>In Hong Kong, MTR (tel: +852 2688 1333; <a href="http://www.mtr.com.hk" target="_blank">www.mtr.com.hk</a>) has express trains running from&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kowloon">Kowloon</a> to Guangzhou. There are also services between Shanghai-Kowloon/Hong Kong (journey time - 19 hours) and Beijing-Kowloon/Hong Kong (journey time - 24 hours).</p>
<p>Further information on rail services is available from the Chinese Ministry of Transport (<a href="http://www.moc.gov.cn" target="_blank">www.moc.gov.cn</a>, in Chinese only).</p>
<p>Note: Travellers on the Trans-Mongolian or Trans-Manchurian Railways are strongly advised to search their compartments and lock the doors before departure, owing to an increase in smuggling via this route.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travelling to China overland is possible, if arduous. China borders multiple countries including <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nepal">Nepal</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mongolia">Mongolia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/myanmar">Myanmar</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/afghanistan">Afghanistan</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/laos">Laos</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kazakhstan">Kazakhstan</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kyrgyzstan">Kyrgyzstan</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pakistan">Pakistan</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>. Border posts are subject to unexpected closures however; the rules change all the time and these should be checked thoroughly before making a journey by road.</p>
<p>Crossings for foreign nationals coming from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a> into China are limited to the Zabaykalsk/Manzhouli border in Siberia. It's advisable to take the advice of a local travel agent and have them organise the necessary paperwork and visas. Within China, tourists are not permitted to self-drive and must use a driver booked through a travel agent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public telephones are becoming harder to locate - your best bets are in post offices and at roadside kiosks. There is a three-minute minimum charge for international calls. The cheapest way to call internationally is to buy a pre-paid calling card, available from most convenience stores and in hotels in units of ¥20, 50, 100 and 200. Skype is a further option.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>China has the most mobile phone users in the world, backed by a very sophisticated mobile communications system that now covers the entire country. Roaming agreements exist with most major international mobile phone companies. Alternatively, you can buy a prepaid GSM SIM card (from China Mobile Ltd stores) that allows you to use your mobile like a local phone with a new number. You'll need your passport to register.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet caf&eacute;s can be found in most towns and cities, and Wi-Fi is increasingly available at hotels and caf&eacute;s in Shanghai, Beijing, Guangzhou, Shenzhen, Tianjin, Hangzhou and other major cities. Access is cheap and usually reliable. The state routinely blocks access to sites run by the banned spiritual movement Falun Gong, rights groups, Western social networking sites and some foreign news organisations. Postings by bloggers are closely monitored.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>
<p>China's media is tightly controlled by the country's leadership. The industry has been opened up in the areas of distribution and advertising but not in editorial content. Access to foreign news providers is limited and re-broadcasting and the use of satellite receivers is restricted; shortwave radio broadcasts are jammed and websites are blocked. In general, the press report on corruption and inefficiency among officials, but the media avoids criticism of the Communist Party's monopoly on power. Hong Kong so far has largely retained an editorially free media. Each city has its own newspaper, usually published by the local government, as well as a local Communist Party daily. All foreign-made TV programmes are subject to approval before broadcast. The <em>People&rsquo;s Daily</em> is the official newspaper of the Communist Party, whilst <em>Reference News</em> is the paper with the largest circulation. The largest English-language newspapers is <em>China Daily.</em></p>
</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Service to Europe takes from between two days and one week. Tourist hotels usually have their own post offices. All postal communications to China should be addressed 'People's Republic of China'.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Terracotta Army</p><![CDATA[<p>The Terracotta Army is an enormous collection of Chinese warriors made out of hardened clay, 40km (25 miles) east of the town of Xi'an. Created in the second century BC by the emperor Shih Huang-Ti, the first emperor of a unified China, it was entombed with him upon his death. The army was discovered in 1974 during an attempt to dig a well, and subsequent digs have revealed over 10,000 figures. Each figure is individual, made to represent actual members of the imperial army, including both soldiers and officers. The collection is often referred to as 'the eighth wonder of the world'.</p>]]><br/><p>Three Gorges of the Yangtze River (Sanxia)</p><![CDATA[<p>The <em>Three Gorges of the Yangtze River</em> are a system of breathtaking gorges on China&rsquo;s longest river, which is also the third longest river in the world (after the Amazon and the Nile), stretching for 6300km (3915 miles). The <em>Qutang Gorge</em> is best known for its steep precipices that form an enormous gateway over the river. The <em>Wu Gorge</em> is home to the famous 12 peaks of the Wushan Mountains. And the <em>Xiling Gorge</em> is known for its hidden reefs, perilous cliffs and tumbling rapids. The controversial Three Gorges Project involves the construction of a dam which will be the largest hydroelectric project in the world. The dam, estimated to have cost $25 billion, is sheduled for completion in 2009 but the first tourist tickets to the dam were sold in the summer of 2005.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be here for New Year</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Falling sometime between late January and late February each year, Chinese New Year sees a week-long national holiday and generous helpings of fireworks, traditional food and lion dances. It's a family affair across much of the country, but the larger cities allow you to get a good sense of how important the event is to the country as a whole.</p>]]><p><b>Circle Mount Kailash</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tibet's Mount Kailash is the holiest mountain on Earth, sacred to one fifth of the planet's population. It's some undertaking to even reach it, given its beautifully remote location, but once you're here, a clockwise circuit of the peak (pilgrims walk around, rather than up, the mountain) is one you'll never forget. Allow three days for the circular walk.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Tai Shan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The UNESCO-listed Tai Shan has been of sacred importance to the Chinese since as long ago as the 11th century BC. Today, heading to Shandong province to climb to its summit has become a rite of passage for many. Don't expect earth paths and rock scrambling, however – the main route is paved, with 7,000 steps lying between bottom and top.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise the Yangzi River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>China's longest waterway is also its most aesthetically powerful, the Yangzi's famous Three Gorges serving up heart-soaring panorama after heart-soaring panorama. Joining a river cruise is the best way to experience the scenery at length – the insatiable appetite for the activity among the Chinese themselves tells its own story.</p>]]><p><b>Encounter pandas in Chengdu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Panda sightings in the wild are elusively rare, even in the creature's home patch of western Sichuan, but the province gives good opportunity to see the animals up close. The large Research Base of Giant Panda Breeding, close to Chengdu, is no two-bit zoo – its bamboo forests do a good job of simulating the pandas' natural environment.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Beijing’s hutongs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Chinese capital isn't just about grand monumental buildings. Its traditional hutongs (alleyways), many of which still stand, retain a neighbourhood feel and give a glimpse into daily life not seen on the large avenues. You might stumble across anything from microbreweries to cafes.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Forbidden City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Beijing's inimitable Forbidden City is one of the world's great historical treasures, a vast palace complex with a superbly preserved collection of ancient buildings. It takes its name from the fact that – as home to the Emperor – it was off-bounds to mere mortals for 500 years. Directly adjacent to the complex spreads Tiananmen Square, the world's largest public square in the world.</p>]]><p><b>Follow the Silk Road</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Trace the ancient Silk Road trading route, which once ran from Xi'an through deserts and mountains to the Caspian and Mediterranean seas, bringing Buddhism and Islam into China – and a thousand other things besides. Key sights include Dunhuang's Buddhist grottoes, the ruins of Jiaohe city near Turpan and Kashgar's lively Sunday market.</p>]]><p><b>Get a feel for Tibet in Lhasa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whether Tibet should be seen as a part of China is a matter of opinion. Less up for debate is the fact that the regional capital, Lhasa, contains some astonishing cultural sights. Top billing goes to Jokhang Temple in the heart of the Old Town, and the majestic Potala Palace.</p>]]><p><b>Hike Tiger Leaping Gorge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>China has some incredible scenery, much of which is best seen on foot. A prime example is the plunging scenery of Tiger Leaping Gorge in northwest Yunnan, where the towering snow-capped mountains are threaded with hiking trails. It stands as one of the deepest gorges on the planet – spectacular doesn't come close.</p>]]><p><b>Immerse yourself in Shanghai</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the cutting-edge atmosphere of economic powerhouse Shanghai, soaring skyscrapers contrast with the European-style Bund waterfront while the art deco laneways of the former French Concession sit alongside on-trend boutiques and galleries. Home to some 24 million, this is a city going places.</p>]]><p><b>Lake-gaze in Hangzhou</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Shop for silk and tea in the ancient Chinese capital Hangzhou, once described by celebrated traveller Marco Polo as 'the most beautiful and magnificent city in the world'. Popular with Chinese and foreign tourists, its main attraction remains the highly photogenic West Lake scenic area.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Zhangjiajie</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In a country brimming with preposterously dramatic landscapes, the Zhangjiajie area in Hunan province boasts arguably the most incredible of the lot. Its jagged sandstone pinnacles look like something from a CGI movie – indeed, belief holds that James Cameron took inspiration here for the unearthly landscapes in his movie Avatar.</p>]]><p><b>Rent a bike</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Some 300 million Chinese use bicycles to get around. Hire shops are everywhere and cycling is one of the best ways to see China's countryside. Popular cycling routes include the area around Yangshuo in the south – renowned for its stunning karst scenery – and the dramatic high-altitude plateaus in the west of the country.</p>]]><p><b>See the Terracotta Army</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Terracotta Army, close to the city of Xi'an, is an enormous collection of Chinese warriors made out of hardened clay. Created in the 2nd century BC for Shih Huang-Ti, the first emperor of a unified China, the figures were entombed with him upon his death. The interred army was discovered by chance in 1974, and remains a phenomenal attraction.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out Buddhist monuments</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel out to the monumental carved Buddhist effigies of Yungang Grottoes, near the city of Datong, or arrange a trip to see the tens of thousands of statues at Luoyang's 5th-century Longmen Buddhist Caves. Elsewhere, at Bingling Lamasery near Lanzhou you'll find 34 early Buddhist caves, while the Mogao Caves in Gansu province still play home to some of China's oldest shrines.</p>]]><p><b>Set foot on the Great Wall of China</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Work on the Great Wall started more than 2,000 years ago and the end result stretches some 5,400km (3,375 miles) across the hills to the west of Beijing (although contrary to legend, it can't be seen from space). The heavily restored Badaling section is the most visited stretch, but many alternatives exist, including remote 'wild wall' stretches that can still be walked.</p>]]><p><b>Take a garden walk in Suzhou</b></p><![CDATA[<p>2,500-year-old Suzhou is China's own Venice, its Grand Canal and famous water gardens once helping it to draw artists, painters and scholars in droves. There's still plenty to make a visit worthwhile – away from the gardens themselves, make sure you set aside time to visit the IM Pei-designed museum.</p>]]><p><b>Take a trip to Hainan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It may come as a surprise, but China has some impressive tropical beaches. Sanya, on the southern coast of China's most southerly province, Hainan Island, is one of China's most popular holiday areas and has international resort hotels, fine sand beaches, golf courses, coconut palms and watersports. Hawaii eat your heart out.</p>]]><p><b>Try out tai chi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try the ancient 'shadow art' of tai chi, a series of linked, slow movements based on the principle of using the entire body to focus the mind. Traditionally practiced early in the morning in parks and public squares throughout China, it can be seen in places including Beijing's Beihai Park and People's Square in Shanghai.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$8.3 trillion (2012).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and data processing equipment, textiles, apparel, textiles, integrated circuits.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, oil and mineral fuels, motor vehicles, metal ores.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, European Union, Hong Kong (SAR), Japan and South Korea</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>
<p>China is now the world's second largest economy behind the USA, and has seen rapid and consistent growth since starting economic reforms in the 1980s. GDP growth has averaged 10% per year for the past decade. However, in recent years the pace of growth has slowed noticeably, with GDP growth of 7.8% in 2012, in part due to the precarious financial situation in Europe.<br />
<br />
There is a significant industrial base with pockets of advanced manufacturing and high-technology enterprises, concentrated on the eastern coast and the Pearl River Delta, including Special Administrative Regions such as Hong Kong and Macau. Massive engineering schemes include the Three Gorges Dam hydro-electric project.<br />
<br />
With huge disparities between the prosperous coastal cities and the socially and economically less developed inland areas, there has been a major population shift from the countryside to cities; in 2011 over 250m citizens had moved from the countryside into the cities. <br />
<br />
China is the world's largest rice producer and a major producer of cereals and grain. Large mineral deposits, particularly coal and iron ore, underpin an extensive steel industry. China has its own petrochemicals industry, but increasingly imports large quantities of oil and gas.<br />
<br />
China joined the World Trade Organisation in 2001. In 2005, its central bank removed the US-Dollar peg for the Yuan, tying it instead to a basket of international currencies. Ever since, the Chinese currency has appreciated at a brisk, albeit strictly managed, pace, though it is still not fully convertible on foreign markets.<br />
China hosts numerous international conventions each year, holding them in extensive facilities in Beijing, Shanghai and other major cities including Guangzhou, Xiamen, Chengdu, Xi'an and Kunming.</p>
</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits should be worn for business visits. Appointments should be made in advance and punctuality is expected. Business cards should be printed with a Chinese translation on the reverse and should be presented with both hands, while cards received should be studied and perhaps commented on. It is rude to put a business card directly into a pocket without giving it due attention, and a cardinal sin to put it in a back pocket. Business meals can last for several hours, and international visitors may well be expected to drink numerous toasts.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800, midday break of one hour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>China Council for the Promotion of International Trade (CCPIT)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7321 2044.
					Website:http://english.ccpit.org
					Address: London,40-41 Pall Mall,London,SW1Y 5JQ]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>First things first: if you&rsquo;re expecting the kind of food served in your average European or American Chinese takeaway, think again. The national cuisine is extraordinarily broad, complex and flavourful, with eight major schools (or regional styles) of cooking all apparent, namely Anhui, Fujian, Guangdong (Cantonese), Hunan, Jiangsu, Shandong, Sichuan and Zhejiang.</p>
<p>These styles are named after their areas of origin &ndash; some are highly spiced, while others are subtler. Many dishes have long histories, dating back to imperial times, and it&rsquo;s common for large numbers of ingredients to be used. Rice and noodles are both common staples, while dairy products are very rare. In the better restaurants, real importance is given to how dishes look when presented.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Peking duck:</strong> Roasted and eaten in a thin pancake with cucumber and a sweet plum sauce.<br />
<strong>Mongolian hot pot:</strong> A Chinese version of fondue, usually eaten communally. It consists of simmering soup in a large round pot, into which is dipped a variety of uncooked meats and vegetables.<br />
<strong>Jiaozi:</strong> Steamed dumplings, typically filled with pork or other meat, and chopped vegetables.<br />
<strong>Kung po chicken:</strong> A classic Sichuan dish, marinated with chillies.<br />
<strong>Dim sum:</strong> Small portions of food served in steamer baskets, usually involving dumplings and rice noodle rolls.<br />
<strong>Stinky tofu:</strong> Fermented tofu, often sold as a snack.<br />
<strong>Shanghai hairy crab:</strong> Considered a delicacy in eastern China.<br />
<strong>Oyster omelette:</strong> A speciality of the Fujian region.<br />
<strong>Hainanese chicken rice:</strong> A Hainan dish also popular in Southeast Asia.<br />
<strong>Baijiu:</strong> A strong alcoholic spirit, also known as sorghum wine.<br />
<strong>Tsingtao:</strong> The most common of China&rsquo;s beers, similar to German lager.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Still not officially approved of, tipping is becoming more commonplace in China. It is usual in tourist hotels and restaurants, and with tour guides and drivers. A service charge is often added by restaurants in large hotels.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Although China has no minimum legal drinking age, a ban on the sale of alcohol to under-18s was introduced in January 2006.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shanghai and Beijing have world-class nightlife scenes, with an eclectic array of international restaurants, bars, cocktail lounges, live music venues and nightclubs heaving until the early hours. Outside the cosmopolitan cities, evening entertainment tends to be restricted to restaurants, karaoke parlours and gaming halls, where people gather to play cards, snooker and mahjong. Increasingly, bars at newly built international hotels are other possible options but they tend to be harder on the wallet. In general the travellers to larger cities can sample something of the culture with visits to Chinese opera, circus, ballet and theatre.</p>
<p>Karaoke (written OK+ on Chinese signs) is very popular countrywide, with some karaoke venues offering over 100 private rooms, dinner buffets and 24-hour service. Traditional local music and dancing (for the benefit of visitors) is often found in areas where there are strong ethnic minority groups, notably in provinces including Yunnan, Guizhou, Guangxi and Sichuan.</p>
<p>Out in the countryside, the nightlife tends to be restricted to traditional dances and drinking to celebrate special occasions, or on an ordinary night, evenings spent playing cards or watching television.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While uncommon in larger stores, haggling is a big part of the buying process in markets (of which there are many) for items such as jade, antique ceramics, local handicrafts, silk garments and other bric-a-brac. All antiques over 100 years old are marked with a red wax seal by the authorities and require an export customs certificate. Beijing's fascinating Panjiayuan market opens every day, although it is best at weekends. Dongtai Lu in Shanghai hosts a popular street market for antiques and repro curios. When haggling, a smile and a certain amount of respect both go an awfully long way.</p>
<p>In Beijing, Shanghai and many other large cities, massive department stores sell everything from luxury fashion to high-tech electronics. In big cities and tourist towns, English is often spoken by shop assistants. You can usually make yourself understood by pointing, otherwise someone nearby will generally speak a little English. Good shops are found in major centres like Shanghai's Nanjing Road or Beijing's Wanfujing. Other enclaves well worth a visit for local designer boutiques are Taikang Lu in Shanghai and Nanluoguxiang in Beijing. Hong Kong is also widely renowned for its retail options, whether you&rsquo;re after electronic goods or catwalk labels.</p>
<p>You can also get handicrafts direct from shops at local factories, from shops specialising in the sale of handicrafts, and at art-and-craft department stores. Special purchases include jade jewellery, embroidery, calligraphy, paintings and carvings in wood, stone and bamboo. Shop personnel often pack and arrange shipping for bulky items. Keep receipts, as visitors may be asked to produce them at customs prior to departure. Hotel shops are more expensive than local shops.</p><p>Mon-Sun 1000-2130, although times vary across the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels have sprung up all over urban China, with the big-name international chains all having a presence in Beijing, Shanghai and increasingly Guangzhou and Shenzhen. The alarming pace of openings means there is no shortage of accommodation, even in peak season, with the range spanning everything from the lowest of budgets to blinged out luxury.</p>
<p>The expansion of high-end Far East groups such as the Shangri-La and Mandarin Oriental brands, has helped raise standards to the point where top hotels more than match the quality of other Asian destinations.. The most impressive choice of accommodation is in cities like Shanghai and Beijing &ndash; unsurprisingly, costs are usually more expensive too. Star ratings for domestically-run hotels can be somewhat generous Facilities generally include restaurants, coffee shops, bars, swimming pools and massage rooms. Some include executive floors and lounges, spas, shopping and business malls, banks and post offices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfast has grown in popularity as an accommodation option for travellers. These can range from down-at-heel affairs which deliver the basics, to smart quirky alternatives to a more expensive hotels. Often called guest houses, these properties can be found in rural areas as well as cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels have sprung up all over urban China, with the big-name international chains all having a presence in Beijing, Shanghai and increasingly Guangzhou and Shenzhen. The alarming pace of openings means there is no shortage of accommodation, even in peak season, with the range spanning everything from the lowest of budgets to blinged out luxury.</p>
<p>The expansion of high-end Far East groups such as the Shangri-La and Mandarin Oriental brands, has helped raise standards to the point where top hotels more than match the quality of other Asian destinations.. The most impressive choice of accommodation is in cities like Shanghai and Beijing &ndash; unsurprisingly, costs are usually more expensive too. Star ratings for domestically-run hotels can be somewhat generous Facilities generally include restaurants, coffee shops, bars, swimming pools and massage rooms. Some include executive floors and lounges, spas, shopping and business malls, banks and post offices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels have sprung up all over urban China, with the big-name international chains all having a presence in Beijing, Shanghai and increasingly Guangzhou and Shenzhen. The alarming pace of openings means there is no shortage of accommodation, even in peak season, with the range spanning everything from the lowest of budgets to blinged out luxury.</p>
<p>The expansion of high-end Far East groups such as the Shangri-La and Mandarin Oriental brands, has helped raise standards to the point where top hotels more than match the quality of other Asian destinations.. The most impressive choice of accommodation is in cities like Shanghai and Beijing &ndash; unsurprisingly, costs are usually more expensive too. Star ratings for domestically-run hotels can be somewhat generous Facilities generally include restaurants, coffee shops, bars, swimming pools and massage rooms. Some include executive floors and lounges, spas, shopping and business malls, banks and post offices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical services tend to be offered through local hospitals rather than private clinics, but tourists are advised to have travel insurance which covers medical costs as many hospitals will expect payment in cash before giving treatment. Costs at local hospitals are low and standards vary. Travellers are advised to take a friend who can translate if going to a local hospital, as many of the medical staff will not understand English. Medical facilities in international hospitals (these are located in the bigger cities) are much better and many common drugs are available over the counter. Traditional Chinese medicine treatments are also used widely in China, such as acupuncture, meridian massage, cupping and herbal medications.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water used for drinking, brushing teeth or freezing should first be boiled or otherwise sterilised. Bottled water, widely and cheaply available, is the most advisable way of getting around this. Be especially careful when eating at small street-side stalls or restaurants where standards of hygiene may not be high. Pork, salad, scallops, snails and mayonnaise may carry increased risk. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and Japanese encephalitis are sometimes advised. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is endemic in the central Yangtze river basin. Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Hepatitis E is prevalent in northeastern and northwestern China and hepatitis B is highly endemic. Sporadic outbreaks of avian influenza (bird flu) have resulted in a small number of human deaths. Rabies is present. If bitten, medical advice should be sought immediately. There are occasional outbreaks of dengue fever. In 2010 China lifted its restrictions preventing HIV-infected visitors from travelling there.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>In addition to the Public Holidays listed, other holidays may be observed locally and certain groups have official Public Holidays on the following dates:<br />
<strong><br />
8 Mar </strong>International Women's Day.<br />
<strong>4 May </strong>National Youth Day.<br />
<strong>23 May </strong>Tibet Liberation Day.<br />
<strong>1 Jun </strong>International Children's Day.<br />
<strong>1 Aug </strong>Army Day.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Labour Day :
							29 April </p><p>National Day :
							01 October </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into China without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 100 cigarettes and 100 cigars and 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1.1L of alcoholic beverages with 12% or more alcoholic content.<br />
&bull; Personal articles up to a value of &yen;5,000 for Chinese residents.<br />
&bull; Personal articles which will be left in China up to a value of &yen;2,000 for non-residents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arms and ammunition, imitation arms, narcotics, fruit, animals and animal products, and any publication (print, audio or video) directed against the public order and the morality of China.</p>
<p>Customs officials may seize audio and videotapes, books, records and CDs to check for pornographic, political or religious material. You must complete baggage declaration forms upon arrival noting all valuables (such as cameras, watches and jewellery); this may be checked on departure. You should keep receipts for items such as jewellery, jade, handicrafts, paintings, calligraphy or other similar items in order to obtain an export certificate from the authorities on leaving. Without this documentation, you cannot take such items out of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All articles banned from import as well as publications or media containing state secrets, valuable cultural artefacts, and endangered/rare animals and plants (and their seeds).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1 Renminbi Yuan (CNY; symbol ¥) = 10 jiao/mao or 100 fen. Notes are in denominations of ¥100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 1, 5 jiao and 1 jiao. Coins are in denominations of ¥1, 5 jiao and 1 jiao. Counterfeit ¥50 and ¥100 notes are commonplace. The Yuan is often referred to as the 'guai' in street slang.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to exchange CNY outside China, albeit mainly in Southeast Asia and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a>. Foreign banknotes and traveller's cheques can be exchanged at branches of The Bank of China. In hotels for tourists, imported luxury items such as spirits may be bought with Western currency. Scottish and Northern Irish banknotes cannot be exchanged.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, Mastercard and Visa are widely accepted in major provincial cities in designated establishments. Credit cards are often unlikely to be accepted away from the major cities.</p><p>ATMs can generally be found in airports, hotels, shopping centres and banks, as well as in many major cities and towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1600/1700. Some banks close for lunch from 1200-1300. Select branches in major cities offer extended hours in the evenings and on weekends.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter China, a passport with at least six months' validity is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>
<p>To enter Hong Kong, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by nationals in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As of 2018, nationals from 53 countries can visit certain parts of China <strong>without a visa for up to 144 hours (six days)</strong> if you're transiting through Beijing, Hebei, Jiangsu, Liaoning, Shanghai, Tianjin and Zhejiang. The key point is you must depart China within 144 hours (six days) for another international destination.</p>
<p>Example 1: if you are flying from New York to Beijing and onwards to Singapore within 144 hours (six days), you can visit Beijing without a visa.</p>
<p>Example 2: if you are flying from London to Shanghai and back to London after five days, you must apply for a visa as you do not transit in China.</p>
<p>The 53 countries whose citizens can take advantage of this 144-hour visa-free transit include: Albania, Argentina, Austria, Australia, Belarus, Belgium, Bosnia-Herzegovina, Brazil, Brunei, Bulgaria, Canada, Chile, Croatia, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Denmark, Estonia, Finland, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Iceland, Ireland, Italy, Japan, Korea (South), Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Malta, Mexico, Monaco, Montenegro, Macedonia (FYROM), Netherlands, New Zealand, Poland, Portugal, Qatar, Romania, Russia, Serbia, Singapore, Slovakia, Slovenia, Spain, Sweden, Switzerland, United Arab Emirates, United Kingdom, and Ukraine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>If you're applying in the UK, the following fees apply:</strong></p>
<p>Single-entry: &pound;30 (UK nationals), &pound;65 (US nationals), &pound;20 (other nationals).</p>
<p>Double-entry:&nbsp;&pound;45 (UK nationals), &pound;65 (US nationals), &pound;30 (other nationals).</p>
<p>Multiple-entry for six months: &pound;60 (UK nationals), &pound;65 (US nationals), &pound;40 (other nationals).</p>
<p>You must also pay a service fee of &pound;34.50 (standard) or &pound;46 (express).</p>
<p><strong>If you're applying in the USA, the following fees apply:</strong></p>
<p>Single-entry: US$140 (US nationals), US$30 (other nationals).</p>
<p>Double-entry: US$140 (US nationals), US$45 (other nationals).</p>
<p>Multiple-entry for six months: US$140 (US nationals), US$60 (other nationals).</p>
<p>You may also choose to pay exta US$20 for an express service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visas are normally valid for three months, double-entry for six months, and multiple-entry either six, 12 or 24 months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). Many consulates (including those in the UK) issue visas through the Chinese Visa Application Service Centre (<a href="http://www.visaforchina.org">www.visaforchina.org</a>) rather than directly through the consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa applications for China should be made one month in advance.</p>
<p>The express service requires three days, and the regular service takes four days.</p>
<p>Postal applications are usually processed and returned within 10 working days, if all the documentation is in good order.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[36.553995]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[104.055965]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>9,596,960 sq km (3,705,406 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,382,323,332 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>142.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Beijing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>People's Republic. China comprises 23 provinces (China considers Taiwan its 23rd province), five autonomous regions, two special administrative regions and four municipalities directly under central government.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>China is bordered to the north by Russia and Mongolia; to the east by Korea (Dem Rep), the Yellow Sea and the South China Sea; to the south by Vietnam, Laos, Myanmar, India, Bhutan and Nepal; and to the west by India, Pakistan, Afghanistan, Tajikistan, Kyrgyzstan and Kazakhstan. China has a varied terrain ranging from high plateaux in the west to flatlands in the east; mountains take up almost one-third of the land.</p>
<p>The most notable high mountain ranges are the Himalayas, the Altai Mountains, the Tian Shan Mountains and the Kunlun Mountains. On the border with Nepal is the 8,848m (29,198ft) Mount Qomolangma (Mount Everest). In the west is the Qinghai/Tibet Plateau, with an average elevation of 4,000m (13,200ft), known as 'the Roof of the World'. At the base of the Tian Shan Mountains is the Turpan Depression or Basin, China's lowest area, 154m (508ft) below sea level at the lowest point. China has many great river systems, notably the Yellow (Huang He) and Yangtze River (Chang Jiang, also Yangtze Kiang). Only 10% of all China is suitable for agriculture.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>China is officially atheist, but the stated religions and philosophies are Buddhism, Daoism and Confucianism. There are 100 million Buddhists and approximately 60 million Muslims, 5 million Protestants (including large numbers of Evangelicals) and 4 million Roman Catholics, largely independent of Vatican control.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cultural differences may create misunderstandings between local people and visitors. The Chinese do not usually volunteer information and the visitor is advised to ask questions. Hotels, train dining cars and restaurants often ask for criticisms and suggestions, which are considered seriously. Do not be offended if you are followed by a crowd; this is merely an open interest in visitors who are rare in the remoter provinces. The Chinese are generally reserved in manner, courtesy rather than familiarity being preferred. <br />
<br />
The full title of the country is 'The People's Republic of China', and this should be used in all formal communications. 'China' can be used informally, but there should never be any implication that another China exists. Although handshaking may be sufficient, a visitor will frequently be greeted by applause as a sign of welcome. The customary response is to applaud back. Anger, if felt, is expected to be concealed and arguments in public may attract hostile attention. <br />
<br />
In China, the family name is always mentioned first. It is customary to arrive a little early if invited out socially. When dining, guests should wait until their seat is allocated and not begin eating until indicated to do so. If using chopsticks, do not position them upright in your rice bowl as the gesture symbolises death. Toasting at a meal is very common, as is the custom of taking a treat when visiting someone's home, such as fruit, confectionery or a souvenir from a home country. If it is the home of friends or relatives, money may be left for the children. <br />
<br />
If visiting a school or a factory, a gift from the visitor's home country, particularly something which would be unavailable in China (a text book if visiting a school, for example), would be much appreciated. Stamps are also very popular as gifts, as stamp-collecting is a popular hobby in China. A good gift for an official guide is a Western reference book on China. <br />
<br />
Conservative casual wear is generally acceptable everywhere and revealing clothes should be avoided since they may cause offence. Visitors should avoid expressing political or religious opinions. <br />
<br />
<strong>Photography: </strong>Places of historic and scenic interest may be photographed, but permission should be sought before photographing military installations, government buildings or other possibly sensitive subjects.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. However, most 4- to 5-star hotels are also wired for 110-volt appliances. American-style plugs with two flat pins and Australian-style plugs with three flat, angled pins are most commonly used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Premier Li Keqiang since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Xi Jinping since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The planet&rsquo;s most populous nation also stands as one of its most influential &ndash; certainly on the political stage &ndash; but the concept of collective dominance is by no means a new one to the country. In broad summary, its history has alternated between periods of disunity and periods of strong national togetherness.</p>
<p>The first time the Chinese were truly united into a single empire was under the Qin Dynasty &ndash; builders of the initial stretches of the Great Wall &ndash; in the 3rd century BC. Power then passed into the hands of the less controlling Han Dynasty for four centuries, after which there was a long period of bitter internal conflict. The last dynasty, the Qing, survived until 1911, when Sun Yat-sen founded the Republic of China.</p>
<p>The Japanese invaded in 1937, resulting in eight years of brutal occupation. When the invaders were eventually repelled, civil war ensued between nationalists and Mao Zedong&rsquo;s communists. In 1949, the victorious communists founded the People's Republic of China, giving rise to the notorious Cultural Revolution and, among other things, the still ongoing occupation of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tibet">Tibet</a>.</p>
<p>Even Chinese historians remain divided on the legacy of Mao, who may have helped assimilate China into a single-minded nation but was also responsible for horrific injustices on a monumental scale. He died in 1976, and only a few years later his successor, Deng Xioaping, felt bold enough to announce that Mao&rsquo;s leadership had been &lsquo;70% good, 30% bad&rsquo;.</p>
<p>By the end of the 1980s, there was widespread agitation in favour of political reform, and action against the corruption that had become widespread. The situation came to a head in May 1989, when several thousand students and workers occupied Tiananmen Square. The army was sent in and the square cleared, with great loss of life.</p>
<p>As the 1990s progressed, those at the top of Chinese politics were gradually replaced. Jiang Zemin, who was appointed president in 1993, typified the new generation of leaders. Vice-President Hu Jintao took over the presidency from Jiang in 2003, and saw the country&rsquo;s role as a forward-looking, although still tightly controlled, economic powerhouse become more defined.</p>
<p>Hu was followed by current incumbent Xi Jinping, who came to power in 2013 promising to quash corruption. He has since had to deal with a deeply uncertain Chinese economic climate.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong>     <br />
&bull; There are more Christians in China (some 54 million) than there are in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a>.   <br />
&bull; It was reported in 2013 that Chinese police in Xinjiang were working with geese, the birds apparently being &lsquo;better than dogs&rsquo; at tackling crime. <br />
&bull; <em>Ke-tsiap</em>, a spicy Chinese fish sauce, gave its name to &lsquo;ketchup&rsquo;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in China]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>0(10) 5192 4000 ; 0(10) 8529 6600 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>0(10) 5192 4000 ; 0(10) 8529 6600 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1200 and 1330-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Jian Guo Men Wai<br/>11 Guang Hua Lu<br/>Beijing<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the People's Republic of China in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 495 2266 ; (202) 338 6688 (visa section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.china-embassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 495 2266 ; (202) 338 6688 (visa section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1730; Mon-Fri 0930-1230 and 1330-1500 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3505 International Place<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the People's Republic of China in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>020) 7299 4049 ; (020) 7631 1430 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.chinese-embassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>020) 7299 4049 ; (020) 7631 1430 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1200 and 1400-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>49-51 Portland Place<br/>London<br/>W1B 1JL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Colossal, dizzying and fiercely foreign, China isn&rsquo;t easily compared to anywhere else on the planet. Home to approximately one fifth of the human race, it variously dazzles, befuddles, frustrates and thrills. The key visitor attractions are renowned around the globe &ndash; think the Great Wall, the Forbidden City, and the Terracotta Warriors &ndash; but it&rsquo;s the sheer scale and off-kilter energy of the place that leave the most lasting impression.</p>
<p>The economic drive of recent times means many of China&rsquo;s cities are as shaped by modernity as anywhere you care to mention, but it&rsquo;s also somewhere underpinned by dearly held customs and a near-unfathomable amount of diversity. China's landscapes unfurl across the map in vast swathes of territory, and its sights, sounds and infinite oddities collectively amount to one of the world&rsquo;s truly great travel experiences. The food&rsquo;s fantastic too, and getting to grips with the different regional cuisines can be hugely enjoyable.</p>
<p>In other areas, tradition only counts for so much. The pace of development in its key cities &ndash; Shanghai, Beijing, Guangzhou and increasingly others &ndash; has thrown up skylines to rival almost any in the world. They&rsquo;re emblematic of the &lsquo;new&rsquo; China, a powerhouse both economically and politically; somewhere eager to make the rest of the world sit up and take notice. Even the ego-driven rulers of the past, from Qin Shi Huang through to Mao, would surely be amazed at just how influential their country has become.</p>
<p>Shift away from the urban sprawl and out into China&rsquo;s rural areas, however, and you&rsquo;re confronted with a very different reality. The scenery veers from lush terraced rice paddies and the harsh peaks of the Himalayas to the gorges of the UNESCO-protected Yangtze River. In some of the rural heartlands, indeed, the tableau of life can seem little changed from 50 years ago, at least on the surface. China is full of endless quirks and contradictions, but that&rsquo;s half the charm.</p><p>Colossal, dizzying and fiercely, endlessly foreign, China is a destination not easily compared to anywhere else on the planet. Home to approximately one fifth of the human race, China variously dazzles, befuddles, frustrates and thrills. The key visitor attractions are renowned around the globe &ndash; think the Great Wall, the Forbidden City, and the Terracotta Warriors &ndash; but on the ground it&rsquo;s the sheer scale and off-kilter energy of the place that leave the most lasting impression. China's landscapes unfurl dramatically across the map, its customs are as fascinating as they are numerous, and its sights, sounds and infinite oddities altogether amount to one of the world&rsquo;s truly great travel experiences.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
