<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Macau" ColCode="mac" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mo" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Macau]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau has a subtropical climate, with temperatures regulated by its coastal location. Seasonal changes are heavily influenced by monsoons: it is warm and humid when southeast and southwest winds come in from the Pacific, drier and colder when the north winds come from Siberia and northern <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/">China</a>.<br />
<br />
Winter for Macau runs from November to February, which is when the northeast monsoon prevails, and is generally cold and dry. Spring comes in March and April, in the transition between the two monsoons, and brings with it wet and foggy weather. From May to September, during the southern monsoon, it is hot and rainy (with most rain occurring in the afternoon). Autumn, from the late September through October, is sunny and comfortably warm. <br />
<br />
The average temperature for the year is around 23C (73F). In winter it can get as low as 10C (50F), while in summer it can reach the low 30s (86F). Winds can reach gale force and typhoons, coming in from the Pacific Ocean, are not unknown. They tend to hit between May and October, bringing with them rain and lower temperatures. Overall the best time to visit is autumn (October to December), when days are sunny and warm and the humidity low.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wear light cotton clothes in summer, take a sweater for cooler nights from September to November and a jacket for winter. Be prepared for rain at any time, but particularly from May to September.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau is too small for domestic flights to be useful.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A harbour sightseeing cruise offers the opportunity to sail along the city&rsquo;s coastline while taking in the views of attractions including the A-Ma Temple and the Macau Tower. The Macau Harbour Cruise runs daily from the historical Inner Harbour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The island is accessible via three bridges running from the peninsula to Taipa Island. Another connects the Cotai Strip (the reclaimed land between Taipa and Coloane) to the Macau-China border at Zhuhai.</p>l<p>Although generally well surfaced, many roads in Macau are narrow, winding and steep; traffic can be congested throughout the day.</p><p>Buses run between the peninsula, Taipa and Coloane, as well as to the airport (you can catch bus AP1, AP1X, MT1, MT2, MT4, N2, 26, 36, 51A).</p><p>Taxis are either black with a cream-coloured top, or all-yellow (the latter are radio taxis). They generally have a destination guide written in Chinese, English and Portuguese, which is helpful since many drivers speak little English and may know only the Chinese names for key sites. Prices are reasonable and meters are used. There are surcharges for luggage carried in the boot, for taking a taxi from the airport or travelling from Macau to Coloane.</p>
<p><strong>Rickshaws and pedicabs (cycle rickshaws):</strong> These are available for hire but many of Macau's attractions are located on hilltops, beyond the reach of even the strongest-legged pedicab driver. Prices should always be agreed in advance.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is recommended.</p><p>The speed limit varies according to the road type. In built-up areas it can be as low as 20kph (12mph) or as high as 60kph (37mph), while on open roads and highways the highest limit is 80kph (50mph).</p><p>Car hire agencies should be able to provide contact details for breakdown services.</p><p>Since the territory is small, with good public transport and affordable taxis, it is generally not necessary to hire a car. If it is required, however, car hire is easily available through several agencies including large international companies; drivers must be over 21. Chauffeur-driven limousines are also available.</p><p>You can hire bikes on Taipa and Coloane but can't take them to the mainland. Bear in mind that parts of Macau are quite hilly, so cycling can be hard work; generally speaking, Coloane is the most suitable area for cycling.</p><p>The speed limit varies according to the road type. In built-up areas it can be as low as 20kph (12mph) or as high as 60kph (37mph), while on open roads and highways the highest limit is 80kph (50mph).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main areas of interest to tourists are compact enough to get around on foot, while longer journeys (including those between the peninsula and the islands) are easily made by taxi or bus.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau has its own airline, Air Macau (<a href="http://www.airmacau.com.mo">www.airmacau.com.mo</a>), which operates regional flights. Visitors from outside of Asia are more likely to fly into <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/hong-kong/">Hong Kong</a> and then visit Macau by ferry; Hong Kong is served by numerous airlines including Cathay Pacific (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.cathaypacific.com/">www.cathaypacific.com</a>).</p>
<p>For those with plenty of disposable income, it&rsquo;s also possible to arrive in Macau by helicopter. Sky Shuttle (<a href="http://www.skyshuttlehk.com/" target="_blank">www.skyshuttlehk.com</a>) operates services from the Hong Kong Ferry terminal &ndash; the flight only takes 15 minutes. It also operates flights from Shenzen airport.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Entry is usually via Hong Kong from Europe and North America.</p>
<p>To Hong Kong: from <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/united-kingdom/england/london/">London</a> - 18 hours; <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/north-america/united-states-of-america/new-york-state/new-york-city/">New York</a> - 21 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau International Airport is located on the eastern side of Taipa, the northernmost of Macau&rsquo;s two connected islands. Taipa is linked to the peninsula by three bridges. From the airport, several bus services run to destinations on the islands and on the peninsula. Taxis are also easily available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the ticket cost.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau International Airport is located on the eastern side of Taipa, the northernmost of Macau&rsquo;s two connected islands. Taipa is linked to the peninsula by three bridges. From the airport, several bus services run to destinations on the islands and on the peninsula. Taxis are also easily available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Macau International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.macau-airport.com]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(853) 5988 888</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Services run to Macau from Hong Kong, Shenzen, Wan Chai and Guangzhou. Ferries from Hong Kong dock at the Jetfoil Terminal on Avenida da Amizade, while those from the Chinese mainland arrive at the China Ferry Port on Avenida de Almeida Ribeiro (San Ma Lo).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no train services between Macau and mainland China. A light rail is currently under construction and the closest stop is the Zhuhai Railway Station. There are, however, trains to Hong Kong from Guangzhou, Dongguan, Foshan, Zhaoqing, <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/shanghai/">Shanghai</a> and <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/beijing/">Beijing</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau is linked by road to mainland <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/">China</a>, with two main points of arrival. One is the Barrier Gate, also known as the Portas do Cerco which is open daily 0600-0100 on the peninsula.&nbsp;The other is the Gongbei Port of Entry, open 0700-0000, on the southern part of Zhuhai. The Kee Kwan Motor Road Co is a bus company that operates buses from Guangdong province between 0800-2000, which go to Guangzhou leaving every 15 minutes and Zhongshan leaving every 20 minutes.</p><p>Macau has its own immigration rules and the crossings from mainland China are treated like international border crossings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International calls can be made from phone booths, the General Post Office in Senado Square, and the Central Post Offices in Taipa and Col&ocirc;ane. It&rsquo;s cheaper, though, to make international calls via the internet. Local calls cost MOP$1 from a public phone, but are free from private land lines (hotels usually add a charge).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet facilities are available at the Information Counter at Senado Square, and in the central library and its branches, but there are also many internet cafes in the city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau's media companies are a mix of private and government run. The Government Information Bureau oversees the media and broadcasters. While Macau's press undoubtedly enjoys more freedom than mainland media, its independence is still tempered somewhat. Media is split between Portuguese-, English- and Chinese-language publications. Portuguese dailies include <em>Hoje Macau </em>and <em>Jornal Tribuna de Macau</em>. &nbsp;Chinese dailies include <em>Macau Daily News </em>and <em>Va Kio Daily</em>. English dailies include <em>Macau Post Daily</em> and <em>Macau</em><em> Daily Times.</em> There is also an English-language monthly business magazine, <em>Macau Business</em>.</p>
<p>In terms of television, the public network&nbsp;Teledifus&atilde;o  Macau (TDM) operates two free-to-air channels, one in Chinese (Cantonese and Mandarin) and one in Portuguese (with news bulletins also in English). TDM also offers several premium channels. There are also several private companies broadcasting satellite channels. Radio Macau, part of TDM, operates Chinese and Portuguese-language stations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes five to seven days. Automatic vending machines are available at various locations for stamps.</p><p>Opening times vary. Some at key locations including the ferry terminal and airport open Mon-Sat 1000-1900. The Senadao Square head office opens Mon-Fri 0900-1800 and Sat 0900-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>A-Ma Temple</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dedicated to the Chinese goddess of the sea known as Mazu, this temple is the oldest place of worship in Macau. Founded before the arrival of the Portuguese, it inadvertently gave its name to the colony &ndash; Macau is a corruption of <em>A-Ma Kok</em> (the Bay of A-Ma) &ndash; but the current complex dates from the 17th century.</p>]]><p><b>Camões Garden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The pleasant Jardim Luís de Camões (Camões Garden) is named after Portugal's favourite poet, active in the 16th century and said to have visited Macau (although this has been disputed). It is, nevertheless, a popular place to exercise or relax.</p>]]><p><b>Colôane Island (Freguesia de São Francisco Xavier)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The larger of Macau's two connected islands, Col&ocirc;ane is perfect for a day trip. Nature trails thread among the hills in Seac Pai Van Park, which also has a walk-in aviary and spectacular views from the A-Ma Statue at the highest point on the island. The best of the beaches is the black-sand H&aacute;c S&aacute;, while Col&ocirc;ane village is an atmospheric place with cobbled streets.</p>]]><p><b>Cotai Strip</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The epicentre for casino development in Macau, the Cotai Strip is reclaimed land which has joined together the islands of Col&ocirc;ane and Taipa (hence the name Cotai). It&rsquo;s where you will find many of the biggest and most opulent casinos &ndash; including the Venetian, the Wynn and the Sands. These mega-complexes have helped Macau to race ahead of Las Vegas when it comes to gambling income.</p>]]><p><b>Festivals</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Macau's colourful festivals include the Dragon Boat Festival in June; the International Fireworks Display Contest, which sees 90 countries competing for honours in September/October; and the Macau International Music Festival, which presents works in Chinese and Western styles throughout October.</p>]]><p><b>Gate of Understanding</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The massive Gate of Understanding (designed by Charters Almeida), stands at 40m (130ft) high over the Praia Grande Bay. This is a symbolic structure representing the goodwill between China and Portugal.</p>]]><p><b>Guia Hill Fortress</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Built at the highest point in Macau, the Guia Hill Fortress dates back to the 17th century and can be reached by cable car or along a walking path which encircles the hill offering views over the city and its bays. Nearby is a fascinating series of wartime bunkers cut into the hill and a small museum telling the stories of those who served here; also note the faded frescoes inside the chapel building, which were uncovered during renovations. The Guia Lighthouse, standing since 1865, is still functional. As well as guiding ships through Macanese waters, its high vantage point is also used to warn the city of impending typhoons.</p>]]><p><b>Historic Centre of Macau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Given UNESCO World Heritage status in 2005, the old city has eight squares and 22 historic buildings. The narrow lanes, markets and sloping cobbles combine the architectural drama of backstreet Porto and the bustling energy, cooking smells and Cantonese dialect of southern China. The focal point is the Largo do Senado, or Senate Square, which holds the Santa Casa de Miseric&oacute;rdia (a Portuguese charitable institution) as well as the Macau General Post Office. Numerous other attractions are found within the old city, including the ruined fa&ccedil;ade of St Paul&rsquo;s church.</p>]]><p><b>Kun Iam Temple</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the complex of temples known as Kun Iam Tong, the biggest and wealthiest of Macau's temples. It dates from the time of the Ming Dynasty, about 400 years ago, and contains, amongst other works of art, a small statue of Marco Polo. In the garden you can see the granite temple where, in 1844, the first trade treaty between the United States and China was signed.</p>]]><p><b>Lou Lim Ieoc Garden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A good place to get away from the busy streets of Macau, this Chinese-style garden includes lotus ponds and bamboo groves. It was once a private garden but fell into ruin before it was bought by the government in 1974, and restored for use as a public park. Today it&rsquo;s a popular spot to practice tai chi.&nbsp;Local legend says the nine windy turns in park&rsquo;s bridge are supposed to confuse evil spirits trying to cross.</p>]]><p><b>Macau Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Macau Museum covers the life of Macau and its people from the first settlement to the present day. Set over three floors, it contains a vast collection of historic and social memorabilia (<a href="http://www.macaumuseum.gov.mo" target="_blank">www.macaumuseum.gov.mo</a>). The location, in the Fortaleza do Monte (Mount Fortress), means that the museum also boasts great views.</p>]]><p><b>Macau Tower</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy panoramic views - or bungee jump - from the Macau Tower (<a href="http://www.macautower.com.mo" target="_blank">www.macautower.com.mo</a>), an entertainment and convention centre situated on the waterfront on the Nam Van Lakes. The 338m (1,109ft) tower is one of the tallest freestanding towers in the world, and on a clear day you can see for 55km (34 miles) from the observation deck. Intrepid souls can take a walk around the outer rim while safely clipped to an overhead rail.</p>]]><p><b>Racing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Macau Jockey Club organises flat horse races on the island of Taipa (<a href="http://www.mjc.mo">www.mjc.mo</a>). The Far East's gala motorcycle and Formula III car racing event, the Macau Grand Prix, is held in November (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.macau.grandprix.gov.mo/">www.macau.grandprix.gov.mo</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Ruins of St Paul's</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Part of the UNESCO-listed Historic Centre of Macau, the ruins of the Church of St Paul's (S&atilde;o Paulo), which was built in 1602, are probably the most famous sight in the region. Although on the approach it looks like the building is intact, actually only the fa&ccedil;ade survived a fire in 1835. It is, nevertheless, an almost-compulsory photo stop on any visit to Macau.</p>]]><p><b>St Dominic's Church</b></p><![CDATA[<p>St Dominic&rsquo;s Church (Igreja de S&atilde;o Domingos), built in the 17th century and renovated in 1997, is one of the most beautiful religious buildings in Macau. A Museum of Sacred Art, on three floors of the renovated belfry, is home to 300 works&nbsp;including sacred Brazilian artwork which together illustrate the history of the Catholic Church in Asia.</p>]]><p><b>Taipa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The smaller of Macau&rsquo;s two islands, Taipa is the location of Macau&rsquo;s international airport. The main point of interest is Taipa Village, a busy place with Chinese shophouses, colonial Portuguese offices and plenty of places to eat (particularly on the Rua da Cunha). Many traditional crafts are still followed in the narrow streets and alleys, and there&rsquo;s a craft fair on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$44.8 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Clothing, textiles, footwear, toys, electronics and machinery.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Raw materials and semi-manufactured goods, consumer goods (food, drinks and tobacco), capital goods, mineral fuels and oil.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/">China (PR)</a>, <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/hong-kong/">Hong Kong</a>, <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/france/">France</a>, <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/japan/">Japan</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/north-america/united-states-of-america/">USA</a> and <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/germany/">Germany</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau reverted to Chinese rule in December 1999, and under the &lsquo;one country, two systems&rsquo; policy its economy has retained its capitalist character &ndash; it&rsquo;s widely regarded as one of the most open (in other words, least regulated) in the world. The territory continues to function as a tax haven and as a free port with no foreign exchange control, and the continuation of Macau's economic autonomy has been guaranteed for 50 years.</p>
<p>The lack of natural resources means that agriculture is negligible in Macau, but the territory has long had an active manufacturing sector and acted as an important distribution outlet for Chinese products. Today, though, it&rsquo;s gambling which is driving growth.</p>
<p>After the handover, the existing casino monopoly was ended and it became easier for people from mainland <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/">China</a> to visit. As a result a massive casino resort construction boom has been under way since 2003. The large <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/north-america/united-states-of-america/nevada/las-vegas/">Las Vegas</a> operators have been investing heavily, bringing with them their name brands. All this has helped Macau to weather recent economic storms, and in 2010 Macau&rsquo;s growth in GDP (at 25%) was judged to be the fastest in the world.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Major meetings venues include the Macau Tower Conference Centre (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.macautower.com.mo/">www.macautower.com.mo</a>), in one of the world's tallest freestanding buildings which also features a revolving restaurant, entertainment area and shopping facilities. Many of the large new hotels which have opened in recent years, including The Venetian, MGM Grand and Wynn Macau, have state-of-the art meeting and dining facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople should dress smartly. Business cards are essential; Chinese people always hand business cards (or any piece of paper) with two hands, sometimes accompanied by a slight lowering of the head. Using just one hand may be interpreted as rudeness. Appointments should be made in advance and punctuality is appreciated. The World Trade Center (tel: +853 2872 7666; <a href="http://www.wtc-macau.com" target="_blank">www.wtc-macau.com</a>) offers assistance and various facilities for businesses, including&nbsp;a members only Executive Business Club.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800 with an hour for lunch, Sat 0900-1300. Most government offices are open from 0900-1300 and 1230-1800 on weekdays. Banks normally open from 0900-1700 weekdays and 0900-1200 on Saturday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Macau Government Tourism Office</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 2831 5566
					Website:http://www.macautourism.gov.mo/
					Address: 12o andar,Alameda Dr Carlos d'Assumpcao,Nos 335-341,Edificio 'Hot Line',,]]><b>Macau Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 2857 6833
					Website:http://www.acm.org.mo/
					Address: Rua de angai,Edificio ACM,5th Floor,,X]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The most tempting things to try are local Macanese specialities, along with the traditional Portuguese and Chinese dishes which contributed to it. Other Asian cuisines are also represented, however, including Japanese, Korean and Indonesian. You&rsquo;ll find other European cooking too, particularly in hotels and casinos; at the higher end is Robuchon au Dome&nbsp;and The Eight. Both restaurants boast earning three Michelin stars and are located the Grand Lisboa hotel.<br />
<br />
Macanese food is spicy, a unique combination of Chinese and Portuguese cooking methods with influences of Indian and African spices &ndash; the result of Portugual&rsquo;s various colonial activities. Restaurants known for their Macanese dishes can be found on Rua Almirante S&eacute;rgio, in the Outer Harbour New Land Reclamation Area (NAPE) and on Taipa island.<br />
<br />
There are also many restaurants which specialise in Chinese cooking, mostly Cantonese although other there are also places serving other regional cuisines such as spicy Szechuan. If you&rsquo;re particularly interested in Chinese seafood dishes then head for the harbour area, on and around Rua do Almirante S&eacute;rgio and Rua das Lorcha. For traditional Portuguese food, try Rua do Almirante S&eacute;rgio (near the A-Ma Temple), Rua Central and Travessa de S&atilde;o Domingos (both in the centre). You&rsquo;ll also find Portuguese restaurants on Coloane (in the village and on Hac-Sa beach) and Taipa (try Rua do Cunha).</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Bacalhau</em> (salted cod, a Portuguese speciality which can be served in many different ways). <br />
&bull;  <em>Caldo verde</em> (a Portuguese soup made from potatoes, onions and greens, with a variety of other ingredients sometimes including ham). <br />
&bull; <em>Sopa a alentejana</em> (a garlic and coriander soup with poached egg, another Portuguese dish). <br />
&bull; <em>Galinha Africana</em> (African chicken &ndash; a Macanese dish of chicken grilled and served with spicy peri peri sauce). <br />
&bull; <em>Galinha a portuguesa</em> (despite the name, this is really a Macanese dish of chicken baked with potatoes, onions and eggs in a coconut-based sauce). <br />
&bull; <em>Minchi</em> (this Macanese comfort food consists of minced meat &ndash; pork, beef or both &ndash; with fried potato and onion). <br />
&bull; <em>Ta pin nou</em> (a Chinese dish in which seafood, meats and vegetables that are boiled in a tureen at the table). <br />
&bull; <em>Dim sum</em> (available from dawn until around noon, with diners choosing from numerous small Chinese dishes &ndash; many of them steamed and served in small round bamboo baskets). <br />
&bull; <em>Pasteis de nata</em> (egg tarts, a cross between the European and Chinese kinds; often considered quintessentially Macanese, they were in fact invented only in the 1980s &ndash; but they are still an unmissable treat).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 10% service charge is added to most hotel and restaurant bills. A small tip should also be left.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are no alcohol licensing laws in Macau, and this means that there is no legal minimum drinking age.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For many visitors, gambling is the big attraction in Macau. Casinos are open 24 hours, providing baccarat, blackjack, roulette and Chinese games like <em>fantan </em>and <em>dai-siu </em>(big and small) in surroundings ranging from slightly seedy to spectacular. Most nightlife is centred on the main hotels and casino resorts, many of which have nightclubs with cabaret, Portuguese folk dancing, dance bands and discos. Nightclub music often has Asian touches, with international pop sung in Cantonese, Mandarin, Thai and Japanese.</p>
<p>Outside of this, a lively bar strip has developed along Avenida Dr. Sun Yat-sen, near the Kun Iam Statue, with many bars offering live Filipino cover bands each night. Alternatively there are great views from Sky21 (<a href="http://www.sky21macau.com" target="_blank">www.sky21macau.com</a>), the bar on the 21st floor of the AIA Tower which also has a restaurant, dance floor and alfresco deck. There are also some popular bars on Taipa island, opposite the Macau Jockey Club. For nightclubs, which typically get going around midnight, try the Outer Harbour or Fisherman&rsquo;s Wharf.<br />
<br />
For international films, try the Cineteatro de Macau on Rua de Santa Clara. The Macau Cultural Centre shows art house and classic movies during a series of film festivals, which take place between September and December.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau is a popular shopping destination due to its free port status: there is no sales tax. Common buys include jewellery (particularly gold), Chinese antiques, porcelain, pottery, electronic gadgets, cameras, watches and beading work. For foodie treats, try dried seafood, abalone (which is something of an acquired taste), pastries or Portuguese wine &ndash; in particular <em>vinho verde</em>, literally &lsquo;green wine&rsquo; and drunk while it&rsquo;s very young. Chinese herbs and medicines are also widely available, although it&rsquo;s important to be aware of what you are buying &ndash; some traditional remedies are made from endangered animals, and quite apart from any moral objections, it may be illegal to import them into another country.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s plenty of variety when it comes to places to shop. Several glitzy luxury goods malls have sprung up around several of the new casino resorts, including Wynn Macau and The Venetian. A rather more down-to-earth shopping experience can be had at the Red Market on the corner of Avenida Horta e Costa and Avenida Almirante Lacerda. It&rsquo;s a three-storey building selling mostly food but also some clothing. There&rsquo;s also a street market running from the Red Market through the Three Lamps District (also known as Sam Jan Dang). The stalls sell mostly clothes and fabrics. The best-known gold shops are along Avenida do Infante D Henrique, Avenida Horta e Costa and Avenida Almeida Ribeiro. For porcelain, try Rua de S&atilde;o Paulo.</p>
<p>Macau also has some good street markets. There&rsquo;s a daily flea market in the lanes around Rua das Estalagens, near the ruins of St Paul's Church, as well as one every Sunday in Taipa Village between Bombeiros Square and Cam&otilde;es Square. These can be good for handicrafts, clothes and souvenirs, but always bargain over prices. There is an Artisan's Fair every Saturday evening in Santo Agostinho Square.</p><p>Generally daily 1000-1900, though some of the new luxury brand malls are open until 2100. Some shops may close on the first day of every month.</p><p>Bargaining is expected. For antiques, gold and jewellery, use officially-recommended shops; always ask for a warranty and receipt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau's hotel stock ranges from older colonial properties, inns and economy-class accommodation up to luxury havens from global chains, with the last of these coming into particular prominence now that Macau is successfully selling itself as an international casino destination. Most of Macau's small and mid-sized hotels are located on the peninsula, which has good access to most of the main tourist sights. The new wave of casino resorts on the Cotai Strip, however, have some of the most upmarket accommodation in the territory. A more laid-back alternative is to stay on one of the islands &ndash; there are several resort hotels on Coloane, for example.</p>
<p>The lure of the casinos mean that prices rise on Friday and Saturday nights, typically by around 20%. The Grand Prix in November also sees an influx of visitors and a rise in prices. In both cases an advance reservation is advised. All rates are subject to a 10% service charge, plus a 5% government tax. Cheaper places sometimes have different rates for single or double occupancy, while more expensive hotels just quote a price for the room.</p>
<p>If you arrive without a reservation, then try enquiring at the desk at the ferry terminal. They sometimes have good deals on hotels, and don&rsquo;t charge a fee &ndash; although you do have to pay a deposit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The nearest things to bed and breakfasts in Macau are the pousadas &ndash; hotels which are typically small and intimate. These include the Pousada de Coloane, the&nbsp;Pousada de Mong-H&aacute; and the Pousada de Sao Tiago. The last of these is perhaps the best known in Macau, an old fortress which is full of character.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau's hotel stock ranges from older colonial properties, inns and economy-class accommodation up to luxury havens from global chains, with the last of these coming into particular prominence now that Macau is successfully selling itself as an international casino destination. Most of Macau's small and mid-sized hotels are located on the peninsula, which has good access to most of the main tourist sights. The new wave of casino resorts on the Cotai Strip, however, have some of the most upmarket accommodation in the territory. A more laid-back alternative is to stay on one of the islands &ndash; there are several resort hotels on Coloane, for example.</p>
<p>The lure of the casinos mean that prices rise on Friday and Saturday nights, typically by around 20%. The Grand Prix in November also sees an influx of visitors and a rise in prices. In both cases an advance reservation is advised. All rates are subject to a 10% service charge, plus a 5% government tax. Cheaper places sometimes have different rates for single or double occupancy, while more expensive hotels just quote a price for the room.</p>
<p>If you arrive without a reservation, then try enquiring at the desk at the ferry terminal. They sometimes have good deals on hotels, and don&rsquo;t charge a fee &ndash; although you do have to pay a deposit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau's hotel stock ranges from older colonial properties, inns and economy-class accommodation up to luxury havens from global chains, with the last of these coming into particular prominence now that Macau is successfully selling itself as an international casino destination. Most of Macau's small and mid-sized hotels are located on the peninsula, which has good access to most of the main tourist sights. The new wave of casino resorts on the Cotai Strip, however, have some of the most upmarket accommodation in the territory. A more laid-back alternative is to stay on one of the islands &ndash; there are several resort hotels on Coloane, for example.</p>
<p>The lure of the casinos mean that prices rise on Friday and Saturday nights, typically by around 20%. The Grand Prix in November also sees an influx of visitors and a rise in prices. In both cases an advance reservation is advised. All rates are subject to a 10% service charge, plus a 5% government tax. Cheaper places sometimes have different rates for single or double occupancy, while more expensive hotels just quote a price for the room.</p>
<p>If you arrive without a reservation, then try enquiring at the desk at the ferry terminal. They sometimes have good deals on hotels, and don&rsquo;t charge a fee &ndash; although you do have to pay a deposit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Macau has a very good healthcare system, which is reflected by excellent life expectancy figures &amp;ndash; in 2017 the life expectancy from birth was one of the highest in Asia, at 84.6 years, and the fourth highest in the world. The private healthcare sector is expanding rapidly, partly thanks to government subsidies (under which vouchers are issued regularly to all permanent residents, to be redeemed at private health facilities).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trend has also been fuelled by provision of private healthcare as part of benefit packages offered to workers. In addition, traditional Chinese medicine is not usually available within the public system and so many people are willing to pay to receive it privately. There is still no western-style medical school in Macau so all doctors working in Macau have qualified overseas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tourists are not covered by the government healthcare scheme and therefore have to pay for any treatment required. This can be expensive, particularly if a hospital stay is required, and so insurance is recommended. Macau&amp;rsquo;s main public hospital is the Hospital Conde S. Janu&amp;aacute;rio (tel: +853 2831 3731; www.ssm.gov.mo), located in the Estrada do Visconde de S. Janu&amp;aacute;rio on the peninsula. The main private hospital, the Hospital Kiang Wu is also on the peninsula on Estrada Coelho do Amaral. In 2006 the Macau University of Science and Technology Hospital (tel: +853 2882 1838; www.uh.org.mo/en) opened in Cotai. More recently, the opening of the Malo Clinic Health and Wellness medical spa, at the Venetian casino resort, suggested tentative steps towards attracting the lucrative international medical tourism market (which is a major contributor to the economies of some countries in the region, such as &lt;a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/singapore/"&gt;Singapore&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pharmacists may be able to help with non-urgent medical problems, and branches of Watson&amp;rsquo;s and Manning&amp;rsquo;s can be found throughout the territory. For emergency medical services, dial 999 (although 112 can also be used).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is generally regarded as safe, but bottled water may be advisable for the first few days of a visit. Milk is pasteurised, but avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. As in many countries it&amp;rsquo;s safer to avoid raw vegetables, reheated foods and shellfish. Wash or peel fruit.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Before travelling, visit a doctor or travel health clinic for up-to-date advice on health risks. Japanese encephalitis may occur between April and October. Immunisation against hepatitis B and tuberculosis is sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is not considered to be any risk of catching malaria in Macau, but dengue fever incidents are not unknown. Like malaria, dengue fever is spread by mosquitoes, and symptoms include a rash, fever, headaches and pain in muscles and joints. In extreme cases the disease can become life-threatening. The risk should be minimised by reducing exposure to mosquito bites, by covering up and using a repellent; there is no vaccination currently available against dengue fever. Local brands of repellent are usually citronella-based, so bring your own DEET-based repellent.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>* Holiday is from 10-12 February.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>National Day of the People's Republic of China :
							01 October </p><p>All Soul's Day :
							02 November </p><p>Feast of the Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Macau Special Administrative Region Establishment Day :
							20 December </p><p>Christmas Eve :
							24 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Macau without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 19 cigarettes or 1 cigars or 25g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcohol over 30% volume.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited or restricted items include firearms and ammunition, narcotics, transceivers, chemicals and pharmaceutical products, and endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pataca (MOP; symbol MOP$) = 100 avos. Notes are in denominations of MOP$1,000, 500, 100, 50, 20 and 10. They are issued by two different banks, the Banco Nacional Ultramarino and the Bank of China, each of which uses its own designs. Coins are issued centrally in denominations of MOP$10, 5, 2 and 1, and 50, 20 and 10 avos. The pataca is loosely pegged to the Hong Kong dollar, but within Macau the two currencies are generally interchangeable &ndash; in fact the Hong Kong currency is preferred in some circumstances (such as in some casinos). Note that patacas cannot be used in <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/hong-kong/">Hong Kong</a>, and can be difficult to change once you have left the territory of Macau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency can be exchanged at hotels, banks and licensed bureaux de change. There are 24-hour exchange counters at Macau International Airport (Taipa Island). Transaction fees can be high at banks, although they generally offer a better exchange rate than private moneychangers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are accepted.</p><p>Numerous ATMs are available for cash withdrawal by international debit or credit cards, many of them dispensing both patacas and Hong Kong dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These may be exchanged at banks, bureaux de change and large hotels. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars, Pounds Sterling or Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700, Sat 0900-1200. Some banks and branches are open slightly longer hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for at least one month is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A visa is not normally required for transit passengers who remain in the airport international lounge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: MOP$100 for individuals or MOP$50 per head for groups.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The validity of visas (if required) depends upon factors including the nationality of the applicant. The visa on arrival is usually valid for 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you do require a visa, then in many cases you can obtain it at the border, but visitors of some nationalities need to apply in advance at a Chinese embassy, so check in advance. If there is no embassy in your place of residence, then it is possible to apply to the Immigration Service (<a href="http://www.fsm.gov.mo" target="_blank">www.fsm.gov.mo</a>) for &lsquo;authorisation to enter and stay&rsquo;. This authorisation, if granted, will usually allow for a stay of up to 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you require a temporary residence permit, you must apply to the Immigration Department or to the Macau Trade and Investment Promotion Institute (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ipim.gov.mo">www.ipim.gov.mo</a>), depending on your circumstances. An interview takes place, and you need to provide a variety of documentation. To work in Macau, you need a work permit (known as a &lsquo;blue card&rsquo;). The application process can take up to six months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most nationalities requiring visas can obtain them quickly at the border. If a visa is required from the embassy, then the normal service in London, for example, takes four to 10 working days; express service is three working days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors may be required to prove that they have sufficient funds for their time in Macau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications to extend your stay by up to 90 days must be made to the Immigration Department at least five days before your current authorisation to stay expires.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If coming from a country with low or zero incidence of rabies, pets will not be quarantined as long as the regulations are followed. The pet must be provided with a microchip, after which it must be vaccinated for rabies. This will be followed by a blood test to check for rabies antibodies, after which a Macau veterinary certificate will be issued (this will need to be endorsed by the relevant authority in your country of residence).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[22.163845]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[113.554994]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>28.2 sq km (10.9 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>601,969 (CIA estimate July 2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>21,346.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special Administrative Region of the People's Republic of China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Downtown Macau is situated on a tiny peninsula at the mouth of the Pearl River, on the southern coast of China&rsquo;s Guangdong Province (although it is politically distinct from the province). It was once an island, but has been linked to the mainland through land reclamation which has also significantly increased the size of the settlement. As a result the terrain is largely flat, although with hilly portions which indicate the location of the original land.</p>
<p>Three bridges link the peninsula to its nearest island, Taipa, which in turn is joined to the island of C&ocirc;loane by the 2.2km (1.4-mile) Cotai Strip causeway (an area of reclaimed land which effectively makes the two islands into one).</p>
<p>At the extreme northern end of the peninsula, on a narrow isthmus, is the imposing Portas do Cerco gateway (Border Gate), which leads to the Zhuhai and Zhongshan areas of the People's Republic of <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/">China</a>. There is also a border crossing from the Cotai strip, designed to make access to the casinos even easier. Some 60km (37 miles) to the east-northeast, across the mouth of the river, is <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/hong-kong/">Hong Kong</a>.</p>
<p>There is talk of a project to build a series of bridges and tunnels which will link Macau, Zhuhai and Hong Kong; the longest section of bridge could be a huge 22.8 km (14.2 miles) long. The start of the &quot;fourth link&quot; project had been scheduled to start in 2009 but had been delayed due to concerns about its environmental impact.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main religions are Buddhism, Roman Catholicism, Protestantism and Taoism. The majority are Buddhists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Entertaining generally takes place in restaurants and public places. It is rare to be invited to a private home, unless the person is wealthy. Spirits are standard gifts in return for hospitality. Apart from the most formal occasions in restaurants and nightclubs, casual wear is acceptable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Three-pin plugs with round or square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chief Executive Fernando Chui Sai On since 2009.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President of China Xi Jinping since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macau came under the sway of <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/">China</a> in the 3rd century BCE, but it was the arrival of the Portuguese &ndash; who had colonial bases in Goa and Melaka &ndash; in 1557 that established Macau as an international trading port.</p>
<p>The union of the Portuguese and Spanish crowns between 1580 and 1640 marked a golden age for Macau. The territory soon became the major entrep&ocirc;t between the Far East and Europe, and several other colonial powers, most notably the Dutch, made repeated but unsuccessful attempts to conquer it. <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/portugal/">Portugal</a> split from the Spanish Habsburgs in 1640, but by then its power in Southeast Asia was in decline.</p>
<p>British prominence in the region began when they opened a trading post nearby on the Chinese mainland in 1750, which is known today as <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/hong-kong/">Hong Kong.</a> Using gunboat diplomacy, <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/united-kingdom">Britain</a> forced the Chinese to accept imported opium from <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/india/">India</a>, a trade that helped Hong Kong compete with Macau.</p>
<p>Conflicting viewpoints and growing resentment between <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/united-kingdom/">Britain</a> and <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/">China</a> sparked the first Opium War (1839-1842), which was essentially a dispute over trade. During this tumultuous time the Macau remained under Portuguese control until the Carnation Revolution of 1974, which sounded the death knell for the Portuguese Empire and saw Macau gain a kind of quasi independence.</p>
<p>In 1985, the Portuguese began negotiations with <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/beijing/">Beijing</a> on the transfer of sovereignty of the territory and the final settlement provided for a handover in 1999, after which Macau would become a Special Administrative Region within China.</p>
<p>Today, Macau is the world&rsquo;s most profitable gambling destination and keeps Beijing at arm's length after China agreed not to interfere in local affairs for 50 years.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Macau is the world&rsquo;s most densely populated region with 21,346 people per sq km in 2017.<br />
&bull;	Portugal&rsquo;s three biggest football teams &ndash; S.L Benfica, Sporting CP and FC Porto &ndash; all have branches in Macau.<br />
&bull;	Macau was the first and last Asian country to be a European colony.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the People’s Republic of China in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 495 2266</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.china-embassy.org/eng</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 495 2266</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Chinese Embassy Chancery: Mon-Fri 0900-1730;&amp;nbsp;The Visa Section: Mon-Fri 0930-1430&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Suite 110, 3505 International Place N.W<br/>Washington DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Consulate-General Hong Kong]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+852 2901 3000</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/guidance/consular-enquiries-in-hong-kong</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+852 2901 3000</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1715.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1 Supreme Court Road<br/>Hong Kong<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the People's Republic of China in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7299 4049.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.chinese-embassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7299 4049.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-120, 1400-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>31 Portland Place<br/> London <br/>W1B 1QD<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Slipping more and more comfortably into its reputation as the &ldquo;Vegas of the East,&rdquo; Macau plays host to a dizzying array of large-scale casino resorts. Famously the world&rsquo;s biggest gambling hub, it is one of two Special Administrative Regions of the People&rsquo;s Republic of <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/">China</a> &ndash; the other being neighbouring <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-city/">Hong Kong</a>.</p>
<p>Macau showcases many of the same brands as its <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/north-america/united-states-of-america/nevada/">Nevada</a> counterpart: MGM, Wynn and Sands are all in town, while its flagship Venetian Resort &ndash; complete with canals and mock Italianate plazas &ndash; is currently the largest casino on the planet.</p>
<p>But there&rsquo;s more to the destination than poker tables and betting halls. When Macau's historic centre was added to the UNESCO World Cultural Heritage list in 2005, it underlined the strategic and cultural importance which the territory has had over the centuries.</p>
<p>Portuguese colonists arrived in the mid-16th century and developed Macau into a major regional trading post. They held onto it long after it had been eclipsed by Hong Kong as a magnet for merchants; longer than they held onto Goa or <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/south-america/brazil/">Brazil</a>.</p>
<p>Overlooking the South China Sea, Macau consists of a peninsula and two small islands, Taipa and Coloane. The three areas have been artificially joined by land reclamation, much of which is covered in casinos. Mercifully, it is possible to escape the neon lights and gambling dens in Macau&rsquo;s urban parks and historic centre, where colonial Portuguese architecture sits among the bustle of a modern Asian city.</p>
<p>The street stalls and restaurants of the old town are also a fine introduction to local food, which encompasses traditional Chinese and Portuguese dishes alongside Goan, Brazilian and African influences.</p><p>Slipping more and more comfortably into its reputation as the &ldquo;Vegas of the East,&rdquo; Macau plays host to a dizzying array of large-scale casino resorts. Famously the world&rsquo;s biggest gambling hub, it is one of two Special Administrative Regions of the People&rsquo;s Republic of China &ndash; the other being neighbouring Hong Kong. <br />
Macau showcases many of the same brands as its Nevada counterpart: MGM, Wynn and Sands are all in town, while its flagship Venetian Resort &ndash; complete with canals and mock Italianate plazas &ndash; is currently the largest casino on the planet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
