<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Hong Kong" ColCode="hkg" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="hk" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Hong Kong]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> has a subtropical climate with four seasons, and weather strongly influenced by two monsoons: the north-northeast monsoon from October to March and the south-southwest monsoon from April to September.</p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a>
<p>Spring &ndash; from February to April &ndash; is warm and humid, with average temperatures of around 23&deg;C (73&deg;F). Weather is generally pleasant but the skies can be quite overcast. By summer, the humidity (around 80% is normal) and temperatures are higher. Heavy rain is a feature throughout the south-southwest monsoon, but particularly from June to August when thunderstorms are also common. Between July and September there is the risk of tropical cyclones, which come in from the South China Sea. There&rsquo;s a well-organised warning system in place, whereby winds are numbered 1, 3, 8, 9 or 10 &ndash; anything rated as an 8 or above is taken very seriously and means the closure of schools and businesses.</p>
<p>Autumn is, certainly in terms of climate, an excellent time to visit Hong Kong. Temperatures are pleasant both day and night, and humidity also falls. There&rsquo;s also less rain &ndash; average rainfall in October is 101mm (4.3 inches), compared to 328mm (12.9 inches) in September. Winter is even drier but can be surprisingly cold, particularly in the evenings: mostly between 15&ndash;20&deg;C (59-68&deg;F), although it can be higher than this, and sometimes the temperature dips as low as 10&deg;C (50&deg;F).</p>
<p>Overall, the best months to visit are the periods between the monsoons (March to April and October to November) when humidity is low, the skies are clear and the temperature is warm but not too hot. That said, there are plenty of indoor attractions in Hong Kong, so rain need not spoil a trip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothing and a light raincoat are recommended during the warmer months, while warmer clothes are useful in winter. It should be noted that even during the hottest weather, a jacket or pullover will be required for the sometimes fierce air conditioning indoors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With only one commercial airport, there are no domestic flights in Hong Kong.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cross-harbour passenger services (shortest route &ndash; 7 to 10 minutes) are operated by the Star Ferry Company (tel: +852 2367 7065; <a href="http://www.starferry.com.hk" target="_blank">www.starferry.com.hk</a>) between Hong Kong Island and Kowloon (sailing every 6 to 12 minutes). The low cost and the great views make this a tourist attraction as well as an essential mode of transport for residents.</p>
<p>There are frequent passenger and vehicle services on other cross-harbour routes. Ferries and hydrofoils service the outlying islands, Peng Chau, Cheung Chau, Lamma and Lantau, including Discovery Bay. Ferry services are run by New World First Ferry Services (tel: +852 2131 8181; <a href="http://www.nwff.com.hk" target="_blank">www.nwff.com.hk</a>), the Hong Kong Kowloon Ferry (tel: +852 2815 6063; <a href="http://www.hkkf.com.hk" target="_blank">www.hkkf.com.hk</a>) and Discovery Bay Transportation Services Ltd (<a href="http://www.visitdiscoverybay.com" target="_blank">www.visitdiscoverybay.com</a>).</p>
<p>Tours of the harbour and to Aberdeen and Yau Ma Tei typhoon shelters are available from Watertours junks (tel: +852 2926 3868; <a href="http://www.watertours.com.hk" target="_blank">www.watertours.com.hk</a>), while visits to outlying islands are possible by public ferry. Weekdays are the best time to go, since ferries tend to be very crowded at weekends. During the typhoon season (May to November), all ferry services may be suspended during bad weather.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Mass Transit Railway (MTR) (tel: +852 2881 8888; <a href="http://www.mtr.com.hk" target="_blank">www.mtr.com.hk</a>) runs Hong Kong's underground network. Three lines cross the harbour and are more expensive than the ferry but quicker, particularly for those travelling further into Kowloon than Tsim Sha Tsui or to Lantau Island.</p>
<p>The MTR also operates the Airport Express, which is a convenient way to get from the airport to Kowloon and Hong Kong Island.</p>
<p>Some airlines allow customers to check in their bags at Kowloon and Hong Kong MTR stations, up to day before departure depending on the airline &ndash; this can very handy for those who want to get rid of their luggage to explore the city on their last day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Trams:</strong> There are double-decker Hong Kong Tramways (<a href="http://www.hktramways.com" target="_blank">www.hktramways.com</a>) trams on Hong Kong Island, running from Kennedy Town to Shau Kei Wan (with the red and blue lines heading inland to Happy Valley Racecourse). Get on at the back and pay the fare upon disembarking; the Octopus Card, which stores credit for pay-as-you-go travel, can be used on trams.</p>
<p>The Peak Tram on Hong Kong Island has operated since 1888 and is a funicular railway to the upper terminus on Victoria Peak. The trip is a mainstay of Hong Kong tourism, with great views on the way up and from the top. Octopus Cards are accepted.</p>l<p>The road network is extensive and of high quality but often congested in central areas of Hong Kong Island and Kowloon.</p><p>The bus network is extensive, covering the New Territories and outlying islands, as well as Hong Kong Island and Kowloon. Helpfully, the destinations are marked in English and may be accompanied by an X (express), R (Sundays and public holidays only) or M (links up with a station on the MTR metro network). Note that no change is given on buses.</p><p>Taxis are plentiful in Hong Kong and Kowloon and are reasonably priced, although note that there is an extra charge for the Cross Harbour Tunnel. Red taxis serve most of Hong Kong (except for Tung Chung Road and the south side of Lantau Island); green ones serve the New Territories; and blue ones serve Lantau Island.</p>
<p>All taxis operate to and from Hong Kong International Airport. Many drivers speak a little English, but it is wise to have the destination written in Chinese characters. Meters are used (it&rsquo;s rare to find a driver unwilling to turn them on) but a small tip is expected. Rounding up to the nearest dollar is usually enough.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is recommended, although not legally required. A valid national licence is accepted for up to 12 months; those who are staying longer need to apply for a temporary or full local licence. The minimum age is 18 years. Third-party insurance is compulsory.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 80kph (50mph) outside built-up areas, 100kph (62mph) on expressways, and 110kph (68mph) on the North Lantau Highway.</p><p>There are numerous breakdown services available in Hong Kong; ask for details from the car hire outlet.</p><p>A wide selection of self-drive and chauffeur-driven cars are available. Car hire isn&rsquo;t very popular however, since congested roads mean that it&rsquo;s generally easier to use public transport on Hong Kong Island and in Kowloon. Some of the outlying islands are completely car-free.</p><p>Hong Kong Island is not particularly cycle-friendly, since roads tend to be busy, steep, or both. Traffic is also heavy in Kowloon, but there are plenty of good cycling options in the New Territories and on the outlying islands.</p>
<p>The most popular route in the New Territories runs 20km (16 miles) from Tai Wai to Tai Mei Tuk, while a good option on the islands is to take a ferry to Mui Wo on Lantau Island and hire a bike from close to the ferry terminal. From there, visitors can ride through quiet villages and to the Silver Mine Waterfall. Those who want to cycle in one of Hong Kong&rsquo;s country parks will need a free permit from the Agriculture, Fisheries and Conservation Department.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 80kph (50mph) outside built-up areas, 100kph (62mph) on expressways, and 110kph (68mph) on the North Lantau Highway.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong Island and Kowloon have very good transport networks, with rail and buses covering almost everything likely to be of interest to tourists. The tram network on Hong Kong Island is also an appealing way to get around. Then there are the cross-harbour Star Ferries, which are not only useful but provide classic views of the city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Hong Kong</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">lantau_is</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Hong Kong</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kowloon</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Hong Kong</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kai_tak</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Hong Kong</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">aberdeen</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The major international airline is Cathay Pacific (<a href="http://www.cathaypacific.com" target="_blank">www.cathaypacific.com</a>), but <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> is a major regional hub so there are plenty of choices for flights. There is no particular time for cheap flights to Hong Kong as the region is popular throughout the year, but the highest prices tend to be around major holiday periods, particularly Chinese New Year.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London - 12 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a> - 16 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the ticket price.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Hong Kong International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.hongkongairport.com<p>Hong Kong International Airport is located 34km (21 miles) northwest of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hong-kong">Hong Kong Island.</a></p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+852 2181 8888</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong has one of the world&rsquo;s busiest container ports (<a href="http://www.pdc.gov.hk" target="_blank">www.pdc.gov.hk</a>). The region is also visited by a large number of cruise ships.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Mass Transit Railway Corporation (MTR) runs intercity passenger trains between Hong Kong and mainland <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>. Among its services is a route from Guangzhou, stopping at Dongguan (Changping) on the way to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kowloon">Kowloon</a> in Hong Kong. There is also a daily service from Foshan and Zhaoqing to Hong Kong. In Kowloon, trains terminate at Hung Hom Station in Tsim Sha Tsui East. Note that mainland Chinese know Kowloon as Jiulong, and this will be on destination boards.</p>
<p>Services between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/shanghai">Shanghai</a> and Kowloon (journey time - 19 hours) and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/beijing">Beijing</a> and Kowloon (journey time - 24 hours) run on alternate days.</p>
<p>Local East Rail Line trains run regularly to Kowloon from Lo Wu, the last stop before the Chinese border. Just across the border is Shenzhen, a special economic zone in China. To go as far as Lo Wu from Kowloon, you must hold a visa for China, otherwise it is only possible to get to Sheung Shui.</p>
<p>For more information on the intercity trains, see this website <a href="http://www.it3.mtr.com.hk" target="_blank">www.it3.mtr.com.hk</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None for intercity travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Local public telephone calls can be made either with phonecards or coins. Local calls are free from private phones.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Mobile telephones also function all over the underground network, thanks to transmitters installed in the tunnels. It is possible to hire a mobile phone at the international airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet facilities are available at libraries and Internet cafes are plentiful. Many cafes and hotels offer Wi-Fi access.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong has an active film industry &ndash; albeit one which has seen significant decline since the 1990s &ndash; and is a major centre for broadcasting and publishing. Hong Kong's media are a lot more editorially free than the rest of China, although there is still self-censorship and external pressure on editorial policies. Many international and pan-Asian broadcasters are based in the territory.</p>
<p>There are scores of Chinese-language newspapers and a handful of English-language dailies, including the South China Morning Post and The Standard.</p>
<p>Hong Kong has two terrestrial commercial TV networks, TVB and ATV, plus several subscription satellite and cable networks.</p>
<p>Public broadcaster Radio Television Hong Kong (RTHK) operates seven radio stations, including the English-language RTHK3 and predominantly English RTHK4. The broadcaster also transmits the BBC World Service on RTHK6. Other broadcasters include Commercial Radio and Metro Radio Hong Kong.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Regular postal services are available. Airmail to Europe takes three to five days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1800; Sat 0800-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Ocean Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Head to Ocean Park Hong Kong and get up close with marine life and furry friends. Sealife lovers will have plenty to keep them entertained at the numerous attractions, including The Grand Aquarium and Ocean Theatre for live shows, or head to the Giant Panda Adventure and Panda Village to discover more about China's native friends. There are also many rides, attractions, shops and restaurants to keep the whole family entertained.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Central Plaza</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The impressive Central Plaza (<a href="http://www.centralplaza.com.hk/" target="_blank">www.centralplaza.com.hk</a>) is 78-stories high. Visitors can view the city from the Sky Lobby on its 46th floor. After 1800 each day, neon rooftop lights change colour every hour to denote the time.</p>]]><p><b>Chi Lin Nunnery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a relaxing stroll around the Chi Lin Nunnery, a modern complex built in a spectacular Tang Dynasty style; continue across a footbridge to the pleasant Nan Lian Gardens. To see Hong Kong's only historic pagoda, head for the Tsui Shing Lau Pagoda, which was built in 1486 in the Yuen Lang district.</p>]]><p><b>Disneyland Hong Kong</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At Disneyland Hong Kong (<a href="http://www.hongkongdisneyland.com" target="_blank">www.hongkongdisneyland.com</a>), on Lantau Island, visitors can meet characters old and new, from Mickey Mouse to Buzz Lightyear, and can tour the park aboard the Hong Kong Disneyland Railroad. It&rsquo;s small by Disneyland standards, but attractions range from the Jungle River Cruise of Adventureland to the rollercoasters in Tomorrowland.</p>]]><p><b>Dragon's Back</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk along the Dragon's Back on the south side of Hong Kong Island, which follows a ridge and gives spectacular views. It takes about two hours to complete, and isn&rsquo;t too challenging. Start at the To Tei Wan Shuen bus stop, and finish with dinner in one of the restaurants in Shek O Village.</p>]]><p><b>Flagstaff House Museum of Tea Ware</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An imposing colonial-style building in Hong Kong Park, the Flagstaff House Museum of Tea Ware houses ancient Chinese artefacts used in tea-making. Dating from 1846, the building is the former residence of the colonial Commander-in-Chief, and the oldest surviving colonial building in Hong Kong. For more information, contact the tourist board for details of classes held in the tea shop next door.</p>]]><p><b>Happy Valley Racecourse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Vast sums of money change hands at Hong Kong's horse-racing meetings, held from September to June on Wednesday evenings (around 1900-2300). The easiest racecourse to access is Happy Valley (<a href="http://www.happyvalleyracecourse.com" target="_blank">www.happyvalleyracecourse.com</a>), which is on a tram route on Hong Kong Island. There is another racecourse in the New Territories, in Sha Tin (<a href="http://www.sha-tin.com" target="_blank">www.sha-tin.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Hong Kong Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A popular escape from the busy city streets, Hong Kong Park includes plenty of green space as well as an aviary, fountains, a restaurant and the Hong Kong Visual Arts Centre. On Wednesday mornings at 0800 there are organised birdwatching sessions starting from the artificial lake; these are cancelled when there&rsquo;s a cyclone warning of level 3 or above.</p>]]><p><b>Kowloon Walled City Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This park and garden were developed on the site of an old fort with a fascinating history. Built by the Chinese after the British first took Hong Kong, the fort did not surrender when Kowloon became part of British territory. It remained a semi-autonomous community until the Japanese tore down the walls during World War II, after which it was squatted. Today, the park includes a small museum with photographs of the old walled city.</p>]]><p><b>Lamma Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the most pleasant of Hong Kong&rsquo;s outlying islands (along with Cheung Chau and Lantau Islands). The best reason to visit Lamma Island is to explore its car-free pathways, although the very good seafood restaurants in Sok Kwu Wan are arguably more popular. The beaches draw crowds too at weekends, although pollution makes swimming inadvisable.</p>]]><p><b>MacLehose Trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head across the New Territories on Hong Kong's longest hike, the 100km-long (62-mile) MacLehose Trail. Although some people do it in one exhausting go, as on the annual Oxfam Trailwalker fundraising event, it has been split into ten sections each taking from 90 minutes to five hours. Along the way it takes on Hong Kong's highest peak, Tai Mo Shan (985m/3,231ft).&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Macau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Not part of the Hong Kong at all, but another Special Autonomous Region which was returned to China by Portugal in 1999, Macau is a very popular destination for day trips and weekend breaks. Locals and mainland Chinese are, on the whole, most interested in the casinos (as there are none in Hong Kong), but there are also some delightful older parts of the enclave (which is actually two islands which were artificially joined).</p>]]><p><b>Man Mo Temple</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Hong Kong&rsquo;s oldest Chinese temples, Man Mo honours the gods of literature (Man) and war (Mo). It&rsquo;s an atmospheric spot in a busy part of town, with large spirals of incense hanging overhead. While in the area, browse through the bric-a-brac shops and street market on Hollywood Road and Upper Lascar Row (known as &lsquo;Cat Street&rsquo;).</p>]]><p><b>Mong Kok</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Thought to be the world's most densely populated urban area, Mong Kok provides the ultimate opportunity to mingle with the crowds. Exotic fish and amphibians are sold at the Goldfish Market, and intricate bamboo birdcages and songbirds can be purchased near the Yuen Po Street Bird Garden.</p>]]><p><b>Ngong Ping 360 and Tian Tan Buddha</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The 5.7km-long (3.5-mile) Ngong Ping 360 cable car (<a href="http://www.np360.com.hk" target="_blank">www.np360.com.hk</a>) is one of the top attractions on Lantau Island, travelling between Tung Chung town centre and Ngong Ping. It offers stunning views across North Lantau Country Park and Tung Ching Bay, as well as of the giant Tian Tan Bhudda statue. Part of the development is Ngong Ping Village, a small theme park incorporating family-friendly attractions such as Walking with Buddha, the Monkey's Tale Theatre, the Ngong Ping Tea House and several dining, retail and entertainment outlets. The Po Lin Monastery, also at the top, is also likely to be interesting to most visitors.</p>]]><p><b>Repulse Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The pristine beach at Repulse Bay is one of the most popular on the southern coast of Hong Kong Island, and on sunny weekends it can get extremely busy. To get away from the crowds walk to Middle Bay or South Bay. Alternatively, visit the Tin Hau Temple, which overlooks Repulse Bay. Another good beach destination is Cheung Sha, a white sandy beach on Lantau Island, which has the awe-inspiring Shek Pik Reservoir Dam. One-day island-hopping tickets allow unlimited ferry trips between islands.</p>]]><p><b>Sai Kung country parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The excellent country parks at Sai Kung East and West, in the New Territories, are home to macaque monkeys, wild boar, civet cats, barking deer and the Chinese pangolin. Sai Kung Town, the nearest settlement and a former fishing village, is known for its seafood restaurants. For birdwatching, try the Mai Po marshes near Yuen Long  (<a href="http://www.wwf.org.hk/eng/maipo" target="_blank">www.wwf.org.hk/eng/maipo</a>), while visitors can look out for the Chinese pink dolphin near Lantau Island.</p>]]><p><b>Shopping</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go shopping down bustling Nathan Road in Kowloon. Grab a bargain at Stanley Market. In Yau Ma Tei, stalls set up at 1400 on Temple Street for the Night Market, selling everything from electrical goods to incense sticks.</p>]]><p><b>St John’s Cathedral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Observe glimpses of Hong Kong's colonial past at St John's Cathedral, thought to be the oldest Christian church in the Far East. Other vestiges of the colonial era can be found at Government House, the residence of 25 British governors from 1855 until Hong Kong's handover to China in 1997 (<a href="http://www.ceo.gov.hk/gh/eng" target="_blank">www.ceo.gov.hk/gh/eng</a>). It is closed to the public except on an annual open day.</p>]]><p><b>Swimming</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong has over 30 highly acclaimed beaches. Excellent snorkelling, waterskiing, sailing, kayaking, windsurfing, and fishing are available. Watersports equipment can be hired from beaches and hotels in Stanley and Sai Kung. One-day island-hopping tickets allow unlimited ferry trips between islands.</p>]]><p><b>Ten Thousand Buddhas Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Ten Thousand Buddhas Monastery, in the New Territories hills above Sha Tin, houses around 13,000 small Buddha statues. Also in the New Territories, amble around a beautifully designed complex, located in Tuen Mun, which features pavilions, bonsai trees, lotus ponds and a Taoist temple.</p>]]><p><b>Tolo Harbour Cycling Track</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For an easy ride through scenic countryside, cycle on the Tolo Harbour Cycling Track, running from Sha Tin to Tai Po. Bikes are available for hire near KCR stations. Most outlying islands do not allow cars.</p>]]><p><b>Victoria Harbour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The green and white tub-shaped Star Ferry (<a href="http://www.starferry.com.hk" target="_blank">www.starferry.com.hk</a>) vessels have been a familiar sight around Hong Kong since the 1920s and are a much-cherished symbol of the city. Far more important, however, is the fact that their decks give one of the best available and most affordable views, day or night, of the waterfronts of Hong Kong Island and Kowloon &ndash; not to mention the plethora of ocean traffic surging through the shipping lanes.</p>]]><p><b>Victoria Peak</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The view of Hong Kong from Victoria Peak (<a href="http://www.thepeak.com.hk" target="_blank">www.thepeak.com.hk</a>) is a must-see, and the journey up on the Peak Tram from Garden Road is no less spectacular. At the top, visitors will find the seven-storey Peak Tower, which is a good vantage point. Alternatively, go for a wander along the various roads, including one up to the very top, and the steep Old Peak Road down to Central in around 40 minutes.</p>]]><p><b>Wong Tai Sin Temple</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ornately decorated Wong Tai Sin Temple, located in Kowloon, combines Buddhist, Confucian and Taoist traditions. The temple is spectacularly colourful with its red pillars, golden ceiling and decorated latticework, and attracts around three million visitors per year. Arguably more interesting than the building itself are the fortune-tellers in their arcade of booths.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$243 billion (2011 estimate).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Electrical machinery and appliances, textiles, clothing, watches and clocks, toys, plastics and precious stones.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Raw materials and semi-manufactured goods, consumer goods, capital goods, food and fuel (most is re-exported).</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China (PR), Japan, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/taiwan">Taiwan</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a> and Korea (Rep).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong's natural deep-water cargo port is one of the busiest and most efficient in the region; it was key to the development of the city and much trade is still conducted through it. Manufacturing is concentrated in textiles, consumer electronics and other consumer goods. Hong Kong's economy has, however, moved away from manufacturing and is now service-based, acting as a major corporate and banking centre, as well as a conduit for China's burgeoning exports.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong dollar is one of the most traded currencies in the world, and the economy has long been based on a strong free market ideology with minimal regulation. That said, the administration has allowed the existence of monopolies in certain sectors (such as the Jockey Club&rsquo;s control over gambling) rather than insist on competition. The last colonial government, in the mid-1990s, significantly increased public spending to improve social welfare. There have been further slow moves in this direction since the handover to China in 1997 &ndash; including the introduction of a minimum wage &ndash; but the gap between rich and poor remains very wide.</p>
<p>The years since the handover have seen numerous economic challenges, starting with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/asia">Asia</a>'s financial crisis. With its mature and stable banking system, Hong Kong weathered the immediate storm, but its economy was affected by a large financial depression across the region. After a brief recovery, by mid-2002 the economy was contracting and in 2003 the SARS epidemic caused a further, prolonged downturn.</p>
<p>A buoyant recovery followed, with a new wave of construction and infrastructure investment evident, and a major influx of cash-rich tourists from mainland China. In late 2008, however, Hong Kong's financial markets were badly affected by the global financial crisis. With such a strong reliance on international trade, this has hit the city hard but again the stability of the economy has been evident.</p>
<p>The city remains a popular location for business meetings and expos. Meetings and Exhibitions Hong Kong is a division of the Hong Kong Tourism Board, which specialises in promoting Hong Kong as a leading venue. It publishes lavish and detailed brochures showcasing the region for conference and incentive planners, together with a glossy catalogue of promotional material, a directory of associations and societies in Hong Kong and an excellent website (<a href="http://www.discoverhongkong.com/mice" target="_blank">www.discoverhongkong.com/mice</a>). The main expo venues are the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Centre and the AsiaWorld-Expo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits are advisable for business; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> can be surprisingly formal in its outward business standards, in contrast to the casual buccaneering entrepreneurialism of its business practice. The culture of business cards is prevalent and, if possible, cards should be printed with Chinese translations on the reverse. Appointments should be fixed in advance and kept, as punctuality is appreciated. Most top hotels provide business centres for visiting businesspeople, with typing, duplication, translation and other services.</p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a>
<p>Although business lunches (especially dim sum) and after-hours drinking are a prevalent part of the Hong Kong business scene, there is not the same emphasis on drinking parties and karaoke bonding evenings as there is in mainland <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> and also in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a>. Expat workers drink together frequently, but this is not a formal part of local business culture.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700, Sat 0900-1300. Some offices remain open later on Saturday, or work longer hours during the week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>AsiaWorld Exhibitions Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 3606 8828
					Website:http://www.asiaworld-expo.com
					Address: Lantau,Hong Kong International Airport,,]]><b>Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 2582 8888
					Website:http://www.hkcec.com.hk/
					Address: Wan Chai,1 Expo Drive,,]]><b>Hong Kong General Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 2529 9229
					Website:http://www.chamber.org.hk/
					Address: 95 Queensway,22nd Floor,United Centre,,]]><b>Hong Kong Trade Development Council</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 183 0668
					Website:http://www.tdctrade.com/
					Address: Wan Chai,38th Floor,Office Tower,Convention Plaza,1 Harbour Road,,]]><b>Hong Kong Trade Development Council in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7616 9500
					Website:http://uk.tdctrade.com/
					Address: London W1K 7PL,16 Upper Grosvenor Street,UK,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Visitors to Hong Kong will find authentic food from all the regions of China, including Cantonese, Northern (Peking), Chiu Chow (Swatow), Shanghai, Szechuan and Hakka. What&rsquo;s more, there&rsquo;s the chance to sample them in all kinds of surroundings: on a sampan in Causeway Bay or a floating restaurant at Aberdeen; in a Kowloon back-street restaurant or street market; or in the dining room of a luxury hotel. Don&rsquo;t miss the chance to try one (or more) of Hong Kong&rsquo;s private kitchens, which started out as unlicensed venues inside private homes but have developed into a scene of their own. Some of them are really quite upmarket and the best offer serious treats for gourmand visitors; many also have the added thrill of being in odd or unexpected locations.</p>
<p>Chinese dishes are by no means the whole story, though, as Hong Kong is one of the great centres for international cooking. There are stalls and restaurants serving most of the key Asian cuisines, including Indian, Vietnamese, Filipino, Singapore/Malaysian and Thai, but there&rsquo;s also some truly excellent Western cooking on offer.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Cantonese specialities include dim sum (savoury snacks, usually steamed and served in bamboo baskets on trolleys typically served until late afternoon), such as <em>cha siu bao</em> (barbecue pork bun), <em>har gau </em>(steamed shrimp dumplings) and <em>shiu mai</em> (steamed and minced pork with shrimp).<br />
&bull; The emphasis in northern food is on bread and noodles, deep frying and spicy sauces. Specialities include Peking duck (roast duck served with pancakes, spring onions and hoisin sauce or sweet bean sauce) and hotpot dishes.<br />
&bull; Chiu Chow cuisine is from a part of Guangdong province. It uses light, slightly vinegary sauces and is strong on seafood and roast goose.<br />
&bull; Hakka food is generally simple in style with baked chicken in salt among the best dishes.<br />
&bull; Szechuan food is hot and spicy with plenty of chillies. One speciality is barbecued meat.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>The Chinese do not usually order an alcoholic drink before dinner.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Basic restaurants do not usually add service to the bill, and it is normal to leave a dollar or two as a tip. Mid-range or high-end restaurants will normally add a 10% service charge, but customers can also leave an additional tip if the service was good (leaving the coins from the change is common).</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> has a good mix of nightlife, with lively nightclub and bar scenes &ndash;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a> which tend to get going late and carry on until dawn &ndash; as well as cultural events such as concerts, plays and exhibitions. The best areas for a drink include SoHo (&lsquo;South of Hollywood Road&rsquo;), which can be reached via the Central-Mid Levels Escalator and is particularly popular with expats. Nearby Lan Kwai Fong is a little rowdier with lots of bars and restaurants spilling out into the street; Wan Chai is also known for its nightlife (including a rather seedy main strip). Over in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kowloon">Kowloon</a>, Tsim Sha Tsui buzzes at night, particularly around Knutsford Terrace.</p>
<p>Major events are held at venues including the distinctively stark Hong Kong Cultural Centre (<a href="http://www.hkculturalcentre.gov.hk" target="_blank">www.hkculturalcentre.gov.hk</a>), which has a 2,100-seat Concert Hall, 1,750-seat Grand Theatre, and a studio theatre with 300 to 500 seats. Hong Kong Art Centre (<a href="http://www.hkac.org.hk" target="_blank">www.hkac.org.hk</a>) in Wan Chai also holds a wide variety of performances. There are also many smaller venues putting on theatre, dance and other events; some bars have regular live music.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Whether shopping in modern air-conditioned shopping centres or more traditional street markets (where bargaining is still practiced), the range of goods available in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> is vast. Many famous brands have opened outlets in Hong Kong, bringing the latest styles and great variety. Look out for the Quality Tourism Services (QTS) sign, which is given to accredited shops and restaurants under a scheme run by the Hong Kong Tourism Board.</p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a>
<p>Generally speaking, Central is a good bet for high-end shopping including lots of designer goods and department stores, such as Shanghai Tang (which is outfitted in 1930s <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/shanghai">Shanghai</a> style). There&rsquo;s good general shopping in Causeway Bay, which is home to the huge Times Square mall. On a smaller scale, the Western Market (near Sheung Wan station) is an Edwardian-style building that was renovated into a shopping complex in the early 1990s. It&rsquo;s a pleasant place to look for handicrafts. Nathan Road in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kowloon">Kowloon</a> used to be the place for cheap electronic goods, but these days there&rsquo;s too much chance of getting ripped off. Visitors are better off heading somewhere like Wan Chai Computer Centre or Mong Kok Computer Centre for these items.</p>
<p>For an authentic market experience, head to Mong Kok in Kowloon, which is home to a bird market, ladies&rsquo; market (for clothing), goldfish market (the fish are said to bring good luck) and flower market. A few streets south, in Yau Ma Tei, are the jade market and Temple Street night market (where there is plenty of choice of food stalls as well as all manner of cheap goods). To the northwest of Mong Kok, the down-at-heel district of Sham Shui Po has a popular flea market and cheap clothing sold from wholesale warehouses.</p><p>Shopping hours may vary greatly, so the following are approximate. Hong Kong Island (Central and Western): 1000-1900 (1000-2000 along Queen's Road). Hong Kong Island (Causeway Bay and Wan Chai), Kowloon (Tsim Sha Tsui, Yau Ma Tei and Mong Kok): 1000-2130. Many shops are open on Sundays.</p><p>Except for a few items, such as alcohol and cigarettes, Hong Kong is a duty-free port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As typifies a major city, hotels in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> include many luxury options and representatives of all the major international chains;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a> there&rsquo;s also a growing upmarket boutique sector. Smaller hotels and guesthouses specialising in 'family style' hospitality can be a cheaper alternative, although there&rsquo;s little in the way of truly cheap hotel accommodation in Hong Kong. Prices rise significantly for places with harbour views in Central or Tsim Sha Tsui. Outside of the city, there are also a number of fairly new hotels in the New Territories, many providing a range of recreational facilities and activities.</p>
<p>In spite of the large number of hotel rooms available in Hong Kong, visitors are strongly advised to make an advance booking. This is particularly important around major public holidays (such as Chinese New Year), but the popularity of Hong Kong as a convention destination means that mid-range and high-end hotels can be full at almost any time. The most pleasant times of year for the weather are March to April and October to November, so these periods are also particularly busy.</p>
<p>Given that room prices in Hong Kong are on a par with those in major European and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> cities, it makes sense to keep an eye open for special deals. This means that generally it&rsquo;s best to book direct with hotels, but those without a reservation can head to the Hotel Reservation Centre at Hong Kong International Airport. Hotels usually add a 10% service charge to the bill; check whether this is included in published prices. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Though there is no grading structure as such, hotel members of the Hong Kong Tourism Board fall into one of four categories: High Tariff A Hotels, High Tariff B Hotels, Medium Tariff Hotels and Hostels/Guest houses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As typifies a major city, hotels in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> include many luxury options and representatives of all the major international chains;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a> there&rsquo;s also a growing upmarket boutique sector. Smaller hotels and guesthouses specialising in 'family style' hospitality can be a cheaper alternative, although there&rsquo;s little in the way of truly cheap hotel accommodation in Hong Kong. Prices rise significantly for places with harbour views in Central or Tsim Sha Tsui. Outside of the city, there are also a number of fairly new hotels in the New Territories, many providing a range of recreational facilities and activities.</p>
<p>In spite of the large number of hotel rooms available in Hong Kong, visitors are strongly advised to make an advance booking. This is particularly important around major public holidays (such as Chinese New Year), but the popularity of Hong Kong as a convention destination means that mid-range and high-end hotels can be full at almost any time. The most pleasant times of year for the weather are March to April and October to November, so these periods are also particularly busy.</p>
<p>Given that room prices in Hong Kong are on a par with those in major European and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> cities, it makes sense to keep an eye open for special deals. This means that generally it&rsquo;s best to book direct with hotels, but those without a reservation can head to the Hotel Reservation Centre at Hong Kong International Airport. Hotels usually add a 10% service charge to the bill; check whether this is included in published prices. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Though there is no grading structure as such, hotel members of the Hong Kong Tourism Board fall into one of four categories: High Tariff A Hotels, High Tariff B Hotels, Medium Tariff Hotels and Hostels/Guest houses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As typifies a major city, hotels in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> include many luxury options and representatives of all the major international chains;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a> there&rsquo;s also a growing upmarket boutique sector. Smaller hotels and guesthouses specialising in 'family style' hospitality can be a cheaper alternative, although there&rsquo;s little in the way of truly cheap hotel accommodation in Hong Kong. Prices rise significantly for places with harbour views in Central or Tsim Sha Tsui. Outside of the city, there are also a number of fairly new hotels in the New Territories, many providing a range of recreational facilities and activities.</p>
<p>In spite of the large number of hotel rooms available in Hong Kong, visitors are strongly advised to make an advance booking. This is particularly important around major public holidays (such as Chinese New Year), but the popularity of Hong Kong as a convention destination means that mid-range and high-end hotels can be full at almost any time. The most pleasant times of year for the weather are March to April and October to November, so these periods are also particularly busy.</p>
<p>Given that room prices in Hong Kong are on a par with those in major European and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> cities, it makes sense to keep an eye open for special deals. This means that generally it&rsquo;s best to book direct with hotels, but those without a reservation can head to the Hotel Reservation Centre at Hong Kong International Airport. Hotels usually add a 10% service charge to the bill; check whether this is included in published prices. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Though there is no grading structure as such, hotel members of the Hong Kong Tourism Board fall into one of four categories: High Tariff A Hotels, High Tariff B Hotels, Medium Tariff Hotels and Hostels/Guest houses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;First-class Western medicine is practised in &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport"&gt;Hong Kong&lt;/a&gt;. Most doctors speak English and hotels should have a list of government-accredited doctors and hospitals. Public hospitals in Hong Kong include Princess Margaret Hospital (Lai King Hill Road, Lai Chi Kok, &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kowloon"&gt;Kowloon&lt;/a&gt;), Queen Elizabeth Hospital (Gascoigne Road, Kowloon) and Queen Mary Hospital (Pok Fu Lam Road, Hong Kong Island). See the Hospital Authority website (&lt;a href="http://www.ha.org.hk" target="_blank"&gt;www.ha.org.hk&lt;/a&gt;) for more information. There is also a well-developed private healthcare industry (&lt;a href="http://www.privatehospitals.org.hk" target="_blank"&gt;www.privatehospitals.org.hk&lt;/a&gt;) in Hong Kong. Although locals and expats are charged reduced rates at public hospitals, the price for public and private facilities can be very similar for tourists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charges are made for all services and treatment, although emergency treatment in casualty departments is free. Travel insurance is a wise precaution, as healthcare bills can be expensive particularly if a hospital stay is required. For emergency medical services, dial 999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pharmacies are plentiful throughout Hong Kong, particularly the Watsons and Mannings chains, which can be found in almost every shopping centre. Pharmacists are usually also able to provide advice about minor ailments.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;It is not recommended visitors drink the tap water in Hong Kong, unless it has been been boiled or purified first. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are also generally considered safe to eat. As in many countries, it&amp;rsquo;s safer to avoid raw vegetables, reheated foods and shellfish. Wash fruit unless it has been peeled. Food from street food stalls and hawkers centres is generally considered safe to eat, although it is recommended to eat food that is cooked directly in front of the customer.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Before travelling, visit a doctor or travel health clinic for detailed and up-to-date advice on health risks. Japanese encephalitis may occur in the New Territories between April and October, although it is rare. Immunisation against hepatitis B, diphtheria and tuberculosis is sometimes recommended. Following the severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) outbreak of 2003, it has been routine for temperature scanning to be carried out at the airport for new arrivals. In the very unlikely event that your temperature is considered abnormal, further examination may be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air pollution can be an issue in Hong Kong; it is often claimed that the worst of it comes from the Chinese mainland rather than from the island itself. At times, when pollution levels are high, visitors with asthma or other respiratory problems are likely to find that their symptoms are exacerbated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The risk of catching malaria is extremely low, but dengue fever incidents are on the increase (as in many Southeast Asian cities) &amp;ndash; although it still remains uncommon and outbreaks tend to be localised. Dengue fever is (like malaria) spread by mosquitoes, and symptoms include a rash, fever, headaches and pain in muscles and joints. In rare cases the disease can become life-threatening. &lt;br /&gt;
There is no vaccine but the risk should be minimised by reducing exposure to mosquito bites, by covering up and using a repellent. Local brands generally include only citronella, so visitors who wish to use DEET-based repellent should bring this with them.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are generally observed the following Monday, with the exception of Lunar New Year.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Hong Kong Special Administrative Region Establishment Day :
							01 July </p><p>National Day :
							01 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 19 cigarettes or 1 cigar or 25g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcohol over 30% volume.</p>
<p>No customs duty is payable on wine or spirits with less than 30% alcohol content.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted imports include psychotropic drugs, narcotics, controlled chemicals, antibiotics (except an acceptable amount for personal use accompanied by a doctor&rsquo;s prescription), arms, ammunition, fireworks, strategic commodities, rough diamonds, protected animals, plants, endangered species, radio transmitting equipment, game, meat and poultry. E-cigarettes containing nicotine will also require a doctor's prescription indicating that they are for personal use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted exports include psychotropic drugs, narcotics, controlled chemicals, antibiotics (except an acceptable amount for personal use accompanied by a doctor&rsquo;s prescription), arms, ammunition, fireworks, strategic commodities, rough diamonds, protected animals, plants, endangered species, radio transmitting equipment, game, meat, poultry and powdered formula milk.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> dollar (HKD;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a> symbol HK$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of HK$1,000, 500, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of HK$10, 5, 2 and 1, and 50, 20 and 10 cents.</p>
<p>The currency is pegged to the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollar at a rate of around HK$7.8 to US$1, although this does fluctuate very slightly.</p>
<p>Notes are issued by three banks &ndash; HSBC, Standard Chartered Bank and Bank of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> &ndash; and therefore come in a variety of designs for each denomination; coins, on the other hand are issued by the government.</p>
<p>Hong Kong Dollars are legal tender in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/macau-city">Macau</a> (where the currency is the pataca) and can be used on a one-to-one basis. Patacas cannot be used in Hong Kong. Small transactions can also be carried out using value stored on an Octopus card; these are primarily used for public transport, but are now accepted in many shops and vending machines &ndash; customers simply touch the card to the reader to the make the transaction.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency can be changed in banks, hotels and bureaux de change. Banks usually offer the best rate of exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted. Look out for stickers in the windows of establishments, indicating which cards can be used.</p><p>There are plenty of ATMs in urban areas, accepting major foreign debit and credit cards. The maximum withdrawal per transaction varies from bank to bank, but is generally around HK$10,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling, US Dollars or Euros. These are accepted in some shops, hotels and other establishments, and can be exchanged for local currency at banks or private moneychangers (check rates carefully at the latter).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Standard banking hours are Mon-Fri 0900-1630, Sat 0900-1230. Some banks and branches are open slightly longer hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Passports are required by all nationals referred to in the chart above and must be valid for at least one month after the date of your departure from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a>.</p>
<p>Visitors are required to have adequate funds to cover the duration of their stay without working.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is recommended that single adults travelling with children contact the Hong Kong Economic and Trade Office in their country of residence, regarding any documentary evidence of parental responsibility that may be required at immigration.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals of most countries do not need a visa for transit in Hong Kong, but it is best to check the requirements (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.gov.hk/en/nonresidents/visarequire/general">www.gov.hk/en/nonresidents/visarequire/general</a>) in advance of travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ordinary visa: HK$190; transit visa: HK$100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The length of visa available to travellers varies according to nationality and the details of the application.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>At the nearest Chinese diplomatic and consular mission, or directly by post to: Receipt and Despatch Unit, Hong Kong Immigration Department, 2nd Floor, Immigration Tower, 7 Gloucester Road, Wan Chai, Hong Kong. You can find details of the paperwork required on the Immigration Department website (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.immd.gov.hk">www.immd.gov.hk</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A visa is required before visiting Hong Kong for the purpose of study, taking up employment, training, investment or residence. Contact a diplomatic and consular mission for further details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing time is usually four to 20 working days, with an express three-day service also available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For a visa-free stay, or using a visa that does not allow employment, visitors may be required to prove that they have sufficient funds to cover the period of their stay in Hong Kong.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Where available, the official fee for an extension of stay is HK$190. If you wish to extend your stay, you must visit the nearest Immigration Department office at least seven days before your current stay is due to expire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To bring your pet to Hong Kong, you must obtain a permit from the Agriculture, Fisheries and Conservation Department (<a href="http://www.afcd.gov.uk">www.afcd.gov.hk</a>). There is no quarantine period for pets coming direct from Australia, Fiji, Ireland, Japan, Hawaii, New Zealand or the UK. Otherwise, pets will be kept in quarantine for up to six months, depending on the documentation provided; there may be an exemption from quarantine if the dogs and cats are over five months of age on arrival and have complied with all the permit terms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[22.247860]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[114.203384]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,104 sq km (426 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>7,346,248 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6,468.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special Administrative Region of the People's Republic of China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (SAR) consists of three main territories &ndash; Hong Kong Island, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kowloon">Kowloon</a> and the New Territories &ndash; plus more than 260 smaller (and mostly uninhabited) islands, located where the Pearl River meets the South China Sea. Both Kowloon and the New Territories are located on the Chinese mainland, separated from Hong Kong Island by the narrow Victoria Harbour. One of the world&rsquo;s deepest natural harbours, this has been key to Hong Kong&rsquo;s economic success.</p>
<p>The SAR is hilly, with land on Hong Kong Island rising to its highest point at Victoria Peak (552m/1,811ft); in the New Territories, the mountain of Tai Mo Shan reaches 957m (3,140ft). Much of the developed land on Hong Kong Island, most notably the northern areas such as Central &ndash; site of many of the city&rsquo;s best-known skyscrapers &ndash; is the product of reclamation projects. The same can be said of much of Kowloon on the other side of the harbour. The combination of hills and developed lowlands means that very little of the land within <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> (only around 6% of the 1104 sq km/426 sq miles) is used for agriculture.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buddhist, Confucian and Taoist, with Christian and Muslim minorities; but there are also places of worship for most other religious groups.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the most common form of greeting. In <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a>, the family name comes first; so Wong Man Ying would be addressed as Mr. Wong.</p>
<p>Most entertaining takes place in restaurants rather than in private homes; during a meal, a toast is often made saying <em>&quot;yam seng&quot; </em>(meaning &quot;drink to success&quot;). There may be up to 12 courses served in a meal, and although it is not considered an insult to eat sparingly, a good appetite is always appreciated and it is considered cordial to taste every dish. It is customary to invite the host to a return dinner.</p>
<p>Informal wear is generally acceptable, although some restaurants and social functions often warrant formal attire. Smoking is widely acceptable, but is now prohibited in most public places.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chief Executive Carrie Lam since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President of China Xi Jinping since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although Hong Kong is largely thought of in terms of its development from the colonial era onwards, humans have settled in the area since the late Stone Age. It came under the influence of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> around 200 BC, with serious settlement by Han Chinese beginning in the 12th century AD. It is thought that they displaced the original inhabitants, whose descendants are now known as Tanka and traditionally live on boats.</p>
<p>Regular contact between China and Europe began with the arrival of the Portuguese, who established a trading settlement in nearby <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/macau-city">Macau</a> in 1557. Their influence had declined, however, by the time the British started trading in the south of the Chinese mainland around 1750. The problem was that although they wanted goods such as tea and porcelain, the Chinese were not interested in buying anything from them.</p>
<p>The solution was to import opium from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>, and when the Chinese authorities &ndash; alarmed at both the cost and the growing addiction rate &ndash; tried to block it, the British sent in gunboats. They seized <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> in 1841 in the First Opium War, and a year later the Treaty of Nanking gave the British control of Hong Kong, plus the right to trade in five Chinese ports. A few years later the British took the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kowloon">Kowloon</a> peninsula as a result of the Second Opium War. Then, in 1898, the New Territories were leased from China for 99 years.</p>
<p>The British rule of Hong Kong was interrupted only by the four-year Japanese occupation during World War 2. In the years after the war, free market policies and an abundance of cheap labour helped Hong Kong&rsquo;s economy grow on the back of financial services and textile manufacture.</p>
<p>It was in December 1984 that an agreement was signed for the terms of the reversion to China, with guarantees that the territory would enjoy a high degree of autonomy, especially in the economic field. The slogan 'one country, two systems' was coined by the Chinese to describe the regime and only in foreign affairs and defence would the new Special Administrative Region be subject to the diktat of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/beijing">Beijing</a>.</p>
<p>China has largely stuck to the concept although it is often argued that the mainland has covert influence over Hong Kong politics and today, despite the lack of true democracy, Hong Kong seems to have grown again in confidence and is becoming more comfortable with its unusual political position.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; Hong Kong's Central-Mid-Levels escalator is the longest outdoor covered escalator system in the world and the total travel time is 20 minutes.</p>
<p>&bull; Hong Kong&rsquo;s oldest university was established in 1911.</p>
<p>&bull; Hong Kong comprises of 261 islands; many are unpopulated and unreachable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Chinese Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7631 1430 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.chinese-embassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7631 1430 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1230, 1400-1700. Visa applications Mon-Fri 0900-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>31 Portland Place<br/>London<br/>W1B 1QD<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Chinese Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 338 6688.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.china-embassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 338 6688.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1230 and 1330-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>N.W. Suite 110<br/>2201 Wisconsin Avenue<br/>Washington, D.C<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Consulate in Hong Kong]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(852) 2901 3222.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinhongkong.fco.gov.uk/en/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(852) 2901 3222.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1715.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>PO Box 528<br/>1 Supreme Court Road<br/>Hong Kong<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Steamy and gargantuan, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> has evolved into one of Asia&rsquo;s most lovable cities. Its incredible skyline &ndash; part neon, part steel-and-glass, part towering hills &ndash; is one of the most majestic in the world, but it&rsquo;s a mere backdrop to the 24-hour flurry of activity that makes Hong Kong what it is.</p>
<p>From its boat-buzzed waterfront to its packed dim sum restaurants, its incense-smoked temples to its clattering teahouses, its street markets to its old-world hotels, Hong Kong is a destination teeming with energy. For travellers, the best advice is to go with the flow.</p>
<p>Situated at the mouth of the Pearl River Delta on China&rsquo;s southwestern coast, Hong Kong is a city that has a remarkable mix of Eastern and Western influences. The handover of this territory from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Britain</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> was back in 1997, but the centuries of British rule still have a lasting legacy, tangible in everything from the grand period architecture to the local passion for horse-racing.</p>
<p>Even the name of Hong Kong&rsquo;s centrepiece &ndash; the iconic Victoria Harbour &ndash; harks back to another era, and today there&rsquo;s an international flavour to the destination that sets it apart from other Chinese cities. The gastronomy, nightlife and shopping are all world-class.</p>
<p>Hong Kong Island, with its glistening skyscrapers and high-end shopping malls, is in many ways the heartbeat of the city. Get down to street level, however, and the laneways, wet markets and traditional Chinese haunts are a reminder that beyond the city lies a working class populace still making ends meet the old fashioned way &ndash; and often the hard way.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s also worth remembering, of course, that there&rsquo;s far more to Hong Kong than the city itself. Its natural attractions include hiker-friendly ranges, volcanic landscapes, pristine woodlands, sleepy islands, protected marine parks and miles of golden beaches.</p><p>Steamy and gargantuan, Hong Kong has evolved into one of Asia&rsquo;s most lovable cities. Its incredible skyline &ndash; part neon, part steel-and-glass, part towering hills &ndash; is one of the most majestic in the world, but it&rsquo;s a mere backdrop to the 24-hour flurry of activity that makes Hong Kong what it is. From its boat-buzzed waterfront to its packed dim sum restaurants, its incense-smoked temples to its clattering teahouses, its street markets to its old-world hotels, Hong Kong is a destination teeming with energy. For travellers, the best advice is to go with the flow.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
