<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Colombia" ColCode="col" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="co" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Colombia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is very warm and tropical on the coast and in the north, with a rainy season from May to November. Though the temperature varies little throughout the year due to Colombia&rsquo;s proximity to the equator, it does vary according to altitude. It is cooler in the upland areas and cold in the mountains, and in the cooler times of the year the nights can be freezing. Bogot&aacute; is always spring-like, with cool days and crisp nights, though when the sun is shining the days can get quite hot. The Amazon region generally stays warm and wet year round. &nbsp;</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>The best time of year to visit is at either of the drier times: December to March or July and August. This is a good time for hiking, too; getting caught out in a storm is not ideal, especially if you can&rsquo;t dry out for several days because you&rsquo;re on a multi-day hike. Bear in mind that major religious holidays will also play a part in the best time of year to visit: Santa Semana is a stunning time to travel to Colombia due to the ostentatious celebrations, but the hotels book up fast and double their rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally, Colombia requires light clothing suitable for warm to hot weather. However, Bogot&aacute; and other places of high altitude get cold at night and even in the shade during the day, particularly in the cooler times of year. You&rsquo;ll definitely need at least a warm sweater and trousers for this, preferably a jacket.</p>
<p>If you are hiking you&rsquo;ll need good boots in the colder mountainous regions and good walking sandals for the Zona Cafetera to let your feet air but still give support. Very light clothing for the Amazon Basin is required, but having long sleeves and trousers for the evenings to prevent mosquito bites is a good idea. For the rainy season, have something waterproof such as a light jacket to fend off the downpours.  </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is an excellent internal air network connecting major cities, including those in the Caribbean coastal area. There are also local helicopter flights. Flights between the mainland and the islands of San Andr&eacute;s and Providencia operate from most major Colombian cities. The main domestic carriers are Avianca (<a href="http://www.avianca.com" target="_blank">www.avianca.com</a>), Lan Colombia (<a href="http://www.lan.com" target="_blank">www.lan.com</a>), Copa Airlines (<a href="http://www.copaair.com" target="_blank">www.copaair.com</a>) and Satena (<a href="http://www.satena.com" target="_blank">www.satena.com</a>).</p>
<p>Some areas have no road access, such as the Amazon River border town of Leticia, which must be accessed by air. Other areas have road routes but a flight is far more expedient and not too expensive; for example, Bogot&aacute; to Cartagena is a flight of 1 hour 25 minutes, but the bus journey takes 20 hours. Flights are cheaper when bought well in advance, but are still reasonably priced at short notice.</p><p>When booking domestic flights, it's often easiest to go into a travel company office &ndash; some domestic airlines don&rsquo;t accept international credit cards online.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cargo ships from Cartagena to San Andr&eacute;s occasionally take passengers, but the trip takes several days. You can obtain information from the Maritima San Andr&eacute;s office.</p>
<p>The Magdalena River is the main artery of Colombia. Some cargo boats take passengers, though this is a slow way to travel. Paddle steamers no longer run services up and down the river and hiring can be expensive.</p>
<p>From Leticia, on the Peruvian border, a number of operators run sightseeing tours and jungle expeditions up the Amazon. It's necessary to make enquiries locally, and wise to shop around before booking on any one trip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although trains still carry freight, inter-city passenger services are virtually non-existent. A restored steam train, Turistren, runs from Bogot&aacute; to Zipaquir&aacute; and Cajic&aacute; (tel: +57 1 375 0557; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.turistren.com.co">www.turistren.com.co</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The quality of the roads in Colombia varies massively. The Panamericana (Panamerican Highway) is mostly well paved, but when you start veering off the beaten track the roads get bumpier. Do not go for an exploratory drive into the jungle or areas deemed dangerous by your embassy. Expect landslides in the more mountainous regions during the rainy season (November to February). City driving is chaotic and dangerous.</p>r<p>There are many coach companies running buses to all towns and cities in Colombia. Among them are Bolivariano (tel: +57 1 424 9090; <a href="http://www.bolivariano.com.co" target="_blank">www.bolivariano.com.co</a>), Expreso Brasilia (tel: 01800 051 8001, in Colombia only; <a href="http://www.expresobrasilia.com" target="_blank">www.expresobrasilia.com</a>) and Copetran (tel: 01800 011 4164, in Colombia only; <a href="http://www.copetran.com.co" target="_blank">www.copetran.com.co</a>).</p><p>There are plenty of taxis in the big cities, and they are reasonably cheap. They are also considered fairly safe to hail in the street. You may get charged a bit more for being a tourist; in Bogot&aacute;, Cali and Medell&iacute;n they have <em>taximetros</em> (meters), but in smaller places you have to negotiate the price. Drivers are generally not tipped.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required; however, many car hire companies will accept a driving licence from your country. Insurance is compulsory.</p><p>Seat belts in the front seats are mandatory; car seats for children are also mandatory. Children under 10 cannot sit in the front seat. The speed limit is 45-60kph (28-37mph) in urban areas, 80kph (50mph) in rural areas and up to 120kph (75mph) on motorways, but few Colombians keep to these limits. It is forbidden to talk on a mobile phone while driving; again, however, most Colombians disregard this rule.</p><p>There are no national breakdown services in Colombia; ensure that your insurance covers you for breakdowns in case you need to be rescued by your car hire company.</p><p>The major international companies have offices and can arrange for vehicle pick-ups at the airport, but driving in cities is not recommended. Most companies require you to be 25 or over; some allow drivers over 21 but they are subject to a surcharge.</p><p>Cycling is immensely popular in Colombia and there are all sorts of routes throughout the country, including cross-country missions, several day-long expeditions, mountain bike routes and city cycling. Check out <a href="http://www.mtbcolombia.com" target="_blank">www.mtbcolombia.com</a> (in Spanish) for mountain bike routes and information.</p>
<p>Hostels and hotels in coastal cities and a few in Bogot&aacute; lend/hire bikes to guests (less so in mountain cities).</p>
<p>You can buy bicycles in Bogot&aacute; and other big cities, but they are generally not cheap. Try <a href="http://www.mercadolibre.com" target="_blank">www.mercadolibre.com</a> for second-hand bikes. Be safe when cycling &ndash; there are many trucks on the roads, and cycling off into the jungle isn&rsquo;t a good idea.</p><p>Seat belts in the front seats are mandatory; car seats for children are also mandatory. Children under 10 cannot sit in the front seat. The speed limit is 45-60kph (28-37mph) in urban areas, 80kph (50mph) in rural areas and up to 120kph (75mph) on motorways, but few Colombians keep to these limits. It is forbidden to talk on a mobile phone while driving; again, however, most Colombians disregard this rule.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bogot&aacute;'s bus service, TransMilenio (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.transmilenio.gov.co">www.transmilenio.gov.co</a>), is the most efficient way to travel round the capital. There are also <em>buseta</em> (shared taxis) which are not expensive and stop on demand. Medell&iacute;n, Colombia's second largest city, has a metro train service and cable-car lines to hillside suburbs. Travelling on public transport in Colombia is safer than you might assume, but you should always exercise vigilance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Colombia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">medelliacuten</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Colombia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">manizales</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Colombia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">leticia</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Colombia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cali</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Colombia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">barranquilla</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Avianca (<a href="http://www.avianca.com" target="_blank">www.avianca.com</a>), which runs direct flights from London&nbsp;and New York to Bogot&aacute;. United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) also offers direct flights from the USA. Prices are similar year-round, apart from Christmas and Easter, when they tend to increase.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/el-dorado-international-airport-0">El Dorado International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 11 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 5 hours 40 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit passengers are exempt. Airport departure tax for others leaving the country varies depending on whether you have stayed longer than 60 days and which airline you are travelling with. Theoretically, your tax should be included in the ticket. To establish this, before you check in, you should queue up for the &lsquo;Tax Exemption&rsquo; stamp in your passport, and then you can find out how much, if any, departure tax you owe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Barranquilla Ernesto Cortissoz International Airport </b><![CDATA[<p>The airport  is 10km (6 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Cali Alfonso Bonilla Aragón International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aerocali.com.co<p>The airport  is 19km (12 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Rafael Núñez International Airport </b><![CDATA[http://www.sacsa.com.co<p>The airport  is 2km (1 mile) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>El Dorado International Airport (Bogota)</b><![CDATA[http://www.eldorado.aero<p>The airport is located 15km (9 miles) north west of central Bogotá.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+57 1 266 2000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Cartagena, Barranquilla, Santa Marta and Turnaco (Caribbean coast); and Buenaventura (Pacific coast). Many ships and cruise lines visit these ports from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico">Mexico</a>, Venezuela, Central America and the Caribbean islands. If you&rsquo;re travelling by boat from Panama to Colombia, you're most likely to go to Cartagena.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Road routes are established and decent from Ecuador into Colombia. The roads into Venezuela are also well paved, but there is frequently border tension and travellers should check the situation before travelling overland between Venezuela and Colombia. It's not possible to drive directly from Brazil or Panama into Colombia, as there are no roads.</p>
<p>While there are no buses crossing the Ecuador border, you can catch a bus to the Colombian border town of Ipiales, cross on foot and hop on another bus at the other side. A reliable Colombian coach service is Bolivariano (tel: +57 1 424 9090; <a href="http://www.bolivariano.com.co" target="_blank">www.bolivariano.com.co</a>). There are some buses crossing the Colombia-Venezuela border.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Most public telephones take phone cards, which you can buy in many shops and kiosks. Many internet cafés also have international phone booths, as well as Skype facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a few international mobile phone companies. Coverage is limited to urban areas. If your phone is unlocked, you can buy a Colombian SIM card from companies such as Comcel, which will make calls and texts a lot cheaper. You may need identification for this.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafés in most towns and cities. Most hotels and hostels in bigger cities provide free Wi-Fi, and the connection is usually quite good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For many years Colombia was a dangerous place for journalists who faced intimidation by drug traffickers, guerrillas and paramilitary groups. In the 1990s, over 120 journalists were killed, many for investigating drug trafficking and corruption. Things have improved, and the law technically provides for freedom of the press, but there is still a long way to go.</p><p>The main papers are <em>El Pa&iacute;s</em> and <em>El Tiempo</em>; English-language papers are not prevalent. Colombia has five national TV channels: Caracol TV, RCN TV, Se&ntilde;al Colombia, Canal Institucional and Canal Uno. There are other local channels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The postal service is not reliable, and travellers are advised to use couriers if sending important documents or packages. There are no traditional post offices, but hotels in major cities offer a postal service.</p><p>Variable, but approximately Mon-Fri 0900-1200 and 1400-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Climb Nevado del Ruiz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Climb the snow-capped Nevado del Ruiz: the 5,400m (17,717ft) peak is one of five permanently white-tipped volcanoes in Los Nevados National Park in the coffee region. Volcanic eruptions and earthquakes are regular occurrences here, though hikers enjoy the benefits of hot springs bubbling from the mountainsides. Guided treks are available from Manizales, one of the main hubs for visitors.</p>]]><p><b>Cycle around car-free Bogotá</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cycle or skate along car-free roads in central Bogotá on Sundays and holidays from 0700 to 1400, when 121km (75 miles) of the capital's streets are transformed into <em>ciclovías</em> (cycleways). Cycling-mad Colombia also has many ideal countryside routes, where mountain-biking and touring groups operate, including the temperate hillsides of the Zona Cafetera.</p>]]><p><b>Delve into the Salt Cathedral of Zipaquirá</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The colonial city of Zipaquirá is home to one of Colombia's most popular attractions: a cathedral made of sale. Inaugurated in 1954, the underground church was hewn out of the mountain, deep within a salt mine near the city. Stalactites and specks of salt mingle with crosses and chapels to create a glowing spiritual atmosphere.</p>]]><p><b>Drift through the Amazon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a jungle tour into the Amazon basin, which covers almost one-third of Colombia's territory. Boat trips depart from Leticia, in the Amazonas region to the nearby Amacayu National Park. Tours often include visits to indigenous tribes, sleeping in hammocks slung in straw-roofed <em>malocas</em>. The park is prone to closure following flooding, so check the latest information before departure.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the jungle and beaches of Tayrona National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its stunning Caribbean location, the Tayrona National Park, close to Santa Marta, is one of the country's most popular parks. Spilling down from the northern slopes of the Sierra Nevada, it boasts coral reefs, sheltered bays, beautiful beaches, mangroves and wildlife-rich jungle. Get back to nature but don't forget to pack your mosquito repellent.</p>]]><p><b>Get wet and wild</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Colombia offers a host of adventures for watersports lovers. Dive into the species-rich tropical waters of the UNESCO Seaflower Biosphere Reserve around San Andrés and Providencia. Other diving hotspots include the Islas del Rosario and Tayrona National Park. Raft the rapids on the Rio Negro in Cundinamarca and Fonce or kayak through the Chicamocha canyon in Santander.</p>]]><p><b>Head for the dizzying heights of Bogotá</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Perched high in the Andes, the Colombian capital has an attractive mix of swish, modern neighbourhoods and windy streets overlooked by a mountainous vantage point (take the cable car up for great sunset views). Historical landmarks include the Capitolio Nacional and the cathedral on the main square, Plaza Bolivar. The star attraction, however, is the magnificent Gold Museum; its collection of pre-Columbian treasures is probably the finest in South America.</p>]]><p><b>Look for pirate treasure in the Caribbean</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fly to the tropical islands of San Andrés and its smaller sibling Providencia, two of Colombia's most idyllic retreats, off the Caribbean coast. San Andrés was once the headquarters of the English pirate Captain Henry Morgan, with an offshore underwater cave reputed to be the site of his buried loot, and a nearby museum dedicated to local pirate lore.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Botero’s artwork in Bogotá</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Latin America's most famous modern artists is Colombian Fernando Botero and visitors can wander among some of his characteristically voluptuous sculptures in the Plaza Botero, found in Bogotá's La Candelaria. Around 120 of his paintings, as well as an impressive collection of Impressionist and modern art, are on display at the Museo Botero, also in La Candelaria.</p>]]><p><b>Party at Carnival in Barranquilla</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once a year, the industrial port of Barranquilla is transformed by one of the world's biggest carnivals, second in size only to Rio de Janeiro's event, and attracting visitors from around the globe. The main parades take place on the four days preceding Ash Wednesday, when the city streets are filled with thousands of costumed dancers, gyrating to the lively Caribbean rhythms.</p>]]><p><b>Pop down to Popayán</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A great town to visit en route to the south, Popayán is a vision of beautifully restored colonial architecture. Wander around the stunning streets and visit the beautiful churches, in particular Belén, which is perched on a hilltop and provides lovely views. Easter week processions here are particularly impressive and nearby are the pre-Columbian tombs in Tierradentro National Park.</p>]]><p><b>Puzzle over San Agustín’s mysterious statues</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Weave your way around more than 500 mysterious pre-Columbian stone statues and tombs in one of South America's most fascinating archaeological sites, San Agustín, in the southern Cordilera Central. Thought to date back some 3,000 years, this is the largest group of religious monuments and megalithic sculptures on the continent, relating to one of the earliest Andean settlements.</p>]]><p><b>Shake your hips in Cali</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Colombia's capital of salsa, the southern city of Cali is the place to go for all-night hip swinging. Dress to impress in the salsa clubs, many of which are found in the Barrio Juanchito<em>,</em> which gets going at 0200 and doesn't stop until 0600. During the day explore San Antonio, the historical centre, or visit one of the highly rated museums.</p>]]><p><b>Soak up the colonial charms of Cartagena</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of South America's prettiest colonial towns, charming Cartagena brims with history and is more than a little easy on the eye. The former home of author, Gabriel Garcia Marquez, visitors can take literary tours of the city, explore cobbled streets and sip coffee beneath beautiful blooms of bougainvillea. Once you've had your culture fix, take a trip to nearby coral islands, which abound with beaches, labyrinthine mangrove forests and colourful coral reefs.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hike to the Ciudad Perdida</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Climb high into the jungle-covered Sierra Nevada de Santa Marta to the archaeological ruins of the Ciudad Perdida ('Lost City'), discovered in 1976. This six-day trek is not for the faint-hearted, but is one of Colombia's most rewarding adventures.</p>]]><p><b>Tour the Zona Cafetera (Coffee Zone)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Colombia is famous for its coffee, and you can take a trip to this region of gently rolling hillsides, visiting the coffee haciendas and hiking, cycling or horseback riding through the countryside, trying different coffees along the way. The triangle is made up of Quindío, Caldas and Risaralda departments, with plenty of towns in the area in which to stay.</p>]]><p><b>Travel back in time to Santa Cruz de Mompox</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Known simply as Mompox, this tiny colonial gem is off the main tourist path due to its comparative inaccessibility, but it's worth the trip by bus and boat. With its well-preserved architecture, the town has a sleepy, friendly feel about it. Simon Bolivar was one of its most famous residents, and Gabriel Garcia Márquez based his classic, <em>One Hundred Years of Solitude, </em>on the town.</p>]]><p><b>Visit vibrant Medellín</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The second largest city in Colombia, Medellín is modern and vibrant, having shaken off its association with violent drug cartels. Today, the pleasantly warm 'City of Eternal Spring' has a lively young community of university students, with a lot of time for the arts. Visit the museums and parks, learn to tango and embrace the serious nightlife on offer. The annual Festival of Flowers in August is superb.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$309.20 billion (2018 estimate).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil, coal, coffee, clothes, flowers and bananas.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Industrial equipment, cars, airplanes, chemicals and paper products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, China, Venezuela, Panama, Brazil and Mexico.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Colombia is Latin America's fourth largest oil producer and a primary coal producer, leaving the country vulnerably to fluctuations in commodity prices. When oil prices fell in 2017, the country's economy slowed down accordingly. Apart from oil and coal, Colombia is the world's second largest cut flowers exporter and third largest coffee exporter.</p>
<p>Colombia is a founding member of the Pacific Alliance which is a regional trade block formed in 2012 by Chile, Colombia, Mexico, and Peru to promote regional trade and economic integration.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Latin Americans take care over their clothes and overall appearance, and those doing business in Colombia are advised to do the same. A business trip that spans several days is likely to include an invitation for drinks or dinner. Many Colombian businesspeople speak English but any effort to speak Spanish is greatly appreciated. The Colombian Ministry of Foreign Affairs has an official translation service, and there are a number of commercial interpreter services.   The best months for business visits to Colombia are March to November. The business community generally takes holidays from September to February, the driest months. It is advisable to avoid Barranquilla in June and July.</p><p>Monday-Friday 0900-1200 and 1400-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Confederación Colombiana de Cámaras de Comercio (Chamber of Commerce)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 381 4100
					Website:http://www.confecamaras.org.co/
					Address: Bogotá,Carrera 13,No 27-47,Oficina 502,,]]><b>Colombian Government Trade Bureau in the USA</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (202) 887 9000
					Website:http://www.coltrade.org/
					Address: NW,1901 L Street,Suite 700,]]><b>CORFERIAS (National Centre of Trade Fairs)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 381 0000
					Website:http://www.corferias.com/
					Address: Bogotá,Carrera 37,No 24-67,,]]><b>Proexport Colombia</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 560 0100
					Website:http://www.proexport.com.co/
					Address: Bogotá,Calle 28,No 13A-15,Pisos 1,35 y 36,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>From hearty meat, potato and yucca-based Andean stews, to Caribbean seafood, Colombian cuisine is varied and tasty, with a touch of Spanish influence. Add to this the fruits of the Amazon, and you have a rich array of edible delights.</p>
<p>The international food found in bigger cities is generally of an excellent standard and vegetarians are well catered for &ndash; though they may struggle outside of Bogota and Medellin. You can find delicious seafood on the coasts, particularly along the Caribbean, where dishes are often flavoured with coconut and served with rice.</p>
<p>To save money, try <em>men&uacute;s del d&iacute;a</em> (menus of the day), which tend to be the most affordable way to eat out. Expect some soup, rice, a piece of meat or fish and an <em>arepa </em>(see below) or two. Colombian wines are generally of poor quality, but Chilean and Argentinian wines are available at a price. Beer and rum-based drinks are the norm, and both are quite cheap.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ajiaco:</strong> A rich soup made with chicken, potato and corn, with cream and capers added at the table.<br />
<strong>Arepas:</strong> Corn pancakes, eaten at every meal, with savoury toppings.<br />
<strong>Bandeja paisa:</strong> Meat with avocado, rice, fried plantain and red beans, typical to Medell&iacute;n.<br />
<strong>Tamales:</strong> Corn dough filled with meat, potatoes, rice or vegetables, steamed and wrapped in plantain leaves; a Colombian street-food classic.<br />
<strong>Arroz atollado:</strong> Rice cooked with a variety of meats, including chicken and chorizo &ndash; a speciality of the Pacific region.<br />
<strong>Empanadas:</strong> Pasties, stuffed with a combination of meat, cheese, vegetables or sweet fillings.<br />
<strong>Sancocho:</strong> A thick soup or stew from the Valle del Cauca region, made with a mixture of meat, plantain, potatoes, yucca and vegetables; served with rice.<br />
<strong>Tinto:</strong> Black coffee, usually sweetened, the way most Colombians prefer.<br />
<strong>Aguardiente: </strong>A fiery sugar cane spirit, flavoured with aniseed.<br />
<strong>Aguapanela:</strong> A sweet, non-alcoholic drink made with unrefined cane sugar; also sometimes with lime, ginger or other spices added.<br />
<strong>Canelazo:</strong> An aguardiente-based cocktail, drunk hot or cold, mixed with cinnamon and aguapanela.<br />
<strong>Chicha:</strong> A powerful spirit popular in the Andes; made from fermented corn, yucca or other fruits and vegetables.<br />
<strong>Chocolate:</strong> Hot chocolate drink, made of milk served with sugar, cinnamon and with small bars of chocolate stirred in.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 10% tip is usual in restaurants. Often added to the bill as a "propina voluntaria", everyone pays it as long as the service is good.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The hot-blooded Colombian people are known for their vibrant nightlife, with busy restaurants, numerous parties and nightclubs filled with dancers twisting hips to the beats of salsa, cumbia and merengue. The busiest nights are Thursday, Friday and Saturday.</p>
<p>Bogot&aacute; in particular offers ballet, opera, drama and music, as well as casinos. The Zona Rosa in Bogot&aacute; contains plenty of bars of all themes: a beer bar, an Irish bar and more Colombian bars than you can count, all with happy hours and offers. You&rsquo;ll also find many clubs around this area, which often have entrance fees.</p>
<p>Cali is the place to go for all-night salsa clubs, which are full of sharp young things dressed up to the nines, all displaying an enviable dancing ability. Medell&iacute;n offers a fantastic variety of bars and clubs. Most big cities have high-end hotels which come equipped with excellent bars, though this is the expensive way to do it. In Cartagena you&rsquo;ll find smaller bars in the walled old town serving good rum cocktails, with a chilled-out salsa vibe.</p>
<p>In smaller towns you&rsquo;ll more easily find local bars and a much more relaxed atmosphere, though the drink choice is largely limited to beers and rum. Colombia also has a well-developed hostel track, and most have their own bars where you can meet other travellers.</p>
<p>Colombia&rsquo;s tourist trail is being steadily established, and along the way entrepreneurial young expats are setting up bars, restaurants and caf&eacute;s. These places are good for happy hours and a taste of home, as well as free Wi-Fi.  </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Goods to look out for include gold jewellery, art, antiques and leather products. Colombia produces first-grade precious stones, and the emeralds are among the most perfect in the world. Shopping for these should only be undertaken if you know what you&rsquo;re doing however; incidents of cheating are high. Try to get recommendations of reputable dealers and acquire some knowledge before shopping for precious stones.<br />
<br />
Bogot&aacute; has numerous large shopping malls as well as several distinct shopping districts. Try the Zona Rosa for designer clothes and high-end jewellery stores, and La Candelaria for independent, unique shops.</p>
<p>In Cali you can find authentic handicrafts and goods from all over the country in the Parque Artesan&iacute;a &ndash; perfect for souvenirs. Cali also has some ultra-modern shopping malls, such as Chipichape, offering more generic produce such as clothes and shoes at prices not much less than you would pay at home. These malls contain bars and restaurants for you to make an evening of your shopping trip, as well as big food courts serving a mixture of North American and Colombian fast food.</p>
<p>You can buy Colombian coffee throughout the country, not just in the Zona Cafetera, but if buying as a gift bear in mind that it might be opened at Customs. Also take care when buying souvenirs made of skin or feather &ndash; cultural artefacts and items of animal origin such as the above are prohibited.</p><p>In colder cities such as Bogotá, typically Mon-Sat 1100-2100. In hotter cities, Mon-Sat 0900-2100.</p><p>When visiting more rural areas and exploring tomb-ridden regions, guides may well offer authentic souvenirs, such as goods from tombs, and drugs. Taking cultural artefacts and illegal substances out of the country is prohibited: bear in mind that Colombian prisons aren't pleasant, and sentences are long.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Colombia vary widely in size and quality; they range from pocket-sized <em>hospedajes</em><em> </em>(guest houses) in humble homes to huge 5-star establishments. It is advisable to choose hotels recommended by the official Colombian Hotel Association (COTELCO) (<a href="http://www.cotelco.org" target="_blank">www.cotelco.org</a>). There is a star grading system similar to that operating in Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfasts in Colombia usually take the form of <em>hospedajes</em> or guest houses, which will generally offer a room with or without breakfast &ndash; it depends if you want to pay a little more. These can range from extensions of people&rsquo;s houses to small hotels. They are usually good value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Colombia vary widely in size and quality; they range from pocket-sized <em>hospedajes</em><em> </em>(guest houses) in humble homes to huge 5-star establishments. It is advisable to choose hotels recommended by the official Colombian Hotel Association (COTELCO) (<a href="http://www.cotelco.org" target="_blank">www.cotelco.org</a>). There is a star grading system similar to that operating in Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Colombia vary widely in size and quality; they range from pocket-sized <em>hospedajes</em><em> </em>(guest houses) in humble homes to huge 5-star establishments. It is advisable to choose hotels recommended by the official Colombian Hotel Association (COTELCO) (<a href="http://www.cotelco.org" target="_blank">www.cotelco.org</a>). There is a star grading system similar to that operating in Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Although cases of &lt;strong&gt;Zika infection&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;in Colombia have dropped dramatically since the initial outbreak in 2015, there is still has a high risk of infection within the country and all travellers are advised to practice strict mosquito bite avoidance at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organisation recommends travellers to Colombia protect themselves from mosquito bites by wearing light-coloured clothes that cover as much of the body as possible, sleeping under mosquito nets and using repellents that contain DEET (diethyltoluamide), IR 3535 ((3- [N-butyl-N-acetyl], aminopropionic acid ethyl-ester) or KBR3023 (also called Icaridin or Picaridin). Pregnant women are advised to postpone non-essential travel until after pregnancy and pregnant women whose sexual partners live in or travel to areas with Zika virus transmission should follow safe sexual practices or abstain from sex for the duration of their pregnancy. Women who are pregnant, at risk of getting pregnant, or planning pregnancy should seek further advice from their doctor before travelling to Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health facilities in the main cities are good, and pharmacies stock most drugs at prices that tend to be lower than in the UK or USA. In rural areas, medical services can be very limited and travellers who become ill in remote areas should try to get to a city as soon as possible to be treated. Visitors travelling to jungle areas are advised to carry first aid kits, including antibacterial ointment and coverings for wounds which can become easily infected and not heal well in the humidity. When travelling to the coast or jungle areas, travellers should take DEET-containing insect repellent in order to avoid any mosquito-borne illnesses. Travellers are strongly advised to take out full medical insurance &amp;ndash; Colombia has many adventurous activities on offer and you should ensure that your travel insurance covers you for all of them.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated outside major cities. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Bottled water is widely available throughout the country however, including in rural towns, so you can always make sure you have some. Milk may be unpasteurised in places and should be boiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only eat well cooked meat and fish. When buying food from stalls or markets, try to ensure that the food has not been sitting there for a while, and is kept hot enough to kill germs. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled. There is an abundance of fruit available throughout Colombia, which includes pre-cut fruit put into bags and sold on beaches or from stalls in tourist areas. Buying whole fruit from the markets is both cheaper and more hygienic, and will help avoid contamination.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccination against hepatitis B is sometimes recommended, especially for those spending long periods of time in Colombia or anyone who could have sexual relations with the local population. Hepatitis C occurs. Outbreaks of dengue fever sometimes occur, particularly in areas along the Caribbean coast and in the Choc&amp;oacute;, Antioquia, C&amp;oacute;rdoba, Sucre, Bolivar and Atl&amp;aacute;ntico departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take care when going from sea level to high altitude &amp;ndash; if you&amp;rsquo;re sensitive to it, don&amp;rsquo;t go on any major hikes the first day you arrive in Bogot&amp;aacute;. Allow several days to acclimatise to altitudes over 2,500m (8,200ft). Initial symptoms include headaches, breathlessness (especially when walking up hills), dizziness and nausea. This should pass within 72 hours.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>St Joseph's Day :
							25 March </p><p>Maundy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							20 July </p><p>Battle of Boyac :
							07 August </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>D :
							12 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Independence of Cartagena City :
							11 November </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be taken into Colombia by travellers 18 years of age and older without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes and 50 cigars and up to 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2 bottles of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; Goods for personal use to the value of US$1,500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ammunition and firearms (unless prior authorisation has been obtained), vegetables, plants or plant material, and meat and animal food products.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taking cultural artefacts out of the country is prohibited, so if tour guides offer to sell you goods from tombs, politely decline. Colombian coffee is not prohibited, but will most likely be opened and checked. Drugs are absolutely forbidden, with harsh penalties for non-compliance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Colombian Peso (COP; symbol Col$) = 100 centavos. Notes are in denominations of Col$100,000, 50,000, 20,000, 10,000, 5,000 and 2,000. Coins are in denominations of Col$1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50 and 20. US Dollars are sometimes accepted, but be aware that you may be viewed as a rich tourist if you try to pay with dollars and you might find that the prices go up. Also be aware that there are a large amount of counterfeit <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars in Colombia, so if you need change, get it in Colombian Pesos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency should be exchanged at hotels, banks and bureaux de change only, though most places charge commission. Travellers are advised against changing money on the street. The US Dollar is the easiest currency to exchange. When crossing borders, in particular in Ipiales, be very careful with the money changers, and make sure you do the calculations on your own.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa and Mastercard are widely accepted, American Express and Diners Club less so. There are ATMs throughout the main cities; some will allow cash withdrawals using Visa, MasterCard or Cirrus. Ensure you know the number to call to cancel your card quickly if it is stolen, and inform your bank beforehand that you will be travelling to Colombia in case your accounts are frozen upon use.</p><p>There are ATMs throughout the main cities; some will allow cash withdrawals using Visa, Mastercard or Cirrus. While the prevalence of ATMs is increasing throughout the country, in smaller, rural towns and villages you should ensure you have enough cash to last until you get back to a bigger city. ATMs can be temperamental, run out of money or not work for you when they worked perfectly well the day before. Try to use ATMs in the daytime rather than after dark, and within banks with security guards if possible.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The most commonly accepted traveller's cheques are those issued by American Express and Citicorp. Traveller's cheques can be exchanged at banks, hotels or bureaux de change. They are generally not accepted as a form of payment, other than at major hotels. While safe, generally traveller's cheques should be avoided in case you can find nowhere which will take them; ATMs are a much more efficient way of handling your money. If you do choose to bring traveller's cheques, make sure you take them in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1500. On the last business day of every month, banks close at 1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above to enter Colombia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no restrictions on entry with children, but children of Colombian nationality must have the written consent of both parents to travel without them, even if travelling on another nation&rsquo;s passport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit passengers do not require a visa or to pay departure tax providing they do not leave the airport and make their connecting flight within 24 hours of arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Enquire at the relevant consulate about the current visa fees.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitor (tourist or temporary): multiple entries within six months; business: multiple entries within three or four years (depending on the type of business visa) with maximum stays of one year each.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy) or online (<a href="http://www.cancilleria.gov.co/en/procedures_services/visas">www.cancilleria.gov.co/en/procedures_services/visas</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Enquire at the consulate for forms and details on how to obtain temporary residence in Colombia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing usually takes five working days, or eight days if the application is referred to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You may be asked to provide proof of sufficient funds to cover your costs in Colombia. Up-to-date bank statements showing more than &pound;1,000 will suffice. In practice, this is rarely requested.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Extensions for up to a further 120 days are available from Migraci&oacute;n Colombia. Visitors cannot stay for more than 180 days within a 12-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can take your pet to Colombia provided they have been vaccinated against rabies (unless coming from a rabies-free country or under four months old), distemper, hepatitis, leptospirosis and parvovirus, and they have a licensed vet&rsquo;s certificate.  However, for the purpose of travelling it is best to leave pets at home.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[3.998034]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-73.278006]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,141,748 sq km (440,831 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>48,829,027 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>43.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bogot&aacute;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Colombia is situated in South America, bordered by the Caribbean Sea and the Pacific Ocean, Panama, Ecuador, Peru, Venezuela and Brazil. The Andes Mountains extend into the country in three ranges running south to north, dipping finally into the lowlands of the Caribbean coast.</p>
<p>Along the southern Pacific coast run marshy lowlands and rugged low mountains. The southwestern coastal lowlands extend in a trough running from the port of Buenaventura to the Caribbean. East of this rise the slopes of the Western Cordillera which, with the Central Cordillera range, runs north to the Caribbean lowlands from Ecuador. Further north lies the fertile Cauca Valley, which becomes a deep gorge running between the Cordilleras to the Caribbean lowlands.</p>
<p>The Eastern Cordillera, the longest range, rises north of the Ecuadorean border and runs north then northeast towards Venezuela. Flat grassy prairies in the east along with the jungles and towering rainforests of the Amazon make up over half the country's area. Colombia also claims two small islands, San Andr&eacute;s and Providencia, located 700km (430 miles) north of the coast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christianity, with 90% Roman Catholic; small Protestant and Jewish minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal courtesies should be observed. It is customary to offer guests black Colombian coffee, well sugared, called <em>tinto</em>. Spanish style and culture can still be seen in parts of the country, although in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bogota">Bogotá</a>, North American attitudes and clothes are becoming prevalent. Casual clothes can be worn in most places; formal attire will be necessary for exclusive dining rooms and social functions. Smoking is allowed except where indicated.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mostly 110 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without round grounding pin) are standard; some sockets may not accept plugs with a grounding pin however, so you may need an adaptor.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Iv&aacute;n Duque M&aacute;rquez since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Iv&aacute;n Duque M&aacute;rquez since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prior to the Spanish invasion, the land comprising modern-day Colombia was ruled by various Amerindian tribes who traded with each other and established their own civilisations. The two main tribes were the Taironas, who were largely based in the Caribbean, and the Muiscas, who were settled in the highlands around Bogot&aacute;. To this day, indigenous peoples who have descended from the Taironas live in Tairona National Park.</p>
<p>Now named after Christopher Columbus, Colombia in its present form has only existed since the 1800s. The Spanish conquistadors grouped it with modern-day Venezuela, Ecuador and parts of Brazil and Central America; they called this vast territory New Granada and ruled it from Europe.</p>
<p>The desire for independence soon followed, however, when discontent among mixed-race Creoles, lower-class Spanish immigrants and indigenous people spread, here and all across the continent. This eventually led to the 1819 rebellion under the legendary figure of Sim&oacute;n Bol&iacute;var, which resulted in the area being split into the four provinces of Gran Colombia: Panama, Ecuador, Colombia and Venezuela. Colombia separated from the others soon after Bol&iacute;var's death in 1830.</p>
<p>The Republic of Colombia was formally established in 1855, four years after the abolition of slavery. Over the next 100 years, politics were dominated by the Conservative-Liberal feud, which often broke out into warfare. Occasionally, however, the two parties united against a common threat. This occurred in 1970, when they prevented a bid for power by the Alianza Nacional Popular (ANAPO), led by former dictator, General Rojas.</p>
<p>Colombia has since had to handle various guerrilla movements against the government, such as from disaffected members of ANAPO, the Fuerzas Armadas Revolucionarias de Colombia (FARC, Colombian Revolutionary Armed Forces) and the Ejercito de Liberacion Nacional (ELN, National Liberation Army).</p>
<p>The 1980s saw drug traffickers become a potent force in Colombia: large sums of money turned into political power, and leading politicians increasingly became tainted by their connections with drug money. Successive US governments, having pinpointed Colombia as the principal source of drugs flowing into the USA, put increasing pressure on the Colombians to fight the 'war on drugs'.</p>
<p>In 2000, the US Clinton administration unveiled Plan Colombia, a controversial initiative aimed at fighting cocaine cartels and left-wing insurgents. This included the aerial fumigation of coca plantations, which destroyed the crops of innocent farmers and has been blamed for birth defects in rural communities.</p>
<p>Over the last decade, Colombia has undergone a remarkable transformation: the guerrillas have &ndash; mostly &ndash; accepted peace agreements and drug-related violence has fallen; tourism is once again booming.&nbsp;In September 2016, President Juan Manuel Santos signed an historic peace agreement with Colombia's leftist FARC rebels to end the country's 53-year conflict.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Infamous drug lord Pablo Escobar reportedly offered to pay Colombia's national debt of $10bn to improve his reputation.<br />
&bull; Colombia is the self-proclaimed cycling capital of South America; Bogot&aacute; has more than 250km (155 miles) of dedicated bicycle routes.<br />
&bull; The town of Yarumal has the world&rsquo;s highest incidence of Alzheimer&rsquo;s, described in <em>100 Years of Solitude </em>by writer Gabriel Garcia Marquez, who was himself a victim of the disease.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Colombia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(1) 326 8300.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukincolombia.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(1) 326 8300.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0830-1230 and 1330-1700, Fri 0830-1330.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Piso 8, Edificio ING Barings<br/>Carrera 9, No 76-49<br/>Bogotá<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Colombia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7589 5037 ; (020) 7927 7123 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://reinounido.embajada.gov.co</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7589 5037 ; (020) 7927 7123 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1800.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Kensington<br/>Hans Crescent<br/>London<br/>SW1X 0<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Colombia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 387 8338.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.colombiaemb.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 387 8338.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1800.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2118 Leroy Place<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Proexport Colombia (tourist office)]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(1) 427 9000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.colombia.travel</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(1) 427 9000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Piso 36<br/>Calle 28A, No 13A-15<br/>Bogotá<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since emerging from decades of civil unrest, Colombia has established itself as one of the world&rsquo;s top destinations. And rightly so: this exquisite South American nation is blessed with natural beauty &ndash; think high Andean peaks, Caribbean beaches, pristine Amazon jungle &ndash; not to mention mysterious archaeological sites, colonial treasures and thriving cities. It&rsquo;s a joy to travel around.</p>
<p>At the heart of it all is Bogota, the pulsating capital. Once synonymous with drug cartels and gangs, the city has recast itself as one of South America&rsquo;s trendiest destinations; a place of hip bars and street art, vibrant markets and colourful architecture. Sprawled across the Andean plateau, Bogota offers a fabulous mix of old and new; the cobbled streets of La Candelaria offer a stark contrast to the urban chic of Zona Rosa. But it works.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Colombia&rsquo;s colonial towns have been lovingly preserved, most notably the UNESCO-listed city of Cartagena. But don&rsquo;t stop there. Other historic settlements also warrant a visit, amongst them the cities of Momp&oacute;s, Villa de Leiva and Barichara. The mysterious &ldquo;lost city&rdquo; of Ciudad Perdida is also worthy of a detour, but you may leave with more questions than you arrived with.</p>
<p>The more you travel around Colombia, the more you marvel at its diversity. While the Caribbean and Pacific shores boast beautiful beaches, islands and coral reefs, the lofty Andes offer high-altitude plains, snow-capped mountains and limpid lakes. Then there are the eastern lowlands with their grassy wetlands and bountiful birdlife, not to mention the virgin forests of the Amazon.</p>
<p>Colombian culture is no less magical. Garcia Marquez&rsquo;s land of magic realism is alive with festivals and music; the high-energy city of Cali is recognized as the salsa capital of Colombia, while bustling Barranquilla hosts a dazzling carnival to rival Rio&rsquo;s. To cap it all off, visitors can expect a warm welcome from the country&rsquo;s friendly inhabitants, who, after years in the wilderness, can finally show their true colours. And what a picture they paint.</p><p>Since emerging from decades of civil unrest, Colombia has established itself as one of the world&rsquo;s top destinations. And rightly so: this exquisite South American nation is blessed with natural beauty &ndash; think high Andean peaks, Caribbean beaches, pristine Amazon jungle &ndash; not to mention mysterious archaeological sites, colonial treasures and thriving cities. It&rsquo;s a joy to travel around. At the heart of it all is Bogota, the pulsating capital. Once synonymous with drug cartels and gangs, the city has recast itself as one of South America&rsquo;s trendiest destinations; a place of hip bars and street art, vibrant markets and colourful architecture.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
