<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Comoros" ColCode="com" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="km" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Comoros]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is tropical and very warm. Coastal areas are hot and very humid, interspaced with rains and seasonal cyclones (January to April). The upland areas are cooler, particularly at night, and have higher rainfall. The rainy season is from November to April.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens with waterproofing during the rainy<br />season. Warmer garments and rainwear are needed for the mountains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Each island has an airfield and there are services between the islands in the region.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The islands are linked by regular ferry services. Travellers can hire motorboats, sailing craft and canoes in port villages and towns. A boat can be especially useful for Mwali (Moh&eacute;li) where the road system is rudimentary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>All the islands have tarred roads, but&nbsp;4-wheel drive vehicles are advisable for the outlying islands and in the interior, especially in the rainy season.&nbsp;Roads are narrow and domestic animals often roam free, so you should drive slowly.</p><p>Bush taxis (<em>taxis-brousses</em>), hired vehicles or private cars are the only forms of transport on the islands.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is valid for up to three months.</p><p>Available on Ngazidja (Grande Comore).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating to the Comoros include Air Madagascar (<a href="http://www.airmadagascar.com" target="_blank">www.airmadagascar.com</a>) and Kenya Airways (<a href="http://www.kenya-airways.com" target="_blank">www.kenya-airways.com</a>).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Moroni Prince Said Ibrahim International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Outgoing international calls must be made through the international operator.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Limited coverage.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A few hotels have Internet access.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no single national newspaper. Although several private newspapers criticise the government, self-censorship is reportedly common. Local radio and TV stations operate without overt government interference. The main (weekly) papers are Al Watwan (state-owned), published on Grand Comore, Kuesi, published on the French island of Mayotte, and La Gazette des Comores (independent); L'Archipel (independent) is published monthly. There are no English-language newspapers. There is a national radio station, Radio Comoros, and a national TV service. RFO Mayotte, run by French public radio and TV, broadcasts French and locally-produced radio and TV programmes from the French island of Mayotte, and can be received in parts of the archipelago.<strong><br /></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mail to Western Europe takes at least one week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Climb Mount Karthala</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you're feeling energetic, climb to the top of Mount Karthala, the Comoros' highest point at 2,260m (7,750ft), and then descend into the crater of this still active volcano. The vast crater, which is 4km (2.5 miles) wide in places, is said to be the largest of any active volcano in the world.</p>]]><p><b>Come face to face with turtles on Mohéli</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Known for its undisturbed natural beauty and tranquillity, Mohéli is the smallest of the Comoros Islands. Home to the nation's first protected area, the Parc Marin de Mohéli, it is a favourite with nature lovers for its populations of green turtle, dolphins, whales and exotic birds.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Nzwani’s Swahili architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nzwani (Anjouan) Island is notable for its waterfalls and abundant vegetation. The main town of Mutsamudu is built in Swahili-Shirazi style, complete with 17th-century houses with carved doors, twisting alleyways, mosques and a citadel. The ancient capital of Domoni is also worth a visit. The best beaches are in the Bimbini area, while perfume distilleries are found at Bambao.</p>]]><p><b>Go scuba-diving in crystalline waters</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With limpid waters and pristine coral reefs, diving opportunities abound throughout the archipelago. The Trou du Prophète in Misamiouli on Ngazidja, Niumashuwa Bay on Mwali and Pamanzi off Mahore are particularly fine sites, often visited by grey reef sharks, barracuda and even manta rays.</p>]]><p><b>Hike to Dziani Boundouni</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dziani Boundouni is a sulphurous crater-lake at the centre of sparsely populated Mohéli, which can be reached on day-walks from the island capital of Fomboni. Popular with birdwatchers, a hike here also throws up the chance of catching sight of rare mongoose lemurs in the nearby rainforests.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are many excellent beaches on the islands and Galawa Beach on Grande Comore has a diving school for those who get bored bathing. Other good beaches include Bouni, Chomoni (near a sheltered bay), Itsandra and the palm-fringed Planet Plage. Traditional canoe races are occasionally staged in the lagoon that surrounds Mahore, while visitors can watch dhows (Arab sail boats) being built on the beach at Fomboni.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Mitsamiouli</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A town in the north of Grande Comore, Mitsamiouli has a number of beaches of white sand popular with tourists, and the remains of a Royal Palace dating back to the era of the Sultans. The town is known both for its good diving facilities and for having the best Comoran dancers.</p>]]><p><b>Stop off at the French island of Mahore (Mayotte)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This French-administered island is surrounded by coral reefs and has good beaches and excellent scuba-diving facilities. The town of Dzaoudzi contains some old fortifications worth visiting. Nature lovers will enjoy the forested island of Pamanzi, 5km (3 miles), as well as the waterfall at Sulu, which plunges straight into the sea.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the laidback capital, Moroni</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The national capital, Moroni, is situated on Ngazidja (Grande Comore). A charming town, it contains a few broad squares and modern government buildings as well as the old, narrow, winding streets and market place. There are numerous fine mosques including the Friday Mosque, the top of which offers attractive views over the town and ocean.</p>]]><p><b>While away the day in Itsandra</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This fishing village, 6km (4 miles) from Moroni on Grande Comore, has a fine beach and opportunities to see traditional dances performed by the local men. The town was once the ancient capital of the island, complete with royal tombs and a fortress built in the 17th century.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$394.4 million (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Vanilla, cloves, ylang-ylang (perfume oil) and copra.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Rice and petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Exports to: France, USA, Singapore and Germany; Imports from: France, South Africa, Japan<, Thailand, Indonesia, Singapore and China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The bulk of the working population is employed in agriculture, which produces vanilla and cloves (the main exports), basil, ylang-ylang (an essence extracted from trees) and copra. There is a small fishing industry and a minimal industrial base devoted mainly to processing vanilla.<br /><br />The tourism industry has grown rapidly during the last 10 years to the extent that the service sector as a whole now accounts for almost 60% of total domestic output: chronic political instability on the islands has, however, probably prevented the industry from reaching its full potential. Moreover, the agricultural economy is vulnerable to low world commodity prices. <br /><br />Substantial French aid remains essential. France is also the country's major trading partner, providing almost half of the Comoros' imports and taking two-thirds of its exports. China, Kenya, Tanzania and Madagascar are the other major importers into the islands.<br /><br />Per capita income is estimated at US$720. The economy grew slowly at 1.3% in 2005.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suit or shirt and tie required. Business is conducted in French or Arabic; English is seldom spoken.<br /></p><p>Mon-Thurs 0730-1430, Fri 0730-1130, Sat 0730-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce, d'Industrie et d'Agriculture</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 730 958
					Website:
					Address: ,BP 763,Moroni,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Comorian cuisine owes a lot to both Arab and French influences, creating a fusion of European classics with a Middle Eastern or East African twist that sees sauces spiced with cloves, cinnamon, cardamom, nutmeg and even vanilla poured over rice-based dishes.</p><p>Coconut milk is an important staple, alongside traditional African ingredients such as plantain, bananas and cassava. A typical Comorian meal will also include meat or fish. Goat is a popular meat, with beef reserved for special occasions. Locally-caught cod, crab and lobster, are all widely eaten.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Langouste a la vanille</strong>: Lobster boiled in a rich vanilla sauce.<br />
<strong>Mkatra foutra</strong>: Fried unleavened bread made with coconut water.<br />
<strong>Pilaou</strong>: Highly-spiced meat and rice dish.<br />
<strong>Ambrevades au curry</strong>: Pigeon pea curry flavoured with cardamom.<br />
<strong>M&rsquo;tsolola</strong>: Fish and green plantains stewed in coconut milk.<br />
<strong>Achard aux legumes</strong>: Lightly pickled vegetable salad.<br />
<strong>Ntrovi ya nazi</strong>: Fried or steamed fish with cooking bananas and coconut stew.<br />
<strong>Poutou</strong>: Hot sauce made with chilli peppers, tomato, onion and lemon.<br />
<strong>Ladu</strong>: Balls of sweetened and spiced ground rice.<br />
<strong>Mataba</strong>: Cassava leaves, used a little like spinach.<br />
<strong>Roti ya ya Houma pampa</strong>: Cod with tomato and onion.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>There may be restrictions on drink within Muslim circles.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Normally 10%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Comoran products can be purchased at Moroni on Ngazidja (Grande Comore). These include gold, pearl and shell jewellery, woven cloth, embroidered skull-caps (<em>koffia</em>) and slippers, carved chests, panels and <em>portes-croix</em> (lecterns), pottery and basketry. Most items can be bought in the villages where they are made.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0830-1200 and 1500-1830 (often shops remain open until later).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although accommodation on the Comoros is being upgraded, there are only a few hotels and pensions, located mostly in Moroni and Mutsamudu, which handle the needs of travelling businesspeople, Government officials and other visitors. Room sharing is quite common. There are simple shelters (<em>gîtes</em>) on the slopes of Karthala (an active volcano).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although accommodation on the Comoros is being upgraded, there are only a few hotels and pensions, located mostly in Moroni and Mutsamudu, which handle the needs of travelling businesspeople, Government officials and other visitors. Room sharing is quite common. There are simple shelters (<em>gîtes</em>) on the slopes of Karthala (an active volcano).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although accommodation on the Comoros is being upgraded, there are only a few hotels and pensions, located mostly in Moroni and Mutsamudu, which handle the needs of travelling businesspeople, Government officials and other visitors. Room sharing is quite common. There are simple shelters (<em>gîtes</em>) on the slopes of Karthala (an active volcano).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are basic and most are private. In order to secure even basic medical care, visitors are strongly advised to take out comprehensive health insurance.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water&lt;br /&gt;used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been&lt;br /&gt;boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be&lt;br /&gt;boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products&lt;br /&gt;which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat&lt;br /&gt;well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and&lt;br /&gt;fruit peeled&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis E is widespread. Hepatitis B is hyperendemic. Vaccination against tuberculosis is sometimes advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Anniversary of the Death of President Said Mohamed Cheikh :
							18 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							06 July </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into the Comoros by travellers 18 years of age and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes or 100 cigars or 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of alcoholic beverage.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of perfume.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Plants or soil, except on presentation of an import permit issued from the Comoros Agriculture Department, together with a phytosanitary certificate of the place of origin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Comoros Franc (KMF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of KMF10,000, 5,000, 2,500, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of KMF20, 10, 5, 2 and 1, and 20 centimes. The Comoros Franc is part of the French Monetary Area and Euros and US Dollars are also commonly used. The Comoros Franc is tied to the Euro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency may be exchanged in banks in the towns. Banking facilities are very limited on the other islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is limited acceptance of most international credit cards (mainly in hotels). Some hotels and restaurants will accept foreign currencies, mostly Euros and US Dollars. Change may be given in local currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Banque d'Industrie et Commerce (BIC) (also known as the Banque Internationale des Comores) is the only bank that will change traveller's cheques. There is no blanket policy on hotels accepting traveller's cheques and travellers are advised to contact hotels individually. <br /><br />To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0730-1300; Fri 0730-1100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter the Comoros islands, nationals referred to in the chart above must present a passport valid for six months beyond the date of entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: free; tourist visa on arrival: &euro;30; long-stay visa: &euro;255.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: 24 hours; tourist visa on arrival: 45 days; long-stay visa: valid for stays of over 45 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are issued on arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-11.830008]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[43.820986]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,235 sq km (863 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>807,118 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>349.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Moroni.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal Islamic Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Comoro archipelago is situated in the Indian Ocean, north of Madagascar. It consists of four main islands of volcanic origin, which are surrounded by coral reefs: Ngazidja (formerly Grande Comore), Nzwani (formerly Anjouan), Mwali (formerly Moh&eacute;li) and Mahor&eacute; (Mayotte). The latter is administered by France, but is claimed by the Federal Islamic Republic of the Comoros. Land can only support subsistence agriculture, but the surrounding seas are rich in marine life.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Muslim (mostly Sunni) with Roman Catholic minority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Religious customs associated with Islam should be respected. Although Comorans are tolerant towards other cultures (for instance, alcohol is not banned and is available in hotels and restaurants), they expect moderate behaviour from non Muslim visitors, such as no consumption of alcohol in public places and modest dress in public.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used. Electricity shortages occur.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Ikililou Dhoinine since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Ikililou Dhoinine since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the 15th century, Arabs settled on what are now known as the Comoros Islands. The islands were ceded to the French in 1841, and became a French protectorate in 1886, before being formally adopted as colonial possessions in 1912. The Comoros were then governed as part of Madagascar until 1947, when they became a separate French Overseas Territory.</p>
<p>Internal self-government was granted in 1961, although full independence was not achieved until 1975. The main reason was the position of Mayotte, one of the original Comoros island group, which insisted upon retaining its links with France. With Mayotte going its own way, the Comoros joined the United Nations as the Federal Islamic Republic of the Comoros, comprising three islands: Grande Comore, Anjouan and Moheli.</p>
<p>Ahmed Abdallah was elected as the first president, but within months Abdallah was overthrown. However, in 1978, with the assistance of French mercenaries, Abdallah regained his position, though his success was short-lived &ndash; he was assassinated the following year.</p>
<p>A confusing series of coups and counter coups ensued for the next decade or so, many led by Bob Denard, a French soldier and mercenary. Although Denard's last attempt was suppressed by French troops despatched from Reunion, he had previously overthrown presidents with the open support of the French government.</p>
<p>Elections successfully took place in 1996, and the new government of Abdoulkarim Taki was determined to introduce Islamic law to the islands. This was fiercely resisted in many quarters.</p>
<p>President Taki died in 1998, and was replaced by Ben Said Massounde. The new government was overthrown in a military coup led by Colonel Azali Assoumani in 1999, which was the country&rsquo;s 18th coup. During the next two years, the military government laid plans for a new constitution that would maintain the group as a single country, but with much greater autonomy afforded to the individual islands. In 2001, it was approved in a national referendum.</p>
<p>The following year Assoumani was declared president of the newly entitled Union of Comoros. The handover of power to his successor in 2006 was the first peaceful change of leadership in the country&rsquo;s history.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Since independence the Comoros Islands have averaged a coup every 22 months, giving it the nickname &lsquo;cloud coup coup land&rsquo;.<br />
&bull;	The Comoros are considered one of only two electoral democracies in the Arab world.<br />
&bull;	Geographically and historically part of the Comoros, the island of Mayotte voted to remain part of France. It is one of the European Union&rsquo;s outermost regions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Mauritius]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(230) 202 9400.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinmauritius.fco.gov.uk/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(230) 202 9400.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0745-1545; Friday 0745-1330. Mon-Thurs 1100-1300, Fri 0900-1100 (visa services).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>PO Box 1063<br/>7th Floor, Les Cascades Building, Edith Cavell Street<br/>Port Louis<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Comoros Islands Honorary Consulate in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7722 1146.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7722 1146.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Flat 6, 24-26 Avenue Road<br/>London<br/>NW8 6DU<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Comoros in France]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(01) 4067 9054.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(01) 4067 9054.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>20 rue Marbeau<br/>Paris<br/>75116<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not your typical tropical island getaway, Comoros may lay claim to sandy shores, limpid oceans and colourful coral reefs, but the archipelago&rsquo;s greatest asset is its fascinating culture, which fuses together the most colourful elements of Africa and Arabia.</p>
<p>Floating between Mozambique and Madagascar, the archipelago has long been a crossroads between civilisations and most Comorians are of mixed Afro-Arab descent. A blend of Swahili and traditional Islamic influences pervade the islands giving them a calm and phlegmatic atmosphere that guarantees a hospitable welcome.</p>
<p>The four main islands that comprise sleepy Comoros do not share the tourist infrastructure of the Seychelles or Mauritius (with the exception of Mayotte), but they do share the warm seas, deserted beaches and stunning hiking that these destinations are renowned for.</p>
<p>Most travellers enter the country via the capital, Moroni, which nestles on the island of Grande Comore and hums with the atmosphere and traditional customs of a long-forgotten outpost. Men drink tea beneath whitewashed buildings in the Arab Quarter, as they have done for decades, while women in brightly coloured East African fabrics smile shyly from ornate doorways.</p>
<p>Also known as the Perfume Islands, the smell of vanilla, cloves and other spices is ever-present in Comoros, and locals are proud to produce more Ylang-Ylang essence for the perfume industry than anywhere else.</p>
<p>Leave fragrant Moroni behind and trek to the summit of Mount Karthala, also on Grande Comore. The archipelago&rsquo;s highest peak, at just under 2,400m (7,800ft), this lofty vantage point happens to be one of the region&rsquo;s most active volcanoes. The views are exquisite.</p>
<p>For a taste of France pay a visit to Mayotte, which, due to a quirk in colonial history is now governed from Paris. Arguably the most developed of the islands, it has a distinctly Gallic air, adding more depth to these already characterful islands.</p><p>Not your typical tropical island getaway, Comoros may lay claim to sandy shores, limpid oceans and colourful coral reefs, but the archipelago&rsquo;s greatest asset is its fascinating culture, which fuses together the most colourful elements of Africa and Arabia.</p>
<p>Floating between Mozambique and Madagascar, the archipelago has long been a crossroads between civilisations and most Comorians are of mixed Afro-Arab descent. A blend of Swahili and traditional Islamic influences pervade the islands giving them a calm and phlegmatic atmosphere that guarantees a hospitable welcome.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
