<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Cook Islands" ColCode="cok" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ck" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Cook Islands]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Weather can be quite changeable from day to day and varies throughout the islands. It is generally hot throughout the year, although the trade winds provide some moderating influence. Rainfall is heaviest in Rarotonga, while the northern atolls tend to be drier. The coolest months are June to August, while November to March marks the warmer season, which also has the highest rainfall.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens throughout the year. Warmer clothes are advised for the evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Rarotonga (<a href="http://www.airraro.com/" target="_blank">www.airraro.com</a>) runs regular inter-island services.<strong><br />
</strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>Cook's Passenger Transport (<a href="http://www.busaboutraro.com" target="_blank">www.busaboutraro.com</a>) runs public buses round Rarotonga. There's one loop, with buses running in both a clockwise and anticlockwise direction.</p><p>Bright green licensed taxis are available 24 hours a day on Raratonga.</p>
<p>Alternatively, give Tik-es a go. These electric tuk tuks are a novel way of getting from A to B on Rarotonga.</p><p>As long as you're over 16, you can drive on a valid national driving licence from your home country for up to six months. If you're not licensed to ride a scooter or motorbike at home, you must obtain a&nbsp;Cook Islands driving licence, which means taking a theory and practical test at the police headquarters in Avarua.</p><p>Speed limits are 30-40kph (19-25mph) in built-up areas and 50kph (31mph) elsewhere.</p><p>Car hire is available through local and international companies. You can also rent bikes or mopeds.</p><p>Speed limits are 30-40kph (19-25mph) in built-up areas and 50kph (31mph) elsewhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Cook Islands are served by Air New Zealand<em>&nbsp;</em>(<a href="http://www.airnewzealand.com/" target="_blank">www.airnewzealand.com</a>), which offers regular flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand">New Zealand</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/california/los-angeles-international-airport">Los Angeles</a>. Virgin Australia (<a href="http://www.virginaustralia.com" target="_blank">www.virginaustralia.com</a>) also flies from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand/auckland-international-airport">Auckland</a>, and both airlines offer frequent connections from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>&nbsp;- 25 hours (including stopover); Los Angeles - 10 hours 15 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare. If you're leaving by private boat, you need to pay a departure tax of NZ$66.30.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Rarotonga International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.cookislandsairports.com<p>The airport is 3km (2 miles) west of Avarua.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to moor yachts at Avatiu Harbour although space is very limited. For maritime matters, contact the Harbour Master, Ports Authority, PO Box 84, Rarotonga, Cook Islands. See <a href="http://www.ports.co.ck" target="_blank">www.ports.co.ck</a>&nbsp;for more information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International telephone is available 24 hours from the telecommunications office (Telecom Cook Islands).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies. Travellers arriving from New Zealand, Australia and Samoa can arrange roaming with their own network providers. Those from other destinations must purchase a Cook Islands' SIM card and top-up cards. Mobile coverage is available in Rarotonga and Aitutaki.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet facilities in Avarua at the Telecom Cook Islands office (open 24 hours a day), at the post office, at Internet cafes and at computer stores.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main radio and TV stations are operated by the privately-owned Elijah Communications, which also publishes weekly newspapers. There are plans in progress for a public radio service. The independent daily, <em>Cook Islands News</em>,<em> </em>is published in Maori and English. The <em>Cook Islands Herald </em>and <em>Cook Islands Independent </em>are weeklies, owned by Elijah Communications.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Book yourself on a tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whether you want to discover the Cook Islands by foot, in the saddle or on a bike, a land tour will ensure you get the most out of your trip. On the water, kayaking tours, lagoon cruises and excursions in semi-submersible vessels offer the chance to get close to coral reefs and colourful marine life. A cultural village tour provides the opportunity to learn about local traditions such as weaving, coconut husking, fire making and carving.</p>]]><p><b>Embrace the festival spirit</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are various jamborees taking place on the Cook Islands throughout the year, most famously Te Maeva Nui Festival, which happens every July. A celebration of independence, as with most festivals here it is marked with float parades, singing, dancing and sport. Festivals on the islands are often characterised by mixture of traditional rituals grafted onto Christian music and ceremony.</p>]]><p><b>Escape to the Takuvaine and Avatiu Valleys</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Scenic drives into the Takuvaine and Avatiu Valleys offer a pretty panorama of lush, tropical scenery. Head inland from the newly redeveloped Avatiu Harbour for the scenic excursion and find maximum tranquillity along the aptly named Happy Valley Road in Takuvaine.</p>]]><p><b>Go whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Come face to fin with humpback whales, which frequent the archipelago's crystalline waters between July and October. In addition to observing the whales from a boat, it is possible to snorkel with them. The waters around the Cook Islands is a designated whale sanctuary, so there's a good chance you'll see one.</p>]]><p><b>Immerse yourself in the underwater world</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Cook Islands are a mecca for scuba divers and snorkelers; visibility is seldom under 30m (100ft) and the underwater sights are stunning with canyons, caves, colourful coral reefs and bountiful marine life. Impressive dive sites include the Matavera Drop-off, the Ngatangiia Swimthroughs, the Koromiri Coral Garden, Mataora Wreck, Papua Canyon and Sand River.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out Arai Te Tonga</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On the outskirts of Avarua lie the stone ruins of Arai Te Tonga, one of the most sacred <em>marae </em>sites in the Cook Islands. Before the Europeans arrived this is was the administrative capital of the islands; it was where the ruling Makea family lived and where tribal chiefs were sworn in. It takes a bit of finding, with the quiet back roads proving as exciting as the destination.</p>]]><p><b>Take a dip at Papua Waterfall</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Also known as Wigmore's Waterfall, this is the only waterfall on Rarotonga and is a popular spot for a dip. There are pony treks to the falls, which take you through steamy forests, but be warned; the humid conditions are a breeding ground for mosquitos.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hike</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hiking trails abound on Rarotonga, the most popular being the Cross Island Trek, which wends along ancient warpaths. Other popular trails include Pa's Mountain Walk, which takes hikers through the island's lush interior; Te Kou Trek, with its steep ascents and great views; and the Ikurangi Trek, which also provides rock climbing opportunities. Guided reef walks are possible at low tide along Rarotonga's coral fringe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>NZ$287 million (2007).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Copra, fresh fruit and canned citrus fruit, coffee, fish and pearls.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Foodstuffs, textiles, fuels, timber and capital goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Australia, New Zealand, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/fiji">Fiji</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourism, pearl farming and agriculture are the principal industries. The islands are economically underdeveloped, largely due to their isolation, and depend on extensive aid from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand">New Zealand</a>. The government is seeking to build up the islands' infrastructure as a precursor to further development.<br /><br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits are necessary.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:http://www.cookislandschamber.org
					Address: ,PO Box 242,Rarotonga,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are restaurants in hotels, and a variety of independent eating places as well, as a result of the increasing tourist trade. Local produce includes a wide variety of citrus and tropical fruits, island chestnuts and garden vegetables. Seafood features on many restaurant menus and so does coconut as the coconut palms produce an abundant supply of fruit all year round. Local meat and poultry are available.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />  <ul>  <li><em>Umukai</em> (at larger resorts you can try this traditional Polynesian feast which involves baking food in an underground oven, and is usually accompanied with traditional entertainment by local people)<br /></li>  <li><em>Matu rori</em> (sea cucumber, served with lemon and cooked green banana). This dish is often likened to spaghetti from the sea..</li>  </ul>  <strong>National drinks:</strong>   <ul>  <li><em>Tumunu</em> (traditionally brewed alcohol made from fermented oranges).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tradition says that all gifts require something in return and tipping is therefore not practised.</li>  </ul></p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Island feast and dance groups feature at major hotels and details are available from local tourist information offices or hotel receptionists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Best buys are woodcarvings, pearls, shell craft, woven products, pottery, and pandanus hats and baskets made out of coconut fibre. Coins and stamps are considered to be valuable collectors' items. Another popular buy is a brightly coloured, all-purpose wrap-around cloth garment worn by both men and women (a <em>Pareu</em>); it's ideal for casual wear in the hot climate. Island Craft (<a href="http://www.islandcraft.com/" target="_blank">www.islandcraft.com</a>) has a retail outlet in Avarua where hand-carved items can be purchased. The art of carving may be observed in Punanganui Market Place. There is also a wide range of duty-free items.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600, Sat 0800-1200. Some stores in tourist areas remain open for longer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation of a high standard is steadily on the increase. There are several resorts, hotels and a number of villas, motels, bungalows and self-catering apartments. Most are situated close to, if not on, a beach. Advance booking is essential, and it is probably wiser to book via an inclusive tour operator specialising in Pacific destinations. For more information on hotels, contact the Cook Islands Tourism Corporation (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation of a high standard is steadily on the increase. There are several resorts, hotels and a number of villas, motels, bungalows and self-catering apartments. Most are situated close to, if not on, a beach. Advance booking is essential, and it is probably wiser to book via an inclusive tour operator specialising in Pacific destinations. For more information on hotels, contact the Cook Islands Tourism Corporation (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation of a high standard is steadily on the increase. There are several resorts, hotels and a number of villas, motels, bungalows and self-catering apartments. Most are situated close to, if not on, a beach. Advance booking is essential, and it is probably wiser to book via an inclusive tour operator specialising in Pacific destinations. For more information on hotels, contact the Cook Islands Tourism Corporation (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Comprehensive travel insurance is recommended. There is one government hospital (on Rarotonga).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is relatively safe but may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available and is advised for the first few weeks of the stay.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccination against hepatitis B and tuberculosis is sometimes advised. There is no defence against dengue fever other than avoiding being bitten by mosquitoes.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>ANZAC Day :
							25 April </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							04 June <b>Date to be confirmed </b>yes
							</p><p>Constitution Day :
							04 August </p><p>National Gospel Day :
							26 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into the Cook Islands by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 1kg of tobacco or 50 cigars.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine or spirits or 4.5L of beer.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of NZ$250.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include illicit drugs, pornography, and copyright- or trademark-infringing materials.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include firearms and ammunition, and fireworks and related goods. Goods listed under the CITES treaty for endangered species must be accompanied by a permit from the National Environment Service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand Dollar (NZD; symbol NZ$) = 100 cents, supplemented by notes and coins minted for local use which are not negotiable outside the Cook Islands. Notes are in denominations of NZ$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of NZ$2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10 and 5 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchange facilities are available at the airport, banks and in some larger stores and hotels. EFTPOS and ATM machines are available at both <em>ANZ</em> and <em>Westpac</em> banks on Rarotonga and Aitutaki, and also major stores and restaurants. <em>ANZ</em> charges a much higher commission than <em>Westpac</em>. At the banks, traveller's cheques attract an exchange rate around 3% higher than cash.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, Mastercard and Visa are all accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted in hotels and some shops; NZ$ recommended as some outer island banks won't change US$.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0900-1500, Fri 0900-1600. GlobalEX Western Union is the only bank open Sat. 0830-1200 and gives a better rate than the banks without commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months beyond the period of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above, except for Australians, who must hold a passport valid for at least seven days beyond the period of stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend your length of stay on a monthly basis at the immigration department up to a maximum of six months. You must do this at least five days before the end of your authorised period of stay.&nbsp;A fee of NZ$50 is payable with each application for those 15 years and older, along with an application fee of NZ$20. There is no fee for applicants aged under 15 years, but they must report to immigration for official paperwork to be completed.&nbsp;For those eligible to stay for more than three months, the fee is NZ$100 plus the application fee of NZ$20.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-16.119034]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-161.786941]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>237 sq km (91.5 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>20,948 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>41.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Avarua (on Rarotonga).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Self-governing territory in free association with New Zealand. New Zealand retains responsibility for external affairs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Cook Islands are situated 3,500km (2,200 miles) northeast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand">New Zealand</a> and 1,000km (600 miles) southwest of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tahiti-and-her-islands">Tahiti</a> in the South Pacific, forming part of Polynesia. The 15 islands fall into two groups: the scattered Northern Group are all coral atolls while the Southern Group is of volcanic origin. Most of the larger islands include lagoons surrounded by small areas of fertile land above which rise volcanic hills.</p>
<p>Rarotonga is the largest and highest island with a rugged volcanic interior, its highest peak being Te Manga, at 652m (2,140ft). Coral reef surrounds the island and the population lives between reef and hills where rich soil supports both tropical and subtropical vegetation. Most of the island is covered by thick evergreen bush. Most of the larger islands include lagoons surrounded by small areas of fertile land, above which rise volcanic hills. The best beaches in the Cook Islands are found on Aitutaki, which is part of the eight-island Southern Group. The Northern Group comprises seven islands, the largest being Penrhyn, Manihiki and Pukapuka.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mainly Cook Islands Christian Church (58%); also Roman Catholic, Latter Day Saints, Seventh Day Adventists and Assembly of God.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dress code is informal, though modest attire should be worn when visiting towns or villages. Women are expected to wear dresses for church services and social functions.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. The New Zealand and Australian plug with three flat blades (two angled in a V shape) is standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Henry Puna since 2010.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Queen's Representative Tom Marsters since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although in 1773 Captain James Cook became the first European to lay eyes on the Cook Islands, he originally called than the Hervey Islands. The name Cook Islands actually originates from a Russian naval chart produced in the 1820s.</p>
<p>However, credit for the discovery of the 15 islands and two reefs that make up the modern country must go to the Polynesians, who came across them during their great migratory journeys over the Pacific in the seventh and eighth centuries.</p>
<p>Mutineers from HMS Bounty are thought to have rediscovered the main island Rarotonga in 1789, although the first recorded landing by Europeans was in 1814. It didn&rsquo;t go well and sailors fought a bloody action with Islanders that left many dead on both sides. A return party seven years later was more peacefully received and Christianity soon spread. In 1888 the Cook Islands became a British protectorate and in 1900 were annexed and declared part of Her Britanic Majesty&rsquo;s dominions. In 1901 the Islands were included within the boundaries of New Zealand.</p>
<p>In 1949 the Islanders were British subjects granted New Zealand citizenship and in 1965, the Cook Islands achieved self-government as a New Zealand Dependency. There are no plans and little pressure to change this status.</p>
<p>Executive power is formally held by the New Zealand High Commissioner, but is effectively devolved to the cabinet. The House of Ariki, which is composed of all the paramount chiefs of the Cook Islands, serves as an advisory body. Advice is given on legislation concerning customs and traditions, though the House of Ariki has no powers of legislation itself. New Zealand is responsible for defence and foreign affairs.</p>
<p>Cook Islanders are citizens of New Zealand, but identified as Cook Islands nationals, a status not enjoyed by other New Zealand citizens.</p>
<p>Although tourism is a mainstay of the local economy, with around 100,000 visitors a year, other sectors include offshore banking &ndash; the Islands specialise in controversial asset protection trusts that allow investors to shelter assets from creditors &ndash; as well as pearls, marine and fruit exports.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<ul>
    <li>The national flower of the Cook Islands is the Tiare Maori.</li>
    <li>The Islands are home to large, non-native populations of ship rats and Polynesian rats, which have dramatically reduced the bird population.</li>
    <li>Tivaevae is the art of handmade patchwork quilts depicting Island scenery. Introduced in the late 19th century by missionaries&rsquo; wives it has evolved into a popular communal activity.</li>
</ul>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Cook Islands High Commission in New Zealand]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(4) 472 5126.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.cook-islands.gov.ck/index.php</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(4) 472 5126.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Thorndon<br/>PO Box 12-242, 56 Mulgrave Street<br/>Wellington<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Find lazy days dripping with sunshine in the tranquil Cook Islands, 15 sandy freckles in the South Pacific. There are no two ways about it, people come to the Cook Islands for the beaches: pristine ribbons, lapped by sparkling aquamarine waters. For those eager to dive straight in, the Cook Islands' best beaches are at Muri Lagoon and Titikaveka.</p><p>Despite covering a vast area, the Cook Islands host a tiny population, and secluded spots are easy to come by. Some islands, such as Rarotonga (where the international airport is situated) and Aitutaki, do feature a number of developed resorts. Mountainous Rarotonga also offers plenty of verdant scenery, should you – unlikely though it sounds – grow tired of the tropical beach paradise.</p><p>Situated between Samoa and French Polynesia, the inhabitants of the Cook Islands are Polynesian, with a proud and interesting culture. Calling themselves the Cook Island Maori, they trace their roots on the southern islands back a millennium to Tahiti and the Marquesas, while Samoans and Togans are responsible for settling the northern islands. The Cook Islanders also hold the tradition that New Zealand Maori migrations originated from their islands.</p><p>Named after Captain James Cook, who came here in 1770, the Cook Islands didn't come under British control until 1888. In 1965, the inhabitants chose self-government in free association with New Zealand, which had assumed administrative control over the islands at the turn of the century.</p><p>Apart from the interesting culture, it's the natural beauty of the Cook Islands that most captivates visitors. The islands are both volcanic and 'near atolls', which is to say land that's mostly lagoon and edged by islets. You'll find Rarotonga teeming with jungle, while Aitutake is the most photogenic island – a true paradise. Expect powdery sand, an abundance of tropical fruits, palm trees and no worries.</p>Find lazy days dripping with sunshine in the tranquil Cook Islands: 15 sandy freckles in the South Pacific.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
