<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Costa Rica" ColCode="cri" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="cr" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the Central Valley, where the main centres of population are located, the average temperature is 22&deg;C (72&deg;F) and the region enjoys a spring-like climate year round. In the coastal areas, the temperature is much hotter and humid, while the Pacific Northwest can be extremely hot and dry.  The rainy season starts in May and finishes in November, although there are distinct regional variations. June and July are the wettest months, particularly on the Caribbean side, but the season can run from May until December.<br />
<br />
The 'warm' dry season is December to May, though temperature differences between summer and winter are slight.  March is the height of the dry season, and the humidity is lower at this time, making this a popular time for visitors. Volcano Arenal is notoriously hard to see due to the clouds, but the best time of year to give it a shot is during April and May.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens most of the year, warmer clothes for cooler evenings. Waterproofing is necessary during the rainy season. Loose-fitting clothing is best. Wear neutral browns and greens for birding and wildlife viewing.  Always bring mosquito repellent for both day and night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>SANSA (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flysansa.com/">www.flysansa.com</a>) operates services between San Jos&eacute; and provincial towns and tourist resorts, including Tortuguero, Tamarindo, Quepos and Golfito.</p>
<p>SANSA's main rival is Nature Air (<a href="http://www.natureair.com" target="_blank">www.natureair.com</a>), which is considered to have the more reliable service and operates almost identical routes. Both use a variety of aircraft carrying up to 35 passengers, but Nature Air&rsquo;s planes are slightly bigger.  A number of companies also provide internal charter flights using small planes.</p><p>Much of Costa Rica is riddled with atrocious roads, so if you can afford to fly, it makes your life a lot more comfortable.  Bear in mind however, that flights almost always go through San Jos&eacute;, so unless you&rsquo;re going that way anyway, you have to change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Train lines are limited to commuter routes connecting San Jos&eacute; with Pavas, Bel&eacute;n and Heredia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The quality of the roads in Costa Rica is, for the most part, not great.  Stretches of the Pan-American Highway leading to and from the major cities tend to be OK, but the rest is a mix of dust, gravel, potholes and perilously mountainous roads.  Be very careful driving, especially if you&rsquo;re in a hire car and want to get your deposit back. If you&rsquo;re a nervous driver, think about public transport instead.</p>r<p>The standard of the roads ranges from generally very good in the highlands to abysmal in many rural regions. Potholes are frequent, many roads remain unpaved, and during wet season landslides are common.</p><p>Public transport via road in Costa Rica ranges from large coach companies such as the Tica Bus (<a href="http://www.ticabus.com" target="_blank">www.ticabus.com</a>) and TransNica (+506 2223 4242; <a href="http://transnica.com" target="_blank">transnica.com</a>), which are comfortable and air-conditioned, to tiny little shuttle buses in the Nicoya Peninsula, where they pack you in and jolt you around for hours.  Bus travel, however long and potentially frustrating, is inexpensive and often quite fun.</p><p>Taxis are numerous and inexpensive in San Jos&eacute;. The taxis are coloured red (except those serving Juan Santamar&iacute;a International Airport, which are orange). Taxis are usually metered, but few drivers use the meters as they figure they can extract more money from tourists by not doing so. Make sure they put it on and that it hasn&rsquo;t already been running, or ask your hotel concierge how much a fare should be, and negotiate with the driver to an agreed amount before setting off.</p><p>Drivers must have a national licence or International Driving Permit. You must be 21 years of age to rent from car hire agencies, although some require drivers be at least 25 years of age.</p><p>A speed limit of up to 90kph (56mph) is enforced on most highways. However, Costa Ricans are notoriously dangerous drivers who pay little heed to speed limits and traffic regulations. Be careful going through towns, as the speed limit drops. If you speed or drink drive, the Costa Rican traffic police (tel: +506 222 9330) can fine you heavily, so it's suggested that you don&rsquo;t do anything to antagonise them and, if you are pulled over, be extremely nice.  Never try to bribe them.  Use of seat belts is mandatory.</p><p>If you break down in Costa Rica, you need to call your car hire company.  If you think it&rsquo;s a problem that can be fixed, there are service stations along the Pan-American Highway which tend to have mechanics or can get in contact with them.  If you do break down, the first thing you need to do is look for two reflecting triangles which should be in the boot. Put them in the front and back of your car so that other drivers can see you&rsquo;re broken down.</p><p>You must be over 21 to hire a car in Costa Rica. Having an International Driving Permit is recommended but you are likely to be able to use just a full licence from your own country. You need a credit card for the deposit, which usually costs at least as much as the car hire.</p>
<p>There are many different car hire companies in Costa Rica, predominantly in San Jos&eacute; and at the main airport, but it's recommended to either book a car through a local travel agency or be exceptionally careful to note and confirm any damage or scratches to the vehicle before you drive off.</p>
<p>Also ensure that the vehicle comes with a spare tyre (a decent one!) and a jack, because Costa Rica&rsquo;s roads are such that you may well need one.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Motorbikes:</strong> It&rsquo;s not the main way of getting around, so hiring motorbikes isn&rsquo;t as easy as in other parts of the world. Hiring a motorcycle isn&rsquo;t cheap, and you may have to pay more in deposit than the cost of the hire. However, motorcycle company Wild Rider (+506 2258 4604; <a href="http://www.wild-rider.com" target="_blank">www.wild-rider.com</a>) provides well-serviced, decent bikes and can have them ready in San Jos&eacute; or even at the airport for you to pick up.  <br />
<br />
<strong> Bicycles: </strong>Cycling in Costa Rica is to be taken cautiously &ndash; San Jos&eacute; has crazy traffic and more hills than you&rsquo;d think; cycling here is to be avoided.  Much of the interior is mountainous with huge trucks and coaches on the narrow roads, and so is both dangerous and exhausting &ndash; it&rsquo;s more for extreme sports cyclists.  But the coastal roads are flatter and wider, and very beautiful. Hiring bicycles isn&rsquo;t that cheap &ndash; expect to pay over US$20 per day, although you can negotiate weekly rates.  On the other hand, the quality tends to be good.  Ask at your hotel if they rent bikes or can recommend anywhere.</p><p>A speed limit of up to 90kph (56mph) is enforced on most highways. However, Costa Ricans are notoriously dangerous drivers who pay little heed to speed limits and traffic regulations. Be careful going through towns, as the speed limit drops. If you speed or drink drive, the Costa Rican traffic police (tel: +506 222 9330) can fine you heavily, so it's suggested that you don&rsquo;t do anything to antagonise them and, if you are pulled over, be extremely nice.  Never try to bribe them.  Use of seat belts is mandatory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Jos&eacute; has privately run bus services, charging fares on a two-zone system.  The buses are crazy and fast moving; to find one going your way, ask a local &ndash; destinations are usually listed on the front windows but aren&rsquo;t clear.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Costa Rica</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">puntarenas</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Costa Rica</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">puerto_limoacuten</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.25</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Costa Rica</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cartago</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Costa Rica</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">alajuela</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to Costa Rica are roughly the same prices throughout the year, with costs rising noticeably only for major holidays.  The main national carrier is Avianca (<a href="http://www.avianca.com" target="_blank">www.avianca.com</a>).  Lots of major international airlines fly to Costa Rica, such as&nbsp;Delta (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.delta.com">www.delta.com</a>) and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>). British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) flies direct to San Jos&eacute; from London Gatwick.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 11 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 5 hours 20 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$29, payable if staying more than 24 hours. Many airlines (including Delta, United, British Airways, Air France and American Airlines) include the departure tax in their airfares. Note that if paying the tax by credit card there is an extra fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Liberia International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 8 km (5 miles) west of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/liberia">Liberia</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Juan Santamaría International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>Juan Santamaría Airport is located 17km (10.5 miles) northwest of the city centre just outside the city of Alajuela.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+506 2437 2400</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Puntarenas, the main port in the Costa Rican Pacific coast, is a major port for cruise-liners and is situated about 113km (70 miles) from San Jos&eacute;. There are hourly public buses to San Jos&eacute; from Puntarenas&rsquo; main bus station.  When crossing the Gulf of Nicoya from Puntarenas to Paquera to explore the southern regions, be aware that although the final ferry leaves quite late, the roads on the other side are bumpy and take a while &ndash; you may well end up arriving at your destination in the middle of the night, so allow plenty of time.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coming into and leaving Costa Rica is by way of the same road &ndash; the Pan-American Highway.  Getting in and out is all very accessible, but have your passport and entry card handy because stop-and-checks are frequent.  For getting in, out and around the country, the Tica Bus (tel: +506 2296 9788;&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ticabus.com">www.ticabus.com</a>) has routes running from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico">Mexico</a> down to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/panama">Panama</a>, and TransNica (+506 2223 4242; <a href="http://transnica.com" target="_blank">transnica.com</a>) services <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/honduras">Honduras</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nicaragua">Nicaragua</a> and Costa Rica.  The international buses can get chilly, so bring a jumper.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes in Costa Rica. Public payphones exist, but they are becoming increasingly rare as increasing mobile phone usage means that phone companies are removing them. However some still exist taking coins or credit cards. Alternatively prepaid phone cards can be bought from most small gift shops and newsagents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some countries. Handsets can be hired, although this can be difficult and time-consuming (<a href="http://www.ice.go.cr/" target="_blank">www.ice.go.cr</a>). Costa Rica employs both GSM and TDMA systems. The state telephone company ICE has a monopoly on service, which is available throughout much of the nation except remote mountain regions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafés throughout the country, and most tourist hotels also provide facilities such as Wi-Fi. Internet speed may be rather slow but this should improve as the government aims to improve infrastructure to allow for faster broadband connections.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Costa Rica has more than half a dozen major newspapers, several private and public TV stations, and a busy FM radio scene. Cable TV is widely available. Costa Rica enjoys near total freedom of media, although the major dailies are considered to be conservative. Daily newspapers printed in Spanish include<em> Al D&iacute;</em>a, <em>Diario Extra</em>, <em>La Nacion</em>, <em>La Prensa Libre</em> and <em>La Rep&uacute;blica</em>; the <em><a href="http://www.ticotimes.net" target="_blank">Tico Times</a></em> is a web-only news publication in English.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail letters to Western Europe usually take at least 10 working days days; those to North America take at least one week.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1730; Sat 0730-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Arenal Volcano</p><![CDATA[<p>Costa Rica's most active volcano, Arenal erupts on average 41 times a day.  Obviously, you can't climb it, but visitors flock here for the night views.  When the sky is clear, the views of the lava eruptions and flows are absolutely spectacular.</p>]]><br/><p>Bosque Nuboso de Monteverde</p><![CDATA[<p>Straddling the Continental Divide and covering 170 sq kilometres (66 sq miles), this vast forest has its head – and its feet – in the clouds. The ever-present drizzle and mist provide a home to an amazing array of flora and fauna. Trails, overnight shelters for camping and a 91-metre (300-feet) suspension bridge enable visitors to experience the incredible biodiversity of the forest. There is also a Visitor Centre, Butterfly Centre, Orchid Garden, Serpentarium and Hummingbird Gallery, as well as the Frog Pond of Monteverde Herpetarium. Other highlights include the Sky Trek and the Sky Walk, a series of trails and platforms reaching high into the jungle canopy.<br /><br />Address: Monteverde Cloud Forest Preserve, Apdo 55-5655, Monteverde, Puntarenas, Costa Rica</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Climb up to the treetops in Santa Elena</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This little town right next to Monteverde Cloud Forest is a good base for a host of popular forest-based activities. One of the best is canopy walking, moving through the cloud forest on a series of rope bridges and platforms high above the ground, coming face to face with the wildlife and being rewarded with great 360° views.</p>]]><p><b>Discover San Jose’s cultural treats</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Costa Rica's capital has some treats to be discovered within its chaotic sprawl. Its Mercado Central is excellent, with some of the city's best restaurants nearby. Top of any visitor's architectural bucket list are the Teatro Nacional, the Legislative Assembly building and the Catedral Metropolitana, while the country's best museums are the National Museum and the Museum of Pre-Columbian Gold.</p>]]><p><b>Escape to the empty beaches of the Osa Peninsula</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hard to reach by land, but worth it: the Osa Peninsula is reckoned to be one of the most beautiful places in Costa Rica, containing over half of its species of wildlife. The region's main attraction is Corcovado National Park: one of the most biologically diverse places on Earth, with miles of empty sandy beaches backed by dense tropical rainforest.</p>]]><p><b>Get your head in the clouds in Monteverde</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Straddling the Continental Divide, the vast Monteverde Cloud Forest Reserve has its head – and feet – in the clouds. The constant humidity provides a home to an amazing array of wildlife. Trails, canopy walkways and a 91m (300ft) suspension bridge enable visitors to observe the fascinating flora and fauna from up close.</p>]]><p><b>Go whale watching in Drake Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Down in the remote Osa Peninsula is Drake Bay, the best place in Costa Rica for whale watching, with the longest humpback whale season in the world. From August through to March, humpback whales migrate from both the north and south through Drake Bay, along with bottlenose and spotted dolphins. Most boat tours leave from the riverside town of Sierpe.</p>]]><p><b>Go windsurfing on Lake Arenal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whizz across the waters of Lake Arenal, one of the world's top windsurfing and kitesurfing spots. Situated at 5,580ft (1,700m) above sea level in northwestern Costa Rica, the lake offers its best windsurfing between April and December. Clustered around the lake's western shore are various agencies, where you can hire equipment and take courses.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about Costa Rica’s indigenous roots</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Centro Neotrópico Sarapiquí is a superb museum, in the Northern Lowlands, dedicated to Costa Rica's neglected indigenous cultures. The museum collection includes pre-Colombian ceramics, weapons, clothing and other artefacts. The site also has an excellent eco-lodge and visitors can also explore the surrounding rainforest, with trips to the nearby river and waterfalls.</p>]]><p><b>Mooch around in Montezuma</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the southern Nicoya Peninsula's most bohemian but isolated areas, Montezuma is a minor mission to get to, but once you're here you might not want to leave. The beaches are glorious and excellent for surfing – careful of the current – and the hippy expat population gives the place a laidback vibe.</p>]]><p><b>Paddle through the canals of Tortuguero National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The best way to explore Tortuguero National Park's is by boat through its canals and lagoons, so you can admire the rainforest quietly and up close to its resident wildlife. The multi-level forest ecosystem is easily identified from the waterways, and a guide can explain the ecology of each level and the various species, including sloths and monkeys.</p>]]><p><b>Plunge into the white water</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Costa Rica has some thrillingly turbulent rivers, where white-water rafters take the plunge through the rapids. Two of the country's best rivers for rafting are the Reventazón (class III) and Pacuare (class IV), with operators based at nearby Turrialba. The best times to go are from June to October, during the wet season, but with gentler conditions throughout the year.</p>]]><p><b>Search for the sacred Quetzal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its iridescent plumage and graceful tail feathers, the quetzal is the Holy Grail of Costa Rica's tropical birds, and considered the most beautiful bird in the Neotropics. The most popular place to see them is in the green haven of the Monteverde Biological Cloud Preserve, where nature guides lead tours to their feeding sites.</p>]]><p><b>Take a cruise to Isla Tortuga</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Boat trips to offshore islands offer a relaxing adventure for anyone in search of a tropical paradise. One of the best is the Calypso catamaran to Isla Tortuga, with day excursions from Puntarenas. This gorgeous island is rimmed with palm-shaded white sands shelving into turquoise waters, good for snorkelling and other watersports, with a beach barbecue to round out your day.</p>]]><p><b>Take a twilight turtle tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Costa Rica's Caribbean and Pacific shores are popular sites for marine turtles to lay their eggs in the soft sands. Guided tours take visitors out at night to witness hawksbill, green, loggerhead, Ridley and leatherback turtles, performing the ritual. Tortuguero National Park is one of the best places to go turtle spotting, with eggs laid from March to October, and hatchlings emerging up till November.</p>]]><p><b>Trek up lofty Chirripó</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cerro Chirripó is the country's highest peak, some 3,820m (12,330ft) above sea level, with trails accessible to hardy walkers. All you need is stamina and the proper hiking gear, plus advance reservation through the national park office. After a night in a lodge near the summit, set off before dawn to reach the summit before the clouds close in.</p>]]><p><b>Visit coffee plantations</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Costa Rica's main exports is coffee and many plantations offer guided tours of the fields and processing factories. Heredia is one of the most important coffee regions, with local plantations showing visitors how their precious beans are picked and roasted, with some also providing farm-style accommodation.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the volcanoes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Costa Rica is pockmarked by awesome, fiery volcanoes. Smouldering Poás is home to the country's only dwarf cloud forest, while the top of Irazú provides fantastic views over the Caribbean and Pacific on clear days. The most active volcano, however, is Arenal, which erupts on average 41 times a day. You can't climb it, but on clear nights it puts on a spectacular pyrotechnic show.</p>]]><p><b>Zip through the forest canopy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Zipwire adventures have taken off all over Costa Rica in recent years, so harness up and be Tarzan for a day. You can swing through the rainforest on a canopying ecotour, enjoying the up-close view of tree-dwelling wildlife, including monkeys, iguanas and birds. Tours are available in several locations, including Rincón de la Vieja National Park in the northwest of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$57.69 billion (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Bananas and pineapples, coffee, sugar, beef and electronic components.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Raw materials, consumer goods, capital equipment, petroleum, construction materials.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>US, Netherlands, Malaysia, China, Mexico, Venezuela.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Electronics represent a significant proportion of Costa Rica's export revenues while 6% of GDP is derived from agriculture (most importantly coffee, bananas and meat, but also melons, pineapple, sugar and cocoa). Staple crops are also grown for domestic consumption. Manufacturing industry consists of food processing, micro-processors and electronics, textiles, chemicals and plastics. This sector is steadily expanding with government encouragement.<br />
<br />
New industries include aluminium production, following the discovery of a large bauxite deposit. Oil imports and hydroelectricity meet the bulk of the country's energy needs. Tourism dominates the service sector and is the most important source of foreign exchange earnings, with the service industry responsible for around 75% of GDP.</p>
<p><strong>Despite the country&rsquo;s relative prosperity in the region, poverty is still a fact of daily life for many with 25% of the population still living under the poverty line for the past 20 years.</strong><br />
<br />
Several of the larger hotels in and around San Jos&eacute; have conference facilities. The largest is the Wyndham San Jose Herradura, at Ciudad Cariari, about 16 km (10 miles) northwest of the city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Customs tend to be conservative. Advance appointments and courtesy are appreciated, although Costa Ricans are rarely punctual. It is preferable to have some knowledge of Spanish, although many locals speak English. The best months for business visits are November and December; avoid the last week of September, which is the end of the financial year.</p>
<p>Though Latin America is known for its relaxed business culture, official visitors to Costa Rica are expected to dress professionally, behave formally and be punctual. Don&rsquo;t expect meetings to finish on time however - it&rsquo;s polite to indulge in a bit of personal chit-chat before diving into business, perhaps followed by an impromptu lunch.  Women are on notably equal footing in Costa Rica, as evidenced by the 2010 election of President Laura Chinchilla. Regardless, it&rsquo;s wise to choose conservative suits over more sexually provocative outfits. You won&rsquo;t, however, be judged for wearing trousers rather than a skirt.</p>
<p>Traditional niceties &ndash; professional titles, business cards, house gifts, and so on &ndash; are still appreciated in Costa Rica. Spanish speakers should be careful with the informal you, &ldquo;tu&rdquo;; in Costa Rica, even children are referred to as &ldquo;usted&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Costa Ricans value &ldquo;playing well with others&rdquo; highly, and go to great lengths to avoid conflict. Foreigners who argue aggressively, raise their voices or directly criticize others are seen as socially inept or offensive and best avoided.  Stay calm in negotiations and couch disagreements in such a way that the other party can save face, and your diplomacy will inspire further cooperation.</p>
<p>Risky ventures rarely go over well in Costa Rica, so take time to discuss any safety nets backing up your business plan.   Best months for business visits are November and December; avoid the last week of September, which is the end of the financial year.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Costa Rican-American Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 220 2200
					Website:http://www.amcham.co.cr/
					Address: San José,Apartado 4946-1000,Costa Rica,]]><b>Cámara de Comercio de Costa Rica (Chamber of Commerce)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 221 0005
					Website:http://www.camara-comercio.com/
					Address: 1000 San José,Apartado 1114-1000,Costa Rica,]]><b>Cámara de Industrias de Costa Rica (Chamber of Industries)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 281 0006
					Website:http://www.cicr.com/
					Address: ,350m (1150ft) south of Fuente de la Hispanidad bridge,Costa Rica,10003]]><b>Promotora del Comercio Exterior de Costa Rica (PROCOMER)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 299 4700
					Website:http://www.procomer.com/
					Address: San José,Apartado 1278-1007,Costa Rica,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Costa Rica is a not a major foodie destination, but what it lacks in sophistication it makes up for in choice.</p><p>The Caribbean coast tends to be more influenced by the island nations. Jamaican-style jerk chicken is a staple; rice and beans (<em>gallo pinto</em>) are ubiquitous, but more likely to be prepared with coconut milk; and curry spices feature heavily as ingredients, creating dishes with a very distinct flavour from their counterparts on the Pacific coast.</p><p>The Costa Rican diet is fairly healthy with low use of dairy or high-fat dishes. Fresh fruits and vegetables make up a high proportion of meals, while pork, chicken and beef are the most popular meats. Seafood is available throughout the country, particularly in coastal regions, with sea bass being the most common fish on menus.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Casado:</strong> A fixed daily lunch, usually featuring rice, beans, stewed chicken or beef, fried plantain, salad and cabbage.<br />
<strong>Olla de carne:</strong> Soup of beef, plantain, corn, yucca and chayote.<br />
<strong>Sopa negra:</strong> Black bean soup with a poached egg in it.<br />
<strong>Picadillo:</strong> Meat and vegetable stew.<br />
<strong>Gallo pinto:</strong> Rice and black beans, with sour cream on the side, a local staple.<br />
<strong>Bocas:</strong> Savoury snacks served at bars or before main meals in restaurants.<br />
<strong>Empanadas:</strong> Small corn flour pasties filled with cheese, beans and sometimes meat.<br />
<strong>Ceviche:</strong> Raw fish marinated in lemon juice, chilli, onion and coriander.<br />
<strong>Coffee:</strong> Usually served black, or mixed half and half with hot milk.<br />
<strong>Horchata:</strong> Sweet cold drink made of ground rice flavoured with cinnamon and cloves.<br />
<strong>Frescos:</strong> Fruit drinks made with water and sugar or syrup.<br />
<strong>Pipas:</strong> Fresh coconut water served in the husk. Found mostly in coastal areas, the green coconuts are served with the tops cut off and a straw. There&rsquo;s always less in there than you&rsquo;d think, but they&rsquo;re great ice cold.<br />
<strong>Cebada:</strong> Fermented barley; an indigenous beverage.<br />
<strong>Pinolillo:</strong> Sweetened cold drink made of toasted corn kernels and cocoa.<br />
<strong>Batidos:</strong>&nbsp;Fresh fruit shakes made with either milk or water blended with ice.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tipping is not necessary but is acceptable if the service was outstanding; no more than 10% though. Restaurants add a 13% sales tax plus a 10% service charge to the bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For the typical bars-and-clubs atmosphere, San Jos&eacute; especially has lots of nightclubs, and most other cities have some venues for this, with varying degrees of respectability. San Jos&eacute; also has the most venues for folk music and dance, as well as theatres and cinemas. Travellers should however be vigilant at night time and use licensed taxis to get around rather than walking.<br />
<br />
Coastal towns are a different matter &ndash; they have their bars and restaurants along the beach, and this is where you can expect the nightlife to take place. The Caribbean side of the country tends to be a rather more chilled out and less developed in party terms, and although poverty and crime has tended to be more of a problem in this region, the increased police presence in towns such as Puerto Viejo has decreased the number of incidents. In many of the coastal towns, the vibe is low key (except for particular times of year such as Spring Break) and more relaxed than in the cities. <br />
<br />
High class hotels tend to have their own bars, but beware of prices being forced through the roof for the American tourist market.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You won&rsquo;t be coming to Costa Rica just for the shopping but good gifts and souvenirs can certainly be found. Special purchases include wood and leather rocking chairs (which dismantle for export), as well as a range of local crafts available in major cities and towns. Local markets are also well worth visiting. Prices are slightly higher than in other Latin American countries. Best buys are wooden items, carved masks, ceramics, gold pre-Columbian <em>replica</em> jewellery and leather handicrafts.</p>
<p>In San Jos&eacute; you&rsquo;ll find the standard shopping malls which house decent quality clothes at cheaper prices than the US &ndash; nothing special, but it will usually be cheaper. Head to the Central Market for stalls where individuals sell handcrafted wooden furniture, as well as more mundane goods for sale.</p>
<p>Most villages will have some shop where you can buy local souvenirs and look out for coffee shops &ndash; this indicates an area which produces coffee, and tourists can buy coffee beans for much cheaper than in the city. In Pacific coast towns you&rsquo;ll find plenty of handcrafted jewellery from the hippy ex-pats who have taken residence there and now spend their days sitting on the pavement with wires and beads. Monteverde Cloud Forest has an impressive range of gift-shop produce &ndash; look out for the blown glass in the shape of hummingbirds and quetzals.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1800. There may be variations between areas.</p><p>If tempted to buy any pre-Columbian artefacts – jewellery, ceramics, stoneware – please be aware that it is an offense and also damages the culture of Costa Rica. Buying goods that are made of animal bones, skin or fur isn't a good idea either – at best, customs will confiscate it. If you must, make sure that the item comes with a CITES certificate which verifies that it can be sold internationally.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Jos&eacute; has many hotels, from the extravagant to smaller, family-run hotels, and several well-run hostels with dorms. There are good chain-run hotels out of town near the airport. Costa   Rica has an excellent reputation when it comes to wilderness lodges - these are found throughout the country in national parks and remote areas, and tend to occupy the middle to high-end of the budget. They are often marketed with an eco-friendly bent.</p>
<p>Most coastal areas have options from luxury hotels to surfers' camps and cheap <em>cabinas</em> are available everywhere. Larger hotels have swimming pools and other leisure facilities. The majority have their own restaurants, which are generally good and reasonably priced. Several of the best boutique hotels in the country promote themselves through the Small Distinctive Hotels of Costa   Rica (<a href="http://distinctivehotels.com" target="_blank">http://distinctivehotels.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded from 1- 5 stars according to facilities, customer service and the condition of the building. Some hotels also have leaf ratings (1 &ndash; 5, 5 being best) to show that they strive to uphold the ICT's tourism guidelines established in the Certification for Sustainable Tourism (CST) program.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>What we know as B&Bs in the UK are more commonly known as guesthouses in Costa Rica.  These are smaller places that feel very much as though you're in someone's home, and they'll give you something to eat in the morning in what feels like their living room.  It's a cheaper option than the big hotels and feels more local and intimate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Jos&eacute; has many hotels, from the extravagant to smaller, family-run hotels, and several well-run hostels with dorms. There are good chain-run hotels out of town near the airport. Costa   Rica has an excellent reputation when it comes to wilderness lodges - these are found throughout the country in national parks and remote areas, and tend to occupy the middle to high-end of the budget. They are often marketed with an eco-friendly bent.</p>
<p>Most coastal areas have options from luxury hotels to surfers' camps and cheap <em>cabinas</em> are available everywhere. Larger hotels have swimming pools and other leisure facilities. The majority have their own restaurants, which are generally good and reasonably priced. Several of the best boutique hotels in the country promote themselves through the Small Distinctive Hotels of Costa   Rica (<a href="http://distinctivehotels.com" target="_blank">http://distinctivehotels.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded from 1- 5 stars according to facilities, customer service and the condition of the building. Some hotels also have leaf ratings (1 &ndash; 5, 5 being best) to show that they strive to uphold the ICT's tourism guidelines established in the Certification for Sustainable Tourism (CST) program.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Jos&eacute; has many hotels, from the extravagant to smaller, family-run hotels, and several well-run hostels with dorms. There are good chain-run hotels out of town near the airport. Costa   Rica has an excellent reputation when it comes to wilderness lodges - these are found throughout the country in national parks and remote areas, and tend to occupy the middle to high-end of the budget. They are often marketed with an eco-friendly bent.</p>
<p>Most coastal areas have options from luxury hotels to surfers' camps and cheap <em>cabinas</em> are available everywhere. Larger hotels have swimming pools and other leisure facilities. The majority have their own restaurants, which are generally good and reasonably priced. Several of the best boutique hotels in the country promote themselves through the Small Distinctive Hotels of Costa   Rica (<a href="http://distinctivehotels.com" target="_blank">http://distinctivehotels.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded from 1- 5 stars according to facilities, customer service and the condition of the building. Some hotels also have leaf ratings (1 &ndash; 5, 5 being best) to show that they strive to uphold the ICT's tourism guidelines established in the Certification for Sustainable Tourism (CST) program.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Standards of health and medical hygiene are among the best in Latin America, although public facilities may not come up to par with more developed countries, particularly in more rural areas. Both public and private hospitals are available but tourists may only use the publicly-run healthcare service known as Caja Costarricense de Seguro Social (CCSS) in genuine emergencies.  Private treatment is on the whole, of good quality and much lower cost than equivalent services in the US. Most doctors will expect payment in cash. Tourists visiting Costa Rica are recommended to take out health insurance before travelling.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally heavily chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe to drink, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Drinking water outside main cities and towns may be contaminated and sterilisation is advisable. Bottled water is available and is advised for the duration of the stay, especially for those who are liable to sensitive stomachs. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Costa Rica is considered to have a high risk of Zika virus transmission. The World Health Organisation advise pregnant women and travellers planning for pregancy postpone all non-essential travel to the country. All travellers should take basic precautions to protect themselves from mosquito bites. These include use of repellents containing 20%-30% DEET or 20% Picaridin on exposed skin, wearing light coloured, long-sleeved shirts and pants, and ensuring rooms are fitted with screens to prevent mosquitoes from entering. Women who are pregnant, at risk of getting pregnant, or planning pregnancy should seek further advice from their doctor before travelling to Costa Rica.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hepatitis B and C occur. Outbreaks of dengue fever are common in lowland areas, notably on the Caribbean coast and these have been on the rise since early 2013, so it is advised that you wear insect repellent. Most of Costa Rica is malaria-free apart from the Limon province. Tourists visiting this area should take appropriate precautions. Rabies is widespread throughout Central America; for those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Some holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Juan Santamar :
							11 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Guanacaste Day :
							25 July </p><p>Virgin of Los Angeles, Feast of Patroness of Costa Rica :
							02 August </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Mother's Day :
							15 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							15 September </p><p>D :
							12 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Costa Rica without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 500g tobacco.<br />
&bull; 5L of alcoholic beverages (travellers aged over 18 only).<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of up to US$500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Food items are generally not allowed to be brought into Costa Rica, in particular fruit, vegetables, dairy products, seeds and plants. Firearms are not permitted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is forbidden under the CITES treaty (the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species) to remove orchids from Costa Rica, or indeed any wild flora and fauna. Removing animals, dead or alive, is also forbidden, and be very careful when buying carvings or antiques in Costa Rica. Most probably you&rsquo;ll get freshly handcrafted art, but removing Aztec, Incan or Mayan cultural artefacts from the country is thoroughly illegal, and happens far too often.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Costa Rican Col&oacute;n (CRC; symbol ₡) = 100 c&eacute;ntimos. Notes are in denominations of ₡50,000, 20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 2,000 and 1,000. Coins are in denominations of ₡500, 100, 50, 25, 20, 10 and 5. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars are also widely accepted.]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available at banks and bureaux de change. Some hotels may also change money. Additionally, small stores will allow visitors to pay for goods in US dollars and receive change in colónes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Diners Club, Mastercard and Visa are all accepted; American Express slightly less so. Many banks will only process MasterCard for cash credits. Cash may be the only form of payment in smaller towns and rural areas but many places will take US dollars, giving change in col&oacute;nes.</p><p>ATMs are common throughout the cities and small towns. They will usually accept foreign cards but in some regions only Visa cards are accepted. Occasionally, paying with credit cards doesn't work for technical reasons. Bringing a good supply of US dollars in cash is advised, as many things such as entrance fees to national parks or meals at restaurants, can be paid for with US dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although travellers can avoid additional exchange rate charges by taking traveller's cheques in US dollars, fewer and fewer businesses in Costa Rica are willing to accept them, and it is better to use the ATM.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>State banks Mon-Fri 0900-1500. Private banks Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US and British passports must be valid for one day from the day you enter Costa Rica.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If travelling alone with a minor, ensure you have a notarised letter of consent from the absentee parent(s) which gives permission for such travel. It is not obligatory to carry a notarised letter of consent from the absentee parent(s), but you still might be required to show this document at the border.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The cost of tourist visas varies according to nationality; check with the consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas issued by consulates of Costa Rica are valid for stays of up to 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A temporary residence permit is usually a working visa, which you need to apply for with numerous pieces of documentation once you are in Costa Rica.  It is issued for six months and can then be extended up to a year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications usually take up to six working days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The most expedient way to extend your stay in Costa Rica has traditionally been to leave the country and then get stamped back in to renew your new visa. The easiest way to do this is overland to either Nicaragua or Panama, but bear in mind that you are supposed to leave the country for at least 72 hours and the Costa Rican authorities are trying to stamp out the practice. Also, Panama has started to get very strict about onward journeys, and will be unimpressed by a declaration that someone is only coming into the country to do a visa run.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You may bring pets into Costa Rica, but it is a frustrating process. Cats and dogs need a certificate of good health to prove they have no communicable diseases, and they must have had a rabies vaccination within the last year. You don&rsquo;t, however, need to quarantine them.  The procedure costs several hundred pounds, depending on how you wish to transport your pet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[10.000032]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-83.880985]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>51,100 sq km (19,730 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,857,218 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>94.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Jos&eacute;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Costa Rica, lying between Nicaragua and Panama, is a complete coast-to-coast segment of the Central American isthmus. Its width ranges from 119km to 282km (74 to 176 miles). A low, thin line of hills that rises between Lake Nicaragua and the Pacific Ocean in Nicaragua, broadens as it enters northern Costa Rica, eventually forming the high, rugged, mountains in the Pacific Northwest and the centre of Costa Rica. <br />
<br />
The southern half of the country is dominated by mountains of tectonic origin; the highest peak is Chirrip&oacute; Grande, which reaches 3,820m (12,530ft). More than half the population live on the Meseta Central, a plateau with an equitable climate. It is the setting for the country's capital, San Jos&eacute;. There are lowlands on both coastlines, mainly swampy on the Caribbean coast, with savannah and dry forest on the Pacific Northwest merging into mangrove and rainforest southward. Rivers cut through the mountains, flowing down to both the Caribbean and the Pacific.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost entirely Christian, with a Roman Catholic majority of 70.5%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greetings usually take the form of a handshake, or a single kiss on the cheek. Formal titular address is important also important. Christian names are preceded by <em>Se&ntilde;or</em> for a man and <em>Se&ntilde;ora</em> for a woman, but <em>Don </em>is used to address a highly respected man and <em>Do&ntilde;a </em>for a female equivalent. When addressing someone in Spanish, use the &lsquo;usted&rsquo; form of &lsquo;you&rsquo;; reserve &lsquo;vos&rsquo; for friends, family and children. Normal courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home and gifts are appreciated as a token of thanks, especially if invited for a meal. </p>
<p>For most occasions casual wear is acceptable, but beachwear should be confined to the beach. Saving face is important in Costa Rican culture, which may make mean you are told &lsquo;yes&rsquo; or &lsquo;maybe&rsquo; even when the answer is really &lsquo;no&rsquo;. In addition, avoid making confrontational statements unless you want to be thought rude.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>120 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without round grounding pin) are standard; some sockets may not accept plugs with a grounding pin however, so you may need an adaptor.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Carlos Alvarado since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Carlos Alvarado since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Along with the other Central American countries, Costa Rica came about as a result of the Spanish conquest, first &lsquo;discovered&rsquo; by Christopher Columbus in 1502. It wasn&rsquo;t an easy country to conquer, largely due to its varied terrain and the lack of valuable mineral resources.</p>
<p>Costa Rica&rsquo;s original inhabitants were predominantly hunter-gatherers, who never developed urbanised civilisations like the Aztecs and Maya in present-day Mexico and Guatemala. The diseases brought into the country by the Europeans wiped out most of the indigenous peoples. Those who were left were largely absorbed into the Spanish population, although there are still a few very small tribes to be found in the country.</p>
<p>The settlers worked hard to farm the land and made the territory into a rural democracy, which no doubt had some effect on the way things are run today &ndash; Costa Rica is noted for being the most egalitarian and democratically developed country in the region, with a conscientious regard for the ecological protection of its environment.</p>
<p>Originally ruled by the Spanish, as one of the viceroyalties of New Spain, Costa Rica was declared independent in 1821. Initially it exchanged one form of colonial rule for another, being absorbed first by Mexico and subsequently as part of a new Central American Republic. Costa Rica finally became an independent country in its own right in 1838.</p>
<p>Throughout the 20th century, Costa Rica enjoyed peace and a steady growth in prosperity, with the notable exception of a civil war in 1948, which followed a disputed presidential election. Significantly, however, Costa Rica disbanded its military forces after the civil war and still today remains the only country in the region with no national army or military prescription.</p>
<p>Generally, Costa Rica has been a peaceful and liberal country for well over a hundred years and despite a national emergency in 1991, when an earthquake hit the country causing widespread loss of life and damage, its tourism industry has boomed in recent decades. In keeping with its eco-friendly image, the government has announced plans to become the first carbon-neutral country by 2021.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Some 300 giant stone spheres are dotted along the southern coast, on the Diquis Delta; dating from around 600 AD, the stones weigh up to 15 tons, but how and why they were made remain a mystery.<br />
&bull;	San Jose airport is named after Juan Santamaria, national folk hero who helped defeat US freebooter William Walker in 1856.<br />
&bull;	The strawberry poison dart frog is one of Costa Rica&rsquo;s tiniest and most colourful creatures; it can change colour from red to green to blue, to confuse predators.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Pura Vida University (PV)]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+506 2299-5800</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.puravidauniversity.eu/uk/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+506 2299-5800</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Costa Rica]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+506 2258 2025.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/costa-rica</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+506 2258 2025.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1200 &amp; 1230-1600; Fri 0800-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Apartado 815 - 1007<br/>Edificio Centro Colón, Paseo Colón and Streets 38 and 40<br/>San José<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Costa Rica in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 499 2991.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.costarica-embassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 499 2991.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1400 (appointment only); Mon-Fri 0900-1700 (phone queries).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2112 S Street<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy and Consulate of the Republic of Costa Rica in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7706 8844.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.costaricanembassy.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7706 8844.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1500 (embassy); Mon-Fri 1000-1300 (consulate).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Flat 1, 14 Lancaster Gate<br/>London<br/>W2 3LH<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Steaming rainforest, iridescent hummingbirds, smouldering volcanoes, tumbling rivers, and miles of palm-fringed sandy beaches: if Mother Nature can ever be accused of showing off, it is in Costa Rica. Sat just north of the equator, this verdant chunk of the Central American isthmus is one of the most bio-diverse spots on the planet. Added to which, as the only country in the region with no standing army, it&rsquo;s a beacon of peace and democracy.</p>
<p>A world pioneer in eco-tourism, Costa Rica has set aside more than a quarter of its territory as a protected natural area, more than any other country on Earth. Its national parks are its greatest glory, comprising a stunning variety of landscapes, microclimates, flora and fauna. The cloud forests of Monteverde are the haunt of the resplendent quetzal, sacred national bird. Corcovado&rsquo;s coastal rainforest is home to all four native monkey species. The northwestern Nicoya Peninsula is teeming with birds, wild cats, whales and dolphins. The canals, beaches and mangroves of Tortuguero are alive with wildlife, including nesting green and leatherback turtles.</p>
<p>Alternatively, if you are looking for an adrenalin kick, whitewater rafting, tree-top zip wires, surfing and quad biking are just a few of the extreme activities on offer. You can hike around the many volcanoes studded along the country&rsquo;s spine; tread carefully on grumpy Arenal Volcano, or wallow in the hot lagoons and mud baths of the more placid Poas and Iraz&uacute;.</p>
<p>Costa Rica&rsquo;s cities may not win many architectural awards but they&rsquo;re worth a visit, if only for an insight into the urban lives of Ticos, as the citizens call themselves. Downtown San Jose has superb museums and excellent caf&eacute;s. Or head to sleepy Puerto Lim&oacute;n on the Caribbean coast; a popular stop-off with surfers en route to the big waves off Isla Uvita. For anyone in search of an ethical adventure, Costa Rica&rsquo;s charms will have you under their spell all too quickly.</p><p>Steaming rainforest, iridescent hummingbirds, smouldering volcanoes, tumbling rivers, and miles of palm-fringed sandy beaches: if Mother Nature can ever be accused of showing off, it is in Costa Rica. Sat just north of the equator, this verdant chunk of the Central American isthmus is one of the most bio-diverse spots on the planet. Added to which, as the only country in the region with no standing army, it&rsquo;s a beacon of peace and democracy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
