<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Croatia" ColCode="hrv" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="hr" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Croatia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Croatia has a varied climate, with continental climate conditions inland and Mediterranean influence on the Adriatic coast. Peak season is July - August, with temperatures in the high 20s or in the 30s in places like Split, but you can expect plenty of sunshine from roughly May to October on the coast, and the shoulder seasons (May-June and September) are among the best times to visit Croatia. Inland is also hot in the summer but can be bitterly cold in the winter with sub-zero temperatures and heavy snowfall. Winter on the coast is milder but can be quite rainy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights and beachwear (including sun protection) for summer. Mediumweights for winter with heavy, warm clothing for inland areas. It is a good idea to pack waterproofs at any time of year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Zagreb (ZAG),<em> </em>Rijeka (RJK), Split (SPU), Pula (PUY) and Dubrovnik (DBV) international airports<em> </em>all receive domestic flights. &nbsp;Domestic services also run to Zadar (<a href="http://www.zadar-airport.hr/" target="_blank">www.zadar-airport.hr</a>) and Osijek (<a href="http://www.osijek-airport.hr/" target="_blank">www.osijek-airport.hr</a>), which both handle some international traffic, and the smaller airports on the islands of Brac (<a href="http://www.airport-brac.hr/" target="_blank">www.airport-brac.hr</a>) and Los&iexcl;inj (<a href="http://www.airportmalilosinj.hr/" target="_blank">www.airportmalilosinj.hr</a>).</p>
<p>The main domestic routes operated by Croatia Airlines (<a href="http://www.croatiaairlines.com" target="_blank">www.croatiaairlines.com</a>) are Zagreb-Dubrovnik and Zagreb-Split.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> Buying domestic tickets while in Croatia can sometimes be cheaper than online.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jadrolinija (tel: +385 51 666 111; <a href="http://www.jadrolinija.hr/" target="_blank">www.jadrolinija.hr</a>) is the main provider of car and passenger ferries and  catamarans in Croatia. There are regular connections between the main ports and the offshore islands. A coastal service runs all the way from Rijeka in the north to Dubrovnik in the south, via Split, Stari Grad and Korcula.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HŽPP (tel: +381 1 378 2583; <a href="http://www.hzpp.hr/en" target="_blank">www.hzpp.hr/en</a>) operates trains in Croatia. The main rail routes are Zagreb-Split, Zagreb-Rijeka and Zagreb-Osijek. There are no trains to Dubrovnik. It's generally quicker to travel by bus.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Croatia. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good motorway network (though the extension to Dubrovnik isn't yet complete). In some areas the road quality decreases somewhat, and the main coastal highway gets extremely congested during peak season.</p>r<p>Croatia has an extensive network of highways (designated as E roads) and unclassified roads. Motorway connections are continually improving, and Croatia's 11 motorways are designated with the numbers A1 to A11.</p>
<p>The A1 is the main artery between Zagreb and Split. The A2 runs between Ljubljana (Slovenia) and Zagreb (Croatia), connecting Zagreb directly to the Western European highway system.</p><p>Regular coaches operate between most towns (see Zagreb bus station website, <a href="http://www.akz.hr" target="_blank">www.akz.hr</a>).</p><p>Registered taxis are easy to find and safe. Since fares are regulated, they're reasonably priced too.</p><p>National or International Driving Permit. All motorists should also carry a valid passport or national identity card as proof of identity at all times. A Green Card should be carried by visitors (except EU nationals) taking their own car into Croatia.</p>
<p>National registration in the country of origin is required for all foreign vehicles. Third party insurance is mandatory when hiring a car and a valid credit card is also needed.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 130kph (81mph) on motorways, 110kph (62mph) on highways, 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas and  90kph (50mph) outside built-up areas. Heavy fines are imposed for speeding.</p>
<p>It's compulsory for front and rear passengers to wear seat belts. It is illegal to use a handheld mobile telephone while driving. Headlights should be turned on at all times. Driving is on the right.</p><p>Hrvatski Autoklub (HAK) operates an emergency service (tel: +385 1 987; <a href="http://www.hak.hr" target="_blank">www.hak.hr</a>).</p><p>International and local car hire firms have offices in Croatia's airports, cities, bigger towns and leading resorts.</p><p>Local tourist agencies in many main centres hire bikes, and some local tourist boards (eg Zagreb County, <a href="http://www.tzzz.hr" target="_blank">www.tzzz.hr</a>) have cycle routes and maps online.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 130kph (81mph) on motorways, 110kph (62mph) on highways, 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas and  90kph (50mph) outside built-up areas. Heavy fines are imposed for speeding.</p>
<p>It's compulsory for front and rear passengers to wear seat belts. It is illegal to use a handheld mobile telephone while driving. Headlights should be turned on at all times. Driving is on the right.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most towns and cities have a comprehensive local bus network; trams operate in many cities (Zagreb, Split, Osijek, etc). The historic centre of some towns (Split, Dubrovnik) are pedestrianised and pleasantly car-free.</p>
<p><strong>Zagreb:</strong>&nbsp;You can easily navigate the centre of Zagreb on foot. It also has a good network of trams and buses run by ZET (<a href="http://www.zet.hr" target="_blank">www.zet.hr</a>), as well as a funicular and taxis.</p>
<p><strong>Dubrovnik:</strong> Dubrovnik's Old City is pedestrianised. Libertas (<a href="http://www.libertasdubrovnik.hr" target="_blank">www.libertasdubrovnik.hr</a>) operates efficient bus services, with stops just outside the Pile and Ploče  gates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Croatia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">zagreb</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.55</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Croatia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">split</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Croatia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">rijeka</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Croatia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">split</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.25</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Croatia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">dubrovnik</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.55</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier is Croatia Airlines (<a href="http://www.croatiaairlines.com" target="_blank">www.croatiaairlines.com</a>). Other airlines flying to Croatia from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and&nbsp;easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>). Flights are at their most expensive in July, August and around Christmas &ndash; book as far in advance as possible at these times of year.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia/dubrovnik-airport">Dubrovnik Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia/split-airport">Split Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia/zagreb-airport">Zagreb Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia/zadar-airport">Zadar Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/zagreb">Zagreb</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 15 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 10 hours 15 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Dubrovnik Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport-dubrovnik.hr<p>Dubrovnik Airport is located 21km (13 miles) to the southeast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dubrovnik">Dubrovnik</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+385 2077 3100</p>]]><b>Split Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.split-airport.hr<p>Split Airport is located along the Adriatic coast, 6km (4 miles) from Trogir to the west and Kaštela to the east. The airport is 25km (15.5 miles) from Split to the southeast.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+385 21 203 555.</p>]]><b>Pula Airport </b><![CDATA[http://www.airport-pula.hr/<p>The airport  is 8km (5 miles) northwest of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Rijeka Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.rijeka-airport.hr<p>The airport is 27km (17 miles) from the city on the island of Krk.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Zagreb Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.zagreb-airport.hr<p>Zagreb Airport is situated 10km (6 miles) south of central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/zagreb">Zagreb</a>, in the Pleso suburb.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+385 1 456 2222</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major ports include Rijeka (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.lukarijeka.hr/">www.lukarijeka.hr</a>), Zadar (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.port-authority-zadar.hr/">www.port-authority-zadar.hr</a>), Split (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.portsplit.com/">www.portsplit.com</a>) and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dubrovnik">Dubrovnik</a> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.portdubrovnik.hr">www.portdubrovnik.hr</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HŽPP (tel: +381 1 378 2583; <a href="http://www.hzpp.hr/en" target="_blank">www.hzpp.hr/en</a>) operates trains in Croatia. Daily international services arrive from Ljubljana, Munich, Vienna and Belgrade.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries. Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> The express trains running from Zagreb to Split are still comparatively slow next to buses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are good, easy routes by road from all neighbouring countries. Hrvatski Autoklub (the Croatian Automobile) (<a href="http://www.hak.hr" target="_blank">www.hak.hr</a>) can provide information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Telephone booths are operated by phonecards available at post offices, news stands and in some tourist shops. There are also payphone booths in many post offices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good. Local SIM cards are also readily available, often bundled with credit and a phone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes can be found in Zagreb and other main towns. They are easy to find (start by looking in one of the tourist agencies), though the connection speed varies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Croatia's media operate in a climate of relative freedom, especially compared to the restrictions of President Tudjman's era. The constitution bans censorship and guarantees press freedom. Croatian Radio-Television, <em>HRT</em>, is a national state-owned public broadcaster and is financed by a mixture of advertising and licence-fee revenues. Other networks include<em> Nova</em> and <em>RTL</em>. Public TV is the main source of news and information. National and regional newspapers include Jutarnji list and Večernji list; the Croatian Times (<a href="http://www.croatiantimes.com" target="_blank">www.croatiantimes.com</a>) is an English-language news website.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Stamps are available in post offices and from news stands. Allow around a week for letters to the UK, 10 days to the US. See Croatian Postal Services website (<a href="http://www.posta.hr" target="_blank">www.posta.hr</a>).</p><p>Mon-Fri 0700-1900 and Sat 0700-1300. Some may be open until 2200 in larger cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Art and sculpture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See fine examples of early Croatian religious art at the Museum of Croatian Archaeological Monuments (<a href="http://www.mhas-split.hr/" target="_blank"><font color="#056ab6">www.mhas-split.hr</font></a>) in Split. Appreciate more of Me&scaron;trović's 20th-century sculptures in the city's Me&scaron;trović Gallery (<a href="http://www.mdc.hr/mestrovic" target="_blank"><font color="#056ab6">www.mdc.hr/mestrovic</font></a>).<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Bird-watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Slavonia's Kopački Rit Nature Park (<a href="http://www.kopacki-rit.com/" target="_blank"><font color="#056ab6">www.kopacki-rit.com</font></a>) is a vast expanse of wetland frequented by myriad migrating birds and well away from the tourist crowds.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Brijuni National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Brijuni National Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.brijuni.hr/">www.brijuni.hr</a>) is an archipelago of 14 unspoilt islands located off the west coast of Istria. Stay overnight on the largest island, Veli Brijun, home to a golf course and a safari park.</p>]]><p><b>Cres</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Escape the crowds on the Kvarner Gulf island of Cres (<a href="http://www.tzg-cres.hr" target="_blank">www.tzg-cres.hr</a>), famous for its colony of Griffon Vultures, the historic settlement of Valun and the laid-back Cres Town.</p>]]><p><b>Cycling</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A top cycling spot is in Mljet National Park (<a href="http://www.np-mljet.hr/" target="_blank">www.np-mljet.hr</a>), located on the green and unspoiled island of the same name. The park boasts dense forests, two interconnected saltwater lakes and, in the centre of the larger lake, the exquisite St Mary's Island and Benedictine Monastery.</p>]]><p><b>Diving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dive in the ethereal Blue Grotto and explore the shipwrecks sunk off the island of Vis (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tz-vis.hr">www.tz-vis.hr</a>), Croatia's most remote inhabited island.</p>]]><p><b>Dubrovnik</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Undoubtedly the most famous place in Croatia, Dubrovnik's old town constitutes one of the best-preserved medieval walled cities on the Mediterranean. Walk a complete circuit of Dubrovnik's (<a href="http://www.tzdubrovnik.hr/" target="_blank">www.tzdubrovnik.hr</a>) 13th-century city walls, then explore the UNESCO World Heritage-listed Old Town. Check out the Franciscan Monastery (home to Europe's oldest pharmacy) and delightful baroque churches. Dubrovnik's turbulent history can be unearthed at the Rector's Palace, War Photo Limited (<a href="http://www.warphotoltd./" target="_blank">www.warphotoltd.com</a>) and the Maritime Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Golden Cape</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The fine golden shingle of Zlatni Rat (Golden Cape) makes it Croatia's most photographed beach, located just outside the tourist resort of Bol (<a href="http://www.bol.hr/" target="_blank">www.bol.hr</a>) on the island of Brac. It's also one of Croatia's top windsurfing destinations.</p>]]><p><b>Hiking and climbing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Velebit is Croatia's most extensive mountain range and the best area for hiking lies just inland from the coast between Senj and Starigrad-Paklenica, and contains two national parks, Sjeverni Velebit in the north and Paklenica in the south.</p>]]><p><b>Hvar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join the jet set on the increasingly exclusive island of Hvar, renowned for its rugged coastline, excellent wines and lavender fields. Drink coffee or sip cocktails in Hvar Town (<a href="http://www.tzhvar.hr" target="_blank">www.tzhvar.hr</a>), a Venetian settlement, built around a picturesque harbour presided over by a hilltop fortress.</p>]]><p><b>Inland Istria</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Driving around Inland Istria will reveal romantic hill towns like Motovun (<a href="http://www.tz-motovun.hr/" target="_blank">www.tz-motovun.hr</a>), Buje (<a href="http://www.tzg-buje.hr/" target="_blank">www.tzg-buje.hr</a>) and Gronjan (<a href="http://www.tz-groznjan.hr/" target="_blank">www.tz-groznjan.hr</a>). While here sample the local delicacy, truffles.</p>]]><p><b>Island-hopping</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Croatia has over 1100 of them, in all shapes and sizes, ranging from the remote islets that make up the Kornati archipelago, to the lavender-scented, party capital of Hvar. Island hop between the largely traffic-free Elaphite Islands of Kolocep, Lopud and Sipan, near Dubrovnik (<a href="http://www.visitdubrovnik.hr" target="_blank">www.visitdubrovnik.hr</a>), with their secluded and beaches and good-value restaurants.</p>]]><p><b>Kornati National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Kornati National Park (<a href="http://www.kornati.hr/" target="_blank">www.kornati.hr</a>) is an archipelago of some 90 scattered islands and islets. Virtually uninhabited, the islands display a harsh, rocky landscape practically devoid of vegetation. Several renovated stone cottages provide 'Robinson Crusoe'-type holiday accommodation.</p>]]><p><b>Korčula Town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Korčula Town (<a href="http://www.korcula.net/" target="_blank"><font color="#056ab6">www.korcula.net</font></a>) is a marvel of medieval urban planning which has charmed foreign visitors since the first tourists arrived on the eponymous island in the 1920s.</p>]]><p><b>Krka National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The river in Krka National Park (<a href="http://www.npkrka.hr/" target="_blank">www.npkrka.hr</a>) has sculpted a picturesque canyon, famed for its spectacular Skradinski buk (Skradin Waterfalls) and the islet of Visovac, home to a Franciscan Monastery.</p>]]><p><b>Plitvice Lakes National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Plitvice Lakes National Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.np-plitvicka-jezera.hr/">www.np-plitvicka-jezera.hr</a>) is one of Croatia's premier tourist attractions - a UNESCO-listed tree-shrouded wonderland of 16 turquoise lakes and waterfalls. Though busy with visitors in the summer, Croatia&rsquo;s most famous national park never fails to disappoint, with water gushing over ancient travertine beds and tumbling down high waterfalls. </p>
<p>Over thousands of years, the waters that flow through this area have passed over limestone and chalk, creating deposits which form natural barriers between the lakes. The lakes range in height from Proscansko Jezero at 636.6m (1746ft) above sea level, to the lowest, Kaludjerovac, at 505.2m (1386ft), and in surface area from 81 hectares (33 acres) to one hectare (2.5 acres).</p>]]><p><b>Poreč</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Built on a small peninsula, the Istrian town of Poreč (<a href="http://www.to-porec.com/" target="_blank"><font color="#056ab6">www.to-porec.com</font></a>) dates back to Roman times. Climb the tower of its star attraction, the UNESCO World Heritage-listed Euphrasius Basilica and admire the Basilica's stunning sixth-century Byzantine mosaics.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Pula</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The city of Pula on the Istrian coast has some of the finest Roman ruins in Croatia, including a magnificent and remarkably well-preserved amphitheatre which is one of the largest surviving in the world.</p>]]><p><b>Split</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel back in time to Split (<a href="http://www.visitsplit.com/" target="_blank">www.visitsplit.com</a>), the capital of Central Dalmatia, which was founded in the third century AD by the Roman Emperor Diocletian. Croatia's second city is a major port, and the main jumping off point for ferries to and from some of the most popular islands, including Hvar and Brač. At its core is the truly amazing Diocletian's Palace (another UNESCO World Heritage Site), built for Diocletian and which is now a warren of houses, shops, alleys and historic architecture spanning some 1700 years.</p>]]><p><b>Trogir</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Just west of Split is the tiny medieval city of Trogir (<a href="http://www.tztrogir.hr/" target="_blank">www.tztrogir.hr</a>), that was was founded by the Greeks in the third century BC. Discover the beautiful Romanesque cathedral and Venetian gothic stone buildings that have earned it a place on the UNESCO World Heritage site list.</p>]]><p><b>Volosko</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Home to some of Croatia's best seafood restaurants, the gastronomic enclave of Volosko is a pretty fishing village just outside the popular resort of Opatija (<a href="http://www.opatija-tourism.hr" target="_blank">www.opatija-tourism.hr</a>), while soaking up attractive Adriatic sea views.</p>]]><p><b>Zadar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Often overlooked by most tourists until comparatively recently, Zadar (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tzzadar.hr/">www.tzzadar.hr</a>) is one of the most important historical centres on the coast, with a beautiful old town centre and now a thriving music festival nearby (the Garden Festival).  Stroll around its narrow cobbled streets, drink coffee on a ruined Roman Forum and listen to classical recitals in the ninth-century Church of St Donat.</p>]]><p><b>Zagorje</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head for the undulating hills and vineyards of Zagorje (<a href="http://www.tz-zagorje.hr" target="_blank">www.tz-zagorje.hr</a>), just north of Zagreb, to explore the historic Veliki Tabor and Trakošćan castles.</p>]]><p><b>Zagreb</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Croatian capital is unquestionably its most interesting city, despite the focus of tourism on the coast. Beautiful architecture, a huge number of museums and galleries, excellent restaurants, a lively caf&eacute; culture and some lovely parks and gardens all make Zagreb an essential part of any visit to Croatia.</p>
<p>Visit the historic monuments of Gornji Grad (Upper Town): the Cathedral, St Mark's Church (noted for its tiled roof) and the Sabor (Croatian parliament). Then check out the museums of 19th-century Donji Grad (Lower Town).</p>
<p>The Museum of Arts and Crafts (<a href="http://www.muo.hr" target="_blank">www.muo.hr</a>) traces Croatian craftsmanship through the centuries, and the Mimara Museum exhibits a rich collection of painting, sculpture and ceramics from abroad. Admire Mestrovic's dramatic sculptures at the Mestrovic Atelier (<a href="http://www.mdc.hr/mestrovic" target="_blank">www.mdc.hr/mestrovic</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Šibenik</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Central Dalmatia's second city, &Scaron;ibenik (<a href="http://www.sibenik-tourism.hr">www.sibenik-tourism.hr</a>), is worth visiting for its 15th-century UNESCO-listed Cathedral of St James alone. The Old Town was founded by the Slavs, not the Romans or Venetians.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$78.52 billion (2010 estimate)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Transport equipment, textiles, chemicals, foodstuffs and fuels.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, transport and electrical equipment, chemicals, fuels and lubricants.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Italy, Bosnia & Herzegovina, Germany, Slovenia, Austria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Along with Slovenia, Croatia was the most developed republic of the former Yugoslavia. The Croatian economy recovered well after the break-up of Yugoslavia and several years of civil war.<br/><br/> Industry is the most important sector in the economy, producing transport equipment (especially shipping), textiles, chemicals, processed foods and fuels. Agriculture, which produces maize, wheat, grapes and other crops, is important for domestic purposes but has never contributed significantly to the export economy. Mineral deposits of exploitable size include oil, coal and natural gas. .<br/><br/> Tourism is also extremely important to Croatia, and is centred on the Dalmatian coast. After being all but wiped out by the civil war, it has recovered and prospered, and is now the major driving force behind Croatia's recent economic progress. .<br/><br/> Annual GDP growth in 2010 was -1.4%. Inflation was around 1.3% and unemployment around 17.6%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As Croatia moves towards becoming a member of the European Union, its business etiquette and traditions are becoming more like those in the rest of the EU countries. Croatians, both male and female, tend to dress fairly smartly inland with more informality on the warmer Adriatic coast, and this more relaxed approach also extends to timekeeping.<br /><br />Communication is no problem as English, Italian and German are widely used as second languages. A firm handshake is the usual start to any business meeting. Business cards including professional or academic titles should be exchanged just after formal introductions.<br /><br />Interpersonal relationships are usually relaxed and develop relatively quickly, and gifts are appreciated, perhaps luxury items such as a bottle of Scottish whisky or a good bottle of Croatian wine. Alcohol, especially wine, often flows during business meals, and deals are often celebrated with hard spirits.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Zagreb Convention Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01) 489 8555
					Website:http://www.zagreb-convention.hr/
					Address: ,Kaptol 5,Zagreb,10000]]><b>Croatian Chamber of Economy</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01) 456 1555
					Website:http://www.hgk.hr/
					Address: ,Rooseveltov trg 2,Zagreb,10000]]><b>Congress and Incentive Office Dubrovnik</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 324 999
					Website:http://www.visitdubrovnik.hr/convention,http://www.croatia.hr/
					Address: ,Cvijete Zuzorić 1/1,Dubrovnik,20000]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Though the Adriatic is mostly associated with the culinary titan that is Italy, Croatia's coast is also renowned for its variety of seafood dishes. Italian influence is strong in this region, while inland areas abound with steaks and hearty stews. Freshwater fish is prominent on menus in Slavonia.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;ll find exquisite cakes and desserts all over the country, with a mix of gelato, pancakes, pastries, <em>torta</em>, and even <em>baklava</em>. Croatia produces plenty of wine, with the best reds generally coming from the Pelje&scaron;ac peninsula, and the best whites usually produced in eastern Slavonia and in Istria. Most towns boast a great pizzeria, too.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pr&scaron;ut i pa&scaron;ki sir</strong>: Air-dried ham similar to Italian prosciutto and sheep's cheese from the island of Pag.<br />
<strong>Salata od hobotnice</strong>: Octopus salad with potato, onion, chopped parsley, garlic and lemon.<br />
<strong>Crni ri&yacute;ot</strong>: Black risotto made from cuttlefish, cooked in its own ink.<br />
<strong>Janjetina</strong>: Roast lamb, often cooked whole on a spit.<br />
<strong>Tartufi</strong>: Truffles, found widely in Istria.<br />
<strong>Fuži</strong>: Pasta, where the dough has been rolled into a cylinder and often filled, typical in Istria.<br />
<strong>Salata od jastoga</strong>: Salad of lobster served with herbs and olive oil.<br />
<strong>Grah</strong>: Soup of paprika-spiced haricot beans with sausage pieces.<br />
<strong>Pari&scaron;ki odrezak</strong>: A pork or veal schnitzel fried in batter, or stuffed with cheese and ham (Zagreb schnitzel).<br />
<strong>Strukli</strong>: Boiled parcels of dough filled with cottage cheese, or baked in earthenware, resulting in a kind of cheese lasagne-cum-pastry.<br />
<strong>Rožata</strong>: Croatia's take on cr&egrave;me caramel, typical of Dubrovnik.<br />
<strong>Beer:</strong> Best known brands include Pan, Karlovacko and Ozujsko (lagers), plus Tomislav (a dark beer).<br />
<strong>Wine:</strong> Visitors will be pleasantly surprised by Croatia&rsquo;s wine offering, which includes Plavac Mali (red) and whites such as Malvazija, Grasevina, and Posip.<br />
<strong>Fruit brandy: </strong>Ubiquitous in Croatia, locals know this potent tipple as <em>rakija</em>. Look out for walnut brandy, plum brandy and grape brandy.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>5% to 10% is sufficient (and is expected in the more upmarket restaurants), otherwise just round up the bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The year-round nightlife scene centres on the capital, Zagreb, which buzzes with everything from swanky cocktail bars to alternative cultural clubs patronised by students. However, come summer, the lion's share of the inland action moves to the tourism-boosted coast. Venues include everything from informal beach bars and pavement cafes through to style bars and glitzy nightclubs. Some of the most up-market clubs are in Dubrovnik, and frequently hit the gossip magazines as they attract both foreign and local celebrities. Likewise, the bars and clubs in trendy Hvar Town on the island of Hvar - dubbed the new Ibiza - are patronised by the glamorous international yachting crowd.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional handicrafts like embroidery, intricate lace from the island of Pag, small decorative &lsquo;hearts&rsquo; from Zagreb, lavender bags from Hvar, locally made glass jewellery, woodcarvings and ceramics make good souvenirs, while Croatian wines and spirits, olive oils and truffle products also make excellent gifts to bring home. Local fashion label I-GLE (<a href="http://www.i-gle.com" target="_blank">www.i-gle.com</a>) has stores in Zagreb. Fairs and festivals can be a good place to buy souvenirs, or seasonal markets such as those in central Zagreb around Easter, and there are a number of shops (particularly in Zagreb and Dubrovnik) selling a good range of local products (try Bakina Kuća, <a href="http://www.bakina-kuca.hr" target="_blank">www.bakina-kuca.hr</a>). Tourists can reclaim VAT on expenditure of more than 500 Kn. Visitors should ensure that all receipts are retained after any purchase is made, as financial police have the power to fine visitors without relevant documents. This is to prevent VAT evasion by shopkeepers.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-2000, Sat 0800-1400/1500. Some shops in cities may open on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ongoing investment in Croatia's hotel stock is seeing the standard in  accommodation increase across the board, with good 4- and 5-star hotels  available along the coast and inland, including some stunning boutique  options. Village tourism is also on the increase in rural areas. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong>  Hotels in Croatia are officially graded by the Ministry of Tourism into  five categories according to the standard of accommodation: 5-star: Luxury. 4-star: Deluxe. 3-star: First class. 2-star: Moderate. 1-star: Basic and budget. For a list of classified hotels, visit the tourist board website (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.croatia.hr/">www.croatia.hr</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Breakfast is usually included at hotels, but not in <em>sobe</em> (private rooms). Full and half board is also widely available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ongoing investment in Croatia's hotel stock is seeing the standard in  accommodation increase across the board, with good 4- and 5-star hotels  available along the coast and inland, including some stunning boutique  options. Village tourism is also on the increase in rural areas. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong>  Hotels in Croatia are officially graded by the Ministry of Tourism into  five categories according to the standard of accommodation: 5-star: Luxury. 4-star: Deluxe. 3-star: First class. 2-star: Moderate. 1-star: Basic and budget. For a list of classified hotels, visit the tourist board website (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.croatia.hr/">www.croatia.hr</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ongoing investment in Croatia's hotel stock is seeing the standard in  accommodation increase across the board, with good 4- and 5-star hotels  available along the coast and inland, including some stunning boutique  options. Village tourism is also on the increase in rural areas. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong>  Hotels in Croatia are officially graded by the Ministry of Tourism into  five categories according to the standard of accommodation: 5-star: Luxury. 4-star: Deluxe. 3-star: First class. 2-star: Moderate. 1-star: Basic and budget. For a list of classified hotels, visit the tourist board website (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.croatia.hr/">www.croatia.hr</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;For UK nationals emergency medical treatment is normally free on presentation of a UK passport. Since Croatia is now part of the EU, EU citizens can use EHIC cards to gain free medical care. Non-emergency care and prescribed medicines must be paid for. All travellers are advised to take out full medical insurance.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food is almost universally safe, and tap water is fine to drink.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against hepatitis B and tuberculosis are sometimes advised. Precautions should be taken against tick bites. For anyone planning to spend long periods of time in forested areas, carrying a pair of tick tweezers is advised, and immunisation against tick-borne encephalitis is also a possible precaution. Rabies is present. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Anti-Fascist Resistance Day :
							22 June </p><p>Statehood Day :
							25 June </p><p>Victory and Homeland Thanksgiving Day :
							05 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							08 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Croatia is within the European Union. If you <a target="_blank" href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/i/ski/are">are</a> travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>,  you are entitled to buy fragance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine,  selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at  tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the  amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for  personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject  to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine  whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22%, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%, 90L  of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be  imported into Croatia by persons over 17 years of age without incurring  customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of Kn3,200 for air and sea travellers and Kn2,200 for other travellers (reduced to Kn1,100 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unauthorised firearms and ammunition and non-prescription drugs.</p>
<p>There are restrictions on the import of plants, animals and food.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Articles of archaeological, historical, ethnographic, artistic and other scientific or cultural value require an export licence issued by the Croatian authorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kuna (HRK; symbol Kn) = 100 Lipa. Notes are in denominations of Kn1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of Kn25, 5, 2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 lipa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency can be exchanged in banks, by authorised dealers and post offices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted. ATMs are widespread.</p><p>ATMs are widespread.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars, Pounds Sterling or Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0700-1900, Sat 0700-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>No/1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes/1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>EU nationals are only required to produce evidence of their EU nationality and identity in order to be admitted to any EU member state. This evidence can take the form of a valid national passport or national identity card. Either is acceptable. They are not required to show possession of a return ticket, a certain length of validity on their document or sufficient funds for the length of their proposed visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Croatia is not yet a member of the Schengen area, but allows holders of Schengen visas to enter the country without the need for an additional visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay visa: &euro;60.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay visas are valid for one, two or multiple entries and are valid for up to three months in each six-month period. Visas can be valid for up to five years, depending on individual circumstances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals of some EU countries (including the UK)&nbsp;are restricted by transitional arrangements until 2020 and require a permit to work in Croatia.&nbsp;Contact your local Croatian Embassy or Consulate for further information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications for visas for Croatia are accepted no more than three months in advance of travel, and take five working days to process.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets must have an identifying microchip, rabies vaccination certificate and valid international or EU pet passport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[45.742996]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[17.098971]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>56,542 sq km (21,831 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,218,584 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>79 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Zagreb.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Croatia stretches along the Adriatic coast, narrowing north-south, with a larger inland area (Slavonia) running west-east from Zagreb to the border with Serbia. The northern two-thirds of this border are formed by the River Drava, the east by the Danube, the southern part by the Sava. The country borders Slovenia and Hungary to the north, Serbia to the east, Montenegro to the southeast and Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina (southeast from Zagreb; northeast from the Adriatic coastline). The coastline is highly indented, with over 1,100 islands and islets lying offshore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic Croats (87.8% of the total population) and Eastern Orthodox Serbs (4.4%), as well as small communities of Protestants, Jews and Muslims.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>People normally shake hands upon meeting and leaving. Smoking is generally acceptable but there are restrictions in public buildings and on public transport.<br /><br /><strong>Photography:</strong> Certain restrictions exist.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Tihomir Ore&scaron;ković since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Kolinda Grabar-Kitarović since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Croatia has a long and eventful history. Although Greek colonies were present on its coast from around the 6th century BC, this was an Illyrian-dominated territory until Celtic tribes began to push them into modern-day Albania in the 4th century BC. The tough Illyrians managed to hold much of Croatia, however, until the Romans defeated the last Illyrian king in 168BC.</p>
<p>The Romans ultimately brought the whole Dalmatian coast under imperial control, going on to rule for some five centuries. They built roads, trading outposts and fortresses, including the grand palace in Split, the finest Roman ruin of its kind in Eastern Europe. Towards the end of the Roman era, there were two Dalmatian emperors, including the great Diocletian.</p>
<p>After the collapse of the Roman Empire, Croats alongside other Slavic tribes began to move westwards. In the 7th century they are thought to have attacked Byzantine Dalmatia with the help of the Avars. By the 8th century, powerful Croat clans in the region had emerged, and an independent Croatian state was established in the 10th century. It lasted less than 200 years. Over subsequent centuries, Croatia was alternately ruled by Hungary, Venice, Napoleon and Austria. After WWI, a new 'Kingdom of Serbs, Croats and Slovenes' was created, and following WWII, Croatia became part of Tito&rsquo;s Yugoslavia along with Serbia, Slovenia, Bosnia, Macedonia.</p>
<p>On 25 June 1991, Croatia declared itself independent from Yugoslavia, a move that resulted in an infamously drawn-out conflict. Croatia was pitted against the might of the Yugoslav army and Serb irregular forces. In any case, by December 1991 the German government had recognised Croatian independence, with the rest of the world quickly following suit.</p>
<p>The death of the country's first democratically elected president, Franjo Tudjman, in 1999 heralded a new era of Croatian politics; Stjepan Mesić stepped into the fold and Croatia adopted a more conciliatory approach at home and abroad. In 2009, Jadranka Kosor became Croatia's first female prime minister following the surprise resignation of former PM, Ivo Sanader. In 2013, Croatia became a member of the European Union.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The English poet Lord Byron once described Dubrovnik as the &ldquo;pearl of the Adriatic&rdquo;.<br />
&bull;	While the old Slavic Glagolitic alphabet was replaced by Cyrillic in the Middle Ages, the Croats kept it alive until the 20th century &ndash; mostly in liturgical writing.<br />
&bull;	Ancient Egyptians in Croatia? The sphinx seen in the Roman ruins of Split was brought over from Egypt by Diocletian in the 3rd century.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Croatia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7387 1144.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://uk.mvp.hr</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7387 1144.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 1100-1400 (visa applications); Fri 1000-1200 (visa collections); Mon-Fri 1500-1600 (phone queries).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>21 Conway Street<br/>London<br/>W1T 6BN<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Croatia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 588 5899.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.croatiaemb.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 588 5899.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 1000-1200 and 1400-1600, Fri 1000-1200 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2343 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Zagreb]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(1) 600 9100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukincroatia.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(1) 600 9100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0830-1700, Fri 0830-1400.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Ivana Lučića 4, 10000<br/>Zagreb<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Occupying a stunning stretch of the Adriatic coastline, Croatia is one of Europe's top seaside destinations. Boasting more than 1,100 islands, the country is renowned for its limpid waters and picture-perfect scenery.</p>
<p>But Croatia is much more than sea and sunshine &ndash; it&rsquo;s home to historic walled cities and spectacular Roman ruins, as well as imposing castles and unspoiled national parks. The fantastic cuisine, including seafood on the coast and truffles in Istria, fine wines and buzzing caf&eacute; culture add to the appeal.</p>
<p>The capital, Zagreb, can be called quintessentially Central European. Everything from the architecture to the hearty cuisine reflects the region&rsquo;s centuries-old ties with the Austro-Hungarian Empire. The city also makes a good base from which to explore the historic castles and vineyards of Zagorje.</p>
<p>One thing that has changed greatly in the last decade in Croatia is tourism. The coast was once an undiscovered, undeveloped natural wonder as beautiful as Italy's, but without the fanfare. Now tourists from Britain, Germany and beyond flock to the Dalmatian region, and many have snapped up holiday homes.</p>
<p>The gorgeous seaside cities of Split and Dubrovnik still maintain their charm, but tend to be crowded with tourists during the day. The evenings in these coastal hubs tend to be much quieter, and there are often classical music concerts and other events in the city centres.</p>
<p>Beyond the tourist zones, Croatia is full of isolated places where you can discover more traditional, local life. Head to Plitvice for its amazing, lake-strewn national park, or explore the rugged mountain ranges of Velebit and Gorski Kotar, havens for hiking.</p>
<p>Back on the Adriatic, Croatia offers ideal sailing conditions, scuba diving and sea kayaking. And of course, those in search of a more restful holiday can enjoy hours of sunshine on the beach. As Europe's top naturist destination, Croatia is also a place where you can even get that all-over tan.</p>
<p>Clothing is advised if you&rsquo;re planning to explore the country&rsquo;s seven UNESCO World Heritage Sites, world-class museums and festivals, which come thick and fast throughout the summer.</p><p>Occupying a stunning stretch of the Adriatic coastline, Croatia is one of Europe's top seaside destinations. Boasting more than 1,100 islands, the country is renowned for its limpid waters and picture-perfect scenery.&nbsp;But Croatia is much more than sea and sunshine &ndash; it&rsquo;s home to historic walled cities and spectacular Roman ruins, as well as imposing castles and unspoiled national parks. The fantastic cuisine, including seafood on the coast and truffles in Istria, fine wines and buzzing caf&eacute; culture add to the appeal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
