<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Cuba" ColCode="cub" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="cu" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Cuba]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot, sub-tropical climate all year. Most rain falls between May and October and the hurricane season officially runs from July to November, with most storms historically occurring in October and November. Humidity varies between 75% and 95%. Cooler months are January to April when the least rain falls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothes most of the year; the high humidity makes it unwise to wear synthetics close to the skin. A light sweater is advisable even during the hottest months for installations with air conditioning (e.g. the Viazul bus, which is always frigid) and a heavier sweater or jacket for December through March when cold fronts can drop the mercury to 10 degrees Celsius (50°F). Light waterproofs are advisable all year round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cubana de Aviaci&oacute;n (<a href="http://www.cubana.cu" target="_blank">www.cubana.cu</a>) is&nbsp;the principal carrier in Cuba. The state-owned company operares internal flights between Havana and regional airports in Santiago de Cuba, Santa Clara, Nueva Gerona, Cayo Largo del sur, Guant&aacute;namo, Cienfuegos and Nueva Gerona.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national rail company is Ferrocarriles de Cuba, often shortened to Ferrocuba (tel: +53 7 861 2959 for train times in Havana or +53 22 622 836 for train times in Santiago de Cuba). There is no official website, but further information is available from The Man in Seat Sixty-One (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.seat61.com/Cuba.htm">www.seat61.com/Cuba.htm</a>).</p>
<p>The principal rail route is from Havana to Santiago de Cuba. Some trains on this route have air conditioning and refreshments. There are also through trains from Havana to other towns. Previously, the rail network connected the vast majority of the country, but it's been badly affected by natural disasters and now only certain parts of the country are accessible by rail. The trains are slow and punctuality does not seem to be a priority, but journeys are scenic and relaxing.</p>
<p>Another option for travellers who want to ride the rails is the Hershey Railway between Havana and Matanzas; this electric railcar departs three times a day from the Casablanca station across the harbour from Havana and is a scenic, off-the-beaten track adventure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Very few Cubans own cars, and outside of major cities almost the only vehicles on the road are agricultural deliveries, whose drivers know their routes by heart.&nbsp;As a result, signposting is a low priority but is improving as of late.&nbsp;Buy the best map available at the Infotur office in La Habana Vieja (the Guia de Carreteras).</p>
<p>Large sections of the <em>autopista</em> (motorway) are in a diabolical condition, potholed and poorly lit; to join or exit the motorway, drivers must often cross oncoming lanes, assuming lane markers exist.&nbsp;With heavy goods traffic concentrated on the motorway, many provincial primary roads are in fairly good condition.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Always stop at level crossings, which are often unmarked and almost always un-gated.</p><p>While it is fairly easy to get around by car, poor lighting and potholes are ubiquitous on Cuban roads. In the countryside, drivers will share the road with horse drawn carriages, bicycles, and various farm equipment and animals.</p><p>Efficient Viazul (tel: +53 7 881 1413; <a href="http://www.viazul.com" target="_blank">www.viazul.com</a>) buses connect most towns across the island of interest to visitors including Havana, Camag&uuml;ey, Santa Clara, Santiago de Cuba, Trinidad, Varadero and Vi&ntilde;ales.</p><p>In all major Cuban cities, taxis are easy to find and each town will have a taxi rank. Look for cars with a 'taxi' sign and blue licence plates (those with yellow plates are privately owned, are usually shared and run on fixed routes). 

There are a small number of bogus taxi drivers operating from Cuba's airports and around Old Havana. If you need a taxi, try to make sure it's a registered one and not a private vehicle. Drivers won't be offended if you ask to see their license.</p><p>Valid national driving licence required.</p><p>Speed limits are 100kph (62mph) on the motorway and 50kph (31mph) in urban areas. Motorcycle traffic police and stationary check points are common, and they are usually very strict. Tourists must be aged 21 or over and appear on the rental contract to be able to drive in Cuba. Seat belts are required; motorcycle riders and their passengers must wear helmets.</p><p>Should you breakdown, you need to contact your car hire agency to arrange roadside assistance.</p><p>All car hire companies are state owned. Prices are negotiable up to a point, but expect to be delayed when picking up the vehicle. It may be easier and has proven to be cheaper to book car hire through a specialist tour operator in your own country. When picking up the car, be sure there is a spare tyre and jack, and consider snapping a date-stamped picture of any existing damage to avoid disputes upon drop-off.</p><p>The lack of traffic makes Cuba a popular choice for cycling tours. You can rent bikes in Havana from a number of bike hire companies.</p><p>Speed limits are 100kph (62mph) on the motorway and 50kph (31mph) in urban areas. Motorcycle traffic police and stationary check points are common, and they are usually very strict. Tourists must be aged 21 or over and appear on the rental contract to be able to drive in Cuba. Seat belts are required; motorcycle riders and their passengers must wear helmets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Plentiful buses, and shared taxis criss-cross Havana, but are almost always overcrowded. Nevertheless, riding a Cuban <em>guagua</em> (bus) or <em>colectivo</em> (collective taxi) is a sure fire way to sneak a peek into daily life on the island.</p>
<p><strong>Taxis: </strong>Opt for a modern air-conditioned vehicle, or for special occasions a vintage American car (available at the best hotels). All official taxis have meters but watch out for taxis with 'broken' meters, especially in Havana. Unofficial 'private taxis', often vintage&nbsp;<em>Ladas</em> with blacked-out windows, can be hailed on the street but beware; while they're generally safe, drivers are breaking the law and if caught, everyone&rsquo;s journey will be over. In view of serious accidents that have involved tourists, travellers should not use mopeds or the three-wheel coco-taxis that are seen around tourist areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cuba</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">varadero</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cuba</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">trinidad</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cuba</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">santiagode_cuba</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">17.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cuba</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">pinardel_rio</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cuba's national airline is Cubana (<a href="http://www.cubana.cu" target="_blank">www.cubana.cu</a>) operate direct services to Mexico, Colombia and Dominican Republic.&nbsp;Flights to Cuba don't fluctuate much in price due to the limited number of carriers servicing the island, but are more expensive around major holidays (especially in December) and during the June to August summer tourist season.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a href="/manage.i/cuba/juan-gualberto-gomez-airport">Varadero Juan Gualberto Gomez Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cuba/havana-jose-marti-international-airport">Havana Jose Marti International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York - 4 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Havana José Martí International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://cubahavanaairport.com/<p>Havana Jos&eacute; Marti International Airport is situated 15km (9 miles) southwest of Havana.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+53 726 64644</p>]]><b>Varadero Juan Gualberto Gómez Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.varadero-airport.com<p>Varadero Juan Gualberto Gómez Airport is located 35km (21 miles) southwest of Varadero and around 40km (24 miles) east of Matanzas in northern Cuba.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+53 553 612</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sailing into Cuba is possible, with a handful of international marinas receiving foreign vessels including Havana's Marina Hemingway (tel: +53 7 209 7270), Marina Santiago de Cuba (tel: +53 22 691 446 and Marina Puerto Sol Cienfuegos (tel: +53 43 255 1241). There is no official website for Cuban marinas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Etecsa phonecards for both internal and external calls are readily available from shops and kiosks. Some calls must be made through the international operator, and may be subject to delays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. The mobile network Cubacel is administered by ETECSA (<a href="http://www.etecsa.cu" target="_blank">www.etecsa.cu</a>), which offers prepaid cell service via phone cards available at Cubacel offices. GSM telephones operating on 900MHz enjoy national coverage, those on 800MHz have coverage in Havana, Varadero, Cayo Coco and Cayo Guillermo only. Phone rental in Cuba can be unreliable; if you must have cellular service, bringing your own handset with roaming activated is advised.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available at hotels and many principal Etecsa offices internet cafes. Some websites are censored by the Cuban government, while others cannot be accessed due to the US embargo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Expect to be starved of printed information in Cuba. All media is state-controlled and Western newspapers are not available. CNN, BBC World and their ilk are available in most hotels. International news websites can be accessed in Cuba and blogs from the island are proliferating rapidly. Journalists must be accredited by the Centro de Prensa Internacional in Havana and operate within the confines of laws against anti-government propaganda. The insulting of officials carries penalties of up to three years in prison. Private ownership of electronic media is prohibited by the constitution, and foreign news agencies must hire local journalists only through government offices.  </p>
<p>Papers are in Spanish, although the Communist Party daily newspaper, <em>Granma</em>, publishes a weekly edition, called <em>Granma International</em>, in English, Italian, German, Portuguese and French. TV channels include <em>Cubavisi&oacute;n</em>, <em>Tele Rebelde</em>, <em>Canal Educativo</em>, and <em>Canal Habana</em>. <em>Radio Habana Cuba</em> is an external broadcaster broadcasting in Spanish, English, French and Portuguese.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Correos de Cuba</em> post offices are located throughout the country. Sending a letter to the USA or Europe costs CUC$0.65. It typically takes two weeks or more for mail sent from Cuba to arrive at its destination. Negotiations between the United States and Cuba regarding postal service are ongoing: as of April 2011, only 'light mail' (letters weighing up to 18 ounces) would be accepted by Correos de Cuba for posting to the USA.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1500. Many luxury hotels have small post offices on site, or can sell stamps and post letters out of hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Old Havana (Vieja Habana)</p><![CDATA[<p><em>Old Havana</em> harks back to Cuba&rsquo;s days as a colonial outpost and its subsequent era as a glamorous, sophisticated Caribbean playground. Although some of the crumbling palaces look like they could do with a lick of paint, many of its colonial buildings, majestic boulevards, elegant plazas and side streets have been restored, attracting more and more visitors each year. The <em>Plaza de la Catedral</em> (Cathedral Square), dominated by the towers of the 18th-century Baroque <em>Catedral de San Cristobal de La Habana </em>(St Cristobal Cathedral), perhaps best captures Old Havana&rsquo;s spirit.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask on beautiful beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cuba boasts beautiful beaches to soak up some sunshine, from Playas del Este near Havana, where the locals play, to exclusive island resorts like Cayo Coco. Santa Maria offers soft sand and turquoise waters just 20 minutes from Havana, while Playa Ancón near Trinidad, and Playa las Tumbas on the Guanhacabibes Peninsula, a UNESCO biosphere, are both picture-perfect.</p>]]><p><b>Canter through the Cuban countryside</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Saddle up and gallop through the scenic sugarcane fields around Trinidad and the Valle de Ingenios, or the hills, tobacco fields and valleys of Pinar del Río. At the likes of Rancho La Guabina, adults can try their hand at playing cowboy with lasso lessons, while Kids love pony rides offered at bigger Havana parks like Parque Almendares.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Torre de Manaca Iznaga for views over history</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy outstanding views of the Valley of the Sugar Mills from the Torre de Manaca Iznaga – a former slave watchtower by an old plantation house-turned restaurant. At the foot of the structure, the large bell that sounded in warning if a slave tried to escape still lies on the ground – a reminder of a sobering past.</p>]]><p><b>Drink daiquiris like Hemingway in El Floridita</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Follow in Hemingway's footsteps with a pub crawl to his favourite haunts, having a daiquiri (or three) at El Floridita and a mojito at La Bodeguita del Medio. Follow up with a visit to his suite at the Hotel Ambos Mundos, where he penned part of <em>For Whom the Bell Tolls.</em></p>]]><p><b>Explore Cuba's oldest fort, Castillo de la Real Fuerza</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wander around the Castillo de la Real Fuerza and its new shipwreck museum. The oldest of Havana's three forts is still standing because it was, to all intents and purposes, built in the wrong place.</p>]]><p><b>Explore mountains and caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pinar del Río is arguably Cuba's most beautiful province, and its most outstanding feature must be the mogotes: oddly rounded limestone mountains, covered in lush vegetation. There is beauty below the surface too; the caves here are awash with stalactites and stalagmites, and underground rivers.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the beat in Santiago de Cuba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience the country's best musicians and dancers hard at work in Santiago de Cuba. Don't miss Ballet Folklorico Cutumba – their Afro-Cuban performances are simply spectacular – and the city's annual carnival, a vibrant celebration of colourful costumes, choreography and traditional conga music. </p>]]><p><b>Find your revolution spirit at Museo de la Revolución</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Museo de la Revolución for a historical context of modern Cuba. Outside is the Granma, a cabin cruiser built for 12 people. In 1956, 80 exiled rebels (both Castros and Ché among them) came perilously close to sinking the overcrowded yacht, as they sought to return to Cuba.</p>]]><p><b>Grasp the horror of the Bay of Pigs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take an emotional journey to the museum at Playa Girón, scene of the US-backed Bay of Pigs invasion in 1961. The display includes tanks, aircraft and personal items from the battle's victims. Far from the Cold War, Playa Girón's warm waters offer much for scuba divers, with flooded caves, a sea wall and superb visibility.</p>]]><p><b>Meander along the Malecón</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join fishermen, families and couples, and take a stroll along the Malecón, the sea wall that links Old Havana to the western edge of Vedado. Careful though: during high seas and storms, the surf surges over the wall and the boulevard is sometimes closed to traffic as a result.</p>]]><p><b>Meet a mummy at Museo Emilio Bacardí</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Museo Emilio Bacardí in Santiago de Cuba ("the heroic city"). It contains the rum magnate's collection of antiques and fine art and the Moncada Barracks, where Fidel Castro launched an abortive uprising in 1953. The Castillo El Morro is now a museum of piracy.</p>]]><p><b>Notice the novelties at Palacio de los Capitanes Generales</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to the Plaza de Armas in Old Havana for a glimpse of colonial majesty at the Palacio de los Capitanes Generales, former residence of the Spanish Crown's representatives. Now the Museo de la Ciudad, treasures include a leather cannon and a throne room built for the Spanish monarch but never used.</p>]]><p><b>Party in Havana</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Live the high life in Havana's Vedado district. The Hotel Nacional has hosted gangsters and film stars and is well placed for a mojito, as well as carnival processions along the Malecón. For a taste of the traditional, try a chilled daiquiri in one of the leafy patios of the Old Town.</p>]]><p><b>Scuba dive at Treasure Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are 30 dive sites at Varadero alone and more reefs around Isla de la Juventud – the inspiration for <em>Treasure Island</em>. The island offers few crowds, bountiful marine life and the chance to wreck dive. One of the world's biggest reefs is offshore at Cayo Coco, and the underwater eye candy at María la Gorda is spectacular.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out the characters of Baracoa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A visit to this lost-in-time corner of Cuba is a must for history and nature buffs. Getting to the quaint seaside town was made feasible only in the 1960s with the construction of La Farola – one of Cuba's most scenic roads. In isolation, Baracoa led a fantastical, fabled existence. The tall tales and colourful characters still remain today.</p>]]><p><b>Take a plane to paradise, Cayo Largo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This small island off the southern coast was developed exclusively for tourism and boasts Cuba's most pristine beaches. Accessible only by plane, there is an air of exclusivity to the pure white sands and shimmering cyan seas. Nature enthusiasts will delight as the beaches here are sea turtle nesting areas too.</p>]]><p><b>Take a tour of Capitolio Nacional</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a tour of the Capitolio in Havana's centre. Built by a dictator to mimic Washington DC's Capitol (though the detailing on Havana's version is finer and structure taller), it housed a puppet parliament until the Revolution. Today it is home to the Cuban Academy of Sciences.</p>]]><p><b>Take a trip back in time at Trinidad</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Feel the history in the colonial town of Trinidad. Founded in 1514, time seemingly stood still in the late 19th century and today locals still ride horses down cobbled streets, past houses painted in pastel colours. Elegant mansions are now museums in this UNESCO World Heritage Site.</p>]]><p><b>Trek through a tropical paradise</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk in the footsteps of the revolutionary army to Cuba's highest peak, Pico Turquino (1972m), in the Oriente's Sierra Maestra range. Other hiking gems include the Sierra del Rosario and Viñales areas of Pinar del Río province, around Baracoa in Guantánamo and the peaceful peaks above the Embalse Hanabanilla reservoir.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the resting place of a revolutionary at Santa Clara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit revolutionary Santa Clara, and the monument, museum and mausoleum of Ché Guevara. His body was only returned from Bolivia in 1997, 30 years after his capture and execution. In 1959, he and 300 rebels defeated 3,000 of Batista's troops here, leading to the dictator's flight just days later.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>77.15 billion (2013).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Sugar, nickel, tobacco, fish, citrus, coffee and medical technology.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, petroleum, chemicals, machinery and equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Venezuela, China, Canada, the Netherlands, Spain.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In response to the recent global economic downturn and domestic inefficiencies, Cuba began a dramatic economic readjustment process in 2011, under the leadership of Ra&uacute;l Castro, which moved the country from a centrally planned economy towards a mixed economic system.</p>
<p>The reforms aimed to stimulate private enterprise and foreign investment, slash nearly one million state jobs, plus cut state subsidies of food. Additionally, over 170 types of private businesses were approved for licensing. Unifying the country's two currencies was outlined as a longer term goal. As of January 2017, the "two currency" system remains in place.<br />
<br />
In spite of the blockade with the US, tourism continues to grow and is a key source of hard currency. Cuban doctors, teachers, and other professionals working abroad in return for raw materials such as oil are significant contributors to the country's continued survival.&nbsp;Among the international community, Cuba has experienced a warming of relations since the economic reforms and increased cooperation with the likes of China, Russia, France, Spain, Mexico and Japan, among others.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The international business community has realised the potential of the Cuban market and new suitors and old beaux have been courted at increasingly successful trade fairs over the last few years. However, work practices can still be stuck in a paternalistic, top-down rut, where there is rarely anybody to take initiative (ie responsibility) or make decisions. <br />
<br />
The laid back attitude to timekeeping found in some parts of Latin America doesn't predominate in Cuba, but transportation, communication and other every-day problems often translate into inefficiency and absenteeism in the workplace - issues government is working hard to address. Initial approaches from international businesses are usually met with great optimism and indications that anything is possible, but this is followed by total inactivity once the visitors return to their home country. <br />
<br />
Business attire in Cuba is usually professional casual, with men forsaking jacket and tie for the dress shirt known as a <em>guayabera</em>, even for the most formal occasions. Courtesy is expected and hospitality should not be lavish, being offered to groups rather than individuals. <br />
<br />
Offices are generally open Monday to Friday 0830-1230 and 1330-1630 with some opening on Saturdays. It's always best to deal with business affairs in the morning, if possible. The best months for business visits in Cuba are November to April.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1230 and 1330-1630. Some offices also open on alternate Saturdays from 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cámara de Comercio de la República de Cuba</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (7) 838 1321
					Website:http://www.camaracuba.cu
					Address: Vedado,Calle 21,No 661,esq a A,Havana,]]><b>Buró de Convenciones de Cuba, COCAL</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (7) 204 8273.
					Website:http://www.cubameeting.travel
					Address: Miramar,Calle 70 y 74,Havana,]]><b>Cubanacán UK Ltd</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7536 8175.
					Website:http://www.cubanacan.co.uk
					Address: ,49 Limeharbour,London,E14 9TS]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Surprisingly for an island so rich in marine life, fish and seafood rarely top the menu – indeed, most seafood is exported. Cuban cuisine is a mix of Spanish and Afro-Caribbean, heavily reliant on rice, beans, chicken and pork. Depending on the season, fresh vegetables may be hard to come by – as a rule, the hotter the month, the more limited the selection.</p><p>Furthermore, flavours are limited by the lack of available herbs and spices and many visitors are surprised that Cubans often shun spicy flavours. Instead, food preparation relies heavily on the frying pan and deep fat fryer. Some of the best cooking – and often an illegal lobster or two – is found in 'paladares', small, private restaurants.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Congrís:</strong> Black beans and rice, known locally as 'Moors and Christians'.</p><p><strong>Frita: </strong>Local version of the American hamburger made with ground beef and chorizo served in small Cuban bread buns topped with onion and julienne potato fries.</p><p><strong>Pulpeta:</strong> Meat loaf made with ground beef and ham stuffed with hard-boiled eggs.</p><p><strong>Pan con timba:</strong> Bread with guayaba paste and cream cheese.</p><p><strong>Ropavieja: </strong>Slow cooked beef simmered in tomato criollo sauce until it can be shredded.</p><p><strong>Boliche: </strong>A beef roast stuffed with chorizo sausage and hard-boiled eggs.</p><p><strong>Mojo: </strong>A sauce for roast pork (and other meats) made with oil, garlic, onion, oregano and bitter orange of lime juice.</p><p><strong>Picadillo: </strong>A hash with minced beef, peppers, onions, garlic, cumin, tomato sauce, stock and olives, also with raisins, potatoes and capers.</p><p><strong>Mojito:</strong> Potent national cocktail made from rum, soda water, crushed mint, lime juice and chopped ice.</p><p><strong>Daiquiri:</strong> Blended cocktail of rum, ice, sugar, lime juice and a dash of maraschino.</p><p><strong>Guarapo:</strong> Sugar cane juice.</p><p><strong>Cafe Cubano:</strong> Espresso-style coffee.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 10% gratuity is normal.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>16.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Havana is renowned for its after-dark entertainment scene, and only the tip of the iceberg is visible to tourists on a short stay. Even medium-sized bars usually have a house band playing Cuban classics. The two Casas de la M&uacute;sica in Havana attract tourists and locals alike, the latter distinguished by their accomplished salsa dance moves. The famous Tropicana nightclub (<a href="http://www.cabaret-tropicana.com" target="_blank">www.cabaret-tropicana.com</a>) stages nightly open-air cabarets that are a throwback to decadent, pre-Revolution days. The Cabaret Parisien at the Hotel Nacional is similar, and both attract tour groups on 'day and night' packages from the coastal beach resorts.<br />
<br />
Theatre, opera and ballet are staged all year round in Havana and seats are very cheap. Cinemas show films in Spanish and blockbuster Hollywood movies - the latter are always subtitled, never dubbed. Santiago de Cuba is the spiritual home of <em>Son</em> - the music that gave birth to salsa, and regular live sessions are on offer at the Casa de la Trova (+53 22 623943). In beach resorts, nightlife tends to mimic what is on offer in Havana, with varying degrees of success. Varadero has a thriving scene, but in the smaller resorts (many of which are all-inclusive) most entertainment is planned and formulaic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Those hoping for a shopping splurge in Cuba will likely be disappointed - art being the obvious exception. There are a few luxury shops in Old Havana and in large hotels like the Habana Libre, but stock is generally uninspiring. <br />
<br />
Cuba makes the world's finest cigars. Buy the real thing at factories such as Real F&aacute;brica de Tabacos Partag&aacute;s in Havana, which also sells fabulously ornate cigar boxes. Other official outlets called Casas del Habano sell authentic wares as well. Cigars from street vendors will probably be fakes or factory rejects. Visitors can export 20 loose cigars, or up to 50 boxed cigars if they are in their original packaging, with all seals and holograms intact. Receipts must be shown to export over 50 cigars. Fidel Castro's favourite brand was Cohiba, Ch&eacute; Guevara favoured Montecristos, and, before he put the blockade in place, JFK stocked up on H Upmanns. <br />
<br />
Santiago de Cuba was once home to the Bacardi family distillery, but Havana Club is now the most famous Cuban rum. Good though it is, connoisseurs prefer Varadero.  The rich seven-year-old variety is sipped like fine malt, while younger and lighter blends are used for cocktails. <br />
<br />
A new, welcoming crafts market, the Almacenes San Jos&eacute;, has opened in the historic port building at Avenida del Puerto, next to the church of San Francisco de Paula; open 1000-1800 Monday to Saturday.</p><p>Mon-Sat 1000-1700, Sun 1000-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From staid and decaying state-owned giants to exciting new partnerships with French and Spanish hotel groups, Cuba's hotels greatly vary in both quality and style. <br />
<br />
Various government operators specialise in different sectors of the market: Habaguanex (<a href="http://www.habaguanexhotels.com/" target="_blank">www.habaguanexhotels.com</a>) tends to deal with historic or boutique hotels - an increasing trend in Cuba and particularly <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/havana">Havana</a>; Cubanacan (<a href="http://www.cubanacan.cu" target="_blank">www.cubanacan.cu</a>) operates a number of mid-range city, beach and rural hotels under different labels; Sol Melia (<a href="http://www.melia.com" target="_blank">www.melia.com</a>) concentrates on luxury, with an emphasis on beach resorts; Islazul (<a href="http://www.islazul.cu/" target="_blank">www.islazul.cu</a>) is at the cheaper end. Many hotels are advertised as luxury, boasting four or five stars, but many of these will not live up to western expectations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Literally meaning 'private house', the <em>casa particular</em> is broadly comparable to bed and breakfast. Rooms are often offered in beautifully-kept homes, complete with private bathroom (occasionally shared) and breakfast. Evening meals are often on offer as well, which can be more varied and plentiful than in state-run restaurants. Legal <em>casas particulares</em> are recognised by a blue triangle on a white background on the front door, and they must ask you for your passport number and signature in the official registration book.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From staid and decaying state-owned giants to exciting new partnerships with French and Spanish hotel groups, Cuba's hotels greatly vary in both quality and style. <br />
<br />
Various government operators specialise in different sectors of the market: Habaguanex (<a href="http://www.habaguanexhotels.com/" target="_blank">www.habaguanexhotels.com</a>) tends to deal with historic or boutique hotels - an increasing trend in Cuba and particularly <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/havana">Havana</a>; Cubanacan (<a href="http://www.cubanacan.cu" target="_blank">www.cubanacan.cu</a>) operates a number of mid-range city, beach and rural hotels under different labels; Sol Melia (<a href="http://www.melia.com" target="_blank">www.melia.com</a>) concentrates on luxury, with an emphasis on beach resorts; Islazul (<a href="http://www.islazul.cu/" target="_blank">www.islazul.cu</a>) is at the cheaper end. Many hotels are advertised as luxury, boasting four or five stars, but many of these will not live up to western expectations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From staid and decaying state-owned giants to exciting new partnerships with French and Spanish hotel groups, Cuba's hotels greatly vary in both quality and style. <br />
<br />
Various government operators specialise in different sectors of the market: Habaguanex (<a href="http://www.habaguanexhotels.com/" target="_blank">www.habaguanexhotels.com</a>) tends to deal with historic or boutique hotels - an increasing trend in Cuba and particularly <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/havana">Havana</a>; Cubanacan (<a href="http://www.cubanacan.cu" target="_blank">www.cubanacan.cu</a>) operates a number of mid-range city, beach and rural hotels under different labels; Sol Melia (<a href="http://www.melia.com" target="_blank">www.melia.com</a>) concentrates on luxury, with an emphasis on beach resorts; Islazul (<a href="http://www.islazul.cu/" target="_blank">www.islazul.cu</a>) is at the cheaper end. Many hotels are advertised as luxury, boasting four or five stars, but many of these will not live up to western expectations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Obtain adequate health insurance before travelling. Prior to treatment, visitors may need to show proof of ability to pay, though some emergency services are provided free of charge. Standards of care and training are excellent, but equipment and drugs are often in short supply.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is not safe to drink. Bottled water is ubiquitous, but boiling water is recommended to limit plastic waste. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products (with the exception of some cheap ice creams) are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafoods and fruit are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Dengue fever may occur as well as outbreaks of dengue haemorrhagic fever and meningitis, particularly in urban areas such as Havana and Santiago. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination should be considered. If bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cuba is considered to have a moderate risk of Zika virus transmission. The mosquito-borne illness can be spread from a pregnant woman to her unborn baby as well as through sexual contact. The World Health Organisation recommend travellers to Cuba protect themselves from mosquito bites and suggests wearing clothes (preferably light-coloured) that cover as much of the body as possible, sleeping under mosquito nets and using repellents that contain DEET (diethyltoluamide), IR 3535 ((3- [N-butyl-N-acetyl], aminopropionic acid ethyl-ester) or KBR3023 (also called Icaridin or Picaridin). Pregnant women are advised to consider postponing non-essential travel until after pregnancy and pregnant women whose sexual partners live in or travel to areas with Zika virus transmission should follow safe sexual practices or abstain from sex for the duration of their pregnancy. Women who are pregnant, at risk of getting pregnant, or planning pregnancy should seek pre-travel advice from their health care provider 6-8 weeks in advance of travel.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Liberation Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Victory of Armed Forces Day :
							2018<br/>02 January </p><p>May Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							20 May </p><p>National Rebellion Day :
							25 July </p><p>Anniversary of the Beginning of the War of Independence in 1868 :
							10 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Cuba by travellers aged 18 years and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 3L alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; Laptop for personal use.<br />
&bull; Gifts up to a value of CUC$50.99.<br />
&bull; Medicines required for personal use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include animal products, explosives, certain household appliances, and all pornographic material and drugs.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Restricted items requiring authorisation include firearms and ammunition, light motor vehicles, live animals and plants and their parts, certain foodstuffs, and works of art.</p>
<p>Note that electrical items with heavy power consumption may be confiscated and returned upon departure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drugs, explosives, pornography, items of cultural value, manuscripts dating from  between 1440 and 1500, library books, books edited by Libros Cubanos under the 'R' imprint, foreign editions published between the 16th and 18th centuries, Cuban editions published in the 18th century, and lobster in any form or quantity.</p>
<p>Note that if taking cigars out of Cuba, you may take up to 50 cigars. These must be unopened and sealed in their original packaging and you must be able to show a receipt proving you bought them in an authorised shop, otherwise they will be seized. The export of raw tobacco and supplies used in the tobacco industry is strictly prohibited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Convertible Peso (CUC; symbol CUC$ or $) = 100 centavos. Notes are in denominations of CUC$100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 3 and 1. Coins are in denominations of CUC$1, and 50, 25, 10, 5, and 1 centavos. <br />
<br />
<strong>Note:</strong>   US Dollars are no longer accepted in Cuba and visitors will be charged 10% commission on exchanging them. In the 1990s, Cuba decided to slowly get rid of its Dollar reserves, banning the currency from general use and introduced the replacement CUC as a convertible currency under its control. CUCs cannot be purchased or exchanged outside of Cuba. Cuban nationals continue to be paid in the Cuban Peso (CUP; symbol CUP$ or $). In some tourist areas, the Euro is also accepted. Hard currency (ie CUCs not CUPs) must be used in most transactions. As of March 2011, 1CUC=1USD.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money should be exchanged at banks or state-run CADECAs. You will be required to present your passport at all Cadecas and Banks when exchanging money. Dollars attract a 10% surcharge on top of the normal commission (US citizens should bring Euros or Sterling to exchange). All local currency must be exchanged again before leaving the country. Card transactions attract a surcharge (of up to 12.5%) - see below.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mastercard and Visa are increasingly accepted, provided they are not issued by a US bank, or a bank with links to the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, but hefty fees are often added. ATMs are more common but not ubiquitous. However, cash can be obtained in banks and Cadecas with non-US Visa credit and Visa debit cards.<br />
<br />
Since June 2016, two American issued Mastercard debit/credits cards have been accepted in Cuba: Stonegate Bank and Banco Popular de Puerto Rico.</p><p>ATMs are more common but not ubiquitous, but cash can be obtained in banks and Cadecas (Casas de Cambio) with non-US Visa credit and Visa debit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar, Pounds Sterling and other major currencies are accepted; US Dollar cheques issued by US banks are not accepted but American Express travellers cheques issued by non-US banks can be exchanged, though not everywhere. It is recommended to take cheques in a currency other than US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1200 and 1330-1600, Sat 0830-1200. Hours may vary and banks may be open all day in larger cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for two months beyond the proposed duration of stay is required for British nationals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parents travelling with children may be required to show proof of parental rights or guardianship.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist card: &pound;39 (you can only apply by post and the application form is <a href="http://misiones.minrex.gob.cu/sites/default/files/formularios/editorreinounido/application_form_for_tourist_card.pdf">here</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The tourist card is valid for one entry of 30 days within 180 days of issue and can be extended in Cuba for a further 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy) in person or by post. Please note that in the UK, you can only apply it by post and <a href="http://misiones.minrex.gob.cu/sites/default/files/formularios/editorreinounido/application_form_for_tourist_card_0_0.pdf">use this official form for your tourist card</a>. If you aren't in the UK, you can obtain application forms for tourist visa cards from certain tour operators and travel agents or from the consulate/embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow up to four weeks for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend your tourist card by an additional 30 days with the immigration department.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bringing pets to Cuba is possible, but it can be time consuming and costly. You need an international (or in the case of licensed travellers from the USA, a state) veterinary certificate, completed no more than 10 days before travel to Cuba, along with proof of a rabies and distemper vaccination administrated at least 30 days before entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[22.102995]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-79.014016]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110,860 sq km (42,803 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>11,392,889 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>99.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Havana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Socialist Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cuba is the largest Caribbean island, about the size of England, and the most westerly of the Greater Antilles group, lying  a mere 145km (90 miles) south of Florida.</p>
<p>A quarter of the country is fairly mountainous. West of Havana is the narrow Sierra de los  &Oacute;rganos, rising to 750m (2,461ft) and containing the Guaniguanico hills in the west. South of the Sierra is a narrow strip of 2,320 sq km (860 sq miles) where the finest Cuban tobacco is grown.</p>
<p>The Sierra de Escambray and Monta&ntilde;as de Guamuhaya behind Trinidad in the centre of the country rise to 1,140m (3,740ft) Encircling the port of Santiago are the rugged mountains of the Sierra Maestra. A quarter of the island is covered with mountain forests of pine and mahogany. Cuba has few rivers of note, the exception being the R&iacute;o Cauto in the east. The country has 3,735km (2,321 miles) of coastline and thousands of offshore islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Technically a Roman Catholic majority, though the percentage drops precipitously for practicing Catholics. A variety of Afro-Cuban religions like Santería and Abakuá are widely practiced.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While handshakes are used in more formal settings, in almost all other situations, the typical greeting in Cuba is one kiss on the right cheek. A handshake is the normal form of greeting. Cubans generally address each other as <em>compa&ntilde;ero</em>, but visitors should use <em>se&ntilde;or </em>or <em>se&ntilde;ora</em>. <br />
<br />
Some Cubans have two surnames after their Christian name; the first surname is the correct one to use. Normal courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home, and a small gift may be given if invited for a meal. Cuban men rarely wear shorts away from the beach. Visitors doing so are not frowned upon, but they may receive the odd sideways glance. Women should cover their legs and shoulders if visiting churches. Cuban women tend to dress up for evenings out. Cubans of all classes like to dress up (especially for evenings out) and tourists are often seen as underdressed as a result. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110/220 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without round grounding pin) are generally used; you may need an adaptor if your plug has three pins however. Some large hotels also have 220-volt outlets accepting European plugs with two round pins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Miguel D&iacute;az-Canel since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Miguel D&iacute;az-Canel since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When Columbus reached Cuba in 1492, declaring it &ldquo;the most beautiful land human eyes have ever seen,&rdquo; he encountered three indigenous groups: the Siboney, Guanahatabey and Taino. Although all three were virtually wiped out within 50 years, Siboney and Taino remain popular terms in Cuba still.<br />
<br />
In addition to disease, the Spanish and French settlers who followed brought with them sugarcane and later slaves and the island&rsquo;s racial make up is a mosaic of these separate waves of human inhabitation.<br />
<br />
Two wars of independence defined 19th century Cuba. The first, between 1868 and 1878, ended in stalemate; the second, in which poet and revolutionary Jos&eacute; Mart&iacute; inspired the rebels, began in 1895 and ended when the USA was drawn into the war in 1898. Cuba was occupied for two years by American forces and even after their withdrawal the USA maintained effective political and economic control of the island, propping up a series of corrupt dictators including Fulgencio Batista. Then came Fidel Castro and his rebel army, which overturned the hugely corrupt Batista government in 1959, establishing a socialist state. All US businesses were expropriated in 1960 and diplomatic relations were broken by the USA as Cuba accelerated relations with the Soviet Union in the face of an American economic and financial blockade of the island.<br />
<br />
In 1961, the CIA organised a corps of anti-Castro rebels to invade the island. The Bay of Pigs invasion was a complete fiasco; all the invaders were captured or killed and US involvement was quickly revealed. The following year, Soviet missiles capable of hitting targets in the USA were installed on Cuba and Kennedy ordered a naval blockade against the island. The confrontation escalated to the threshold of nuclear war, before Kennedy and Khrushchev reached a settlement.<br />
<br />
When the Eastern Bloc dissolved in 1989, Cuba experienced an extraordinarily difficult economic period, but in the new millennium, it pulled back from the economic abyss and in recent years has moved closer to both China and the United States. In 2016, a year after diplomatic relations were restored, Barack Obama became the first sitting US President to visit Cuba since Coolidge in 1928.</p>
<p>Fidel Castro resigned as President in 2008 in favour of his brother Ra&uacute;l, who has announced he will also step down in 2018.&nbsp;Fidel's death&nbsp;in November 2016 was followed by nine days of national mourning. The revolutionary politician&nbsp;had survived more than 600 assassination plots to become the longest serving non-royal leader of the 20th Century.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p><span style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); color: rgb(84, 84, 84); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small;">☻&nbsp;</span>Cuba has tripled its share of Caribbean tourism since the turn of the century.</p>
<p><span style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); color: rgb(84, 84, 84); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small;">☻&nbsp;</span>The sale of computer equipment is heavily regulated, access is controlled and email messages closely monitored.</p>
<p><span style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255); color: rgb(84, 84, 84); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small;">☻&nbsp;</span>Culture is a key part of Cuban life and the government supports a range of arts organisations from the classical Ballet Nacional de Cuba to the hip hop Agencia Cuban de Rap.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Cuba]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+53 7 214 2200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukincuba.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+53 7 214 2200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0800-1615. Due to security considerations, public access is by appointment only. Telephone: Mon-Thurs 0800-1600; Fri 0800-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Miramar<br/>Calle 34, no. 702 e/7ma y 17<br/>Havana<br/>11300<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[US Embassy in Cuba]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+53 7 839 4100</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://cu.usembassy.gov</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+53 7 839 4100</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1630; Fri 0800-1530. Public access by appointment only. Telephone: Mon-Thurs 0900-1000 and 1400-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Vedado<br/>Calzada<br/>Havana<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Cuba in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>020 7240 2488; 020 7420 3100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://misiones.minrex.gob.cu/en/united-kingdom/embassy-cuba-united-kingdom</p><p><b>Tel:</b>020 7240 2488; 020 7420 3100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1230 and 1400-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>167 High Holborn<br/>London<br/>WC1V 6PA<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Cuban Tourist Board in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7240 6655.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.travel2cuba.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7240 6655.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>167 High Holborn (Embassy of Cuba)<br/>London<br/>WC1V 6PA<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Immaculate beaches and verdant hills, wildlife-rich rainforests and tumbling waterfalls, imposing mountain ranges and vibrant cities, all wrapped in defiantly Revolutionary politics; the island of Cuba can rightfully claim to be one of the most singular destinations on the planet.</p>
<p>The largest and most populous island in the Caribbean, Cuba's 1959 socialist revolution and the subsequent US trade embargo has frozen the island in time; vintage American cars still roar through the ramshackle streets of its cities, while horses and carts clatter through the countryside.</p>
<p>The capital, Havana, serves up a heady mix of dilapidation and debauchery. It is a city where beautifully restored colonial buildings rub shoulders with the rundown tenements of regular Cubans. The contrasts can be stark, but Havana&rsquo;s ubiquitous salsa rhythms, uninhibited dancing and potent cocktails galvanise the city and make for an enthralling urban experience unlike any other.</p>
<p>Cuba&rsquo;s other cities are experiences in themselves. Santiago de Cuba is a veritable melting pot of Afro-Caribbean cultures, where pastel covered buildings meet grand cathedrals. And then there&rsquo;s Trinidad, which offers a snapshot of a bygone era with its cobblestone streets, faded colonial fa&ccedil;ades and charming courtyards.</p>
<p>Delightful though these cities are, for many visitors Cuba&rsquo;s greatest allure is its beaches. Christopher Columbus described the sandy coast of Guardalavaca as &ldquo;the most beautiful land I have ever seen,&rdquo; and you can see why he was so taken &ndash; the improbably white sands and warm turquoise waters are exquisite. Others prefer to head inland and gaze upon the verdant, limestone peaks of Vi&ntilde;ales, where Cuba&rsquo;s famous tobacco is cultivated.</p>
<p>As Cuba slowly opens up to the West, modern resorts have become increasingly common, but the most rewarding stays are in <em>casa particulares</em>. These private homestays offer a true insight into everyday Cuban life, which you won&rsquo;t get in a hotel.</p>
<p>Though travelling around Cuba can be challenging, the country&rsquo;s affable climate, captivating history, beautiful beaches, swinging salsa rhythms and ubiquitous mojitos are fair compensation indeed.</p><p>Immaculate beaches and verdant hills, wildlife-rich rainforests and tumbling waterfalls, imposing mountain ranges and vibrant cities, all wrapped in defiantly Revolutionary politics; the island of Cuba can rightfully claim to be one of the most singular destinations on the planet.&nbsp;The largest and most populous island in the Caribbean, Cuba's 1959 socialist revolution and the subsequent US trade embargo has frozen the island in time; vintage American cars still roar through the ramshackle streets of its cities, while horses and carts clatter through the countryside.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
