<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Cyprus" ColCode="cyp" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="cy" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Cyprus]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cyprus has a sub-tropical climate with sunshine likely on most days of the year. Spring and autumn are pleasantly warm, while summer days are long, dry and hot with temperatures reaching the high 30s and even 40s. The heat is tempered by sea breezes in coastal areas. Winters are mild with often heavy, although sporadic, tropical-style rainstorms. Villages located on higher ground are often subjected to freezing temperatures and frost, while heavy snowfall is experienced in the interior Troodos  Mountains and usually stays for several weeks, giving good ski conditions.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The best time to visit for those who like the heat is June, July and August, although the intense sun can make sightseeing a challenge. Drinking lots of bottled water is essential to avoid dehydration. September to January, and April to May, tend to be quieter and are ideal for exploring the island and enjoying pursuits such as cycling and hiking. The ski season generally runs from early February to March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pack lightweight, cotton clothing for the summer months, such as loose tops, shorts and linen trousers, along with a hat to protect against the sun. Warmer medium-weight clothing is ideal for spring, autumn and sunny winter days, together with cardigans or jackets for evening which can get very cold. Rainwear should be packed for winter visits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exploring the island by car is the best way to get around. Cyprus&rsquo;s road infrastructure is excellent. The result is a traffic jam-free motorway drive that takes you from Paphos in the east straight into Limassol and on to the centre of Nicosia, plus a branch heading off to Larnaca, Agia Napa and Protaras. Driving in the Troodos Mountains is good, albeit with roads that zig-zag around ravines. Off-road driving should only be done with a suitable vehicle.</p>
<p>Drivers wishing to reach the north of Cyprus need to cross the border, known as the Green Line, at one of five designated checkpoints (there are a further two checkpoints in Nicosia for pedestrians only). The Green Line is controlled by UN forces. The five crossings are Limnitis at Kato Pygros, Astromeritis near Morphou, Agios Dometios in Nicosia, Pergamos at Pyla and Strovilia near Agios Nikolaos. In Nicosia you can cross on foot at the Ledra Palace checkpoint and Ledra Street in the centre of the city.</p>l<p>Motorways and main roads are of a high standard. Inner city and smaller town roads are generally good, but infrastructure upgrades have resulted in uneven surfaces. Roads in villages are often poor. All roads are toll free.</p><p>Private coach companies operate in all the main cities and offer day excursions.</p><p>There are three types of taxi service in south Cyprus: urban, trans-urban, which are shared and can be booked, and rural. Taxis are safe and relatively inexpensive. In north Cyprus, taxis are available in the main towns only. Fares are regulated by the government and all taxis have meters. Shared taxis operate every 30 minutes between major cities. Rural taxis can only be hired from the base station and do not have a meter.</p><p>An International Driving Permit or national driving licence is required for driving in Cyprus.</p><p>The maximum speed limit is 100kph (62mph) on highways, 80kph (50mph) on most other roads and 30-50kph (19-31mph) in built-up areas. There are strict repercussions for anyone not wearing a seat belt or crash helmet, using a mobile phone or being under the influence of alcohol whilst driving. Children under the age of five must not sit in the front passenger seat, and must be strapped into a child seat fitted to the rear.</p><p>Car hire companies offer a comprehensive breakdown service as part of their agreement.</p><p>Cyprus has car hire companies with offices in the airports and towns, including major names like Hertz and Europcar. Cars should be reserved well in advance during the summer season. You should be sure to check your agreement if you are planning to take a hired car across the Green Line as not all hire companies in the south permit taking their vehicles to north Cyprus. The minimum driving age is 18, but drivers often need to be 21 years old and to have held a valid licence for three years to hire a car.</p><p>Cyprus encourages cycling and bikes are available for hire from most hotels.</p><p>The maximum speed limit is 100kph (62mph) on highways, 80kph (50mph) on most other roads and 30-50kph (19-31mph) in built-up areas. There are strict repercussions for anyone not wearing a seat belt or crash helmet, using a mobile phone or being under the influence of alcohol whilst driving. Children under the age of five must not sit in the front passenger seat, and must be strapped into a child seat fitted to the rear.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buses are modern, reliable and inexpensive.  There are four types of service: urban buses that run around town, trans-urban buses that link major towns, rural buses to service the villages and a shuttle between the airports at Larnaca and Paphos. In north Cyprus, buses run between Nicosia and the main towns. Taxis are more expensive. Fares are regulated by the government and all taxis have meters. A 15% surcharge is in operation from 2300-0600. Tipping is expected.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cyprus</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">pafos</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cyprus</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">limassol</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cyprus</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">larnaca</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Cyprus</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ayia_napa</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cyprus is served by international airlines that fly direct to Larnaca International Airport and Paphos International Airport from around the world. Numerous airlines fly from the UK&nbsp;to Cyprus include Aegean (<a href="http://www.aegeanair.com" target="_blank">www.aegeanair.com</a>), Cobalt Air (<a href="http://cobalt.aero" target="cobalt.aero">cobalt.aero</a>), Blue Air (<a href="http://www.blueairweb.com" target="_blank">www.blueairweb.com</a>), British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>), Monarch (<a href="http://www.monarch.co.uk" target="_blank">www.monarch.co.uk</a>), Norwegian (<a href="http://www.norwegian.com" target="_blank">www.norwegian.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>).</p>
<p>All flights to the north arrive at Ercan International Airport in north Nicosia via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey">Turkey</a>. Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>) is the Turkish national carrier, with Pegasus Airlines (<a href="http://www.flypgs.com" target="_blank">www.flypgs.com</a>) and Atlasglobal (<a href="http://www.atlasglb.com" target="_blank">www.atlasglb.com</a>) among the companies offering flights to north Cyprus.&nbsp;</p>
<p>While Cyprus is a year-round destination that can boast of attracting tourists who like to relax on the beach in the morning and ski on snow in the afternoon, at least during the month of February, many airlines offer limited flights during the winter. July and August are the most expensive months to fly, while bargains can be found in winter, early spring and late autumn.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cyprus/paphos-international-airport">Paphos International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cyprus/larnaca-international-airport">Larnaca International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>: to Paphos and Larnaca&nbsp;-&nbsp;4 hours 30 minutes; to Ercan in north Nicosia, via Turkey - 6 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since 1974, the Cyprus government declared Ercan International Airport an illegal port of entry to Cyprus and there are no direct flights other than from Turkey. However, tourists can now fly into the south and travel by road across the border in Nicosia to holiday in the north.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since 1974, the Cyprus government declared Ercan International Airport an illegal port of entry to Cyprus and there are no direct flights other than from Turkey. However, tourists can now fly into the south and travel by road across the border in Nicosia to holiday in the north.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Larnaca International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.hermesairports.com<p>Larnaca International Airport is situated 5km (3 miles) south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/larnaca">Larnaca</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+357 7777 8833</p>]]><b>Paphos International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.hermesairports.com<p>Paphos International Airport is located 15km (9.5 miles) east of central Paphos.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>7777 8833.</p>]]><b>Ercan Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.ercanairport.co.uk<p>The airport is 8km (5miles) east of Nicosia, in the north.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cyprus has a growing number of marinas that welcome visiting yachtspeople. Larnaca&rsquo;s marina is the largest.</p><p>Since 1974, the Cyprus government has declared the ports of Famagusta (Ammochostos) and Kyrenia, both in the north of the island, as illegal ports of entry to Cyprus.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Telecard or coin-operated public telephones are installed at various central locations in towns and villages. Call Direct (cheaper than ordinary collect calls) is available to most EU countries, as well as Australia, USA and Canada.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes are located in the main towns and resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Cypriot media reflects the island's political divide with the south and the Turkish-controlled north operating their own press and broadcasters. The media on both sides of the divide are frequently critical of the authorities. Newspapers published in English include the <em>Cyprus Mail</em>, <em>Cyprus Weekly </em><em>and Cyprus Today</em> (Turkish Cypriot). Most English newspapers are available.</p>
<p>State-run services compete with private TV and radio stations. The public Cyprus Broadcasting Corporation (CyBC) operates TV channels RIK 1 and RIK 2, and Radio 1 (in Greek), Radio 2 (in English, Turkish and Armenian), and Radio 3 (in Greek) in the south. In northern Cyprus, Bayrak Radio-TV operates channels BRT 1 and BRT 2, and Bayrak Radio 1 (in Turkish) and Bayrak International (in English).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are daily airmail services to all developed countries. Service within Europe takes three to four days, and four to five days to the US.</p><p>(District) Sep-Jun: Mon-Fri 0730-1330, Wed 1500-1730 and Sat 0900-1030; Jul-Aug: Mon-Fri 0730-1300 and Sat 0900-1030. Other post office opening hours: Mon-Fri 0730-1330, Thurs 1500-1800 at other times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Kykkos Monastery</p><![CDATA[<p>Kykkos Monastery is the largest and most famous monastery in Cyprus. Founded in AD1100 by the Byzantine emperor Alexios Komnenos, the monastery is dedicated to the Virgin Mary and is home to one of the three surviving icons painted by the Apostle Luke. Kykkos Monastery is ornately decorated and covered in a silver gilt, enclosed in a tortoiseshell shrine. It is also famous for its museum, located within the monastery grounds, which houses an impressive collection of icons, woodcarvings and manuscripts, and other Cypriot antiquities. The nearby Troodos Mountains, with magnificent hills and valleys, should also be explored as they are home to nine Byzantine churches, included on UNESCO's World Heritage list, and richly decorated with murals and Byzantine paintings.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the craftsmanship of Cyprus’s Painted Churches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Byzantine churches and monasteries of the Troodos Mountains are protected as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, in recognition of their extraordinary frescoes and mosaics. Perhaps the most spectacular are Agios Nikolaos tis Stegis at Kakopetria with frescos from the 11th century, and the Church of Archangelos Michael in Pedoulas, with its floor-to-ceiling frescoes of the Archangel Michael.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy sun, sea and sand in Agia Napa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once the hedonistic party capital of Cyprus, Agia Napa (Ayia Napa) has 'grown up' in recent years, with a growing number of more sophisticated nightspots, restaurants and cultural venues, as well as the lively beach clubs that still attract hordes of young 20-somethings on tour. The resort also has some of the best beaches and diving opportunities on the island.</p>]]><p><b>Escape to the Akamas Peninsula</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its rugged unspoiled landscape and sandy bays, the Akamas Peninsula is a wonderful place to escape and be at one with nature. Rough dirt roads run around the isthmus from the harbour at Agios Georgios, north of Paphos, to Chrysochou Bay near Polis. The peninsula is home to many species of birds and flowers and rare sea turtles nest here every summer.</p>]]><p><b>Fall in love with Petra tou Romiou</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cyprus was the legendary birthplace of Aphrodite, ancient Greek goddess of love, and this miraculous event has been mapped to Petra tou Romiou (Rock of Aphrodite), a dramatic marble outcrop rising from the turquoise ocean between Limassol and Paphos. Nearby are the imposing ruins of the Temple of Aphrodite, marking the site of the ancient city of Palaipafos.</p>]]><p><b>Find silence and sand on the Karpaz Peninsula</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The most untouched quarter of North Cyprus, the scenic Karpaz peninsula juts east towards Turkey, fringed by some of the most unspoiled beaches on the island, most of which see more nesting sea turtles than tourists. Beyond, at the very tip of the peninsula is the splendidly isolated Orthodox monastery of Apostolos Andreas.</p>]]><p><b>Gaze at Gazimağusa (Famagusta)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The magnificent walled city of Famagusta, in North Cyprus, was a wonder of the ancient world, with towering Frankish churches dotted around its sandstone streets. This was the real-life home of Shakespeare's Othello, and Cyprus's most important port before the 1975 war. Today, the churches are picturesque ruins and the city snoozes quietly within its mighty Venetian city walls.</p>]]><p><b>Get lost in Lefkosia (Nicosia)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Cypriot capital is sliced in two by the Green Line, which divides the island between the Republic of Cyprus in the south and the Turkish Republic of Northern Cyprus in the north. Both sides are studded with ancient mosques, churches and winding streets of stone houses. The historic old town is bound by towering Venetian city walls, and must-see sights include the spectacular Byzantine Art Museum, St John's Cathedral and the Cyprus Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Get lost in Turkish Lefkoşa (Nicosia)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The northern half of the Cypriot capital feels even more lost in time than the Greek half. The focal point of the city is the grand Selimiye Mosque, formerly the Ayia Sofia Cathedral, which was built at around the same time as London's Westminster Cathedral. Easing relations between the two governments mean that jaunts across the border are easy today.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Girne</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once an important Roman and Venetian port, Girne, formerly known as Kyrenia, is one of the jewels of the Mediterranean. Set around a postcard perfect harbour guarded by a vast Venetian fortress, this picturesque town has played witness to most of the significant events in Cypriot history, from Hellenisation to the arrival of the Crusaders. It's probably best known for its castles, one of which houses the remains of a 2,300-year-old merchant ship.</p>]]><p><b>Potter around in peaceful Paphos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The most friendly resort in the republic, pretty Paphos is set around a picturesque harbour, dominated by an imposing medieval fort. During 2017 Paphos can boast with the title &quot;European culture capital&quot;. It's worth visiting during the summer festival when the sound of opera reverberates around the ancient walls. The city is also famous for the Greco-Roman, rock-carved Tombs of the Kings and the immaculate ancient mosaics in the House of Dionysos.</p>]]><p><b>See Byzantine brilliance at Kykkos Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The largest and most famous monastery in Cyprus, Kykkos was founded in AD1100 by the Byzantine emperor Alexios Komnenos. Set in gorgeous pine forests, the monastery is dedicated to the Virgin Mary and is home to one of the three surviving icons painted by the Apostle Luke. It is also renowned for its stunning museum of icons, woodcarvings and manuscripts.</p>]]><p><b>See a forgotten side to Cyprus at the Hala Sultan Tekke</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tucked away near Larnaca International Airport, the Hala Sultan Tekke was once one of the most sacred shrines in the Muslim world, housing the ancient tomb of the aunt of the Prophet Mohammed. Now quietly forgotten, it's a lovely 19th-century Islamic structure, set amidst date palms beside Larnaca's Salt Lake where migratory flamingos stay in winter.</p>]]><p><b>Shop for Lefkara lace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The charming village of Lefkara, between Limassol and Larnaca, is famous for silver filigree and lace. Legend has it the Italian painter Leonardo da Vinci visited Lefkara in the 15th century and purchased some of its <em>lefkaritika </em>lace for the cathedral in Milan, and in doing so secured its fame.</p>]]><p><b>Ski in the Troodos Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Surprisingly for an island squeezed between Greece, Turkey and Egypt, Cyprus has a busy ski season from January to mid March, when the villages of the Troodos Mountains briefly transform into winter resorts. Both Platres and Kakopetria are handy for the ski slopes on Mount Olympus, but Troodos is actually the nearest resort to the skiing area.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll along the promenade in Larnaca</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stretching for 3 km (2 miles) along the seafront, from the marina to Larnaca's Crusader fort, Finikoudes Beach is one of the island's favourite promenades. Visitors stroll beneath the palm trees, pausing at local seafood restaurants or sunbathing on the sand. Inland are fascinating museums, including the impressive Pierides Museum, housing one of the largest private collections in Cyprus.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll around Salamis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As the south has Kourion, so the north has Salamis, the ruins of a sprawling Greco-Roman city that spill out onto a gorgeous sandy beach just north of Famagusta. The site has been somewhat neglected since the island was divided, but the setting is magical, and there's an impressively restored amphitheatre ringed by the ruins of temples, houses and civic buildings.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the wonders of the Cyprus Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Historic treasures have been spilling out of the ground in Cyprus for millennia and many of the finest pieces are proudly displayed in the Cyprus Museum, just outside Lefkosia's city walls. The vast collection includes astonishingly well-preserved Mycenaean pottery, prehistoric Chalcolithic figurines, Egyptian and Roman statues, and carvings from the Royal Tombs at Salamis.</p>]]><p><b>Tramp through the Troodos Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rising in a dramatic ridge along the middle line of the island, the Troodos Mountains are covered in dry pine forests and dotted with medieval winemaking villages and UNESCO-listed Byzantine monasteries. The peaks are criss-crossed by hiking and cycling trails and in winter, locals ski on the snow-covered slopes of Mount Olympus, the island's highest point at 1,952m (6,404ft).</p>]]><p><b>Walk in the footsteps of Aphrodite</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set in the gorgeous surroundings of the Akamas Peninsula, in the far west of the island near Polis Crysoschous, this isolated freshwater pool is where, according to legend, the Greek goddess of love bathed and enjoyed trysts with the god Adonis. Today, the natural beauty of the surrounding countryside is as much of an attraction as the grotto.</p>]]><p><b>Watch the sun go down from Kourion</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rising above the coastal plain on a rocky plateau, Kourin is perhaps the most spectacularly located ancient site in Cyprus. Spanning the ancient Greek and Roman eras, the ruins are centred on a magnificent amphitheatre, and there are numerous recognisable structures, including an <em>agora </em>(marketplace) and the House of Eustolios, with fine 5th century floor mosaics.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$24.9 billion (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Pharmaceuticals, potatoes, citrus fruits, cement and clothing.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Consumer goods, raw materials, machinery, transport equipment and petroleum.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Greece, UK, Germany, Italy and Israel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Figures released in November 2012 show that the Cypriot economy experienced negative growth of 2.3% in the third quarter of 2012 compared to the same quarter in 2011. &nbsp;Inflation stands at 1.7%. The island&rsquo;s economy has suffered since an explosion at the Evangelos Florakis Naval Base in July 2011, which is located next to Cyprus&rsquo;s main electricity power station. It is listed as being the 7<sup>th</sup> largest non-nuclear explosions to have occurred in the world. The electricity station has had to be rebuilt, with the expected final cost to the island of around US$2.83 billion.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Cyprus&rsquo;s market economy is dominated by its service sector, which accounts for around four fifths of the economy. While tourism remains a mainstay of the Cypriot economy, the industry has also been affected by the recent global economic downturn. Tourist arrivals stood at nearly 2.4 million to December 2011 compared with 2.17 million to December 2010. <br />
<br />
The Republic of Cyprus is a full member of the European Union, however negotiations are ongoing for membership to include the internationally unrecognised territory of north Cyprus. The area north of the Green Line depends heavily on tourism and the service industry to form the backbone of its economy and remains heavily reliant on the mainland Turkish economy for support.</p>
<p>Many of the upmarket hotels have conference facilities. Nicosia is a popular destination for budget-priced conferences and has modern facilities. Larnaca, Paphos and Limassol have a number of 5-star hotels with excellent conference and incentive facilities in what is very much a growing market. Advice can be obtained from the Cyprus Tourism Organisation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cypriots prefer face-to-face meetings rather than business via telephone or in writing, which are regarded as too impersonal. Business dress is similar to most European conventions.<br /></p><p>Typical office hours are 0800-1300 and 1500-1800 (winter), and 0800-1300 and 1600-1900 (summer).<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cyprus Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (22) 889 800
					Website:http://www.ccci.org.cy/
					Address: PO Box 21455,38 Grivas Dhigenis Avenue,Chamber Building,Nicosia,1509]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Healthy and hearty, Cypriot cuisine draws its inspiration from both Greece and Turkey. In the south, the cuisine is pure Mediterranean, with an emphasis on fish and pork dishes such as the ubiquitous <em>souvlaki</em> kebab. Cooks make extensive use of the wild thyme that grows across the island, as well as cinnamon, cumin and coriander, showing the influence of the Middle East. Perhaps the most famous Cypriot dish of all is grilled halloumi, a hand-made Cypriot cheese.</p><p>In north Cyprus, the cuisine is effectively Turkish, with lamb replacing pork in grills, stews and soups. Many of the inhabitants of the north are settlers from Anatolia and meaty kebab dishes dominate menus. North and south come together in the <em>mezze</em>, a rambling meal of dips, snacks and tasty small dishes – almost invariably featuring houmous and halloumi – served on both sides of the island.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Afelia: </strong>A Greek Cypriot stew of pork marinated in wine and ground coriander seed. <strong>&nbsp;<br />
</strong><strong>Kleftiko ofto: </strong>Lamb on the bone, slowly roasted with herbs in a sealed clay oven.<br />
<strong>Halloumi: </strong>Cyprus cheese, kneaded by hand and then grilled.<br />
<strong>Dolmades: </strong>Preserved vine leaves stuffed with meat and rice.<br />
<strong>Stifado</strong>: A casserole of beef cooked with wine, vinegar, onion and spices.<br />
<strong>Souvlaki: </strong>The ubiquitous pork kebab of Greek Cyprus.<br />
<strong>Seftalia:</strong> Seasoned pork rissoles, grilled in a skin of caul fat.<br />
<strong>Imam bayildi</strong>: Aubergines stuffed with tomato and onions, a Turkish Cypriot favourite.<br />
<strong>Adana kebabs: </strong>Minced lamb with herbs and red pepper, grilled on metal skewers, from the Adana region of Turkey.<br />
<strong>Tava: </strong>A tasty baked stew of lamb, cumin, onions and potatoes.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Dinner is the most important meal of the day and locals rarely eat before 2000. Seek out local restaurants in the old parts of Lefkosia, Larnaca, Limassol and Girne to find authentic traditional Cypriot cuisine.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 10% service charge is added to all bills, and tipping is discretionary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>17.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a thriving nighttime scene in the capital Nicosia and the coastal towns and cities of Cyprus. Hundreds of restaurants serving everything from Indian cuisine to Italian, French and Chinese, along with wine bars, lively bars with live entertainment, theatres offering classical plays, cinemas and nightclubs are popular with locals as well as visitors. Restaurants and bars line the seafront of places like Larnaca, Paphos and Limassol, and Kyrenia in northern Cyprus.</p>
<p>The party capital of Cyprus remains Agia Napa where youngsters dance until late, even though the resort is seeing a growing number of restaurants and sophisticated nightspots emerging. Hotels and resorts have their own restaurants, bars and nightspots.</p>
<p>Most cities host a regular programme of evening cultural events and festivals. Among the most popular are the Aphrodite operatic festival held in front of the castle in Paphos Harbour and Shakespeare at the Kourion. Casinos are a rarity in Cyprus. While online gambling venues are steadily opening throughout the island, true casinos that offer roulette and poker can be found only in northern Cyprus.</p>
<p>Nightlife in the rural villages tends to revolve around the local taverna, but nonetheless can be a lively affair with traditional music and dances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cypriot purchases include handmade lace, woven curtains and tablecloths, silks, basketwork, pottery, silverware and leather goods. Lefkara lace, known as <em>lefkaritika</em>, is famous throughout the world as one of the products most closely associated with Cypriot workmanship. It is intricately patterned and used for tablecloths and table mats. Women can be seen working in small workshops in the village Lefkara after which the lace is named. The village is located on a hill just off the Nicosia-Limassol highway. The Troodos village  of Omodos also has a thriving lace industry. Lefkara is also famous for its silverwork; traditionally the men of the village would work with silver while the women produced lace. Silver spoons and forks are a traditional symbol of Cypriot hospitality.</p>
<p>Jewellery is an art which has been practised on the island since the Mycenaean Greek period; craftspeople working in contemporary and traditional styles produce some very fine pieces. Filigree silver is a popular gift or souvenir. Local wines, including Commandaria, which is one of the oldest wines in the world and produced in region north of Limassol, and Cyprus&rsquo;s own brandy and its potent Zivania liqueur also make good purchases. Imported goods sell at competitive prices, including cameras, perfume, porcelain and crystal. In north Cyprus, embroidered tablecloths and cushions with patterns traditional to Turkey are widely available.</p>
<p>Throughout the island, monasteries sell icons, which are often painted by the monks themselves. The Monastery of Chrysorrogiatissa in the foothills of the Troodos is one of several that has its own icon studio.</p><p>In summer (June to August) shops are open 0800-1400 and 1700-2030. In winter opening hours are 0800-1300 and 1430-1800 (until 1900 in spring and autumn). However many larger department stores and supermarkets, and shops in tourist areas, do not close for lunch. Shops are closed Wednesday and Saturday after 1300, as well as all day Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cyprus has a wide choice of accommodation to suit all budgets and tastes. It boasts some beautiful luxury five-star hotels and holiday resorts with facilities that include pools, playgrounds and even bowling alleys, to hotel apartments, villas, rural guesthouses and agro-tourism stone houses.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>Most of the top-end hotels - those with a four-star or five-star rating - can be found in Limassol, Larnaca and Paphos and include international restaurants, some of the best<strong> </strong>thalassotherapy spas in the Mediterranean region, infinity pools, bars and even golf courses. In Nicosia, the upmarket hotels are geared more towards business with conference and meeting facilities.</p>
<p>North Cyprus has a growing number of higher graded hotels with a range of facilities that often include a casino. In the Troodos  Mountains, a handful of hotels provide a great base for hiking and cycling enthusiasts, as do the many converted village houses that have been turned into guesthouses or agro-tourism accommodation.</p>
<p>Most hotels and hotel apartments in seaside resorts offer discounts during the low season - generally November to March &ndash; while mountain resorts can represent excellent value for money with special rates in the winter months. There are often discounts for children occupying the same room as their parents, and some hotels may only charge 80% of the daily room rate for single occupancy of a double room.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Cyprus are graded deluxe 5-star to 1-star, while hotel apartments and guesthouses are classified A, B or C.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The trend for bed and breakfast accommodation has largely bypassed Cyprus, with mainly private entrepreneurs offering this option. Most bed and breakfast guesthouses are located in the rural regions of Limassol, Paphos and Larnaca, in the Akamas and in the Troodos Mountains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cyprus has a wide choice of accommodation to suit all budgets and tastes. It boasts some beautiful luxury five-star hotels and holiday resorts with facilities that include pools, playgrounds and even bowling alleys, to hotel apartments, villas, rural guesthouses and agro-tourism stone houses.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>Most of the top-end hotels - those with a four-star or five-star rating - can be found in Limassol, Larnaca and Paphos and include international restaurants, some of the best<strong> </strong>thalassotherapy spas in the Mediterranean region, infinity pools, bars and even golf courses. In Nicosia, the upmarket hotels are geared more towards business with conference and meeting facilities.</p>
<p>North Cyprus has a growing number of higher graded hotels with a range of facilities that often include a casino. In the Troodos  Mountains, a handful of hotels provide a great base for hiking and cycling enthusiasts, as do the many converted village houses that have been turned into guesthouses or agro-tourism accommodation.</p>
<p>Most hotels and hotel apartments in seaside resorts offer discounts during the low season - generally November to March &ndash; while mountain resorts can represent excellent value for money with special rates in the winter months. There are often discounts for children occupying the same room as their parents, and some hotels may only charge 80% of the daily room rate for single occupancy of a double room.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Cyprus are graded deluxe 5-star to 1-star, while hotel apartments and guesthouses are classified A, B or C.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cyprus has a wide choice of accommodation to suit all budgets and tastes. It boasts some beautiful luxury five-star hotels and holiday resorts with facilities that include pools, playgrounds and even bowling alleys, to hotel apartments, villas, rural guesthouses and agro-tourism stone houses.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p>Most of the top-end hotels - those with a four-star or five-star rating - can be found in Limassol, Larnaca and Paphos and include international restaurants, some of the best<strong> </strong>thalassotherapy spas in the Mediterranean region, infinity pools, bars and even golf courses. In Nicosia, the upmarket hotels are geared more towards business with conference and meeting facilities.</p>
<p>North Cyprus has a growing number of higher graded hotels with a range of facilities that often include a casino. In the Troodos  Mountains, a handful of hotels provide a great base for hiking and cycling enthusiasts, as do the many converted village houses that have been turned into guesthouses or agro-tourism accommodation.</p>
<p>Most hotels and hotel apartments in seaside resorts offer discounts during the low season - generally November to March &ndash; while mountain resorts can represent excellent value for money with special rates in the winter months. There are often discounts for children occupying the same room as their parents, and some hotels may only charge 80% of the daily room rate for single occupancy of a double room.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Cyprus are graded deluxe 5-star to 1-star, while hotel apartments and guesthouses are classified A, B or C.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Free emergency treatment is offered to all international tourists at the island&amp;rsquo;s government hospitals&amp;rsquo; Accident and Emergency Department. Further free or reduced-cost medical treatment is available to European residents who should produce a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC) issued by their country of residence&amp;rsquo;s health authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that a European Health Insurance Card (EHIC) is not valid in the Turkish part of Cyprus. It is also advisable to check the working of any private medical insurance policy you purchase to ensure it is valid in north Cyprus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All visitors are advised to purchase additional medical insurance for the duration of their stay, and should have access to funds to cover the cost of treatments. Receipts are issued to reclaim costs back from your insurance company. The island has private medical centres where health and cosmetic treatments are offered. They can be found in all the main towns. Dental services are not free and visitors should have medical insurance that covers emergency treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Milk is pasteurised and tap water is generally safe to drink. Bottled water is widely available from supermarkets and kiosks. As with all destinations, it is advisable to eat well-cooked fish and meat, especially chicken and pork which are staples on all hotel and restaurant menus. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit washed in fresh water or peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Cyprus temperatures can be high and the sun's rays strong, especially in the summer months. It is advisable to stay out of the sun around midday and wear a hat, sunglasses and a good, high factor sunscreen at all times to protect your skin against sunburn. Drink plenty of water to avoid dehydration.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Clean Monday :
							19 February </p><p>Greek Independence Day :
							25 March </p><p>Greek Cypriot National Day :
							01 April </p><p>Greek Orthodox Good Friday :
							06 April </p><p>Greek Orthodox Easter Monday :
							09 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Kataklysmos (Pentecost) :
							27 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							01 October </p><p>Greek National Day (Ochi Day) :
							28 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cyprus is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices. There are no allowance restrictions on these tax-free items.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Cyprus by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits (over 22% volume) or 2L of fortified wine or sparkling wine.<br />
&bull; 4L of still wine.<br />
&bull; 16L&nbsp;of beer.<br />
&bull; Goods in addition to the above up to the value of &euro;430 (reduced to &euro;175 for travellers under 15 years of age).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drugs, obscene materials, flick knives and daggers, counterfeit and pirated goods, goods used for illegal hunting of game, and firearms and ammunition.</p>
<p>Restricted goods requiring authorisation include plants, animals and animal products, meat, fish, cheese, honey, precious metals, hunting guns and cartridges, sporting pistols and telecommunications equipment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All items prohibited from import are also prohibited from export.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Restricted exports include antiquities and wild flora and fauna.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The currency in the Republic of Cyprus is the Euro (EUR;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a> symbol &euro;) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.  The currency used in north Cyprus is the Turkish Lira (TL; symbol ₺ ) = 100 kuruş. Notes are in denominations of  ₺200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of ₺1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 kuruş. Euros, Pound Sterling and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars are generally accepted in the north.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Non-Cypriot currency can be bought and sold at banks in Nicosia and other large towns in both the south and north.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major credit cards, such as Visa, MasterCard, Diners Club and American Express, are accepted at larger restaurants and shops, and in hotels. Smaller shops, such as those in villages, and rural tavernas are unlikely to accept credit cards. Entry to museums and tourist attractions are payable in cash. As of early 2013 credit and debit cards may be less accepted, due to ongoing capital controls imposed on banks.</p><p>There are reliable ATMs in main towns and tourist areas. As of early 2013, withdrawals from Cypriot banks are limited due to the ongoing capital controls imposed on banks throughout the country. Carrying cash, rather than relying on cards, is recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cheques may be cashed in all banks. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South Cyprus: Mon-Fri 0815-1330. North Cyprus: Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1400-1600. Banks are closed on public holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Cyprus, a passport valid for three months from the date of return (non-EU visitors) or for the duration of stay (EU visitors)&nbsp;is required, except for (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals&nbsp;who hold a valid national ID card, provided there is a photograph.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Children under 18 who do require a visa must provide a certified letter of consent from both parents and/or legal guardians.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals of some countries (but not those listed above) must obtain a transit visa; check with the consulate for a list.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cyprus is not part of the Schengen area. However, Schengen visa holders are allowed to enter Cyprus without obtaining an additional short-stay visa, provided they have already used the Schengen visa to enter another country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: &euro;20; double- or multiple-entry visa: &euro;60; transit visa: &euro;15.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are usually valid for 90 days within a 180-day period. Certain nationals can apply for a three-year multiple-entry visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nearest embassy or high commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors may stay for 90 days before seeking temporary residency. Applications should be made to the Ministry of Interior of the Republic of Cyprus.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least five working days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Proof of funds to cover repatriation costs is required when granting visas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Apply to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs for visa renewal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets should have a passport or animal health certificate, plus a vaccination certificate (to include rabies) if entering from a non-EU country. Pets arriving from within the EU require a pet passport, microchip and rabies vaccination certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[35.051012]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[33.294992]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>9,251 sq km (3,572 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,205,575 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>128.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nicosia (Greek: Lefkosia; Turkish: Lefkoşa).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cyprus is the third-largest island in the Mediterranean and lies to the east at a point where European, Asian and Middle Eastern cultures merge. To the east of the island is Syria and Lebanon, while to the southeast is Israel and to the west is Greece and its Dodecanese group of islands. North of Cyprus is Turkey and to the south Egypt.</p>
<p>The island&rsquo;s landscape varies between rugged coastlines with dramatic gorges, bays and sandy beaches, rocky hills, flat plains, river valleys and forest-covered mountains. The Troodos Mountains dominate the interior of the island. Its highest peak is Mount  Olympus at 1,952m (6,400ft) above sea level. North of Nicosia and following a course towards the barren Karpasia Peninsula runs the mountain range of Pentadaktylos, meaning five fingers after its shape. Between the two is the fertile Mesaoria plain where produce is grown.;</p>
<p>To the west of the island is the Akamas peninsula, a thickly wooded area that runs from Agios Georgios around headland to Latsi near Polis. It is home to a vast variety of flora and fauna, many species of which are endemic to Cyprus. &nbsp;In north Cyprus the Morphou basin runs around the coast of Morphou Bay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greek Orthodox is the main religion of Cyprus, with Islam the most prominent in the north.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The family, which includes the extended family, is at the centre of Cypriot society. Particular respect is shown to elders. It is not uncommon to see great, great relatives cradling tiny babies, especially at family occasions and festivals. Religious beliefs are also at the core of society and all members of the family are expected to attend church regularly.</p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a>
<p>It is customary to shake hands when greeting, irrespective of whether you have just met or have known the person a long time. Normal courtesies should also be observed. It is viewed as impolite to refuse an offer of Greek coffee or a cold drink. For most occasions, casual attire is acceptable. Beachwear should be confined to the beach or poolside. More formal wear is required for business, and in more exclusive dining rooms and social functions.<br />
<strong><br />
</strong>Photography is forbidden near military camps or installations. A licence from the appropriate authorities is required to photograph museum artefacts - this can sometimes be purchased from the museum's ticket desk. No flash photography is allowed in churches with murals or icons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South: President Nikos Anastasiade since 2013. North: President Mustafa Akinci since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Nicos Anastasiades  since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cyprus has a long history that incorporates nearly 12,000 years of human activity. It was first inhabited by Neolithic man and subsequently settled by the Mycenaean Greeks, before being conquered in turn by the Assyrians, Egyptians and Persians then seized by Alexander the Great in 333 BC.</p>
<p>It was incorporated into the Classical Roman Empire then the Eastern Byzantine Empire and following a brief rule by Arab caliphates fell to the English King Richard I. A year later he sold it to the Knights Templar, who in turn flogged it to the French Lusignans before the Venetians assumed control in the late 15th century. They held it until 1570 when an all-out assault brought it under control of the Ottoman Empire where it remained for three centuries before being leased to Great Britain in 1878.</p>
<p>Being close to the Suez Canal, the main route to India, under British rule Cyprus was a key military base. After WWI, during which Cyprus had been formally annexed by Britain, the newly created Turkish republic renounced any claim over Cyprus and in 1925 it became a British colony.</p>
<p>Greek and Turkish Cypriots fought on the Allied side during WWII, but after the war nationalists began to agitate for self-determination, either as a nation in its own right, or as part of Greece or Turkey. In the event, Cyprus gained independence in 1960 with the charismatic Archbishop Makarios III as its first president.</p>
<p>However, the island remained fraught with ethnic tension and independence fell apart in 1974 when Makarios was deposed by the Greek military junta. Within days, Turkish troops invaded, the Greeks failed to respond effectively and only after Turkey had taken control of the northern third of the island was a ceasefire arranged by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Cyprus has remained partitioned ever since by a divide that runs through the heart of its capital Nicosia. In mid-2015 the president of Cyprus Nicos Anastasiades and Turkish-Cypriot leader Mustafa Akinci met and resolved to work towards ending its partition. Watch this space.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Legend has it that the Greek goddess of love, Aphrodite, emerged into the world from the surf off what is today known as Aphrodite&rsquo;s Beach. <br />
&bull;	The Cypriot dessert wine, Commandaria, is the oldest named wine in the world.   <br />
&bull;	The writer Lawrence Durrell lived on Cyprus from 1952 until 1956.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission of the Republic of Cyprus in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7321 4100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mfa.gov.cy/highcomlondon</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7321 4100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1300 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>13 St James's Square<br/>London<br/>SW1Y 4LB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Cyprus in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 462 5772/0873 ; (202) 462 0632 (consulate).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.cyprusembassy.net</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 462 5772/0873 ; (202) 462 0632 (consulate).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2211 R Street<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Cyprus]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(22) 861 100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukincyprus.fco.gov.uk/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(22) 861 100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Tues and Thurs 0930-1230 (consular services); Mon-Fri 0730-1430 (phone enquiries).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>PO Box 21978<br/>Alexander Pallis Street<br/>Nicosia<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The legendary birthplace of Aphrodite, Cyprus is every inch the Mediterranean &ndash; sandy beaches, ancient monasteries, classical ruins, thyme scented mountains, terracotta houses and, of course, the obligatory party resorts full of sun-seeking twenty-somethings.</p>
<p>Cyprus has always been at the crossroads between Europe and Asia. In ancient times, a succession of empires squabbled over its seaports and mountain fortresses, which guaranteed supremacy over the eastern Mediterranean. These empire-builders left behind an incredible legacy of historical relics: ancient Greek and Roman ruins, Crusader castles, mighty Venetians city walls and towering mosques and minarets left behind by Ottoman invaders.</p>
<p>Until the 1970s, Cyprus was a sleepy backwater, but a devastating civil war saw the island split into Greek Cypriot and Turkish states. In the south, the Greek Republic of Cyprus grew into a modern European state, while the Turkish north half of the island remains isolated, recognised only by Turkey and well off the mainstream tourist radar.</p>
<p>After Partition, tourist development went into overdrive in the Greek half of the island, with the emergence of Ayia Napa, Protaras, Limassol, Paphos and a string of other package holiday resorts along the southern coast.  This is one face of Cyprus &ndash; whitewashed villas, sunbathers, banana-boat rides, boisterous nightclubs and hordes of young people enjoying blistering summer sunshine.</p>
<p>Inland, the old Cyprus endures, with beautiful villages full of UNESCO-listed churches, peaceful mountain trails and vineyards that have been producing wines since ancient times. A similar old-world atmosphere pervades in the divided capital, Lefkosia (Nicosia), where quiet lanes lined with Turkish mosques and Byzantine churches come to a sudden halt at the Green Line, the de facto border between the two enclaves.</p>
<p>The north is something else again, more Turkish than Greek, even down to the menus on restaurant tables, but studded with ancient ruins and dramatic Crusader castles. While rampant development is taking place along the coast around Famagusta (Gazimagusa) and Kyrenia (Girne), the remote Karpas Peninsula offers a journey back in time, where ancient ruins spill out onto golden beaches that see more sea turtles than human visitors.</p><p>The legendary birthplace of Aphrodite, Cyprus is every inch the Mediterranean &ndash; sandy beaches, ancient monasteries, classical ruins, thyme scented mountains, terracotta houses and, of course, the obligatory party resorts full of sun-seeking twenty-somethings.</p>
<p>Cyprus has always been at the crossroads between Europe and Asia. In ancient times, a succession of empires squabbled over its seaports and mountain fortresses, which guaranteed supremacy over the eastern Mediterranean. These empire-builders left behind an incredible legacy of historical relics: ancient Greek and Roman ruins, Crusader castles, mighty Venetians city walls and towering mosques and minarets left behind by Ottoman invaders.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
