<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Czech Republic" ColCode="cze" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="cz" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Czech Republic]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Czech Republic is an all year round destination. The climate is very seasonal &ndash; spring, summer, autumn and winter are very distinct, as epitomised by a Czech saying: &ldquo;<em>Březen, za kamna vlezem, duben, je&scaron;tě tam budem, m&aacute;j, půjdeme v h&aacute;j</em>&rdquo; (&ldquo;March &ndash; we get behind the stove, April &ndash; we&rsquo;ll still be there, May &ndash; off we go to the garden&rdquo;).</p>
<p>Winter can see temperatures drop to low minus numbers, whilst the summer period from May to August can see them soar above 30&ordm;C (86&ordm;F). Rather inconveniently, summer also sees the highest rainfall across the country. Shoulder seasons, such as the months of September and October, will still be hot, but are also likely to be drier than preceding months, so it may be preferable to travel during this time.</p>
<p>Depending on where in the country you&rsquo;re travelling, the climate may differ considerably. In the mountains, the weather tends to be cooler, experiencing higher levels of precipitation at higher altitudes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>No special clothes are required for the Czech Republic. Wear mediumweights, such as denim and heavy wools, a topcoat and sturdy shoes for winter. Lightweights such as cottons, linens and thin wools will be suitable for summer, but remember to bring waterproofs as rain showers are more frequent during this time.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Czech Airlines (<a href="http://www.csa.cz" target="_blank">www.csa.cz</a>) operates an extensive domestic service. There are regular domestic flights from Prague to Ostrava and Karlovy Vary. However, as this is only a small country, taking a bus, train or driving is generally the easier and cheaper alternative.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Navigable waterways can be found in the country, and the main river ports are located at Prague and &Uacute;st&iacute; nad Labem, although there are no regular passenger services along these.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The rail network is operated mainly by Czech Railways (tel:  +420 221 111 122; <a href="http://www.cd.cz" target="_blank">www.cd.cz</a>) but there are also limited services by Regio Jet (tel: +420 542 424 242; <a href="http://www.regiojet.cz/" target="_blank">www.regiojet.cz</a>) and Leo Express (tel: +420 220 311 700; <a href="http://www.le.cz/" target="_blank">www.le.cz</a>).  There are several daily express trains between Prague and the main cities and resorts.</p>
<p>Reservations should be made in advance on major routes; see timetables at <a href="http://jizdnirady.idnes.cz" target="_blank">http://jizdnirady.idnes.cz</a>. Fares are low, but supplements are payable for travel by express trains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>European East Pass: </strong>offers unlimited first or standard class train travel for five days in one month in Austria, Czech Republic, Hungary and Slovakia. You can buy it through Rail Europe (<a href="http://www.raileurope.com" target="_blank">www.raileurope.com</a>), as long as you live outside one of these four countries.</p>
<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass: </strong>offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within the Czech Republic. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 28 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving is a great way to see the Czech Republic, particularly the eastern region of Moravia. The highways in the country are reasonably maintained and road signs are simple to follow.</p>r<p>Main roads within the Czech Republic are reasonably well maintained. However, be prepared that smaller roads through villages or less inhabited areas may be a little bumpy with potholes and unexpected obstacles. Flooding is also a distinct possibility during winter.</p><p>Student Agency (tel: +420 841 101 101; <a href="http://www.studentagency.eu" target="_blank">www.studentagency.eu</a>) offers a range of domestic routes between Prague and most major Czech cities and towns, and they are all very affordable. Popular routes include Prague to Plzen (Pilsen), Prague to Brno, and Brno to Ostrava.</p><p>It is easy and safe to flag down a taxi in the Czech Republic, and rates are very affordable by Western standards. It is also easy to hire a taxi in advance. Most taxi offices in Prague, Brno or other major cities have staff who speak English. Fares are higher at night.</p><p>A valid national driving licence is required. If this has no photocard, an International Driving Permit is also required. A Green Card should be carried by visitors taking their own car into the Czech Republic, but it's not compulsory for EU visitors.</p><p>All users of the Czech motorways have to buy a windscreen sticker. There are three stickers available, valid for ten days, one month and one year. This is usually included with hire cars.</p>
<p>The minimum driving age is 18 years. Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (55mph) outside built-up areas and 130kph (80mph) on motorways. Seat belts are compulsory and those aged under 12 years must sit in the back of the car. Drinking and driving is prohibited, as is using a hand-held mobile phone. Headlights must be turned on at all times when driving.</p>
<p>All private cars must carry: one fluorescent high-visibility safety jacket for each passenger; one first aid kit; one spare tyre and repair kit (including jack and wheel nut wrench); a warning triangle and a spare set of spare bulbs. Winter tyres are mandatory from 1 November until 31 March each year, and children's car seats are needed for children shorter than 150cm or lighter than 36kg (79lb). Spare prescription glasses are also recommended.</p><p>A 24-hour service is available from &Uacute;AMK (tel: 1230, in the Czech Republic only) and the ABA (tel: 1240, in the Czech Republic only).</p><p>Cars can be hired at airports, railway stations and at other city locations throughout Prague and elsewhere in the Czech Republic. Reliable and trusted hire operators include Europcar (<a href="http://www.europcar.com" target="_blank">www.europcar.com</a>) and Sixt (<a href="http://www.sixt.com" target="_blank">www.sixt.com</a>), who have offices throughout the country. You must be aged over 21 and have held a driving licence for at least one year to rent a vehicle.</p><p>Bicycle hire isn't common in Czech cities, as the public transport systems are excellent. You can find hire places in tourist destinations such as Krkono&scaron;e and the Moravian wine region.</p><p>All users of the Czech motorways have to buy a windscreen sticker. There are three stickers available, valid for ten days, one month and one year. This is usually included with hire cars.</p>
<p>The minimum driving age is 18 years. Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (55mph) outside built-up areas and 130kph (80mph) on motorways. Seat belts are compulsory and those aged under 12 years must sit in the back of the car. Drinking and driving is prohibited, as is using a hand-held mobile phone. Headlights must be turned on at all times when driving.</p>
<p>All private cars must carry: one fluorescent high-visibility safety jacket for each passenger; one first aid kit; one spare tyre and repair kit (including jack and wheel nut wrench); a warning triangle and a spare set of spare bulbs. Winter tyres are mandatory from 1 November until 31 March each year, and children's car seats are needed for children shorter than 150cm or lighter than 36kg (79lb). Spare prescription glasses are also recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public transport within the Czech Republic's cities is excellent. Dopravn&iacute; Podn&iacute;k (<a href="http://www.dpp.cz" target="_blank">www.dpp.cz</a>) operates Prague's public transport system, and the city's metro service runs almost 24 hours a day, from 0500 to 0000. There are also tram and bus services (for which tickets must be purchased in advance from vending machines, tobacconist shops, newsagents, metro stations, information centres or travel agents). Night trams and buses run from 0000 until 0430 in Prague.</p>
<p>Buses, trolleybuses and trams also exist in Brno, Ostrava and several other towns, all of which run from early morning until around midnight.</p>
<p>All the cities operate flat-fare systems, and passes valid for a certain number of journeys or specific period of time can be purchased in advance. Tickets should be validated in the appropriate machine on entering the tram, bus or in the case of Prague, metro station. There is a fine for fare evasion.</p>
<p>Taxis are available in all main towns and cities and should always be metered. Higher fares are charged at night. You should ask for an approximate price before getting into a taxi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Czech Republic</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ostrava</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Czech Republic</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">karlovy_vary</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.10</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Czech Republic</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">brno</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.15</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier is Czech Airlines (<a href="http://www.csa.cz" target="_blank">www.csa.cz</a>). Airlines operating direct flights from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>), Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) and Wizz (<a href="http://www.wizzair.com" target="_blank">www.wizzair.com</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/czech-republic/prague-ruzyne-airport">Prague Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 1 hour 50 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 8 hours 40 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in all flight tickets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Prague Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.prg.aero/en<p>Prague Airport is located 20km (12 miles) northwest of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/prague">Prague</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+420 220 111 888.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Czech Republic is landlocked, so there are no sea or river routes into the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Czech Republic forms part of the European InterCity network, so it's easy to travel into the country by train. The most convenient routes to the Czech Republic from Western Europe are via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/berlin">Berlin</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cologne">Cologne</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/frankfurt">Frankfurt</a>, Nuremburg, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/munich">Munich</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vienna">Vienna</a>, W&uuml;rzburg, or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/z%C3%BCrich">Zurich</a>.</p>
<p>A daily overnight service travels from Vienna to Brno and Prague and on to Berlin. Rail travel information is available from Czech Railways (tel: +420 840 112 113; <a href="http://www.cd.cz" target="_blank">www.cd.cz</a>). Train timetable information is available online at <a href="http://jizdnirady.idnes.cz" target="_blank">http://jizdnirady.idnes.cz</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong>offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 30 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days, 7 days in a month, 10 days in a month or 15 days in a month across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass, however the age depends on what country you are traveling. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK;<a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 22 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 1 month, 7 days in one month, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can enter the Czech Republic overland from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a> to the north and west, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/austria">Austria</a> from the south, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/slovakia">Slovakia</a> from the south east and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/poland">Poland</a> from the north east. Every entry point has a major, reasonable-quality highway leading directly to either Prague in the west or Brno in the east.</p><p>To use the highways within the Czech Republic you need to purchase a sticker to place on your windscreen. There are three stickers available, valid for ten days, one month and one year. You can buy them at post offices or petrol stations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are plenty of public telephone booths; international calls can be made from any of them. Most of the public telephone booths take phonecards, which can be purchased at hotels, tourist information offices, newsagents and tobacconist shops. Surcharges can be quite high on long-distance calls from hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Czech Republic uses the GSM 900 system, and is 3G compatible. Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies and coverage is excellent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is available in most hotels, bars and cafes, negating the need for internet cafes, although there are still plenty of these in the cities. Some venues may levy a charge for usage.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Private media in the Czech Republic mushroomed in the 1990s, and private radio and TV stations provide stiff competition for public broadcasters. Public TV broadcaster Česká televize operates two networks and a 24-hour news channel.</p><p>Czech public radio, Český rozhlas (CRo), operates three national networks as well as local services. The <em>Prague Post </em>newspaper and <em>Czech Business Weekly </em>magazine are published in English, while the main Czech dailies include <em>Mladá Fronta Dnes</em>, <em>Právo </em>and <em>Lidové Noviny</em>, the country's oldest daily paper. Two major private television channels broadcast nationally and there are more than 70 private radio stations. Radio Prague has programmes in a number of languages including English. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail takes a couple of working days to reach other European destinations; allow up to a week to North America.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1800, 0800-1200 Sat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Kutná Hora</p><![CDATA[<p>Explore an ancient silver mine and marvel at the magnificent murals in St Barbara's Cathedral in Kutn&aacute; Hora, a pretty medieval town and another UNESCO World Heritage site (<a href="http://www.kutnahora.cz" target="_blank">www.kutnahora.cz</a>). Kutn&aacute; Hora once rivalled Prague and even London in terms of  size and importance. The discovery of silver ore here in the 14th  century led to the creation of the Royal Mint and the town became the  political, cultural and economic centre of Bohemia. The legacy of this  glorious epoch can be seen in the fine Gothic and Italianate buildings  that line the cobbled streets.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be enchanted by the capital, Prague</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The capital city is an obvious place to start, but you'd be mad to miss it. Soak up the atmosphere in one of Europe's most beautiful and cultural spots with a cruise on the Vltava. Discover its UNESCO World Heritage-listed Old Town, medieval Charles Bridge and the spire-filled district of Malá Strana, which is home to the world's largest citadel, Prague Castle. </p>]]><p><b>Clamber the Adršpach-Teplice Rocks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you love rock climbing, you'll love the Adršpach-Teplice Rocks. These unusual sandstone rock formations form the basis of a nature reserve in the north of the Czech Republic, which is also home to contorted canyons and wildlife-filled forests – and make for unique rock climbing opportunities. You'll find many operators in the area.</p>]]><p><b>Cycle and sip your way through Moravia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hire a bike and pedal your way around the rolling hills, glistening vineyards and historic villages of South Moravia. Sample wines within picturesque surroundings, in places like Mikulov and Valtice, or cycle your way through the stunning UNESCO-listed Lednice-Valtice Cultural Landscape that was once owned by the principality of Liechtenstein.</p>]]><p><b>Expect outdoor adventure at Krkonoše</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whether you come in summer or winter, a trip to Krkonoše is a must. This lofty mountain range, which skirts the Czech-Polish border and has the highest peak in the country, offers wonderful hiking and cycling during the summer – and even better skiing during the winter. Just don't expect to have it all to yourself.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Bohemia's once-mighty economic centre, Kutná Hora</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the ancient silver mine and marvel at the magnificent murals in St Barbara's Cathedral in Kutná Hora. This pretty medieval town and UNESCO World Heritage Site once rivalled Prague and even London in terms of size and importance, and this legacy can be seen in the fine Gothic and Italianate buildings that line the cobbled streets.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Renaissance town of Telč</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The cobbled streets of Telč are one of the most idyllic examples of a Renaissance town in Europe, earning it well-deserved UNESCO World Heritage Site. The town was rebuilt after a fire in 1530, so medieval arcades with their gabled houses surround the picturesque town square.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the fairytale castles of Karlštejn and Konopiště</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Czech Republic is home to an array of picture-postcard castles and two of the finest are within easy reach of Prague. 14th-century Karlštejn is a Disney-esque fairytale castle hidden in a valley between forested hills, while Konopiště is a spectacular Baroque-style château and the last residence of Archduke Franz Ferdinand of Austria.</p>]]><p><b>Fall in love with the pretty city of Český Krumlov</b></p><![CDATA[<p>UNESCO World Heritage Site Česk&yacute; Krumlov is widely considered to be the Czech Republic's most picturesque town. Wander the ramparts of its fairytale castle, stroll along the banks of the infant Vltava River (or hire a canoe to get even closer), and lose yourself among its medieval back streets.</p>]]><p><b>Find the time to visit pretty Olomouc</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The attractive university town of Olomouc is noted for its green parks, baroque churches, sculptures and fountains – not to mention its UNESCO-listed Holy Trinity Column and grand astronomical clock. The surrounding Hana region is strongly agricultural, with many villages holding attractive harvest festivals in late September.</p>]]><p><b>Luxuriate at the famous Karlovy Vary spa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Kick back and relax at the attractive spa resort of Karlovy Vary, which offers hot mineral springs, fine baroque and Gothic architecture, forest walks and a lively cultural scene. Finally, don't miss the picturesque castle at nearby Loket, set high above the River Ohre.</p>]]><p><b>Paddle the Vltava river at Borová Lada</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to the upper reaches of the Vltava at Borová Lada for an exciting day of canoeing. This section of the river is picturesque, with gentle rapids and weirs, which makes it ideal canoe-touring territory for beginners. Many outfits will rent you canoes and camping gear in this region.</p>]]><p><b>Reflect on the past horrors at Terezín</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn about a darker period in Czech history at Terezín, a former Nazi concentration camp north of Prague. The Ghetto Museum, barracks and isolation cells, execution grounds and mass graves bring the horrors of the Holocaust to life, ensuring it will never be forgotten.</p>]]><p><b>See more grand designs at Hluboká and Vranov</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Both history and design enthusiasts will find worthy excursion to Hluboká and Vranov nad Dyjí. The former is a grand and romantic baroque castle dating back to the 13th century, while the latter is an imposing Moravian château perched atop a giant rock overlooking the town.</p>]]><p><b>See skull sculpture at Sedlec Ossuary</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get the creeps at Sedlec Ossuary, where the centuries-old bones of more than 40,000 people have been crafted into a stunning display of garlands, chandeliers, sculptures and coats of arms. This isn't one for the faint of heart, but there's nowhere else in the world quite like it.</p>]]><p><b>Take a sip at the Pilsner Urquell Brewery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Make a pilgrimage to the birthplace of the world's best beer – the Pilsner Urquell Brewery in Plzeň, just an hour from Prague. It was here that pilsner lager was invented in 1842. Don't miss a guided tour through the medieval tunnels and beer cellars beneath the old centre.</p>]]><p><b>Unearth the natural splendour of Šumava</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pack up your trekking poles and head for Šumava, the country's largest national park. A gobsmackingly beautiful region of forest-clad hills along the border with Austria, the giant park includes scenic lakes, trout streams, areas of virgin forest and important historic monuments.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind in peace at Mariánské Lázně</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Czech Republic is famous for its hot springs, mineral baths and spa treatments, and they are not only to be found in touristy Karlovy Vary. Pretty Mariánské Lázně, in the west of the country, offers equally wonderful spa facilities for a significantly reduced price – as does nearby Františkovy Lázně.</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at the sheer scale of Macocha's sinkhole</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Peer into the dizzying abyss of Macocha, a spectacular 140-m (459-ft) deep sinkhole at the heart of the Moravský Kras (Moravian karst) near Brno, a limestone region riddled with caves. Then follow up this adventure with a cruise along an underground river at the nearby Punkevni Caves.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$193 billion (2016 estimate).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cars, vehicle parts, digital disk drives, monitors and projectors, and electricity.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cars, vehicle parts, digital disk drives, petroleum, insulated wire</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Slovakia, Poland, UK,&nbsp;France, Italy and Austria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Years of stringent state control and public ownership during the Soviet era took its toll on the economy of the former Czechoslovakia, and caused the economy of the new Czech Republic to flounder and fall into recession in 1997.</p>
<p>But now the country is reaping the benefits of an aggressive reform policy, which included a programme of mass privatisation (the majority of economic input is now in private hands) and an overhaul of the country's financial system.<br />
<br />
The Czech Republic's long-standing membership of the IMF, World Bank, the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development and, of course, the European Union has afforded the economy a further boost, with the country strengthening trading relationships in the EU. It no longer relies on trade with Russia; Germany is now its biggest export and import partner.<br />
<br />
Prague is the country's main conference venue, with a dedicated Congress Centre and many high-end hotels with meeting facilities. Good hotel facilities are also available in other major Czech cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Czech society is still largely male-dominated, with a large proportion of older businessmen, though things are slowly changing. Dress is conservative for older businesses, while new companies tend to be more relaxed. English is widely spoken, particularly amongst the younger generation, but it is a good idea to check if an interpreter will be needed in advance.</p>
<p>By and large, the Czechs are a warm people who value hospitality. In some instances, when dining with Czech business colleagues, it will emerge the bill has quietly been settled. If this happens, visitors should accept gracefully and find a later means of showing appreciation.</p>
<p>Initial business meetings can be serious affairs, during which even business partners refer to one another by title and surname. The use of first names is a mark of friendship, but using them without permission is rare, especially among older groups. Degrees are considered important and are always used in addressing correspondence. However, most businessmen and women in the Czech Republic are tolerant of foreigners who do not follow these rules.</p>
<p>Punctuality is essential &ndash; colleagues should be informed of any unavoidable delays. Avoid visits during July and August as many businesses close for the holidays.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Trade Fairs Brno</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 647 00 ,5411 51111
					Website:http://www.bvv.cz/
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Economic Chamber of the Czech Republic</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 190 00 ,2966 46112
					Website:http://www.komora.cz/
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Prague Convention Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 110 00 ,2242 35159
					Website:http://www.pragueconvention.cz/
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Traditional Czech food is best described as hearty. It's dominated by meat, served with either bread, potatoes, or bread and potato dumplings, and slathered in sauce. The influences from neighbouring Austria and Hungary (and to a lesser extent Poland, Germany and Russia) are plain to see.</p>
<p>Czech cuisine is also delicious and filling, and a new wave of Prague chefs are offering up increasingly light and creative takes on Bohemian classics. When it comes to drink, beer is the accompaniment of choice, and it&rsquo;s one of the few places in the world where it&rsquo;s not frowned upon to sip a frothy Pilsner over breakfast.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Vepřo-knedlo-zelo:</strong> This omnipresent Czech classic consists of roast pork with dumplings and sauerkraut.<br />
<strong>Goulash:</strong> A thick beef stew with a rich onion base, usually served with bread dumplings.<br />
<strong>Sv&iacute;čkov&aacute; na smetaně:</strong> This strangely-satisfying sweet-savoury mash-up consists of pot-roasted beef tenderloin and vegetables with a sweet cream sauce, topped with cranberries.<br />
<strong>Smažen&yacute; s&yacute;r:</strong> Edam-style cheese covered in breadcrumbs, deep-fried, then served with a side of French fries and tangy tartar sauce.<br />
<strong>Česnekov&aacute; pol&eacute;vka:</strong> A water-based garlic soup with melted cheese and croutons.<br />
<strong>Brambor&aacute;k:</strong> Pancake of grated potato with egg, breadcrumbs and garlic.<br />
<strong>Tatarsk&yacute; biftek:&nbsp;</strong>A Czech take on steak tartare, this dish is made with seasoned raw beef and egg yolk.<br />
<strong>Budweiser Budvar:</strong> A world-famous Czech beer, the fight for naming rights with the US brand is still brewing, but this is the victor where taste is concerned.<br />
<strong>V&aacute;nočn&iacute; kapr:</strong> Slices of carp covered in breadcrumbs and deep-fried &ndash; a Christmas staple.<br />
<strong>Ovocn&eacute; knedl&iacute;ky:</strong> A sweet dumpling filled with fresh strawberries, plum, apricot or fruit preserves, typically topped with melting butter and a dusting of sugar.<br />
<strong>Pilsner Urquell</strong>: This popular beer brand spawned a beer style named after it (pilsner), and is still served in most Czech drinking establishments.<br />
<strong>Wine:</strong> Moravian wine available in white (such as Mopr, P&aacute;lava and Hibernal) red (Cabernet Moravia and Neronet) as well as rose and sparkling.<br />
<strong>Becherovka:</strong> A herbal bitters spirit with a cinnamon-like taste from Karlovy Vary.<br />
<strong>Slivovice:</strong> A potent plum brandy, though other fruit varieties are also available.<br />
<strong>Fernet:</strong> A bitter and aromatic, liquorice-like spirit usually served as a digestif.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>If you only have a small appetite, and don't need anything warm, head to a bar. Almost every drinking establishment within the Czech Republic, even those with no food menu, will serve either pickled sausage or cheese.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It is customary to tip 10% for good service in a restaurant, though up to 15% may be added to your bill in the touristy areas of Prague.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As you'd expect, the hub of Czech nightlife is Prague. The Czech capital has an extraordinarily diverse after dark scene, incorporating a bit of everything, from live theatre, ballet and opera, to clubs, casinos and lap dancing bars. There are also a seemingly infinite range of cafes, bars and jazz joints dotted around the city centre and the riverside. The central districts of the Old Town and Malá Strana are crammed with pubs, nightclubs and music venues mostly aimed at the tourist market, while the area around Wenceslas Square has a concentration of sports bars and strip clubs – stay clear of this part of town if you want to avoid drunken stag parties.<br/><br/>The up-and-coming suburbs of Vinohrady, just east of Prague city centre, and Holešovice, to the north, have lots of cool cafes and hip cocktail bars, and are also home to some of the city's top clubs, including Radost FX (<a href="http://www.radostfx.cz" target="_blank">www.radostfx.cz</a>) and Cross Club (<a href="http://www.crossclub.cz/" target="_blank">www.crossclub.cz</a>).<br/><br/>Brno, the Czech Republic's second city, also has a varied nightlife and has its own opera and ballet venue in the National Theatre (<a href="http://www.ndbrno.cz" target="_blank">www.ndbrno.cz</a>). Spa resorts such as Karlovy Vary support a lively cultural scene, with a regular programme of classical concerts and a stylish casino, while there are several good live music bars tailored to the tourists in Český Krumlov.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unsurprisingly for a country that gave us the word 'Bohemian', the Czech Republic specialises in souvenirs that are original, inventive, and often unexpected. So avoid the usual selection of tacky t-shirts and novelty pens and instead pick up an authentic slice of this fine country.</p><p>Without doubt, the most common souvenir people bring home from the Czech Republic is Bohemian crystal. Famed for its colour and beauty, and used in everything from decanters to chandeliers (most royal residences around the world boast Bohemian chandeliers), it makes for a unique and beautiful gift – and costs a fraction of the price buying it here than it does outside of the country. On a similarly luxurious level, garnet is the Czech national gem, so jewellery lovers are apt to find a piece lined with the beautiful deep red stone.</p><p>Other great mementos from the Czech Republic include an ice hockey jersey (ideally with the name of national hero Jaromír Jágr), wooden folk carvings and, if in Prague, a marionette puppet. Prague was at the heart of a continent-wide puppetry revolution in the 18th century, so you can watch marionette shows at many theatres here, then buy a puppet as a souvenir.</p><p>Most souvenir stores in Prague are centred around the Old Town and Wenceslas Square, but a more relaxed place to pick up trinkets is on the other side of town. Walk the Golden Lane, under Prague Castle, then visit the unique art and antique stores that line Nerudova Street. For utterly unique fashion, visit designer outlet Boheme (<a href="http://www.boheme.cz" target="_blank">www.boheme.cz</a>), or for traditional Czech handicrafts make a beeline for the near ever-present market in the Old Town Square.</p><p>There is also great regional shopping outside of Prague, and it's often even cheaper. Discover the china ornaments and geyser stone carvings of Karlovy Vary, the delicate lace and needle embroidery of Moravia, and the very distinctive 'Mrazek-style' pottery of Western Bohemia.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1800. Some stores, especially in smaller towns and rural areas, close at 1200 on Saturdays and are closed on Sundays, while others in larger towns and cities will be open 1000-1600 on Sundays. Supermarkets and food shops in large towns and cities are open from 0700 and stay open until late.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Prague are now just as expensive as anywhere in western Europe, but the standard of hotel accommodation has improved enormously over the past decade, and Prague offers everything from beautifully restored historic buildings, to boutique hotels created by cutting-edge designers. Outside of the capital, hotel rates - and standards - are a bit lower, though there are certainly high-end hotels in major cities such as Brno and Ostrava, and in popular resorts like Karlovy Vary and Česk&yacute; Krumlov. Watch out for hotels described as  <em>hotel garni</em> &ndash; this indicates a hotel that does not have a restaurant.</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A pension is usually a small, family-run place with up to half a dozen rooms. These are a bit like a British bed and breakfast, though slightly more formal, and they tend to be more common than hotels in rural areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Prague are now just as expensive as anywhere in western Europe, but the standard of hotel accommodation has improved enormously over the past decade, and Prague offers everything from beautifully restored historic buildings, to boutique hotels created by cutting-edge designers. Outside of the capital, hotel rates - and standards - are a bit lower, though there are certainly high-end hotels in major cities such as Brno and Ostrava, and in popular resorts like Karlovy Vary and Česk&yacute; Krumlov. Watch out for hotels described as  <em>hotel garni</em> &ndash; this indicates a hotel that does not have a restaurant.</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Prague are now just as expensive as anywhere in western Europe, but the standard of hotel accommodation has improved enormously over the past decade, and Prague offers everything from beautifully restored historic buildings, to boutique hotels created by cutting-edge designers. Outside of the capital, hotel rates - and standards - are a bit lower, though there are certainly high-end hotels in major cities such as Brno and Ostrava, and in popular resorts like Karlovy Vary and Česk&yacute; Krumlov. Watch out for hotels described as  <em>hotel garni</em> &ndash; this indicates a hotel that does not have a restaurant.</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The standard of healthcare facilities in the Czech Republic is high, and hospitals are generally well-equipped in terms of facilities. There is a mixture of public and private healthcare; the country is becoming a burgeoning hub for medical tourism due to the relatively cheap cost of procedures compared to the rest of Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European Health Insurance Card (EHIC) entitles European travellers to free or reduced cost emergency medical care, at state-run facilities, in the European Economic Area (EEA) and Switzerland. Contact the Centre for International Reimbursements (&lt;a href="https://www.kancelarzp.cz/index.php/en  " rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.kancelarzp.cz/index.php/en&lt;/a&gt;) for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tourists are advised to take out comprehensive travel insurance before travelling. In the event of a medical emergency, call 112.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The Czech Republic is relatively risk-free in terms of food and drink. It&amp;rsquo;s fine to drink the tap water, and as long as you take the usual precautions regarding hygiene and preparation, the danger from food and drink, is minimal, unless it&amp;rsquo;s from overindulging.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tick-borne encephalitis exists in rural forested areas during summer months; it may help to wear long sleeves, long trousers and hats, in order to minimise the risk of getting bitten. Immunisation against hepatitis B is sometimes advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Liberation Day :
							08 May </p><p>Saints Cyril and Methodius Day :
							05 July </p><p>Anniversary of the Martyrdom of Jan Hus :
							06 July </p><p>Czech Statehood Day :
							28 September </p><p>Independence Day :
							28 October </p><p>Freedom and Democracy Day :
							17 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Czech Republic is within the European Union. If you are  travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragrance, skincare,  cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts  and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be   imported into Czech Republic by travellers over 17 years of age without  incurring  customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic   beverages up to 22% volume.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine.<br />
&bull; 16L of beer.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers (reduced to &euro;200 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Explosives are prohibited. Firearms and ammunition are only permitted with a licence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited or restricted exports include veterinary goods, items of cultural value, weapons, ammunition, explosives and narcotics.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Koruna (CZK; symbol Kč) or Crown = 100 haler. Notes are in denominations of 5,000, 2,000, 1,000, 500, 200 and 100Kč. Coins are in denominations of 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1Kč, and 50 haler.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency (including traveller's cheques) can be exchanged at all bank branches and at authorised exchange offices, main hotels and road border crossings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major credit cards such as American Express, Diners Club, Discover, Visa, MasterCard are accepted for most types of transaction. For smaller amounts you may have to pay in cash.</p><p>ATMs are widespread throughout the country, and will almost certainly offer an English translation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are accepted in banks, but only rarely in hotels and almost never in restaurants. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars, Euros or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0900-1700. Some banks close early on Fridays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals requiring a transit visa can use it for one or two entries within six months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Czech Republic is a member of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit and short-stay Schengen visas: &pound;55/&euro;62; long-stay visa: &pound;88/&euro;100. Prices differ for some nationals however; check with the consulate for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The short-stay Schengen visa is valid for 90 days in a six-month period within the Schengen area; the long-stay visa is required for visits of over 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate (or consular section at embassy); you must make an appointment online in advance. In the UK, you need to apply through VFS Global's Czech Visa Application Centre (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/czechrepublic/UK" target="_blank">www.vfsglobal.com/czechrepublic/UK</a>). All visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at the visa appointment. VFS Global charges an additional &euro;26.20 service charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Usually 10 to 15 days for short-stay Schengen visas (maximum 30 days), but allow longer for long-stay visas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa applicants must show they have the equivalent of &pound;30 per day for the duration of their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa holders can only extend their visas in exceptional circumstances, such as <em>force majeure </em>or for humanitarian reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet from another EU country, your animal must have a microchip, pet passport and valid rabies vaccination certificate. Animals arriving from outside the EU require a microchip and veterinary certificate confirming they have been vaccinated against rabies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[49.738968]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[15.332993]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>78,866 sq km (30,450 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>10,550,085 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>135 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prague.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Czech Republic is a landlocked country situated in central Europe, sharing frontiers with Germany in the west, Poland in the north, the Slovak Republic in the east, and Austria in the south. Covering only about one-third of the area of the United Kingdom, the country is hilly and picturesque.</p>
<p>The western two-thirds of the country is known as Bohemia, and consists of a vast river basin fringed by hills and mountains. The Czech Republic's longest river, the Labe, rises in the Krkono&scaron;e Mountains in the northeast, on the border with Poland, and flows south, then west, then north into Germany where it becomes the River Elbe. These mountains are also home to the country's highest summit, Sněžka which stand 1,602m (5,262ft) tall.</p>
<p>Prague sits almost in the middle of Bohemia on the River Vltava, which flows into the Labe just to the north of the city. The Vltava rises in the forested &Scaron;umava hills that run along the country's southern border with Austria. The plains to the north of Prague are bordered by the Kru&scaron;n&eacute; Hory (Ore Mountains, named for the iron ore and other minerals found there).</p>
<p>The eastern third of the Czech Republic is known as Moravia. This region is also based on a river basin, that of the Morava River, which rises in the northern hills near the Polish border and flows south to join the Danube at Bratislava. The main city of Moravia is Brno, the second-largest in the Czech Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mostly Roman Catholic and some Protestant, including churches such as the Reformed, Lutheran, Methodist, Unity of Czech Brothers and Baptist. There is a small Jewish community, mainly in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/czech-republic/prague-ruzyne-airport">Prague</a>. According to&nbsp;a Pew Research Center survey, 72% of the population were not affiliated with any religious beliefs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is considered polite to say &lsquo;<em>dobr&yacute; den</em>&rsquo; (good day) when you meet a stranger, including the person behind the counter in a shop or a pub. You should also say '<em>na shledanou</em>&rsquo; (goodbye) when you leave. The Czech manner can feel a little brusque sometimes, but often a smile and a joke will lighten up most interactions. When greeting a new person, shake hands, and maintain eye contact.</p>
<p>If you are invited to someone's house, it is polite to take a small gift - a bunch of flowers will do. Remember to remove your shoes when you enter.&nbsp;When attending a classical music concert, an opera performance or even the cinema, most Czechs will dress formally - you can usually spot the tourists by their casual clothes.</p>
<p>There is a smoking ban in public places, in railway stations, on public transport and in restaurants and pubs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Andrej Babis since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Milo&scaron; Zeman since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Czech Republic is one of Europe's most fledgling states, having only come into existence in 1993. But the narrative of this land and its people stretches far back into European history. Prior to the Czech Republic, the territory formed the westernmost region of Czechoslovakia, a country which itself had only been created in 1918, following the collapse of the Habsburg Empire after WWI.</p>
<p>But let's start at the beginning. There is evidence of life in this part of Europe since the Lower Palaeolithic era, yet the story of the Czech lands really began to take shape with the arrival of the Slavs in the 6th century. They founded the first West Slavic state, Great Moravia. This was followed by the Duchy of Bohemia, and later, the Kingdom of Bohemia, which reigned from the 9th century through to the 16th century, and oversaw a period of great prosperity and importance for the region (it is widely known by Czechs as 'the Golden Age').</p>
<p>The Habsburgs seized power of the Bohemian lands after this, and maintained this power in many different guises &ndash; latterly known as the Austro-Hungarian Empire &ndash; right up until the early 20th century.</p>
<p>In 1918, from the ashes of the Habsburgs grew the new democratic state of Czechoslovakia, which had a significant role on the European stage. However, this was curtailed in 1938, as Hitler's forces began their invasion of the country and took control. The Nazis maintained power for most of the war, until September 1944, when its liberation was started by the Red Army.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, it wasn't long before Czechoslovakia fell under communist rule, with a coup d'&eacute;tat in 1948 that would usher in 40 years of socialism. More liberal policies were briefly imposed in the 1960s &ndash; leader Alexander Dubček wanted to give socialism &lsquo;a human face&rsquo; &ndash; but these were soon put to an end with the invasion of Soviet tanks in August 1968.</p>
<p>Since the Velvet Revolution of 1989, and the Velvet Divorce of 1993 (when the nation agreed to split into two separate countries, the Czech Republic and Slovakia), the Czech Republic has cemented its ties with Western Europe, including signing up as a part of the European Union. And it is now one of the most stable and prosperous of all post-communist European states.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	This may not come as a surprise to anyone that has been there, but Czech people consume the highest amount of beer per capita.<br />
&bull;	Big Hollywood productions, including Casino Royale and Mission Impossible have all filmed in the Czech Republic.<br />
&bull;	Former Czech President V&aacute;clav Klau caused quite a stir back in 2011 after a video of him pocketing an expensive pen during an official visit to Chile went viral.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Czech Republic in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7243 7908; (020) 7243 7915 (visa section); 09065 540 727 (24-hour fully automated visa service).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mzv.cz/london/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7243 7908; (020) 7243 7915 (visa section); 09065 540 727 (24-hour fully automated visa service).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 1400-1600 (visa phone queries); Mon-Fri 0900-1200 (visa applications, by appointment); Mon-Thurs 1400-1500 (visa collections).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>26-30 Kensington Palace Gardens<br/>London<br/>W8 4QY<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in the Czech Republic]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+420 257 40 2111.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-prague</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+420 257 40 2111.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Thunovská 179/12<br/>Prague<br/>118 00<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Czech Republic in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 274 9100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mzv.cz/washington</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 274 9100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1700, Fri 0800-1430; Mon-Fri 0830-1130 (consular and visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3900 Spring of Freedom Street<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A historic jewel at the heart of Europe, the Czech Republic packs a sizeable punch for such a small country; from majestic castles to medieval towns, elegant spa resorts to scenic national parks, it has much to offer international visitors. It is also, lest we forget, the birthplace of the world&rsquo;s finest beer.</p>
<p>At the heart of it all is the culture-crammed capital, Prague. Dubbed the &ldquo;city of a thousand spires,&rdquo; it comprises beautiful churches, cobbled lanes and medieval bridges, all watched over by a fairytale castle. Add to that a mix of ancient monuments, fine dining, old breweries, bustling markets and lively jazz clubs. There really is never a dull moment.</p>
<p>Yet those who fail to venture beyond the city boundaries are truly missing out. Located just a short drive from the capital are some extraordinary attractions; the hot springs of Karlovy Vary; the giant gothic castle of Karl&scaron;tejn; the church made of human bones in Kutn&aacute; Hora; and the city of Plzeň, where pilsner beer was born.</p>
<p>Formerly part of Czechoslovakia, since the Velvet Divorce of 1993 &ndash; when Slovakia and the Czech Republic parted company &ndash; the latter has emerged the more popular with tourists. And to understand its appeal one must consider its assets; the stunning wine-growing region of Monrovia, home to rolling hills, traditional food and the spirited cities of Brno and Olomouc; the snow-capped mountains of Krkono&scaron;e; the otherworldly rock formations of Česk&yacute; R&aacute;j; the wild forests of &Scaron;umava National Park; and the historic town of Česk&yacute; Krumlov, a fully deserving UNESCO World Heritage Site.</p>
<p>And yet, for all this, the Czech Republic is far more than the sum of its sights. This is a nation of proud, forthright and friendly people, eager to take a significant role on the European stage. It may only be a small country &ndash; and a relatively new one &ndash; but the Czech Republic leaves a big impression.</p><p>A historic jewel at the heart of Europe, the Czech Republic packs a sizeable punch for such a small country; from majestic castles to medieval towns, elegant spa resorts to scenic national parks, it has much to offer international visitors. It is also, lest we forget, the birthplace of the world&rsquo;s finest beer. At the heart of it all is the culture-crammed capital, Prague. Dubbed the &ldquo;city of a thousand spires,&rdquo; it comprises beautiful churches, cobbled lanes and medieval bridges, all watched over by a fairytale castle. Add to that a mix of ancient monuments, fine dining, old breweries, bustling markets and lively jazz clubs and there really isn&rsquo;t a dull moment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
