<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Democratic Republic Of Congo" ColCode="zar" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="cd" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Democratic Republic of Congo]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Varies according to distance from the equator, which lies across the north of the country. The dry season in the north is from December to February, and in the south, April to October. The temperature is warm year round and humidity is high.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothes are recommended all year, with rainwear during the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CAA (<a href="http://www.caacongo.com" target="_blank">www.caacongo.com</a>) operates domestic flights within the Democratic Republic of Congo.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Over 1,600km (1,000 miles) of the Congo River are navigable and there are sporadic services from Kinshasa to the upriver ports of Kisangani and Il&eacute;bo, but services are unreliable owing to political instability and fuel shortages.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main internal railway runs from Lubumbashi to Il&eacute;bo, with a branch to Kalemie and Kindu, and from Kinshasa to the port of Matadi. Rail services are generally subject to disruption. There is no air conditioning, but there are couchettes and dining cars on the principal trains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Owing to poor maintenance, the roads are among the worst in Africa and only achieve a fair standard around the main towns.&nbsp;It is wise to check that bridges are safe before crossing.&nbsp;Vehicle thefts, including hijackings at gunpoint, occur.</p><p>Available in Kinshasa but unreliable.</p><p>International Driving Permit required.</p><p>Available on a limited basis at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Conventional bus services in Kinshasa can be severely overcrowded. Minibuses and converted truck-buses also offer public transport, and are known as <em>fula fulas</em>. Pick-up trucks are known as 'taxibuses'. A better standard of transport is provided by shared taxis, which are widely available. There is little or no public transport in most other large centres.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines serving the Democratic Republic of Congo include Brussels Airlines (<a href="http://www.brusselsairlines.com" target="_blank">www.brusselsairlines.com</a>), Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="http://www.ethiopianairlines.com" target="_blank">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>), Kenya Airways (<a href="http://www.kenya-airways.com" target="_blank">www.kenya-airways.com</a>), Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>), South African Airways (<a href="http://www.flysaa.com" target="_blank">www.flysaa.com</a>) and Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 12 hours (including stopover); <a href="new-york-city">New York</a> - 19 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Kinshasa (N'Djili) Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 25km (15 miles) east of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The country's crumbling rail network means there are no reliable international rail services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Internal telephone service is often unreliable and exists only in major towns. Satellite or cellular telephones are often used by international organisations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a few international mobile phone companies. Note: Using a handset in public can attract unwanted attention and make the user a target for robbery.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available, though power shortages may cause difficulties. There are Internet cafes in Kinshasa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Congolese media operate against a backdrop of political power struggles and sometimes violent unrest. The press has been able to criticise the Government bodies in certain publications but the media still do so at the risk of threats and possible violence. There are several daily newspapers; many more publications appear sporadically. There are many privately-run TV and radio stations. Church radio networks are growing, but the state-controlled broadcasting network reaches the largest numbers of citizens. <strong><br /></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The country is included in the Universal Postal Union and the African Postal Union. Airmail to Europe takes officially takes four to 18 days but in practice can take much longer.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Discover Upemba National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Upemba National Park straddles the River Lualaba and is accessible from the towns of Lubumbashi and Kolwezi. It includes several lakes and picturesque riverine sections inhabited by hippos, crocodiles and aquatic birds. Wildlife stocks were previously decimated by poachers and militias but are slowly returning with the help of the Frankfurt Zoological Society. For now, this beautiful park remains tantalizingly tourism free.</p>]]><p><b>Experience the beauty of Bukavu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The beautiful, verdant town of Bukavu hugs the southern tip of Lake Kivu and serves as a departure point for the under-visited Kahuzi-Biega National Park and Idjwi Island. The former is home to eastern lowland gorillas and some great hiking; the latter is the second-largest lake island in Africa and a perfect spot for a few days peaceful relaxation.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Inkisi Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the southwest, the Inkisi Falls (60m/197ft high) and the massive complex of caves that wrap around them may be visited in one day, but many visitors stay for two or three days at the pleasant resort in the town of Mbanza-Ngungu. The impressive falls are an easy hike from the resort and 130km (80 miles) by road from the capital city Kinshasa.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the pulse of Kinshasa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Kinshasa is a crazy and sometimes scary place. Not for the faint of heart, this sprawling city on the banks of the mighty Congo River has some great nightlife, cultural offerings and music. If the chaos of the capital gets too much, on its fringes there's an equatorial forest surrounding a beautiful lake called Ma Vallée with a tavern on its banks.</p>]]><p><b>Get to know Garamba National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A UNESCO World Heritage Site, this remote national park in the northeast of DRC boasts a staggering array of habitats, from open undulating savannah grasslands to dense rainforests. Managed by African Parks since 2005, Garamba was once home to the last population of wild northern white rhinoceros and still boasts large elephant, hippo and giraffe populations.</p>]]><p><b>Hang out with bonobos at Lolo Ya Sanctuary</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Just 90 minutes outside of Kinshasa, this sanctuary provides a home for orphaned bonobos. These inherently peaceful primates, who resemble chimpanzees, are incredibly intelligent and known for solving most of their problems with sex. There are various trails through their forested enclosures, but you're just as likely to find these loving creatures hanging around by the main building.</p>]]><p><b>See the resurgence of Goma</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On the northern shore of Lake Kivu, Goma has been at the centre of the various wars that have engulfed the wider region. As a result, it's had to become a master of reinvention. It's the DRC's tourism capital, if such a thing exists, and the main access point to Virunga National Park. It's also got a surprisingly lively and youthful arts scene.</p>]]><p><b>Track Gorillas in Virunga National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Virunga National Park is Africa's oldest national park. It comprises two jagged mountain ranges and game that includes lions, elephants, buffaloes, hippos and numerous antelope species. Best of all, this park is renowned for its mountain gorillas. Track these incredible creatures through the dense forest and then peer into an active lava lake from the top of Nyiragongo volcano.</p>]]><p><b>Visit likeable Lubumbashi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lubumbashi is the capital city of the mineral rich Katanga Province and DRC's primary economic hub. It's the country's most diverse city, and has the best infrastructure, as well as good travel connections with the wider region. But it's also a pleasant place to explore for a couple of days, with some fine Belgian architecture and good restaurants and accommodation options.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around Kalemie</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the Democratic Republic of Congo's areas of watery beauty from the pretty and laidback town of Kalemie on the banks of the immense Lake Tanganyika. The town has a functioning airport to connect with the wider region and Tanzania across the border. There's also some fascinating, crumbling colonial architecture, colourful markets and pleasant accommodations with great lake views.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$8.5 billion (2006).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Diamonds, crude oil, coffee, copper and cobalt.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food stuff, fuels, machinery and transport equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Belgium, South Africa and Finland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With rich agricultural land and extensive mineral and energy deposits, the Democratic Republic of Congo is potentially one of the richest countries on the African continent. However, decades of chronic neglect at the hands of the corrupt Mobutu left it as one of the poorest, with a per capita annual income of just US$150. Such plans as the Kabila governments may have had for development have been undermined by the civil war.<br /><br />At least two-thirds of the population are engaged in subsistence farming: farmers produce palm oil, coffee, tea, cocoa, rubber, cotton, tropical woods, fruit, vegetables and rice. Industry runs well below capacity due to a lack of spare parts and foreign exchange with which to buy them.<br /><br />The country could be one of the world's largest producers of copper and cobalt, but production is far short of its potential; what is produced has typically been sold by the warring party in control of the mine to finance continued fighting. (In some cases, mining concessions have been handed over to a government ally in exchange for military support: Zimbabwe, which controls several copper mines in the south is the most notable example.)<br /><br />The mining sector can also produce manganese, zinc, uranium and tin. There are also some oil deposits located off the short Atlantic coastline.<br /><br />Manufacturing for domestic consumption dominates the industrial sector, producing textiles, cement, food and beverages, wood products and plastics. <br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople should wear lightweight suits. Interpreter and translation services are available as business is mainly conducted in French. The best time to visit is in the cool season (which varies from one part of the country to another).<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1500, Sat 0730-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce, d'Industrie et d'Agriculture de la République Démocratique du Congo</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (12) 22286
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Congo&rsquo;s major towns and cities have a decent and eclectic array of caf&eacute;s, restaurants and bakeries that bear witness to a rich and complex cultural heritage. Influences include Chinese, Lebanese, French, Belgian, Italian, Arabic, Indian and even South African.</p>
<p>Many of the smarter restaurants and bars are found inside city hotels and lodges, where both food and accommodation can be expensive. For the more adventurous, Kinshasa&rsquo;s <em>Nganda</em> restaurants serve specialties from different regions of the Congo. A good local beer such as Primus or Skol to wash it all down is never far away.</p>
<p>In the bustling markets, which you&rsquo;ll find in any populated area, are full of weird and wonderful fruits, vegetables and local delicacies.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moambe:</strong> DRC&rsquo;s national dish consisting of chicken or fish with cassava leaves, hot pepper sauce, bananas, rice, peanuts, fish, chicken, and palm nuts.<br />
<strong>Chikwanga:</strong> Cassava cooked and stored in banana leaves.<br />
<strong>Fufu:</strong> A sticky, dough-like staple made from cassava flour.<br />
<strong>Pili Pili:</strong> Hot chilli sauce or paste served with almost everything.<br />
<strong>Satori:</strong> A tasty fish dish consisting of tilapia fillets fried with pumpkin seeds, plantains and garlic.<br />
<strong>Saka Saka:</strong> Ground cassava leaves cooked with palm oil, peanut paste, beans and salt fish.<br />
<strong>Maboke:</strong> A freshwater fish cooked in large marantacee leaves.<br />
<strong>Linguila:</strong> A wine made from fermented sugar cane.<br />
<strong>Palm wine:</strong> A tipple made from the sap of palm trees and fermented by natural yeasts.<br />
<strong>White elephant:</strong> A popular alcoholic drink made from rum, coconut and milk.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% service charge is added to hotel and restaurant bills. Extra tipping is unnecessary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kinshasa is the best place for nightlife, especially in the sprawling township of the <em>Cit&eacute;</em>, where most of the population live. In spite of recent political turmoil, the local music scene is thriving. There are hundreds of dance clubs in Kinshasa. Congolese music is popular throughout Africa as well as in Europe and the USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local craftware includes bracelets, ebony carvings and paintings. The large towns all have markets and shopping centres, selling everything from fresh ginger to baskets and African carvings.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1200 and 1500-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The difficult terrain has resulted in relatively few settlements except along river banks. Accommodation is essentially restricted to the main cities, and is virtually non-existent in the interior. For further details, contact the embassy (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>). The few hotels that cater for visitors are expensive and generally booked up well in advance. The majority of hotels are in Kinshasa, with others in Boma, Bukavu, Kerning, Kisangani, Kolwezi, Lubumbashi, Matadi, Mbandaka, Mbanzangunu and Muanda.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The difficult terrain has resulted in relatively few settlements except along river banks. Accommodation is essentially restricted to the main cities, and is virtually non-existent in the interior. For further details, contact the embassy (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>). The few hotels that cater for visitors are expensive and generally booked up well in advance. The majority of hotels are in Kinshasa, with others in Boma, Bukavu, Kerning, Kisangani, Kolwezi, Lubumbashi, Matadi, Mbandaka, Mbanzangunu and Muanda.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The difficult terrain has resulted in relatively few settlements except along river banks. Accommodation is essentially restricted to the main cities, and is virtually non-existent in the interior. For further details, contact the embassy (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>). The few hotels that cater for visitors are expensive and generally booked up well in advance. The majority of hotels are in Kinshasa, with others in Boma, Bukavu, Kerning, Kisangani, Kolwezi, Lubumbashi, Matadi, Mbandaka, Mbanzangunu and Muanda.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Government expenditure on health is low and the quality of hospitals is poor. It is advisable to take specific personal medicines as well as supplies such as syringes and drip needles, as medical facilities are available only in larger centres. Doctors and hospitals expect cash payment in full for health services. Health insurance is essential and it is advisable to include cover for emergency air evacuation.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Hepatitis B and E are present and meningococcal meningitis may occur. There is a very high risk of diarrhoeal diseases, the dysenteries and various parasitic worm infections. Ebola outbreaks have occurred. Avoid tick bites which spread African tick typhus. Wear shoes to avoid soil-borne parasites. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Commemoration of the Martyrs of Independence :
							2018<br/>04 January </p><p>National Heroes Day :
							2018<br/>17 January </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Liberation Day :
							17 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							30 June </p><p>Parents Day :
							01 August </p><p>Army Day :
							17 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Congo (Dem Rep) by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 100 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 227g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of alcoholic beverage.<br />
&bull; A reasonable amount of perfume for personal use.<br />
&bull; Cameras if temporarily imported by tourists.</p>
<p>Radios, audio equipment and gifts are subject to duty.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An import licence is required for arms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Franc Congolais (CDF) = 100 centimes. Owing to the precarious nature of the economy, the denominations of the currency are subject to rapid change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Because of the parlous state of the economy, the only true repository of value is the US Dollar. Free circulation of foreign currencies is now allowed within the country. Note that purchase of airline tickets within the country can be made only with money exchanged officially.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The use of MasterCard and Visa is limited to Kinshasa's major hotels. Credit cards cannot be used to obtain cash advances at banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not recommended. Commission fees are very high, and traveller's cheques are not accepted outside Kinshasa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1130.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Congo, a passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry transit visa: &pound;30; double-entry transit visa: &pound;60; one-month single-entry visa: &pound;60; one-month multiple-entry visa: &pound;90; two-month single-entry visa: &pound;100; two-month multiple-entry visa: &pound;120; three-month single-entry visa: &pound;140; three-month multiple-entry visa: &pound;150; six-month single-entry visa: &pound;180; six-month multiple-entry visa: &pound;220.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One to six months. You must use the visa within three months of the date of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow five to nine working days for visa processing if you apply in person and 10 to 18 days for postal applications. An express service of two to three days is available for an additional charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-2.861115]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[23.565674]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,345,410 sq km (905,563 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>79,722,624 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>33.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kinshasa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Democratic Republic of Congo is the third-largest country in Africa and is bordered to the north by the Central African Republic and Sudan, to the east by Uganda, Rwanda, Burundi and Tanzania, to the south by Zambia and Angola, and to the west by the Republic of Congo and the Angolan enclave, Cabinda. The country has a coastline of only 27km (17 miles), at the outlet of the Congo River, which flows into the Atlantic. The country straddles the equator and has widely differing geographical features, including mountain ranges in the north and west, a vast central plain through which the Congo River flows, and the volcanoes and lakes of the Kivu region. The river has given rise to extensive tropical rainforests on the western border with the Republic of Congo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic 50%, Islam 10%, Protestant 20%, indigenous beliefs 10% and Kimbanguist 10%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Casual clothes are widely suitable, although scanty beachwear should be confined to the beach or poolside.<br /><br /><strong>Photography:</strong> A permit is required. Even then, local authorities are likely to be sensitive. Avoid official areas, airports and riverbanks.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Bruno Tshibala since April 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Joseph Kabila since 2001.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Belgian Congo was created in 1885, essentially as the personal property of the Belgian monarch, King Leopold II. He provided only the minimum infrastructure necessary to support the extraction of the country's vast mineral wealth and killed an estimated 10 million Congolese, setting a pattern which has dominated this troubled country ever since.</p>
<p>By the end of WWII, the Belgian Congo had become one of the many African colonies whose occupiers were concerned simply to dispose of with minimum fuss and maximum commercial advantage.</p>
<p>The Belgian Congo was duly granted independence, with little preparation, in 1960. With the support of the Americans and Belgians &ndash; and through the exploitation of the country's myriad factional, tribal and regional disputes &ndash; the new government, headed by the visionary Patrice Lumumba, was deposed after just six months in an army coup led by Colonel Joseph Mobutu. Lumumba was executed.</p>
<p>Four years later, Mobutu took over as head of state and established the regime, which ruled Zaire, as the country was renamed, for the next three decades.</p>
<p>In the 30 years up to his demise, Mobutu Sese Seko (his adopted title) reduced the country to the point where it barely functioned as a nation state. The military campaign that finally brought down the Mobutu regime was triggered by the genocide in neighbouring Rwanda.</p>
<p>The genocide had been brought to an end by the intervention of the Rwandan Patriotic Front (RPF), a Tutsi-led force based in Uganda. The Hutu genocide perpetrators had mostly fled into north eastern Zaire. The RPF pursued them, but their incursion took on a different aspect and a momentum of its own as other groups, including many long-term exiled opponents of Mobutu, coalesced around the RPF.</p>
<p>Laurent Kabila was adopted as leader of this newly-formed anti-Mobutu coalition. By the autumn of 1996, the Alliance des Forces D&eacute;mocratiques pour la Liberation du Congo-Zaire (AFDL) had completed their takeover.</p>
<p>Once in power, however, Kabila proved incapable of ruling the country, which was renamed the Democratic Republic of Congo. Years of bloody civil war followed and culminated in the assassination of Kabila by one of his bodyguards in 2001.</p>
<p>He was succeeded by his son Joseph, who won disputed UN-guided general elections in 2006 and 2011. During Joseph Kabila&rsquo;s tenure, episodes of extreme rebel-led violence have continued to erupt sporadically in various regions, while Kabila&rsquo;s own human rights record has grown increasingly dubious.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Although it&rsquo;s one of the world&rsquo;s poorest countries, the DRC boasts a space program.<br />
&bull; Kinshasa and Brazzaville, just on the other side of the Congo River in the neighbouring Republic of Congo, are the closest capital cities in the world.<br />
&bull; The DRC covers a land area larger than the combined territories of Spain, France, Germany, Sweden, and Norway.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Democratic Republic of Congo]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>8155 66200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/democratic-republic-of-congo</p><p><b>Tel:</b>8155 66200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0730-1600; Fri 0730-1400.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Gombe<br/>83, Avenue Roi Baudoin<br/>Kinshasa<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Democratic Republic of Congo in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234 7690.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambardcusa.org/index.html</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234 7690.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1726 M Street, Suite 601<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Democratic Republic of Congo in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7580 3931.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ambardc-londres.gouv.cd/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7580 3931.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1100 (visa application); Wed-Fri 1100-1200 (collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>49 Great Portland Street<br/>London<br/>W1W 7LT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) is one of the largest and most enigmatic countries in Africa. It has many beautiful landscapes, mainly comprising dense and undulating rainforest interspersed with waterfalls and teeming with fascinating wildlife.</p>
<p>The great body of the Congo River runs across the northern reaches of the country and has long been a site of considerable historic importance, made famous by the explorer Henry Morton Stanley and later used as the backdrop for Joseph Conrad&rsquo;s Heart of Darkness.</p>
<p>In many ways, much of the DRC remains as wild and impenetrable today as it would have been in Conrad&rsquo;s time. The transport infrastructure built by the brutal Belgian colonial regime has largely been reclaimed by the jungle and there are few links between the country&rsquo;s vast interior and the urban areas dotted around its fringes.</p>
<p>Kinshasa, the capital, is situated in the far west of the country and, though largely impoverished and crumbling, it is a veritable hub for colourful African music and culture.</p>
<p>DRC&rsquo;s tourist capital, if such a thing exists, is Goma, which sits on the banks of Lake Kivu in the far east of the country. It is presided over by the imposing Nyiragongo volcano, which sits at the heart of Virunga National Park, the oldest national park in Africa and one of just a handful of places where you can still see mountain gorillas in their natural habitat.</p>
<p>Goma and the mineral-rich Kivu region were hit particularly hard by a civil war from 1998 to 2003 that resulted in the deaths of at least three million people; sporadic bouts of violence since the war officially ended have continued to burden the region&rsquo;s considerable tourist potential.</p>
<p>However, peace and a semblance of stability have returned to Goma for the time being and small handfuls of adventurous tourists are beginning to trickle across the border once again. Visitors are advised to check the latest travel advice before visiting.</p><p>The Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) is one of the largest and most enigmatic countries in Africa. It has many beautiful landscapes, mainly comprising dense and undulating rainforest interspersed with waterfalls and teeming with fascinating wildlife. A&nbsp;brutal civil war from 1998 to 2003 has burdened the country's considerable tourist potential, but&nbsp;peace and a semblance of stability have returned for the time being and small handfuls of adventurous tourists are beginning to trickle across the border once again.&nbsp;Visitors are advised to check the latest travel advice before visiting.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
