<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Denmark" ColCode="dnk" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="dk" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Denmark]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Summer extends from June to August, which are also the best months to visit. Winter is from December to March, and tends to be wet with long periods of frost and dark days. Spring and autumn are generally mild.<br />
<br />
The Faroe Islands are under the influence of the warm current of the Gulf Stream, and they enjoy a very mild climate for the latitude. Winters are warm, but the islands are cloudy, windy and wet throughout the year. Summers are cool, but with little sunshine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight for summer and heavyweight for winter snows.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internal flights in Denmark are served by a network of scheduled services&nbsp;from Copenhagen (Kastrup). Other airports well served by domestic airlines include &Aring;lborg, &Aring;rhus, Billund, Bornholm, Karup and S&oslash;nderborg. Domestic airports are generally situated between two or more cities that are within easy reach of each other. Internal flights are usually of no more than 30 minutes' duration. SAS (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flysas.com/">www.flysas.com</a>) is the main domestic carrier.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are frequent ferry sailings from Kalundborg to &Aring;rhus, Ebeltoft to Sj&aelig;llands Odde and R&oslash;nne to Copenhagen. The larger ferries usually have restaurants or caf&eacute;s and may have TV, video and cinema lounges, shops, play areas for children and sleeping rooms. Local car ferries link most islands to the road network.</p>
<p>The principal domestic ferry operator is Scandlines (tel: +45 3315 1515; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.scandlines.dk/">www.scandlines.dk</a>). Ferries to Bornholm island are operated by F&aelig;rgen (tel: +45 7023 1515; <a href="http://www.faergen.com" target="_blank">www.faergen.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main cities on all islands are connected to the rail network: &Aring;lborg, Copenhagen, Esbjerg, Herning, Horsens, Odense and Randers. Danish State Railways (DSB) (tel: +45 7013 1415; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.dsb.dk/">www.dsb.dk</a>) operates a number of express trains called Lyntogs which provide long-distance, non-stop travel. Intercity IC3 trains are faster and more direct. Seat reservations are compulsory. Children under 10 years old travel free. There are also price reductions for passengers over 65 and groups of eight people or more.</p>
<p>DSB passenger fares are based on a zonal system. The cost depends on the distance travelled; the cost per kilometre is reduced the longer the journey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Denmark. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Danish Motoring Organisation is Forenede Danske Motorejere (FDM) (tel: +45 7013 3040; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.fdm.dk/">www.fdm.dk</a>).</p>r<p>The road system in the Danish archipelago makes frequent use of ferries.</p><p>A national driving licence is acceptable. EU nationals taking their own cars to Denmark are strongly advised to obtain a Green Card. Without it, insurance cover is limited to the minimum legal cover in Denmark; the Green Card tops this up to the level of cover provided by the car owner's domestic policy.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 110kph (68mph) on motorways, 80kph (50mph) on other roads and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas (signified by white plates with town silhouettes). Speed laws are strictly enforced, and heavy fines are levied on the spot; the car is impounded if payment is not made. Drivers must keep their headlights switched on at all times, including during the day.&nbsp;Children under 12 years old need to travel in the rear of the car.</p><p>Dansk Autohj&aelig;lp A/S (tel: +45 7010 8090).</p><p>Generally available to drivers over the age of 21, and can be reserved through travel agents or airlines. <a href="https://www.hertzdk.dk/rentacar/reservation/ " target="www.hertzdk.dk/rentacar/reservation/ ">Hertz</a> requires a minimum age of 19 years. However, many firms will only hire vehicles out to drivers over 25 years of age. All major international firms are represented.</p><p>There are cycle lanes along many roads and, in the countryside, many miles of scenic cycle track. It's easy to take bikes on ferries, trains, buses and domestic air services.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 110kph (68mph) on motorways, 80kph (50mph) on other roads and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas (signified by white plates with town silhouettes). Speed laws are strictly enforced, and heavy fines are levied on the spot; the car is impounded if payment is not made. Drivers must keep their headlights switched on at all times, including during the day.&nbsp;Children under 12 years old need to travel in the rear of the car.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Copenhagen has an integrated bus and urban train network, known as S-tog (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.dsb.dk/s-tog">www.dsb.dk/s-tog</a>), as well as a metro (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.m.dk/">www.m.dk</a>). Taxi fares include a tip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Denmark</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">soslashnderborg</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.45</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Denmark</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">esberg</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.12</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Denmark</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">aringrhus</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.08</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Denmark</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">aringlborg</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main carrier is SAS<em>&nbsp;</em>(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flysas.com">www.flysas.com</a>). Other airlines offering direct flights from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>), Norwegian (<a href="http://www.norwegian.com" target="_blank">www.norwegian.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>).&nbsp;</p>
<p>The major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/denmark/copenhagen-airport">Copenhagen Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/billund-airport">Billund Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 1 hour 50 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours 35 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Copenhagen Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.cph.dk<p>Copenhagen Airport is located 8km (5 miles) southeast of Copenhagen.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+45 3231 3231</p>]]><b>Århus Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport  is 44km (27 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Billund Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bll.dk<p>The airport is located 2km (1.2 miles) northeast of central Billund.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+45 7650 5050</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Copenhagen (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.cmport.com/">www.cmport.com</a>), Esbjerg (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.port-of-esbjerg.dk/">www.port-of-esbjerg.dk</a>), Frederikshavn (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.frederikshavn.dk/">www.frederikshavn.dk</a>), Hanstholm and Hirtshals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Copenhagen is connected by rail to all other major European cities. Typical express journey times to Copenhagen are: from London - 15 hours (including changes); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hamburg">Hamburg</a>&nbsp;- 5 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/berlin">Berlin</a>&nbsp;- 7 hours 30 minutes. All international trains connect with ferries where applicable.</p>
<p>The national rail company is Danish State Railways (DSB)<em> </em>(tel: +45 7013 1415; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.dsb.dk/">www.dsb.dk</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Scanrail</strong><strong> Pass:</strong><em> </em>allows unlimited travel within Denmark, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/finland">Finland</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/norway">Norway</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sweden">Sweden</a>.&nbsp;Valid for three, four, five or eight days within one month. Available to visitors from outside the EU only from Eurail.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is excellent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafés are available in most urban areas, and most hotels offer a Wi-Fi connection in rooms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A free press operates under Danish law and the media, which cover a broad range of political views, are frequently critical of government policy. Danmarks Radio (DR), funded by a licence fee, is Denmark's main public broadcaster, operating two TV networks as well as national and regional radio stations. TV2, a national public-service TV station, is partly state funded. Private satellite and cable TV stations also exist. Newspapers are largely regional: the main papers in the capital include Berlingske Tidende, Dagbladet Information, Ekstra Bladet and Politiken. English-language newspapers and magazines are also available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All telephone and postal rates are printed at the post offices.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1730, some are open Sat 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Kronborg Castle</p><![CDATA[<p>Follow in the fictional footsteps of Hamlet to Elsinore (Helsing&oslash;r in Danish), where the mighty 16th-century Kronborg Castle (<a href="http://www.kronborgcastle.com/" target="_blank">www.kronborgcastle.com</a>) watches over the waters of &Oslash;resund and the nearby Swedish coast. Kronborg Castle is of great historical importance playing a key  role in the history of Northern Europe during the 16th to 18th  centuries.</p>

Address: Kronborg 2c, 3000 Elsinore, Denmark]]><br/><p>Legoland</p><![CDATA[<p>Take the kids to Legoland at Billund (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.legoland.dk/">www.legoland.dk</a>), which is open from April to October. The renowned ten-hectare (25-acre) amusement park located north of  Billund features attractions and rides built from no less than 40  million plastic LEGO blocks. Shows are performed daily by the Children's  Theatre, and there are also circus acts in high season. Adults and  children can marvel at the detailed LEGO reconstructions of famous  sights from around the world in Miniland; Duplo Land, with its chunkier  bricks, is particularly popular with younger children. Other popular  attractions include Pirateland and Castleland.&nbsp;</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Amalienborg Palace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take in the pomp at Amalienborg Palace (<a href="http://kongehuset.dk/" target="_blank">http://kongehuset.dk</a>), the royal winter residence in the centre of Copenhagen. It is worth being there at 1200, when the daily changing of the ceremonial guard takes place.</p>]]><p><b>Assistens Cemetery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Assistens Cemetery is not just a resting place for the dead it is used by many as a park for picnicking. Residents of interest include Hans Christian Anderson and Søren Kierkegaard.</p>]]><p><b>Audio walk of Copenhagen</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Combine fiction and reality with an audio walk. Listeners choose a route, (downloaded from <a href="http://www.flamingoeffekten.dk/" target="_blank">www.flamingoeffekten.dk</a>) and are guided around the city by an author. It's essentially an interactive podcast.</p>]]><p><b>Birthplace of Hans Christian Andersen</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relive childhood with a visit to the birthplace of the great fairytale writer Hans Christian Andersen in Odense. Visitors can also have a look around the Hans Christian Andersen Museum (<a href="http://www.museum.odense.dk/" target="_blank">www.museum.odense.dk</a>) and his childhood home.</p>]]><p><b>Book a treatment</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spoil yourself with a relaxing treatment from a health resort, which are widespread throughout the country. Some offer medical and physiotherapeutic treatments, others simply offer recreation in beautiful quiet surroundings.</p>]]><p><b>Carlsberg Brewery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pay homage to one of the world's best-known beers at the famous Carlsberg Brewery (<a href="http://www.carlsberggroup.com/" target="_blank">www.carlsberggroup.com</a>), which is a short train ride from Copenhagen's central station, and has an extensive visitor centre telling the story of the company and its products.</p>]]><p><b>Cycle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the most cycle-friendly countries in the world, exploring Denmark by bike is easy. For details, contact the Danish Cyclists' Association, <em>Dansk Cyklist Forbund</em> (<a href="http://www.dcf.dk/" target="_blank">www.dcf.dk</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Dansk Design Center</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Contemplate how cluttered your house is after being inspired by typically sleek and minimal Danish interior design at the Dansk Design Center (<a href="http://www.ddc.dk" target="_blank">www.ddc.dk</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Fisheries and Maritime Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Outside Esbjerg, a strong tide often orphans seal pups. Many are rescued and taken to this museum where visitors can have a peek (and fall in love) with these irresistibly cute baby animals.</p>]]><p><b>Geocenter Møns Klint</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Keep the kids busy by tracing Denmark's geological history at the Geocenter Møns Klint, which opened in 2007 on Sjælland island (<a href="http://www.moensklint.dk/" target="_blank">www.moensklint.dk</a>). The centre illustrates how the modern land and seascape of the country were formed.</p>]]><p><b>Go fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Denmark has excellent facilities for both freshwater and saltwater angling. Sea-fishing tours can be arranged with local fishermen at many Danish harbours.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the shops on Strøget</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From upmarket shops with designer brands to intimate boutiques, Strøget is a car-free shopper's paradise where too much choice often leads to a badly bruised credit card.</p>]]><p><b>KUNSTEN Museum of Modern Art Aalborg </b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated in the heart of North Jutland, KUNSTEN is a delight for all visitors. With a permanent collection of about 1,500 pieces of art, a Sculpture Park and Water Pavilion, it also offers activities, delectable delicacies and top-notch shopping.</p>]]><p><b>Kronborg Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Follow in the fictional footsteps of Hamlet to Elsinore (Helsing&oslash;r in Danish), where the mighty 16th-century Kronborg Castle (<a href="http://www.kronborgcastle.com/" target="_blank">www.kronborgcastle.com</a>) watches over the waters of &Oslash;resund and the nearby Swedish coast. Kronborg Castle is of great historical importance playing a key  role in the history of Northern Europe during the 16th to 18th  centuries.</p>]]><p><b>Learn to kayak polo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ever heard of kayak polo? Well, you soon will as it's a popular sport in Denmark and the largest facility to learn it is in Copenhagen. You need to be in good shape though, if not, opt for a kayak tour through Christianhavn's canals and the Harbour.</p>]]><p><b>Legoland</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take the kids to Legoland at Billund (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.legoland.dk/">www.legoland.dk</a>), which is open from April to October. The renowned ten-hectare (25-acre) amusement park located north of  Billund features attractions and rides built from no less than 40  million plastic LEGO blocks. Shows are performed daily by the Children's  Theatre, and there are also circus acts in high season. Adults and  children can marvel at the detailed LEGO reconstructions of famous  sights from around the world in Miniland; Duplo Land, with its chunkier  bricks, is particularly popular with younger children. Other popular  attractions include Pirateland and Castleland.&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Marelisborg Palace and gardens in Århus</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In summer, do as the Danish royal family does and take a trip to &Aring;rhus. Their summer residence is the Marselisborg Castle (<a href="http://www.kongehuset.dk/" target="_blank">www.kongehuset.dk</a>), whose grounds are open to the public when the Queen is not in residence. Being the European culture capital in 2017 &Aring;rhus has much more to offer to its visitors.</p>]]><p><b>Pig out</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stop at a <em>pølsevogn</em> (sausage stall) to savour the nation's favourite snack, the hot dog. These can be found almost anywhere there are people, and at any time of day or night.</p>]]><p><b>Play a round of golf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Denmark (whose Thomas Bjørn is one of Europe's best-known golfers) has numerous courses, many of championship standard, among them Holstebro (<a href="http://www.holstebro-golfklub.dk/" target="_blank">www.holstebro-golfklub.dk</a>), in the northwest, and Simon's (<a href="http://www.simonsgolf.dk/" target="_blank">www.simonsgolf.dk</a>), north of the capital.</p>]]><p><b>Strip off</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Be daring, and go nude bathing. This is quite common at Danish seaside resorts. The only beaches where it is actually prohibited are Henne Strand and Holmsland Klit (both on Jutland's western coast).</p>]]><p><b>The Light Visions Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The usually quiet harbour town of Frederikshavn lights up with artist installations for two weeks each October. Neon structures and lighting experimentation take over the small city creating a cultural buzz that transforms Frederikshavn into a 'city of light'.</p>]]><p><b>Viking Ship Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Retrace Denmark's Viking heritage at the Viking Ship Museum at Roskilde (<a href="http://www.vikingeskibsmuseet.dk/" target="_blank">www.vikingeskibsmuseet.dk</a>), around 30km (19 miles) from Copenhagen, featuring five ancient vessels rescued from the waters of the harbour.</p>]]><p><b>Ålborg Viking site</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the largest-remaining Viking burial site at the city of Ålborg, which also counts a castle, a cathedral and a monastery among its attractions, and is the home of a well-known variety of akkevit spirit (a spiced schnapps-type drink).</p>]]><p><b>Århus Teater</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Århus Teater (<a href="http://www.aarhusteater.dk/" target="_blank">www.aarhusteater.dk</a>) - the town's architectural pride and joy. Designed in art nouveau style by Hack Kampmann, it opened in 1900 and has been the venue for many critically acclaimed productions. It has five stages and its very own theatre troupe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$308 billion (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, food, chemicals, wind turbines and furniture.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Consumer goods, chemicals, food, petroleum and raw materials.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK, USA, Sweden, Norway and Germany.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The standard of living is generally high. Compared to most industrialised countries, Denmark retains a large and important agricultural sector, two-thirds of whose produce is exported.<br /><br />Most of Denmark's trade is conducted within the EU, of which it is a member, although it has proved reluctant to adopt measures that are perceived as threatening to its sovereignty. It has thus so far refused to join the single European currency zone.<br /><br />Recent economic performance has been steady: inflation (1.3%) and unemployment (4.3%) are better than the EU averages. In 2009, annual growth was estimated at -4.3%.<br /><br />Denmark is a member of the Nordic Union. Its links with Scandinavia were further enhanced by the Øresund road and rail bridge linking it to Sweden, which opened in 2000. The Malmö/Copenhagen region is now increasingly integrated economically.<br />Copenhagen is home to Scandinavia's largest convention centre, the Bella Center, near the airport. Further sizeable conference facilities can be found at Odense, Aalborg and Aaarhus.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local businesspeople expect visitors to be punctual and the approach to business is often direct and straightforward. Avoid business visits from mid June to mid August, which are prime holiday periods.<br />
<br />
Business contacts should shake hands on arrival and departure, with business cards exchanged after introduction. Most Danes, particularly those in the international business community, speak excellent English and some speak German and French too. <br />
<br />
Business visitors can expect to be well looked after. Nearly all meetings are held in non-smoking venues but moderate alcohol consumption over a business lunch or dinner is not inappropriate.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700 (some offices close earlier on Fridays).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Handelskskammeret (Danish Chamber of Commerce)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 7733 4711
					Website:http://www.hts.dk/
					Address: Postboks 2698,Sundkrogskai 20,DK-2100 Copenhagen,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Given its geographical position, it is not surprising that fish forms an important part of Danish cuisine. Around a dozen restaurants in Denmark, the majority in the capital, boast Michelin star or 'rising star' status. Most towns have fast food outlets, and sausage (<em>p&oslash;lser</em>) stalls also offering soft drinks and beer. There are no licensing hours.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Sm&oslash;rrebr&oslash;d is a traditional lunchtime Danish dish consisting of a slice of dark bread with butter, topped with sliced meat, fish or cheese<em>.</em><br />
&bull; Buffet-style lunch (the <em>koldt bord</em>) is also popular with a variety of fish, meats, hot dishes, cheese and sweets, usually on a self-service basis. <br />
&bull; A normal Danish breakfast, or <em>morgen-complet</em>, consists of an assortment of breads, rolls, jam and cheese, often also sliced meats, boiled eggs and warm Danish pastries. <br />
<strong><strong><br />
National drinks:</strong></strong><br />
&bull; Scandinavian coffee is usually drunk strong and black. <br />
&bull; Denmark also has many varieties of beer, famous breweries being <em>Carlsberg</em> and <em>Tuborg</em>. Most popular is <em>pilsner</em> (lager) but there are also specialist beers, notably those produced by <em>Jakobsen</em>, whose brewery is located at the original Carlsberg installation. <br />
<em>&bull; Akvavit</em>, popularly known as schnapps, is meant to be drunk with cold food or at Christmas, preferably with a beer chaser. It is served ice cold.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>The Danish Hotel and Restaurant Association displays signs indicating restaurants where the needs of diabetics are given special attention. It consists of the words '<em>Diabetes mad - sund mad for alle</em>' ('Food for Diabetics - healthy food for everyone') encircling a chef's head.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Hotels and restaurants quote fully inclusive prices and tipping is not necessary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide selection of nightlife, particularly in Copenhagen. &Aring;rhus and &Aring;lborg are also lively in the evenings. Jazz and dance clubs in the capital city are top quality and world-famous performers appear regularly. There are numerous caf&eacute;s, beer gardens and speciality beer bars. Entertainment includes opera at the recently opened opera house in Copenhagen, ballet and theatre at a number of venues in the larger cities, and live music of all kinds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Copenhagen has excellent shopping facilities. Special purchases include Bing &amp; Gr&oslash;ndal and Royal Copenhagen porcelain, Holmeg&aring;rd glass, Bornholm ceramics, handmade woollens from the Faroe Islands and <em>Lego</em> toys. Visitors from outside the EU can often claim back some of the <em>MOMS</em> (VAT) on goods purchased that are sent straight to their home country from the shop in Denmark.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900/1000-1730/1800, Sat 0900-1700. Supermarkets are often open Mon-Fri 0900-2000. Opening hours vary from town to town. At some holiday resorts, bakers, florists and souvenir shops are open Sunday and public holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Denmark can be booked at one of the provincial tourist offices. Denmark's fine beaches attract many visitors, and there are hotels and pensions in all major seaside resorts.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Excellent inns are to be found all over Denmark. Some are small and only cater for local custom, but others are tailored to the tourist and have established culinary reputations for both international dishes and local specialities. For further details, contact VisitDenmark.</p><br />There are private rooms to let, usually for one night, all over Denmark. Signs along the highway with <em>zimmer frei </em>or <em>vårelse </em>on them indicate availability of accommodation. In Copenhagen, rooms can be booked in person through the Tourist Information Department (see <em>Accommodation Information</em>) for a small fee. Local tourist offices may be contacted, either by writing or in person.]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Denmark can be booked at one of the provincial tourist offices. Denmark's fine beaches attract many visitors, and there are hotels and pensions in all major seaside resorts.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Denmark can be booked at one of the provincial tourist offices. Denmark's fine beaches attract many visitors, and there are hotels and pensions in all major seaside resorts.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;If suddenly taken ill or involved in an accident during a visit to an EEA country, such as Denmark, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available for European travellers - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). Comprehensive insurance is advised for all other nationals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, health risks in Denmark are few and far between, with most visitors likely to suffer nothing more serious than a few blisters from hiking or insect bites in the summer. Standards of healthcare are high and chemist shops&amp;nbsp;can be found on most high streets.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;There's nothing to mark out Danish food as particularly risky to general health, in fact food hygiene standards are very high across the country. The tap water is also safe to drink. However, resist the temptation to drink from streams or lakes, no matter how clean they look, as they may contain pollutants.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;There are few risks associated with travelling to Denmark. Tick-borne encephalitis poses a minor risk in Bornholm Island and vaccination is advisable if you plan to visit. Other than that sunburn is likely to be the main issue. The usual precautions apply: use a generous amount of sunscreen and be sensible about how long you spend in direct sunlight. Be aware that a breezy day can sometimes mask high temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Maundy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Great Prayer Day :
							27 April </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Constitution Day :
							05 June </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Denmark is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices. There are no longer any allowance restrictions on these tax-free items.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> The Faroe Islands and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greenland">Greenland</a> are not part of the EU.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22%, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%, 90L of wine and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>Tobacco and spirit allowances apply to travellers aged 18 and over. Beer and wine allowances apply to travellers aged 16 and over.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Denmark by travellers aged 17 or over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of kr3,250 for air and sea travellers and kr2,250 for other travellers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted goods include narcotics, meat and dairy products, medicine, pets, wild animals and plants and their products, weapons and explosives, fireworks and pesticides.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Danish Krone (DKK; symbol kr) = 100 øre. Notes are in denominations of kr1,000, 500, 200, 100 and 50. Coins are in denominations of kr20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 and 50 øre.<br /><br />The 25 øre coin was removed from circulation in October 2008 but will be accepted by banks until 1 October 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Personal cheques cannot be used by visitors to Denmark. Some banks may refuse to exchange large foreign bank notes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted. There are plenty of ATMs.</p><p>There are plenty of ATMs across Denmark, especially in the major towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers cheques can be cashed by banks and hotels, and can be used at most restaurants and shops. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros, Pounds Sterling or US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon to Wed and Fri 0930-1700, Thurs 0930-1800. Some banks in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/denmark/copenhagen-airport">Copenhagen</a> are open Mon-Fri 0930-1700. Some bureaux de change are open until 2400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Denmark is a signatory to the 1995 Schengen Agreement.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay Schengen visa: &euro;60/&pound;48.</p>
<p>The normal Schengen visa is not valid for travel to the Faroe Islands or Greenland. To visit these destinations, nationals requiring a visa must apply for a Schengen visa from a Danish mission with the wording 'Valid for the Faroe Islands' or 'Valid for Greenland' on the visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors travelling on a Schengen visa must travel within three months from the date of issue of the visa. It is valid for 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). UK residents requiring a visa should apply to VFS Global (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/denmark/uk/">http://www.vfsglobal.com/denmark/uk/</a>). All visa applicants must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications for Schengen visas are usually completed within 15 days, but may take up to 60 days if they require additional processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa applicants are required to prove they have adequate funds to support their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa holders can only extend their visas in exceptional circumstances, such as <em>force majeure</em> or for humanitarian reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet from another EU country, the animal must have a microchip or tattoo, an EU pet passport and a valid rabies vaccination certificate. Animals from outside the EU must also have a microchip or tattoo and rabies vaccination certificate along with a veterinary certificate issued by an authorised veterinarian.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[56.101978]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[9.556011]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>43,098 sq km (16,640 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5,699,715 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>129.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Copenhagen.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Denmark is the smallest Scandinavian country, consisting of the Jutland peninsula, north of Germany, and over 400 islands of various sizes, some inhabited and linked to the mainland by ferry or bridge. The landscape consists mainly of low-lying, fertile countryside broken by beech woods, small lakes and fjords. Greenland and the Faroe Islands are also under the sovereignty of the Kingdom of Denmark, although both have home rule. The Faroe Islands is a group of 18 islands in the North Atlantic inhabited by a population of 49,947 (2014), whose history dates back to the Viking period. Fishing and sheep farming are the two most important occupations. T&oacute;rshavn, the capital of the Faroes, is served by direct flights from Copenhagen. During the summer months, there are direct flights from Aberdeen and Glasgow.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly Evangelical Lutheran with small Roman Catholic and Muslim minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal courtesies should be observed. Guests should refrain from drinking until the host toasts his or her health. Casual dress is suitable for most places but formal wear is required at more exclusive dining rooms and social functions. Smoking is banned on public transport and in public buildings. Smoking is only allowed in bars smaller than 40 sq metres (131 sq ft) and most restaurants and pubs have designated outdoor smoking areas.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are used, sometimes with a third grounding pin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Lars L&oslash;kke Rasmussen since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Queen Margrethe II since 1972.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Inhabited since before the Stone Age, the first tribal Danes arrived during the Iron Age and established trading links with the Roman Empire. In the later centuries of the first millennium the Danes, or Vikings, were fiercely colonial seafaring explorers who raided, traded and upbraided lands from Iceland to Canada and by the early 1000s they had colonised lands in England, Ireland and France.</p>
<p>Having converted to Christianity the Vikings were at their most powerful in the early 11th century, when Cnut the Great created a united Anglo-Danish kingdom with Norway that held for nearly 30 years. (The story of Cnut demonstrating that he could not fight the tide, thereby illustrating that secular power is in vain compared to the power of God, is apocryphal.)</p>
<p>Denmark's power peaked in the early 13th century, by which time Cnut&rsquo;s successors had taken control of Scandinavia, parts of modern-day Germany and Estonia. This empire rapidly disintegrated and although Denmark, Norway and Sweden were reunited in the late 14th century through blood ties between their ruling families, the three nations spent much of the ensuing 350 years in near permanent conflict with one another.</p>
<p>After establishing colonies in India, West Africa and the West Indies during the 17th century, Denmark discovered its libertarian heart and in the wake of the bloody People&rsquo;s Spring democratic revolutions in France, Germany, Austro-Hungary, the Netherlands, Italy, Poland and other European countries in 1848, Denmark peacefully became a constitutional monarchy.</p>
<p>Its lost appetite for war resulted in climactic defeat to Prussia and the Austrian Habsburg Empire and the cessation of Schleswig-Holstein in 1864. Afterwards Denmark sought to remain neutral in Europe and signed a non-aggression pact with Nazi Germany in 1939. Months later it was invaded.</p>
<p>In the post-war era, Denmark co-founded NATO and the European Free Trade Association, joined the EEC (now the EU) in 1973 and rejected the Euro in 2000. Since 1953 Denmark&rsquo;s single-chamber parliament has been elected by proportional representation, making coalition administrations a standard feature.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Denmark&rsquo;s largest island Zealand is home to 2.5 million people, about 45 per cent of the population.<br />
&bull;	Denmark&rsquo;s most famous literary figure Hans Christian Andersen was a great admirer of Charles Dickens, but a five-week stay with the author ended when Andersen was asked to leave.<br />
&bull;	In 2014 stegt fl&aelig;sk &ndash; crisp fried strips of pork belly served with potatoes and parsley sauce &ndash; was voted the national dish.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Denmark in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7333 0200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://storbritannien.um.dk/en/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7333 0200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1630, Fri 0900-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>55 Sloane Street<br/>London<br/>SW1X 9SR<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Denmark in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234 4300.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://usa.um.dk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234 4300.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3200 Whitehaven Street<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Denmark]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(45) 3544 5200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukindenmark.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(45) 3544 5200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Kastelsvej 36-40<br/>DK-2100 Copenhagen<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It might not have the azure fjords and soaring peaks of Sweden and Norway, but Denmark, the smallest of the four Scandinavian countries, has a unique charm that is all its own.&nbsp;</p>
<p>A land of flat farmland pockmarked with Viking burial mounds, the peace of the Danish countryside belies a historical reputation for terror and a modern one for producing some of the finest murder mysteries on television.</p>
<p>Copenhagen, the capital, is a cool, cosmopolitan city whose debonair inhabitants foster an affable atmosphere more typical of a small town than capital city.&nbsp;Synonymous with bold architecture and cutting-edge design, Copenhagen is also a culinary pioneer. The city&rsquo;s cobbled streets and windswept squares harbour some of the best restaurants in the world, most notably Noma, the brilliant brainchild of Rene Redzepi.</p>
<p>The suburbs also sparkle. There&rsquo;s Vesterbro, made famous by the hit television show, The Killing, and Nyhavn, best known for its quaint harbour, colourful merchants&rsquo; houses and throbbing nightlife.</p>
<p>But there&rsquo;s more to Denmark than its cool capital. Zealand, the island on which Copenhagen sits, is also home to Roskilde &ndash; once the Viking capital of Denmark. Along with a soaring UNESCO-listed cathedral, there&rsquo;s a museum housing one of the best-preserved Viking ships ever uncovered and a smattering of pretty caf&eacute;s, shops and galleries.</p>
<p>To the north, on the main Jutland peninsular, there&rsquo;s more Viking fun to be had; from visiting the mighty runestones at Jelling to tucking into a Viking supper at Lindholm H&oslash;je.</p>
<p>Smaller rural towns such as Vejle and Aarhus offer have a lot to offer in the form of art galleries and adventure activities such as kayaking, hiking or horse riding.</p>
<p>Of all Denmark&rsquo;s towns, though, none is lovelier than Skagen. A seaside settlement at the tip of the Jutland peninsular, it is a favourite amongst Danish families, who come to bask on golden beaches and watch scintillating Scandinavian sunsets.</p><p>It might not have the azure fjords and soaring peaks of Sweden and Norway, but Denmark, the smallest of the four Scandinavian countries, has a unique charm that is all its own.</p>
<p>A land of flat farmland pockmarked with Viking burial mounds, the peace of the Danish countryside belies a historical reputation for terror and a modern one for producing some of the finest murder mysteries on television.&nbsp;Copenhagen, the capital, is a cool, cosmopolitan city whose debonair inhabitants foster an affable atmosphere more typical of a small town than capital city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
