<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Dominica" ColCode="dma" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="dm" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Dominica]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dominica has a hot and subtropical year-round climate. June to October is the principle rainy season, when it is at its hottest and most humid; December through to May is generally thought the best months to visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens. Keep waterproofing close at hand as showers can occur year-round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>Roads are well maintained in and around Roseau, but total just 700km (450 miles).&nbsp;Traffic is scarce outside Roseau.</p><p>These are efficient, and rates are set by law, so taxi drivers don't expect tips.</p><p>International Driving Permit recommended. A valid foreign licence can be used to get a Temporary Visitor's Permit.</p><p>There is a 32kph (20mph) speed limit in towns and villages. Visiting drivers must be between 25 and 65 years old and have had at least two years' driving experience in order to apply for a local driver's permit.</p><p>Available, but rural roads can be tricky to navigate.</p><p>There is a 32kph (20mph) speed limit in towns and villages. Visiting drivers must be between 25 and 65 years old and have had at least two years' driving experience in order to apply for a local driver's permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Dominica (Commonwealth of)</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">portsmouth</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Dominica (Commonwealth of)</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">melville_hall_airport</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Dominica (Commonwealth of)</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">canefield_airport</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main airline to serve Dominica is LIAT (<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.liat.com" target="_blank">www.liat.com</a></span>). There are no direct, non-stop flights from Europe or the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, mostly because the two airports are too small for jets. Popular routes from Europe are via Antigua, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/barbados">Barbados</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-lucia">St Lucia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guadeloupe">Guadeloupe</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/puerto-rico">Puerto Rico</a>, then a local flight to Dominica.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/roseau">Roseau</a> from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> via Antigua is approximately 10 hours (depending on length of stopover), and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> is 7 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EC$55 (US$21). Transit passengers continuing their journey on the same day and children under 12 years of age are exempt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Canefield Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Melville Hall Airport</b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong>&nbsp;Woodbridge Bay, Roseau and Prince Rupert Bay, Portsmouth.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>TDMA (Time division multiple access) network with unregistered roaming is available for users with TDMA handsets provided they can give a credit card number. Handsets can be hired.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Access is available at the offices of <em>Cable & Wireless </em>in Roseau, at an Internet cafe and in some hotels. Connections tend to be slow.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no daily newspapers in Dominica; newspapers are in English and include <em>The Chronicle</em>, <em>The Sun </em>and <em>The Tropical Star</em>. There is no national television service, but a private cable TV network covers part of the island, and there is a mix of public and private radio stations. All media are free from Government interference.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no Poste Restante facilities. The main post office is located at Bayfront, Roseau. Mail takes one to three weeks to arrive in Europe and the USA.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600; smaller branches: 1500-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Buckle up for a jeep safari</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Dominica's hidden reaches by jeep and experience a tranquil contrast to bustling Roseau. Once you've arrived at some of the more remote spots, you can scour forests for birdlife and marvel at vibrant tropical blooms nestling amongst rock crevices and moss-covered scrub.</p>]]><p><b>Delve into the Central Forest Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This beautiful reserve is home to a vast population of gommier trees whose wood has provided building and craft material to Caribs for hundreds of years. Visitors can drive through the reserve, which was established in 1952, and enjoy the surrounding greenery, lakes and rivers.</p>]]><p><b>Dive into crystalline water</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The warm waters of Dominica are perfect for scuba diving and snorkelling, especially at Soufrière, where dramatic volcanic cliffs tumble into the sea. Visibility is excellent with some of the best, lesser-known snorkelling spots reached by kayaking along the coast.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the heat at Boiling Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Morne Trois Pitons National Park is home to the Boiling Lake: a steaming basin of bubbling liquid found at an altitude of 762m (2,500ft). Only reachable by foot, it is highly recommended that anyone undertaking the 7-mile journey from Laudat is accompanied by a guide.</p>]]><p><b>Follow the L'Escalier Tête Chien</b></p><![CDATA[<p>L'Escalier Tête Chien (which, in French Creole, means "Stairway of the Snake's Head") is an impressive rock formation jutting out into the Atlantic, and is found in the Carib Territory. It's perhaps one of the most sacred sites on the whole island.</p>]]><p><b>Go whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The waters surrounding Dominica are teeming with marine life, most notably cetaceans. Sperm whales, pilot whales and pygmy whales all glide around the coast, as do Atlantic and spotted dolphins. Dominica is the only country in the world where the sperm whale stays all year long, although sightings are most common between November and March.</p>]]><p><b>Have a bath at Soufriere Sulphur Springs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If Dominica's balmy climate isn't hot enough for you, take a dip in these sultry springs. Locals believe the water here has healing properties and some Dominicans even sip small amounts of it to cleanse themselves. We don't recommend that, but we do recommend a dip in the springs, which leave bathers feeling revitalised.</p>]]><p><b>Hike in Morne Trois Pitons National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stretch your legs amid the lush greenery, towering trees and exotic foliage in Morne Trois Pitons National Park. With its steep slopes and deep valleys, visitors can stumble upon hot springs, freshwater lakes and five volcanoes. The park presents a heady mix of natural features, which earned it a place on UNESCO's list of World Heritage Sites.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You don't have to travel far to find a good beach in Dominica. For the archetypal Caribbean experience head to the north, where gentle waves lap onto white, sandy shores. Once a hangout for pirates, Pointe Baptiste is a gateway to one of the island's best black beaches, which offers a pleasant change. If for some reason you don't like feeling the sand between your toes, head to the rocky shores of Castle Bruce Beach.</p>]]><p><b>Make a day trip to Trafalgar Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dominica's most popular waterfall is incredibly beautiful and many flock to see it cascade down the rocks. After heavy rains the falls get pretty powerful and the rocks are dangerously slippery, so take care if you do decide to take a dip.</p>]]><p><b>Meet Dominica’s indigenous inhabitants</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Home to the last remaining indigenous community in the Caribbean, the Carib Territory offers a rare glimpse into the lives of Dominica&rsquo;s original inhabitants.&nbsp;Renowned for their canoe-building skills, the Caribs' long, pointed vessels are hewn from the trunk of a gommier tree and lucky visitors may be able to witness craftsman at work using age-old carving techniques.</p>]]><p><b>Relax in Roseau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its friendly locals and sea views, Dominica's pretty capital is a fine place to while away a day or two. Join in the hubbub of the lively downtown area or kick back in the beautiful Botanical Gardens. The city's colourful streets are home to a stellar selection of bars and restaurants, which keep appetites sated and booties shaking.</p>]]><p><b>Show your Carnival colours</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With February comes Carnival: two weeks of raucous revelry culminating in a wild costume parade. Expect sequin dresses, feather masks and skimpy outfits aplenty, plus street jugglers, prancing musicians and marching drummers, all of which are lapped up by a cheering crowd of merrymakers.</p>]]><p><b>Swim in the Emerald Pool</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Waters appear green in the leafy light of Emerald Pool, which is one of the most tranquil spots in Morne Trois Pitons National Park. The cool waters of this pool come from a gentle waterfall, which provides an invigorating shower for bathers.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Cabrits Historical Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On the Cabrits Peninsula find the fine ruins of Fort Shirley and Fort George, which date back to the 18th century. There's a small museum near the entrance, which features collections of artefacts discovered on the site, and various jungle trails nearby.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$364 million (2008).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Bananas, soap, coconuts, grapefruit and galvanised sheets.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, live animals, machinery, transport and mineral fuels.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK, USA, Canada, Japan, Barbados and Guadeloupe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vast areas of the island remain under cultivation, with bananas, coconuts, citrus fruits and cocoa the main crops. As the country's prime export sector, the banana industry has suffered market strain since a World Trade Organization outlawed previously enjoyed preferential access to key European markets. <br /><br />To counterbalance any negative impact on economy, the government has made great efforts to diversify the country's pecuniary base. Tourism is seen as the sector with greatest promise, though this has been slower to flourish than in other areas of the Caribbean. The offshore financial services industry has also been actively promoted world-wide. However, in a highly competitive market, success has been limited.<br /><br />At present there is a little light industry producing vegetable oil, canned juices, cigarettes, soap and other consumer goods largely for domestic consumption. <br /><br />Dominica is a member of the Caribbean economic bloc CARICOM and of the Organisation of East Caribbean States.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople should dress smartly, in lightweight clothing. Dealings tend to be formal, initially at least. Punctuality is expected.</p><p><strong>Government office hours: </strong>Mon 0800-1300 and 1400-1700, Tues-Fri 0800-1300 and 1400-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Dominica Association of Industry and Commerce (DAIC)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: 6 Cross Lane,PO Box 85,Roseau,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>For the freshest food opt for the daily special or the dish of the house. Island cooking includes Creole, Continental and American dishes so food is good and plentiful - and reasonably priced. During the week, restaurants close at about midnight but are open later at weekends. Root vegetables, such as yams and turnips, are often referred to as 'provisions' on a menu. Local spirits, rum especially, are inexpensive. Wines (mainly French and Californian) are expensive. There is a wide choice of beers. There are no licensing hours.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; <em>Tee-tee-ree</em> (tiny freshly spawned fish).<br />&bull;<em> Lambi</em> (conch). <br /><em>&bull; Manicou</em> (small opossum). <br /><em>&bull;</em> Crab backs (seasoned crab meat).<br /><em>&bull; Bello Hot Pepper Sauce</em> (a fiery local accompaniment served with almost everything)<em>.<br /></em><br /><strong>National drinks:</strong><br />&bull; Island fruit juices (mango, melon, pineapple or a blend). <br />&bull; Rum punches, particularly coconut rum punch (made from fresh coconut milk, sugar, rum, bitters, vanilla and grenadine). <br /><em>&bull; Sea Moss (</em>a non-alcoholic beverage made from sea moss or seaweed, with a slightly minty taste).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 10% service charge is applied by most hotels and some restaurants. In less touristic places, service isn't added to the bill so tipping is discretionary; 10 to 15% of the bill is the norm.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dominica's after-dark revelry centres on live music joints and bars, together with a growing number of cafés and dance halls.<strong> </strong>La Robe Creole in Roseau is a favourite hangout and has nightly dance music and live bands at weekends. Popular local discos<strong> </strong>include The Warehouse<em>,</em> Scorpio<em>,</em> and Doubles International. Folklore evenings with authentic costumes and music run throughout high season - ask your hotel for tips on what's on.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although Dominica's duty-free shopping scene isn't as established as many other Caribbean isles, new outlets are planned; pick up cut-price jewellery, tobacco, sunglasses and clothing. Elsewhere, excellent buys include local handicrafts such as hats, bags and rugs made from vetiver grass joined with wild banana strands. Pick up bags made from two layers of reeds stained by burying underground at the Carib Reserve Crafts Centre.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1300 and 1400-1600, Sat 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels are small to medium, and offer accommodation according to a number of 'Plans' widely used in the Caribbean region, including a Modified American Plan (MAP; room, breakfast and dinner) or a European Plan (EP; room only). A 10% government room tax is added to hotel bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A wide variety of guest houses and inns offer comfortable, homely tourist accommodation around the island. A 5% government tax and 10% service charge is levied on rooms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels are small to medium, and offer accommodation according to a number of 'Plans' widely used in the Caribbean region, including a Modified American Plan (MAP; room, breakfast and dinner) or a European Plan (EP; room only). A 10% government room tax is added to hotel bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels are small to medium, and offer accommodation according to a number of 'Plans' widely used in the Caribbean region, including a Modified American Plan (MAP; room, breakfast and dinner) or a European Plan (EP; room only). A 10% government room tax is added to hotel bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Full medical insurance is advised for international visitors as treatment is on a 'payment on advance' basis. Four main hospitals serve the island together with some private clinics where high fees are the norm.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;In larger towns and cities, mains water is normally chlorinated, and whilst relatively safe, may cause mild stomach upsets. Bottled water is available and is advised for the first few weeks of the stay. Drinking water outside main towns is not advisable. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Outbreaks of dengue fever occur in the area, as well as dengue haemorrhagic fever. Vaccination against hepatitis B and tuberculosis is sometimes advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Carnival Monday :
							12 February </p><p>Carnival Tuesday :
							13 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Bank Holiday :
							07 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>August Monday :
							06 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							03 November </p><p>National Day of Community Service :
							04 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Dominica without incurring customs duty by passengers aged 18 and above:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 227g  of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of wine or spirits.<br />
&bull; Gifts and souvenirs to the value of EC$400 (this allowance can only be claimed once a year and does not apply to cigarettes and alcohol).<b><br />
</b></p>
<p>Travellers carrying prescription medication must bring it in the original labelled container.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A permit is required to import animals, plants or seeds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wildlife (alive or dead).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>East Caribbean Dollar (XCD; symbol EC$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of EC$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of EC$1, and 50, 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents. US Dollars and Pounds Sterling are also legal tender.<br /><br />The Eastern Caribbean Dollar is tied at a fixed rate to the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged at banks and bureaux de change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard (limited) and Visa are accepted. ATMs are located around the island.</p><p>ATMs are located around the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted by most hotels. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take travellers cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1500, Fri 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Dominica, a passport valid six months and a return ticket are required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit passengers do not require visas providing they hold return tickets and can satisfy the immigration officer they will not remain in Dominica longer than 21 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors visa: &pound;25.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>High commission or consulate (or consular section at embassy).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 10 working days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visitors to Dominica must have sufficient funds to cover their length of stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to bring your pet into Dominica, you must obtain an import permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[15.414999]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-61.370976]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>751 sq km (290 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>73,016 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>98 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roseau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dominica is nestled in gleaming Caribbean waters - with Guadeloupe to the north and Martinique to the south - and its rippling terrain is shrouded in emerald rainforest. The island features five volcanoes, and the greenery is protected by several conservation areas including Cabrits National Park and Morn trois Pitons National Park; throughout the island run mountain streams, rivers, lakes and waterfalls, and bursting geysers and bubbling volcanic pools make the scenery even more breathtaking. The rich vegetation of the island's spectacular valleys includes towering palms and orchids, and is home to several endemic animal species, while the coast boasts beaches of both black (volcanic) and golden sand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost entirely Christian, with Roman Catholic majority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Casual dress is normal. Evening clothes are informal but conservative. The Catholic Church is one of the most dominant social influences. <strong>Photography: </strong>Visitors should ask before taking photographs of local people.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220/240 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are used. Many hotels have dual 220/110 voltage.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Roosevelt Skerrit since 2004.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Charles Savarin since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Before being discovered by Christopher Columbus in 1493, Dominica&rsquo;s mountainous natural beauty was originally enjoyed by the Carib Indians who made the island their home in the 14th century. The Caribs called their sunny isle Waitukubuli, meaning &lsquo;Tall is her body, and some Carib descendants remain in Dominica today &ndash; the last surviving community of this indigenous group.</p>
<p>Following Columbus&rsquo; arrival, the island became known as Dominica, taking its name from the day he landed (Dominica is Latin for Sunday). France colonised it in the 1600s, before, in 1805, the island became a British possession, remaining under British rule until the late 1960s. During both world wars thousands of Dominicans volunteered to fight in Europe for the Allies and the country provided a place of safety for Free French refugees fleeing the Vichy-controlled French islands.</p>
<p>Dominica has been nicknamed the &lsquo;Nature Isle of the Caribbean&rsquo; on account of its stunning natural features, not least Boiling Lake, the appropriately named hot spring &ndash; the second largest in the world.</p>
<p>Since 1978, the island has enjoyed full independence although self-rule has been somewhat stormy, with two coup attempts by leftist members of the island&rsquo;s Defence Force during the early 1980s.</p>
<p>The arrival of Hurricane David in 1979 brought mass chaos as the immense tropical storm damaged three quarters of the island, destroying homes and killing 42 people. A bus still remains to this day crushed under a storm-felled tree in Rousea&rsquo;s Botanical Gardens.</p>
<p>After the 1980 elections Dominica appointed Eugenia Charles, the Caribbean&rsquo;s first female prime minister.</p>
<p>Politically, the early 2000s proved eventful, with two Prime Ministers &ndash; Roosevelt Douglas and Pierre Charles &ndash; both dying while in office. Since 2004, Roosevelt Skerrit has been leading the country and remains a popular figure.</p>
<p>In recent years, Dominica has developed a close, if controversial, relationship with Japan, which has provided extensive development aid including a modern fisheries complex. In exchange, Dominica now supports Japan&rsquo;s much criticised efforts to undermine international controls on whaling. Nevertheless, given the island&rsquo;s serious economic problems, the deal enjoys wide popular support.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; Dominica&rsquo;s national bird is the Sisserou parrot, which features on the national flag.</p>
<p>&bull; The Commonwealth of Dominica has emerged as a major international offshore financial centre thanks to its low-tax regime.</p>
<p>&bull; Playwright and novelist Jean Rhys was born in Dominica, which features as the &lsquo;honeymoon island&rsquo; in her best known work, <em>Wide Sargasso Sea</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Office for the High Commission for the Commonwealth of Dominica in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7370 5194.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.dominicahighcommission.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7370 5194.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1300 (visa and passport section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Earls Court<br/>1 Collingham Gardens<br/>London<br/>SW5 0HW<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Commonwealth of Dominica in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 364 6781/2.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 364 6781/2.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3216 New Mexico Avenue<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20016<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Caribbean island of Dominica is a natural treasure. Visitors will find a medley of brooding volcanic peaks, gushing mountain streams, dense forests, quiet lakes and spouting geysers. As you might have already guessed, it's a diverse and beautiful land.</p><p>Given its natural assets and warm and welcoming locals, Dominica should be a bustling tourism hotspot. Despite being one of the poorest in the region, crime is relatively low. But a marked lack of pumping nightlife, no direct flights to Dominica from the UK and little in the way of sandy beaches all mean it remains off the radar for many travellers. And yet this is what makes the island so appealing for the intrepid few.</p><p>Those partial to hiking amid thick tropical rainforest and gazing at bubbling lakes, will find this sunny green isle has many charms. In fact, much of Dominica is the domain of sprawling jungle, making it ideal for trekking. Adventuring your way around Dominica's natural delights is very much a primordial experience. On your travels through red mud trails and over undulating volcanic slopes, you'll find thundering waterfalls, hot springs where you can let nature heal your aches and pains, and even swim through a narrow gorge. Explore colourful coral reef with your snorkelling gear, be buoyed by bubbling volcanic water and visit the rawest spas imaginable – Dominica has so much to offer.</p><p>Perhaps the most attractive thing about the island, though, is the very thing that keeps the hordes away. Dominica has avoided mass tourism, and as a haven where Mother Nature is in charge, unspoilt by human hands. Having been both a French and British colony, the 70,000 or so inhabitants have various roots, including the indigenous Caribs, though the people are largely African in origin. As for visitors, they see Dominica as an unblemished alternative to the more commercial Caribbean islands. Here you can get away from the crowds, welcomed by the friendliest of local populations.</p>The Caribbean island Dominica is a medley of brooding volcanic peaks, gushing mountain streams, dense forests, quiet lakes and spouting geysers; this is a diverse and beautiful land.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
