<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Dominican Republic" ColCode="dom" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="do" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Dominican Republic]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate in Dominican Republic is generally hot with tropical temperatures all year, although it does vary from region to region.</p>
<p>In Santo Domingo, the temperatures are constant throughout the year, ranging between 25&deg;C (77&deg;F) and 28&deg;C (82&deg;F) while rain falls abundantly from May to November.</p>
<p>The resort town Punta Cana on the east coast is extremely popular with European and American tourists from December to March who seek to escape the cold in the northern hemisphere. In January, the average high in Punta Cana is 29&deg;C (84&deg;F) while the average low is 21&deg;C (70&deg;F). Precipitation is high from June to November, with a risk of hurricanes too. April is the shoulder season, meaning good weather (27&deg;C/81&deg;F) and fewer crowds.</p>
<p>If you're visiting the mountainous interior, it's best to pack a light sweater as it can get very cold at high elevations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight fabrics are best suited to the tropical temperatures. Waterproofs are essential during the rainy seasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dominican Shuttles (<a href="http://www.dominicanshuttles.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.dominicanshuttles.com</a>) runs charter and scheduled domestic flights. SAP Group (<a href="http://www.sapair.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.sapair.com</a>) also runs charter flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p> There is a scheduled passenger ferry service between Samaná and Sabana de la Mar. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p> The rail network is mainly used for freight. In Santo Domingo, the city has a good metro service, with the north-south metro line passing the Plaza de la Cultura, while the east-west line connects major shopping and business areas. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p> For Santo Domingo metro, you can purchase a single-charge card or a rechargeable card. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a reasonable network of roads, including the Sanchez Highway (DR-2), running westwards from Santo Domingo to El&iacute;as Pi&ntilde;a on the Haitian frontier. The Mella Highway (DR-4) extends eastwards from Santo Domingo to Hig&uuml;ey in the southeast and the Autopista Juan Pablo Duarte (DR-1), running north and west from Santo Domingo to Monte Cristi on the northwest coast are also popular highways.</p>
<p>Autovia del Este (DR-3) connects the two main tourist towns (Punta Cana and Santo Domingo). The journey takes about two hours and 30 minutes.</p>r<p>Not all roads in the Dominican Republic are all weather, and 4-wheel drive vehicles are recommended for wet weather. Checkpoints near military installations are ubiquitous, though no serious difficulties have been reported (those near the Haitian border are most likely to be sensitive). Keep doors and windows locked at all times. Driving at night is not recommended because of poor lighting and signage.</p><p>There are several privately-owned bus companies running coach services between major destinations. Popular companies include Metro Bus (<a href="http://metroserviciosturisticos.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">metroserviciosturisticos.com</a>) and Caribe Tours (<a href="http://caribetours.com.do/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">caribetours.com.do</a>).</p><p>Travellers are advised to hire tourist taxis or radio taxis that can be arranged in advance. Avoid unmarked taxis.</p><p>A valid driver's license, passport and rental documents including insurance must be with you at all times.</p><p>Drivers and all passengers are required to wear seat belts and using a mobile phone while driving is prohibited. Turning right on a red light after stopping is allowed. The speed limit is 120kph (75mph) on highways, 80kph (50mph) on main roads and 40kph (25mph) in small towns and villages.</p><p> There are several car hire companies in Santo Domingo. Despite the law stating that you must be at least 18 years of age to drive, many car rental companies usually require you to be at least 21 years old, and in some cases, at least 25 years old. A passport, a valid driving license and a credit card are required for car hire. </P><p> There are bike rental companies in Dominican Republic. </P><p>Drivers and all passengers are required to wear seat belts and using a mobile phone while driving is prohibited. Turning right on a red light after stopping is allowed. The speed limit is 120kph (75mph) on highways, 80kph (50mph) on main roads and 40kph (25mph) in small towns and villages.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Santo Domingo has flat-fare bus and minibus services, and thousands of share-taxis known as Conchos, who usually have pre-established routes. To get one, wave at the driver and check if your destination is on their routes. </p>

<p>Hotel taxis are also available. In old Santo Domingo, the streets are narrow with blind corners, so do pay attention, particularly as Dominican drivers have a tendency to use their horns rather than their brakes. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Dominican Republic</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">samanaacute</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Dominican Republic</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">puerto_plata</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Dominican Republic</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">la_romana</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.25</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Dominican Republic</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">barahona</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.ba.com</a>) operates direct flights from Gatwick to Punta Cana all year round. Airlines offering non-stop flights from the USA including American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>), Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>), JetBlue (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>) and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.united.com</a>).</p>
<p>Visitors are advised to arrange airport transportation prior to travelling. Please see the passport and visa section for information regarding entry requirements.</p>
<p>Major airports in the Dominican Republic are <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominican-republic/punta-cana-international-airport/">Punta Cana International Airport</a>, Las Am&eacute;ricas International Airport (Santo Domingo) and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominican-republic/puerto-plata-gregorio-lupern-airport">Puerto Plata International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominican-republic/punta-cana-international-airport">Punta Cana</a>: 9 hours 5 minutes.<br />
From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Santo Domingo: 12 hours 20 minutes (including stopover).</p>
<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominican-republic/punta-cana-international-airport">Punta Cana</a>: 3 hours 45 minutes. <br />
From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> to Santo Domingo: 3 hours 45 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A departure tax of US$20 is levied on all passengers which is usually included in your airfare. Passengers should check with their airline to verify this.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Puerto Plata Gregorio Luperón Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aerodom.com<p>Puerto Plata Gregorio Luperón International Airport is located in the Silver Port province, 18km (11 miles) to the east of Puerto Plata on the north coast of the Dominican Republic.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 809 291 0000</p>]]><b>Punta Cana International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.puntacanainternationalairport.com<p>Punta Cana International Airport is located on the eastern tip of the island, 44km (27 miles) east of Higúey.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 809 959 2376</p>]]><b>Las Americas International Airport </b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Claro, formally known as CODETEL, is Dominican Republic's largest telecommunications company, providing local, long-distance, and wireless voice services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a number of international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good along most coastal areas and around towns but patchy elsewhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi access is widely available in hotels, cafés and restaurants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a wide range of TV channels and radio stations in the country.</p>
<p>Press freedom is protected by law. Consequently, media outlets carry diverse political views although some subjects, such as the Catholic Church and the army, are generally avoided. Daily papers are in Spanish and include <i>El Caribe, Hoy, Listín Diario and El Nacional.</i> The English-language Santo Domingo News is published weekly and can be obtained in many hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail takes about 10 days to reach Western Europe. It is advisable to post all mail at the central post office in Santo Domingo to ensure a rapid and safer handling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be dazzled by the Columbus Lighthouse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This colossal cross-shaped monument to Christopher Columbus on the south coast was built to commemorate the 500th anniversary of the discovery of South America. It projects a cross-shaped beam of light into the sky, visible from as far as neighbouring Puerto Rico. Today, you can visit the 'lighthouse', which doubles as a museum, whose exhibits include a sarcophagus supposedly containing Columbus' remains. </p>]]><p><b>Catch some baseball</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Affectionately known as 'pelota', baseball isn't so much the Dominican national sport as the national obsession – male and female, young and old, they're all hooked. The professional domestic season, featuring six teams from across the country, runs from mid-October through late January, providing visitors a chance to experience the game in all its glory. </p>]]><p><b>Dance, dance, dance</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Throw yourself into Santo Domingo's nightlife by dancing down-and-dirty to the merengue with the locals. The city's Malecón boardwalk has a number of lively options, and there are several steamy nightclubs in the Zona Colonial which offer live jazz and Latino beats. </p>]]><p><b>Drop in on Columbus junior’s family home</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Santo Domingo's Zona Colonial is a World Heritage Site, where you can explore some of the most historic buildings in Americas. Completed in 1514, the Alcazar de Colón was the palatial residence of Diego Columbus, son of Christopher Columbus. Equally unmissable is the Cathedral of Santa María la Menor, the oldest Cathedral in Americas, completed in 1540. The cathedral is known as Christopher Columbus' resting place, and outside stands a bronze statue of the explorer overlooking Plaza de Colon. </p>]]><p><b>Go mountain biking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The country's mountainous interior makes for a great biking terrain, with the Cordillera Septentrional being a particularly popular choice. The scenic Constanza and the forested Valle Nuevo National Park are also preferred by cyclists. Specialist agencies like Iguana Mama run cycling tours to the countryside with bikes and equipment included. The best time to go mountain biking is during the dry season, from May to September. </p>]]><p><b>Hit the surf at Puerto Plata</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This historical northern city has an absorbing Old Town, centred around Fortaleza San Felipe, which was constructed by the Spanish as both a defensive outpost and a keep for captured smugglers. If you're looking for adrenalin action though, the nearby beaches are superb, particularly Sosua and Cabarete, whose big surf and powerful breezes create some of the world's best windsurfing and kite-boarding conditions. </p>]]><p><b>Join the Carnival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The city of La Vega bursts into life on every Sunday in February for its annual carnival, El Carnaval de la Vega. This pre-Lent festival has parades featuring costumed characters including a limping devil (Diablo Cojuelo). Although La Vega is known for the carnival, other cities hosting unique parades include Santiago, Santo Domingo, Montecristi, Bonao, Puerto Plata, Río San Juan, and Barahona. </p>]]><p><b>Meet the Tainos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Museum of Dominican Man (Museo del Hombre Dominicano) is Santo Domingo's best museum, devoted to the country's anthropology. Its sculptures and artefacts offer a fascinating insight on the Tainos, the island's earliest settlers. You can also see colourful carnival costumes and masks here, as well as exhibits of the Voodoo cult religion that once dominated the Caribbean.</p>]]><p><b>Mind the crocs in Lago Enriquillo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Populated by countless flocks of tropical birds (and a healthy population of crocodiles), Lago Enriquillo is an enormous saltwater lake near the Haitian border, and largest lake in the Caribbean, which you can go on boat trips to explore. Its flora and fauna are protected within a combined national park: the Jaragua-Bahoruco-Enriquillo Biosphere Reserve. </p>]]><p><b>Pick up some amber</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Arguably the most authentic Dominican souvenir on the market, amber is widely available at reasonable prices. The northern coastline is known for producing some of the finest amber in the world. You can visit an amber museum (<a href="http://www.ambermuseum.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.ambermuseum.com</a>) in Puerto Plata, or tour the mines in the hills of La Cumbre (about 43km/28m from Puerto Plata). Keep a look out for blue amber which is found only in Dominican Republic. You can purchase them raw on the mining sites and get them polished, carved and set in jewellery later. However, be mindful of fakery.</p>]]><p><b>Reel in a fighting dorado</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Game fishing is popular and you can ask your hotel to arrange a fishing trip for you. Top catches include mahi-mahi (between October and March), white marlin (April to June), blue marlin (July to September), and tuna and kingfish (July to August). </p>]]><p><b>Soak up the views on top of Mount Isabela de Torres</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Close to Puerto Plata on the north coast, Mount Isabela de Torres provides awesome views of the ocean and surrounding national parks. If you feel adventurous you can climb to the top in a few hours, if not the cable car will whisk you up in minutes from Monday to Saturday. A replica of Rio de Janeiro's Christ Redeemer statue stands on the peak; there's also a botanical garden. </p>]]><p><b>Tee off</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy a round of golf under the Caribbean sun. The sport is popular in the country, with luxury resorts offering challenging courses – some are even considered in the top 50 in the Caribbean. Several of the country's courses enjoy dramatic ocean-facing settings, with some of the best concentrated on the south coast, a short swing from Santo Domingo. </p>]]><p><b>Watch out for whales</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Jump on a whale watching boat and search for magnificent humpback whales, thousands of which make their annual winter arrival off the Samaná headland, on the northeastern tip of the island. The season for witnessing this thrilling spectacle, generally stretches from mid-January to mid-March. You can find organised boat trips in the little port of Santa Barbara de Samaná. Punta Cana is another great location to witness the beautiful humpback whales spring above the surface, in the attempt to mate with the female species. The Dominican Republic law enforces strict protection and guidelines for whales.  </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$71.58 billion (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Gold, medical instruments, tobacco, bananas and electronic equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Refined petroleum, cars, packaged medicaments and plastic products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, China, Haiti, Canada, Mexico and India.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Dominican Republic has the largest economy in the Caribbean. The country is a major tourist destination and its free-trade zones have attracted a significant sum of foreign investments and now a key aspect of the economy. These have helped to reduce the country&rsquo;s dependence on agriculture products such as cocoa, tobacco, sugarcane and coffee, among others.</p>
<p>Income inequality remains an issue. It's not uncommon to see gleaming new 4x4 vehicles bumper-to-bumper with rusting, rasping old hatchbacks. Improved water and electricity are needed to assist growth in tourism, manufacturing and agriculture.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dominicans can be fashion-conscious. It is usual for business people to dress smartly and to deal formally with each other at first, although the general atmosphere is informal. Spanish is the main business language and knowledge of it will be of assistance. Hotels can usually assist with interpreter services.</p><p>Business hours Mon-Fri 0800-1800. Some companies work on Saturday mornings.<br />
<br />
Government offices have shorter working hours, Mon-Fri 0730-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cámara de Comercio y Producción de Santo Domingo</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (809) 682 2688
					Website:http://www.camarasantodomingo.org.do/
					Address: Arzobispo Nouel 206,Apartado Postal 815,Santo Domingo,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Native Dominican cooking combines Spanish and African influences with local produce. There is plenty of fresh fish and seafood, and the most popular meats are chicken, beef and pork. </p>

<p>Island-grown tomatoes, lettuce, papaya, mangoes, passion fruit and citrus fruits are delicious, while rice, yucca, and sweet potatoes are staples. Meat dominates restaurant menus, with the gut-busting <em>La Bandera </em>(&lsquo;The Flag&rsquo;) being the closest to a national dish &ndash; it comprises chicken or beef and is served with rice, plantain, avocado, yucca and salad. Lunch is the main meal of the day. </p>
<p>As for drinks, the island&rsquo;s traditional sugarcane is used to produce some fine rum, including <em>blanco</em> (white), <em>dorado</em> (golden) or <em>a&ntilde;ejo</em> (aged). Delicious, though very sweet, fruit shakes are sold from street stalls. Known as <em>batidos</em>, they are made with fruit, milk, sugar and crushed ice &ndash; just the tonic for a hot day.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Asopao de pollo:</strong> Chicken and rice stew, a hearty dish.<br />
<strong>Chicharrón de cerdo:</strong> Fried pork rinds, a popular snack.<br />
<strong>Chimichurris:</strong> A common street-food, this sandwich is loaded with ground beef or pork, covered with mayonnaise, ketchup, tomatoes and cabbage.<br />
<b>La bandera:</b>A reference to the country's flag and widely considered the national dish. Comprising white rice, red beans, stewed meat, salad and crispy fried plantain known as tostones.<br/> 
<strong>Mofongo:</strong> Fried green plantains, seasoned with garlic, olive oil and pork cracklings.<br />
<strong>Niño Envuelto:</strong> Rice and meat wrapped in cabbage.<br />
<strong>Sancocho: </strong> Served on special occasions, this thick stew is made with pork, chicken and beef with various vegetables including yam, yucca and plantains. Often served with white rice and avocado slices.</p>

<p><b>Drinks</b></p>
<p><b>Coffee:</b> Dominican coffee is excellent and served very strong, usually black. <br />
<b>Local beer:</b> Presidente is the most popular beer and often served chilled. Other brands include Bohemia (a pilsner-based beer) and Quisqueya.<br />
<b>Mamajuana:</b> A potent herbal drink made from cured tree barks soaked in rum, red wine and honey. <br/><strong>Rum:</strong> Popular brands include Brugal and Barceló. Rum is the liquor of choice and it is used as the base for many cocktails. </p>

<p><b>Desserts</b></p>
<p><b>Majarete:</b> Sweetcorn and coconut milk pudding sprinkled liberally with cinnamon and nutmeg.<br/><strong>Tres leches:</strong> Sponge cake soaked in condensed milk and heavy cream. </p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Avoid drinking tap water and consume pineapple and coconut juice in moderation as they are laxative. </p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Hotel and restaurant bills usually include a 10% service charge (on top of the 18% tax). Additional tip may be given as an appreciation of good service. </p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Choice varies from discos and casinos to cafés and festivals. Hotels offer more traditional shows, including Latin music and dancing. Popular dances are the inescapable merengue, bachata (a guitar-based genre, very popular across the country), and salsa. The Malecón, Santo Domingo's long waterside boulevard, is known for its nightlife. Punta Cana, a popular tourist destination, loves a good party and some consider it as the top nightlife destination in the Caribbean. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hand-rolled cigar, rum and amber jewellery are widely considered as the best buys from the island. Larima, a semi-precious, turquoise-coloured stone found only in the heart of Bahoruco mountains, also makes a great souvenir. Other popular souvenirs include woodcarvings, macramé, pottery, Taino artefacts, Creole dolls, baskets, limestone carvings and CDs of salsa and merengue. Bargaining is recommended, and in most cases expected.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700<br/>Sat 0900-1300</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good selection of hotels in the Dominican Republic. The stretch of white sandy beaches at <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominican-republic/punta-cana-beaches">Punta Cana</a> and Bávaro has a plethora of hotels including many stylish mega-resorts. Located on the north side, Puerto Plata is slightly less busy than Punta Cana and with cheaper hotel prices too. In the capital Santo Domingo, there is a few luxury hotels occupying restored 16th-century buildings within Ciudad Colonial (Colonial Zone).<br />
<br />
<strong>Note:</strong> The Dominican Republic is a popular destination for Europeans and Americans to visit during the winter months in the northern hemisphere. Consequently, hotel prices are high from December to March.<br />
<strong><br />
<strong>Grading: </strong></strong>There is a 5-star grading system.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfast hotels and guesthouses can be found in the main tourist areas, including Santo Domingo, Playa Dorada and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/puerto-plata">Puerto Plata</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good selection of hotels in the Dominican Republic. The stretch of white sandy beaches at <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominican-republic/punta-cana-beaches">Punta Cana</a> and Bávaro has a plethora of hotels including many stylish mega-resorts. Located on the north side, Puerto Plata is slightly less busy than Punta Cana and with cheaper hotel prices too. In the capital Santo Domingo, there is a few luxury hotels occupying restored 16th-century buildings within Ciudad Colonial (Colonial Zone).<br />
<br />
<strong>Note:</strong> The Dominican Republic is a popular destination for Europeans and Americans to visit during the winter months in the northern hemisphere. Consequently, hotel prices are high from December to March.<br />
<strong><br />
<strong>Grading: </strong></strong>There is a 5-star grading system.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good selection of hotels in the Dominican Republic. The stretch of white sandy beaches at <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominican-republic/punta-cana-beaches">Punta Cana</a> and Bávaro has a plethora of hotels including many stylish mega-resorts. Located on the north side, Puerto Plata is slightly less busy than Punta Cana and with cheaper hotel prices too. In the capital Santo Domingo, there is a few luxury hotels occupying restored 16th-century buildings within Ciudad Colonial (Colonial Zone).<br />
<br />
<strong>Note:</strong> The Dominican Republic is a popular destination for Europeans and Americans to visit during the winter months in the northern hemisphere. Consequently, hotel prices are high from December to March.<br />
<strong><br />
<strong>Grading: </strong></strong>There is a 5-star grading system.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance (including emergency repatriation) is strongly recommended. Medical care is limited and variable in quality. An emergency service is available in Santo Domingo.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated and sterilisation should be considered essential. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is pasteurised. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;A vaccination for hepatitis A is recommended to all tourists. For travellers spending longer at Dominican Republic, a vaccination for tuberculosis and hepatitis B is recommended. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is endemic; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Outbreaks of dengue fever occur from time to time. Rabies may be present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. &lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Some holidays falling midweek are observed on the closest Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Lady of Altagracia Day :
							2018<br/>21 January </p><p>Duarte Day :
							2018<br/>26 January </p><p>Independence Day :
							27 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Restoration Day :
							16 August </p><p>Lady of Mercedes Day :
							24 September </p><p>Constitution Day :
							06 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into the Dominican Republic by travellers older than 16 without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or a box of cigars.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; Gifts to the value of US$100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All animal products, agricultural and horticultural products and drugs are forbidden.<br/> Firearms and ammunition must be accompanied by an import licence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dominican Peso (DOP; symbol RD$). Notes are in denominations of RD$2,000, 1,000, 500, 100 and 50. Coins are in denominations of RD$25, 10, 5 and 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The peso is not available outside the Dominican Republic. Currencies of Canada, France, Germany, The Netherlands, Spain, Switzerland, UK and USA may be converted into local currency. On departure, up to 30% of the exchanged currency can be reconverted into US Dollars at any bank, provided original receipts are shown. All exchanges must be done through official dealers such as banks and hotels approved by the Central Bank. Most resorts quote prices in (and are happy to accept) US Dollars. Some street vendors in touristic areas also accept US Dollars although these are not a legal tender in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are all accepted.</p><p>Most ATMs in the Dominican Republic accept international bankcards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are not commonly used nowadays, but they are still accepted by banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1630. <br/>Some banks are open on a Saturday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above to enter the Dominican Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Charges vary from consulate to consulate. In the UK, a tourist card costs &pound;11.50 instead of US$10. British passport holders can also get a tourist card upon arrival, which is US$10 and must be paid in US dollars.</p>
<p>American travellers may choose to apply online (<a href="http://www.dgii.gov.do/Paginas/inicio.aspx)" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.dgii.gov.do/Paginas/inicio.aspx</a>) or obtain a tourist card upon arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist cards are valid for 30 days from the date of entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can apply for a tourist card at a consulate near you, online (<a href="http://www.dgii.gov.do/Paginas/inicio.aspx" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.dgii.gov.do/Paginas/inicio.aspx</a>) or at the airport upon arrival.</p>
<p>For tourist visa, please visit a consulate near you.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Please allow up to seven days for your visa to be processed. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To extend your visit, you must go to the Migration Department (Dirección General de Migración) in Santo Domingo and pay an additional fee up to RD$1,000, which varies depending on the length of stay. You must book an appointment online and arrange for an extension at least two weeks before your stay expires.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet to the Dominican Republic, your animal needs an up-to-date rabies vaccination certificate (issued at least 30 days, but not more than 12 months, before travel) and a veterinary certificate of good health. Without these, your pet will be quarantined for up to 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[19.050963]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-70.336979]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>48,442 sq. km (18,792 sq. miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>10,776,988 (UN estimate 2016).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>233 per sq. km (86.1 sq. miles). </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Santo Domingo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Dominican Republic shares the Caribbean island of Hispaniola with the nation of Haiti. It is larger than its French-speaking neighbour, occupying two-thirds of the landmass.</p>
<p>A series of mountain belts stretch across the border region, most notably in the form of the Cordillera Central; at 3,175m (10,414ft) the peak of Pico Duarte represents the highest point of the country.</p>
<p>The Dominican landscape is frequently forested and often undulating, with a multitude of valleys, plains and plateaux. The soil is fertile with excellent white beaches on the north, southeast and east coasts. Ten per cent of the country was set aside in the 1970s to be protected as national parks and science reserves, and, in spite of occasional hurricanes and fires, these areas remain largely intact. Today there are 17 national parks in the Dominican Republic.</p>
<p>Capital city Santo Domingo sits on the south coast (providing a popular stop-off for cruise ships), while the country's second largest city, Santiago, is located in the central northwest region.</p>
<p>The Reserva Cientifica Banco de Plata is an underwater park located off the north coast, set up to preserve a breeding ground for the thousands of humpback whales that visit each winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic 95%</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dominicans are friendly and hospitable, with a big emphasis on family value and loyalty. It is not uncommon to see your hosts go out of their way to make you feel comfortable.</p>

<p>Social appearance is important. Daytime dress is generally casual but beachwear and shorts are only acceptable in resorts and at pools; it is rare for locals to enter a church wearing shorts or a T-shirt. In many areas, evenings tend to be smarter, with dressing up common at better restaurants, hotels and for social functions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without round grounding pin) are in use. Some sockets may require an adaptor if you have a three-pin plug.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Danilo Medina since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Danilo Medina since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christopher Columbus discovered the island of Hispaniola, which comprises present-day Dominican Republic and Haiti, in 1492 and established it as his main base for the further exploration of the region.</p>
<p>For two centuries the Spanish ruled the island, but as they became increasingly distracted by their fledgling settlements on the mainland, English pirates plundered and ransacked almost at will, while French colonisers threatened to take over. Finally, in 1697, western Hispaniola (present-day Haiti) came under French control, with the east remaining under Spanish control, a division that still exists today, with the Dominican Republic and Haiti sharing the island.</p>
<p>A century later, Santo Domingo (the oldest city in the Americas), which was founded by Columbus' brother in 1496, was ceded to the French; the rest of the island soon followed suit. The Battle of Palo Hincado, in 1808, heralded the collapse of French rule in the eastern part of the island. The colony reverted to Spanish sovereignty the following year, and in 1821, the colonial treasurer, José Nunez de Caceres, proclaimed Santo Domingo's independence.</p>
<p>This independence was short-lived, however, as in 1822, the Haitians invaded the colony and occupied it for 22 years, until, on 27th February 1844, the territory of Santo Domingo recovered its sovereignty and declared independence as the Dominican Republic.</p>
<p>After years of civil war and US occupation, the republic was taken over by General Rafael Trujillo (1930-1961), whose dictatorship was characterised by cruelty and megalomaniac excess. Finally, after years of brutally oppressing his opponents, Trujillo was assassinated in 1961, prompting a period of civil unrest.</p>
<p>Since then, the country has had a series of Presidents and each has tried to rebuild and diversify its economy. Today, the service sector has overtaken agriculture and is now the largest contributor to the GDP.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Dictator Rafael Trujillo (1891-1961) was famous for his love of fine clothes. He had almost two thousand suits and more than ten thousand neckties.<br />
&bull;	Santo Domingo is the oldest city in the new world.<br />
&bull;	The flag of the Dominican Republic is thought to be the only flag in the world that features a Bible. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy and Consulate of the Dominican Republic in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 332 7670</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.drembassyusa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 332 7670</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600 (Embassy)&lt;br/&gt;
Mon-Thu 0900-1300 and 1400-1500 (Consular)&lt;br/&gt;
Fri 0900-1300 (Consular)&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1715 22nd Street<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Dominican Republic in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7262 6856</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.dominicanembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7262 6856</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1500&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>High Holborn<br/>8 Gloucester Square<br/>London<br/>W2 2TJ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in the Dominican Republic]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(809) 472 7111 </p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-santo-domingo</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(809) 472 7111 </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0900-1200, and 1300-1600&lt;br/&gt;Fri 0900-1300&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Edificio Corominas Pepin<br/>Ave 27 de Febrero No 233<br/>Santo Domingo<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dominican Republic is ensconced as the Caribbean&rsquo;s most visited destination. It&rsquo;s not hard to see why; a seemingly endless spread of white-sandy beaches and palm trees play host to a similarly sizeable range of holiday resorts. The country has developed a reputation for a good-quality break at a reasonable price, for what it&rsquo;s worth.</p>
<p>With its 32km (20 miles) stretch of beaches and clear blue sea, the region around Punta Cana on the east coast is particularly popular, offering golf courses, all-inclusive holidays and the usual fun-in-the-sun trappings.</p>
<p>Dominican Republic makes up one half of the island of Hispaniola &ndash; which it shares with Haiti in the west. The country is one of the most geographically diverse parts of the Caribbean, showcasing everything from tropical rainforests and high-mountain ranges to mangrove swamps and semi-deserts. Mountain-bikers, windsurfers, hikers, climbers and even whale-watchers are well catered for.</p>
<p>No less notably, however, the Dominican Republic is heaving with life, blending the heady rhythms of merengue and bachata music, with a fondness for rum and religion, not to mention a near-unrivalled passion for baseball.</p>
<p>The country has a long history. It was the first part of the region to be discovered by Christopher Columbus in 1492. A visit to capital city Santo Domingo still makes the most natural starting point for cultural visitors. The oldest fortress Fortaleza Ozama (built in 1502) and colonial-era churches still stand proud, while the city as a whole is a thrusting, energetic destination full of speaker-blaring corner stores and dance-till-you-drop nightclubs.</p>
<p>While it&rsquo;s a large country by Caribbean standards, it remains relatively easy to combine different elements of the destination in one itinerary. And whether you&rsquo;re here for the beaches, the music, the countryside or the culture, the DR in full swing is a force to be reckoned with.</p><p>Dominican Republic is ensconced as the Caribbean&rsquo;s most visited destination. It&rsquo;s not hard to see why; a seemingly endless spread of white-sandy beaches and palm trees play host to a similarly sizeable range of holiday resorts. The country has developed a reputation for a good-quality break at a reasonable price, for what it&rsquo;s worth.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
