<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="East Timor" ColCode="tls" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="tp" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[East Timor]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical monsoon climate. It is very hot and dry from July to November with the western monsoon bringing the rains from December to March. It is cooler and more humid in the mountain region.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights with rainwear throughout the year. Warmer clothes are needed for cool evenings and mountain areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferries run between Oekusi and Dili.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Mikrolets</em> are the main transport in East Timor as they are extremely cheap.&nbsp;These are mini-vans converted into people carriers.</p><p>Travellers need a valid driving licence or permit either from their country or issued in East Timor, and detailing which class of vehicle they are entitled to drive. Third-party motor insurance is not available.</p><p>Available in Dili.</p><p>Mountain biking is gaining popularity in East Timor. You can bring your own or buy one locally, but rentals may not be available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airnorth&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.airnorth.com.au" target="_blank">www.airnorth.com.au</a>) flies from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/darwin">Darwin</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> to Dili.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/darwin">Darwin</a> - 1 hour 20 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 22 hours (including stopovers); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 32 hours (including stopovers).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$10.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Baucau Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Comoro International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage provided by <em>Timor Telecom International </em>in and around Dili and other main urban areas. International roaming agreements are stilll being set up but cannot be relied upon as yet. In some parts of the country, however, telephone communication may still only be possible with satellite telephones.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Facilities are not generally available to the public at the present time but <em>VPM Internet Services</em> (website: <a href="http://www.vpm.com" target="_blank">www.vpm.com</a>) does operate in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>East Timor's national public radio and TV services began broadcasting in May 2002 when the country gained independence, replacing the interim broadcasting services operated by the UN. Public radio services are said to reach some 90% of the population; public TV has a smaller coverage. Community radio stations have played a key role in the process of national reconstruction. Many of the stations receive funding, training and equipment from international agencies and organisations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A limited postal service does exist.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask on the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are many beautiful beaches in East Timor, but discerning bathers should make a beeline for Jaco Islands, which is home to the country's finest golden sands. It's about six hours by car from the capital, but the journey cuts through beautiful forests and wends along scenic coastal roads. Looking for something a little closer to Dili? Then try Areia Branca and Dollar Beach.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the charms of Maubara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This small town is a few hours from Dili and notable for the fact that most inhabitants speak Tocodede, a language unique to this district of East Timor.&nbsp;Once in Maubara, visit the 17th-century fort. Once a prison, it has a substantial coastal wall with cannons still pointing out.</p>]]><p><b>Dress up for Carnival de Timor</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This annual jamboree lights up Dili every April (or sometimes May, depending on the duration of the rainy season). Revellers don traditional costumes during the carnival and compete for awards, which are given out to the best dressed. The dancing and merriment goes on long into the night with live music and much more entertainment.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Baucau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As they retreated from East Timor, the Indonesians wrought carnage upon the town of Baucau. Yet its quaint, colonial charm still shines through and it remains a fine place to while away a few days. The city abounds with pretty Portuguese colonial architecture and visitors can explore caves used by the Japanese during WWII. There's also a pool, should you fancy cooling off.</p>]]><p><b>Feed your brain in Dili</b></p><![CDATA[<p>East Timor's colourful capital abounds with Portuguese architecture, which serves as a reminder of its colonial history. After independence the country was occupied by Indonesia and visitors can learn all about the country's struggle for sovereignty at the poignant Resistance Museum. Housed in a former prison, the Chega! Exhibition offers a grittier take on the struggle against Indonesia.</p>]]><p><b>Go climb a mountain</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Thrill seekers are well catered for on East Timor with a selection of mountains that make for world class trekking. The most notable climbs include Mount Matebian and Mount Kablaki in the Baucau district and Mount Ramelau in Ainaro. The breath-taking views are complemented by stunning wildlife that includes eight species of bird unique to Timor.</p>]]><p><b>Plan a getaway to Com</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Make a journey to Com, a beautiful fishing village, popular for weekend getaways. The main activities are fishing and snorkelling. The 20 sublime rooms of the Com Beach Resort are a sign of things to come, with talk of a real 5-star resort being developed in the future.</p>]]><p><b>Set sail for Atauro Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tutuala is the region to head for if you like watersports and great beaches. Atauro Island and nearby Jaco Island offer excellent diving, snorkelling and birdwatching. Atauro (which means "goat") is now firmly on the map as an eco-tourism destination. Watch this space.</p>]]><p><b>Venture into Oecussi province</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Oecussi province belongs to East Timor politically, yet is a part of Indonesian West Timor culturally and geographically. Its capital, Pante Makassar is a sleepy little town that lies between the coast and the mountains. Coral reefs off coast offer spectacular diving and snorkelling. Mountain biking and hiking are possible in the interior or in the mountains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$335 million (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Coffee, sandlewood and timber.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, food and construction material.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Indonesia and Australia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Subsistence agriculture, forestry and fishing sustain most of the population. The sole export products are coffee beans, timber and sandalwood.<br /><br />The economy as a whole was chronically underdeveloped as a result of centuries of neglect by the Portuguese. The Indonesians built some basic infrastructure (roads, power, telecommunications), but most of that was destroyed or removed by the Indonesians themselves and their client militias in the aftermath of the August 1999 vote for independence.<br /><br />Since then, East Timor's principal source of income has been international aid. However, the country's originally poor economic prospects have been transformed by the discovery of large oil and gas fields in the Timor Sea, which lies between Timor itself and the north coast of Australia. <br /><br />East Timor remains one of the region's poorest nations, with a per capita annual income estimated at between US$200 and US$500.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Department for Economic Affairs and Planning</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:http://www.gov.east-timor.org
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The staple diet for most East Timorese is similar to that of Indonesians (rice and spices) although there may well be difficulty in obtaining a variety of foods outside main urban areas due to the unstable political situation, the financial situation of many of the people and internal logistical difficulties. In Dili, there are a number of restaurants and cafes serving western cuisine, catering to the foreigners living and working there.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Fish (preferably fried, with delicacies being prawns).<br />&bull; Curries (chicken is a favourite).<br />&bull; Authentic Chinese, Japanese and Portuguese dishes.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>There is no service charge added to bills, but if the service calls for it, a 10% tip is sufficient.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous bars and nightclubs in Dili, with many on the beachfront. All are open late, and serve food as well as drinks. Try the <em>Poy Cholor</em> for food service until 0500, a live band and a DJ. If you are looking for something more adventurous then the <em>Caz </em>bar hires kayaks for late night fun, while a barbecue cooks fried fish.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Batik and embroidered fabrics in traditional patterns and colours are a good souvenir, as are woodcarvings and silverwork.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel rooms and other accommodation are still very limited and very expensive, especially for independent travellers. A government tax of 12% is added to all bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel rooms and other accommodation are still very limited and very expensive, especially for independent travellers. A government tax of 12% is added to all bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel rooms and other accommodation are still very limited and very expensive, especially for independent travellers. A government tax of 12% is added to all bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical services in East Timor are extemely limited. There are currently no optical or dental services. It is essential to take out comprehensive medical and travel insurance which includes emergency repatriation cover.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Dengue fever and Japanese encephalitis occur. Tuberculosis is prevalent. Rabies may be present. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Independence Day :
							20 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Consultation Day :
							30 August </p><p>Liberation Day :
							20 September </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Santa Cruz Day :
							12 November </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following may be imported into East Timor by travellers aged 17 years and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 75 cigars or 30g of tobacco or a proportional assortment of these products.<br />
&bull; 1.5L of spirits of more than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; 5L of wine.<br />
&bull; 75ml of perfume and 375ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; 1kg of coffee.<br />
&bull; 200g of tea or 80g of tea essence.<br />
&bull; Medicines for personal use.</p>
<p>The maximum value of goods is US$300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Weapons.</p>
<p>If you wish to import live animals and plants or animal and plant products, you must obtain a licence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The US Dollar (US$) is the official currency. For local transactions, the Indonesian Rupiah (IDR) may be accepted in border areas, but this should not be relied on.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers should take plenty of cash. Both the Australian ANZ bank and the Portuguese Banco Nacional Ultramarino have branches in Dili. Banks will not exchange Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These can only currently be used in the very few expensive hotels in East Timor. Cirrus/Maestro credit cards can be used to withdraw US Dollars from an ATM.</p><p>Cirrus/Maestro credit cards can be used to withdraw US Dollars from an ATM.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are not widely exchangeable. Only some top-of-the-range hotels may be able to exchange them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for at least six months beyond the date of entry into East Timor is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: US$30 if bought on arrival. You must pay in cash, so make sure you have the money in advance, as you won't necessarily have access to an ATM.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry tourist and business visas: 30 days. If you apply in advance, the visa can be valid for up to 90 days.</p>
<p>Visa Application Authorizations must be used within 12 months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On arrival (if arriving by air or sea) or via the consulate (or consular section at embassy). If you don't have access to a consulate, you can apply for a Visa Application Authorization online (<a href="http://www.migracao.gov.tl">www.migracao.gov.tl</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least 10 working days for visa processing if applying in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sufficient funds are required amounting to US$100 for each entry and US$50 a day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's better to apply for the 90-day multiple-entry visa if you are going to stay longer, otherwise you must submit visa extension applications directly to the Immigration  Service in Dili. Extensions cost US$35 for up to 30 days,  or US$75 for between 30 and 60 days. You can only extend a tourist visa up to a maximum of 90 days.&nbsp;Fines for overstaying can far outweigh the cost of arranging a visa extension.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-8.856838]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[125.797155]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>14,919 sq km (5,760 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,211,245 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>82.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dili.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>East Timor makes up the eastern half of the island of Timor (the western half belongs to Indonesia) which is situated off the northern coast of Western Australia. Also included within East Timor is the Oekussi Ambeno enclave on the northwest coast of the island, as well as the islands of Ata&uacute;ro (Pulo Cambing) and Jaco (Pulo Jako). East Timor is mountainous in the interior.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christian majority with 86% Catholic. Islam and animist beliefs are also practised.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most social courtesies are fairly formal. Many conventions will be similar to those of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/indonesia">Indonesia</a> (despite their political and religious differences) and many old East Timorese conventions will doubtless come to the fore in the coming years.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard, but some hotels also have sockets for Australian-style plugs with three flat pins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Taur Matan Ruak since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Francisco Guterres since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In May 2002, after 450 years of foreign occupation, East Timor became the 21st century&rsquo;s first new nation. Timor&rsquo;s pre-occupation history is sketchy. The migration of various peoples along the South-East Asian monsoon track evidently led to the population of the island by a civilisation that had no written records but worked in iron and had a relatively sophisticated agricultural system.</p>
<p>The Portuguese arrived in the early 16th century and by the 1550s had occupied the eastern part as the Dutch took control of the west, which became part of the Dutch East Indies.</p>
<p>The Japanese invaded in 1942, occupying the territory until its liberation in 1945 when <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/portugal">Portugal</a> regained possession and remained until the Carnation Revolution of 1974 after which the new government dissolved its colonial empire.&nbsp;Just nine days after East Timor declared independence in November 1975 it was invaded by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/indonesia">Indonesia</a> and in the savage counter-insurgency that followed, more than 100,000 East Timorese lost their lives either as a direct result of fighting or through hunger and illness.</p>
<p>In June 1999, Indonesia&rsquo;s President Habibie announced a referendum offering independence or integration, but after 80% opted for independence the Indonesian army went on an orgy of destruction that displaced hundreds of thousands of people.</p>
<p>In October 1999, a UN transitional administration was set up, pending elections, which were eventually held in April 2002 and Xanana Gusm&atilde;o was installed as the new nation&rsquo;s first president. More than 200,000 refugees returned to the fledgling nation.&nbsp;In 2008 the new president, Jos&eacute; Ramos-Horta was injured in an assassination attempt. UN peacekeeping forces were deployed until the mission ended in December 2012.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Xanana Gusm&atilde;o is a distinguished poet. A former freedom fighter, in prison in 1993 he was awarded the Great Cross of the Portuguese Order of Liberty. <br />
&bull;	East Timor competed at the 2014 Winter Olympics after Alpine skier Goutt Goncalves became its first athlete to qualify for the Games.<br />
&bull;	According to the East Timorese creation story a crocodile transformed into the island to return a favour to the boy who helped it recover from sickness.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of East Timor in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3415 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of East Timor in Belgium]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Cortenberghlaan 12<br/>Avenue de Cortenbergh<br/>Brussels<br/>1040<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In May 2002, after 450 years of near-continuous foreign occupation, East Timor became an independent state. The road to independence was long and traumatic. Even so there's plenty to admire in this picturesque country of beaches and mountains while getting to grips with the complex history.</p><p>The Portuguese first arrived on the island in the early 16th century and by the 1550s had occupied the eastern part. The Dutch took control of the western part, which became part of the Dutch East Indies and, after independence, Indonesia. In 1975, the new left-wing Portuguese government relinquished all of its colonies. East Timor then enjoyed just a few days of independence, before the Indonesians annexed it as their 27th province. There was little local resistance and the international community largely acquiesced.</p><p>In the aftermath, the main independence movement faced a savage counter-insurgency, during which the Indonesian army killed over 100,000 East Timorese. Finally, a referendum was offered to East Timor in 1999, and 80% opted for independence. Violent reprisals by the military followed, but the country eventually became independent.</p><p>Colonial architecture, Portuguese fortresses and other treasures from the 100-year Portuguese occupation can be found all over the country. However, many towns and villages were destroyed during the Indonesian occupation and the fighting in 1999, and these are only slowly being rebuilt. Many houses are still erected on stilts in the traditional way, using local materials such as grass, bamboo, tree trunks and palm leaves.</p><p>Despite the tragic recent history, East Timor's immaculate reefs, little-trodden mountain paths and rich, traditional cultural that has endured in the face of war make it a true hidden gem. Hiking in the hills will bring you to otherworldly jungle caves, while exploring settlements away from the capital of Dili give a taste of village life. Well off the beaten track, East Timor is still getting back on its feet, but is a raw and compelling destination.</p><p>In May 2002, after 450 years of continuous foreign occupation, East Timor became the world's newest independent state.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
