<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Ecuador" ColCode="ecu" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ec" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Ecuador]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ecuador has a highly changeable climate, which means that it can be variable at any time. Generally though, in the Sierra, there is little variation by day or by season, with changes occurring as you climb or descend instead. The coastal and Amazonian lowlands have a wet equatorial climate, but the higher you climb the colder it gets.</p><p>Rainfall is primarily affected by proximity to the eastern or western slopes of the Andes; in the west, June to September are drier with October to May typically wetter; in the east the opposite is true with October to February drier and March to September much wetter. There is also a variation in the amount of rainfall as you journey north to south, with the southern highlands much drier than the landscapes in the north. The coast can be enjoyed all year round, although it is cooler between June and November, when a sea mist known as <em>garua</em> sets in. January to May are consistently the hottest and rainiest months here. The Galapagos are also affected by <em>garua</em> between May and December; January to April here are the hottest months, with heavy but brief rainfall also possible. In the Oriente you can be affected by rainfall at any time, but it is wettest from March to September. Most cities are located in a comfortable subtropical zone.</p>
<p>Taking all of this into account, Ecuador&rsquo;s high season is June to early September. There is a shorter tourist season from December to January as well. However, the country is still not overly busy at any time and it&rsquo;s easy to engineer an escape from the crowds. The Galapagos however are often very busy and you must book well in advance to visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight natural fabrics; rainwear in subtropical areas. Warmer clothes are needed in upland areas. Make sure that you have good-quality, well-broken boots with plenty of ankle support for trekking or walking on uneven terrain.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ecuador is a small country and internal flight times are usually less than one hour, making air travel a quick and easy way to get around. Most flights operate out of Quito although Guayaquil also has direct services to main centres such as Cuenca, Loja and Galapagos.</p>
<p>TAME (<a href="http://www.tame.com.ec" target="_blank">www.tame.com.ec</a>) and LATAM (<a href="http://www.latam.com" target="_blank">www.latam.com</a>) fly frequently between Guayaquil, Quito and other destinations throughout the country. A number of small airlines serve the coast and eastern part of the country. Flying is the usual mode of transport for intercity travel.</p>
<p>Galapagos Islands: There are daily flights to the Galapagos Islands on national airlines from both Quito and Guayaquil; note that airfares to Galapagos are much higher than to any other domestic destination, although there are discount fares for Ecuadorian nationals and residents of Galapagos. There is also a national park admission charge, payable in cash only.</p><p>If you don&rsquo;t have a ticket there is the option to go along to the airport and join a waiting list for the flight as people frequently don&rsquo;t turn up.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ecuador's rocky coastline makes coast-hopping an inefficient and even dangerous means of transport for visitors. Several navigable rivers flow eastwards into the Amazon basin. Dugout canoes, which carry up to about 25 people, are widely used as a means of transport in roadless areas, particularly in the Oriente jungles and in the northwest coastal regions.</p>
<p>Tourist boats, luxury cruisers, converted fishing boats and hired yachts can all be used to travel between the Gal&aacute;pagos Islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>After years of neglect, the line between Quito and Guayaquil reopened in 2013. Tren Ecuador (tel: 1800 873 637; <a href="http://www.trenecuador.com" target="_blank">www.trenecuador.com</a>) runs luxury trains on this route.</p>
<p>Tren Ecuador also runs the famous Nariz del Diablo (Devil's Nose), which makes a spectacular mountain descent on its route between Riobamba and Sibambe. Also worth booking is its excursion from&nbsp;Quito to El Boliche, near Cotopaxi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>The Panamericana or Pan-American Highway is largely in good condition; there are still plenty of potholes in places though and some roads are more akin to rough tracks. Roads in the highlands can be especially bad due to the weather and cracks or holes here can be sizeable.</p><p>Ecuador&rsquo;s bus and coach service is extensive and affordable. Taking a bus can be an exhilarating, exciting way of seeing the country although it can also be cramped and scary too given the recklessness with which some drivers tackle corners and overtaking.</p>
<p>There are a number of different companies throughout the country and services to almost anywhere that you might want to go. Some of the most established have their own bus stations separate from the main terminals (<em>terminal terrestres</em>) and operate air-conditioned, comfortable buses, ideal for longer distance journeys.</p><p>These are widely available, particularly in larger cities and towns. Fares tend to be low but should be negotiated in advance. Taxis are metered in Quito, but rarely elsewhere. Taxis may be hired for a whole day. Drivers do not expect tips. All licensed taxis have a registration number prominently displayed; note this if there&rsquo;s a problem or if you feel threatened or mistreated.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is not required, but insurance is.</p><p>The national speed limit is 90kph (55mph) on highways and around 50kph (30mph) in urban areas, unless otherwise indicated. There are strong penalties for even the most minor driving offences.</p><p>Since getting around by public transport is so easy, few people rent cars in Ecuador. Nonetheless there are international and local car hire companies operating in Ecuador, with cities such as Quito, Guayaquil and Cuenca the places to arrange pick-up and drop off. It may be difficult to hire a vehicle in smaller towns, and even in main cities you should arrange your vehicle hire in advance. 4-wheel drive is necessary for some areas.</p>
<p>Drivers need to be at least 25 years old and have a major credit card for the deposit. Some companies hire cars to those aged 21-25 but the surcharges are much higher. Check for existing damage and make sure the car comes with a spare tyre and a jack. Drive carefully, make sure the car is always secure and check what the car rental insurance policy covers.</p><p>Increasingly popular, cycling is a good, if somewhat strenuous way of seeing Ecuador. Mountain bikes are recommended and you should ideally bring your own as bike hire services are scarce outside of Quito. Bring your own spares too. Bikes can also be taken on buses, canoes and almost every other type of transport if you find you&rsquo;ve run out of energy. Organised bike tours in Ecuador tend to be one-day trips, and mostly downhill, having been ferried to the top of the descent in a car by the company you book with.</p><p>The national speed limit is 90kph (55mph) on highways and around 50kph (30mph) in urban areas, unless otherwise indicated. There are strong penalties for even the most minor driving offences.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guayaquil and Quito have bus and minibus services operating at flat fares. Buses usually have a board in the window displaying their route.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Ecuador</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">puerto_ayora</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Ecuador</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">guayaquil</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Ecuador</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">esmeraldas</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Ecuador</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cuenca</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ecuador has two main international airports: Quito International Airport and Aeropuerto Simon Bolivar in Guayaquil. International airlines with flights to Ecuador include American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>), Iberia (<a href="http://www.iberia.com" target="_blank">www.iberia.com</a>), KLM (<a href="http://www.klm.com" target="_blank">www.klm.com</a>), LAN Airlines (<a href="http://www.lan.com" target="_blank">www.lan.com</a>) and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>). Baltra Airport serves the Galapagos islands.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s main airline, TAME (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tame.com.ec">www.tame.com.ec</a>), flies frequently between Guayaquil, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/quito">Quito</a> and other destinations throughout the country, as well as to a handful of international destinations. A number of small airlines serve the coast and eastern part of the country. Flying is the usual mode of transport for intercity travel.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ecuador/quito-mariscal-sucre-international-airport">Quito Mariscal Sucre International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 15 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 6 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International airfares vary according to season; high season is generally July to September and December.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International airfares vary according to season; high season is generally July to September and December.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Quito Mariscal Sucre International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeropuertoquito.aero<p>Quito Mariscal Sucre International Airport is located around 18km (12 miles) northeast of central Quito (36km/24 miles by road).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+593 2 294 4200</p>]]><b>Guayaquil José Joaquín de Olmedo Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.tagsa.aero<p>The airport is 5km (3 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guayaquil is the main port in Ecuador for both passengers and freight. However, very few cruise ships use Guayaquil as a port of call when sailing down South America. Some cargo lines that stop in the city also carry passengers, but this can be prohibitively expensive. If you are on your own boat or crewing a sailing vessel, it's possible to arrive in Ecuador, with Salinas the most popular port for international yachts.</p>
Manta is the second major port in Ecuador behind Guayaquil. A new cruise terminal at the port is currently under construction and is set to expand capacity on completion in the first half of 2018. The port typical sees just shy of 20 cruise calls in a calendar year.<p>Sailings from Europe take approximately three weeks to arrive in Ecuador.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are roads and international crossing points from neighbouring Colombia and Peru. Border formalities are fairly straightforward as long as your documents are in order. There are no taxes on tourists when travelling this way.</p>
<p>The main crossing point to Colombia is Tulcan in the northern highlands. There is a second border point in the Oriente but the area is dangerous to travel in. The vast majority of traffic to Peru crosses the border at Machala. Less popular but interesting alternative crossing points are available at Macara and La Balsa.</p>
<p>Some long-distance bus companies offer services from major cities such as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lima">Lima</a> and Bogota all the way to Ecuador.</p><p>There is no road access from North or central America; the Pan-American Highway stops in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/panama">Panama</a> and restarts in Colombia. In between lies 200km (124 miles) section of road-less jungle known as the Darien Gap. Lawless and wild, it is difficult to travel through and most people fly over it.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public phone boxes are scarce at present, but telephone offices can be found everywhere and are cheaper. Also, cellular public phones can be used with a pre-paid card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile phone service is provided by three private companies: ALEGRO, Movistar and Porta. Coverage is variable. Prepaid SIMs designed specifically for tourists are available from CNT (<a href="http://www.cnt.gob.ec" target="_blank">www.cnt.gob.ec</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet access is broadly available, especially in Quito where there are a number of internet cafes. They are used by both tourists and locals alike. Both the cost and speed of usage vary considerably, with the best service available in cities such as Quito, Guayaquil and Cuenca. Wi-Fi is increasingly available in hotels and some public places.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Under the Ecuadorian Constitution, journalists are given freedom of speech. However, the seizure of three private TV journalists and one radio journalist by the government in July 2008 prompted many concerns. Defamation in Ecuador is punishable by prison sentences of up to three years. By law, the government is given free air time on radio and TV.</p>
<p>Daily newspapers include <em>El Comercio</em>, <em>El Tiempo </em>and <em>La Hora</em>, with regional editions. There are two English-language newspapers, <em>Inside Ecuador </em>and <em>Q</em>, though both are published irregularly. International newspapers and magazines are available at international airports, main post offices and in some bookshops. The national commercial television station is TC Television; other stations include Ecuavisa, Gamavision, ETV Telerama and Teleamazonas<em>.</em> Radio Sucre provides news and information, whilst Cadena Radial Ecuatoriana (CRE)<em> </em>is a Guayaquil-based commercial network and Radio Nacional del Ecuador<em> </em>is government owned. Radio Centro is privately owned.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post in Ecuador is not especially reliable; airmail to Europe and the USA takes anything from a week to a month, while incoming deliveries are even less certain. Courier companies are the only viable alternative.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1800, Sat 0800-1200. Shorter hours are likely in rural areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Galapagos Islands</p><![CDATA[<p>Straddling the Equator 1000km (622 miles) off the coast of Ecuador, the Galapagos Islands are famous for being the inspiration for Charles Darwin's theory of evolution. Everyone can appreciate the beauty and uniqueness of somewhere where the impact of people has been kept to a minimum. There are 13 large islands and six small, which were formed by oceanic volcanoes some three to five million years ago. The most popular are Isla Bartolome, Isla Fernandina and Isla San Cristobel. Visitors come to the islands to see the unparalleled variety of wildlife that flourishes due to the remote location and temperate climate. The most famous residents are the giant tortoises after whom the islands are named, although other common species include iguana, dolphins, boobies and cormorants. The animals are so used to human company visitors can even swim with penguins and sea lions. Snorkelling and sailing are also popular.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>All aboard Tren Crucero</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ecuador's railways fell out of favour in the 1970s as the country's inhabitants took the roads. However, train travel has been enjoying a renaissance since 2012, when a £183million project to reopen the country's ancient railways was completed. The flagship service is Tren Crucero, a luxury tourist train that wends its way from the lofty capital, Quito, to the coastal city of Guayaquil via the infamous Devil's Nose.</p>]]><p><b>Bathe in Baños</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This tourist resort is booming despite having been several times evacuated because of its violent neighbour – the permanently erupting Tungurahua volcano. At night you can watch the mountain exhale fumes and lava, and during the day you can slip into one of the thermal baths, shower beneath a waterfall, take a hike or saddle up and ride through the forest.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Cotopaxi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cotopaxi is one of the world's highest active volcanoes and is the perfect peak to start your climbing career. Previous experience is not necessary if you want to scale Cotopaxi's ice-capped summit, but you need to be very fit and accustomed to high altitude. All ascents ought to be accompanied by an experienced, qualified guide.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the lofty town of Zaruma</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hidden in the highlands of El Oro is this beautifully preserved colonial town that doubles as a mountain retreat. Perched on a hilltop at the heart of a pre-Hispanic gold mining area, it has steep twisting streets, painted wooden houses, a beautiful main plaza and Ecuador's largest wooden church.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the lofty capital, Quito</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Scattered across a spectacular valley and surrounded by snow-capped volcanoes, Quito is one of South America's best-preserved colonial cities. Its lavishly decorated 16th-century churches are full of exquisite religious art, while its plazas remember marching conquistadores, shackled slaves and Jesuits preaching to the Indians. It's not all crumbling colonial facades, though: the hip New Town abounds with chic hotels, contemporary restaurants and cool bars.</p>]]><p><b>Go surfing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Pacific coast of Ecuador has sandy beaches and rolling surf that are a big draw for board riders. The village of Montañita has grown into something of a surfers' enclave with plenty of cheap accommodation and a lively nightlife. Mompiche in the north is also a superb place to catch a wave.</p>]]><p><b>Go to the Galapagos Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Straddling the Equator, 1,000km (622 miles) off mainland Ecuador, the Galapagos Islands famously helped inspire Charles Darwin's theory of evolution. Considered the most biodiverse place on Earth, this volcanic archipelago is home to a unique collection of wildlife including giant tortoises, iguanas, boobies, penguins, flamingos, sea lions, whales and sharks. The creatures are largely indifferent to humans, which means visitors can get up close and personal without them scurrying off. If you can, fork out for a cruise: it's the best way to see Galapagos.</p>]]><p><b>Haggle at an Indian market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Indigenous markets are an ethnologist's wonder, but also a cheap and efficient way to stock up on gifts for your friends and families. Otavalo is perhaps the most famous bazaar in Ecuador and its stalls sell anything from alpaca pashminas to wooden handicrafts. For a less touristy experience, head to the market in Saqisili, which offers an authentic slice of local life.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Cuenca</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cuenca is a charming colonial city crammed full of heritage buildings, which have earned it a place on UNESCO's World Heritage list. Wander down Cuenca's cobblestone streets and discover an excellent archaeology museum, beautiful blue-domed cathedral, pretty plazas and countless whitewashed buildings with ironwork balconies. Nearby Ingapirca gives a glimpse of Ecuador's pre-colonial history; the country's best-developed archaeological site, which dates back to pre-Inca times but was incorporated into an Inca site.</p>]]><p><b>Learn Spanish</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Quito is the Spanish language learning capital of South America, with a wealth of schools and classes set up to help you master the language, which locally is spoken softly and clearly. One-on-one and group tuition is available with personalised programmes drawn up to help speaking and communication skills in a short period of time. Check reviews and talk to other students to gauge the quality of the course and the academy in advance.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the mounds of Cochasqui</b></p><![CDATA[<p>North of Quito stand the most elaborate pre-Inca mounds and monuments in the country; 15 truncated clay pyramids, nine of which have long ramps attached. Covered by earth and grass they vanished from view but several have been subsequently uncovered and excavated to show how they were built.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the Devil's Nose</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Trains rattling along the so-called Devil's Nose pull off the seemingly impossible task of scaling a mountain, making this one of the world's most impressive railway journeys. Zigzagging through switchbacks and skirting along track inches from a rocky precipice, trains flirt with the edge as they navigate this perilous route, which takes passengers from the jungle to the lofty Andes above. A must do if you're visiting Ecuador.</p>]]><p><b>Straddle the equator</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A huge granite monument marks the equator just north of Quito – the only problem is that this massive marker is in the wrong place. The nearby Inti Nan museum claims to sit on the true equator, where guides show you how water swirls clockwise and anti-clockwise on either side of the line, plus various other tricks.</p>]]><p><b>Subject yourself to a good thrashing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The traditional healers of San Francisco Market in Quito offer cures for various afflictions, ranging from anxiety to nightmares. Treatments differ, but most involve being thrashed with nettles, which is thought to help patients gain control of their feelings. If the healers aren't sure what's wrong with you, they may give you an x-ray… using a dead guinea pig.</p>]]><p><b>Tackle the white water at Tena</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Famous for its rainforest and the rivers that flow through it, Tena is a beautiful place from which to discover the Amazon. It is, however, whitewater rafting that Tena is most famous for, with some of the best runs in the world available to tackle nearby. Sign up with a licensed agency and paddle down stunning stretches of river before riding grade 3-4+ rapids, depending on the route and river.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hike in the Andes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>High-altitude walks in the Cotopaxi and El Cajas national parks require some serious stamina due to the lack of oxygen, but if you can brave the altitude they offer the chance to see the stunning scenery of the grass-covered paramo plateaus, surrounded by volcanoes.</p>]]><p><b>Trek through the Amazon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The tropical rainforest of the Oriente teems with wildlife; there are thought to be at least 230 species of mammal and 1,600 species of bird here, not to mention 3,500 types of orchids and 4,500 butterflies. The Oriente begins as cloud forest on the flanks of the Andes, before plunging into the steamy Amazon jungle. This wet wilderness is home to a smattering of eco-lodges, from where travellers can embark on canoe expeditions through the intricate network of rivers and creeks that form the Amazon basin. Independent travel in the jungle is unadvisable.</p>]]><p><b>Veer off the tourist trail to Loja</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The isolated province of Loja is a maze of small ranges, valleys and cloud forest that is home to the town of Loja, one of Ecuador's most cultured cities. Removed from the regular tourist trail, it has a distinct character. Culturally self-sufficient it is home to the proud Saraguros people who maintain many of their old traditions. Loja is also a good base for visiting Parque Nacional Podocarpus and is a stopping point on the route to Vilcabamba.</p>]]><p><b>Wend your way down the ‘Avenue of Volcanoes’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Driving along the Pan Americana Highway, you'll find yourself surrounded by the snow-capped volcanoes that dominate the central highlands. Dubbed the 'Avenue of Volcanoes' by German explorer, Alexander Von Humboldt, the lofty Andean peaks are prime for hiking and climbing. Cotopaxi and Chimborazo are the most notable volcanoes; the latter has the distinction of being the closest point on Earth to the sun, thanks to something called the equatorial bulge.</p>]]><p><b>Wend your way to Guayaquil</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The economic heartland and commercial centre of the country, as well as the logical access point from the south, Guayaquil is a proud and prosperous place. The Malecon, the long riverside promenade that doubles as a town square, is a masterpiece of modern architecture, with shady gardens and nice restaurants. Nearby, Barrio las Peñas is a former slum converted into a bohemian district, full of galleries, souvenir shops and bars. All flights to the Galapagos originate or stop here en route from Quito.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$65.9 billion (2011 estimate).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, bananas, coffee, cacao, cut flowers and shrimp.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Industrial materials, nondurable consumer goods, fuels and lubricants.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Panama, Peru, Venezuela,  Colombia, China</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following economic crisis and poverty, the adoption of the US Dollar (in 2000) stablised the nation's economy. However, 33% of the population are still below the poverty line (2010). Growth has been slow but steady, at 3.6% in 2010 and 6.5% in 2011, with unemployment for 2011 at 4.2% and inflation at 5.4%.<br /><br />Ecuador has substantial petroleum resources, which has earned more than a half of the country's export revenue in recent years. It is the world's largest exporter of bananas and also grows coffee, cocoa, palm oil and sugar in significant quantities.<br /><br />Fishing is another important sector: seafood exports have expanded rapidly to the point where Ecuador is now the world's second-largest producer of shrimps. The mining sector produces gold, silver, copper and other metals.<br /><br />Ecuador is a member of the World Trade Organisation. In recent years, the country's increasing oil revenues have largely been devoted to paying off the country's substantial foreign debt. Ecuador is a member of the main regional integration bodies: the Andean Union and <em>Asociación Latinoamericana de Integración </em>(ALADI).<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dress in Ecuador is usually smart and conservative, punctuality is important, and greetings are made with a handshake. If possible, have business cards printed in English on one side and in Spanish on the other. Present the card with the Spanish side facing your Ecuadorian colleague. Fine wines and liquors make good gifts (avoid lilies and marigolds, which are used at funerals).<br /><br />Lunch is the usual business meal. Ecuadorians are used to alcohol with lunch. Women should note that while it is acceptable to drink wine, Ecuadorians are not accustomed to seeing a woman drink whiskey or other hard liquor. If a businesswoman wishes to pay for an Ecuadorian man's meal, arrangements should be made in advance; otherwise the man will refuse to let her pay. Business hours are usually Mon-Fri 0830-1630, with some businesses closing during lunch.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Centro de Exposiciones Quito de la Federación Ecuatoriana de la Pequeña Industria de Pichincha</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 244 3388.
					Website:
					Address: ,Centro de Exposiciones,Quito,]]><b>The Federación Nacional de Cámaras de Comercio del Ecuador</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (4) 268 2771
					Website:
					Address: ,,Quito and Guayaquil,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Ecuadorian dinner tables are blessed with some of the finest produce in South America; a testament to the country's fertile soil, varied typography and wildly different climates.</p><p>There are three main regions in Ecuador, each with its own style of cooking: highland cuisine revolves around warm, hearty dishes such as roast guinea pig and <em>locro</em>, a soup of potato, cheese, corn and avocado; coastal cuisine is dominated by seafood; and Oriente dinner tables typically feature rice, banana, yucca (a type of manioc root) and fish, including piranha.</p><p>Most food isn't spicy, but is inevitably accompanied by a bowl of <em>aji</em>, a hot pepper sauce for the bold to add at their peril.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cuy:</strong> Roast guinea pig.<br />
<strong>Locro:</strong> Soup of potatoes, corn, cheese and avocado.<br />
<strong>Empanadas:</strong> Corn pasties stuffed with meat, cheese or vegetables.<br />
<strong>Llapingachos:</strong> Cheesy potato cakes.<br />
<strong>Seco de chivo:</strong> Goat stew usually served on special occasions.<br />
<strong>Ceviche:</strong> Raw seafood &lsquo;cooked&rsquo; in lime and chilli.<br />
<strong>Encocados:</strong> Traditional coastal dish of fish served in a coconut sauce.<br />
<strong>Aji:</strong> An Ecuadorian hot pepper sauce.<br />
<strong>Fanesca:</strong> A special soup served at Easter, made with beans, grains and cod.<br />
<strong>Fruit:</strong> The best jungle fruits include: <em>chirimoya</em>, with its delicious custard-like inside; <em>mamey</em>, with its sweet, squash-like meat; and <em>pepinos</em>, a sweet cucumber-like fruit.<br />
<strong>Pilsner:</strong> A beer drunk by half of Ecuador.<br />
<strong>Club:</strong> A beer drunk by the other half.<br />
<strong>Pisco:</strong> The local brandy.<br />
<strong>Chicha:</strong> Fermented corn drink.<br />
<strong>Inca Kola:</strong> A green version of Irn-Bru.<br />
<strong>Herbal teas:</strong> Made from a range of native plants.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>12% tax and 10% service charge are usually added to the bill in hotels and restaurants. If the service has been good, add an additional quantity for the staff. In cheaper establishments, tip your server directly.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is little nightlife, except in Quito and Guayaquil where there are excellent restaurants and other attractions. Dining out can be varied, excellent and upmarket whilst still affordable. All sorts of restaurants are available in Quito and every type of cuisine is here. Bars and nightclubs are convivial places although the word nightclub in Ecuador can also translate as brothel so do be careful. Bars and clubs are also often raided for drugs by police. <br />
<br />
Quito&rsquo;s nightlife is concentrated in La Mariscal although there are cultural events and happenings taking place all over the city, often free of charge. Check out the monthly booklet Quito Cultura to see what&rsquo;s on. In smaller towns, social life takes place in the home and in private clubs. The cinema is the most popular form of entertainment. Things liven up from Thursday to Saturday evenings. Bars are generally open between 2000-0200, with clubs staying open until about 0400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the Province of Azuay, the cities of Cuenca and Gualaceo offer a wide variety of handicrafts at <em>ferias </em>(fairs) or special market days. The top attractions are the <em>ferias </em>of Otavalo, Ambato, Latacunga, Saquisili and Riobamba, most held once a week. They offer the visitor excellent bargains for Indian crafts and silver. Otavalo market is the largest and most-visited indigenous craft market in South America. This weekly, Saturday morning extravaganza, is an unforgettable experience. Plaza de Ponchos is full of textiles designed for tourists but he surrounding streets are packed with stalls selling paintings, jewellery, weavings, baskets, lether goods, hats, carvings, ceramics and antiques from all over the country. On the edge of town there&rsquo;s also an animal market. Saquisili market, on a Thursday is quieter and ostensibly for locals. Seven plazas are filled with brightly dressed highlanders in traditional outfits, who come from the surrounding communities to buy and sell everyday goods as well as textiles, bags and ornamental crafts. Polite bargaining is acceptable in small shops and in markets, but prices are usually fixed in 'tourist stores'. A few stores around the major hotels have fixed prices.</p>
<p>Principal silver stores are in Quito. Special purchases include native woodcarvings, varnished and painted ornaments made of bread dough, Indian tiles, woollen and orlon rugs, blankets, baskets, leather goods, <em>shigras</em> (shoulder bags) and hand-loomed textiles, indigenous art and native weapons.</p>
<p>Popular purchases also include Panama hats. Known locally as <em>sombreros de paja toquilla, </em>they are incorrectly described as being from Panama the world over. This iconic headgear is made from the woven fibres of a palm-related plant grown in the hills above Manabi. The finest are from Montecristi and the provinces of Aznoy and Canar, although they can most easily be bought in Cuenca.</p>
<p>Other traditional purchases include maz&aacute;pan, figures made of bread dough. These vibrantly coloured characters were originally sold to people to leave in cemeteries on the Day of the Dead for the hungry souls of the departed but they are now incorporated into several celebrations throughout the year.</p><p>Generally, most shops are open Mon-Sat 0900-1800. Family shops, set up outside the main towns, often stay open as long as someone is awake. Some shops open Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of accommodation options in Ecuador, with something to suit every taste and budget. Make sure to take a look at a room though and check out facilities before booking in to ensure that you are happy with them &ndash; if things aren&rsquo;t to your taste don&rsquo;t be afraid to ask for a better or bigger room, or to bargain politely for a better rate. Large cities boast upscale hotels and international chains as well as independent boutique options and family-run establishments. Luxury and eco-lodges can be found in the jungle.</p>
<p>The cheapest and shabbiest accommodation is usually adjacent to the bus station or main market, with better standards of accommodation usually found around the main plaza. Air conditioning is only really relevant on the coast or in the Oriente, whilst fans will suffice elsewhere; rooms with the service will cost around a third more. Conversely hot water is most important in the highlands. Better hotels have their own restaurants whilst cheaper and smaller places tend not to offer any sort of catering. During high season and over festivals such as New Year, carnival and Easter places to stay may get quickly booked up so plan your overnights carefully. </p>
<p>Hotel rooms should be booked at least one week in advance. Outside the main towns, a more or less standard price is charged per person for one night in a <em>pensi&oacute;n, residencial</em> or hotel. There is, however, a minimum charge per person. A 10% service charge and 5% tax are added to upper- and middle-range hotel bills. Cheaper hotels usually charge 5% at the most. There is also a range of accommodation on the Galapagos Islands. Booking hotels during fiestas and festivals can be difficult. Visitors should book well in advance.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Ecuador have been graded into three main categories according to standard and price bracket; complicated and often not used in practice, the terms have come to be loosely applied. A hotel is a generic establishment; a <em>hostal</em> or posada is an elegant inn, whilst pensions, <em>residencials</em> and <em>hospedajes</em> are more modest options. All categories provide at least basic facilities. Boutique is a buzzword applied rather randomly to new ventures and eco-lodges ought to be jungle retreats but again, the name isn&rsquo;t always attached to a place matching the description.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of accommodation options in Ecuador, with something to suit every taste and budget. Make sure to take a look at a room though and check out facilities before booking in to ensure that you are happy with them &ndash; if things aren&rsquo;t to your taste don&rsquo;t be afraid to ask for a better or bigger room, or to bargain politely for a better rate. Large cities boast upscale hotels and international chains as well as independent boutique options and family-run establishments. Luxury and eco-lodges can be found in the jungle.</p>
<p>The cheapest and shabbiest accommodation is usually adjacent to the bus station or main market, with better standards of accommodation usually found around the main plaza. Air conditioning is only really relevant on the coast or in the Oriente, whilst fans will suffice elsewhere; rooms with the service will cost around a third more. Conversely hot water is most important in the highlands. Better hotels have their own restaurants whilst cheaper and smaller places tend not to offer any sort of catering. During high season and over festivals such as New Year, carnival and Easter places to stay may get quickly booked up so plan your overnights carefully. </p>
<p>Hotel rooms should be booked at least one week in advance. Outside the main towns, a more or less standard price is charged per person for one night in a <em>pensi&oacute;n, residencial</em> or hotel. There is, however, a minimum charge per person. A 10% service charge and 5% tax are added to upper- and middle-range hotel bills. Cheaper hotels usually charge 5% at the most. There is also a range of accommodation on the Galapagos Islands. Booking hotels during fiestas and festivals can be difficult. Visitors should book well in advance.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Ecuador have been graded into three main categories according to standard and price bracket; complicated and often not used in practice, the terms have come to be loosely applied. A hotel is a generic establishment; a <em>hostal</em> or posada is an elegant inn, whilst pensions, <em>residencials</em> and <em>hospedajes</em> are more modest options. All categories provide at least basic facilities. Boutique is a buzzword applied rather randomly to new ventures and eco-lodges ought to be jungle retreats but again, the name isn&rsquo;t always attached to a place matching the description.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of accommodation options in Ecuador, with something to suit every taste and budget. Make sure to take a look at a room though and check out facilities before booking in to ensure that you are happy with them &ndash; if things aren&rsquo;t to your taste don&rsquo;t be afraid to ask for a better or bigger room, or to bargain politely for a better rate. Large cities boast upscale hotels and international chains as well as independent boutique options and family-run establishments. Luxury and eco-lodges can be found in the jungle.</p>
<p>The cheapest and shabbiest accommodation is usually adjacent to the bus station or main market, with better standards of accommodation usually found around the main plaza. Air conditioning is only really relevant on the coast or in the Oriente, whilst fans will suffice elsewhere; rooms with the service will cost around a third more. Conversely hot water is most important in the highlands. Better hotels have their own restaurants whilst cheaper and smaller places tend not to offer any sort of catering. During high season and over festivals such as New Year, carnival and Easter places to stay may get quickly booked up so plan your overnights carefully. </p>
<p>Hotel rooms should be booked at least one week in advance. Outside the main towns, a more or less standard price is charged per person for one night in a <em>pensi&oacute;n, residencial</em> or hotel. There is, however, a minimum charge per person. A 10% service charge and 5% tax are added to upper- and middle-range hotel bills. Cheaper hotels usually charge 5% at the most. There is also a range of accommodation on the Galapagos Islands. Booking hotels during fiestas and festivals can be difficult. Visitors should book well in advance.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Ecuador have been graded into three main categories according to standard and price bracket; complicated and often not used in practice, the terms have come to be loosely applied. A hotel is a generic establishment; a <em>hostal</em> or posada is an elegant inn, whilst pensions, <em>residencials</em> and <em>hospedajes</em> are more modest options. All categories provide at least basic facilities. Boutique is a buzzword applied rather randomly to new ventures and eco-lodges ought to be jungle retreats but again, the name isn&rsquo;t always attached to a place matching the description.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of pharmacies in urban areas. Good medical care is available in Quito, Guayaquil, and most of the big cities. Medical facilities outside the major towns are limited. Acute surgical and cardiac services are not available on the Galápagos Islands; therefore, for more serious illnesses, patients may be evacuated to the USA. Health insurance (to include emergency repatriation) is strongly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;It is advisable to drink only bottled or sterilised water in Ecuador. Avoid unpasteurised dairy products. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Ecuador is considered to have a high risk of Zika (ZIKV) virus transmission. The mosquito-borne illness can be spread from a pregnant woman to her unborn baby as well as through sexual contact. The World Health Organisation recommends travellers to Ecuador protect themselves from mosquito bites and suggests wearing clothes (preferably light-coloured) that cover as much of the body as possible, sleeping under mosquito nets and using insect repellent. Women who are pregnant, at risk of getting pregnant, or planning pregnancy should seek further advice from their doctor before travelling to Ecuador.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Vaccinations for tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Hepatitis B inoculation is recommended for those staying longer than 6 months and having intimate contact with local residents. Altitude sickness is a risk, particularly if flying directly into Quito (2,850m/9,350ft). Give yourself time to acclimatise before setting off into the mountains. Walk slowly and drink plenty of water.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling midweek are often observed on the closest Monday or Friday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Battle of Pichincha :
							24 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							10 August </p><p>Guayaquil Independence Day :
							09 October </p><p>All Soul's Day :
							02 November </p><p>Cuenca Independence Day :
							03 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>New Year's Eve :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Ecuador without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes or 25 cigars or 500g of tobacco (if arriving by air) or 60 cigarettes (if arriving overland).<br />
&bull; 3L of alcoholic drinks (no alcohol allowance if arriving overland).<br />
&bull; 300ml of perfume or 600ml per family.<br />
&bull; Gifts and personal effects up to US$500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prior permission is required for the import of fresh or dry meat, uncanned meat products and all plants and vegetables.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gold bars, antiques, narcotics, and wild animals and their parts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar (USD; symbol US$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of US$100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of US$1 and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents. Some coins are usual <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> cents and some are Ecuadorean centavos. They have the same value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged at banks and at <em>casas de cambio</em> (exchange houses), the latter being generally the best option. It may be difficult to exchange money in the Oriente. The rate of commission varies between 1 to 4%, so it is worth shopping around.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit/debit cards are accepted in most businesses. ATMs are available at most banks in urban areas. On the Galápagos Islands, currently only Mastercard is accepted.</p><p>ATMs are available at most banks in urban areas. Note that dirty or torn notes will not be accepted. Try to keep cash in smaller denominations; shopkeepers tend to refuse $50 and $100 bills as forgeries of these notes are common.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are generally accepted in the larger cities and can be exchanged into currency at most banks and <em>casas de cambio</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0830-1600; Sat mornings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All tourists need a passport valid for at least six months beyond their travel dates. In principal you also need an onward ticket or return ticket as well, although this is rarely asked for. Upon entry you will have to complete an international embarkation/disembarkation form, which is stamped along with your passport and must be kept together with it; you will have to present it when leaving the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals of a handful of countries (but not those listed above) require a transit visa; check with the consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-term visit visa: US$60 (US$30 visa fee plus US$30 application fee). Not applicable to nationals listed in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-term visit visas are valid for 90 days within a 12-month period and can be used for multiple entries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Temporary residence visas are issued by Ecuador&rsquo;s diplomatic representatives abroad and administered in Quito by the Direcci&oacute;n General de Extranjer&iacute;a.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Officially you need proof of sufficient funds to enter the country but this is rarely asked for. Proof of some savings or a credit card ought to suffice.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ecuador does not quarantine healthy cats or dogs that have been vaccinated for rabies at least 30 days in advance of entry into the country. You need to present a copy of the rabies certificate along with an endorsed veterinary certificate. All other pets may have to meet other requirements as to the limit on numbers that can be brought in and certificates pertaining to other diseases. Check with the relevant authority in your own country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-1.421970]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-78.870963]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>283,560 sq km (109,483 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>16,385,450 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>66 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Quito.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ecuador comprises a number of very distinct, dramatic geographical regions. The Andes run north-south through the country and form a mountainous spine with a number of peaks over 5,000m (16,404 ft) and some climbing to 6,500m (21,325ft). There are two main ranges, the central Cordillera and the Western Cordillera, which are separated by the Central Valley. At 400km (249 miles) long, the valley is just 50km (31 miles) wide. Its two rims are connected by a series of high plateaux that are separated by a series of gentle ridges. Rivers from the peaks run east to the Amazon and west to the Pacific Ocean.</p>
<p>The rims of the valley are crowned with the cones of more than 50 volcanoes, many of which are active. The highest is Chimborazo at 6,310m (19,685ft), although this behemoth is now extinct. Cotopaxi is the highest active volcano in the world at 5,897m  (19,347ft) but hasn&rsquo;t had a major eruption since the 19th century. Pichincha on the other hand issued an enormous mushroom cloud in 1999, Reventador has erupted several times sine 2002 and Sangay continuously fumes and emits ash. Earthquakes are also common in this region.</p>
<p>The Sierra, or central highlands, is a central trough. Home to almost half the population, it is also where the oldest and most important cities are situated. The Costa, or coastal plain, in contrast is a lowland area with a belt of hillier ground north of Guayaquil. In the extreme north there is tropical rainforest, whilst in the south the forest thins out and becomes tropical dry forest.</p>
<p>East of the Central Cordillera the forest-covered slopes descend into the jungle of the Oriente. This vast region comprises about a third of Ecuador&rsquo;s total surface area but is very sparsely populated and in fact home to just 5% of the population, most of whom are indigenous Indians or adventurous agriculturalists.</p>
<p>The Galapagos Islands lie 1,000km (621 miles) to the west of Ecuador, on the equator. These atolls are in fact the tips of massive volcanoes jutting above the sea and mark the point where two tectonic plates meet. Several of the islands are still active today; Fernandina, which last erupted in 2009, is the most active here. This extreme isolation is what has allowed the evolution of the unique flora and fauna found here.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christianity, with 95% Roman Catholic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Casual wear is widely acceptable, other than for business. Smart clothes are often required when visiting hotel dining rooms and better restaurants. Revealing clothes should not be worn in towns.<br /><strong><br />Photography: </strong>A tip may be requested if you wish to take someone's photograph and it is better to seek permission first.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>120 volts AC, 60Hz. Plugs used are North American-style (two perpendicular flat blades with or without a circular grounding pin).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Lenín Boltaire Moreno Garcés since May 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Lenín Boltaire Moreno Garcés since May 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As you would expect from a land peppered with ancient Inca sites and colonial cities, Ecuador has a colourful history. It began in earnest with the arrival of the Incas in the mid-15th century, who conquered the various tribes that had previously eked out a livelihood in northern South America.</p>
<p>The sun-worshipping Incas developed advanced cities such as Ingapirca, the ruins of which still stand today, but they couldn&rsquo;t fight off the Spanish, who conquered the region in the 1530s. The territory fell under the jurisdiction of Gran Colombia, a Spanish state that incorporated Colombia, Venezuela, Peru, Panama, Brazil and Guyana.</p>
<p>Spanish rule lasted until the early 19th century; the Spaniards were finally overthrown in 1822, by a force backed by Simon Bolivar, fresh from victory in Colombia. In 1828, the country declared war on Peru, whose armies had invaded Gran Colombia. A year later, a peace treaty was signed.</p>
<p>In 1831 Gran Colombia was dissolved and Ecuador's boundaries were permanently established. However, relations between Ecuador and Peru have been tense ever since.</p>
<p>The period between 1925 and 1948 was characterised by continual changes of government, administrative chaos and economic hardship. The discovery of oil and the sharp increase in world oil prices in the 1970s should have transformed Ecuador's economic fortunes, but the windfall was largely squandered.</p>
<p>After years of military rule, Ecuador had its first presidential elections in 1979. Power swung between left and right for the next two decades, until 1998 when Jamil Mahaud, of the centre-right Popular Democracy Party took office. However, he proved unable to arrest Ecuador's deteriorating economic situation, which included the freefall devaluation of the Sucre and a proposed switch to the US Dollar in a desperate bid for stability.</p>
<p>In January 2000, Mahaud was forced out under pressure from the military. Under strong international pressure, his successor, Gustavo Noboa, introduced an unpopular austerity programme, which destroyed his prospects for retaining office.</p>
<p>Rafael Correa, took office in 2007 and has since presided over a period of relative stability, investing heavily in infrastructure projects, education and welfare. However, his populist policies have been largely funded by oil, which has tumbled in value recently and left gaping holes in Ecuador&rsquo;s budget. Correa&rsquo;s treatment of political opponents and the media have also raised questions about his presidency.&nbsp;In 2017, Len&iacute;n Moreno - who served as Vice President under Correa from 2007 to 2013 - clinched a narrow victory&nbsp;in a contenous presidental election, with a promise to&nbsp;triple poverty relief, tackle corruption and ease up on the media.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; In 2008 Ecuador became the first nation in the world to declare that nature has constitutional rights.<br />
&bull; Quito and Krakow became the first World Cultural Heritage Sites in 1978.<br />
&bull; President-elect Moreno will become the world's first paraplegic head of state when he is sworn in on 24 May 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Ecuador in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 234 7200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ecuador.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 234 7200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1500 (consular services).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2535 15th Street<br/>Washington, DC<br/>20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Ecuador in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 207 584 1367.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://reinounido.embajada.gob.ec</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 207 584 1367.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1730.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Flat 3B, 3 Hans Crescent<br/>London<br/>SW1X 0LS<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Ecuador]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+593 2397 2200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinecuador.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+593 2397 2200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1100 (consular services).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>14th Floor<br/>Citiplaza Building, Naciones Unidas Avenue and Republica de El Salvador<br/>Quito<br/>P.O Box 17-17-83<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tiny by South American standards, Ecuador is packed with an amazing range of natural and cultural attractions; a microcosm of everything that is appealing about this fascinating continent. Tucked between Colombia and Peru, Ecuador outdoes its heavyweight neighbours because of, rather than despite, its size. In a single day you could take an early morning safari in the Amazon, drive up through a valley of active volcanoes and past verdant cloud forest before winding down to the Pacific coast in time for a seafood dinner.</p>
<p>Bisected by the equator (hence the name), Ecuador is divided into three distinct regions &ndash; Costa, Sierra and Oriente. The coast, or Costa, is hot and dry with sandy beaches, rolling surf and lively Afro-Ecuadorian towns. The mountainous centre, or Sierra, is a place of snow-capped Andean peaks, colonial towns and vibrant local markets. And the tropical lowland, the Oriente, which takes in parts of the Amazon, is home to innumerable species of wildlife and indigenous inhabitants. In addition, Ecuador controls the Galapagos Islands, a wildlife-rich archipelago in the Pacific Ocean, where Charles Darwin developed his theory of evolution.</p>
<p>At the heart of all this is Quito. As well as laying claim to being the world&rsquo;s second highest capital city (after La Paz in Bolivia) this lofty metropolis has the best-preserved historic centre in Latin America, not to mention an excellent culinary scene, vibrant nightlife and string of world-class cultural attractions.</p>
<p>However, it&rsquo;s Ecuador&rsquo;s natural beauty that draws in the crowds. Visitors flock from around the world to admire the wildlife, particularly on the Galapagos Islands, which is home to giant tortoises, whale sharks, sea lions and many more. For those seeking an adrenalin hit, world-renowned scuba diving, exceptional trekking and breathtaking climbing is rarely far away. Whether you explore it on two wheels or four hooves; on a raft, kayak or surfboard, Ecuador is a joy to get to know.</p><p>Tiny by South American standards, Ecuador is packed with an amazing range of natural and cultural attractions; a microcosm of everything that is appealing about this fascinating continent. Tucked between Colombia and Peru, Ecuador outdoes its heavyweight neighbours because of, rather than despite, its size. In a single day you could take an early morning safari in the Amazon, drive up through a valley of active volcanoes and past verdant cloud forest before winding down to the Pacific coast in time for a seafood dinner.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
