<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Egypt" ColCode="egy" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="eg" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Egypt]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Egypt is a huge country with plenty of variety in its climate; when it&rsquo;s chilly and wet in Alexandria, it can be ravishingly hot in Aswan.</p>
<p>The best time to visit most sights, including the pyramids and the Valley of the Kings, or diving in the Red Sea, is from February to April and October to November. During these months the heat reminds you that it's the &lsquo;Land of the Sun', but not too hot to be enjoyable. At this time, the skies and sea are a perfect blue. The downside is that these are the most popular times of the year for visitors.</p>
<p>In April, the hot, dusty <em>khamsin</em> wind blows from the Sahara, making touring of sights potentially troublesome; during an intense sand storm, vision may be reduced to a few metres. During the hot, dry summers (June-August) there&rsquo;s always the risk of dehydration and heat exhaustion, which might confine visitors indoors during the early afternoon.</p>
<p>Winters (November-February) are usually mild and often overcast, leaving the desert and its ancient monuments looking lacklustre. Rainfall is negligible except on the coast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Loose, lightweight, modest cottons and linens, with warmer clothes for winter and cooler evenings, are culturally and climatically suitable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The safest, and quickest, way to get around Egypt is by air, especially as travel by road can be hazardous. EgyptAir (<a href="http://www.egyptair.com" target="_blank">www.egyptair.com</a>) operates daily flights between the international airports at Cairo, Alexandria, Luxor, Aswan, Sharm El Sheikh, Assiut, Mersa Matrouh, Sohag and Hurghada, with flight times scheduled for convenient morning and evening departures. Flight times are short; between Cairo and Luxor, for example, the flight is just 45 minutes. It is advisable to book well ahead of your trip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are slow and fast ferry services linking Hurghada with Sharm el-Sheikh in Sinai (journey times - 1 hour 30 minutes (fast ferry) or 6 hours (slow ferry)). The traditional Nile sailing boats, <em>feluccas</em>, can be hired by the hour for relaxed sailing on the Nile. Regular Nile cruises operate between Luxor and Aswan, and sometimes between Cairo and Aswan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A comprehensive rail network run by Egyptian National Railways (tel: +20 2 2574 8279; <a href="https://enr.gov.eg" target="_blank">https://enr.gov.eg</a>)&nbsp;offers a high standard of service, with a range of fast and slow services. Routes operate from Salloum on the Libyan border to Alexandria and Cairo, and south down the Nile from Cairo to Luxor and Aswan. There are also links to Port Said and Suez and frequent trains between Cairo and Alexandria. Reduced fares are available for children.</p>
<p>To serve the Nile Valley tourist trade, several luxury air-conditioned day and night trains with sleeping and restaurant cars run from Cairo to Luxor and Aswan. For the overnight train, make bookings through a travel agent, or through Ernst (<a href="http://www.wataniasleepingtrains.com" target="_blank">www.wataniasleepingtrains.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The road network in Egypt serves the Nile Delta to Sinai and Cairo, and then follows a course along the banks of the Nile to Abu Simbel via Luxor and Aswan. Desert roads link the oases of the Western Desert and the Red Sea resorts via the Eastern Desert.</p>r<p>There are motorways in and around Cairo but the standard of driving is notoriously chaotic. Motorways are generally in good condition. Roads along the Mediterranean and African Red Sea coasts, and the route looping through the Western Desert oases from Asyut to Giza are fully paved. Private motoring in the desert regions is not recommended without suitable vehicles and a guide.</p><p>Long-distance buses and coaches connect the country&rsquo;s major towns and can be fast and inexpensive. Tickets can be booked for all routes at the Cairo Gateway bus terminal. The East Delta Bus company serves the Sinai Peninsula. It is affiliated to the West Delta Company (<a href="http://www.westmidbus-eg.com" target="_blank">www.westmidbus-eg.com</a>) which covers the Western Desert, and the Upper Egypt Company (<a href="http://www.bus.com.eg" target="_blank">www.bus.com.eg</a>) which runs services around the delta to Cairo, the Nile Valley and the Red Sea coastal region.</p><p>Taxis are available in all the larger cities and are metered. In Cairo, taxis are white and black, in Alexandria they are orange and black. Long-distance group taxis for all destinations are relatively cheap. It&rsquo;s important to agree fares in advance. Be prepared to haggle if necessary.</p><p>Third-party insurance is compulsory and should be included in your car hire agreement. An International Driving Permit is required to drive any motor vehicle. A carnet de Passage or a suitable deposit is necessary for the temporary import of your own vehicle.</p><p>The speed limit is usually 90kph (56mph) on motorways and 100kph (62mph) on the desert motorway from Cairo to Alexandria. Seatbelts must be worn when travelling. All vehicles (including motorcycles) are required by law to carry a fire extinguisher and a red hazard triangle.</p><p>Major car hire companies like Hertz, Avis and Budget, which have offices in the airports, offer breakdown services.</p><p>Car hire is available through international and local car hire companies. The driver must be at least 25 years of age.</p><p>You would have to have a death wish to cycle in Cairo. That said, in Luxor it&rsquo;s a pleasant way to get around town, and there are many places for bicycle hire especially on the west bank.</p><p>The speed limit is usually 90kph (56mph) on motorways and 100kph (62mph) on the desert motorway from Cairo to Alexandria. Seatbelts must be worn when travelling. All vehicles (including motorcycles) are required by law to carry a fire extinguisher and a red hazard triangle.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government-owned Cairo Transport Authority runs buses and tram services in Cairo and also operates cross-Nile ferries. There is a central area flat fare. In addition, there are other buses and fixed-route shared taxi and minibus services run by private operators. Vehicles normally wait at city terminals to obtain a full load, but there are frequent departures. Fares are three to four times higher than on the buses with the advantage of a little more comfort. The easiest way to get around Cairo is using the modern Metro.</p>
<p>Alexandria has buses and tramways, with first- and second-class and distance-regulated fares. The trundling tram, although quaint, can be very slow to travel through the city.</p>
<p>Luxor has minibuses with fixed routes. A more picturesque way to travel around the city is in a <em>caleche</em> (horse-drawn cart). Aswan and Luxor also have passenger boats criss-crossing the Nile.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Egypt</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">suez</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Egypt</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">marsa_matrrsquoh</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Egypt</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">aswan</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">16.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">19.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Egypt</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">alexandria</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Egypt is well served by international airlines that fly direct from around the world, including multiple routes operated by its national carrier, EgyptAir (<a href="http://www.egyptair.com" target="_blank">www.egyptair.com</a>). British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) offers direct flights from the UK. The main international airports are in Cairo, Alexandria, Sharm el Sheikh, Luxor, Marsa Alam and Aswan. Charter flights depart mainly from Europe and the Middle East into the Red  Sea coast airports.</p>
<p>The most expensive time to fly is spring and autumn, with the cheapest time of year being during the months of July and August.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a href="http://i/egypt/cairo-international-airport">Cairo International Airport</a>, <a href="http://i/egypt/sharm-el-sheikh-international-airport">Sharm El-Sheik International Airport</a>, <a href="http://i/egypt/hurghada-international-airport">Hurghada International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Cairo: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 4 hours 40 minutes; <a href="new-york-city">New York</a> - 10 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cairo International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.cairo-airport.com<p>Cairo International Airport is located 22km (13.5 miles) northeast of Cairo in Heliopolis.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+20 2 2265 5000</p>]]><b>Sharm el-Sheikh International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.sharm-el-sheikh-airport.com<p>Sharm el-Sheikh International Airport is located 18km (11 miles) northeast of Sharm el-Sheikh.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+20 69 360 1140</p>]]><b>Hurghada International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.eac-airports.com<p>Hurghada International Airport is located inland, 6km (4 miles) southwest of Hurghada.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+20 65 344 5543</p>]]><b>Luxor International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport  is 5.5km (3.5 miles) from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/luxor">Luxor</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no ferry routes linking Egypt with mainland Europe. Daily ferries ply the route between Nuweiba and Taba on Egypt&rsquo;s Sinai Peninsula and Aqaba in Jordan. There is an intermittent ferry service along the Nile between Wadi Halfa in Sudan and Egypt&rsquo;s High Dam, and a car ferry service from Jeddah to Suez via the Suez canal.</p><p>Ferries arrive and depart from the seafront ferry terminal building in Nuweiba and the Taba Heights marina in Taba for the daily trips to Jordan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no international rail links to any of Egypt's northwestern neighbours. The railheads at Aswan and Wadi Halfa, in Sudan, are connected by a ferry across Lake Nasser.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Egypt, which is bordered by Sudan in the south, Libya to the west, Israel and the Gaza strip to the east and the Mediterranean Sea to the north, is not easily accessed by road and bureaucracy at border points can prevent entry by both car drivers and coaches. The border crossing to Israel at Rafah is closed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public telephones take cards available from pharmacies, tobacconists and newspaper shops, and are a convenient way to call home. Telephones in hotels can be expensive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming exists with many international mobile phone companies, although coverage is limited to Cairo, Alexandria and major towns along the north coastline of the Red Sea and the Nile. If you&rsquo;re in Egypt for some time, it is much cheaper to buy a local SIM card, either Vodafone or MobiNil, if your mobile phone is unblocked.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet caf&eacute;s in the main cities, including Cairo, Alexandria, Dahab and Luxor. Even small, more remote towns including Siwa will have at least one venue, usually in the market area. Connection is usually reliable. Tourists can also access the Internet in hotels, with in-room Wi-Fi available, though often at a hefty price.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Egyptian press is one of the most influential and widely read in the region, while Egyptian TV and the film industry supplies much of the Arab-speaking world with shows from its Media Production  City.<br />
<br />
<em>Al-Ahram Weekly</em>&nbsp;(http://weekly.ahram.org.eg/) is the oldest newspaper in the Arab world and is published in English. State-runEgypt Radio Television Union (ERTU) operates domestic networks; it also operates satellite networks such as Nile TV International, which broadcasts some programmes in English and Hebrew. Egypt was the first Arab nation to have its own satellite TV station, Nilesat 101. The country's first private TV stations came on air in 2001, broadcasting via satellite.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The postal system is efficient for international mail. Airmail takes about five days to western Europe, and eight to 10 days to the USA.</p><p>Daily 0900-1400 (some until 1500) except Friday; the central post office in Cairo is open 24 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Abu Simbel temples</p><![CDATA[<p>Dedicated to the Pharaoh Ramses II (1304-1237 BC), and his beloved queen Nefertari, the two temples at Abu Simbel stand on the shores looking out over Lake Nasser. They were discovered covered in sand by the Swiss explorer Burckhardt in 1813, and later moved as part of an UNESCO-funded project when the Aswan Dam was built and the waters of the lake rose significantly.</p>]]><br/><p>Deir el Bahri</p><![CDATA[<p>Hatshepsut's Temple is the mortuary temple of Queen Hatshepsut. Located on the West Bank in Luxor, this spectacular temple was built by the Queen's architect, Senenmut, in honour of the only woman ever to reign over Egypt as Pharaoh. Set against towering cliffs in the Theban Hills, this unique temple attracts bus loads of tourists every day to see one of the most impressive sites in the Necropolis. The temple, with its many monumental ramps, fine terraces, elegant columns and hieroglyphic paintings, also tells the story of Hatshepsut's journey to the Land of Punt (which is believed to be modern-day Somalia) to bring back treasures such as ebony, ivory, gold, perfumes and myrrh trees.</p>]]><br/><p>Karnak Temple (Ipet-Isut)</p><![CDATA[<p><em>Karnak Temple</em> is a vast complex consisting of three main temples, several smaller enclosed temples, and a number of outer temples. The most spectacular of these is the <em>Temple of Amun </em>(<em>Amun&rsquo;s Precinct</em>). This is entered via the <em>Avenue of the Sphinxes</em> that once connected Karnak and <em>Luxor Temples</em>, and led through the ancient city of Thebes, the capital of Egypt during the period of the Middle and New Kingdoms. The whole complex was built over a period of 1300 years and includes several of the finest examples of ancient Egyptian design and architecture. Among them are the <em>Hypostyle Hall</em>, considered one of the world&rsquo;s great architectural achievements with around 130 enormous carved columns covering an area of 6000 sq metres (64,586 sq ft), and the <em>Obelisk of Thutmose I</em>, a 22m (71ft) monument, the only one of four original obelisks that is still standing.</p>]]><br/><p>Pyramids of Giza</p><![CDATA[<p>Egypt's main tourist attraction has long been the Giza Necropolis on the edge of Cairo. One of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World, the Great Pyramid is the oldest here, dating back to around 2550BC and the reign of Khufu. It is also the largest pyramid, originally standing 146m (479ft) high. Nearby are the pyramids of Khafre (Khufu's son) and the considerably smaller Menkaure's (his grandson). Meanwhile, the Great Sphinx watches over all. Once crowded with tourists, the site has been eerily quiet since the first revolution. A visit now brings with it the unusual privilege of having the pyramids practically to yourself.</p>]]><br/><p>Valley of the Kings</p><![CDATA[<p>The Valley of the Kings is a limestone valley situated in the Theban Hills where the mummified bodies of many Egyptian pharaohs were interred. The area marks a period in ancient Egyptian history in which the pharaohs abandoned the pyramid style and chose instead tombs dug within limestone in order to preserve the mummies for eternity and prevent grave robbing. The tombs, although stripped of their contents centuries ago, still display fantastic wall paintings depicting the lives of the pharaohs in ancient Egypt, down to the minutest detail. The most famous tomb is that of Tutankhamun, discovered in pristine condition by Howard Carter in 1922. The many treasures found in the tomb are now exhibited in the Egyptian Antiquities Museum in Cairo.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire Alexandria</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nestling the Mediterranean, Egypt's 'second city' has a French colonial atmosphere and a relaxed Greek influence, a mix of continental patisseries, art deco architecture and crowded sandy beaches in summer. Don't miss the Roman Amphitheatre's mosaics or the modern Bibliotecha and museums. Take a walk along the corniche to work up an appetite for a dinner of freshly-caught fish.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the Valley of the Kings</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Valley of the Kings, in the Theban Hills, is where the mummified remains of many Egyptian pharaohs were interred. Although stripped of their contents centuries ago, the tombs still display fantastic wall paintings depicting the lives of the pharaohs. The most famous tomb is that of Tutankhamun, discovered in pristine condition by Howard Carter in 1922.</p>]]><p><b>Dive the Red Sea</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Red Sea justly deserves its worldwide reputation for underwater adventure. Teeming with colourful marine life, the crystalline waters are landscaped with coral and dramatic drop-offs. The Ras Mohamed National Park, a headland 20 km (12 miles) west of Sharm el-Sheikh, shows off this underwater world at its best.</p>]]><p><b>Experience Islamic Cairo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It's bustling and busy in ancient Islamic Cairo, but the crowds thin out along the serene street of Al-Muezz Al-Din, with spot lit mosques and mausoleums lining the pedestrianised cobbled street. A local will, doubtless, offer to take you up a minaret; ascend the one at Al-Azhar Mosque – home to the world's oldest university – for panoramic views.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the temples at Luxor</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Straddling the Nile, Luxor is the site of the ancient city of Thebes. On the east bank lies the spectacular Temple of Karnak featuring epic statues, obelisks and lotus-columned halls. In the city centre is Luxor Temple, spectacular when lit up at night. Make the most of the experience by taking a gods-eye view in a hot-air balloon.</p>]]><p><b>Get lost in Khan-el Khalili bazaar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a trip to Cairo's famous labyrinthine, medieval Khan-el Khalili bazaar, where haggling for spices, copper, perfume and trinkets has been refined into an art form. Don't miss Fishawi's teahouse; in business for over 200 years, it is the ultimate place to people watch.</p>]]><p><b>Go on pilgrimage to Mount Sinai</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For centuries, Christian pilgrims have made the journey to Mount Sinai to witness the sunrise over the desert landscape. The three-hour trek is breathtaking, but if it sounds too ambitious, stay overnight at the UNESCO-listed 6th-century Saint Catherine's Monastery, hire a camel and walk down in leisure.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Aswan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The former frontier town of Aswan is a popular stopping-point for cruise liners, and the <em>feluccas</em> drifting along the Nile at sunset is one of Egypt's enduring sights. Attractions include Elephantine Island and Elnabatat's Island (the 'island of plants'), upon which Lord Kitchener built a beautiful botanical garden in the 1890s that's still open to visitors today.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the Pyramids of Giza</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Egypt's main tourist attraction has long been the Giza Necropolis on the edge of Cairo. One of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World, the Great Pyramid dates back to around 2500BC. Wander the site to truly understand the enormity of the building task, or take in the sights by horse or camel, not forgetting to visit the Great Sphinx nearby.</p>]]><p><b>Play a round of golf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>While it's not a sport readily associated with Egypt, the country has made quite a golfing name for itself and offers around 20 courses. They range from locations within sight of Cairo's Pyramids – the most famous being the Mena House Oberoi 18-hole course – to settings alongside the Nile and the Red Sea.</p>]]><p><b>Relax at Siwa Oasis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of six oases in the vast Western Desert, and a good base for desert exploration, Siwa is a peaceful haven of palm-fringed saltwater lakes. Home to the Oracle Temple of Amun visited by Alexander the Great, Siwa is dramatically crowned by the 13th-century fortress ruins of Shali, best climbed at sunrise or sunset to avoid the fierce desert heat.</p>]]><p><b>Snorkel in Sharm el-Sheik</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Diving is an ever-popular way to see the dazzling marine life and coral, however Egypt's spectacular coastline is accessible even without a wetsuit. Simply wade out with a mask or snorkel or take a glass-bottomed boat from the shores of Sharm el-Sheik and the fish will come to you.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the Old Kingdom at Saqqara and Dahshur</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Few visitors know before arriving in Egypt that the country's Old Kingdom precedes the building of the Pyramids of Giza by many centuries. Acting as the necropolis to the ancient capital of Memphis, Saqqara's crowning glory is the stepped Pyramid of Djoser. Nearby Dahshur is famous for its Bent Pyramid and a huge field of royal tombs.</p>]]><p><b>Take to the Nile</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ply the river between Luxor and Aswan for that quintessential Nile experience. Egrets flock to the water's edge and Egypt's ancient archaeological wonders, including the temple of Kom Ombo, unfold like a storybook along the bank. Lasting between three and five days, take a traditional white-sailed <em>felucca</em>, or splash out on a <em>dahabiya</em>, a luxury furnished wooden barge.</p>]]><p><b>Test your skills as a camel trader</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Not the place to buy souvenirs, frenetic (and fragrant) trading takes place most mornings from 0700 at the Camel market (Souq al-Gamaal). An entertaining assault on the senses, Camels are transported from Sudan to Birqash 35 km (20 miles) west of Cairo, before being prodded and poked by potential buyers.</p>]]><p><b>Traverse the Suez Canal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The best way to see this great feat of modern engineering is by boat; the view from the Peace Bridge that crosses the canal near Ismailiya comes a good second. The sight of giant tankers plying the narrow channel between the Red Sea with the Mediterranean is something you don't forget in a hurry.</p>]]><p><b>Wander the Abu Simbel temples</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dedicated to the Pharaoh Ramses II (1304-1237 BC), and his beloved queen Nefertari, the two temples at Abu Simbel stand on the shores of the stunning Lake Nasser. Discovered covered in sand by the Swiss explorer Burckhardt in 1813, they were later moved as part of a massive UNESCO-funded project to save them from the rising water of the lake.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$336.3 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, petroleum products, cotton, textiles and metal products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, food, chemicals, wood products and fuels.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Germany, Italy, China and Turkey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On taking power in 1970, Anwar al-Sadat introduced a policy of <em>infitah </em>(openness) towards investment. Egypt's economy underwent rapid growth during the 1970s with the swift expansion of the oil industry, tourism and the Suez Canal, and it has continued to expand in subsequent decades.<br />
<br />
The tourist sector is expanding rapidly, particularly along the Red Sea and Mediterranean coasts, despite sporadic terrorist activities of Islamic fundamentalists. Agriculture, which relies on irrigation from the Nile, employs one-third of the working population. Foreign aid, especially from the USA, is an important source of government funds.</p>
<p>Cairo<has an increasing number of &nbsp;hotels and meeting halls, which are equipped for use as conference centres. The Cairo International Conference Centre, 12km (7 miles) east of Cairo International Airport, has an exhibition hall complex, banquet hall, parking and comprehensive facilities. There is also a convention centre at Alexandria  University, which has a main hall with seating for 2,400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Courtesy and hospitality are important when doing business in Egypt. The host of a business meeting will usually offer tea or a small snack before commencing. It&rsquo;s polite to refuse the first offer, but once the host insists, the guest should then accept.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Alcohol is legal, but should be avoided until visitors know their Egyptian colleague's attitude towards drinking, and, if acceptable, should be drunk in moderation. It is not considered seemly for women to over-indulge in alcohol. If invited to a business lunch, expect food to be lavish and plentiful.</p>
<p>Throughout the Arab world, it is considered bad manners either to display anger or to openly criticise another person in public. Tact and diplomacy are always required. In social life, punctuality is almost laughable. For business, visitors should be on time but expect locals to be often late, and do not take offence. Men should not offer to shake a woman's hand, and vice versa, unless clearly invited to do so. Men and women should dress smartly for business meetings &ndash; suits and tie for men; suit for women or smart trousers/skirt/jacket &ndash; and always dress modestly. Shoulders and knees should never be shown.</p><p>Government offices are open 0900-1600 (some until 1700) except Fridays and sometimes Saturdays. Muslim businesses may be closed for Friday prayers, Christian businesses on Saturday afternoons and Sundays. All offices keep shorter hours during Ramadan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cairo International Conference and Exhibition Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 2263 3222
					Website:http://www.cicc.egnet.net
					Address: Nasr City,Nasr Road,Cairo,]]><b>Egyptian General Company for Tourism and Hotels (Information on Conferences/Conventions)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 7925 5529 ,795 7355
					Website:http://www.egoth.com.eg
					Address: Garden City,6th floor,4 Latin America Street,Cairo,]]><b>Federation of Egyptian Chambers of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 795 1835 ,795 6479
					Website:
					Address: Bab El Lok,4 El-Falaky Square,Cairo,]]><b>Egyptian-British Chamber of Commerce in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7499 3100
					Website:http://www.theebcc.com
					Address: 299 Oxford Street,PO Box 4EG,London W1A 4EG,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Egyptian cuisine combines many of the best traditions of African, Middle Eastern and Mediterranean cooking, and is both delicious and healthy. Vegetables, meats and aromatic herbs and spices are combined to create colourful and flavoursome dishes.</p>
<p>Typically, a meal starts with soup made from pulses or beans, onions, tomatoes and leafy green vegetables. A large helping of garlic or spices give them a kick. A dish of meats slow-roasted with herbs, or fish stew accompanied by couscous or rice may follow. Meals are almost always served with salad, dips and flatbread.</p>
<p>Desserts, particularly pastries made using figs, nuts, and dates and smothered in honey are common, as is yogurt.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Aish merahrah</strong>: Pitta-like flatbreads made with fenugreek seeds and maize flour.<br />
<strong>Slow-roast meats</strong>: Chicken, lamb, veal and rabbit are all popular meats for slow-roasting with herbs. Served with rice or couscous.<br />
<strong>Ful medames</strong>: Fava beans topped with hard-boiled eggs and sliced vegetables.<br />
<strong>Babaganoush</strong>: Pureed aubergine dip.<br />
<strong>Samak Makli</strong>: Fried fish considered a speciality of Alexandria.<br />
<strong>Ful</strong>: Fava beans with lemon and herbs.<br />
<strong>Molokheyya</strong>: Wild okra soup flavoured with a garlic and coriander.<br />
<strong>Mahshi/Dolma</strong>: Vine leaves stuffed with rice, herbs, tomato and sometimes beef mince.<br />
<strong>Temayya</strong>: Spicy deep-fried mashed bean or chickpea patties. Egypt&rsquo;s take on falafel.<br />
<strong>Shawarma</strong>: Pieces of meat, often lamb, skewered, barbequed and served in a flatbread.<br />
<strong>Koshari</strong>: Rice or pasta mixed with lentils, tomato and fried onion.<br />
<strong>Mahallabiyaa</strong>: Rice pudding traditionally served cold and flavoured with rose water and sprinkled with spices such as nutmeg.<br />
<strong>Kahwa</strong>: Thick, strong Turkish-style coffee.<br />
<strong>Shay bil na'na'</strong>: Tea served with a large sprig of fresh mint and plenty of sugar.<br />
<strong>Karkaday</strong>: Bright red drink made from hibiscus flowers.<br />
<strong>Aswanli</strong>: Dark beer made in Aswan, southern Egypt.<br />
<strong>Zibib</strong>: Alcoholic aniseed-flavoured drink.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>If you are invited to dine with a family in their home and you are served meat such as poultry, lamb or veal, then consider this an honour. Egyptians regard a meat dish as a luxury. Pigeon is a delicacy and cooked on special occasions. It will be prepared and cooked with great care, but probably served complete with its head.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A tip of 10-12% is added to hotel and restaurant bills but an extra tip of 5% is normal.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As the sun sets, people start spilling onto the streets, congregating in coffee shops and restaurants. Go to any waterfront - along the Nile in Cairo and Luxor, or the seafronts in Alexandria and Sharm el Sheikh - and you'll find the corniche humming with the chatter of friends cruising arm in arm to catch the breeze. Street vendors selling kebabs, chai-sellers shouldering giant urns and trinket merchants with the latest colourful imports vie for the attentions of passers-by. This is the place to meet the locals, gauge the national mood and share in the jubilations of a local football success.</p>
<p>A huge draw for visitors &ndash; both domestic and foreign &ndash; are the sound and light shows held in spectacular fashion in many of the country's archaeological sites. Here, you can come face-to-face with the spot-lit Sphinx at Giza or watching the entire Temple of Karnak unfold to music at Luxor. The best of these shows is held at the Temple of Ramses II in Abu Simbel. Commentary is often in different languages every evening so check it&rsquo;s the right one for you.</p>
<p>Sophisticated nightclubs, bars and restaurants can be found in Cairo, Alexandria and most large towns. The nightlife in Luxor and Aswan often includes barbecues along the Nile or dinner cruises.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One of Egypt&rsquo;s best shopping experiences is Cairo&rsquo;s medieval market Khan-el-Khalili. Everything from cheap souvenirs to household goods, reproduction &lsquo;antique&rsquo; jewellery, brass plaques and jugs, copper utensils and cotton goods fill the narrow noisy alleyways. Be sure to visit the Spice Bazaar, where the aroma of cloves, coriander and cinnamon will leave you intoxicated. Nearby is the Perfume Bazaar. Cairo also has its share of modern shopping centres, department stores and small fashionable shops, particularly near its central intersection, Tahrir   Square. In Alexandria, antique stalls cluster the area around Sharia el Attareen, while in Luxor the souk is mainly geared for the tourist market but is a fun place to wander around in the evenings.</p>
<p>The vendor is likely to charge what he feels happy&nbsp;with charging, usually a hugely inflated price for foreigners. Bargain hard! Check the price of everything before purchasing (and consuming), even food and drink. Best buys include alabaster vases, old books, brass and copperware, papyrus prints, leatherwork and ceramics. Muski glass is a popular souvenir; this colourful glass is identified by its air bubbles and has been hand-blown in Cairo for centuries. Carpets make good buys too.</p><p>Shopping hours vary widely according to season and location. In most cities, shops are generally open daily 1000-2000, taking a lengthy lunch break in summer, and some will close on Fridays. Markets tend to stay open later in the evening. During Ramadan, especially when it falls in summer, shops may well close at sunset and reopen several hours later, after eating. Some shops may close during Friday midday prayers, for a couple of hours. Christian-owned shops might close on Sundays.</p><p>Haggling is expected, and usually encouraged in bazaars, but prices are fixed in new department stores.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Egypt boasts some beautiful luxury hotels, resorts set in landscaped gardens, characterful guesthouses, historic hotels, eco-lodges and desert camps that offer great value for money. It has seen a massive investment in its accommodation sector in recent years with the introduction of a system that monitors and categorises each establishment.</p>
<p>Hotels are graded 1-5 stars, although standards in each category can differ to those expected in similarly starred hotels in Europe and the USA. Standards are improving significantly with more emphasis being placed on service and providing enhanced facilities. All hotel categories must now have wheelchair access, for example, along with the availability of medical services.&nbsp;</p>
<p>All the top resorts, at Sharm el-Sheik, Hurghada and Luxor for example, offer lavish accommodation for less than top-dollar prices. Many include international restaurants, spas and infinity pools, and golf courses, and they are a good place to watch belly dancing or other cultural entertainment which cater especially for tourists. Most of the resorts on the Red Sea coast specialise in arranging diving and snorkelling excursions, while all offer horse- and camel-riding trips, and tours of the desert or to archaeological sites.</p>
<p>Top-end hotel accommodation in Egypt surprisingly represents the best value for money. In Cairo, there are some spectacular five-star hotels run by international chains, many of them on the banks of the Nile. In Alexandria and Luxor, old colonial hotels located right on the Corniche overlooking the waters of the Mediterranean or Nile respectively are convenient and charming.</p>
<p>A choice of mid-range hotels that offer comfortable accommodation, business facilities and help with onward connections can be found in all towns and cities. Most require reservations several months in advance, particularly in the winter months and during major Islamic holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All the main towns have smaller, cheaper guesthouses that are often full of character and run by a family. They offer the chance to integrate more readily with Egyptian people. Standards vary considerably from simple but clean to the very basic where bringing your own linen is advisable. Most guesthouses offer tours and help with transport arrangements although it's still best to shop around to compare prices and services. In Cairo, inexpensive accommodation is concentrated downtown, above office buildings on and around Sharia Talaat Harb and some cheaper, although rustic, options in Islamic Cairo. All tend to be hot in summer as they rarely have air conditioning.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Egypt boasts some beautiful luxury hotels, resorts set in landscaped gardens, characterful guesthouses, historic hotels, eco-lodges and desert camps that offer great value for money. It has seen a massive investment in its accommodation sector in recent years with the introduction of a system that monitors and categorises each establishment.</p>
<p>Hotels are graded 1-5 stars, although standards in each category can differ to those expected in similarly starred hotels in Europe and the USA. Standards are improving significantly with more emphasis being placed on service and providing enhanced facilities. All hotel categories must now have wheelchair access, for example, along with the availability of medical services.&nbsp;</p>
<p>All the top resorts, at Sharm el-Sheik, Hurghada and Luxor for example, offer lavish accommodation for less than top-dollar prices. Many include international restaurants, spas and infinity pools, and golf courses, and they are a good place to watch belly dancing or other cultural entertainment which cater especially for tourists. Most of the resorts on the Red Sea coast specialise in arranging diving and snorkelling excursions, while all offer horse- and camel-riding trips, and tours of the desert or to archaeological sites.</p>
<p>Top-end hotel accommodation in Egypt surprisingly represents the best value for money. In Cairo, there are some spectacular five-star hotels run by international chains, many of them on the banks of the Nile. In Alexandria and Luxor, old colonial hotels located right on the Corniche overlooking the waters of the Mediterranean or Nile respectively are convenient and charming.</p>
<p>A choice of mid-range hotels that offer comfortable accommodation, business facilities and help with onward connections can be found in all towns and cities. Most require reservations several months in advance, particularly in the winter months and during major Islamic holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Egypt boasts some beautiful luxury hotels, resorts set in landscaped gardens, characterful guesthouses, historic hotels, eco-lodges and desert camps that offer great value for money. It has seen a massive investment in its accommodation sector in recent years with the introduction of a system that monitors and categorises each establishment.</p>
<p>Hotels are graded 1-5 stars, although standards in each category can differ to those expected in similarly starred hotels in Europe and the USA. Standards are improving significantly with more emphasis being placed on service and providing enhanced facilities. All hotel categories must now have wheelchair access, for example, along with the availability of medical services.&nbsp;</p>
<p>All the top resorts, at Sharm el-Sheik, Hurghada and Luxor for example, offer lavish accommodation for less than top-dollar prices. Many include international restaurants, spas and infinity pools, and golf courses, and they are a good place to watch belly dancing or other cultural entertainment which cater especially for tourists. Most of the resorts on the Red Sea coast specialise in arranging diving and snorkelling excursions, while all offer horse- and camel-riding trips, and tours of the desert or to archaeological sites.</p>
<p>Top-end hotel accommodation in Egypt surprisingly represents the best value for money. In Cairo, there are some spectacular five-star hotels run by international chains, many of them on the banks of the Nile. In Alexandria and Luxor, old colonial hotels located right on the Corniche overlooking the waters of the Mediterranean or Nile respectively are convenient and charming.</p>
<p>A choice of mid-range hotels that offer comfortable accommodation, business facilities and help with onward connections can be found in all towns and cities. Most require reservations several months in advance, particularly in the winter months and during major Islamic holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are no vaccinations needed to visit Egypt unless you are arriving from an infected area. Vaccinating against some diseases, such as those in the table above, are advisable as a precautionary measure. You should avoid touching stray animals as rabies is prevalent throughout the country, and take care if visiting street markets where poultry or other birds are present as many have been reported as being carriers of Avian flu. HIV and Aids is present in Egypt and you should take normal precautions to avoid exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public hospitals are open to tourists. The standard of care is good in Cairo and Alexandria, with most doctors speaking good English, but is of varying standard in other parts of the country. Health care provision and standards of hygiene is particularly lacking in remote rural areas, especially in the Western Desert oases and in the wilderness of southern Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adequate health insurance that covers you for treatment, local hospitalisation and medical repatriation to your country of residence is strongly advised for any trip to Egypt, and its conditions for health precautions understood. If you are need of emergency assistance during your stay dial 123 and ask for an ambulance. Ensure you have access to funds should you be asked to pay for medical services, and always obtain a receipt for your insurance company. If you are referred to a medical centre or hospital seek the advice of your insurance company without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;You should avoid uncooked vegetables and peeled fruit that may have been washed in tap water, and make sure any poultry or egg-based dishes, and any seafood or shellfish, is thoroughly cooked. Hotels and restaurants are generally safe to eat and drink in, but it is advisable to avoid street vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use only bottled water for drinking and, to be on the safe side, when brushing teeth. When buying bottled water, check the seal of the bottle is intact. A popular scam is for unscrupulous individuals to collect used bottles from rubbish bins, refill them with tap water, attempt a reseal and sell them as genuine clean bottled water. Also, avoid unbottled beverages and ice except in top hotels and restaurants. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Immunisation against polio is advised because of the persistence of polio in Egypt. Precautions against hepatitis E should be considered. Immunisation against hepatitis B and tuberculosis is sometimes advised. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis), a tropical disease caused by parasites burrowing into the skin, is known to be present in the Nile Delta and the Nile  Valley. You should avoid swimming and wading in their waters. Avoid touching any stagnant water as this, too, may result in bilharzia.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid long exposure to the sun, which can be intense. Use plenty of high factor sun cream, wear light cotton clothing, a hat or scarf covering your head, and drink plenty of water to avoid dehydration and sunburn. It is a good idea to pack rehydrating salts.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Sinai Liberation Day :
							25 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>National Day :
							23 July </p><p>Armed Forces Day :
							06 October </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Egypt by travellers over 18 without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 25 cigars or 200g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic beverages.</p>
<p>Other goods like gifts and personal items up to a value of 1500 E&pound;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drugs, firearms and cotton.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drugs, firearms and cotton.</p>
<p>You may only export small quantities of locally bought gold and silver for personal use.</p>
<p>If exporting antiquities over 100 years old, you must obtain a licence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Egyptian Pound or ginee (LE; symbol E&pound;) = 100 piastres. Notes are in denominations of E&pound;200, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 1, 50 piastres and 25 piastres. Coins are in denominations of 25, 20, 10 and 5 piastres.<br />
<br />
British pounds sterling, Euros and the US Dollar are accepted everywhere although change may be given in Egyptian pounds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Egyptian pound is available outside Egypt and you can change money before you leave for your trip. Alternatively, 24-hour currency exchange is available at <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/egypt/cairo-international-airport">Cairo</a> airport. It is worth exchanging at least a small amount for incidentals during your first day or two in Egypt. Keep small denomination notes for taxis fares as drivers rarely seem to have any change, and for tips, known as baksheesh, which are a way of life in Egypt.</p>
<p>Currency exchange is also available at banks, official bureaux de change outlets and most hotels. Banks often have better exchange rates than bureaux de change or hotels. All common international currencies are accepted. It is wise to divide your currency between you if there is more than one person in your party and keep it secure to guard against theft. It is advisable to take only what you will need for a day&rsquo;s excursion and keep the remainder of your money in your hotel safe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, Mastercard and Visa are widely accepted in all but the smallest hotels and restaurants throughout the country, except in the Western oases. It is wise to keep your credit card in view when you make purchases or pay a restaurant bill, and to keep receipts for checking exchange rates and charges on your statement.</p><p>ATMS can be found in all major towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most bank will not cash traveller's cheques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sun-Thurs 0830-1400. Bureaux de change are generally also open in the evening 1800-2100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes 1/2</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes 1/2</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes 1/2</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes 1/2</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes 1/2</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Egypt, a passport valid for at least six months from the date of issue of the visa is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above. Visitors from all countries, except nationals of the EU and the USA, must register with the police within one week of arrival in Egypt, although this service is normally undertaken by hotels. When you check in at your hotel the receptionist will ask to see your passport, and will record its details for the police.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Children under 16 travelling without an adult must carry a letter from their parent or legal guardian.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Those continuing their journey to a third country within 24 hours and remaining in the airport do not need a visa, providing they hold confirmed onward tickets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: US$25.</p>
<p>Consulate visa cost varies according to nationality. UK and Australian nationals: tourist: &pound;20 (single-entry); &pound;32 (multiple-entry); business: &pound;65 (single-entry); &pound;105 (multiple-entry).</p>
<p>Canadian nationals: tourist: &pound;20 (single-entry); &pound;32 (multiple-entry); business: &pound;50 (single-entry); &pound;75 (multiple-entry).</p>
<p>USA nationals: tourist: US$15 (single- or multiple-entry); business: US$40 (single-entry); US$55 (multiple-entry).</p>
<p>Visa fees for other EU nationals visiting Egypt vary according to country, but most follow the same fees that apply to UK and Australian nationals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: 30 days.</p>
<p>Single- and multiple-entry visas are valid for six months from the date of issue for a maximum stay of 60 days and 90 days respectively. Extensions are available from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs in Egypt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can obtain tourist visas from the Egyptian consulate in your country of residence or from the airports in Cairo, Luxor, Sharm El Sheikh and Hurghada, and the port at Alexandria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign nationals can apply for residency in Egypt, subject to conditions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications made in person require two days and postal applications normally take about five days. For certain nationalities, applications can take up to six weeks if they need to be referred to the authorities in Egypt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas can be extended for up to a year at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pet dogs and cats must be microchipped and vaccinated for rabies, and you must complete an Egypt Veterinary Certificate. Vaccinations must be administered at least 30 days (but not more than a year) before travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[26.747023]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[29.868980]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,001,450 sq km (386,662 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>94,137,816 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>88.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cairo (El Qahira).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional home of the roaming Bedouin, most of Egypt's landmass is comprised of flat, mostly featureless desert, supportive of minimal vegetation.</p>
<p>The Mediterranean Sea forms Egypt's northern border, bringing cooler weather to the seaboard city of Alexandria and providing a coastal getaway for Cairo's residents. To the east, lies the mountainous Sinai Peninsula, which borders Israel and the Palestinian Territories; to the south, the deserts of Egypt quietly roll into the deserts of Sudan; to the west, the Great Western Desert forms an almost seamless wilderness through Libya and beyond.</p>
<p>Sinai is divided from the main landmass of Africa by the country's busy shipping lane, the Suez Canal. For centuries, however, it was the River Nile, plied by <em>felucca</em> (traditional Nile sailing boats), that provided the main conduit for trade along the country's length. Railways and roads now compete for that distinction, but the Nile remains an important economic and cultural artery.</p>
<p>The Nile perfuses the Delta north of Cairo, supporting 90% of the population in a flood land of cotton and rice-growing crops. The river's potency has been reduced since the building of the Aswan Dam; on the positive side, the dam has provided the country with a safe and reliable electricity supply - and has had the side effect of keeping the crocodiles out.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>About 90% of the population are Muslim, with the majority of the remainder being Christian, including followers of the Coptic Christian faith. There is also a small Jewish population.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Islam is part of all aspects of daily life with many social conventions stemming from the teachings of the Koran, the Muslim holy book. Hospitality is a significant element, especially to visitors. Shaking hands is the normal greeting but male visitors should wait for a woman to offer her hand first.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Dress should always be conservative and women should cover upper arms and legs. This is particularly important when visiting religious buildings - when hair should also be covered - and conservative towns. Dress standards tends to be a little more relaxed in modern nightclubs, restaurants, hotels and bars in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/egypt/cairo-international-airport">Cairo</a>, Alexandria and other tourist resorts. Official or social functions and smart restaurants usually require more formal wear. Smoking is widespread.</p>
<p><strong>Photography:</strong> Tourists are required to pay a fee if wishing to take photographs inside pyramids, tombs and museums. Ask permission when taking&nbsp;pictures of someone, especially women. Some traditionally-dressed locals demand money when they &lsquo;pose&rsquo; outside historic sites, especially temples and pyramids.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Sockets take the continental European-style plugs with two round pins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Mostafa Madbouli since June 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Egypt&rsquo;s history is one of the oldest and most evocative of any country in the world. Who can fail to be captivated by the lives of pharaohs like Tutankhamun who ruled for just ten years but is, arguably, the most famous of all the ancient Egyptian kings? Or Cleopatra, Egypt&rsquo;s last pharaoh?</p>
<p>Egypt can trace its history back to around 8000 BC when drier conditions forced early civilisations in need of food and water closer to the Nile. However, Pharaonic Egypt began some 5,000 years ago and comprised kings from 30 different dynasties whose phenomenal knowledge of mathematics, biology and astronomy made the country one of the most powerful kingdoms the world. Their legendary wealth enabled them to build monumental structures like the Karnak Temple in Luxor, and the Pyramids of Giza.</p>
<p>Pharaonic rule is divided into kingdoms. The Old Kingdom saw the building of the Gizan pyramids, the Middle Kingdom saw Egypt&rsquo;s capital at Thebes, present-day Luxor, while the New Kingdom began around 1500 BC and gave us some of the greatest pharaohs in Egypt&rsquo;s history. Later, Egypt saw the arrival of Alexander the Great, who founded Alexandria, and then the Roman Empire.</p>
<p>The arrival of Napoleon in AD 1798 brought Egypt once more into violent contact with a European power. By 1805, however, the struggle for autonomy had been won, with Muhammad Ali being recognised as the first Sultan of Egypt.</p>
<p>The completion of the Suez Canal in 1869, built in conjunction with France, brought popular discontent, since heavy taxation was required to pay for it, and eventually resulted in more than 70 years of British rule. Demands for the canal&rsquo;s nationalisation and the country&rsquo;s independence continued until revolution in 1952.</p>
<p>2011 saw the country again engulfed in widespread protests against the government, which resulted in long-standing President Hosni Mubarak&rsquo;s resignation, and the eventual return of the military to power. The downing of a Russian passenger jet over the Sinai Peninsula in 2015 &ndash; an act of terror claimed by Islamic State militants &ndash; severely affected Egypt&rsquo;s tourism industry. Elections in the same year brought stability to Egyptian politics, but the country has been criticised internationally for its suppression of the media and lax airport security.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Ancient Egyptians worshipped over 1,400 different gods and goddesses.<br />
&bull;	The young Egyptian citizen, Facebook Jamal Ibrahim, was named after the social media site to honour its role in fermenting the 2011 revolution.<br />
&bull;	The Pyramids of Giza are the oldest of the Seven Ancient Wonders of the World, and the only one to still exist.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Egypt]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+20 2 2791 6000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinegypt.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+20 2 2791 6000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Sun-Wed 0800-1530; Thurs 0800-1400.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Garden City<br/>7 Ahmed Ragheb Street<br/>Cairo<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Egypt in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 895 5400.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.egyptembassy.net</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 895 5400.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3521 International Court<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Egyptian Consulate in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7235 9777</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.egyptianconsulate.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7235 9777</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1230 (lodging applications); 1430-1600 (visa collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2 Lowndes Street<br/>London<br/>SW1X 9ET<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A complicated but fascinating country with some of the most enduring historical monuments on Earth, Egypt stands as an unforgettable travel destination. It&rsquo;s had to deal with its fair share of turmoil in recent times, but this North African nation remains proud, welcoming and accessible.&nbsp;And with treasures as timeless as the temples and pyramids of the Nile to shout about, it&rsquo;s not somewhere that&rsquo;s going to slip from public consciousness any time soon. A trip here still very much has the potential to thrill.</p>
<p>In many ways, there are two Egypts. The first is the Egypt of Cairo and the Nile, of bustling medieval bazaars, noseless Sphinxes, river cruises and Agatha Christie-era exoticism.  The second, and just as integral to many visitors, is the Egypt of the Red Sea, where a spread of large-scale modern resorts caters to sun-seekers and scuba divers. Sharm el Sheikh, with its world-class diving, high-end hotels and desert adventures, is the best known of them.</p>
<p>Most of the country&rsquo;s ancient treasures were built during the time of the pharaohs. The Pyramids of Giza (the sole survivors of the Seven Ancient Wonders of the World); the lotus-columned temples of Luxor and Karnak; the Valley of the Kings; Aswan and the temples of Abu Simbel: strung along the Nile, these monuments have drawn visitors for centuries. They represent a lasting legacy of one of the most fabled periods of human history.</p>
<p>Of course, the country is best understood not so much for its great monuments or its coral reefs, splendid though they are, but through its people. Bartering for a bargain in Cairo&rsquo;s ancient Khan al-Khalili bazaar, taking tea and falling into long conversation with a local, or simply stopping awhile in a remote village, silent but for the chatter of hooves on tarmac, will give a glimpse of a country full of character, colour and fortitude.</p>A complicated but fascinating country with some of the most enduring historical monuments on Earth, Egypt stands as an unforgettable travel destination. It's had to deal with its fair share of turmoil in recent times, but this North African nation remains proud, welcoming and accessible. And with treasures as timeless as the temples and pyramids of the Nile to shout about, it's not somewhere that's going to slip from public consciousness any time soon. A trip here still very much has the potential to thrill. ]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
