<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="El Salvador" ColCode="slv" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sv" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[El Salvador]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>El Salvador&rsquo;s dry season (known locally as <em>verano</em>, or summer) runs between November and April, with a rainy season (<em>invierno</em> or winter) between May and October. In the rainy season, coastal and central regions typically suffer afternoon storms sandwiched between pleasant weather.&nbsp;In terms of temperature, the country&rsquo;s subtropical climate can be divided into three separate zones, dependent on altitude. Coastal areas are uniformly hot throughout the year, the central plateau shows more extremes of hot and cold (though still rarely dropping below 10 &deg;C) while upland areas have a cooler, more temperate climate. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/el-salvador">El Salvador</a> is rarely affected by hurricanes, though tropical storm Agatha caused heavy rains and flooding in 2010. <br />
<br />
For most travellers, it is best to visit during the dry season and to avoid the hottest time of the year (March-April) when humidity levels are particularly high. Surfers, however, should aim for April to October, or March at a push. In August beach and lake resorts are busy with Salvadoran holidaymakers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothing and rainwear during the wet season in coastal areas. Waterproof clothing is advisable all year round. Warm clothing should be taken for higher altitudes. For camping and outdoor countryside activities, aim to cover up as much as possible to avoid potentially dangerous insect and animal bites.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no scheduled internal domestic flights.</p><p>San Salvador&rsquo;s old international airport, Ilopango, lies to the east of the city and is now shared between the military and civil charter operators. It may return to a civilian use for scheduled flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a regular ferry service across Lago Suchitl&aacute;n to Suchitoto and ferries ply the waters around La Uni&oacute;n.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Salvador's railways are managed by FENADESAL (Ferrocarriles Nacionales de El Salvador) (<a href="http://www.fenadesal.gob.sv" target="_blank">www.fenadesal.gob.sv</a>). However, there are no fully-functioning passenger services at present.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Well-maintained paved roads cover most of the country. New cars, particularly with foreign licence plates, are targets not just for any valuables that might be left in the car but also for parts theft. Carjacking is not uncommon (especially in the cities) and drivers are advised to travel only by day and with the doors locked at all times.</p>r<p>El Salvador has an extensive network of good-quality intercity paved roads and San Salvador&rsquo;s roads are among the best in Central America. However, of all the country&rsquo;s roads, at least a third are unpaved, many in large towns. Dust, mud and potholes are all common.</p><p>Without formal timetables or ticketing systems, competing colourfully painted buses criss-cross El Salvador, visiting almost all towns, villages and cities. Don&rsquo;t expect luxury (these are old US school buses) but fares are low &ndash; pay on board after grabbing seat. Some routes feature <em>especial</em> or <em>super-especial</em> services, typically with air conditioning and fewer stops, and usually with less overcrowding.</p><p>Travellers who would rather avoid the cross-country chicken buses might opt to hire a taxi to take them to their destination. El Salvador is small enough to make this feasible, though it is best to clearly negotiate a fixed price before departure. Larger hotels often offer their own car service to guests.</p>
<p>Taxis on the street are plentiful but not metered, so it's essential to agree the fare beforehand. Cabs are yellow with a chequered stripe and easy to flag down. Alternatively, head to the town square (or similar), where taxis usually congregate between fares. Drivers do not expect tips, except when the taxi has been hired for the day.</p><p>A national or International Driving Permit is required for 30-day visits, after which visitors need to obtain a Salvadoran licence.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn. Speed limits vary from region to region.</p><p>Autom&oacute;vil Club de El  Salvador (tel: +503 2231 5555; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.aces.com.sv/">www.aces.com.sv</a>) has reciprocal agreements with some international motoring organisations and can provide further information on driving in El Salvador.</p><p>Available in San Salvador and at the airport from international and local firms. Drivers must be at least 21 years old and have held their licence for a minimum of one year.</p><p>Cycling on main highways is certainly possible. Although a densely populated country, El Salvador&rsquo;s roads are often surprisingly quiet and hard shoulders are generally wide enough to give a margin of safety. Some of the climbs can seem long and arduous, but there are few that are impossible. Unpredictable, erratic driving is always a risk, and off main highways, potholes and mud can make cycling a chore.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn. Speed limits vary from region to region.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>City buses are cheap and offer a good service, but are often crowded.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">El Salvador</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">santa_ana</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">El Salvador</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">san_miguel</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">El Salvador</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">costadel_sol</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Salvadorian national airline is Avianca&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.avianca.com" target="_blank">www.avianca.com</a>). It flies to a number of US, Central and South American destinations. Flights to El Salvador are cheapest during the periods from February to March and August to October, with Christmas and New Year the most expensive period.</p>
<p>Of the major US carriers, American Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aa.com">www.aa.com</a>) has the most flights to the country, departing <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dallas">Dallas-Fort Worth</a> and Miami International. Delta (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.delta.com">www.delta.com</a>) flies direct from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/atlanta">Atlanta</a> and United (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.united.com">www.united.com</a>) from Newark and&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/houston">Houston</a>. Travellers from Europe looking for the quickest flight are advised to travel via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida">Florida</a> in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 15 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 5 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>El Salvador International Airport (SAL) is the country&rsquo;s chief airport and point of arrival for almost all international air travellers. Locally known as Aeropuerto Internacional de Comalapa, it is 50km (31 miles) south of San Salvador, the country&rsquo;s capital.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>El Salvador International Airport (SAL) is the country&rsquo;s chief airport and point of arrival for almost all international air travellers. Locally known as Aeropuerto Internacional de Comalapa, it is 50km (31 miles) south of San Salvador, the country&rsquo;s capital.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The port of Acajutla lies closes to the western border with Guatemala and has modern cruise facilities. La Uni&oacute;n lies at the Eastern End of the country and is a port of entry for sea traffic (again mostly freight) from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nicaragua">Nicaragua</a> and Honduras.</p><p>The country&rsquo;s first port, La Libertad, is now a surfing destination, with a just a few fishing and day tour boats plying the harbour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Pan-American Highway runs west from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/honduras">Honduras</a> and east from Guatamala. Tica Bus (<a href="http://www.ticabus.com" target="_blank">www.ticabus.com</a>) operates well-equipped express coach services to San  <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brazil">Salvador</a> from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/panama">Panama</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/costa-rica">Costa Rica</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guatemala">Guatemala</a> with connections to the south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico">Mexico</a>.</p><p>Avoid driving at night for safety and leave your vehicle in hotel car parks if possible. Four-wheel drives are advised for travelling on minor roads.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Phone numbers have eight digits, and no area codes. Get phonecards from corner kiosks to use payphones. Many travellers may find it easier to use VOIP calling from internet cafés or from their hotels, or to buy a local SIM card for their mobile phone (ensure your phone is network-unlocked before leaving home).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies, though calls are likely to be costly. Coverage is variable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet access is readily available in San Salvador and the main tourist destinations, at cyber cafes and hotels. Wi-Fi is less ubiquitous.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Press freedom is guaranteed under El Salvador's constitution. Among the daily newspapers published in San Salvador are <em>El Diario de Hoy</em>,<em> El Mundo</em> and <em>La Prensa Gr&aacute;fica</em> plus several provincial papers. Most TV stations are privately run. Cable TV is available across much of the country and carries a wide range of international channels including <em>Teledos</em>, <em>Canal Seis</em> and <em>TV Doce</em>. There are some 70 radio stations in the capital alone, most of these are also commercial run such as&nbsp;<em>Radio YSKL</em>, <em>FM Globo</em>, <em>Femenina 102.5</em> and <em>Radio Cadena Central.</em> <em>Radio El Salvador</em> is a state-run station.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes up to two weeks. In San Salvador, the main branch is in Centro de Gobierno.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Canyon down El Imposible’s rushing rivers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>El Imposible, the country's most important ecological reserve, is a must for the nature-hungry traveller and thrill seeker. Over 500 species of bird flit between the trees; you may even catch a glimpse of the rare black hawk eagle whilst trekking through the forest, or canyoning down the steep river gorges.</p>]]><p><b>Dip into the volcanic lakes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try your hand at fishing, sailing, waterskiing and kayaking on the volcanic crater lakes of Coatepeque and Ilopango, either side of San Salvador. And if that's not enough adventure for you, go for a dive to explore the rocky depths of Ilopango, whose waters have tepid temperatures all year.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the cloud forest of Cerro Verde</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spectacular cloud forest, sweeping views, clean mountain air, exhilarating walks and three volcanoes are yours to explore in this 505 hectare (1,250 acre) national park in central El Salvador. Expert local guides lead day hikes from San Salvador, taking in Cerro Verde, Izalco and Santa Ana volcanoes looming high above the steamy jungle.</p>]]><p><b>Follow the Floral Route</b></p><![CDATA[<p>To the west of San Salvador lies some of the country's most luscious landscapes, which are peppered with lazy villages and linked by the scenic Ruta de las Flores. Here you can hike up volcanoes, clamber over Pre-Columbian ruins and explore peaceful indigenous villages, such as Nahuizalco, Juayua, Apaneca, Ataco and Ahuachapán.</p>]]><p><b>Go butterfly spotting in Barra de Santiago</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Arguably El Salvador's most pristine beach, this sandy expanse in the far west doubles as a nature reserve for butterfly and bird species. You can explore the mangroves of the Zapote estuary by boat or canoe, or just chill in a beachfront cafe. Local groups and hotels including La Cocotera eco lodge are working to re-establish endangered species like the marine turtle and red macaw.</p>]]><p><b>Go horse riding up Guazapa volcano</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ecotourism is one of El Salvador's fastest growing activities, with an increasing number of specialist agencies offering multi-activity tours of its unspoilt wilderness. One of the most popular adventures is a horseback ride through beautiful scenery, covering three climate zones, to the summit of the Guazapa volcano, before returning to base to learn how to make maize tortillas.</p>]]><p><b>Go white-water rafting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whether you are new to the thrills and spills of this exciting sport or a seasoned expert, the rivers of El Salvador are classic white-water experiences. The best rafting rivers are Lempa, Guajoyo and Paz during the rainy season (May to October) and the Paz in the dry season (November to April). You can find specialist operators in San Salvador and Suchitoto.</p>]]><p><b>Join in Panchimalco’s indigenous festivities</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Pancho, who give the village of Panchimalco its name, are sadly among the few remaining indigenous people in El Salvador who have retained their old traditions. The best times to visit this historic town near San Salvador are 13-14 September (Fiesta de Santa Cruz de Roma) or 3 May (Las Palmas harvest procession), colourful occasions when pagan and Christian customs merge.</p>]]><p><b>Let former guerrillas lead you on the Peace Route</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Peace has now been restored to the beautiful countryside around Perquín, scene of some of the bloodiest battles in El Salvador's civil war. Former guerrillas explain the history in the Museo de la Revolución Salvadoreña; you can also mix politics with pleasure by going swimming in the Rio Sapo, birdwatching in the ecological reserve, or canoeing, horse riding and rock climbing.</p>]]><p><b>Ramble around Maya ruins</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Before the Spanish conquest, the great Maya civilisation reached as far as El Salvador. No great pyramids have survived here but sites worth visiting include San Andres, Tazumal and Joya de Cerén, a uniquely preserved Maya settlement whose houses were buried under volcanic ash 1,400 years ago and which is now on UNESCO's World Heritage list.</p>]]><p><b>See Fernando Llort’s vivid artworks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Born in 1949, Fernando Llort is El Salvador's greatest living artist. He is known for his use of bright colours and highly individual style that incorporates symbols representing life in the country of his birth. You can view Llort's work in his museum, El Arbol de Dios, in San Salvador; a collection of his murals also stands on the city's southern entrance.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out the sights of San Salvador</b></p><![CDATA[<p>El Salvador's capital is a traffic-clogged jumble, but worth a visit for several historic and cultural gems, such as the Palacio Nacional, the restored Teatro Nacional and the Biblioteca Nacional. The nicest church is La Ceiba de Guadalupe, with a fine wooden ceiling, and the best museum is the modern National Anthropology museum, displaying the country's history as well as putting on cultural events.</p>]]><p><b>Soak up the sights of Suchitoto</b></p><![CDATA[<p>By far and away El Salvador's prettiest colonial town, Suchitoto is famous for its parish church, which dominates the main square. There is a craft market here most days and it comes alive on weekend nights with a loud and lively fair. Wander around its cobbled streets lined with colonial architecture, or take a boat cruise around the nearby Lago de Suchitlán.</p>]]><p><b>Stay on a coffee plantation</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Coffee became El Salvador's most important export in the mid 19th century; plantations are still dotted around the countryside, some offering tours for visitors. Buy the local product when visiting Ecoparque El Espino on the slopes of the Boquerón volcano. Alternatively, book a stay at the Hotel Santa Leticia in Apaneca, a working plantation in the Ruta de las Flores.</p>]]><p><b>Visit surfing heaven</b></p><![CDATA[<p>El Salvador's Pacific coastline is surfing heaven, with crowd-free beaches and world-class breaks. South of San Miguel is Las Flores, from where boats head to Punta Mango and the biggest waves in the country, suitable for beginners and experts alike. Closest to the capital are El Sunzal (La Libertad), El Zonte and El Tunco beaches, dotted along the idyllic Costa del Bálsamo.</p>]]><p><b>Zip through the forest canopy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For a powerful adrenalin rush, it's hard to beat the spectacular Apaneca Canopy Tour, a thrilling zip-line circuit strung 150m (492ft) above the tropical forests of western El Salvador. Enjoy a bird's-eye view of Apaneca's coffee plantations as you glide over breathtaking mountain scenery. (Not recommended for those with a fear of heights).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$21.21 billion (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Textiles, coffee, sugar, shrimp, medicines.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Consumer goods, capital goods, raw materials, petroleum, food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Honduras, Mexico and EU.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A long-running civil war (1980-1992) caused a significant decline in El Salvador's agriculture-dependent economy, exacerbated by a fall in world coffee prices that only continued until 2004. Other economic sectors such as textiles and clothes manufacturing were able to expand and take up some of the slack, and in recent years the economy has come to rely heavily on the financial sector and service industries such as call centres. Agriculture is now just 11% of GDP with services accounting for 59%, and industry for the remaining 30%.</p>
<p>Dollarisation (the adoption of the US dollar as the country&rsquo;s currency) began in 2001. Its merits are still hotly debated here, with opposition politicians continuing to call for a reversal.<br />
<br />
Underemployment remains a serious problem, and remittances from Salvadorans working abroad are a vital source of income for many families. These have fallen substantially as a result of the global financial recession. The Central America-Dominican Republic-United States Free Trade Agreement (CAFTA-DR) provides El Salvador preferential access to American markets, benefitting the textiles and clothing, and processed food sectors, but it also means that an increased proportion of the remittances that arrive from the USA soon find their way back into US-owned companies, rather than circulating in the local economy. El   Salvador is a member of the Central American Common Market. After contracting in 2009, the economy experienced less than 1% growth in 2010. Inflation in 2009 was 0.4% rising to 1.2% in 2010.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business people are expected to wear suits. Although some local business people speak English, a good knowledge of Spanish is important. Business cards are essential. The best months for business visits are September to March, but avoid the Christmas and New Year period.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cámara de Comercio e Industria de El Salvador</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 2231 3000
					Website:http://www.camarasal.com/
					Address: ,9A Avenida Norte y 5A Calle Pte,San Salvador,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>El Salvador's cuisine is influenced by both its pre-Colombian heritage and the Spanish conquest. The <em>pupusa</em> (stuffed tortilla) is the classic Salvadoran street dish – hearty, basic and tasty. As with most Pacific-facing countries in the region, <em>ceviche </em>(raw marinated fish) is a popular dish, and shellfish, including grilled clams, lobster and crabs, is common in coastal areas.</p><p>Salvadorans love fresh fruit (bananas, pineapple, mango and papaya are common) and <em>minutas</em> (crushed ice with fruit syrup) and fresh coconuts are sold on street-food stands everywhere. A light breakfast might be fruit or eggs, with <em>típicosalvadoreño</em> (see below) for a full blowout.</p><p>There are numerous fast-food chains, together with authentic street food stands and market foodstalls, which can be great value.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pupusa:</strong> A fried tortilla, filled with pork, cheese, refried beans or vegetables.<br />
<strong>T&iacute;picosalvadore&ntilde;o:</strong> Standard Salvadoran breakfast comprising eggs, local cheese, refried beans, fried plantains and tortillas.<br />
<strong>Casamiento:</strong> Rice and black beans, often served for breakfast.<br />
<strong>Pacalla: </strong>Palm-flowers fried and coated in breadcrumbs, a side dish served with tomato sauce.<br />
<strong>Tamal de elote:</strong> Cornflour batter with meat filling, wrapped in banana leaves and steamed.<br />
<strong>Gallo en chicha: </strong>Soup made from corns, rooster and cane sugar.<br />
<strong>Sopa de pata:</strong> Soup made from plantain, cow's feet, corn and tripe.<br />
<strong>Mariscada:</strong> Seafood chowder that&rsquo;s rich and sometimes spicy.<br />
<strong>Curtido:</strong> Pickled cabbage and other shredded vegetables, a bit like sauerkraut.<br />
<strong>Huevospicados:</strong> Scrambled eggs with diced vegetables, typical breakfast dish.<br />
<strong>Caf&eacute;:</strong> El Salvadoran coffee is good and strong, usually drunk sweet and black.<br />
<strong>Refrescos:</strong> Natural fruit drinks, often sold in street stalls.<br />
<strong>Kolachampan:</strong> Sugarcane flavoured soft drink.<br />
<strong>Tic tac and torito:</strong> Strong alcoholic spirit made from distilled sugar cane.<br />
<strong>Chaparro:</strong> Moonshine spirit, illegal to serve in bars but widely available, including a fruit or honey-flavoured version called <em>chaparrocurado</em>.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>If paying by credit card, beware of credit card skimming scams (where your card is cloned using a hidden machine). Try not to let your card out of your site. If dining with locals, wait for your host to say 'buen provecho' before tucking in.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tipping is not a long-standing tradition in El Salvador, but wages are low, so do reward good service. 10% is appropriate.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Salvador's best bars and nightclubs are in the plush Zona Rosa district, west of the city centre. Drinks are expensive and entry charges are common. Less expensive and a bit more funky are the streets around Boulevard de los H&eacute;roes, just north of the city centre. Here, La Luna Casa y Arte is something of an institution and a good starting point if exploring the area. The atmosphere is artsy and relaxed with sofas, live music and exhibitions, but it still attracts those who dress to impress. West of Zona Rosa, the centre of the Santa Tecla district has recently been cleaned up and turned into a new &lsquo;cultural zone&rsquo; with pleasant pavement caf&eacute;s, restaurants and bars.</p>
<p>In San Salvador, openly gay and lesbian nightclubs are thin on the ground, but Scape and Millennium are two of the best known clubs, and just few metres away from each other.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s quite common to find nightclubs in shopping malls, and cinemas too &ndash; many of which show English-language films with Spanish subtitles. The capital's theatres include the Teatro Presidente in Zona Rosa and the beautifully restored Teatro Nacional<em> </em>in the downtown city centre. Other evening entertainment venues are the Feria Internacional for concerts, and Estadio Cuscatl&aacute;n and Estadio M&aacute;gico Gonzalez for football (soccer) matches and concerts.<br />
<br />
Downtown San   Salvador has little to offer in the way of late-night entertainment and you should not walk around in this area after 1900. Outside the capital most places of entertainment (even hotels) close around 2300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best souvenirs are handicrafts, including ceramics (especially in Ilobasco), handpainted wood (La Palma) and wicker furniture (Nahuizalco). A great gift is the ubiquitous <em>sorpresa</em> (surprise), a little ceramic orb originating from Ilobasco. Often, these are decorated to look like eggs, apples, pine cones or animals. Lift the top to reveal a miniature diorama, such as a baker at work, a musician or dancing girl. Also popular are models of El Salvador&rsquo;s chicken buses, miniature house facades in bright colours, and hammocks. Kids will enjoy a <em>capirucho</em> &ndash; a hand-held wooden toy made up of kind of donut and stem. The object is to flip the stem (connected by string) into the donut hole: it&rsquo;s tricky and strangely addictive.</p>
<p>In San Salvador, you can pick up bargains at the Mercado Cuartel (though you should only go there if accompanied by a Salvadoran) or at the Mercado Nacional de Artesan&iacute;as. For clothing and accessories, a trip to a shopping mall is a good bet. Major mall chains include Multiplaza, Galerias, Metrocentro, Gran V&iacute;a, Hiper Mall and<em> </em>Cascadas. With over 500 outlets, Metrocentro is San Salvador&rsquo;s biggest mall &ndash; though a little downmarket. There are more recognisable designer outlets at Multiplaza or Galerias, though Central American brands still predominate.</p><p>Vary. Mostly Mon-Sat 0830-2000. Malls 1000-2000. Limited opening Sundays. Some local shops, especially those selling food and drink, open until late.</p><p>Don't expect to pay with a credit card if shopping at craft markets, and if paying anywhere by card, keep it in sight as skimming is widespread.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luxury 5-star hotels belonging to the major international chains are plentiful in and around the capital &ndash; particularly in Zona Rosa and Colonia Escal&oacute;n - but elsewhere they are not prevalent. Visitors from the US and UK may still feel that standards and facilities in luxury hotels do not match those at home. For more modest accommodation in San Salvador, look to the Boulevard de los H&eacute;roes, and avoid the downtown area.</p>
<p>Outside of the capital, standards do vary. In La Libertad, which is popular with surfers, accommodation has tended towards the basic and perilous, but is improving rapidly as investment flows in. You can expect to find clean and comfortable accommodation in popular tourist destinations and resorts such as Sonsonate, Suchitoto, and Costa del Sol, southeast of La Libertad. In the same places, luxury boutique accommodation is becoming more common and larger chains are moving in.</p>
<p>Luxury spa hotels like the mountainous Entrepinos (<a href="http://www.entrepinosresortandspa.com/" target="_blank">entrepinosresortandspa.com)</a> in Chalatenango province and the beachside Las Flores (<a href="http://www.lasfloresresort.com/" target="_blank">lasfloresresort.com</a>) in San Miguel province are relatively new in El Salvador, but offer a full gamut of tours and facilities, with service to satisfy the most demanding international traveller. Sustainable resort complexes such as La Cocotera (<a href="http://www.lacocoteraresort.com" target="_blank">www.lacocoteraresort.com</a>) are thin on the ground though the situation is now improving.</p>
<p>Prices are rising across the tourist hotspots but there are still online bargains to be had in low season. In some cases, it can pay to call direct from home to negotiate the best room rate, through be sure to get email confirmation and bring a printout with you. Whatever the destination, visitors will generally find Salvadorans to be a hospitable, friendly people, with hotel staff eager to please. Try to adjust your expectations to the price bracket and the resources available to your host. Be careful with your belongings wherever you&rsquo;re staying and don&rsquo;t flash around expensive accessories or money.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in El Salvador can be classified into three groups: deluxe, first-class and budget.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guest houses and budget backpacker hotels, often with private bathrooms, can be found in the main tourist towns and around Boulevard de los Héroes in the capital. Facilities can be patchy, and petty crime such as theft may be an issue, so ensure you choose carefully, taking advice from other travellers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luxury 5-star hotels belonging to the major international chains are plentiful in and around the capital &ndash; particularly in Zona Rosa and Colonia Escal&oacute;n - but elsewhere they are not prevalent. Visitors from the US and UK may still feel that standards and facilities in luxury hotels do not match those at home. For more modest accommodation in San Salvador, look to the Boulevard de los H&eacute;roes, and avoid the downtown area.</p>
<p>Outside of the capital, standards do vary. In La Libertad, which is popular with surfers, accommodation has tended towards the basic and perilous, but is improving rapidly as investment flows in. You can expect to find clean and comfortable accommodation in popular tourist destinations and resorts such as Sonsonate, Suchitoto, and Costa del Sol, southeast of La Libertad. In the same places, luxury boutique accommodation is becoming more common and larger chains are moving in.</p>
<p>Luxury spa hotels like the mountainous Entrepinos (<a href="http://www.entrepinosresortandspa.com/" target="_blank">entrepinosresortandspa.com)</a> in Chalatenango province and the beachside Las Flores (<a href="http://www.lasfloresresort.com/" target="_blank">lasfloresresort.com</a>) in San Miguel province are relatively new in El Salvador, but offer a full gamut of tours and facilities, with service to satisfy the most demanding international traveller. Sustainable resort complexes such as La Cocotera (<a href="http://www.lacocoteraresort.com" target="_blank">www.lacocoteraresort.com</a>) are thin on the ground though the situation is now improving.</p>
<p>Prices are rising across the tourist hotspots but there are still online bargains to be had in low season. In some cases, it can pay to call direct from home to negotiate the best room rate, through be sure to get email confirmation and bring a printout with you. Whatever the destination, visitors will generally find Salvadorans to be a hospitable, friendly people, with hotel staff eager to please. Try to adjust your expectations to the price bracket and the resources available to your host. Be careful with your belongings wherever you&rsquo;re staying and don&rsquo;t flash around expensive accessories or money.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in El Salvador can be classified into three groups: deluxe, first-class and budget.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luxury 5-star hotels belonging to the major international chains are plentiful in and around the capital &ndash; particularly in Zona Rosa and Colonia Escal&oacute;n - but elsewhere they are not prevalent. Visitors from the US and UK may still feel that standards and facilities in luxury hotels do not match those at home. For more modest accommodation in San Salvador, look to the Boulevard de los H&eacute;roes, and avoid the downtown area.</p>
<p>Outside of the capital, standards do vary. In La Libertad, which is popular with surfers, accommodation has tended towards the basic and perilous, but is improving rapidly as investment flows in. You can expect to find clean and comfortable accommodation in popular tourist destinations and resorts such as Sonsonate, Suchitoto, and Costa del Sol, southeast of La Libertad. In the same places, luxury boutique accommodation is becoming more common and larger chains are moving in.</p>
<p>Luxury spa hotels like the mountainous Entrepinos (<a href="http://www.entrepinosresortandspa.com/" target="_blank">entrepinosresortandspa.com)</a> in Chalatenango province and the beachside Las Flores (<a href="http://www.lasfloresresort.com/" target="_blank">lasfloresresort.com</a>) in San Miguel province are relatively new in El Salvador, but offer a full gamut of tours and facilities, with service to satisfy the most demanding international traveller. Sustainable resort complexes such as La Cocotera (<a href="http://www.lacocoteraresort.com" target="_blank">www.lacocoteraresort.com</a>) are thin on the ground though the situation is now improving.</p>
<p>Prices are rising across the tourist hotspots but there are still online bargains to be had in low season. In some cases, it can pay to call direct from home to negotiate the best room rate, through be sure to get email confirmation and bring a printout with you. Whatever the destination, visitors will generally find Salvadorans to be a hospitable, friendly people, with hotel staff eager to please. Try to adjust your expectations to the price bracket and the resources available to your host. Be careful with your belongings wherever you&rsquo;re staying and don&rsquo;t flash around expensive accessories or money.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in El Salvador can be classified into three groups: deluxe, first-class and budget.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Travellers to El Salvador should arrange to see their doctor around two months prior to travel, in order to discuss their specific vaccination needs. All nationals older than six months wishing to enter El Salvador from Europe are required to produce a certificate of vaccination against measles and rubella (German measles). Travellers from non-European countries are advised to take the same precaution, which is designed to reduce the chance of the re-introduction of these diseases into countries where they have been eradicated. A Hepatitis B vaccine is recommended for all infants and for children aged 11 to 12 years who did not receive the vaccine in infancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within El Salvador, the provision of medical services varies enormously. Outside of San Salvador, medical facilities are limited. In the capital, doctors are well trained but hospitals may lack state-of-the art facilities. Doctors and hospitals expect immediate cash payment. Credit cards are accepted by most hospitals, but not necessarily by all doctors. Travellers are advised to take out adequate medical insurance &amp;ndash; of at least &amp;pound;2m and covering the cost of repatriation as well as treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At all times, travellers should carry a copy of their insurance documents and passport, since hospitals may not provide treatment otherwise. State-run hospitals are basic and visitors are advised to use private clinics where possible. Some medical providers may have at least a basic command of English, but a Spanish phrase book covering language for emergency situations is recommended. The phone number for the emergency services is 911.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Dengue fever is reported to be on the increase. Vaccinations for tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Dangerous currents on El Salvador&amp;rsquo;s beaches have claimed several lives in recent years, and many beaches do not have adequate lifeguard coverage or warning signage. Always exercise caution, take local advice on swimming safety and avoid deserted beaches. The currents around La Bocana de San Diego are known to be unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Road traffic accidents are a common cause of injury among travellers. Avoid drink-driving, driving in torrential rain or driving at night on poorly-lit roads with which you are not familiar. There is always a danger of whiplash injury, or worse, on overcrowded buses. If travelling by bike or motorcycle, wear a helmet, and take care when crossing all roads.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Below are listed Public Holidays for the January 2014-December 2015 period.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Maundy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Holy Saturday :
							31 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Fiesta de San Salvador :
							03 August </p><p>Fiestas Agostinas :
							04 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							15 September </p><p>D :
							12 October </p><p>All Soul's Day :
							02 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>New Year's Eve :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into El Salvador by travellers over the age of 18 without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 500g of tobacco in any form.<br />
&bull; 5L of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; 2kg of sweets.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of US$500.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms, explosives, ammunitions and other weapons except with a special Ministry of Defence permit.</p>
<p>There are restrictions on the import of fruit, vegetables, plants and animals and meat products. Ham and sausage are only allowed if sterilised by heat, boneless and hermetically canned.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar (USD; symbol US$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of US$100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of US$1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.<br />
<br />
Note: US Dollars were introduced as dual currency in 2001 and have now completely replaced the Col&oacute;n. Don&rsquo;t carry bills higher than $20 as you will struggle to get them accepted in many bars, restaurants and shops. You can usually change larger bills in hotels, or of course in banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are advised to change currency only at banks and official bureaux de change. Visitors are advised not to bring UK sterling currency to El Salvador as this is difficult to exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Of the major credit cards, Visa is most widely accepted, then Mastercard and then American Express. Diners Club has more limited use. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> travellers with chip and pin cards will typically be expected to sign a slip after their card is swiped. Beware of 'card skimming' (cloning using a hidden machine), particularly in out of the way or rough-and-ready establishments, and try not to let your credit card out of your sight. Keep all receipts, at least until you have returned home and checked your bank and credit statements for any irregularities.</p><p>There are bank ATMs in all major cities as well as in shopping malls and service stations. The same is now true of most beach upmarket beach resorts, but access is limited in smaller towns and villages. Avoid using ATMs in small shops where fees may be exorbitant, and machines can be poorly maintained leading to card loss. Most ATMs in major locations now accept Mastercard/Cirrus as well as Visa/Plus cards. Take care to hide your PIN number when using machines and be aware that there is a small risk you could be followed after using an ATM.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These may be cashed at any bank or hotel on production of a passport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1345-1700; Sat 0900-1300 (limited service).<br /><br /><strong>Note:</strong> Most banks are closed for balancing the books on 29-30 Jun and 30-31 Dec. These dates may vary for individual banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter El Salvador, a passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist card (on arrival): US$10; single-entry visa: US$30; multiple-entry visa: US$60.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist cards are valid for 30 days; single-entry visas are valid for 30, 60 or 90 days; multiple-entry visas are valid for a year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can obtain tourist cards on arrival. For other visas, you must apply to the consulate (or consular section at the embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One to three days, or five to eight for applications referred to the immigration department for authorisation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[13.669021]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-88.866004]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>21,041 sq km (8,124 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6,146,419 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>291.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Salvador.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>El Salvador is situated in Central America between 13&deg; and 14&deg;N. It is bordered north and west by Guatemala, north and east by Honduras, and south and west by the Pacific Ocean. The country is the smallest in Central America and uniquely within the region, it has no Caribbean coastline.</p>
<p>North-easterly movement of the offshore Cocos tectonic plate and the westerly movement of El Salvador&rsquo;s northern neighbours accounts for the frequency of earthquakes and volcanic activity in the country. Most of El Salvador is volcanic uplands, along which run two almost parallel volcanic ranges. The highest volcanoes are Santa Ana at 2,365m (7,759ft), San Vicente at 2,182m (7,159ft) and San Salvador at 1,943m (6,375ft). Volcanic activity has resulted in a thick layer of ash and lava on the highlands, creating a richly mineralised soil, ideal for coffee planting. Lowlands lie to the north and south of the high backbone.</p>
<p>On the country&rsquo;s longest river, the Rio Lempa, the 800m (2,624ft)-wide hydroelectric Cerr&oacute;n Grande Dam provides power to much of the country and has created a reservoir with capacity of 2,180 million m&sup3;. Fed by rivers in Guatemala and Honduras, the Lempa flows in a broadly southern direction spreading into the Bajo Lempa flood plain before draining into the Pacific.</p>
<p>Lago De Ilopango is the country&rsquo;s largest &lsquo;natural&rsquo; lake with surface area of 72 sq km (28 sq miles). A scenic crater lake with steeply scalloped banks, it lies just to the east of San Salvador. Of the country&rsquo;s other lakes, Lago De Coatepeque is the most notable and perhaps most scenic with hot springs an added attraction for visitors. The lake covers 26 sq km (10 sq miles) in the province of Santa Ana, and like Ilopango it has steep high banks. Rising up from Coatepeque&rsquo;s watery blue crater is Isla Teop&aacute;n (&lsquo;sprouting island&rsquo;) where important Mayan artefacts have been found.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority (75%) of Salvadorans are Roman Catholic. A growing number (around 21%) are Protestant with Evangelical churches gaining influence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors should not point their finger or their foot at anyone. First names should not be used to address someone unless invited to do so. Casual wear is acceptable. Men and women who already know each other greet with a kiss on the cheek, otherwise a handshake is always offered as a greeting. Siesta is still a tradition from around 1200-1400, although most shops and restaurants remain open.<br /><br /><strong>Photography: </strong>Sensitive (eg military) areas should not be photographed.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>115 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without circular grounding pin) are most commonly used; you may sometimes need an adaptor if your plug has a third pin however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Salvador S&aacute;nchez Cer&eacute;n since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Salvador S&aacute;nchez Cer&eacute;n since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>By the mid 1520s, a Spanish expedition to El Salvador had established a settlement named San Salvador, defeating the indigenous Pipil people who had previously occupied the region. The territory of El Salvador later became part of the Kingdom of Guatemala, but Salvadorans strongly objected to the Guatemalans' plan to incorporate the territory into the Mexican Empire.</p>
<p>In 1824, after a brief war and having established its own constitution, El Salvador became one of the United Provinces of Central America (later the Federal Republic of Central America).</p>
<p>Nonetheless, it was several decades before El Salvador was able to rid itself of the overwhelming influence of Guatemala. This came about largely through the influence of the coffee barons, who dominated El Salvador until the 1920s, and the military, which had by then entered the political arena.</p>
<p>Economic problems blighted the country from the 1950s to the 1970s, with a brief diversion provided by the 1969 Soccer War with Honduras (essentially a border dispute). The 1980 assassination of Archbishop Oscar Romero &ndash; a leading critic of civil rights abuses &ndash; by right-wing elements, saw El Salvador plunge into civil war.</p>
<p>As the war spread throughout the country in the 1980s, the government received huge amounts of US military and civil aid, with which it fought a brutal and fairly effective counter-insurgency campaign against leftist guerrillas of the Farabundo Marti Liberation Front (FMLN). Peace talks began in earnest in 1989, and a formal ceasefire, under UN auspices and supervised by a joint forum of the two sides, came into force at the beginning of 1992.</p>
<p>It was not until the 2000 National Assembly election that the FLMN became the largest party. Political differences were temporarily set aside in January 2001, when the country was struck by a massive earthquake, which killed several thousand and left tens of thousands homeless.</p>
<p>In 2009, Mauricio Funes, a former television journalist, became the first president from the FMLN party. He has presided over a number of key social reforms including the abolition of end-user fees for public health care, and the introduction of free shoes, clothes and meals for schoolchildren. Opponents point out that crime has not abated and the countrywide murder rate remains one of the highest in the world.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Archbishop Oscar Romero, who was assassinated in 1980, was declared a martyr by Pope Francis in 2015.<br />
&bull;	The infamous Mara Salvatrucha (MS-13) street gang originated in Los Angeles, where many Salvadorans fled during the civil war.<br />
&bull;	The nickname for Salvadorans is <em>guanacos</em>, a relative of the llama, though the name may also derive from the indigenous word for &lsquo;brotherhood&rsquo;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of El Salvador in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 595 7000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.elsalvador.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 595 7000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1730&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Suite 100,1400 16th Street<br/>Washington<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of El Salvador in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7224 9800.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://elsalvador.embassyhomepage.com/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7224 9800.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon–Fri 1000–1600&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>8 Dorset Square<br/>London<br/>NW1 6PU<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in El Salvador ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7224 9800.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/el-salvador</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7224 9800.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0730-1630, Fri 0730-1130.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Edificio Torre Futura, 14th floor, Colonia Escalon<br/>San Salvador <br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The smallest country in Central America, El Salvador is big on natural wonders. The word is out among more intrepid travellers that this is the region&rsquo;s up-and-coming destination. Newcomers are bowled over by the stunning landscape, with smoking volcanoes, surf-pounded beaches, pristine cloud forests and crystalline lagoons. And those in the know are drawn back time and again by its warm-hearted and dynamic people.</p>
<p>This tiny tropical land, about the size of Wales or Massachusetts, is packed with highlights. Magnificent, crowd-free national parks include Cerro Verde, Montecristo and the irresistibly named El Imposible. You can shoot the rapids on whitewater rafts, or take a lazy boat ride across volcanic crater lakes Ilopango and Coatepeque. Surfers flock to the world-class Pacific breakers at Sonsonate, El Zonte and La Uni&oacute;n, only a short drive from the capital. The archaeological remains at Tazumal mark the furthest outpost of the Maya empire; the Ruta de Las Flores features colourful, flower-filled villages, with volcanic hot springs and indigenous craft markets; and Moraz&aacute;n province offers tours of civil war trenches led by former guerrillas turned guides.</p>
<p>El Salvador still has a bad reputation for violent crime, but the truth is that the locals have always suffered much more than tourists at the hands of criminals, most of whom are more concerned with the feuding of rival drug gangs.</p>
<p>The tourism industry is responding rapidly to the country&rsquo;s rising popularity. Coffee plantations are inviting guests to visit, to eat and drink, to stay, to work. Beach resorts are becoming more boutique, spa hotels are multiplying and the eastern Gulf of Fonseca is being developed, with boat-and-bus routes connecting with neighbouring Nicaragua. El Salvador may not yet be the most comfortable place to visit in the region, but for the increasing number of people who are making the effort, the rewards are plentiful.</p><p>The smallest country in Central America, El Salvador is big on natural wonders. The word is out among more intrepid travellers that this is the region&rsquo;s up-and-coming destination. Newcomers are bowled over by the stunning landscape, with smoking volcanoes, surf-pounded beaches, pristine cloud forests and crystalline lagoons. And those in the know are drawn back time and again by its warm-hearted and dynamic people. This tiny tropical land, about the size of Wales or Massachusetts, is packed with highlights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
