<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Eritrea" ColCode="eri" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="er" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Eritrea]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no time of year that is particularly unsuitable for visiting Eritrea. The country can be divided into three major zones: the central highlands, the coastal region, and the western lowlands. Each has a different climatic pattern.<br />
<br />
In the highlands, the hottest month is usually May with highs around 30&deg;C (86&deg;F). Winter is between December and February with lows at night that can be near freezing and dramatic temperature differences between day and night. Asmara itself enjoys a pleasant climate all year round. There are two rainy seasons: the short rains in March and April and the main rains from late June to the beginning of September. These are unlikely to impede travel or general enjoyment of the highlands.<br />
<br />
On the coast, the months from June to September are extremely hot with daily temperatures ranging from 40&deg;C (100&deg;F) to 50&deg;C (122&deg;F) (and hotter in Dankalia). In winter the daily temperature ranges from 21&deg;C (70&deg;F) to 35&deg;C (95&deg;F). This is a good time to visit, when it is not insufferably hot and skies are invariably clear. It is always warm enough to swim, even in the winter months of February to April, which can be cloudy. The rainy season on the coast north of Dankalia falls in the winter months; in Dankalia itself, rain is extremely rare.<br />
<br />
In the western lowlands, the high temperatures are comparable to those on the coast in the hottest months of April until June. December is the coldest month with temperatures falling as low as 15&deg;C (59&deg;F). The rainy seasons are the same as for the highlands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are in the highlands during winter it is advisable to bring at least one set of warm clothes. Otherwise shirts and a couple of pairs of trousers are enough: lightweight cotton for walking, and for wearing in the evening. Despite their limited resources Eritreans are always smartly dressed and even during sandstorms in the lowlands they seem to be able to remain pristine.<br />
<br />
Eritrea has a large Muslim population and women should dress with this in mind, not exposing the knees or shoulders. This will avoid a lot of trouble, especially in the lowland areas. Shorts are not generally worn, by men or women, in Asmara or other towns, with the exception of the coast, but obviously if you are travelling in Dankalia or other out of the way areas they are practical. As a general rule, Eritreans dress modestly and you should do the same.<br />
<br />
A sunhat is essential on the coast and in the western lowlands, as too are a good pair of sunglasses.<br />
<br />
Good walking shoes or boots are essential if you are travelling anywhere other than the major cities. Trainers, flip flops or sandals are all useful, depending on the purpose of your stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eritrea is a small country and there are no passenger services between major settlements.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to hire boats in Massawa for travelling to or sailing around the Dahlak Islands, but services are scarce and should be arranged in advance through a local travel agent, such as Travel House International, who can provide a complete list of boat operators, including speedboats and dhows on which to visit the islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A steam railway built which fell into disrepair during the &lsquo;Struggle&rsquo; for independence has been lovingly restored by former employees and now operates only as a tourist route. The 2,300m (7,500ft) climb from the coast to Asmara was built by the Italians in 1911 and later extended it to the city of Keren in the north of the country. It takes about 10 hours.</p>
<p>The railway currently offers trips for organised tours from anywhere between Asmara and Massawa. The route, from the highland plateau to the Red Sea coast, surely ranks as one of the world&rsquo;s most unforgettable railway journeys, but to do it, you must pay several hundred dollars, so group bookings are the norm.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All foreign tourists have to obtain a permit from the Ministry of Tourism in Eritrea to travel outside Asmara. These are usually issued within 24 hours.&nbsp;</p>r<p>The main roads are generally in very good condition. All major are sealed and well maintained, making road travel in standard-drive vehicles between cities relatively comfortable and swift.&nbsp;Minor roads are often unsealed and can be less comfortable, but they are generally well maintained. 4-wheel drive vehicles are recommended on all non-main roads and tracks.</p>
<p>Travelling on minor roads or off-road in the rainy season is inadvisable as heavy downpours can cause flooding, making tracks impassable and extremely dangerous.</p><p>Taxis are unmetered and can be found in the major towns and cities and at Asmara airport. The airport route is relatively expensive compared with single journeys in the city. Taxis usually carry multiple passengers, but for a higher fee travellers can hire a taxi for themselves. Fares are higher at night (usually double) and should be negotiated in advance.</p><p>International driving licences are valid in Eritrea; you should also carry your national licence.</p><p>Seatbelts are required when driving or seated in the front of a car, but not on buses.</p><p>There are no breakdown services in Eritrea, so make sure you have sufficient spare parts and supplies if travelling off the main roads or away from major towns and cities.</p><p>You can book cars through the all major travel agents and local hire companies.</p><p>Although Eritreans love bicycle racing, there are no hire bikes in Eritrea. Towns and cities, including the centre of Asmara, are small enough to walk around comfortably.</p><p>Seatbelts are required when driving or seated in the front of a car, but not on buses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although taxis and some minibus services do operate in the larger cities (eg Asmara, Massawa and Keren), the most common and pleasurable method of getting around towns and cities in Eritrea is on foot. Asmara is the only city large enough to require taxi or buses for urban transit beyond the centre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating flights to Eritrea include Egyptair (<a href="http://www.egyptair.com" target="_blank">www.egyptair.com</a>), flydubai (<a href="http://www.flydubai.com" target="_blank">www.flydubai.com</a>), Qatar Airways (<a href="http://www.qatarairways.com" target="_blank">www.qatarairways.com</a>) and Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>).</p>
<p>Prices fluctuate throughout the year, peaking during the summer holidays when Eritreans from overseas return in their droves, and around the Christmas holidays when the foreign community in Eritrea perform a similar exodus in the opposite direction.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours (including stopover); <a href="new-york-city">New York</a> - 19 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Asmara International Airport </b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 6km (4 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eritrea has two ports: Assab, in the far south of the country, which is open only to commercial and military vessels and the main port, Massawa, the largest deep-water port in the Red Sea. Massawa is primarily a commercial port, but it does occasionally attract cruise ships or passenger vessels passing along the Red Sea. Massawa also serves as the departure point for the beautiful Dahlak Archipelago.</p><p>No scheduled passenger ships pass through Massawa. It is advisable therefore to check well in advance if you plan to travel into or out of Massawa by boat. Contact either a local travel agent or Eritrean Shipping Lines, who have an office in Asmara (tel: +291 120 402) and Massawa (tel: +291 552 475).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only main road route into Eritrea is from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sudan">Sudan</a>, which links Khartoum with Tesseney via Kassala, but this is closed to foreigners. The road from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/djibouti">Djibouti</a> is invariably closed and impractical, as it enters the southern tip of the country, from which it is a 1,000km (620-mile) journey to Asmara.</p><p>The southern border with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ethiopia">Ethiopia</a> has been closed since the war in 1998 and, despite a ceasefire in 2000, will remain closed for the foreseeable future.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>All towns and cities are connected via the internal system and public phone boxes can be found in the main streets. International calls can be made from the public phones in the Telecommunication building outside the theatre in Asmara.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with mobile phone companies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is internet access in the main towns, but coverage is variable and often frustratingly slow.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eritrea is the only African country to have no privately-owned news media. It also has no private radio or TV stations. No criticism of the government is tolerated. The government closed the private press in 2001 on the premise that it endangered national security.</p>
<p>There are no independent newspapers in Eritrea. <em>Hadas Eritrea</em> is published three times a week in English, Arabic and Tigrinya. A youth paper called <em>Tirigta</em> is published once a week, as is the only English language paper, <em>Eritrea Profile</em>.</p>
<p>The only official television channel is the state-run Eri TV. CNN, BBC, Al-Jazeera and some other foreign news channels are broadcast in some of the higher-end hotels and cafes or bars.</p>
<p>The radio, like the television and printed media, is dominated by the state-run Voice of the Broad Masses of Eritrea (Dimtsi Hafash) which operates two networks with programmes in 11 languages. Radio Zara has a state-run, FM network.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International post services are reliable, though slow. Services have not been resumed with all countries since the previous war.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1200, 1400-1900; Sun 1900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Akordat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Turkish and Egyptian colonial periods left numerous interesting buildings and sites in Akordat (Barka Province) including the tomb of Said Mustafa wad Hasan. Qohaito, Metera and Rora Habab are also important archaeological sites.</p>]]><p><b>Asmara Walks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are few cities so suited to the simple pleasure of walking and exploring as Asmara. The climate is perfect, the streets are clean, refreshment is widespread, crime is very rare, the architecture is stunning, the distances are manageable, the sights are varied, and the people are warm. Explore the city on foot and discover its many hidden treasures, from 1930s cinemas to futuristic petrol stations, and when you're tired there's always a café nearby in which to refuel with a wide selection of drinks and pastries.</p>]]><p><b>Beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With nearly 1,000km (620 miles) of Red Sea coast, Eritrea boasts a stunning range of untouched beaches – from pristine white sands to black volcanic shorelines and from the deserted to the popular tourist beaches around Massawa.</p>]]><p><b>Dankalia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dankalia occupies a large portion of southern Eritrea and the lowlands of northeastern Ethiopia. The portion of Dankalia that lies within Eritrea comprises the narrow strip of land extending to the south and kissed by the sea for almost 500km (310 miles). Even the gentle breezes off this most majestic of Red Sea coasts barely stirs the thick soupy air, which boils up from the baked ground in unforgiving waves that burn the skin and choke the lungs. If the devil wanted to create hell on earth, the infernal wastes of Dankalia would be his choice, but for the most intrepid travellers this hostile landscape offers an unforgettable journey.</p>]]><p><b>Decemhare</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The town of Decemhare is a short drive south of Asmara. It was a favourite settlement of the Italians who originally intended it to be the transport hub of the entire Italian Empire in the Horn of Africa. It is worth stopping in Decemhare to have a look around, if only to see what remains of this once proud town.</p>]]><p><b>Emberemi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Emberemi is famous for the mausoleums of Sheikh el Amin and Muhammad Ibn Ali. It is an important pilgrimage site.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Asmara's Modernist architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Asmara was the centre of Italy's East African Empire. Following Italy's invasion of Ethiopia in 1935, Asmara became a boom town and transformed into one of the most modern cities in Africa. Today, it appears like a city lost in time and possessing the highest concentration and most complete collection of Modernist architecture in the world.</p>]]><p><b>Filfil</b></p><![CDATA[<p>To the northeast of Asmara lies the Semienawi Bahri, or 'Green Belt' region of Eritrea. The area is more commonly known as Filfil and contains the last remnants of Eritrea's once abundant tropical forest, home to an impressive array of birds and mammals. It is hard to imagine such dense forest exists in this region of Africa. The forest thrives on the vast, moist escarpment that links the highland plateau with the burning lowland plains.</p>]]><p><b>Go cycling</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Although cycling is one of the country's popular sports, it is unusual for bicycles to be rented out to tourists. However, each year Eritrea hosts one of the toughest races along the Asmara-Keren road. Regular meetings are organised by the Cycling Federation (tel: (1) 117 280).</p>]]><p><b>Keren</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Keren is the capital of the Anseba province and the third largest city in Eritrea after Asmara and Massawa. It is a relaxed pretty town, famed for its quiet pace of life, colourful markets and ethnic diversity. It forms the crossroads between several roads that branch out towards Nakfa, Agordat, and Asmara. The town rests in a bowl, the rim of which is formed by the formidable peaks of Lalemba, Ziban, Senkil, Felestaw, Itaber and Amba Mountains.</p>]]><p><b>Massawa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Massawa was an ancient port and remains the largest natural deep-water port on the Red Sea. If Asmara is an Italianate city, Massawa is Turko-Egyptian style, reflecting the periods of Ottoman and Egyptian rule from the 16th century to the late 19th century. The beautiful but ramshackle old town was damaged during the 'Struggle' but its coral block buildings still retain some of the former grandeur that makes this antique port appear like a miniature version of Zanzibar's Stone Town.</p>]]><p><b>Metera and Senafe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The site of Metara on the outskirts of Senafe covers about 10 hectares, and is known variously amongst locals as Balaw Calaw, King Kaleb's remains and the Gate of Axum. There are many ruins including the ancient obelisk dating to the 3rd century. The nearby town of Senafe is dominated by the huge rocks to the south. You can climb to the top of the largest of these and it is worth it for the views but you should ask someone to show you the easiest way, as it is not a simple climb.</p>]]><p><b>Monastery of Debre Bizen</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Journey the spectacular road from Asmara to Massawa, 105km (65 miles). It descends from 2,438m (8,000ft) to sea level, with hair-raising hairpin bends negotiating the escarpment, and magnificent views over the coastal desert strip. 20km outside Asmara, the road passes through the pretty town of Nefasit, behind which, perched on top of the mountain ridge, is the famous Monastery of Debre Bizen.</p>]]><p><b>Qohaito</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Eritrea is rich in archaeological sites, many of which have yet to be excavated.  The ruins of Qohaito, on the road south of Asmara towards Senafe, and Adulis, on the coast, are the most famous. The site contains the Safra's Dam and the ruins of the palace of King Saba from the Axumite and pre-Axumite period. The ancient port of Adulis is currently being excavated.</p>]]><p><b>The Dahlak Archipelago</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With around 350 islands off the Eritrean coast the Dahlak Archipelago is a national park that is the window on an unspoilt underwater world of flat reef gardens and an extraordinary variety of sea life. Travellers cannot go alone or without permission and should also be mindful of the extreme temperatures.</p>]]><p><b>Tomb of Said Abu Bakr el Mirgani</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the religious sites of the Tomb of Said Abu Bakr el Mirgani and the Mariam de Arit. Debre Sina, near Elabered on the Asmara-Keren road, is also a noteworthy monastery.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the steam railway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Eritrea's railway used to run from Massawa to beyond Agordat via Asmara. After falling into disrepair it has been restored between Massawa and Asmara. To explore the railway sheds and visit the old manufacturing facilities is a railway enthusiast's dream. The skeletal remains of locomotives in varying states of repair sit patiently on tracks in their sheds or on the hand-driven turntable outside. Those that have been lovingly restored by the aging workforce famously brought out of retirement and now in their 80s positively gleam. If you're lucky (or wealthy!) you might be able to experience a small excursion a few kilometres along the track in the direction of Massawa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$3 billion (2012).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Copper, gold, sorghum, textiles, livestock, and small manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, petroleum products, food and manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Italy, Saudi Arabia, Egypt, China, Nigeria.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The long-running Ethiopian civil war left Eritrea, which was, until 1991, the northernmost province of Ethiopia, with its economy in a parlous condition. Since the split from Ethiopia in 1993, Eritrea has been engaged in a series of military campaigns which have stunted its economic development. The most recent border war with Ethiopia (1998-2000) cost Eritrea several hundred million dollars.<br />
<br />
Agriculture sustains the bulk of the population with indigenous grains, maize, wheat and sorghum as the main crops. However, reconstruction has been hampered by the legacy of war (damage to land, mines, and a lack of equipment and human resources) and poor rainfall, making the country prone to needing food aid.<br />
<br />
The small industrial economy produces glass, cement and textiles. The government has been developing fishing and mineral industries, particularly as there are thought to be significant oil and gas deposits within Eritrea's territorial waters and precious metals on land. Exploration rights have been granted by the government to several major multinational oil companies to conduct marine surveys and copper, gold and silver are already being mined in the western regions. <br />
<br />
With an average annual per capita income of US$400, Eritrea is one of the world's poorest countries. The economy expanded rapidly after independence, but this was hampered by the renewed hostilities in 1998 and has struggled to improve until recently. Erratic rainfall and below-average cereal production continues to limit growth, but mining in the last two years has made Eritrea&rsquo;s economy one of the fastest growing in Africa. The growth rate was 9% and 7% in 2011 and 2012 respectively.<br />
<br />
Eritrea has been granted admission to the ACP group of Third World countries, which receive preferential access to certain European Union markets, and it is now a member of the International Monetary Fund.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are three official languages in Eritrea: Tigrinya, Arabic and English. Local businesspeople in Asmara, particularly the older generations, may also speak Italian.<br />
<br />
Business is generally quite problematic in Eritrea, principally due to the level of bureaucracy that prevails. Business stamps are a necessity for every piece of paper that leaves or enters an office, making business slow and often unnecessarily complicated. Paperwork and its needless creation can often be tiresome, but it must always be remembered that this is a system still struggling to get to grips with a fast and technologically advanced world into which it was forced to engage almost overnight. Lack of facilities, equipment and manpower compound the problem. <br />
<br />
In general, if you have a business visa and are doing business, insist on signing a contract which includes an advance payment before you start doing any work, for it could be many weeks or months before the necessary paperwork is created that will allow you to receive full payment. This unfortunate inefficiency is certainly not likely to be caused through any desire to swindle. Eritreans are unreservedly honest to their word; it is simply that the system struggles to operate efficiently at the best of times.</p><p>Mon-Thurs 0700-1200, 1400-1800, Fri 0700-1130, 1400-1800. Hours may vary slightly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Eritrean National Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 121 589 ,122 456
					Website:
					Address: Abiot Av 46,PO Box 856,Asmara,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Italian cuisine dominates in the restaurants in Asmara, where you can find pizza, pasta and a wide range of meat, seafood and vegetarian dishes. Massawa is renowned for its excellent seafood, where, if you&rsquo;re lucky, you may be able to find fresh prawns and even lobster.</p>
<p>Local Eritrean food, famous the world over for its delicious spicy dishes of meat and vegetables served on large spongy pancake called <em>injera</em>, the staple made from <em>teff</em>, wheat or sorghum. The grains are ground up, made into a watery dough and then left to ferment for a couple of days before being fried or baked. Injera is eaten with stew made from meat, fish, vegetables, or any combination of these. Meat or fish stews are called <em>zigini</em>. When it is served, several injera are placed on a tray and the stew poured into the middle. You eat with your hands by breaking off bits of injera and scooping up the stew. People eat together, sharing the food. In practice the choice of food is often limited when you are in the countryside.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Kitcha</em> (a thin bread made from wheat).<br />
&bull; <em>Injera</em> (a spongy pancake).<br />
&bull; <em>Tsebhi</em> (meat saut&eacute; of either lamb or beef with fresh tomatoes and hot peppers).<br />
&bull; <em>Alicha birsen</em> (lentil curry).<br />
&bull;	<em>Zigini</em> (meat stew). <br />
&bull;	<em>Zigna assa</em> (fish stew). <br />
&bull;	<em>Tibzi</em> (meat saut&eacute; of either lamb or beef with fresh tomatoes and hot peppers). <br />
&bull;	<em>Ful</em> (stewed beans with onion and tomato, normally eaten for breakfast or dinner). <br />
&bull;	<em>Kitcha fitfit</em> (pieces of kitcha served with yogurt and butter). <br />
&bull;	<em>Shiro</em> (chick pea pur&eacute;e). <br />
&bull;	<em>Ades</em> (lentils). <br />
&bull;	Capretto (goat, usually served like a rack of lamb). <br />
&bull;	Frittata (scrambled eggs with onion and peppers). <br />
&bull;	<em>Nai tsom</em> (fasting food - vegetarian combination).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>The traditional coffee ceremony is an experience to savour, so if someone invites you for coffee then you should accept the offer with open arms (and bring a small gift, such as a selection of cakes from the bakery).</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Hotels and restaurants add a service charge, usually around 10%. Tipping is fairly common, in small amounts. Taxi drivers are not usually tipped.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bars in most towns and cities will be busy into the evening, but tend to quieten down or close well before midnight.Discos are normally at weekends and are advertised in the streets.<br />
<br />
Among the most popular clubs in Asmara is Shamrock in the Expo grounds on the way to the airport. Other venues include Warsa, in the Godaif district, which has good live music at the weekend, and Mocambo in the city centre. Entrance fees vary from completely free, to Nfa200. There are often bands playing for special occasions. <br />
<br />
Asmara has many cinemas which are very popular both for films and screening football matches at the weekend. Do not base your visit to Asmara on its potential nightlife; with the exception of the discos, life shuts down by 2300 and the frequent power cuts often bring the curtain down on a night out. In smaller towns and cities the nightlife can be scarce or non-existent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Asmara has several interesting markets, but Eritrea is still no place for the avid shopper. Souvenirs are available, ranging from rather uninteresting African souvenirs which you might find in any duty free shop on the continent, to some much more interesting gold and silver jewellery, and religious artefacts such as prayer scrolls, old decorated Bibles, crosses and incense burners, and craft items. <br />
<br />
Keren is the best place to hunt for jewellery. Elsewhere in the country, in the west for example, you can find pottery, swords, daggers, traditional haircombs, baskets and other items in the marketplaces. The quality of weaving with grasses for baskets is especially good in the western lowlands.<br />
<br />
While many of the textiles worn by Eritreans are attractive, most of the material is imported from the Far East. The Tigrinya shawl (<em>netsela</em>) you will see everywhere in the highlands is the most authentic cloth you can buy in Eritrea, but since the last war it has soared in price, as most were imported from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ethiopia">Ethiopia</a>. Eritreans are slowly developing a manufacturing industry of their own and some textile manufacturers are now producing garments for export from cotton grown in the western lowlands.<br />
<br />
The marketplaces in towns and cities are always vibrant and fascinating places to wander around. A wide variety of fresh vegetables, fruit, spices and pulses are available in the central market in Asmara. There is also a more craft-oriented market behind the main mosque that sells a wide range of wicker and pottery goods. Although you may find these items for a much cheaper price outside Asmara, this is certainly the most practical place to buy such items. <br />
In Asmara there are also many Italian style grocery shops where you can buy anything from mineral water to Chianti. A wide range of wines, spirits and imported beers can also be bought in these shops.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0830-1300, 1430-2030 (regional variations occur).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Asmara has a wide range of accommodation, from the only five star hotel in Eritrea to the dingiest hovel. At certain times of the year it might be difficult to find a bed in the price range you want, especially during the summer holidays when Eritreans from overseas visit in considerable numbers, but generally there is seldom a problem. You will only be able to book from overseas in the upper-range hotels. Privately owned hotels are generally cleaner and more inviting than the state-run establishments and have a better customer service. Many of the independent &lsquo;pensions&rsquo; are also more than adequate. The low-end pensions often double as brothels and you tend to get what you pay for &ndash; very little.</p>
<p>Water and electricity supplies are unpredictable. The whole country has had problems in recent years, but most upper-range hotels will have back-up water supplies and a generator. It is important always to be prudent with your use of resources.</p>
<p>Massawa and Keren have a much smaller range of hotels, so it is worth booking in advance if possible. Prices are, in general, slightly lower than in Asmara. Meals are available in all major hotels in Eritrea. When making reservations, check for service charges and sales taxes. Hotel bills must be paid in hard currency.</p>
<p>Outside the larger towns and cities accommodation can be very basic, so be prepared for few frills and intermittent water and electricity supplies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no system of bed and breakfasts in Eritrea. The higher standard hotels all have their own restaurants, while the smaller hotels and pensions do not offer food, though cafes and restaurants are generally close by.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Asmara has a wide range of accommodation, from the only five star hotel in Eritrea to the dingiest hovel. At certain times of the year it might be difficult to find a bed in the price range you want, especially during the summer holidays when Eritreans from overseas visit in considerable numbers, but generally there is seldom a problem. You will only be able to book from overseas in the upper-range hotels. Privately owned hotels are generally cleaner and more inviting than the state-run establishments and have a better customer service. Many of the independent &lsquo;pensions&rsquo; are also more than adequate. The low-end pensions often double as brothels and you tend to get what you pay for &ndash; very little.</p>
<p>Water and electricity supplies are unpredictable. The whole country has had problems in recent years, but most upper-range hotels will have back-up water supplies and a generator. It is important always to be prudent with your use of resources.</p>
<p>Massawa and Keren have a much smaller range of hotels, so it is worth booking in advance if possible. Prices are, in general, slightly lower than in Asmara. Meals are available in all major hotels in Eritrea. When making reservations, check for service charges and sales taxes. Hotel bills must be paid in hard currency.</p>
<p>Outside the larger towns and cities accommodation can be very basic, so be prepared for few frills and intermittent water and electricity supplies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Asmara has a wide range of accommodation, from the only five star hotel in Eritrea to the dingiest hovel. At certain times of the year it might be difficult to find a bed in the price range you want, especially during the summer holidays when Eritreans from overseas visit in considerable numbers, but generally there is seldom a problem. You will only be able to book from overseas in the upper-range hotels. Privately owned hotels are generally cleaner and more inviting than the state-run establishments and have a better customer service. Many of the independent &lsquo;pensions&rsquo; are also more than adequate. The low-end pensions often double as brothels and you tend to get what you pay for &ndash; very little.</p>
<p>Water and electricity supplies are unpredictable. The whole country has had problems in recent years, but most upper-range hotels will have back-up water supplies and a generator. It is important always to be prudent with your use of resources.</p>
<p>Massawa and Keren have a much smaller range of hotels, so it is worth booking in advance if possible. Prices are, in general, slightly lower than in Asmara. Meals are available in all major hotels in Eritrea. When making reservations, check for service charges and sales taxes. Hotel bills must be paid in hard currency.</p>
<p>Outside the larger towns and cities accommodation can be very basic, so be prepared for few frills and intermittent water and electricity supplies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;It is possible that some travellers will feel the effects of Asmara&amp;rsquo;s high altitude and low oxygen levels. Some visitors might therefore give some time to acclimatising to the conditions. Those who suffer from heart ailments or high blood pressure should consult a doctor before travelling. Medical services are limited throughout the country; modern facilities are not always available and supplies can be irregular. Visitors should bring a supply of any necessary drugs and prescriptions. Chemists can be found in larger towns. The country has an extensive network of health workers. Regional and district clinics and the central hospital in Asmara deal with emergencies. Comprehensive health insurance is strongly advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Eritrea has many natural springs that produce excellent drinking water. Carbonated and non-carbonated bottled drinking water is now widely available in the major towns and cities. Tap water is ok for brushing teeth but should not be used for drinking or making ice. Pasteurised milk is available in Asmara. Elsewhere it is likely to be unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available in Asmara. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Eritrea has no permanent rivers, but Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) can be found in freshwater pools and reservoirs. Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Dengue fever and Rift Valley fever are present. Hepatitis E is widespread and hepatitis B is hyperendemic. Meningococcal meningitis is a risk, particularly in savannah areas and during the dry season. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>Orthodox Epiphany :
							2018<br/>19 January </p><p>Fenkil Day :
							10 February </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Orthodox Easter Monday :
							09 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							24 May </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							20 June </p><p>Revolution Day :
							01 September </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Eritrea without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; 500ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; 100g of jewellery.<br />
&bull; 1 camera and 1 item of electronic equipment for personal use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The usual import restrictions apply on organic products and firearms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The export of antiques, such as religious parchments and artefacts, is prohibited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nakfa (ERN) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of ERN100, 50, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of ERN100, 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1.</p>
<p>The nakfa was introduced in 1998 to replace the Ethiopian birr, which signified a symbolic end to colonial rule and, as some say, contributed to tensions with their neighbour that precipitated the last war.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar bills are the most convenient form of exchange. Foreign currencies can be exchanged at the Commercial Bank of Eritrea in Asmara (which provides the best exchange rate), private currency exchange offices and major hotels.</p>
<p>Until recently, the government sought to prevent the black market currency trading by requiring visitors to declare all foreign currency when entering and leaving Eritrea. Although this inconvenient and largely futile measure has been abandoned, it is still inadvisable to change money on the black market. There are periodic clampdowns on unofficial money changers (once common in Asmara around the central Post Office). You might be approached by a few daring souls, but to change money outside a bank or authorised dealership is <em>not</em> legal and you do so entirely at your own risk.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are not accepted in Eritrea; payment is by cash only.</p><p>There are no ATMs in Eritrea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers cheques are not accepted anywhere. Payment should be in cash only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1400-1700, Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Eritrea, all nationals referred to in the chart above require a passport valid for a minimum of six months beyond their intended departure date and have two clear pages that are side-by-side.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa: &pound;25; single-entry business visa: &pound;40.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visas are normally valid for three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 10 to 15 days for visa processing. An express service is available for an additional charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must provide proof of sufficient funds to cover the duration of your stay with your visa application.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[15.638009]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[38.850999]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>117,600 sq km (45,405 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5,401,231 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>55.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Asmara.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eritrea is a land of extraordinary physical diversity. It is one of the few countries where visitors can truly experience &lsquo;four seasons in a day&rsquo;.</p>
<p>The eastern lowlands that stretch along the Red Sea for almost 1,000km (625 miles ) offer a stunning variety of scenes, from barren deserts to towering volcanic landscapes. Scattered off the coast and its myriad coral reefs are the 350 islands of the Dahlak Archipelago.</p>
<p>In the north is the border with North Sudan and in the south, Djibouti. The centre of the country comprises the precipitous highland plateau that appears to float in the clouds as you wind up the vertiginous slopes of the escarpment from the coast by road or even steam railway.</p>
<p>At nearly 2,500m (8,200ft) altitude, Asmara is the highest capital in Africa. Much of the southern highlands is agricultural and borders Ethiopia. To the west of Eritrea, the plateau fractures and tumbles into the western lowlands where a desert landscape stretches out across vast plains and meets the border with the north of Sudan.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eritrea's religious community is divided in two almost equal portions of Orthodox Christians and Muslims. There are some Catholics, Protestants and Jews in the highlands, especially in Asmara, and some animists in the western lowland regions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is the normal form of greeting, though you will also see locals performing the shoulder greeting. This looks like two people engaging in a mild scuffle as they press their shoulders together three times as a symbol of friendship, especially among ex-fighters. As with shaking hands, this greeting may take some time, so do not be disconcerted by this.</p>
<p>Casual tourist wear is suitable for most places, but visitors should dress modestly. For business, a suit is most appropriate, though ties are not necessary, unless for very formal occasions.</p>
<p>Coffee is a delicacy in Eritrea and to be asked to take coffee is a symbol of hospitality and the way that Eritreans honour their guests. It takes up to an hour for the coffee to be prepared in a coffee ceremony and it is standard practice that you must have three cups and compliment the taste before leaving.</p>
<p>Smoking is not popular with traditional or elderly Eritreans. Shoes should be taken off in churches and, particularly, in mosques. Homosexual behaviour is illegal.<br />
<br />
<strong>Photography:</strong> It is not permitted to photograph government or military buildings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50 Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Isaias Afewerki since 1993.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Isaias Afewerki since 1993.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eritrea has for thousands of years been home to people of diverse living patterns, religions and traditions. After the South Arabian immigrations in the first millennium BC, Eritrea and much of Tigray were known as the Kingdom of the Habeshat. From the third to the seventh centuries AD, much of the present day territory lay within the Axumite Kingdom. </p><p>The Italians took the port of Massawa in 1885. They were relative latecomers in the so-called 'Scramble for Africa', but this was the beginning of an ambitious imperial campaign that sought to create a new Roman Empire in Africa. By 1900 they moved their capital from the steaming coastal lowlands to the salubrious climate enjoyed by the highland settlement of Asmara. The principal aims were to develop the colony with Italian immigrants, to exploit the natural resources and to equip it as a base for further expansion, which they later achieved in Libya, Somalia and Ethiopia.</p><p>In the early 20th century, Eritrea became one of the six provinces of Italian East Africa and the capital, Asmara, was the jewel in their imperial crown – a truly modern city with stunning architecture, spacious planning and the most advanced infrastructure, including more traffic lights than Rome. However, Italy's African dream was short lived and in 1941 the British expelled them from Eritrea and administered the territory as a protectorate for a decade.</p><p>In 1952 the UN decided that Eritrea should become part of a federated Ethiopia, but this arrangement only lasted a decade. Ethiopia's annexation of Eritrea in 1962 sparked a war for independence that lasted until 1991 and ended with Eritrean victory. In the subsequent referendum 99.8 per cent voted in favour of independence.</p><p>However, hostilities between Ethiopia and Eritrea persisted and the two countries went to war again from 1998 to 2000, with Eritrean forces also fighting skirmishes with forces from Yemen and Djibouti.</p><p>The war ended and a UN peacekeeping Mission in Eritrea and Ethiopia was installed. In 2002 the Permanent Court of Arbitration in The Hague agreed upon a "final and binding" verdict that awarded the contested territory to Eritrea. Ethiopia rejected the verdict and the border issue remains unresolved with the consequent 'no war, no peace' scenario that has devastated so many lives throughout the region.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>&bull; Eritrea, with parts of Djibouti, Ethiopia, Northern Somalia and Sudan is the likely location of the land known to the Ancient Egyptians as Punt.</p><p>&bull; There are thought to be around 100 African bush elephants left in Eritrea, but between 1951 and 2001 there were no reported sightings at all.</p><p>&bull; As in Ethiopia the ritualised coffee ceremony is a key part of Eritrean culture.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Eritrea]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+ 291 1 20 28 39</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-asmara</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+ 291 1 20 28 39</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1630; Fri 0800-1230.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>66-68 Mariam Ghimbi Street, PO Box 5584<br/>Asmara<br/>Zip Code 174<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the State of Eritrea in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>202 319 1991</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyeritrea.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>202 319 1991</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1708 New Hampshire Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the State of Eritrea in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7713 0096.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://eritrea.embassyhomepage.com/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7713 0096.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1300 (visa application); 1400-1600 (visa collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>96 White Lion Street<br/>London<br/>N1 9PF<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eritrea is a difficult country to define. Although in Africa, it doesn&rsquo;t feel wholly African. While its broad shore faces the Middle East, it is not overtly Arabian. And though its capital evokes the spirit of Europe, it is far from European.</p>
<p>For such a small country, Eritrea offers an astonishing variety and it tends to attract a motley crew of visitors: from archaeologists to architects; scholars to scuba divers; historians to hikers; and cyclists to steam railway buffs.</p>
<p>While there are many reasons to come to Eritrea, there is one impression that endures when you leave: the remarkable kindliness of the Eritrean people. Making friends here is an unavoidable pleasure and one that touches the lives of so many visitors.</p>
<p>The country stretches along the Red Sea and is low-lying in the eastern coastal regions and western border with Sudan, with a precipitous mountainous interior rising to a majestic 2,500m (8200ft) above sea level.</p>
<p>Having been colonised in part by the Turks and Egyptians, Eritrea took on a European flavor with the arrival of the Italians in 1885 during their belated entry in the &ldquo;scramble for Africa&rdquo;.&nbsp;The legacies of successive foreign forces, combined with a rich mix of nine local ethnic groups have created a diverse cultural landscape that offers the best of African, Middle Eastern and European influences.</p>
<p>Eritrea also boasts an abundance of historical and natural attractions. The colonial and modernist architecture of its towns and cities is as stunning and startling as the wildlife that populates its mountainous escarpments, deserts and coastline.</p>
<p>Elephants, lions, baboons, gazelles, leopards, ostriches, turtles, dugongs and some of the continent&rsquo;s rarest birds can all be found here. And with a coastline extending nearly 1,000km (621miles) along the Red Sea, Eritrea offers some of the best diving and snorkelling in the world, as well as the most secluded beaches.</p>
<p>Once you&rsquo;ve experienced Eritrea&rsquo;s many secrets &ndash; travelled across its mountains and deserts, swam off its coastline, and met its warm people &ndash; it will only be a matter of time until you return for more.</p>Eritrea is a difficult country to define. Although in Africa, it doesn't feel wholly African. While its broad shore faces the Middle East, it is not overtly Arabian. And though its capital evokes the spirit of Europe, it is far from European. For such a small country, Eritrea offers an astonishing variety and it tends to attract a motley crew of visitors: from archaeologists to architects; scholars to scuba divers; historians to hikers; and cyclists to steam railway buffs.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
