<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Estonia" ColCode="est" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ee" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Estonia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Located in the northern part of the temperate climate zone and influenced by the Atlantic Ocean and Baltic Sea, Estonia has four distinct seasons with July being the warmest month and February the coldest. Rainfall is moderately low throughout the year, but falling frequently in summer and autumn.</p>
<p>Spring (March to May) sees water levels rise due to snow melts, flooding low-lying lands and giving keen canoers access to places that are otherwise accessible by foot. In Tallinn, the average temperatures rise gradually from -1&deg;C (30&deg;F) in March to 11&deg;C (52&deg;F) in May.</p>
<p>Summer (June to August) is the best time to visit Estonia as visitors can enjoy warm days and a string of festivals. However, do bring a raincoat as summer can be wet with frequent showers. In some coastal areas, visitors get to enjoy 19 hours of daylight in June.</p>
<p>Autumn (September to November) sees many gloomy days and frequent rainfall. September is still a good time to visit Estonia but by November, the weather turns cold and wet with temperatures averaging just 1&deg;C (34&deg;F).</p>
<p>Winter (December to February) is cold and snowy, particularly in the southwest where the warm sea current does not quite reach. Despite cold, Tallinn is most atmospheric with the Christmas Market sparkles in the charming Old Town.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lighter clothes are worn during the summer months, although a jacket is advisable in the evening.</p>
<p>Wrap up warm if you're visiting during the winter months. Check the climate of the specific area you intend to travel to as winter temperatures vary greatly between the coast and inland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Domestic flights within Estonia are not common. Avies (<a href="http://www.flyavies.ee" target="_blank">www.flyavies.ee</a>) operates flights between Tallinn and K&auml;rdla on the island of Hiiumaa. Flyest (<a href="http://www.flyest.eu" target="_blank">www.flyest.eu</a>)&nbsp;runs domestic private charter flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Praamid (www.praamid.ee) provides ferry services connecting the mainland with the islands Saaremaa and Muhumaa.<br />
Veeteed (www.veeteed.com) runs ferry services to several islands including Hiiumaa, Kihnu, Manilaid, Ruhnu and Vormsi.<br />
Leisure boats also operate on Lake Peipsi and along the Emaj&otilde;gi River.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Domestic trains run by ELRON (tel: +372 673 7400; <a href="http://www.elron.ee" target="_blank">www.elron.ee</a>) link Tallinn with many destinations within Estonia, including P&auml;rnu, Viljandi, Valga, Narva, Tapa and Tartu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving is an excellent way to see Estonia as the country is relatively small and has a good network of roads.</p>r<p>Roads are generally of good quality with routes usually adequately signposted.</p><p>Estonia has an extensive coach network with regional coaches between all main towns. Tallinn to Tartu and Tartu to Narva are popular routes and should be booked in advance, especially in summer. Check local route planner Peatus (<a href="http://www.peatus.ee" target="_blank">www.peatus.ee</a>) for up-to-date schedules.</p><p>Private taxis must display the name of the company and their number on the roof. Fares should be agreed upon beforehand and most taxis have prices for various journeys marked. Uber, Taxify, Taxigo, Taxofon and Yandex.taxi are popular apps to order a taxi or share a ride.</p><p>Drivers must have the original V5C (Vehicle Registration Document) as well as insurance documents covering them for Estonia if driving into the country.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18, and EU licences are valid for foreign drivers. Speed limits are well marked, ranging from 30-50kmph (19-31mph) in towns to 90-110kmph (56-68mph) on main intercity roads. Wearing a seatbelt is compulsory. There is a zero-tolerance policy towards drink-driving so blood alcohol level must be 0%. Dipped headlights must be used 24 hours a day.</p>
<p>Use of mobiles while driving is forbidden, but use of a hands-free device is fine. From 1 December to 1 March drivers must use winter tyres, although this can vary slightly depending on the weather so check conditions in advance.</p><p>In the event of a breakdown, call Falck (tel: 1888, in Estonia only).</p><p>Car hire is simple and well catered for, with all the international operators and plenty of local companies offering rental.</p><p>Cycling is a great way to see Estonia. The terrain is flat and there's a low volume of traffic to contend with, plus marked cycle paths and trails around the country make touring a perfectly viable option.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18, and EU licences are valid for foreign drivers. Speed limits are well marked, ranging from 30-50kmph (19-31mph) in towns to 90-110kmph (56-68mph) on main intercity roads. Wearing a seatbelt is compulsory. There is a zero-tolerance policy towards drink-driving so blood alcohol level must be 0%. Dipped headlights must be used 24 hours a day.</p>
<p>Use of mobiles while driving is forbidden, but use of a hands-free device is fine. From 1 December to 1 March drivers must use winter tyres, although this can vary slightly depending on the weather so check conditions in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the major cities are compact enough to get around on foot, but they also have an established public transport system served by bus, trolleybus and tram. You can pay the driver directly for single journeys (they don't sell returns) but if you plan to do much travelling on public transport it is cheaper to buy a book of tickets in advance from stalls in the main shopping areas. Alternatively, you can book a taxi with a Smartphone app.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Estonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tartu</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Estonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">paumlrnu</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Estonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">narva</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many European airlines connect Tallinn with major destinations across Europe such as Amsterdam, Berlin, Copenhagen, Helsinki, London, Oslo, Paris, Riga and Stockholm, among other destinations.</p>
<p>Four airlines fly direct from London to Tallinn - airBaltic (<a href="https://www.airbaltic.com/">airbaltic.com</a>), British Airways (<a href="https://www.britishairways.com">britishairways.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="https://www.easyjet.com">easyjet.com</a>), Ryanair (<a href="https://www.ryanair.com/">ryanair.com</a>) and Wizz (<a href="https://wizzair.com/">wizzair.com</a>) - such keen competition has helped to keep prices low, making Tallinn a popular weekend-break destination for British.</p>
<p>There are no direct flights from the USA.</p>
<p>The major airport is&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/estonia/tallinn-airport">Tallinn Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 45 minutes</p>
<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 9 hours 35 minutes (including stopover)</p>
<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sydney">Sydney</a> - 23 hours (including stopover)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Tallinn Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.tallinn-airport.ee<p>Tallinn Airport is located 4km (2.5 miles) southeast of Tallinn, in northern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/estonia">Estonia</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+372 605 8888</p>]]><b>Kärdla Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.kardla-airport.ee<p>The airport is located 5km (3 miles) east of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Port of Tallinn (<a href="http://www.portoftallinn.com">www.portoftallinn.com</a>) handles both cargo and passenger traffic. As an active ferry and cruise hub, more than 10 million passengers pass through the passenger terminals every year. Regular ferry routes include Helsinki, Stockholm and St Petersburg.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A daily train to/from St Petersburg and Moscow is run by RZD Russian Railways (<a href="http://pass.rzd.ru/main-pass/public/en" target="_blank">http://pass.rzd.ru/main-pass/public/en</a>). There&nbsp;are no direct trains running from Western Europe through to Estonia but it's possible to do the journey via an indirect route.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>All payphones in Estonia were taken out of service in 2010 and the country has no payphones today.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies and there is good coverage even on smaller islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The internet is key to Estonia's economic success and you can get excellent coverage via your mobile even in the forests. Free wireless zones can be found all over the country too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The post-independence years of the early 1990s saw a large increase in the production of newspapers, which has now fallen off as the market becomes more stable. Today, it is estimated that 91% of the population get their news from the internet.</p>
<p>The&nbsp;Eesti Rahvusringh&auml;&auml;ling&nbsp;(Estonian Public Broadcasting, ERR) operates two television stations&nbsp;Eesti Televisioon&nbsp;(ETV),&nbsp;ETV2&nbsp;and five radio stations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post to western Europe takes three to six days. In Tallinn the central post office is at 1 Narva maantee.</p><p>Mon-Fri 1000-1700. Some larger post offices may stay open longer, and also open on weekends.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Haapsalu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Haapsalu (<a href="http://www.haapsalu.ee/" target="_blank">www.haapsalu.ee</a>) is a small town on the western coast which has been a well-known resort since the 19th century. It is the ideal place to get away from it all with its romantic wooden houses and tree-lined avenues. A worthy diversion is the Raiway Museum which pays respects in the 'train graveyard' behind the museum.</p>]]><p><b>Hiiumaa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Estonia's second-largest island, Hiiumaa (<a href="http://www.hiiumaa.ee/">www.hiiumaa.ee</a>) is a true oasis of tranquillity. Most of the island is covered with forests and scrublands, giving wildlife such as moose, deer and wild boars a chance to roam freely. K&auml;ina Bay is also a prime destination for birdwatching. During the winter months, visitors can reach the island via an ice road across the frozen Baltic Sea. Said to be the longest ice road in Europe, it is about 25km (16 miles) and usually open from January to March.</p>]]><p><b>Mustvee</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This quiet corner on the shore of Lake Peipus is home to Old Believers, a religious group who did not accept the official reforms of the Russian Orthodox Church and sought refuge here in the 17th century. A key attraction is the small Old Believer's Museum in Mustvee.</p>]]><p><b>Narva</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Narva (<a href="http://www.narva.ee/">www.narva.ee</a>), the easternmost town in Estonia, sits by the River Narva that separates Estonia and Russia. The Narva Castle is the main attraction. Nearby, the Narva-J&otilde;esuu resort is home to a large sandy beach and many spas, drawing in a good crowd every summer.</p>]]><p><b>National parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the unspoilt forest and bogs, picturesque old fishing villages and historic manor houses in one of Estonia's national parks and reserves – Kõrvemaa, Lahemaa, Matsalu, Soomaa and Vilsandi.</p>]]><p><b>Pärnu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Established in the 13th century, P&auml;rnu (<a href="http://www.parnu.ee/">www.parnu.ee</a>) is the largest resort in Estonia, boasting a long sandy beach and a string of hotels offering relaxing spa services. Visitors can also engage in horse riding, birdwatching, and activities like making traditional dolls (Travnitsa) filled with herbs.</p>]]><p><b>Saaremaa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The largest island in Estonia, Saaremaa (<a href="http://www.saaremaa.ee/">www.saaremaa.ee</a>) is criss-crossed with hiking trails and dotted with bird-watching towers. Its coastal resort town Kuressaare has one spa for every ten residents; such high concentration is undoubtedly good news for visitors looking for a pampering session. A must-see on the island is the Kaali crater, a group of nine meteorite craters thought to be 3,500 years old.</p>]]><p><b>Tallinn</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wander the magical medieval cobble-stone streets of the capital, Tallinn (<a href="https://www.visittallinn.ee/">www.visittallinn.ee</a>), an ancient Hanseatic city. Particularly interesting is the Old Town, which is dominated by the soaring steeple of Oleviste Church, once the tallest building in the world. Climb up to Toompea Castle for spectacular views. See the Tallinn travel guide for more information.</p>]]><p><b>Tartu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Estonia's second-largest city, Tartu (<a href="http://www.tartu.ee/">www.tartu.ee</a>) revolves around its prestigious University of Tartu and young people enlivening the many cafes and bars dotted across the city. Visit the university, the Botanical Garden and the A. Le Coq Beer Museum. The city also has a few quirky diversions including the Tagurpidi Maja (upside-down house), the Leaning House of Tartu (which is also home to Tartu Museum of Art) and the Crazy Scientist's Office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$25.92 billion (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, mineral fuels, food products, vehicles, chemical products and metals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, food products, mineral fuels and wood products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Finland, Sweden, Germany, Russia and Lithuania.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Estonian economy is widely seen as an excellent example of a transitional economy, providing its citizens with one of the best standards of living in the former Eastern bloc.</p>
<p>Estonia has a thriving information technology sector with the government relentlessly pursuing and encouraging startups by introducing various schemes, including a Startup Visa scheme which helps non-EU entrepreneurs grow their businesses in Estonia, and e-Residency which allows non-Estonians access to vital business-friendly services like company formation, banking and taxation.</p>
<p>Trade with Finland, Sweden, Germany and Russia remains strong and key to the healthy of its economy; the downside is that Estonia is also vulnerable to volatile trade flows and external shocks.</p>
<p>Estonia has a significant amount of oil-shale which supplies over 90% of its electricity needs. Apart from oil-shale, Estonia has few raw materials of its own and relies mostly on imported commodities to produce finished goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Estonia embraces the European Union example of how business is conducted.<br />
<br />
Dress code is relatively formal, with suit and tie expected for business meetings, although new technology-based industries have incorporated more casual attire. Handshakes are the normal way to start any meeting, and gifts are appreciated. Prior appointments are necessary, it may take time to arrange a meeting and it is best to reconfirm before setting off. Business is conducted formally and business cards are exchanged after introduction. Successful meetings are often followed by drinks in a pub or dinners at an Estonian restaurant.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Estonian Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (6) 040 060
					Website:http://www.koda.ee/
					Address: ,Toom Kooli 17,Tallinn,10130]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Traditional Estonian food has meat and potatoes dominating the table, alongside rye bread, smoked fish and pickled vegetables. Jellied meat and fish are also popular. In Tallinn, Asian restaurants are sprouting up in recent years.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><em>&bull; S&uuml;lt</em> (a terrine or meat jelly made with meat from the head of a calf or pig).<br />
<em>&bull; T&auml;idetud vasikarind</em> (roast stuffed shoulder of veal).<br />
<em>&bull; Rosolje</em> (potato salad). <br />
<em>&bull; Leib</em> (rye bread).<br />
<em>&bull; Mulgipuder</em> (grain and potato porridge).<br />
<em>&bull; Verivorst</em> (blood sausage).<br />
<em>&bull; Pirukad</em> (pastries filled with meat or vegetables).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is standard for restaurants, although sometimes it will be added automatically, so check your receipt before adding anything extra.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tallinn is a favoured city break getaway for people all over Europe, especially Finns who come for cheaper alcohol (in comparison to Finland) and Brits who fly in for stag and hen nights. There is a wide range of restaurants, cafes and cosy bars, as well as livelier nightclubs that sometimes feature live bands. Socialising is at its most active between Thursday and Saturday, with most people heading to clubs open 2300-0300. For culture vultures in Tallinn, there is the Estonia National Opera (tel: +372 683 1201; <a href="http://www.opera.ee/">www.opera.ee</a>), the Estonia Concert Hall (tel: +372 614 7700; <a href="http://www.concert.ee">www.concert.ee</a>), the Vanemuine Theatre (tel: +372 744 0165; <a href="http://www.vanemuine.ee">www.vanemuine.ee</a>) and for children, the Nuku Puppet Theatre (tel: +372 667 9500; <a href="http://www.nuku.ee">www.nuku.ee</a>). For further details on cultural events, contact the Estonian Institute (tel: +372 631 4355; <a href="http://www.culture.ee" target="_blank">www.culture.ee</a>).</p>
<p>In the rest of the country, Tartu has a thriving bar and caf&eacute; scene, while the seaside resort of P&auml;rnu gets going during the summer months with thousands of visitors from other parts of the country descending on the town.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Estonia has a long history of producing high-quality handicrafts including hand-knitted jumpers, carved wooden items and embroidered Muhu slippers, which are some of the best things to buy. This is not a place to purchase run-of-the-mill items and electronics as they tend to be more expensive than in western Europe.</p>
<p>In Tallinn, you can also find regional souvenirs and the prices are pretty standard throughout the country.</p><p>Mon-Fri 1000-1800; some on Sat 1000-1700; department stores: daily 1000-2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of hotels available in Tallinn. Outside Tallinn, Estonia enjoys an adequate range of acceptable accommodation, left over from the pre-independence days or built by Estonian entrepreneurs, including large hotels and smaller pension-type establishments.</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of hotels available in Tallinn. Outside Tallinn, Estonia enjoys an adequate range of acceptable accommodation, left over from the pre-independence days or built by Estonian entrepreneurs, including large hotels and smaller pension-type establishments.</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of hotels available in Tallinn. Outside Tallinn, Estonia enjoys an adequate range of acceptable accommodation, left over from the pre-independence days or built by Estonian entrepreneurs, including large hotels and smaller pension-type establishments.</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;For European visitors who are taken ill or have an accident, free or reduced-cost treatment is available - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). The EHIC gives access to state-provided medical treatment only. For emergency assistance telephone 112.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is safe to drink but due to its high mineral content some may dislike the taste. Bottled water is widely available. There are no safety risks pertaining to Estonian food but it pays to use common sense and pay attention to the hygiene and cleanliness of any establishment where you may be considering dining.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;There is a risk of tick-borne encephalitis (TBE) in Estonia, particularly in the province of L&amp;auml;&amp;auml;neEesti from early spring to late autumn. Visitors who plan to hike in the forests should wear protective clothing to protect from ticks and mosquitoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At night or when visibility is poor, pedestrians in Estonia are required to wear reflectors on clothing in a bid to prevent traffic accidents. These are available at most supermarkets; failure to adhere to the rule could result in &amp;euro;400 fine.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Independence Day :
							24 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Whit Sunday (Pentecost) :
							20 May </p><p>V̵idup :
							23 June </p><p>Jaanip :
							24 June </p><p>Restoration of Independence Day :
							20 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Travellers from EU countries to Estonia</strong><br />
Estonia is within the European Union and in general, EU countries do not impose a limit provided that the goods you carry are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:<br />
&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% volume, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p><strong>Travellers from non-EU countries to Estonia</strong><br />
Travellers from non-EU countries visiting Estonia can bring the following products into the country:<br />
&bull; 200 cigarettes (if travelled by air, otherwise 40 cigarettes) or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco (if travelled by air, otherwise 50g of tobacco) or 20ml of tobacco liquid or 120g of solid tobacco substitute. You're allowed to bring these tobacco products on the first and second entry into Estonia within a calendar month.<br />
&bull; Up to 4L of wine (except sparkling wine and liqueur wine), 16L of beer, plus 2L of alcoholic beverages with alcohol content up to 22% (including sparkling wine and liqueur wine) or 1L of strong alcoholic beverages (22% or more alcohol content). You're allowed to bring the alcoholic beverages on your first entry in each calendar month.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is not permitted to import meat or milk products into Estonia from outside the EU member states. Contact the Estonian Tax and Customs Board (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.customs.ee">www.emta.ee</a>) for further information.</p>
<p>Also prohibited are unlicensed firearms and ammunition, dangerous weapons, pirated goods, counterfeit goods, narcotics, pornographic materials featuring children, and alien species which may pose an ecological threat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited exports include unlicensed firearms and ammunition, dangerous weapons, pirated goods, narcotics, pornographic materials featuring children, and alien species which may pose an ecological threat.</p>
<p>You must obtain a licence to export cultural artefacts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol &euro;) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;5 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.  Estonia joined the eurozone on 1 January 2011, with the Euro replacing the Kroon, which is removed from circulation on 14 January 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major currencies can be exchanged at banks and bureaux de change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are widely accepted. Most banks will give cash advances on credit cards with a passport. There are ATMs in nearly all towns.</p><p>There are ATMs in nearly all towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are no longer popular.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1600; hours may vary. Although banks are usually closed on Saturdays, bureaux de change are open 0900-1500, and some open on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Estonia is a member of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-term Schengen visa: &euro;60.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visas are valid for three months within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). Visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The normal processing time is up to 15 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EU nationals wishing to stay longer than three months must apply for a residence permit; contact the Police and Border Guard (<a href="http://www.politsei.ee">www.politsei.ee</a>) for details.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Schengen visa holders can only extend their visas in exceptional circumstances, such as <em>force majeure</em> or for humanitarian reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet from another EU country, your animal must have a microchip, rabies vaccination certificate and pet passport. Pets from non-EU countries must have a microchip or tattoo, rabies vaccination certificate and veterinary certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[58.694014]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[25.252958]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>45,228 sq km (17,462 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,251,171 (UN estimate 2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>30 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tallinn.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Estonia is the most northerly of the three Baltic Republics and is bordered to the north and west by the Baltic Sea, to the east by the Russian Federation and to the south by Latvia. The country is one of great scenic beauty with many forests, more than 1,400 lakes and 1,500 islands. Smaller than Lithuania and Latvia, it has nevertheless the longest coastline of all the Baltic States.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Estonia is one of the least religious countries in the world, with only 14% of the population declaring religion to be an important part of their daily life.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Estonians are generally quite reserved and polite. A hand shake is the customary greeting. Normal courtesies should be observed. The Estonians are proud of their culture and their national heritage, and visitors should take care to respect this.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister J&uuml;ri Ratas since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Kersti Kaljulaid since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Vikings passed through the Baltic in the ninth century and over the next few centuries, Denmark, Germany, Russia, Sweden and Poland all fought to control Estonia. In the 13th century, Estonia was ruled by the Livonia Order, an autonomous branch of the Teutonic Order but became a part of Sweden after the Livonian War of 1558-1583. It remained in the Swedish hand until 1710 when Sweden ceded Estonia to Russia following the Great Northern War of 1700-1721.</p>
<p>The Russian period from 1750 to 1840 was particularly noted for the Estophile Enlightenment Period where German elites and other non-Estonians became interested in Estonian language, literature and culture. Following the Russian revolutions of 1917 and World War I (1914-1918), Estonia attained its independence in 1918. The new Soviet government at first refused to recognise Estonian independence, but soon gave way. In 1940, under the Nazi-Soviet Pack of 1939, the Soviet Union occupied Estonia once again but barely 12 months later, Estonia was conquered by Nazi Germany.</p>
<p>In 1944 the Red Army retook the country, after which Estonia was constituted as one of the 15 Soviet Socialist Republics.</p>
<p>Four decades passed before the advent of Mikhail Gorbachev who, as Communist Party General Secretary, offered the prospect of change for the Baltic States. A key part of the economic reform programme was the devolution of power to the republics and Estonia led the way among the Baltic states. Measures to establish an Estonian currency and to restore Estonian as the official language quickly followed.</p>
<p>In 1990, the Estonian Communist Party voted in favour of full independence from the Soviet Union. Rapid international recognition of Estonia as a sovereign state, followed by admission to the United Nations, completed the transition to full nationhood in 1991. In 2004, Estonia joined NATO and the EU.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; The medieval old town of Tallinn is on the UNESCO World Heritage List.</p>
<p>&bull; The sport of Kiiking was invented in Estonia in 1996 by Ado Kosk. It involves a swing on which the rider attempts to go round 360 degrees.</p>
<p>&bull; The epic folk poem <em>Kalevipoeg</em>, composed from oral legends by Friedrich Reinhold Kreutzwald around 1853, is the national story of Estonia. Kreutzwald is considered the father of Estonian literature.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Estonia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+372 667 4700</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-tallinn</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+372 667 4700</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Wismari 6<br/>Tallinn<br/>10136<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Estonia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7589 3428 / +44 20 7838 5388 (passport &amp; visa)</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://london.mfa.ee</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7589 3428 / +44 20 7838 5388 (passport &amp; visa)</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Consular hours: Mon &amp;amp; Wed 1000-1300, Thu 1300-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>44 Queen's Gate Terrace<br/>London<br/>SW7 5PJ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Estonian Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 588 0101</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.estemb.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 588 0101</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2131 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From reluctant Soviet state to one of the European Union's brightest young stars, Estonia has undergone something of a transformation in recent decades &ndash; and finally the world has woken up to its many charms.</p>
<p>The smallest and arguably most scenic of the three Baltic states (which also includes Latvia and Lithuania), Estonia is a wildly beautiful land of pristine forests, biodiverse wetlands and remote offshore islands; its natural assets offer a spectacular contrast to the brooding, gothic aesthetic of its medieval capital, Tallinn.</p>
<p>In Tallinn, the cobbled streets are peppered with historic churches, monuments and cosy caf&eacute;s, not to mention a burgeoning restaurant scene that pays homage to the country's Baltic and Nordic heritage. The nightlife is pretty lively too, which has made it a popular destination for stag parties, although not everybody has welcomed that.</p>
<p>Most adventure travellers escape the city and make for the primeval forests and lakes of rural Estonia. And who can blame them? These areas offer landscapes and ecosystems which have, for the most part, been lost in much of Europe. More than 1,000 lakes shimmer in the Estonian countryside, while bogs and swamplands cover an astounding one-fifth of the country. These habitats are a haven for birds and birdwatchers.</p>
<p>Estonia's natural wonders are on impressive display in its national parks; most notably, Soomaa, in the heart of the country, and Lahemaa, on the northern coast, which rewards visitors with challenging hikes and impressive views of the Baltic Klint, a 1,200km-long (745 mile) ridge of limestone cliffs that stretches from Sweden to Russia. Elusive wolves, bears and lynxes can also be spotted in these parts.</p>
<p>Estonia's history, like that of its Baltic neighbours, has been almost singly devoted to maintaining independence from its powerful neighbours, most notably Russia. Annexed by Stalin in 1944, Estonia never entirely became the Soviet republic it might have done, retaining its language and culture far more strongly than other members of the USSR. This plucky, independent spirit endures in Estonia today.</p><p>From reluctant Soviet state to one of the European Union's brightest young stars, Estonia has undergone something of a transformation in recent decades &ndash; and finally the world has woken up to its many charms.&nbsp;The smallest and arguably most scenic of the three Baltic states (which also includes Latvia and Lithuania), Estonia is a wildly beautiful land of pristine forests, biodiverse wetlands and remote offshore islands; natural assets that offer a spectacular contrast to the brooding, gothic aesthetic of its medieval capital, Tallinn.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
