<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Eswatini (Swaziland)" ColCode="swz" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sz" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Eswatini (Swaziland)]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Due to variations in altitude, the weather can be changeable. In the Highveld region, temperatures are relatively mild, ranging from between 5&deg;C (41&deg;F) and 21&deg;C (70&deg;F) in the winter, and between 13&deg;C (55&deg;F) and 25&deg;C (77&deg;F) in the summer. The Lowveld has a warmer, drier climate, with average temperatures ranging from 8&deg;C (46&deg;F) to 27&deg;C (81&deg;F) in the winter, and from 18&deg;C (64&deg;F) to 32&deg;C (90&deg;F) in the summer.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Choosing when to visit Eswatini (Swaziland) is a matter of personal preference. The wet summer season, between October and March, can be unbearable in the Lowveld but pleasant in the Highveld. Hikers should aim for an early start during the summer, as the midday heat can get intense and afternoon electrical storms are also quite common. Heavy rains can also have a negative impact on activities such as white-water rafting and caving. The dry winter season, between June and August, is usually mild in the Lowveld but can get quite cold in the Highveld. In the dry season, there is a lack of lush vegetation which makes it easier to see the wildlife. However, since the wildlife reserves throughout the country are so small, it&rsquo;s always fairly easy to see game all year round. Visit during the rainy season, though, if you want to witness the variety of birds Eswatini (Swaziland) has to offer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bring light clothing, such as linens, and a jacket for the evenings. Waterproofs are rarely needed unless you're doing a lot of walking between October and March. Since hiking is the best way to see the beautiful landscape, hiking boots or sturdy trainers are a must.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hiring a car can be one of the easiest ways to explore the country. The road system is largely well developed, although there is little street lighting.  The main road from east to west is the MR3.  Some roads are winding and roads can be rough in the bush.&nbsp;</p>l<p>The country is served by an extensive bus network, which is privately owned. Buses are regular and follow a timetable, but many timetables are not openly displayed at bus stops &ndash; when in doubt, just ask a local. Tickets can be bought on board.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><p>Kombi taxis (small minibuses) run on fixed routes, which are usually the same as the bus routes. Kombis are faster, but more expensive than buses, and they do not follow a fixed timetable &ndash; once they&rsquo;re full of passengers, they head off to their next destination. You can pick up a kombi taxi either at a designated stop or by flagging one down along the route.</p><p>A national licence in English or with an English translation is permitted, as are International Driving Permits.</p><p>The maximum speed limit is 120kph (75mph) on motorways, 80kph (50mph) on the open road, and 60kph (37mph) in built-up areas.</p><p>There are a number of international car hire companies in Eswatini (Swaziland). You may need a 4-wheel drive vehicle if travelling to more remote areas.</p><p>The maximum speed limit is 120kph (75mph) on motorways, 80kph (50mph) on the open road, and 60kph (37mph) in built-up areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Swaziland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">siteki</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Swaziland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">piggs_peak</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Swaziland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">nhlangano</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Swaziland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">manzini</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Swaziland Airlink (<a href="http://www.flyswaziland.com/" target="_blank">www.flyswaziland.com</a>) is the national airline. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), South African Airways (<a href="http://www.flysaa.com" target="_blank">www.flysaa.com</a>) and Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) fly from the UK to Johannesburg, from where it's less than an hour's flight to King Mswati III International Airport. South African Airways also operates direct flights to Johannesburg from the USA.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 14 hours 55 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 17 hours 40 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>E100</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Matsapha Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 5km (3 miles) northwest of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If arriving by road, you need to pay a R50 on entry. For trucks and company cars, the fee is R80. If bringing a hire car, you must show a letter from the car hire company, along with your passport and driving licence. Note that some of the border crossings close at 1600 (Josefsdal, Waverley and Bothashoop) or 1800 (Mananga, Nerston, Emahlathini and Onverwacht).</p>
<p>TransMagnific (<a href="http://www.goswaziland.co.sz" target="_blank">www.goswaziland.co.sz</a>) and Sky World Travel and Tours (<a href="http://www.skyworld.co.sz" target="_blank">www.skyworld.co.sz</a>) run luxury minibuses run between Johannesburg and Manzini.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>A landline network covers most of the country, but most people rely on mobile phones. Outgoing international calls must go through the international operator.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only mobile network available throughout Eswatini (Swaziland) is MTN. Mobile coverage is good, with 90% of the population having access, but it can be patchy in extremely rural areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet facilities can be found in the main towns like Mbabane and Manzini. Not all hotels or lodges offer Wi-Fi services, so it&rsquo;s best to check before booking.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eswatini (Swaziland) is an absolute monarchy, meaning that complete freedom of the press does not exist in the same way as it does in democratic societies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post offices can be found in all towns. Airmail to Europe can be unreliable, taking anywhere from two weeks to two months to arrive.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1300 and 1400-1600, Sat 0800-1100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Ezulwini Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Also known as &ldquo;The Valley of Heaven&rdquo;, the Ezulwini Valley boasts lush and magnificent countryside - some of the finest that southern Africa has to offer. Neighbouring Malkerns Valley is equally fertile and verdant, and is well known for its scenic drive.</p>]]><p><b>Hot mineral springs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The aptly named Cuddle Puddle is one of the many hot mineral springs that can be found throughout Eswatini (Swaziland). This magnesium-rich pool has waters that remain at a constant 42&deg;C (108&deg;F) &ndash; perfect for soaking those weary bones &ndash; and can be found in the Ezulwini Valley.</p>]]><p><b>Lobamba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lobamba, located southeast of Mbabane, is one of the main cultural hotspots in Eswatini (Swaziland). It is here that the <em>Incwala</em> (ritual of Kingship) and <em>Umhlanga</em> (Reed Dance) celebrations take place. Swazi festivals are loud and colourful, drawing the nation together to share in traditional dancing, singing and culinary delights. During the <em>Incwala</em>, the king gives his people permission to eat the first crops of the season (December/January), while the spectacular <em>Umhlanga</em> (Reed Dance) sees maidens present reeds to the Queen Mother and takes place in August/September.</p>
<p>Lobamba is also home to The National Museum, Somhlolo National Stadium and King Sobhuza II Memorial Park &ndash; all are much visited tourist attractions. As the legislative capital city of Eswatini (Swaziland), you can also find the Houses of Parliament and the royal Embo State Palace in Lobamba.</p>]]><p><b>Malolotja Nature Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover true African wilderness at the rugged Malolotja Nature Reserve. There are hiking trails galore, ranging from after-lunch strolls to week-long treks, and 280 species of bird have been recorded here.</p>]]><p><b>Malolotsha Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike the magnificent countryside. There are plenty of options including the ascent to Malolotsha Falls at Piggs Peak; Sibebe Mountain, a huge granite outcrop that provides a scenic spot for a picnic; and the climb up Emlembe, Swaziland's highest peak.</p>]]><p><b>Manzini market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Poke around the handicraft stalls amidst the hustle and bustle of Manzini's vibrant market. This is probably Eswatini&rsquo;s (Swaziland's) best place for crafts at bargain prices, so come prepared to negotiate.</p>]]><p><b>Mlawula Nature Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the best things about Mlawula Nature Reserve is that you can explore by foot and without a guide. There are ten walking trails available, ranging from a short 1.5km (0.9miles) walk to a full-day hike. As this is the place where the Lubombo Mountains meet with the surrounding Lowveld, you'll experience the impressive flora and fauna it has to offer, which includes over 350 species of bird.</p>]]><p><b>Mlilwane Wildlife Sanctuary</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go on a bike tour, stopping to photograph the zebra and impala along the way, or take part in a guided game walk where you can learn more about the animals and plants that make Mlilwane their home. For something extra special, head out on a horse-riding safari. Keep your eyes peeled for eagles, hoopoe, blesbuck, kudu and gnu – many animals let you get a lot closer to them when you're on the back of a horse. Mlilwane is also ideal for hiking, with the most popular trail being the slightly arduous ascent to Execution Rock for fabulous views of the plains.</p>]]><p><b>Ngwenya Glass Factory</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Admire the exquisite detail on the expertly made products at the Ngwenya Glass Factory (<a href="https://ngwenyaglass.co.sz/">ngwenyaglass.co.sz</a>). Many are in the shape of African animals and birds, making them an ideal souvenir of your trip. Each item is made from 100% recycled glass and the forge is open to the public, so you can watch the skilled glassmakers create their elaborate shapes &ndash; if you can handle the heat!</p>]]><p><b>Swazi Candles Centre </b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Swazi Candles Centre (<a href="http://www.swazicandles.com/">www.swazicandles.com</a>), located in the Malkerns Valley, showcases a selection of quality, handcrafted candles. You can see the candles being made in the lively workshop, and you can even have a go at making one yourself. Buy a few candles to remember your trip by before taking a wander around some of the other artisan shops at the centre, all of which are community-led. The centre also offers carved wooden souvenirs, batik clothing and African jewellery.</p>]]><p><b>Swazi festivals</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Attend colourful Swazi festivals full of African dancing and singing that draw the nation together. During the Incwala, the king gives his people permission to eat the first crops of the season (December/January). Or in August/ September, see the Umhlanga (Reed Dance).</p>]]><p><b>White-water rafting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hurtle down the Great Usutu River on a white-water rafting trip (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.swazitrails.co.sz/">www.swazitrails.co.sz</a>). The rapids through Bulungu Gorge provide an exhilarating ride and you'll also need to negotiate a 10m (33ft) waterfall. Once you&rsquo;re away from the rapids, you can float lazily down the river &ndash; but keep your eyes peeled for the 'flat dogs' (crocodiles) in the water!</p>]]><p><b>Wildlife drive</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go game-spotting on a wildlife drive, organised through Big Game Parks (<a target="_blank" href="https://biggameparks.org">https://biggameparks.org</a>). Mkhaya Game Reserve is a top private reserve where you may spot the elusive black rhino; and in Hlane Royal National Park look out for lion, elephant and plenty of antelope.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2.7 billion (2007).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Soft drink concentrates, sugar, pulp, canned fruits and cotton yarn.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Chemicals, clothing, food, machinery and motor vehicles.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>South <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/africa">Africa</a>, EU and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The economy is dominated by and closely linked with that of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa">South Africa</a>, and the country is a member of the Southern African Customs Union (through which the government receives around half its total revenue).<br />
<br />
Agriculture is by far the largest part of the economy, employing over 75% of the working population. The industrial sector is mainly concerned with processing agricultural products, largely food and wood products including paper, and also the production of textiles and metal goods. The country's mining industry produces coal, of which there are extensive reserves, and diamonds.<br />
<br />
Unemployment remains at an estimated 40% (2006); GDP growth rate is 1.6% (2007); and inflation is running at about 6% (2007).<br />
The principal facilities are at the Royal Swazi Convention Centre in the Ezulwini Valley, which has seating for up to 600 people. Several hotels also have facilities for smaller numbers, with back-up services. The tourist office (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>) can supply information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits are generally expected for business. Appointments are necessary and business cards are exchanged. English is widely spoken in business circles.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1300 and 1400-1645.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Swaziland Industrial Development Co (SIDC)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (40) 44010
					Website:http://www.sidc.co.sz/
					Address: Mdada and Lalufadlana Streets,PO Box 866,5th Floor,Dhlan'ubeka House,Mbabane,]]><b>The Federation of Swaziland Employers and Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (40) 40768
					Website:http://www.business-swaziland.com/
					Address: Malagwane Hill,Emafini Business Center,Mbabane,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Restaurants are found mainly in Mbabane and Manzini, as well as in tourist areas such as the Ezulwini Valley. Portuguese cuisine &ndash; an influence from nearby Mozambique &ndash; is popular and features fresh seafood including excellent prawns. Other international food available includes Thai, Chinese, Indian, Italian and French. African staples, such as stew and pap, can be sampled in more remote locations and in traditional homesteads and guesthouses.</p>
<p>The time of year and the region of the country will largely determine the ingredients used in local cooking, although staple foods like sorghum and maize are common across the country. Many Swazis are subsistence farmers, supplementing their diet with food bought from local markets including seafood and freshwater produce. There are no formal licensing hours and traditional Swazi beer &ndash; tjwla &ndash; can be tasted in rural areas. But approach with caution as it packs a punch!</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Tahragout: </strong>Traditional Swazi meat stew, usually made with goat that&rsquo;s been cooked slowly with a variety of vegetables, kawakawa (bush basil) and dried horopito (pepperwood leaves).</p>
<p><strong>Umncweba: </strong>Dried meat similar to South African biltong.</p>
<p><strong>Shishwala:</strong> Hearty porridge served with meat or vegetables.</p>
<p><strong>Sidlwadlwa: </strong>Meat stew with cabbage and peanuts.</p>
<p><strong>Siphuphe semabhontjisi: </strong>Thick porridge made from mashed beans.</p>
<p><strong>Incwancwa:</strong> Sour porridge made with fermented cornmeal.</p>
<p><strong>Siphuphesetindlubu: </strong>Thick porridge of ground nuts.</p>
<p><strong>Umbidvo wetintsanga: </strong>Boiled pumpkin leaves with ground nuts.</p>
<p><strong>Roasted corn on the cob: </strong>Sold on market stalls when in season.</p>
<p><strong>Slaai: </strong>Refreshing salad made from avocado marinated in lemon juice, ginger and salt, and topped with peanuts.</p>
<p><strong>Tinkhobe: </strong>Whole boiled maize.</p>
<p><strong>Sidvudvu: </strong>Porridge made from sweet pumpkin mixed with cornmeal.</p>
<p><strong>Emasietinkhobetemmbila:</strong> Ground corn and sour milk.</p>
<p><strong>Sibebe: </strong>A local lager brewed in Matsapha.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>A tip of 10 to 15% of the bill is customary in restaurants and hotels.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol can be drunk at any age, but can only be bought by over 18s.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mbabane and Manzini are cities with a lively nightlife scene, offering a number of bars and clubs with everything from local DJs to live bands and cabaret. House on Fire, in Malkerns Valley, is an outdoor performance venue that often showcases local and visiting DJs. Check out the House on Fire website (<a href="http://www.house-on-fire.com">www.house-on-fire.com</a>) to find out more about their upcoming events. The Gables and Galleria shopping mall in Ezulwini Valley is home to the country&rsquo;s only cinema. For a chance to flirt with Lady Luck, head to the casinos at the Royal Swazi, Happy Valley and Piggs Peak hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700, Sat 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eswatini (Swaziland) is home to many high-quality, luxury hotels with a range of first-class features including excellent dining, large grounds, sport and leisure facilities, and the option to participate in local activities such as horse riding and cultural excursions. There are also a number of family-run hotels, such as the Foresters Arms (<a href="https://forestersarms.co.za" rel="nofollow">forestersarms.co.za</a>) that are smaller in size and less luxurious, but provide more of a local flavour and a homely feel. Cheaper hotels are often functional and basic, offering comfortable beds but not much else.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong>The star-grading system is in use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>B&amp;Bs and guesthouses are often smaller than hotels and more simply furnished. Many provide outstanding views of the surrounding area, well-manicured gardens and large pools. Generally, the hospitality and quality of food at these establishments are at a high standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eswatini (Swaziland) is home to many high-quality, luxury hotels with a range of first-class features including excellent dining, large grounds, sport and leisure facilities, and the option to participate in local activities such as horse riding and cultural excursions. There are also a number of family-run hotels, such as the Foresters Arms (<a href="https://forestersarms.co.za" rel="nofollow">forestersarms.co.za</a>) that are smaller in size and less luxurious, but provide more of a local flavour and a homely feel. Cheaper hotels are often functional and basic, offering comfortable beds but not much else.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong>The star-grading system is in use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eswatini (Swaziland) is home to many high-quality, luxury hotels with a range of first-class features including excellent dining, large grounds, sport and leisure facilities, and the option to participate in local activities such as horse riding and cultural excursions. There are also a number of family-run hotels, such as the Foresters Arms (<a href="https://forestersarms.co.za" rel="nofollow">forestersarms.co.za</a>) that are smaller in size and less luxurious, but provide more of a local flavour and a homely feel. Cheaper hotels are often functional and basic, offering comfortable beds but not much else.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong>The star-grading system is in use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Eswatini (Swaziland) has extensive medical facilities, with hospitals and clinics available in all major towns. Since Government hospitals are often stretched to the limit &amp;ndash; mostly due to the HIV/AIDS epidemic &amp;ndash; you are more likely to receive reliable care at private facilities such as the Mbabame Clinic. Dentists and general practitioners are widely available, and all main towns have pharmacies. Up to date health insurance is recommended. Personal medications may be brought into the country, but a doctor's note is advisable in case of questioning by authorities.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water is safe to drink in all main towns, but should be avoided in more rural communities. Bottled water is widely available throughout the country. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption; exercise caution if you are unsure of the milk&amp;rsquo;s origin. Only eat meat and fish that has been cooked well and is served hot. Vegetables should be cooked thoroughly and fruit should be peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Swimming pools that are well chlorinated and maintained are safe.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>King Mswati III's Birthday :
							19 April </p><p>National Flag Day :
							25 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>King Father's Birthday :
							22 July </p><p>Somhlolo Day (Independence Day) :
							06 September </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Eswatini (Swaziland) without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes and 20 cigars and 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine and 1L of spirits.<br />
&bull; 50ml of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of E5,000.</p>
<p>These allowances only apply to travellers arriving from countries other than <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/botswana">Botswana</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lesotho">Lesotho</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/namibia">Namibia</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa">South Africa</a>. Travellers coming from these countries may import goods up to the value of E25,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlicensed arms and ammunition, narcotics, unlicensed medicines and pornography. There are also restrictions on meat and dairy products, as well as vegetables, fruits and plants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lilangeni (SZL; symbol E) = 100 cents. The plural of Lilangeni is Emalangeni. Notes are in denominations of E200, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of E5, 2 and 1, and 100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.<br />
<br />
The South African Rand is also accepted as legal tender (E1 = 1 Rand) so if coming from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa">South Africa</a>, there's no need to change money.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are advised to exchange Emalangeni back into their own currency (or into South African Rand) before leaving Eswatini (Swaziland).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard and Visa are accepted at hotels and upmarket shops and restaurants.</p><p>Only a few ATMs accept international credit/debit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted. Several banks will exchange travellers cheques, but to avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take them in Euros, Pounds Sterling or US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1430, Sat 0830-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Eswatini (Swaziland), a passport valid for at least three months upon entry, and with at least two blank pages, is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: E80; multiple-entry visa: E300 (three months), E700 (six months), E1,000 (nine months) or E1,300 (12 months).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: three months; multiple-entry visa: three to 12 months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you plan to stay longer than 60 days, you must apply for a Temporary Residence Permit (TRP).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you receive a 30-day stamp on arrival, you can apply for a 30-day extension at the Ministry of Home Affairs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-26.564963]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[31.501005]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>17,364 sq km (6,704 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,343,000 (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>78 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mbabane.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Absolute monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eswatini (Swaziland) is surrounded to the north, west and south by the Mpumalanga province of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa">South Africa</a> and to the east by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mozambique">Mozambique</a>. There are four main topographical regions: the Highveld Inkangala &ndash; a wide ribbon of partly reforested, rugged country including the Usutu pine forest; the Peak Timbers in the northwest; the Middleveld, which rolls down from the Highveld through hills and fertile valleys; and the Lowveld, or bush country, with hills rising from 170 to 360m (560 to 1,180ft).</p>
<p>The Lubombo plateau is an escarpment along the eastern fringe of the Lowveld, comprising of mainly cattle country and mixed farmland. Eswatini&rsquo;s (Swaziland's) four major rivers are the Komati, Usutu, Mbuluzi and Ngwavuma.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>82% Zionist (mix of Christianity and traditional beliefs).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional ways of life are still upheld and Swazi culture, in the form of music, dance, poetry and craftsmanship, plays an important part in daily life. Casual wear is standard, although formal wear is customary at casinos and sophisticated hotels. Visitors wishing to camp near villages should first inform the local chief. <br />
<br />
<strong>Photography: </strong>Permission to photograph individuals should always be sought. In some cases, a gratuity fee may be required, especially if the subject has gone to some effort - for example, by wearing traditional regalia. It is prohibited to photograph the royal palace, the royal family, uniformed police, army personnel, army vehicles or aircraft and bank buildings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. South African-style plugs with two circular metal pins above a large circular grounding pin are in use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Mandvulo Ambrose Dlamini since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Mswati III since 1986.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following the Boer War of 1899-1902, Eswatini (Swaziland) became a British Protectorate in 1907 and later became independent in September 1968. After independence, the British refused to hand over Swazi territory to South Africa, and instead administered Eswatini (Swaziland) as a 'High Commission Territory' &ndash; one of three established by a 1910 Act of Parliament.</p>
<p>Since independence, the country's domestic politics have suffered constant turbulence. Between 1973 and 1978, the constitution was suspended and a state of emergency imposed at the instigation of the king. Political parties, public gatherings and freedom of speech were all outlawed. In 1978, a new constitution concentrated political power in the hands of the monarch, who appointed a prime minister and cabinet; the state of emergency remained in force, however. An elected parliament of 30 members, the <i>Libandla</i>, was established, although its functions were restricted to conveying advice to the king and his principal advisory body, the <i>Liqoqo</i> (Supreme Council of State).</p>
<p>The current monarch, King Mswati III, was crowned in April 1986. Political stability continued to prove elusive during the late-1980s &ndash; the Mswati monarchy was repeatedly threatened by plots organised by dissident members of the royal family and disaffected politicians but all were stifled with apparent ease. The focus of opposition has been the People's United Democratic Movement (PUDEMO), which operated largely clandestinely until February 1992, when it declared itself a legal opposition party &ndash; in contravention of the government ban on political association &ndash; and demanded a constitutional referendum. Although steady pressure has been exerted against the king from both inside and outside the country, he remains impervious to any entreaties and continues to be one of the world's few absolute monarchs. The current premier, who took up the post in 2008, is Barnabas Sibusiso Dlamini.</p>
<p>Eswatini&rsquo;s (Swaziland's) foreign relations are dominated by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa">South Africa</a>. In general, foreign relations have undergone a steady improvement since 1994 and the advent of majority rule in South Africa. However, there are a number of territorial disputes in which Eswatini (Swaziland) claims tracts of land in the KwaZulu-Natal and Mpumalanga provinces.</p>
<p>Eswatini (Swaziland) is a poor country and has suffered from several serious food shortages. Moreover, according to a January 2003 World Health Organisation report, the country has the world's highest per capita incidence of HIV/AIDS, with an estimated 40% of the adult population afflicted. Average life expectancy was 35 years and falling. However, due to the implementation of better HIV/AIDS awareness, and increased access to medication and condoms, the average life expectancy has increased to 49 years and the prevalence of HIV/AIDS has decreased to around 27% in 2016 - although it still holds the title of the country with the highest prevalence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Kingdom of Eswatini (Swaziland) in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 (0) 202 234 5002.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.sz/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=453&amp;Itemid=270</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 (0) 202 234 5002.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1712 New Hampshire Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Kingdom of Eswatini (Swaziland) High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 (0)20 7630 6611.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.sz/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=456&amp;Itemid=270</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 (0)20 7630 6611.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1630 (by appointment only).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Westminster<br/>20 Buckingham Gate<br/>London<br/>SW1E 6LS<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On 19 April 2018, King Mswati III renamed Swaziland to Eswatini, meaning &ldquo;Land of the Swazis&rdquo;.</p>
<p>With traditional customs still central to everyday life, the Kingdom of Eswatini (Swaziland) offers an unparalleled insight into Africa&rsquo;s tribal societies in a setting that is safe and welcoming to visitors. Combine this with a varied landscape and untamed wildlife, and you have a nation ripe for exploration.</p>
<p>Eswatini (Swaziland) holds the accolade as the only absolute monarchy in Africa (and one of only a handful left in the world). The monarch plays a central role in political and cultural life, with the country&rsquo;s most important annual events, such as Independence Day, closely linked with the royal household.</p>
<p>Though smaller events involving traditional dress and celebrations can be found across the country at almost any time of year, it is the set piece ceremonies that draw the largest number of participants. In fact, the Umhlanga (Reed Dance) festival is one of Africa&rsquo;s biggest cultural events. Thousands of unmarried Swazi women travel to the round, mud-brick buildings of the royal compound at Ludzidzini, where they pay tribute to the Queen Mother with reeds, song and dance.</p>
<p>The Incwala, or Kingship Ritual, takes place during the summer solstice and is a rare survivor of what was once common across southern Africa. The highlight of the festival is the spectacular sight of Swazi men in full battle regalia, the likes of which you will not have seen outside a Hollywood blockbuster.</p>
<p>Eswatini (Swaziland) also hosts a great diversity of landscape, ranging from river valleys and cool mountainous Highveld in the west, and hotter and dryer Lowveld in the east. A typical African landscape of acacia-dotted grasslands, the Lowveld is where the country&rsquo;s most iconic wildlife can be viewed. Mkhaya Game Reserve, one of 17 protected areas, is considered one of the very best places in Africa to witness rhino in their natural habitat.</p>
<p>Friendly, safe and spirited, the country&rsquo;s distinct and ever-present cultural traditions, together with its landscapes and wildlife, make this small land-locked country a unique and enticing destination.</p><p>On 19 April 2018, King Mswati III renamed Swaziland to Eswatini, meaning &ldquo;Land of the Swazis&rdquo;.</p>
<p>With traditional customs still central to everyday life, the Kingdom of Eswatini (Swaziland) offers an unparalleled insight into Africa&rsquo;s tribal societies in a setting that is safe and welcoming to visitors. Combine this with a varied landscape and untamed wildlife, and you have a nation ripe for exploration.</p>
<p>Eswatini (Swaziland) holds the accolade as the only absolute monarchy in Africa (and one of only a handful left in the world). The monarch plays a central role in political and cultural life, with the country&rsquo;s most important annual events, such as Independence Day, closely linked with the royal household.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
