<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Ethiopia" ColCode="eth" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="et" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Ethiopia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ethiopia is an ecologically diverse country; you can therefore expect several climate zones ranging from tropical savanna in the west to warm desert climate in the east. Most of the country is highland with many of its tourist destinations like Lalibela and Gondar are at an elevation above 2,000m (6,561ft). These places enjoy a considerably cooler climate year-round.</p>
<p>Generally, the best time to visit Ethiopia is between November and February when clear, sunny days bring regular average temperatures of 25&deg;C (77&deg;F). This period is considered the dry season as rainfall is at its lowest. This is also a prime time for bird watching. If you're heading to the countryside, the period between September to October is an excellent time to visit as the landscapes are lushly pretty after all the rain.</p>
<p><strong>The best time to visit Addis Ababa, Aksum, Lalibela and Gondar</strong></p>
<p>The best time to visit Addis Ababa, Aksum, Lalibela and Gondar is from November to April.<br />
The rainy season (July and August) brings soaring temperatures and humid conditions to most places in Ethiopia, including Addis Ababa, Aksum, Lalibela and Gondar. July is the wettest month for Gondar and Aksum, while August is the wettest month for Addis Ababa and Lalibela.<br />
March, April, May, June, September and October are considered the shoulder months. It's typically cheaper to travel during these months, but you may get a short burst of rain every now and then.<br />
Visitors may also want to coincide your travel with colourful festivals. September 11 is Ethiopian New Year while September 27 is Meskel, which marks the discovery of the True Cross by the Roman Empress Helena. The biggest celebration takes place in Addis Ababa's Meskel Square.<br />
Other big days include Gena or Ledet celebrated on January 7, this is considered the Ethiopian Christmas when families gather to enjoy doro wat (chicken stew) with injera. Timkat, the Ethiopian Orthodox equivalent to Epiphany, is celebrated on January 19. The best place to see this festival is Gondar where the Fasil's Pool is filled with water for a re-enactment of the first baptism.</p>
<p><strong>The best time to visit the Lower Omo Valley</strong></p>
<p>The best time to visit the Lower Omo Valley is from January to April. The weather is dry but hot (particularly in areas around Turmi) and there are many traditional ceremonies taking place.</p>
<p><strong>The best time to visit the Danakil Depression</strong></p>
<p>Situated in northern Ethiopia near the border with Eritrea, the Danakil Depression sits at the juncture of three tectonic plates and is one of the hottest places on earth with temperatures regularly top 41&deg;C (106&deg;F). There really is no best time to visit this otherworldly place, although some tours may claim that temperatures are more tolerable from October to February.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Due to vast altitude differences between highland and lowland areas, if you plan to explore Ethiopia fully you should prepare for a wide range of temperature differences. Bringing clothes that can be easily layered is the obvious choice. You will also need lightweight clothing for the lowlands and medium-weight for the hill country. At least one warm sweater or pullover should be brought along to cope with dramatic temperature drops once the sun goes down.</p>
<p>Please note that many churches and monasteries (particular in Lalibela) require women to wear a headscarf and cover their arms and legs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="www.ethiopianairlines.com">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>) runs internal flights to 20 cities and towns throughout the country from its hub at Addis Ababa Bole International  Airport. Domestic destinations include the highly popular 'Historic route' &ndash; connecting the capital with the main tourist destinations of Aksum (Axum), Bahir Dar, Gonder and Lalibela.</p>
<p>Other domestic destinations include Arba Minch, Assosa, Bale Robe, Dire Dawa, Gambella, Gode, Hawassa, Humera, Jijiga, Jimma, Kabri Dar, Kombolcha, Mekelle, Semera, Shire and Shilavo.</p>
<p>It is common to see a flight serving multiple destinations within the same day so it pays to make sure that your checked luggage is tagged for the right destination.</p><p>Expect to pay a much higher price (two to three times higher) for domestic routes if you don&rsquo;t hold an Ethiopian passport, resident permit, or international tickets with Ethiopian Airlines.</p>
<p>Ethiopian Airlines has an app which you can book and pay for your tickets. The company also offers the widest payment options in comparison to other airlines in Africa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Within the sprawling capital Addis Ababa, there is a light-rail system, the first to be built in sub-Saharan Africa. The Addis Ababa light rail has two lines: the blue line runs from Menelik II Square in the north to Kality in the south, while the green line serves 22 stops from Tor Hailoch in the east to Ayat in the west. Extensions are being planned. All signs and announcements are in Amharic and English, making it easy for foreign travellers to use.</p>
<p>There is also a rail service between Addis Ababa and Djibouti City (in Djibouti) started in 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ethiopia's road network has improved substantially in the past decade thanks to an extensive road maintenance program. Almost every major road is tar-sealed. Off-roading routes, such as driving to remote hiking or rock climbing starting points, remain largely unsealed.</p>
<p>As of June 2018, the roads in the mountainous region of Lalibela are being repaved and tar-sealed.</p>r<p>The major roads leading out from Addis Ababa are tar-sealed, all-weather roads, although not all roads have street lighting. Minor roads in smaller towns may remain unpaved. Also, during the wet season, some roads in the east and south of the country may become impassable.</p><p>As Ethiopia's road network has improved, so has its inter-town public transport network. Public buses, painted yellow and red, are basic and cheap, though they can be crowded.</p>
<p>A more comfortable bus option is to choose from one of the many privately-run coach services which operate between major destinations. Coach companies include Selam Bus (<a href="https://selambus.wordpress.com/">selambus.wordpress.com</a>) and Sky Bus (<a href="http://skybusethiopia.com/site/">skybusethiopia.com</a>), among others. Be mindful that the coach journey can be long. For instance, a coach service from Addis Ababa to Gondar will take 13 hours, while flying with Ethiopian Airlines takes only an hour.</p>
<p>Nearly all buses depart from their starting point between 0500 and 0700 Eastern Africa Time and the ticketing and boarding processes can be bewildering to the uninitiated, particularly if you don't read or speak Amharic. Anyone assisting you with your luggage, including the person passing it up to the conductor's assistant on the roof, will expect a small tip.</p>
<p>As buses are not allowed to travel after dark, some long-distance journeys are split into two days with an overnight rest stop. You may not be allowed to remove your baggage from the roof of the bus during this overnight stop and so should pack essentials in a day bag to carry onboard.</p><p>Within Addis Ababa there are two types of taxis. You can hire a yellow taxi which is differentiated by its newer fleet of cars at Addis Ababa Bole International Airport or outside of major hotels. Although every yellow taxi is fitted with a meter, fares are usually negotiated first. Blue taxis, on the other hand, tend to be older cars and they aren&rsquo;t metered. It is advisable to negotiate with the driver before you travel with them.</p>
<p>Shared taxis, in a form of shared minibuses, are common in towns and between villages in the countryside. Routes are fixed and fares are inexpensive. Each shared taxi has a driver and a conductor who shouts out the route and collects the journey fees. As each route is fixed, you may need to take two or more minibuses to get across town.</p>
<p>Bajajs, similar to tuk-tuks, are common throughout the country except within the city limit of Addis Ababa. These three-wheelers can take three to five people, while some are even fitted to transport goods.</p><p>Foreign visitors are allowed to drive in Ethiopia using an International Driving Permit for three months. After that an Ethiopian licence is required.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18.</p>
<p>The speed limit is 30-50kph (19-31mph) within city limits and 100kph (62mph) outside.</p><p>There is no official breakdown service for Ethiopia. If you are having problems with your vehicle and you are in town, the best option is to ask your hotel for garage recommendations. If you break down while on the road, you should flag down the next vehicle for help.</p><p>Self-driving car hire is available within Addis Ababa. Outside of the capital, you can hire a car with a driver through a tour company. These drivers tend to know the local areas very well and can take you from one place to another effortlessly. Tips are expected.</p><p>Keen cyclists have discovered the rewards of cycling in Ethiopia. Although terrain can be tough, the stupendous views more than make up for it. Many cyclists choose to bring their own bike and hire a local driver to carry spare parts for maintenance or join a local cycling tour.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18.</p>
<p>The speed limit is 30-50kph (19-31mph) within city limits and 100kph (62mph) outside.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ethiopian towns and cities are generally safe and easy to get around by taxi or bajaj, but all fares should be negotiated beforehand. Addis Ababa has a network of fixed route blue and white minibuses that can be hailed down by passengers from anywhere along the route. This is a cheap and efficient way of exploring the capital.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to Ethiopia are served by the national airline, Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="www.ethiopianairlines.com">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>), which has regular flights to Addis Ababa from all of the major European capitals&nbsp;including Brussels, Frankfurt, London, Milan, Paris, Rome, and Stockholm. There are also routes from Chicago, Los Angeles, Newark, Toronto and Washington in North America.</p>
<p>From Asia, Ethiopian Airlines serve many destinations including Bangkok, Beijing, Hong Kong, Seoul, Shanghai and Singapore.</p>
<p>Apart from Lufthansa (<a href="www.lufthansa.com">www.lufthansa.com</a>), which has direct departures from Frankfurt, flying with any other European or North American airlines requires a stopover. Regional airlines which have direct flights to Addis Ababa include Egypt Air (<a href="www.egyptair.com">www.egyptair.com</a>) from Cairo and Kenya Airways (<a href="www.kenya-airways.com">www.kenya-airways.com</a>) from Nairobi.</p>
<p>The major airport is <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ethiopia/addis-ababa-bole-international-airport">Addis Ababa Bole International Airport</a>, which is currently undergoing a grand expansion plan.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 7 hours 35 minutes.</p>
<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/washington-dc">Washington DC</a> - 13 hours 15 minutes.</p>
<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a> - 9 hours 30 minutes.</p>
<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/beijing">Beijing</a> - 11 hours 10 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Addis Ababa Bole International Airport is Ethiopia's only international hub. It is located 6km (4 miles) from the capital Addis Ababa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$20, included in the airfare. On local flights, there is a boarding charge of 10 Birr per person.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Addis Ababa Bole International Airport is Ethiopia's only international hub. It is located 6km (4 miles) from the capital Addis Ababa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Addis Ababa Bole International Airport </b><![CDATA[http://www.addisairport.com<p>Addis Ababa Bole International Airport is located in Bole, 8km (5 miles) southeast of Addis Ababa in Ethiopia.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+251 11 665 0400</p>]]><b>Dire Dawa International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.ethiopianairports.com]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A standard gauge line between Addis Ababa and Djibouti City (in Djibouti) with passenger services started in 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ethiopia borders Sudan and South Sudan to its west, Kenya to its south, Somalia, the self-proclaimed separatist territory of Somaliland, and Djibouti to its east and Eritrea to its north.&nbsp;Check current information if you plan to travel to Ethiopia by road from Eritrea, Somalia or South Sudan as it may not be possible.</p>
<p>Driving from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kenya">Kenya</a>, the main border crossing is Moyale on the main A2 highway, 777km (483 miles) from Nairobi.</p>
<p>If crossing by land from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sudan">Sudan</a>, you can only use the Gallabat/Metema border crossing, 570km (354 miles) from Khartoum.</p>
<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/djibouti">Djibouti</a> has two border crossings with Ethiopia. The Galafi border is 162km (101 miles) from Djibouti City on the N8 and N1 highways. This route is sealed on both sides of the border and is the easiest route if you are self-driving. Another border crossing is on the N5 road via Ali Sabieh.</p>
<p>The Somaliland border crossing is at Wajale, 93km (58 miles) from the capital Hargeisa.</p><p>Visas for Ethiopia are not available at any of the land borders mentioned above so must be procured in advance from an Ethiopian Embassy or Consulate. Using a 4-wheel drive is highly recommended and before travelling, please pay attention to current government travel advisories.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>With mobile phones so widely used by locals and tourists alike, public payphones are no longer widely available in towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with many international mobile phone companies. Getting a local pay-as-you-go SIM card is highly recommended if you have an unlocked phone. A SIM card starts from 15 Birr and visitors only need a passport to register.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is available in hotels, though the coverage can be patchy and the service can be restricted by the government during school exams. Using your mobile data is a good alternative.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although there are many privately-owned TV networks and radio broadcasters as well as independently-owned newspapers in Ethiopia, the government still has a stranglehold over media within the country. The control ranges from frequent censorship to outlawing stations that are deemed as &quot;terrorist organisations&quot; by the government. Ethiopians are deeply passionate about football. Consequently, satellite services like DStv which show football matches are hugely popular. EBS is another popular privately-owned network featuring talk shows, game shows, movies and dramas.</p>
<p>Major newspapers include the privately-owned The Reporter (published in Amharic and English) and the state-owned Ethiopian Herald (in English).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail services to and from Europe take five to eight days to arrive and are reliable.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1100 and 1330-1500; Sat 0830-1100</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Addis Ababa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This high-altitude capital city, at 2,355m (7,726 ft), hides a multitude of charms. Though sprawling and chock-a-block with traffic, it is home to many fascinating museums including the Ethiopian National Museum where the star attraction is the 3.2-million-year-old Lucy, humankind's oldest ancestor. When the sun goes down, enjoy a fantastic Ethiopian meal with local music and dance at one of the many cultural restaurants scattered across town.</p>]]><p><b>Aksum (Axum)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>According to folklore, Aksum was once home to the legendary Queen of Sheba mentioned in the Old Testament. The local legend says she travelled to meet King Solomon in Jerusalem and bore him a son, King Menilik I, who was raised in Ethiopia but later travelled to Jerusalem and came back to the Kingdom of Aksum with the Ark of the Covenant. Today, the Aksum Stelae Park is the main attraction but you can also peek across the St Mary of Zion Church to see the chapel where the Ark is supposedly kept.</p>
<p>On the first seven days of each month (according to the Ethiopian calendar), there is a procession where St Mary of Zion's replica Ark is paraded through the streets with thousands of pilgrims following the Ark and chanting in unison. The procession, locally known as Mihla or Mehelela, starts at 0500 on Daro Eila (square).</p>]]><p><b>Babile</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An easy daytrip from the walled city of Harar, tracking elephants on foot is the major highlight of a visit to Babile, though the sanctuary is also home to plentiful birdlife, gazelles, and rarely-seen lions, leopards and cheetahs. Gorges give way to rocky outcrops and tree-studded grassland home to more than a quarter of Ethiopia&rsquo;s elephant population.</p>]]><p><b>Bale Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Bale Mountains offers hikers and horse riders high-altitude mountain scenery. The circuit, with a well-organised series of lodges along the way, passes through remote villages, high grasslands and dense forest, with great wildlife spotting potential.</p>]]><p><b>Danakil Depression</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Surreal and otherworldly, the Danakil Depression is one of the lowest and hottest places on Earth, coming in at 125m (410 ft) below sea-level with temperatures that regularly top 41&deg;C (106&deg;F). This geological wonderland is a magical place featuring vistas of swirling orange twisted rock, lava lakes, and fiercely traditional nomads. The star attraction is Erta Ale, an active volcano bubbling at 1,000&deg;C (1,832&deg;F).</p>]]><p><b>Gondar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Africa's own fairytale castles are a testament to the wealth and whimsy of Emperor Fasil who made Gondar his capital in the 17th century. The 7-hectare (17-acre) UNESCO World Heritage site is now a museum complex encompassing six fortified stone castles and a sunken pool where Gondar's colourful annual <em>Timkat </em>(Ethiopian Epiphany) takes place with a re-enactment of the first baptism. Entrance fee is 200 Birr per person.</p>]]><p><b>Harar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The historic walled city of Harar is a labyrinth of dusty alleyways. Once the commercial hub between Arabia and Africa, legendary tales led both explorer Richard Burton and French poet Rimbaud here. Today Harar oozes a lost-in-time ambience that enchants all who visit, while the Muslims consider it the fourth holy city of Islam. The hyena feeding ritual, which takes place every evening on its outskirts, adds to its exotic appeal.</p>]]><p><b>Konso cultural landscape</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Despite modernity's slow encroachment, the Konso people have stayed true to their cultural heritage, proudly preserving their unique maze-like village architecture and way of life. Some of the top places to visit in the region are the town of Konso itself and the villages of Buso, Dokatu, Gamole and Macheke.</p>]]><p><b>Lake Chamo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated by the Nechisar National Park, this high-altitude lake is home to a healthy population of crocodiles who like to sun themselves on the banks of the lake or glide through the water. Afternoon boat trips on the lake where you can see these massive creatures up close and personal (and maybe hippos too) are a must.</p>]]><p><b>Lake Tana</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The source of the Blue Nile, Lake Tana is one of Ethiopia's most fascinating places. Fishermen glide across the shimmering lake surface in traditional papyrus boats, while many its 37 islands are home to priestly communities and their ancient, round thatched monasteries decorated with dazzling biblical murals. The best way to explore the lake monasteries is on a boat trip - but please note that not all monasteries allow female visitors. Not far away is the impressive Blue Nile Falls, best visited in August and September after the rainy season.</p>]]><p><b>Lalibela</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This massive complex of churches, hewn out of rose-pink rock, is a feat of 12th-century ingenuity and sheer willpower. Walking into one of the churches amid the eerily-beautiful chanting of priests will be an abiding memory of Ethiopia. It is highly recommended that you hire a guide who can explain the unique features of each church and how the layout of major churches is a symbolic representation of Jerusalem. The entrance fee to the church complex is US$50 per person. Apart from the churches, there is a good trekking network around Lalibela allowing visitors a cultural insight into village life as well as the chance to see other ancient churches including the cave church Yemrehanna Kristos.</p>]]><p><b>Lower Omo Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Lower Omo Valley is home to 16 culturally distinct tribes including the Mursi, known for the lip plates worn by female tribe members, and Hamer, whose females are famed for their ornate hairstyles while the men must perform a dangerous bull-jumping ceremony as an initiation into adulthood. Market days - when people from all tribes flock to the region's towns - are a colourful and fascinating experience.</p>]]><p><b>Simien Mountains National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Trekking along the escarpment, surrounded by jagged pinnacles, with the slash of the Great Rift Valley tumbling down before you is one of the finest panoramas on the continent. This is also the home of the Gelada 'bleeding heart' baboons. Coming face-to-face with a troop of them while ambling along is almost guaranteed. Visitors who can spend a few days trekking through its grasslands and deep ravines are likely to see Walia Ibex (mountain goats with arching horns) and Ethiopian wolf, both are endemic to the Simien Mountains. Experienced trekkers may also want to tackle Ras Dashen, the highest peak in the country. Entrance fee is 90 Birr per person with extra for a guide and a ranger.</p>]]><p><b>Tigray (rock hewn churches)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Carved into the towering canyons, the remote monolithic churches and monasteries of the Tigray region offer a fascinating look into religious life that has remained largely unchanged for centuries. The scenery here is ruggedly beautiful, and some of the monasteries are so precariously positioned they are reached by free climbing or a flimsy rope. Abuna Yemata Guh, one of the finest churches in the area, requires you to climb up the wind-worn sandstone cliff barefooted. Despite its remoteness, the church attracts about 80 worshippers every Sunday attending its service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$79.74 billion (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Coffee, oilseeds, vegetables, gold and cut flowers.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, aircraft, metal products, electronics, petroleum products, vehicles, chemical and fertilizers.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, USA, India, Kuwait.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driven by healthy investments in infrastructure and manufacturing, and sustained development in the agricultural and service sectors, Ethiopia has been growing at a rate between 8% to 11% annually from 2005.</p>
<p>Despite the strong growth, challenges remain. Less than 15% of its land is arable but with 70% of the population employed in the agricultural sector, which is also subject to shifting weather patterns, soil erosion and over-grazing, there are limited options when it comes to managing drought and famine.</p>
<p>To overcome this, Ethiopia has been attracting investment from Chinese investors with flagship projects including the Light Rail System in the capital and the Addis Ababa to Djibouti Railway funded entirely by several Chinese firms. The construction of the multi-billion Grand Renaissance Dam project in the western region of Benishangul-Gumuz is currently underway. When finished, the dam promises substantial future revenues for the state by selling electricity to neighbouring countries while also providing Ethiopia with cheap electricity.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the state-owned Ethiopian Airlines has expanded its network and grown to become Africa's largest carrier in terms of revenue and profit. This, together with the growth in the hospitality sector, means services have now surpassed agriculture as the principal source of GDP.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>English is widely used in business circles. Nonetheless, knowledge of a few words of Amharic will be appreciated by Ethiopian business associates. Interpreter services are available in Addis Ababa if necessary. Business etiquette is quite formal in Ethiopia with appointments required for business meetings and suits and ties normal attire for visits.</p>
<p>Business meetings usually start 10 to 15 minutes later than planned, and most often start with a handshake and an exchange of phone numbers or business cards. Ethiopians are sociable, so it is natural to have a round of greetings at the start of a meeting to include several polite queries into the health and wellbeing of each person and their family members. The small talk may also encompass weather or any current news.</p>
<p>Ethiopia is a forward-looking country. However, in the event that the business associate is a Muslim woman who wears a hijab, foreign male visitors should not attempt to shake hands with her unless she extends her hand first.</p>
<p><strong>Ethiopian time explained</strong></p>
<p>One key thing to note is Ethiopian time. According to international time zones, Ethiopia falls under Eastern Africa Time (EAT) which is 3 hours ahead of Coordinated Universal Time (UTC). However, almost all Ethiopians use a 12-hour clock that follows the sunrise/sunset cycle. It must be explained that geographically, Ethiopia sits just 18 degrees north of the equator, it therefore enjoys fairly consistent 12 hours of daylight and 12 hours of night-time throughout the year, making it easy for Ethiopians to divide the day this way.</p>
<p>For example, at 0700 Eastern Africa Time is when the sun rises, marking the first hour on the dawn-to-dusk cycle and therefore locals call this &quot;one-o'clock&quot;. At 0800 Eastern Africa Time is the second-hour (two o'clock), so on and so forth. In the evening at 1900 Eastern Africa Time, Ethiopians start the other 12-hour cycle from dusk to dawn, so 1900 is the other one-o'clock to the locals. Keep this in mind and confirm with your business associates if the meeting is set for Eastern Africa Time or the local Ethiopian time.</p>
<p>Coincidentally, Ethiopian also has its own calendar which sees the first 12 months having 30 days each, plus a 13 month with either 5 or 6 days. However, business meetings usually follow the widely-used Gregorian calendar.</p><p>Government offices operate from Mon-Thu 0830-1230 and 1330-1730. And Fri 0830-1130 and 1330-1730.</p>
<p>Banks open from Mon-Sat 0800-1730.</p>
<p>Shops generally open from Mon-Sat 0800-1300 and 1400-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ethiopian Trade Promotions Section in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7838 3870
					Website:http://www.ethioembassy.org.uk
					Address: London SW7 1PZ,17 Princes Gate,UK,]]><b>Addis Ababa Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (11) 551 5055
					Website:http://www.addischamber.com
					Address: Mexico Square,PO Box 2458,Addis Ababa,]]><b>United Nations Conference Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (11) 551 4874
					Website:http://www.un.org
					Address: ,(Information on Conferences/Conventions),,]]><b>Commercial Bank of Ethiopia</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (11) 551 5004
					Website:http://www.combanketh.com
					Address: Unity Square,PO Box 255,Addis Ababa,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Ethiopian food is like nothing you've tried before. Having evolved mostly in isolation from neighbouring cultures, the cuisine is different to both the standard dishes found throughout sub-Saharan Africa and also to the Middle Eastern basics of North Africa.</p>
<p>Meals are based around the pancake-like <i>injera</i>, made from an endemic grain called <i>tef</i>. To make injera, tef flour is mixed with water and fermented for three days before it is cooked, giving it a slightly sour taste. Injera is naturally gluten-free and rich in fibre, iron and protein.</p>
<p>Sauces, meats and stewed vegetables are then placed directly on the injera, which is eaten with your right fingers by tearing sections off bit by bit. The spiciness of the sauces varies according to the amount of berbere, Ethiopia's famed spice-mix.</p>
<p>Traditional Ethiopian food does not use pork because most Ethiopians are Orthodox Christians or Muslims. Vegetarianism is also popular due to the strict fasting rituals of the Orthodox Church.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Injera</strong> is a slightly sour flatbread roundel with a crumpet-like texture. This staple food is enjoyed three times a day and often with <strong>wat</strong>, a spicy stew made from beef (<em>kai</em>), chicken (<em>doro</em>), fish (<em>asa</em>), lentil (<em>messer</em>), chickpea (<em>shiro</em>), or vegetables.</p>
<p><u>Other must-try dishes include:</u><br />
<strong>Ayibe</strong>: Soft crumbly cottage cheese made from cow's milk.<br />
<strong>Dulet</strong>: Breakfast dish of pan-fried minced tripe, liver, beef, and chilli.<br />
<strong>Enkulal tibs</strong>: Breakfast dish of scrambled eggs with peppers and tomatoes.<br />
<strong>Kitfo</strong>: Raw or very rare ground beef marinated in a hot chilli powder, often eaten with a chewy bread made from False Banana. <strong>Tere sega</strong> is the fancy version that is often served at weddings.<br />
<strong>Kolo</strong>: Roasted barley served in cones on the street as a snack.<br />
<strong>Kita</strong>: Herb flatbread.<br />
<strong>Tibs</strong>: Pan-fried goat or beef.</p>
<p><u>Must-try beverages include:</u><br />
<strong>Coffee</strong>: The Ethiopian province of Kaffa is said to be the home of coffee and it is traditionally served in tiny cups. <br />
<strong>Beer</strong>: Local lagers include Bedele, Habesha, St George and Walia.<br />
<strong>Areke</strong>: A pure grain alcohol.<br />
<strong>Sparkling water</strong>: Ambo is a spa town known for its sparkling mineral water, its namesake brand is most popular.<br />
<strong>Talla</strong>: Traditional sour beer, usually made from various grains such as millet, barley or wheat.<br />
<strong>Tej</strong>: Fermented honey wine.<br />
<strong>Wine</strong>: Local red and dry white wines are worth trying. Notable brands include Awash and Rift Valley.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels provide cutlery to foreign visitors. If you dine at a traditional restaurant, you will be given soap and water to wash your hands before the meal. When eating, only the right hand is used.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In most hotels and restaurants, a 10% service charge is added to the bill. Tipping is usual, but amounts are small.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><i>Azmari</i> is hugely popular throughout Ethiopia. The term refers to a wandering minstrel (the azmari) who plays a masinko (a type of musical instrument), sings and interacts with the audience. The songs are about life in general, with impromptu poems and witty wordplay which often has double meanings. There are fantastic azmari bets (bars where azmari regularly performs) in Addis Ababa, Bahir Dar, Gonder and Lalibela.</p>
<p><i>Yebahil Misuit</i>, meaning cultural night, is a vibrant mixture of singing and dancing performed by men and women who often dressed in traditional costumes to a roaring crowd.</p>
<p>The other form of traditional nightlife revolves around <i>tej</i> (Ethiopia's fermented honey wine). Tej bets, meaning the house that serves tej, are found throughout the country, even in the smallest towns.&nbsp;Tej bets generally close by midnight so don't expect a late night.</p>
<p>In Addis Ababa, there is a growing number of Western-style bars, pubs and nightclubs. Jazz is enjoying a revival in the capital city while the Beer Garden Inn (Bole Road) houses Garden Br&auml;u, the first microbrewery in East Africa, producing beers using German barley and adhering to the Reinheitsgebot (German beer purity law) which permits only water, barley and hops to be used in the brewing process.</p>
<p>Going to the cinema is a popular evening activity among Ethiopians. Local productions and foreign films are screened in their original language, while foreign films may have Amharic subtitles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The widest range of locally made products is found in Addis Ababa but the main tourist destinations (Lalibela, Bahir Dar, Gonder, Aksum, and Harar) all have plentiful souvenir stalls and shops.&nbsp;In marketplaces, bargaining is expected, but prices at shops in towns are fixed. Special purchases include traditional clothing, hand-woven scarves and <em>shamma </em>(the long cotton robe worn by men and women), crosses made from wood, silver or other metals, leather goods, drums and religious paintings.</p>
<p>Addis Ababa's main market (known as the <em>merkado</em>) is thought to be the largest in Africa and is more an experience than a shopping destination. A pleasant alternative is Shiromeda Market, which is often considered as a good place to purchase traditional clothing. For other souvenirs, you are likely to find a bargain in the myriad of stalls and shops that line Churchill Avenue and around the Piazza district.</p>
<p>For high-quality goods, Gallery 21 (Churchill Avenue) and Alert Handicraft Shop (off the Addis Ababa Ring Road) are your top choices, while SoleRebels Footwear (several stores with one at the Hilton hotel) is the world's only Fair Trade certified shoe company that makes super-funky footwear using organic cotton and traditional eucalyptus looms.</p>
<p>Outside of the capital, Aksum is known for its basketry work, Bahir Dar is famed for its leather 'picnic basket' known as <em>agelgil</em>, and Harar is the place to head for quality coffee beans.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1300 and 1400-1730 (with local variations).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good hotels in Ethiopia can be found in Addis Ababa and other main tourist destinations including Mekelle and Lalibela. Facilities and service tend to vary widely, although breakfast is usually included. A 10% service charge and 15% room tax is commonly charged at top-end hotels.</p>
<p>Within Addis Ababa, Golden Tulip (<a href="http://www.goldentulipaddisababa.com/">www.goldentulipaddisababa.com</a>) on Cameroon Street is a good 4-star hotel popular with business travellers and foreign visitors. Its Spice Restaurant offers an outstanding spread of buffet breakfast, lunch and dinner as well as a la carte options. <a href="http://www3.hilton.com/en/hotels/ethiopia/hilton-addis-ababa-ADDHITW/index.html?WT.mc_id=zELWAKN0EMEA1HI2DMH3LocalSearch4DGGenericx6ADDHITW">Hilton</a> and <a href="https://www.radissonblu.com/en/hotel-addisababa?facilitatorId=CSOSEO&amp;csref=org_gmb_sk_en_sn_ho_ADDZA">Radisson Blu</a> are the two other hotels preferred by foreign visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good hotels in Ethiopia can be found in Addis Ababa and other main tourist destinations including Mekelle and Lalibela. Facilities and service tend to vary widely, although breakfast is usually included. A 10% service charge and 15% room tax is commonly charged at top-end hotels.</p>
<p>Within Addis Ababa, Golden Tulip (<a href="http://www.goldentulipaddisababa.com/">www.goldentulipaddisababa.com</a>) on Cameroon Street is a good 4-star hotel popular with business travellers and foreign visitors. Its Spice Restaurant offers an outstanding spread of buffet breakfast, lunch and dinner as well as a la carte options. <a href="http://www3.hilton.com/en/hotels/ethiopia/hilton-addis-ababa-ADDHITW/index.html?WT.mc_id=zELWAKN0EMEA1HI2DMH3LocalSearch4DGGenericx6ADDHITW">Hilton</a> and <a href="https://www.radissonblu.com/en/hotel-addisababa?facilitatorId=CSOSEO&amp;csref=org_gmb_sk_en_sn_ho_ADDZA">Radisson Blu</a> are the two other hotels preferred by foreign visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good hotels in Ethiopia can be found in Addis Ababa and other main tourist destinations including Mekelle and Lalibela. Facilities and service tend to vary widely, although breakfast is usually included. A 10% service charge and 15% room tax is commonly charged at top-end hotels.</p>
<p>Within Addis Ababa, Golden Tulip (<a href="http://www.goldentulipaddisababa.com/">www.goldentulipaddisababa.com</a>) on Cameroon Street is a good 4-star hotel popular with business travellers and foreign visitors. Its Spice Restaurant offers an outstanding spread of buffet breakfast, lunch and dinner as well as a la carte options. <a href="http://www3.hilton.com/en/hotels/ethiopia/hilton-addis-ababa-ADDHITW/index.html?WT.mc_id=zELWAKN0EMEA1HI2DMH3LocalSearch4DGGenericx6ADDHITW">Hilton</a> and <a href="https://www.radissonblu.com/en/hotel-addisababa?facilitatorId=CSOSEO&amp;csref=org_gmb_sk_en_sn_ho_ADDZA">Radisson Blu</a> are the two other hotels preferred by foreign visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;It is essential to take out comprehensive travel insurance before travelling to Ethiopia and to make sure that necessary vaccinations are up to date. Those with pre-existing medical conditions which require medication should bring the necessary medication with them to last the entirety of their trip. They should also bring a letter from their doctor showing the generic names of the medication and listing any syringes or needles being carried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Clean water is available in tourist destinations. Having said that, as of June 2018, foreigners are encouraged not to drink or brush your teeth with tap water. Bottled water is widely available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travellers with a sensitive stomach should also avoid raw meat (both kitfo and tere sega dishes contain raw meat), fresh vegetables and unpasteurised dairy products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may choose to carry a bottle of hand sanitizer with you. However, please avoid using wipes as they may clog up sewers and septic tanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Diarrhoeal diseases, including giardiasis, and typhoid fevers occur. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Hepatitis A is widespread; hepatitis B is hyperendemic. Meningococcal meningitis risk is present, particularly in dry areas and during the dry season. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The high altitude and low oxygen level of much of Ethiopia need time to be acclimatised to. Anyone who suffers from heart ailments or high blood pressure should consult a doctor before travelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Victory of Adowa :
							02 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Derg Downfall Day :
							28 May </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Ethiopia by passengers aged 18 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes, 100 cigars or 250 grams of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2 litres of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; 500ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Gifts not exceeding value of 500 Birr.<br />
&bull; 100g of gold and other precious metal.<br />
&bull; 30g of precious stones.<br />
&bull; 100g of semi-precious stones.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include narcotics, firearms, explosives, counterfeit currency, pornography and materials which infringe upon intellectual property rights.</p>
<p>Restricted imports requiring permits include hunting guns, air guns, swords, endangered plants and animals, live plants and animals, fruit and vegetables, seeds, ivory, medicines and satellite cameras.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited or restricted exports include ivory (even if already processed into jewellery), precious metals, precious gems, religious artefacts, antiques and animal hides. &nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ethiopian Birr (ETB; symbol Br) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of 100, 50, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of 1 Birr, as well as 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar bills are the most convenient currency to exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa and MasterCard are accepted at major hotels.</p><p>ATMs are widely available in Addis Ababa and other major towns. Always get a receipt for every transaction, and immediately let your bank know if the ATM does not give you the amount you have entered.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travel cheques are not popular nowadays but if you want to buy some, you&rsquo;re advised to take traveller&rsquo;s cheques in US Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1730 and Sat 0800-1600</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Ethiopia, all nationals must have a passport valid for six months from the date you intend to enter the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A transit visa is required for transit passengers who plan to leave the airport for any length of time between flights. Transit visas are available for 12, 24, 48 or 72 hours. To apply for a transit visa, please visit a consulate near you before travelling to Addis Ababa.</p>
<p>For those who do not plan to leave the airport, no visa is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The cost for an e-VISA (applied at <a href="www.evisa.gov.et">www.evisa.gov.et</a> before travelling) and the cost for a tourist visa on arrival is the same: US$52 for a single-entry visa with validity up to 30 days, or US$72 for a single-entry visa with validity up to 90 days.</p>
<p>It may be cheaper to apply in person at a consulate near you. For example, applying in person at the Ethiopian Embassy in London will cost you &pound;32 for a single-entry visa, instead of US$52 online.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry: 30 days or 90 days.</p>
<p>Multiple-entry: three months or six months.</p>
<p>You are not allowed to stay in Ethiopia beyond the validity period of your visa. If you want to request for an extension before the visa expires, please visit the head office of the main department for Immigration and Nationality Affairs in Addis Ababa in person.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For single-entry visas, you can apply online at <a href="www.evisa.gov.et">www.evisa.gov.et</a> before travelling, or apply in person by visiting a consulate near you. You may also apply for a visa on arrival (please see above).</p>
<p>For multiple-entry and transit visas, please apply at a consulate near you.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas for Ethiopia take around one to three working days to process.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In some cases, visa applicants may be asked to supply proof of sufficient funds; a bank statement usually suffices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[8.621967]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[39.634973]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,104,300 sq km (426,372 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>107.53 million (2018)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>102 per sq km</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Addis Ababa</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal Democratic Republic</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ethiopia is situated in northeast Africa, in the area known as 'The Horn of Africa'. It is bordered by Eritrea, Sudan, South Sudan, Kenya, Somalia, the self-proclaimed separatist territory of Somaliland, and Djibouti. Encompassing an area of 1,104,300 sq km (426,372 sq miles), it is roughly twice the size of France and is completely landlocked.</p>
<p>The central area is a vast highland region of volcanic rock forming a watered, temperate zone surrounded by hot, arid, inhospitable desert. The Great Rift Valley (which starts in Palestine, runs down the Red Sea and diagonally southwest through Ethiopia, Kenya and Malawi) slices through the central mountain ranges. The escarpments on either side of the country are steepest in the north where the terrain is very rugged.</p>
<p>Within the country there is a huge diversity in altitude. The highest point is at Ras Dashen in the Simien Mountains, which at 4,550m (14,930 ft) is Africa's 10th tallest mountain. The lowest point is inside the Danakil Depression which reaches 125m (410ft) below sea level. To the south, the landscape is generally flatter and much of the east and southeast is taken over by semi-arid scrubland. Although mass- deforestation has been a problem since the Middle Ages, the lowlands are still noted for their verdant evergreen forests. Ethiopia is home to four major river systems, the most important being the Blue Nile which begins at Lake Tana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ethiopian Orthodox Church, 43%; Islam (mainly in the east and south), 35%; Traditional religions and Protestants are also significant.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Religion permeates nearly every facet of Ethiopian life and society. Fasting, as part of a religious ritual, is common. Ethiopian society is rather conservative with traditional values very much in place. Many Ethiopians also harbour a strong national identity, taking pride in their profound history as well as recent economic accomplishments.</p>
<p>Ethiopians are a sociable bunch. They take time to greet one another and close friends may kiss three times on the cheeks. Hand-holding between two same-sex friends is a sign of affection, not a sign of a gay relationship.</p>
<p><strong>Eating &amp; drinking</strong>: Only the right hand is used for eating or passing things. The left hand is used when going to the toilet and therefore considered dirty.</p>
<p><strong>Monasteries &amp; churches</strong>: When visiting a monastery or a church (particularly in Lalibela), women must wear a headscarf, and cover their arms and legs. Some monasteries and churches are only open to male visitors. Women travellers should always check before entering if they're unsure.</p>
<p><strong>Ethiopian time</strong>: Please see the 'Doing business &amp; staying in touch' section for an explanation on this.</p>
<p><strong>Photography</strong>: In smaller towns, locals will expect a small payment in return for being photographed. Video photography in famous tourist attractions normally carries a small charge. Photography may be prohibited near government buildings and military installations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins and Italian-style plugs with three round pins in a line are both used. Power cuts are frequent; you may want to pack additional power banks for your electronic devices and bring a torch too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Sahle-Work Zewde&nbsp;since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the discovery of the hominid fossil Lucy, Ethiopia is much touted as the cradle of humanity. As part of the Land of Punt, the people here enjoyed trade with the ancient Egyptians some 5,000 years ago and then, around 3,500 years ago, Ethiopia's first great civilisation arose.</p>
<p>Various kingdoms then spawned, the most famous being the Aksumite Kingdom (100AD to 940AD). Dynasties rose, flourished and fell throughout the region up until the 19th-century, uniting and then splitting the country into feuding states.</p>
<p>Ethiopia can lay claim to be the only country in Africa to have never been fully colonised, despite the best efforts of the Italians, who suffered a series of devastating defeats at the hands of the Ethiopians in the late 19th-century and made a successful (but short-lived) occupation between 1936 and 1941.</p>
<p>The first half of the 20th century was dominated by Haile Selassie, who became emperor in 1930. Widespread discontent with continuing imperial rule led to a military coup in 1974, bringing the Derg to power. In 1977 a further coup established Lieutenant Colonel Mengistu as ruler. Ethiopia slid into a state of terror as mass arrests and executions became commonplace. A multitude of armed opposition groups rose up across Ethiopia in response, ushering in the start of Ethiopia's civil war.</p>
<p>It was the civil war, along with severe drought, economic mismanagement and mutual mistrust between the government and Western aid agencies that contributed to the widespread Ethiopian famine of 1983. The war ended in 1991 when the Ethiopian People's Revolutionary Democratic Front (EPRDF) took control of the capital. Not long after, in 1993, Eritrea extricated itself from Ethiopia, and tension continues between the two governments.</p>
<p>EPRDF leader, Meles Zenawi, was elected head of a transitional administration and became Ethiopia's first democratically elected prime minister after elections in 1995. Since then, more political parties have been created and the government is keen to reform and encourage economic growth.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Rastafarians believe Ethiopia's former emperor, Haile Selassie, is an incarnation of Christ.<br />
&bull;	Ethiopia is the only country in the world to have a 13-month year. The first 12 months have exactly 30 days for each month and the 13th month has five or six days.<br />
&bull;	Coffee is thought to have been discovered in the Kaffa region when a shepherd found his goats behaving oddly after eating the plant.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Ethiopia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+251 11 617 0100</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinethiopia.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+251 11 617 0100</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0800-1645&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Comoros Street, 858<br/>Addis Ababa<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Ethiopia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 364 1200</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ethiopianembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 364 1200</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3506 International Drive<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Ethiopia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7589 7212</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ethioembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7589 7212</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700 (Embassy) / Mon-Fri 0900-1500 (Consular)&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>17 Princes Gate<br/>London<br/>SW7 1PZ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Putting its turbulent history behind, Ethiopia has been busy transforming its economy and making remarkable progress in infrastructure development over the past two decades. Today tourists are returning to the country in increasing numbers, keen to discover its wondrous landscapes, ancient religious sites and fascinating indigenous tribes.</p>
<p>Billed as 'The Land of Origins' by the Ethiopian Tourism Organisation, this amazing country is where the Blue Nile begins and home of the 3.2-million-year-old hominid fossil 'Lucy', whose discovery has put Ethiopia on the map as the cradle of humanity. One of the oldest Christian nations in the world, Ethiopia is a multi-ethnic and multifaceted destination where the art of hospitality is alive and well. Visitors are typically greeted with a steaming cup of coffee, which is said to be first discovered in the region of Kaffa in southeast Ethiopia.</p>
<p>Most visitors start their Ethiopian odyssey in the capital Addis Ababa, a lively city nestling in the lofty Entoto Mountains. Founded in 1886 by Emperor Menelik II after his wife Empress Taytu chose the site for its hot mineral springs, Addis Ababa has enjoyed a fascinating transformation over a relatively short period of time. The city is now a hub of international missions and embassies, including the headquarters of the African Union and the UN Economic Commission for Africa (UNECA).</p>
<p>Few linger long in the Ethiopian capital, choosing instead to head north to Lalibela, a pilgrimage site famed for its ancient churches which have quite literally been hewn out of a cliff. Lalibela is one of nine UNESCO World Heritage Sites in Ethiopia. Other notables include the ancient Kingdom of Aksum (or Axum), the fairytale castle of Gondar, the walled city of Harar, the Konso cultural landscape, the prehistoric sites of Awash and Omo valleys, the mysterious stelae of Tiya and the spectacular Simien National Park where the indigenous Gelada baboon and Walia Ibex thrive.</p>
<p>Ultimately, it is Ethiopia's epic landscapes that truly capture the imagination of many travellers. From the cloud-shrouded peak of Ras Dashen (the highest mountain in Ethiopia) to the sulphur fumaroles of the Danakil Depression (which is also the lowest point in Ethiopia at 125m/410ft below sea level), the scenery could inspire paintings, provoke poetry.</p>
<p>These wild environments sustain ancient tribes such as the Bodi, whose men live on a diet of blood and milk in a bid to become the region's fattest man of the year, and the Hamer, famous for their dangerous bull-jumping ceremony which is considered a rite of passage for young men.</p>
<p>Ethiopia has come a long way since the famine of 1983-85 which prompted Bob Geldof to write the fundraising hit <i>Do They Know It's Christmas?</i> (by a curious twist of fate, he now owns a stake in a wine company in Ethiopia). This country, long misunderstood by many, is now enjoying a booming economy, posting a strong and sustainable 8% to 11% growth rate since the turn of the 21st-century.</p>
<p>With Ethiopian Airlines boasting a wide network of air routes radiating from Addis Ababa, travelling to and around the country is getting easier, and for those who ride it out, the rewards are immense.</p><p>Putting its turbulent history behind, Ethiopia has been busy transforming its economy and making remarkable progress in infrastructure development over the past two decades. Today tourists are returning to the country in increasing numbers, keen to discover its wondrous landscapes, ancient religious sites and fascinating indigenous tribes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
