<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Falkland Islands" ColCode="flk" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="fk" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Falkland Islands]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is temperate and largely conditioned by the surrounding sea being cooled by the Antarctic Current. The most popular time to visit is between November-February, when the weather is at its warmest.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A windproof jacket is essential, as is a stout pair of walking boots when crossing the rugged terrain. Because the air is so clear and unpolluted, suntan lotion is advisable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can reach most of the settlements and offshore islands in the Falklands by light aircraft. This service is run by the Falkland Islands Government Air Service (FIGAS) (tel: +500 27219). There are no fixed schedules but daily flights operate to all parts of the islands, subject to demand. Capacity for flights is eight passengers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can charter boats for day trips from Stanley and elsewhere in the islands. Some settlements may be able to offer the use of landing vessels or other craft to reach the outlying islands. There are plenty of tour operators and guides to choose from in Stanley.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>Taxi services are available in Stanley and the airport.</p><p>You can hire 4-wheel-drive and other vehicles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no public transport in the Falkland Islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Falkland Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sea_lion_island</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Falkland Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">port_howard</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Falkland Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">pebble_island</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Falkland Islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">mount_pleasant</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to and from Mount Pleasant Airport (MPN) are operated by the UK Ministry of Defence. There are direct flights from RAF Brize Norton in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>. Tour operators and travel agents will make the necessary arrangements if the trip is booked through them; independent travellers need to contact a travel coordinator at the Falkland Islands Government Office (tel: +44 20 7222 2542). Return flights from the UK are via Ascension Island.</p>
<p>The other option is to fly to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/santiago">Santiago</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chile">Chile</a>) and connect with a flight to Punta Arenas&nbsp;in southern Chile and then on to Stanley. LAN (<a href="http://www.lan.com" target="_blank">www.lan.com</a>) runs this service.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From Brize Norton to Mount Pleasant - 20 hours (including a refuelling stop at Ascension Island); from Punta Arenas (Chile) to Mount Pleasant - 5 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&pound;22 for LAN passengers. Included in the fare if you book a Ministry of Defence flight.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Mount Pleasant Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is approximately 56km (35 miles) from Stanley.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cruise companies operate to the Falklands. The main shipping company operating to and from the UK is Falkland Islands Shipping (<a href="http://www.the-falkland-islands-co.com" target="_blank">www.the-falkland-islands-co.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Good satellite telephone links to the Islands. The Cable & Wireless office is open Mon-Thurs 0815-1200 and 1315-1630 (Fri until 1615), and sells phone cards for use in the international telephone service booths situated in the office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cable & Wireless launched a mobile phone service in December 2005. Coverage is initially in Stanley and Mount Pleasant with fairly good coverage along the MPA road and more limited coverage between MPA and Goose Green. No roaming agreements have been declared.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is an Internet cafe in Stanley.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage of local affairs is provided by a radio station and by the territory's sole newspaper. Satellite television channels are widely available. There are no daily local papers, but <em>Penguin News</em> (weekly) is published in Stanley and all British national newspapers are also available; the<em> Falkland Islands</em> <em>Gazette</em> is a government publication; the <em>Falkland Islands News Network </em>relays news daily via fax and email. <em>BFBS Radio Falklands</em> provides radio coverage for British forces; the <em>Falkland Islands Broadcasting Station</em> (<em>FIBS</em>) operates on both AM and FM.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes four to seven days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Explore the capital, Stanley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its traditional boozers, Stanley has more than a whiff of Great Britain about it. If you fancy getting to know the locals order a pint and prop up the bar. If you're feeling peckish there are a various restaurants to sate your appetite. Fancy a flutter? Then head to the local racecourse to watch the nags.</p>]]><p><b>Go birdwatching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The penguins are, of course, the headline attraction, but for discerning twitchers the archipelago offers the chance to spot other rare and enchanting birds, such as the caracara, albatross and the endemic Cobb's wren. The Falkland's flightless steamer duck is another popular inhabitant and is found nowhere else on Earth.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about the archipelago’s maritime history</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Back in the day, sailing ships and steam vessels would regularly call in at Stanley before embarking on the often-precarious journey around Cape Horn. A self-guided Maritime History Trail has been set up in the capital, which takes half a day and leads from Stanley to Cape Pembroke, offering an interesting introduction to the Falkland Islands' birdlife.</p>]]><p><b>Pay a visit to Sea Lion Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sea Lion is home to some amazing wildlife, including elephant seals, sea lions and king penguins, as well as killer whales offshore. It is the most southerly-inhabited island, and all areas are accessible by 4x4 or on foot from Sea Lion Lodge.</p>]]><p><b>Peer at the resident penguins</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many migratory birds come to the Falkland Islands, but penguins are the star attraction. There are five species to see in all – the gentoo, rockhopper, Magellanic, king and macaroni penguin – which come to breed on the archipelago in September and depart in March. Be sure to catch a glimpse of these wonderful creatures, which really are adorable.</p>]]><p><b>Saddle up for horse riding</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the best ways to explore the archipelago, horse riding is available in Port Howard and Port San Carlos. Need more horsepower? Then hire a quad bike, which is another way of exploring the archipelago's dramatic landscape.</p>]]><p><b>Support eco-tourism</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tourist accommodation on the Islands makes every effort to reduce human impact on the environment, as such many of the tourist lodges using wind generators, solar panels and other renewable energy. Farms and tourist establishments all over the Islands also tend to grow their own produce.</p>]]><p><b>Take a boat tour of Stanley Harbour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A number of lodges in Stanley have motorboats, which are used for taking guests to see wildlife and places of interest in Stanley Harbour. Tours around Kidney Island and Sparrow Cove can also be arranged. It's worth layering up, as the weather can change quickly at sea.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the battlefield sites</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The 1982 conflict looms large over the islands and so it would be remiss not to take a trip to some of the battlefield sites associated with the war (including Wireless Ridge, Mount Tumbledown and Sapper Hill). There are also military cemeteries, memorials and museums dealing with the conflict.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>£75million (2002).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Wool, hides and meat.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fuel, food and drink, building materials and clothing.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK, Spain, Chile and France.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The economy is dominated by fishing and sheep-farming. Productivity in sheep-farming has increased sharply since the mid 1980s with improved working practices.<br /><br />The fishing sector now accounts for the islands' much improved economic performance. The industry has grown substantially since 1982, assisted by the introduction of a licensing system in Falklands territorial waters. The presence of large quantities of squid, a very popular dish in several parts of the world, has fuelled an economic boom and the emergence of a 'squidocracy': a group of individuals who have become extremely wealthy as a result.<br /><br />Other plans for the Falklands' economic development have proved less successful. Restrictions on Antarctic development have undermined the islands' hope of deriving benefit from being an en route staging post. The search for oil and gas reserves began in earnest in 1995 after the signing of an agreement between the UK and Argentina; test drilling started in 1998 but no viable deposits have yet been located.<br /><br />However, as long as the squid last, the Falklands economic outlook remains bright. Tourism, especially eco-tourism, is increasing rapidly. Another significant source of income is interest paid on money that the government has in the bank. The British military presence also provides a sizable economic boost. <br /><br />Trade between the islands and Argentina is small; most trade is still conducted with the UK.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Punctuality for meetings is expected.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200, 1300-1630 (government); Mon-Fri 0800-1200, 1300-1700 (private).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Falkland Islands Development Corporation (FIDC)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Falkland Islands Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:http://www.falklandislandschamberofcommerce.com
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Almost everything is home-cooked and many traditional recipes, generally British in character, have been handed down through several generations.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Lamb, mutton, beef, sea trout, mullet and home-grown vegetables.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>If no service charge has been added to the bill, 10% is appropriate.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a variety of clubs and societies which welcome visitors. There are several pubs in Stanley, as well as restaurants and cafes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Costs tend to be slightly higher than in the UK as much has to be imported, though smaller luxury goods may be cheaper. There is a good range of shops in Stanley selling the same type of goods found in a small town in Britain and a variety of souvenirs. Sweaters made from pure Falkland Wool and local art, jewellery made from Falkland Islands' pebbles, coins, stamps and books are also sold. Fresh vegetables are available all year round but many Islanders are virtually self-sufficient. Print film is available but it is advisable to bring a supply.</p><p>Shopping hours vary, but shops are generally open Mon-Sat 0800-1800; some shops may stay open until 2100 in some areas. Earlier closing times on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation is limited and should be booked in advance. There are hotels, lodges and boarding houses, as well as full-board accommodation on a farm. As well as accommodation in Stanley, there are lodges on Pebble Island, Port Howard, San Carlos and Sea Lion Island. Arrangements can be made through Stanley Services Limited, Stanley (tel: 22622; <a href="http://www.stanley-services.co.fk" target="_blank">www.stanley-services.co.fk</a>) and the Falkland Islands Tourist Board.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> A new grading system is now in use. Contact the Falkland Islands Tourist Board for full details (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation is limited and should be booked in advance. There are hotels, lodges and boarding houses, as well as full-board accommodation on a farm. As well as accommodation in Stanley, there are lodges on Pebble Island, Port Howard, San Carlos and Sea Lion Island. Arrangements can be made through Stanley Services Limited, Stanley (tel: 22622; <a href="http://www.stanley-services.co.fk" target="_blank">www.stanley-services.co.fk</a>) and the Falkland Islands Tourist Board.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> A new grading system is now in use. Contact the Falkland Islands Tourist Board for full details (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation is limited and should be booked in advance. There are hotels, lodges and boarding houses, as well as full-board accommodation on a farm. As well as accommodation in Stanley, there are lodges on Pebble Island, Port Howard, San Carlos and Sea Lion Island. Arrangements can be made through Stanley Services Limited, Stanley (tel: 22622; <a href="http://www.stanley-services.co.fk" target="_blank">www.stanley-services.co.fk</a>) and the Falkland Islands Tourist Board.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> A new grading system is now in use. Contact the Falkland Islands Tourist Board for full details (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Hospital, dental and other medical treatments are free, as are prescribed medicines and ambulance travel to visitors whose country has a reciprocal NHS agreement. Otherwise, medical insurance is recommended. Proof of residence in the UK (eg medical card or UK driving licence) or an EHIC form for other nationals are required to benefit from free treatments.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							21 April </p><p>Liberation Day :
							14 June </p><p>Spring Holiday :
							01 October </p><p>Battle Day :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into the Falkland Islands without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 100 cigarillos or 250g tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic beverage over 22% volume or 2L up to 22% volume.<br />
&bull; 2L of sparkling or still table wine.<br />
&bull; 10L of beer or cider.</p>
<p>Tobacco allowances apply to travellers aged 16 years or over. Alcohol allowances apply to travellers aged 18 years or over.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drugs, pornography and counterfeit goods.</p>
<p>Import licences are required from Department of Agriculture for plants, fresh meat, fresh poultry and fresh dairy produce. An import licence is required from the Falkland Islands' Policy Authority for firearms and ammunition.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include fruit, used fishing equipment, used agricultural or gardening clothing, used camping equipment and soiled footwear or clothing. Some items require a licence, while others may require treatment with disinfectant.</p>
<p>The import of endangered species (eg whale bone, ivory and coral) is only allowed with a special permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Falkland Islands Pound (FKP) and the British Pound Sterling (GBP; symbol £) = 100 pence. Notes are in denominations of £50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of £2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 pence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchange facilities are available in Stanley and the Standard Chartered Bank. British Pound Sterling cheques up to £50 from Barclays, Lloyds and Natwest banks can be cashed on production of a valid cheque card, but a fee will be charged. The Falklands' currency cannot be exchanged anywhere outside the islands. English Sterling banknotes and US Dollars are accepted by most businesses. Travellers are advised to carry some currency in US Dollars in case flights are diverted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard and Visa are accepted in most hotels and shops in Stanley but few shops outside the main town will accept credit cards. American Express and Diners Card are accept by some businesses. There are no ATMs.</p><p>There are no ATMs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>May be changed at the Standard Chartered Bank and at some commercial outlets. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for the length of stay in the Falkland Islands is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British embassies charge &pound;115 for receiving, handling and forwarding visa applications for British Overseas Territories.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Consulate (or consular section at embassy) or High Commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your initial four-week stay, you must apply directly to Customs and Immigration in Stanley.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-51.772985]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-59.727984]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>12,173 sq km (4,700 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,912 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>0.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Stanley.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Overseas Territory, which is not recognised by Argentina, as it considers the Falkland Islands to be part of Argentina.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Falkland Islands are located 560km (350 miles) off the east coast of South America and consist of two main islands and hundreds of small outlying islands, amounting to approximately 1.2 million hectares (3 million acres). Generally, the main islands are mountainous, with low-lying and undulating terrain in the south of East Falkland. The highest mountain is Mt Usborne at 712m (2,312ft).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christian, with Catholic, Anglican and United Reformed Church of Stanley denominations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The lifestyle in the Falkland Islands resembles that of a small English or Scottish village/town and communities on the Falkland Islands are highly self-contained. The influx of the British Forces has obviously had an effect on the Islands. More people now visit for a variety of reasons. The islanders themselves have benefited from the additional amenities offered by the Forces. The population is very keen to remain under British sovereignty.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chief Executive Barry Rowland since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor Nigel Phillips since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Until the war of 1982, the rainy, windswept Falkland Islands were a lowly, almost forgotten remnant of the old British Empire.</p><p>First occupied by the French in 1764, the islands were quickly ceded to Spain, which then ruled the adjacent territory in Latin America.</p><p>However, the Spanish only established themselves on West Falkland and, in 1765, the British took control of the eastern island.</p><p>There are a further 776 smaller islands.</p><p>By 1816, due to the islands' inclement climate and strategic uselessness, both powers had removed their respective garrisons and the Falkland Islands had no permanent inhabitants.</p><p>In 1820 a vessel from newly independent Argentina was sent to establish a permanent settlement, but was driven out by a British expedition in 1832.</p><p>When the British declared full sovereignty over the Falkland Islands the following year Argentina refused to recognise the claim and has asserted its own right to sovereignty ever since.</p><p>This claim was pursued periodically through diplomatic channels until 1982, when an Argentine force overran the British garrison and established a military base on 'Islas Malvinas', a name derived from the original French settlers, who named the islands after their homeport of St Malo.</p><p>After negotiation failed, a British task force, which had been despatched at the start of the crisis, was ordered to continue its journey and engage the Argentines.</p><p>Argentina surrendered 10 weeks after the invasion.</p><p>In the subsequent contact between the two governments, it has become apparent that the issue of sovereignty is a stumbling block and that the Falkland Islands issue has remained a key aspect of Argentine foreign policy.</p><p>The UK adamantly refuses to discuss sovereignty and the wishes of the 3000 or so islanders, who are determined to stay British, remain paramount. Since 1983 the islanders also enjoyed full British citizenship.</p><p>The Islands' weekly newspapers The Penguin News is published every Friday and made its own headlines in 2012 when it appeared to insult the then Argentine President Cistina Fernández de Kirchner in a photo caption.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>&bull; It is thought indigenous Fuegians from Tierra del Fuego may have visited the Falkland Islands in prehistoric times.</p><p>&bull; Following the 1982 war, some 20,000 mines of various types were left. Following several casualties, clearance work was abandoned in 1983 and not resumed until 2009.</p><p>&bull; The Falklands' only native terrestrial mammal, the warrah, had been hunted to extinction by 1876.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Falkland Islands Immigration Office]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+500 27340</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.falklands.gov.fk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+500 27340</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>3 H Jones Road<br/>Stanley<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Diplomatic representation]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nineteenth-century shipwrecks and a plethora of marine life are among the attractions awaiting visitors to the Falkland Islands. Although these islands are perhaps best known as the battleground of the eponymous 1982 war between Britain and Argentina, but this archipelago in the Atlantic is an intriguing and relaxing holiday destination.</p><p>Situated nearly 500km from Patagonia, the Falklands – or Islas Maldivas, depending on who you talk to – are a frequent stopping point on Antarctic voyages, and with such an abundance of rare animal life, it's not hard to see why. There are two main islands, East and West Falkland, as well as several hundred islets. Wildlife lovers will find strewn among them five different species of penguins (including macaroni, king, Magellanic, gentoo, and rockhopper), as well whales, and sea birds. Head to Volunteer Point for the islands' largest group of king penguins, while there are a predictably vast amount of sea lions to be found on Sea Lion Island.</p><p>Reminders of the 1982 conflict do remain, with battlefields, such as Goose Green and Pebble Island, now tourist attractions. Also claimed by Spain, France and Argentina over the years, the Falklands have been British Overseas Territory since 1833. Argentina famously still contests this status and there have been recent political ramblings on the matter by that country's government. However, a recent referendum found that an overwhelming majority of the 3,000 or so islanders want to remain under British rule.</p><p>Most of the Falkland Islands' population live in the capital Stanley, over whose harbour much avian life can be seen circling above the waves. More than a thousand members of the British military live at the Mount Pleasant Base. There's a rural feel to the islands, with hamlets and sheep abounding, while you'll find no traffic lights on the Falklands' country roads. There are more than a dozen endemic plants, including Felton's flower, thought to be extinct in the wild until recently, which gives off a whiff of caramel. Also, look out for the ubiquitous snakeplant.</p>Nineteenth-century shipwrecks and a plethora of marine life are among the attractions awaiting visitors to the Falkland Islands.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
