<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Fiji" ColCode="fji" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="fj" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Fiji]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fiji has a warm tropical climate perfect for beachside holidays. Maximum temperatures rarely move out of the 31&deg;C (88&deg;F) to 26&deg;C (79&deg;F)&nbsp;range all year round. Southeast trade winds from March to November bring dry weather and the rainy season runs from December to April. On average there are 15 cyclones per decade, and two to four actually cause severe damage. They occur from November to April and with greatest frequency in January and February. There is more risk in the outlying northwest island groups.</p>
<p>Fiji does have a wet season, which is characterised by heavy, brief local showers and contributes most of the country&rsquo;s annual rainfall. The wet season is normally from November to April and results from the southerly movements of the South Pacific Convergence Zone. Typically the smaller islands in Fiji receive less rainfall than the main Island with various amounts according to their location and size. Cyclones do occur in Fiji and are normally confined to wet season.</p>
<p>The best months for holidaying in regards to Fiji weather is late March through to early December.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight for summer, rainwear for the wet season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While most international flights&nbsp;to Fiji are focused on Nadi, many domestic air services to eastern Fiji&nbsp;fly into Suva's Nausori Airport.</p>
<p>Fiji Link (<a href="http://www.fijiairways.com/fiji-holidays/fiji-link/" target="_blank">www.fijiairways.com</a>)&nbsp;operates shuttle services around the islands. The flight time from Nadi to Suva is approximately 30 minutes. Turtle Airways (<a href="http://www.turtleairways.com/" target="_blank">www.turtleairways.com</a>) operates a seaplane service to numerous resorts in the Mamanuca and Yasawa groups from Nadi.</p>
<p>Booking isn&rsquo;t essential and flying is an easy (and relatively inexpensive) method of getting around all year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most resorts have their own boat transport, some have catamaran services. Government and local shipping companies operate passenger services linking the outer islands. Yachts and cabin cruisers are available for charter; enquire at the shipping agents, being sure to confirm all arrangements with the captain once the vessel is in port.</p>
<p>A number of ferries operate between the major islands, including South Sea Cruises (tel: +67 9 675 0500; <a href="http://www.ssc.com.fj" target="_blank">www.ssc.com.fj</a>), Awesome Adventures (tel: +67 9 675 0499; <a href="http://www.awesomefiji.com" target="_blank">www.awesomefiji.com</a>), Patterson Brothers&nbsp;and Consort Shipping.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The approximate driving time from Nadi to Suva is three hours. The main roads on Viti Levu follow the coast, linking the main centres.</p>l<p>Main roads are paved.&nbsp;Beware of livestock on the roads as they wander freely during the night, although it is best to avoid driving during the night altogether.&nbsp;When driving past villages, drivers are advised to slow down as locals use the roads as footpaths.</p><p>You can find taxis on Viti Levu, Vanua Levu, Taveuni and Ovalau. The bus stations in the main towns usually have taxi depots and there is often an oversupply of taxis vying for business. Unlike in Suva, the taxi drivers in Nadi, Lautoka and most rural areas don't use their meters. Ask locals what the acceptable rate is for a particular trip and agree with your driver the fee in advance. If the taxi does have a meter, ask the driver to switch it on &ndash; it will likely be significantly cheaper than a negotiated price.</p><p>Valid national or international driving licence required. Third-party insurance is included in car-hire rates but collision insurance with rather high deductible amounts is extra.</p><p>The speed limit in built-up areas is 50kph (31mph) and 80kph (50mph) on highways. The minimum age for car hire is 21 or sometimes 25.</p><p>Car hire in Fiji is available through several international companies. Car hire can be relatively expensive; 4-wheel drive is recommended for islands other than Viti Levu. Limousines and chauffeurs are also available.</p><p>The speed limit in built-up areas is 50kph (31mph) and 80kph (50mph) on highways. The minimum age for car hire is 21 or sometimes 25.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Road travel tends to be more dangerous than many people are used to: potholes, washouts and dilapidated bridges are commonplace. And, while there is rarely much traffic present, most vehicles run on diesel, which means pollution can be severe. Buses are the best, unless you are truly comfortable and capable of renting and driving a car on your own. Avoid travel at night, especially outside of urban areas.</p>
<p>Many locals drive small trucks (known as carriers) with a tarpaulin-covered frame on the back. These often have passenger seating and some run trips between Nadi and Suva. Minivans are also an increasingly common sight on the road. Popular with locals, they're also quicker and more expensive than a bus but much cheaper than a taxi - though your ride will be far from comfortable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline, Fiji Airways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.fijiairways.com/">www.fijiairways.com</a>), flies from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sydney">Sydney</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/auckland">Auckland</a> and many South Pacific countries. There are no direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>; Air New Zealand flies from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Nadi via Los Angeles, or you can fly with Cathay Pacific (<a href="http://www.cathaypacific.com" target="_blank">www.cathaypacific.com</a>) to Hong Kong and continue your journey with Fiji Airways.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 25 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 20 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a> - 11 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Nausori Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airportsfiji.com<p>The airport is at Nausori, 16km (9 miles) from Suva (journey time - 30 minutes), and is the hub for internal flights.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:&nbsp;</strong>Suva  and Lautoka (Viti Levu). Lautoka, Levuka, Savusavu, and Suva are ports of entry for cruising yachts. Several cruise ship lines serve Fiji.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International calls can only really be made from Viti Levu. Calls from hotels via an operator are very expensive. It is cheaper to get a public phonecard, available from post offices and newsagents or from the Fiji International Telecommunications (FINTEL) office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with many international mobile phone companies. There is no coverage on outlying islands, only on Viti Levu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet caf&eacute;s are available in Suva, Nadi, Lautoka and most resorts. They are relatively inexpensive, however, Internet connectivity in Fiji isn&rsquo;t the best.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fiji's private press includes English-language dailies and Fijian- and Hindi-language weeklies. It has maintained its reputation for independent reporting despite interim military rule. The government has a stake in several publications. Radio is a prime source of information, particularly for the outer islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe and North America takes up to 10 days. The main post office is on Victoria Parade, Suva.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600; Sat 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bury your toes in Sigatoka Sand Dunes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Fiji's natural highlights, the spectacular sand dunes lining the Sigatoka River have been in the making for millions of years. Windblown and rugged, these dunes are a far cry from those of the Sahara – the sand is grey-brown in colour and covered with vines and shrubs. They are also one of the largest burial sites in the Pacific.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise through mangrove forests</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mangrove forests can be found along Viti Levu's gorgeous coastline and are extremely rich in wildlife. Take a boat trip along the meandering corridors of the mangrove forests, up the Rewa River Delta, for a chance to see myriad bird species and remote fishing villages.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the Fiji Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located in Thurston Gardens in Suvu, the Fiji Museum houses an extensive archaeological collection, which dates back 3,700 years and includes cultural objects representing both Fiji's indigenous inhabitants and other communities that have settled in the islands. Of particular note is the rudder of the HMS Bounty, which was destroyed by mutineers.</p>]]><p><b>Enter the Garden of the Sleeping Giant</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For peace and tranquillity, the Garden of the Sleeping Giant on the road between Nadi and Lautoka, at the foot of the Sabeto Mountains is the place to go. Formally a private orchid garden now open to the public, beautiful orchids and flowering plants abound here.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Fiji’s magnificent underwater world</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fiji has been called "the soft coral capital of the world" and few seasoned divers will deny that Fiji has some of the finest scuba diving in the South Pacific. Diving is possible all year, with the best sites including Beqa Lagoon, Rainbow Reef or the Somosomo Straits with the famous Great White Wall.</p>]]><p><b>Find inner peace at Sri Siva Subramaniya Temple</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A must-see for culture vultures, Nadi's Sri Siva Subramaniya Temple is the largest Hindu temple in the Southern Hemisphere. Illustrating the architectural diversity for which Fiji is well known, the temple is dedicated to the deity Murugan whose statue, specially carved in India, is housed in the main temple.</p>]]><p><b>Go windsurfing in the Mamanuca Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ideal water conditions, big waves and a year round breeze conspire to make Fiji an amazing windsurfing destination. Most resorts offer the sport – with instruction too – but if you're a pro and are looking for something special, the best windsurfing can be found in the Mamanuca Islands.</p>]]><p><b>Hike across Taveuni</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Taveuni has hiking trails all over the island, but the Lavena Coastal Walk and Tavoro Falls route offer some of the best trekking opportunities. Serious hikers can test their mettle on the Vidawa Forest Walk. The trek up to Lake Tagimaucia and the Des Voeux ascent are also challenging climbs.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the waves in Viti Levu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A number of surfing camps are springing up off southern and western Viti Levu. There's surf throughout the year with the best swells out of the south from March to October. Fiji's waves typically break on coral reefs. Most of the well-known spots are off Viti Levu and can often only be reached by boat.</p>]]><p><b>Imbibe local culture at the Arts Village</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A fusion of historical fantasy and contemporary arts, Pacific Harbour's quaint Arts Village is well worth a visit. Take a boat tour around the lagoon, wander around the temple and explore the market, where you will be treated to various cultural performances including traditional displays of Fijian fire walking.</p>]]><p><b>Keep an eye on the wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fruit bats, parrots and marine turtles are just some of the star attractions. You should also check out the acres of orchids and flowering plants in the Garden of the Sleeping Giant at the foot of the Sabeto Mountains, and the Sigatoka Sand Dunes off the main Queens Highway on Viti Levu.</p>]]><p><b>Scale the heights of Mount Batilamu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fiji isn't short of spectacular vistas, but for unparalleled panoramas take a day trip from Nadi or Lautoka to scale the "sleeping giant", also known as Mount Batilamu. The ascent wends through the Koroyanitu National Heritage Park through small villages, past watering holes and up vertiginous summits.</p>]]><p><b>Take to the water</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The warm, crystalline waters surrounding Fiji are a playground for watersports enthusiasts. It's possible to try your hand at diving, swimming, snorkelling, surfing, sailing, fishing, wakeboarding, kayaking and much more on most of the islands. You can also swim in numerous waterfalls found in the forest, coastal parks and reserves.</p>]]><p><b>Trek to the Church of Saint Francis Xavier</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Perched atop a hill on Fiji's main island, Viti Levu, The Church of Saint Francis Xavier is a must-visit for its unique marrying of European and Fijian culture. Straw mats instead of pews lie beneath beautiful frescos, originally commissioned by the former chaplain to the famous Von Trapp family (of <em>The Sound of Music </em>fame).</p>]]><p><b>Unwind with a relaxing mud baths</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The hot springs of Nadi are believed by locals to have healing properties. We can't qualify that, but we do know the three pools, warm mud baths and lush backdrop make for a seriously relaxing experience. Located in Sabeto Valley, the springs are run by friendly locals who will help you get muddy.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the sacred Naihehe Caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated deep in the Sigatoka Valley, the caves are popular with tourists and locals alike. Once a fortress of Fiji's last pagan tribes, the caves contain a priest chamber, sacred pond and great Cathedral Chamber. The caves are still considered sacrosanct today and locals frequent go there to pay tribute to their ancestors.</p>]]><p><b>Witness the Fijian dancing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experiencing a <em>meke</em>, the traditional dance of indigenous Fijian people, is almost unavoidable, particularly if you're staying at an island resort. <em>Mekes</em> are performed by women, who cover themselves with fans, and men, who dance with spears or clubs. Typically, the performers dress in the national costume of flower leis, grass skirts and tapa cloth.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$3.4 billion (2009).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Sugar, garments, mineral water, timber and fish.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Manufactured goods, machinery and transport equipment, petroleum and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Australia, Singapore, New Zealand, USA and UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Fijian economy has a sizeable subsistence agricultural economy as well as producing cash crops, of which sugar is the most important. Despite reform attempts, the state-owned sugar monopoly remains close to collapse through years of inefficiency and the state of the world sugar market. Indo-Fijian farmers are being forced off the land as leases held by indigenous Fijians expire.<br /><br />Fish and timber, especially mahogany (of which Fiji is the world's second-largest producer) are also vital export earners. Low-grade copper deposits exist on Viti Levu but have been judged uneconomic by transnational mining companies.<br /><br />Tourism is the main service industry, but has been affected by various political upheavals.<br /><br />Annual GDP growth was estimated at -4.4% in 2007 due to repercussions from the military coup. When Australia and New Zealand imposed ecomonic sanctions, Fiji established closer economic relations with Asian countries, including China, Korea (Republic of) and Taiwan.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most business people are Indo-Fijians, although there is a growing presence of Indigenous Fijians in business.<br /><br />
Business dress is informal with normal attire for men comprising of trousers with an open-neck, short-sleeve shirt; suits and jackets are seldom required. Most business people prefer to be called by their first name, however, certain indigenous Fijians have the title 'Ratu' (for men) or 'Adi' (for women), meaning that they are of chiefly status.<br /><br />
Fiji Indians can be quite direct and want to know the &lsquo;deal&rsquo; fairly quickly. They are traders by instinct and often base their evaluation on price. Part of the culture is Fiji time. Timeliness is not strictly observed, however, in recent years, this has become less apparent. Meetings and appointments may not start on time - delays of 10-15 minutes are quite normal.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1630/1700 (some offices close one hour earlier on Fridays).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Fiji Islands Trade and Investment Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 331 5988
					Website:http://www.ftib.org.fj
					Address: Civic Tower,PO Box 2303,Government Buildings,6th Floor,Suva,]]><b>Suva Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 331 4044
					Website:http://www.suvachamber.org/
					Address: Government Buildings,PO Box 2475,Suva,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Local cooking is Fijian, Chinese and Indian. International cuisine is also available. Table service is normal, although some establishments offer buffet-style food at lunchtime. Hotels often serve meals to non residents. Bars and cocktail lounges have table and/or counter service. Only licensed restaurants, clubs and hotel bars can serve alcohol on Sunday.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Kokoda (raw fish marinated in coconut cream and lime).<br />
&bull; <em>Rourou</em> (a taro leaf dish soaked in coconut cream).<br />
&bull; <em>Tavioka</em> (manioc or tapioca, often boiled, baked or grated and cooked in coconut cream with sugar and mashed bananas).<br />
&bull; <em>Duruka</em> (an unusual asparagus-like vegetable in season during April and May). <br />
&bull; <em>Lovo</em> (a covered pit or underground oven used to cook meat, fish, and vegetables).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Generally not necessary; only small amounts for special services.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While many of the resorts and hotels on the islands have discos and live bands to keep crowds going late into the night, the capital city of Fiji, Suva, is at the heart of the country's nightlife. Dotted with numerous bars, pubs nightclubs in areas such as the stretch from Civic Auditorium to Albert Park and Victoria parade. Most of the nightclubs and pubs in the country are situated within the main business areas or within townships and therefore easy to access. Some of the most popular venues include Traps - one of the liveliest venues around &ndash; and the glass-fronted Bad Dog caf&eacute;; a caf&eacute;-bar with a seriously comprehensive beer and wine list.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Favourite buys are woodcarvings (such as <em>kava</em> bowls), polished coconut shells, woven works (such as mats, coasters, hats, fans and trays), tapa cloth and pearls. Bargaining is not the norm in shops but is expected at handicraft markets. Some shopkeepers will give a discount with large purchases. Duty-free items are available and include electrical goods, pewter, crystal and porcelain.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700, Sat 0800-1300. Many places close for lunch 1300-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a good number of luxury hotels in Fiji, the majority of which are located in Nadi, Suva and Savusavu, along the Coral Coast of Viti Levu, in the Mamanuca and Yasawa groups, and on Beqa and Taveuni islands. There are also many small inexpensive hotels in Fiji throughout the islands, some offering dormitory accommodation. It is preferable to book in advance as some outer island resorts accommodate no more than 16 guests. A 5% hotel tax is levied on all services charged to guests' accounts, including meals in hotel restaurants.<br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> A star system is used to indicate the price range, as follows: 3-star (deluxe), 2-star (medium) and 1-star (budget).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guest housesin Fiji are mostly clean, comfortable and some even have a licensed bar, pool, restaurant, air conditioning and kitchen. Lodges are another popular budget option.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a good number of luxury hotels in Fiji, the majority of which are located in Nadi, Suva and Savusavu, along the Coral Coast of Viti Levu, in the Mamanuca and Yasawa groups, and on Beqa and Taveuni islands. There are also many small inexpensive hotels in Fiji throughout the islands, some offering dormitory accommodation. It is preferable to book in advance as some outer island resorts accommodate no more than 16 guests. A 5% hotel tax is levied on all services charged to guests' accounts, including meals in hotel restaurants.<br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> A star system is used to indicate the price range, as follows: 3-star (deluxe), 2-star (medium) and 1-star (budget).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a good number of luxury hotels in Fiji, the majority of which are located in Nadi, Suva and Savusavu, along the Coral Coast of Viti Levu, in the Mamanuca and Yasawa groups, and on Beqa and Taveuni islands. There are also many small inexpensive hotels in Fiji throughout the islands, some offering dormitory accommodation. It is preferable to book in advance as some outer island resorts accommodate no more than 16 guests. A 5% hotel tax is levied on all services charged to guests' accounts, including meals in hotel restaurants.<br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> A star system is used to indicate the price range, as follows: 3-star (deluxe), 2-star (medium) and 1-star (budget).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Healthcare facilities in Fiji urban areas are adequate for routine medical problems. In the rural areas staff training is limited and there are often shortages of supplies and medications. Emergency response is extremely limited, and the few ambulances available are poorly equipped and staffed. Two major hospitals, the Lautoka Hospital in the western city of Lautoka, and the Colonial War Memorial Hospital in Suva, provide limited emergency and outpatient services. Medical emergencies may be referred to Australia or New Zealand. Doctors and hospitals expect immediate cash payment for health services. The national emergency number for emergency services is 911.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is safe to drink in hotels, resorts and main towns, but precautions should be taken in rural areas. Bottled water is available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Diarrhoeal diseases are common. Hepatitis B is endemic. Take precautions against mosquito bites as Fiji is has recently suffered from a large outbreak of dengue fever.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are generally observed the following Monday.  Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.  Hindu festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Saturday :
							31 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							11 June </p><p>Fiji Day :
							10 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported by travellers 18 years of age and over into Fiji without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 200g of cigars or 200g of tobacco goods.<br />
&bull; 2.25L of spirits or 4.5L of wine or beer.<br />
&bull; Other dutiable goods to the value of F$1,000.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drugs, unlicensed firearms and ammunition, certain weapons (eg flick knives), pornography, gambling devices, any goods considered to disturb the peace in Fiji, tubers, bulbs, peanuts and oil seeds, and cereal grains, pulses and legumes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drugs.</p>
<p>Also prohibited unless certain conditions or restrictions are complied with are: unprocessed turtle shells, whale teeth (and products), ivory products, birds (alive or dead), reptiles, and wooden or stone carvings of human or animal figures (not including replicas).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fijian Dollar (FJD; symbol F$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of F$100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 2. Coins are in denominations of F$1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchange facilities are available at the airport, at trading banks, at private exchange offices and at most hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, Mastercard and Visa are accepted at a number of establishments and can be used in resorts on most islands.</p><p>Major international cards are accepted at ATMs, which can be found in Nadi, Suva and Savusavu, and although they are cropping up throughout the rest of the islands, these cannot always be relied upon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques attract a rate slightly higher than cash and are easily changed at banks (for a commission) and private exchange offices (often without commission).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Thurs 0930-1500, Fri 0930-1600. Foreign Exchange Dealers: Mon-Fri 0830-1700, Sat 0830-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Fiji, a passport valid for at least six months beyond intended period of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: &pound;47; multiple-entry visa: &pound;82.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: three months; multiple-entry visa: up to four months per visit within 12 months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consular section of high commission or embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa applications normally take two to six days to process.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To extend your stay, contact the Department of Immigration (<a href="http://www.immigration.gov.fj">www.immigration.gov.fj</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-16.415009]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[179.560547]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>18,274 sq km (7,055 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>897,537 (UN estimate 2016).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>49.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suva.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fiji is located in the South Pacific, 3,000km (1,875 miles) east of Australia and approximately 1,930km (1,200 miles) south of the equator. It comprises 322 islands, 105 of which are inhabited (some are little more than rugged limestone islets or tiny coral cays). The three largest are Viti Levu (Great Fiji), Vanua Levu (Great Land of the People), both of which are extinct volcanoes rising abruptly from the sea, and Taveuni. There are thousands of streams and small rivers in Fiji, the largest being the Rewa River on Viti Levu, which is navigable for 128km (80 miles). Mt Victoria, also on Viti Levu, is the country's highest peak, at 1,322m (4,430ft).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Methodist and Hindu with Roman Catholic and Muslim minorities. The 1997 Constitution of Fiji guarantees freedom of religion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fijians are a very welcoming people and visitors often experience local hospitality. Informal casual wear is generally acceptable.<br />
<strong><br />
Tips for visiting villages:</strong> Before visiting on your own, it is customary to purchase a bundle of unpounded <em>yaqona</em> (kava) - the traditional <em>sevusevu</em> (gift). When approaching the village, visitors should not enter immediately but wait until greeted. They will then be taken to the chief or <em>turaga ni koro</em> (headman), to whom the kava should be offered. Visitors who are accepted by the chief will be assigned a guide and host.<br />
<br />
Once inside the village, please also note the following: visitors should dress modestly and not wear shorts or hats, and women should not have their shoulders bare; shoes should always be taken off when entering someone's house or any other village building; visitors should speak softly and not raise their voices too much as this may be interpreted as expressing anger; visitors should show respect but be cautious about praise as Fijians will feel obliged to make a gift of an object if visitors show too much liking for it; Fijians will always, out of custom, ask visitors to stay or eat with them; visitors who spend a night in the village should reward their host with a useful gift of similar value for each member of the party; money is acceptable if it's offered as a goodbye <em>sevusevu </em>and not direct payment.</p><br />]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs used are Australian-style with two flat angled blades and one vertical grounding blade.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama since 2014 (previously interim prime minister since 2007).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Jioji Konrote since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fiji has come a long way since the days of being referred to as the 'Cannibal Isles' by European sailing ships, back when mariners carefully avoided its shores because of its fierce warriors and treacherous waters.</p><p>The first inhabitants came from Melanesia, some 3500 years ago, and established a hierarchical society based on clans. Little is known of the islanders' history before the arrival of Europeans in the mid 17th century. The establishment of plantations destabilised the economy resulting in serious friction between the Fijians and Europeans.</p><p>In 1874, Fiji became a British colony. Large numbers of workers from India were imported to develop a plantation economy, accounting for the islands' present ethnic mix. After gaining independence in 1970, the moderate conservative Alliance Party governed without interruption. However, Fiji's political situation was to be anything but stable, with friction between ethnic Fijians and Indo-Fijians dominating politics over the last few decades, and resulting in several military coups over the last 30 years. In 1987 a republic was declared following a coup and after another in 2006 Fiji's then president, President Ratu Josefa Iloilo, suspended the constitution and appointed himself head of state in early 2009.</p><p>Later that year, Fiji's failure to hold democratic elections saw the country become the first nation to be expelled from the Pacific Islands Forum; a few months later, Fiji was suspended from the Commonwealth of Nations because Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama refused to hold elections by 2010.</p><p>After years of delays a new Constitution was enacted and elections were finally held in September 2014 with Bainimarama's FijiFirst party winning a resounding victory with 59.2 per cent of the vote as Fiji was re-admitted to the Commonwealth.</p><p>Perhaps not surprisingly Fiji has relatively large armed forces – almost 4000 active soldiers and sailors with a further 6000 reservists – and has contributed to several UN peacekeeping missions.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>&bull; Before 2012 the traditional Cibi war dance was performed by the Fijian national rugby team before each match. After it was decided the Cibi was a celebration of victory it was replaced by the new Bole war cry – an acceptance of a challenge.</p><p>&bull; The population of Fiji has the world highest proportion of practicing Methodists, some 34.6 per cent.</p><p>&bull; The Meke dance is an indigenous art form and usually incorporates men's and the women's dances to mark an important event. Some Mekes are generations old.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Fiji]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+679 3229 100</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-high-commission-suva</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+679 3229 100</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1240 and 1300-1600; Fri 0800-1300. Opening hours for visas, consular and immigration: Mon-Thurs 1000-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>47 Gladstone Road<br/>Suva<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Fiji in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 466-8320</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.fijiembassydc.com/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 466-8320</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Suite 710<br/>2000 M Street,NW<br/>Washington<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Fiji High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7584 3661</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.fijihighcommission.org.uk/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7584 3661</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1300, 1400-1700, Fri 0900-1630; Mon-Fri 0900-1200 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>34 Hyde Park Gate<br/>London<br/>SW7 5DN<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A friendly Fijian welcome and broad smiles await you in this tropical paradise of beautiful beaches, blue lagoons and swaying palm trees. Renowned for stunning sunsets, breathtaking waterfalls, awesome surf, and pristine rainforests, Fiji unsurprisingly draws thousands of visitors to its shores each year.</p><p>Chief among the attractions has to be the cyan-blue sea. It may look tranquil and majestic, but beneath the surface it's teeming with life. Amid multicoloured reefs, the intrepid can explore over 1,500 fish species. You'll also find five species of sea turtle, sharks, dolphins and even whales around Fiji. You can't come here without snorkelling or diving at least some of the time.</p><p>Beyond the sealife, you'll find ample opportunities to go hiking, while birdwatchers love the islands for the abundance of winged species. There are many forests to explore, especially on the island of Kadavu, which is practically roadless, and even more so on the Garden Island of Taveuni.</p><p>Perhaps above all, though, it's the people that make Fiji. Comprising more than 300 islands, the country is a vibrant melting pot of cultures, where East Indian, Polynesian, Melanesia, Chinese and European converge to form a unique cultural medley. English is widely spoken, which means communication is a breeze. You can also expect locals to give you the warmest welcomes, and don't be surprised if they invite you into their homes.</p><p>If, somehow, you tire of the beaches and wildlife of the islands, you'll find Suva to be an intriguing cultural hub, with a jumble of colonial and modern architecture. Laid out over lush hills by the sea, the capital is home to half of the country's population and is the biggest city in the South Pacific. If you like to party, Fiji isn't all laid-back, either, with Suva offering up a large dose of irreverent nightlife.</p><p>Brimming with colourful attractions, awe-inspiring scenery, friendly people and cultural and sporting activities aplenty, Fiji offers something for everyone. From the wanderlust-suffused traveller to the hedonistic sports junkie, this archipelago at the crossroads of the South Pacific is tourist heaven. And, best of all, there's an array of accommodation and activities to suit all tastes and budgets.</p>A friendly Fijian welcome and broad smiles await you in this tropical paradise of beautiful beaches, blue lagoons and swaying palm trees.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
