<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Finland" ColCode="fin" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="fi" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Finland]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate of Finland varies greatly depending on the latitude; the relatively temperate climate of the south coast is quite different from the challenging winters in Lapland. Summer is Jun-Aug, winter is Nov-Mar, but snow in Lapland can start around October and linger until May.</p>
<p>July temperatures average 21&deg;C (70&deg;F) in the capital Helsinki and 20&deg;C (68&deg;F) in Rovaniemi. 86. In the far south there is no midnight sun, but around 19 hours of daylight in the summer. In Lapland you can expect midnight sun for up to 2 months.</p>
<p>January temperatures average -7&deg;C (20&deg;F) in Helsinki and -15&deg;C (5&deg;F) in Rovaniemi. Keep in mind that the record low temperatures range from -35&deg;C to -45&deg;C (-31&deg;F to -40&deg;F) regardless of region, and recent years have seen particularly cold winters. Around midwinter the sun will not rise in Lapland, perfect for spotting the northern lights. Further south there will be about 6 hours of daylight during the winter months.</p>
<p>Rainfall is distributed fairly evenly throughout the year in the south, with an average of around 18 days of rainfall in Helsinki per month. The north may be drier, but also particularly plagued by gnats and mosquitoes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In summer, travellers can get away with lightweight clothing in the daytime, but long sleeves and long trousers or skirts may be more comfortable for the evening. Waterproof clothes are useful throughout the year. If you are hiking through forests, wear waterproof boots, long sleeves and trousers to protect against mosquitoes and ticks. In Lapland you will need insect repellent.</p>
<p>In winter, bring appropriate clothing for snowy conditions, including wool under-layers and socks (not cotton) as well as snow boots with a good grip. In the Arctic North, you may need expedition-quality winter clothing. Towns and resorts generally offer these for hire and hotel staff can give recommendations on what you will need.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Finnair&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.finnair.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.finnair.com</a>) and SAS (<a href="http://www.flysas.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.flysas.com</a>) run an excellent network of domestic services. Look out for discounted <em>&auml;kkil&auml;hdot</em> (last minute) fares.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many of Finland's inland waterways are serviced by waterbuses<strong> </strong>and ferries. Popular routes include the Silver Line (<a href="http://www.hopealinja.fi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.hopealinja.fi</a>), which operates between H&auml;meenlinna and Tampere and Tampere and Viikinsaari island, and the Poet's Way (<a href="http://www.runoilijantie.fi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.runoilijantie.fi</a>), which runs between Tampere and Virrat.</p>
<p>Lake P&auml;ij&auml;nne Cruises (<a href="http://www.paijanne-risteilythilden.fi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.paijanne-risteilythilden.fi</a>) runs services on the P&auml;ij&auml;nne Waterway, between Jyv&auml;skyl&auml; and Heinola, Lahti and Suolahti. Roll Cruises (<a href="http://www.roll.fi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.roll.fi</a>) offers cruises around Kuopio.</p>
<p>There are also regular car ferry services around the Lake Pielinen area. All ferries have restaurants or canteens and accommodation on overnight trips is provided in small private cabins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Finnish trains are spacious, comfortable, clean and quiet, thanks to special booths where people can make mobile phone calls. Valtion Rautatiet - VR (tel: 0600 41902, in Finland only or +358 800 166 888; <a href="http://www.vr.fi" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.vr.fi</a>) operates an extensive rail service around Finland. The main lines are Helsinki-Turku, Helsinki-Tampere-Jyv&auml;skyl&auml;, Jyv&auml;skyl&auml;-Kuopio and Helsinki-Sein&auml;joki-Oulu-Rovaniemi.</p>
<p>Prices vary according to the standard of the train; regional trains are cheapest and fast Pendolino trains are the most expensive. Sleeping berths are available on night trains and seat reservations are compulsory on IC and Pendolino services. Children under four travel free and tickets for children aged 4-16 have up to a 40% discount. Special discounts are available for groups, students, and seniors.</p>
<p>There are trams available in Finland but they are mostly available in inner-city Helsinki. The Helsinki Region Transport (<a href="https://www.hsl.fi/en" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.hsl.fi/en</a>), also called the HSL, has an extensive tram network. The service is easily accessible as it has 11 lines, connecting different areas of the inner-city to each other.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Interrail One-Country Pass:</strong> Offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Finland. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence except for one outbound and one inbound train. Travellers under 27 years receive a discount of up to 25% on the standard adult price. Children 11 and under travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Interrail (<a href="https://www.interrail.eu/en" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.interrail.eu</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Finland Pass:</strong> Offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Austria. Travellers under 27 years receive a 20% discount on the standard adult price. Children aged 4-11 can travel for free on their first day of travel. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>In forested areas, heed the signs warning of elk and reindeer crossing the carriageway - many drivers are injured in collisions with deer every year.</p>
<p>Petrol stations are often unmanned but you can operate petrol pumps using banknotes and credit cards.</p><p>Available in every city and from airports and major hotels. Taxis have a yellow &lsquo;taksi&rsquo; sign that is lit when the taxi is vacant. They can be booked at taxi ranks or hailed from the street. In Helsinki, you can call Taksi Helsinki on +358 100 0700. Fares are more expensive at night and at weekends; tipping is not customary. Taxis run by Yellow Line (tel: +358 600 555 555) operate to and from Helsinki Airport.</p><p>In Finland, the legal driving age is 18. A National driving licence or an International Driving Permit and insurance are required.</p>
<p>EU and Swiss driving licenses are both eligible to use in Finland.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 80kph (50mph) on non-urban roads and 80-120kph (50-75mph) on motorways. Seat belts must be worn by all passengers and headlights must be kept on at all times.</p>
<p>Traffic entering from the right has right of way, even when joining a major road from a minor road. Cars towing caravans may not exceed 80kph (50mph). From 01 December until 31 March, snow tyres are a legal requirement; you can hire them from rental firms.</p>
<p>Further information can be obtained from Autoliitto (Automobile and Touring Club of Finland) (tel: +358 9 7258 4400; <a href="https://www.autoliitto.fi/en" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.autoliitto.fi</a>)</p><p>Car hire is available in larger towns and cities from a variety of local and international firms. The minimum age varies from 20 to 25 years depending on the company, but all firms require a minimum of one year's driving experience.</p><p>You can hire bikes in most towns from tourist offices or camping grounds. HSL city bikes (<a href="https://kaupunkipyorat.hsl.fi/en" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">kaupunkipyorat.hsl.fi</a>; tel: +358 9 425 788 10) are available in Helsinki and Espoo and accept most credit cards.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 80kph (50mph) on non-urban roads and 80-120kph (50-75mph) on motorways. Seat belts must be worn by all passengers and headlights must be kept on at all times.</p>
<p>Traffic entering from the right has right of way, even when joining a major road from a minor road. Cars towing caravans may not exceed 80kph (50mph). From 01 December until 31 March, snow tyres are a legal requirement; you can hire them from rental firms.</p>
<p>Further information can be obtained from Autoliitto (Automobile and Touring Club of Finland) (tel: +358 9 7258 4400; <a href="https://www.autoliitto.fi/en" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.autoliitto.fi</a>)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Larger towns have efficient and integrated bus services, and Helsinki also has a metro and tram service, suburban rail lines and ferry services. Local transport in Helsinki (including the ferries) is covered by a single ticket system with a zonal flat fare and free transfers between services. Multi-trip tickets are sold in advance, as are various passes.</p>
<p>You can buy tickets from the driver, ticket machine or via mobile phone text message (Finnish service providers only). Tramline 3T runs past most of the main tourist attractions - a free brochure in English is available covering the stops along the route.</p>
<p><strong><strong>Helsinki</strong><strong> Card:</strong></strong> This handy discount card (<a href="http://www.helsinkicard.fi" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.helsinkicard.fi</a>) is available for 24, 48 or 72 hours. Once purchased, it allows unlimited free travel on public transport (including the Suomenlinna ferry) and free entry to numerous museums and other sights in the city. Several other large cities offer similar transport cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Finland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">turku</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Finland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tampere</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Finland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">rovaniemi</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">15.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">11.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Finland's national carrier is Finnair&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.finnair.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.finnair.com</a>), which flies direct from numerous countries, including the UK and the USA. Other airlines operating direct flights to Finland from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.ba.com</a>) and Norwegian (<a href="http://www.norwegian.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.norwegian.com</a>).</p>
<p>Major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/finland/helsinki-vantaa-airport">Helsinki-Vantaa Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/helsinki">Helsinki</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 50 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 8 hours 10 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in ticket price.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Helsinki-Vantaa Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.finavia.fi<p>Helsinki-Vantaa Airport is located 19km (11.5 miles) north of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/helsinki">Helsinki</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+358 200 14636.</p>]]><b>Rovaniemi Airport </b><![CDATA[http://www.finavia.fi/airports/airport_rovaniemi<p>10km (6 miles) from Rovaniemi.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Turku Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.finavia.fi<p>7km (4 miles) north of Turku city centre;</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Tampere Airport</b><![CDATA[http://tampereairport.com<p>15km (9 miles) from Tampere;</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Vaasa Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.finavia.fi/airports/airport_vaasa<p>12km (7 miles) from Vaasa;</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Helsinki (<a href="http://www.portofhelsinki.fi" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.portofhelsinki.fi</a>), Turku (<a href="http://www.port.turku.fi" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.port.turku.fi</a>), Mariehamn (&Aring;land; <a href="http://www.visitaland.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.visitaland.com</a>) and Vaasa (<a href="http://www.vaasa.fi/port" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.vaasa.fi/port</a>). Car ferries sail daily to Finland from Stockholm and other Swedish ports, as well as from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tallinn">Tallinn</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/estonia">Estonia</a>).</p>
<p>International ferry companies include Viking Line (tel: +358 600 41577; <a href="http://www.vikingline.fi/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.vikingline.fi</a>) and Tallink&nbsp;Silja Line (tel: +49 40 547 541 222; <a href="http://www.tallink.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.tallink.com</a>). Note that many locals use the international ferries for overnight 'booze cruises' as duty-free alcohol is sold on board; therefore they can be noisy and crowded at weekends.</p>
<p>Finnlines (tel: +358 10 34350; <a href="http://www.finnlines.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.finnlines.com</a>) runs ferry services to Finland from Rostock and Travem&uuml;nde (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a>).</p>
<p>Several major international cruise lines call at Finnish ports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trains run daily to Helsinki from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-petersburg">St Petersburg</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a>. Contact Valtion Rautatiet - VR (+358 923 192 902 (from abroad); <a href="http://www.vr.fi" target="_blank">www.vr.fi</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Interrail:</strong> Offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 30 countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in European countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence except for one outbound and one inbound journey. Reductions of up to 25% are available for travellers under 27 with the Interrail Youth Pass. Children aged 11 and under travel for free on their first day with a Child Pass as long as they are with an adult using an Adult Pass. Travellers 60 or over get a senior discount. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Interrail (<a href="https://www.interrail.eu/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.interrail.eu</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail: </strong>Offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Local and international calls can be made from street-side telephone booths and, in larger cities, tele-centres. Most public telephones operate using a pre-paid card purchased from R-kiosks, shops and post offices. Shops also sell cards that can be used to make discounted international calls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies and GSM 900/1800 coverage is excellent - as you might expect from the home of Nokia. You may find it cheaper to buy a Finnish SIM card, available for about &euro;15, which includes &euro;10 of calling credit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is widely available in hotels, restaurants and on public transport. There are also hotspots in some cities. Most large conurbations have commercial internet cafes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Finland has a strong and independent media with privately-owned newspapers that reflect a broad spectrum of political views. Public communications network <em>YLE</em> provides national radio and TV programming. Freedom of the press is enshrined in Finnish law, and Finns read the newspapers avidly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0900-1800, with regional variations. Helsinki's central post office (Elielinaukio 2, 00100 Helsinki) is open Mon-Fri 0800-2000, Sat 1000-1600, Sun 1200-1600.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0900-1800, with regional variations. Helsinki's central post office at Mannerheiminaukio 1, 00100 Helsinki, is open Mon-Fri 0700-2100, Sat-Sun 1000-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire modernist masterpieces</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Finns are rightly proud of Alvar Aalto, a giant of 20th-century architecture, and Jyv&auml;skyl&auml;, an appealing Lakeland university town, contains many of his most famous buildings. Come August, Jyv&auml;skyl&auml; revs into action as it hosts the Finnish round of the World Rally Championship.</p>]]><p><b>Brave the cold for ice fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Every winter, thousands of Finns drill holes in the ice and try their luck at the masochistic sport of ice fishing, with a bottle of <em>Kossu</em> (Finnish vodka) on hand to keep the chills at bay. Of course, if you want to avoid hypothermic conditions, you could always go fishing during the summer by a lake or the shore.</p>]]><p><b>Celebrate Midsummer</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go up north and you will find the sun never truly sets during the summer months, and Finns take full advantage of the 24-hour daylight to party through the night. Midsummer is also the time when thousands of locals retreat to their <em>m&ouml;kit</em> (summer cottages) in the countryside to enjoy the great Finnish outdoors.</p>]]><p><b>Delve into Sámi culture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The capital of S&aacute;mi culture in Lapland, the tiny village of Inari is home to the wonderful Siida museum and the Pielpaj&auml;rvi Wilderness Church, a meeting place for reindeer herders since at least 1646. Nearby Lemmonjoki National Park is the largest in Finland, and a popular destination for trekkers and gold-panners.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Karelian culture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Split in two by the Russian border, the district of Karelia marches to the beat of its own drum. It&rsquo;s famous for its Orthodox Christian culture, unique cuisine, distinct language, traditional villages and its centuries-old religious festivals. It is also the setting of the Finnish national epic, the <em>Kalevala</em>.</p>]]><p><b>Don your skis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>During the icy Finnish winters, cross-country skiing is not just the most efficient but often the only way to get around. There are marked tracks all over the country, including in many national parks. Fans of downhill skiing and snowboarding should head to the hills of Lapland for an exhilarating time.</p>]]><p><b>Eat and drink al fresco in Oulu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Famed for its beer terraces and technological whizz-kids, Oulu is one of the most appealing cities in Finland, particularly in summer, when stalls selling wild berries and seasonal foodstuffs fill the marketplace. Stock up on supplies for a picnic on the bird-filled wonderland of nearby Hailuoto Island.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy culture and nightlife in Turku</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The oldest town in Finland, Turku gazes across the archipelago towards Stockholm in Sweden. The main attractions include the town&rsquo;s magnificent medieval castle, stately cathedral and intriguing museums, while the lively nightlife, centred on the floating 'boat bars' moored along the Aura River, provides ample light relief after dark.</p>]]><p><b>Escape to the snow-covered wilds</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Point your nose northwards and keep going until you reach Finland's Arctic wilderness. Mystical and awe-inspiring Lapland is home to traditional S&aacute;mi reindeer herders, around 300,000 reindeer and three spectacular national parks, as well as, of course, the region&rsquo;s most famous resident: Santa Claus.</p>]]><p><b>Explore handsome Helsinki</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Finnish capital is aesthetically pleasing; its architecture reflects its Russian and Swedish past as well as the more recent Scandi-style modernism of famous Finnish architects. Good design is ubiquitous; almost every caf&eacute; and shop will have a quirky chair, chic lamp or covetable coffee cup you&rsquo;ll wish you had in your own home.</p>]]><p><b>Go climbing in Kilpisjärvi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the far northwest corner of Finland, a tiny spit of land juts out between Sweden and Norway. Climb from the village of Kilpisj&auml;rvi to picturesque Saana Fell or Halti Fell, the highest peak in Finland, and look out over three countries from one spot.</p>]]><p><b>Harness up huskies</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are few more thrilling experiences than whizzing across the snow on a traditional Arctic sled. After some expert instruction, you&rsquo;ll be put in the driving seat to mush your very own dog sled through the wintery Finnish landscape. There are numerous dog-sled centres in Lapland, such as Hetta and &Auml;k&auml;skero.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the waters of Lakeland</b></p><![CDATA[<p>&lsquo;Land of a thousand lakes&rsquo; may be Finland&rsquo;s nickname, but also an understatement; there are in fact 187,888 of them. They provide a natural adventure playground for swimmers, canoeists, fishermen and boating enthusiasts, as well as people who just appreciate the soothing calm of still waters. With one lake per 26 Finns, there is more than enough space for everyone. The heart of the lake country is Lakeland in eastern Finland.</p>]]><p><b>Meet Santa Claus</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nudging into the Arctic Circle, Rovaniemi is home to Santa Claus Village, where there are child-friendly, Santa-themed attractions and the opportunity to meet Santa Claus himself. Explore SantaPark, where you can take part in Elf school, make gingerbread biscuits with Mrs Gingerbread and even send greetings from the Post Office.</p>]]><p><b>Party at Finnish Festivals</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Some of Finland's festivals are just plain bizarre. Attendees engage in rock mimes for Oulu&rsquo;s Air Guitar World Festival, husbands haul their wives like sacks of potatoes for the Wife-Carrying World Championships in Sonkaj&auml;rvi, Naantali's laziest resident is tossed into the sea on Sleepyhead Day, and thousands of people go down the Vantaa river and drink beer in rubber boats during the annual <em>Kaljakellunta</em>, or Beer Float festival. It&rsquo;s safe to say festivals and parties in Finland are very unique.</p>]]><p><b>Scan the night skies</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Searching the Arctic skies for the spectacular Northern Lights (Aurora Borealis) takes a lot of dedication but is definitely worth it in the end. Watch the spectacle transform the skies over Finland into a psychedelic light show during the polar night (<em>kaamos</em>) from November to May.</p>]]><p><b>Sleep outdoors in Savonlinna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Famous for its medieval castle and its summer opera festival, Savonlinna is an enchanting jumping-off point for exploring Lakeland. The surrounding lakes and forests are full of camping grounds that provide a perfect base for watery activities and birdwatching.</p>]]><p><b>Stay overnight in a lighthouse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The southernmost destination in Finland, Bengtsk&auml;r lighthouse is an impressive building perched alone on an island of bare rocks. The tallest lighthouse in the Nordics, Bengtsk&auml;r functions as a home to lighthouse keeper Paula Wilson, and she runs it as a hotel between June and September. The granite sauna dating back to 1907 is available for guests to use.</p>]]><p><b>Sunbathe on the beaches of Pohjanmaa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See a different side of Finland in the Swedish-speaking villages that sprawl along the west coast near Vaasa. Also known as Ostrobothnia, this region offers long sandy beaches, warm summer weather, forested islands full of swimming elks, and quaint wooden villages such as Jakobstad and Kristinestad.</p>]]><p><b>Sweat it out in a sauna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sweating your troubles away in a steamy sauna is one of the quintessential Finnish experiences. Most hotels and holiday cottages have saunas, but there is a special magic to the J&auml;tk&auml;nk&auml;mpp&auml; smoke sauna just outside Kuopio, and the super-modern architecture of L&ouml;yly in Helsinki&rsquo;s Hernesaari district is sure to impress.</p>]]><p><b>Try exhilarating watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>When the Finns can't ski on snow, they do the next best thing: ski on water. The 1,000-plus lakes of the Lakeland region provide some fantastic opportunities for water-skiing, jet-skiing and sailing. Many holiday cottages and outdoor centres offer water-sports facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$252.5 billion (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Metals, electrical and optical equipment, machinery, timber and scientific instruments, paper and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, petroleum and petroleum products, chemicals, transport equipment, iron and steel, commodities, machinery and electronic industry products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Russia, Sweden, the Netherlands, China and the UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Finnish economy was sluggish in the 1990s but bounced back in the early years of the new millennium. As a result, the nation has a budget surplus and low levels of debt. Their economy began to dip after the 2008 financial crisis but Finland eventually returned to growth in 2016. They saw the economy grow by 3.3% in 2017, and economic growth is expected to continue at a rate of 2-3% per year.  </p>
<p> The Finnish economy has traditionally been driven by the export of timber and paper and heavy manufacturing, but the rise of the Nokia mobile phone company made Finland a leading light in the world of telecommunication &ndash; which along with optics account for nearly 25% of Finnish exports. Finland's GDP per capita is just above US$47,000, which puts it on par with the most successful Western European economies.  </p>
<p> Although only 7.5% of its land is used for agriculture, Finland is virtually self-sufficient in basic foodstuffs such as grain, dairy products and root crops. However, industry is heavily dependent on imported components. Finland has exploited its geographical position to develop strong trading links to Scandinavia, Western Europe and Russia. The national airline Finnair has massively expanded its network, particularly in Asia, significantly increasing the number of tourists visiting Finland en route to other countries.  </p>
<p> Unemployment continues to be a problem in rural areas - the overall rate stands at just under 8%, but this is inflated by the statistics from Lapland and North Karelia, where unemployment regularly exceeds 15%. In southern Finland, the rate is closer to 5%. Although the economy has been liberalised, the traditional network of social welfare services remains strong - helped by a low rate of population growth - and Finland ranks consistently highly on standard-of-living indices. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople are expected to dress smartly, although trousers and a shirt are becoming more common than the traditional suit-and-tie. Most Finnish businesspeople speak English as well as Swedish and/or German. Finns are naturally reserved and do not like speaking for the sake of it. Loud or talkative people are sometimes viewed with suspicion, though an open-minded, global perspective have in recent years made Finns more accepting of foreign mannerisms.  </p>
<p>Punctuality is essential for business as well as social occasions. A handshake and verbal introduction is customary when meeting for the first time, regardless of gender. Business cards should always be exchanged. Be aware of the holiday seasons in Finland; many Finns take a winter holiday in February, and business virtually shuts down for the summer holidays from late June to the end of July.  </p>
<p>Meetings and business deals are often conducted by telephone or at a sauna. Although saunas are regarded as retreats in other countries, in Finland they have a more flexible purpose.  </p>
<p>Standard office hours are 0800 to 1615 Monday to Friday, although many businesses open earlier and close later in major cities. Some open on Saturday morning.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1615, though some places stay open till 1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Keskuskauppakamari (Central Chamber of Commerce of Finland)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (9) 4242 6200
					Website:http://www.chamber.fi
					Address: Aleksanterinkatu 17,World Trade Center Helsinki,Helsinki,101]]><b>FINPRO in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 8600 7260
					Website:http://www.finpro.fi/
					Address: 177-179 Hammersmith Road,Finland Trade Centre,London W6 8BS,]]><b>Finland Convention Bureau (Information on Conferences/Conventions)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (9) 668 9540
					Website:http://www.finlandconventionbureau.fi/
					Address: ,Fabianinkatu 4 B 11,Helsinki,130]]><b>FINPRO</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 800 134 344
					Website:http://www.finpro.fi/
					Address: ,Porkkalankatu 1,Helsinki,181]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>As you might suspect for a nation dominated by water, seafood plays an essential role in Finnish cuisine. Salmon, herring and other fish are cooked fresh or served smoked and pickled in cold courses. Meat comes in various forms, including the ubiquitous meatballs and HK Sininen Lenkki sausage.</p>
<p>Reindeer, elk and bear meat are served as delicacies. In summer and autumn, look out for tender new potatoes, fresh fish, fresh peas, wild mushrooms and a fabulous assortment of wild berries, which are often used in jellies and preserves.</p>
<p>Finns drink more coffee than anyone else in the world and <em>kahvilat</em> (cafes, singular <em>kahvila</em>) are found in every village and town square. They&rsquo;re also partial to beer. And vodka. And wine.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><ul><br />    <li><strong>Sk&auml;rg&aring;rslimpa:</strong> Rye bread loaf sweetened with molasses, a speciality of the archipelago region.</li><br />    <li><strong>Karjalanpiirakka:</strong> A savoury pastry from Karelia, stuffed with rice pudding and eaten with egg butter.</li><br />    <li> <strong>Lihapullat:</strong> Beef and egg meatballs, traditionally served with lingonberries and gherkins.</li><br />    <li><strong>Poronk&auml;ristys:</strong> Saut&eacute;ed reindeer eaten by the S&aacute;mi. </li><br />    <li><strong>Pullat:</strong> Sweet cardamom-flavoured buns &ndash; a traditional accompaniment to coffee.</li><br />    <li><strong> Leip&auml;juusto:</strong> Cow&rsquo;s milk cheese, oven-baked or fried leaving it brown on the outside with a squeaky interior. Traditionally eaten with cloudberry jam.</li><br />    <li><strong>Viili:</strong> A type of soured milk, eaten like yoghurt.</li><br />    <li><strong>Silakat:</strong> Breaded fried herring seasoned with salt.</li><br />    <li><strong>Perunarieska:</strong> A flatbread made from potato, often served with gravlax.</li><br />    <li><strong>Lakka:</strong> Cloudberries, native to Lapland. They look like yellow or orange raspberries and have a unique flavour. Cloudberries cannot be cultivated and therefore are picked by hand in the wild.</li><br />    <li><strong>Koskenkorva:</strong> Commonly referred to as Kossu. A clear, distilled grain spirit usually served ice-cold and straight up. </li><br />    <li><strong>Berry liqueurs:</strong> Try mesimarja (arctic bramble), lakka (cloudberry) and mustikka (bilberry).</li><br /></ul></p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Waiter service is common in restaurants. Bars and cafes are usually counter service. Alcohol is served until half an hour before the restaurant closes.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A service charge may be added in restaurants. Tipping is otherwise not expected, but appreciated.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18 years; 20 for anything over 22%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Finns are enthusiastic party people, and going out is usually a lively affair, even in small towns. Friday and Saturday are the big party nights, but many locals break the week by going out on 'little Saturday' - Wednesday night - when things can get as lively as they do at weekends.</p>
<p>Most large towns have nightclubs and even small villages have restaurants that become bars later in the evening. At clubs, there are often floorshows and live bands as well as DJs playing dance music and Finnish pop. Vodka bars are popular amongst young and trendy urbanites; in rural areas, traditional 'country dances' are still a popular activity. Look out for Finnish tango, which fuses the classic Argentinian beat with a Nordic sense of melancholy. The minimum age at nightspots serving alcohol is generally 18, though this can range up to 25. Nightclubs are typically open until 0200, or up to 0400 at weekends.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Duty-free:</strong> Anyone permanently resident outside the EU can claim a refund of 12-16% on goods that cost more than &euro;40 at the time of departure from the EU. Retailers (look out for the 'Tax Free for Tourists' sign) will provide a cheque that can be redeemed at airports, ports or major land borders.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800, Sat 0900-1500. Many large shopping centres are also open 0900-2100 during the week and Sat 0900-1800; some also open on Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the hotels in Finland belong to large national and international chains and rooms tend to be functional rather than luxurious or charming. Business travellers are the hotels' primary customers and room rates are significantly cheaper at weekends, as well as in late June and July. Rates generally include a shared sauna and a breakfast buffet. Hotels are graded from <strong>1 to 5 stars</strong> and prices are significantly higher in Helsinki and in Lapland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cheaper accommodation is available at guest houses known as <em>matkakoti</em> in towns and cities. These budget lodgings range from doss-houses for travelling workers, with basic rooms and shared bathrooms, to cosy family homes that rent en-suite<em> </em>rooms to paying guests. Prices vary widely according to facilities and location, but a simple breakfast is nearly always included.<br />
Bed and breakfast accommodation is widely available in the countryside in family homes or farmhouses. These cosy lodgings provide an excellent opportunity to experience the rural way of life and you can take full advantage of the surrounding countryside for walks and other outdoor activities. Most bed and breakfasts have a sauna and many offer lunch and dinner or facilities for self-catering. Unless you speak Finnish, it is wise to book via the Finnish Tourist Board, the local tourist office or the organisation <em>Lomarengas</em> (<a href="http://www.lomarengas.fi/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.lomarengas.fi</a>). Graded from <strong>1 to 5 stars</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the hotels in Finland belong to large national and international chains and rooms tend to be functional rather than luxurious or charming. Business travellers are the hotels' primary customers and room rates are significantly cheaper at weekends, as well as in late June and July. Rates generally include a shared sauna and a breakfast buffet. Hotels are graded from <strong>1 to 5 stars</strong> and prices are significantly higher in Helsinki and in Lapland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the hotels in Finland belong to large national and international chains and rooms tend to be functional rather than luxurious or charming. Business travellers are the hotels' primary customers and room rates are significantly cheaper at weekends, as well as in late June and July. Rates generally include a shared sauna and a breakfast buffet. Hotels are graded from <strong>1 to 5 stars</strong> and prices are significantly higher in Helsinki and in Lapland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;If you are suddenly taken ill or involved in an accident during a visit to Finland, treatment is available for travellers from the European Economic Area at the same subsidised cost as for Finnish citizens. However, you must produce a European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). Comprehensive insurance is advised for all other nationals, but first check with your country's health department to see if a reciprocal cover agreement is in place with Finland. Australia, for example, has such an agreement as long as long as citizens carry their Medicare card. The emergency number to call an ambulance is 112.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food in Finland is safe to eat and usually prepared in accordance with hygiene guidelines, although care should be taken when purchasing food from unlicensed stalls. Tap water is also safe, although drinking from streams, lakes and rivers &amp;ndash; however clean they look &amp;ndash; isn&amp;rsquo;t recommended as even the most inviting-looking water can harbour parasites.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Campers and trekkers should take precautions against tick bites; immunisation against tick-borne encephalitis is recommended if visiting rural areas in the south (particularly the Archipelago). Mosquitoes are a pest during the damp summers, particularly in the north - bring mosquito repellent and topical cream to stop bites becoming infected.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>May Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Sunday :
							20 May </p><p>Midsummer :
							23 June </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Independence Day :
							06 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>St Stephen's Day (Tapaninp :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Finland is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the UK, you are entitled to buy fragance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. However, if you are importing alcohol, you must be able to show it is for personal use when amounts exceed the following:</p>
<p>&bull; 20L of alcoholic drinks up to 22% volume.<br />
&bull; 90L of wine (including a maximum of 60L of sparkling wine).<br />
&bull; 110L of beer.<br />
&bull; 10L of alcoholic drinks over 22% volume.&nbsp;</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Finland without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine or 16L of beer or 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume by one person.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers.</p>
<p>Alcohol limits apply to travellers aged 20 and over for spirits and aged 18 and over for other alcoholic drinks. Tobacco allowances apply to travellers aged 18 and over. Passengers importing tobacco products from inside or outside the EU must ensure each unit has a health warning printed on it in Finnish and in Swedish as well as the tar, nicotine and carbon monoxide quantities; passengers may only import 200 cigarettes, 100 cigarillos, 50 cigars and 250g of tobacco not labelled in this way.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Electric-shock batons, radar detectors, knuckle dusters, stiletto blades, endangered plant species (unless licensed in certain cases), pirated goods and certain plants from Russia (e.g. apple and pear trees).</p>
<p>Restricted imports include narcotics, firearms and ammunition, pets, pot plants and nursery plants, and endangered animal species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Endangered plant species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol &euro;) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10 and 5 cents. Note that 1 and 2 cent coins, while valid in other eurozone countries, are not used in Finland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency and traveller's cheques can be exchanged in banks, post offices and at bureaux de change in major cities, ports and airports. Banks tend to charge higher commissions. As there are direct train and bus links from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/helsinki">Helsinki</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-petersburg">St Petersburg</a> in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a>, it is easy to exchange Euros for Russian Roubles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major international credit and debit cards are widely accepted.</p><p>ATMs are found in every town and even in small villages.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques can be exchanged at banks or exchange offices (at a lower commission), and can be used to pay for goods in some tourist-oriented shops. Travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros, Pounds Sterling or US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1630 (regional variations may occur).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Finland is a signatory to the 1995 Schengen Agreement.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60/&pound;50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Schengen visa is valid for 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate (or consular section of embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow five to 10 working days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers who do require a visa must show proof of sufficient funds when applying, which can be in the form of recent bank statements or traveller's cheques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa holders can only extend their visas in exceptional circumstances, such as <em>force majeure</em> or for humanitarian reasons.</p>
<p>If staying longer than three months, non-EU nationals require a residence permit; contact the nearest embassy or the Finnish Immigration Service (<a href="http://www.migri.fi" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.migri.fi</a>) for further information.</p>
<p>EU nationals do not require a residence permit, but must register with the local police within three months of entry into Finland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets require a microchip, rabies vaccination and pet passport. To fight against the Echinococcus-tapeworm, dogs require a deworming treatment. The treatment needs to happen at least one and at most five days before entering Finland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[60.930432]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[24.785156]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>338,145 sq km (130,558 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5,532,365 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>16.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Helsinki.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With Sweden to the west, and Russia to the east, the history and politics of Finland have been shaped by its location. The national character of the Finns has been further coloured by the water-logged landscape - the country is hemmed in by the Gulf of Bothnia and the Gulf of Finland and 10% of its landmass lies underwater.</p>
<p>Finland has over 179,000 islands, including the 98,050 islands in its 188,000 inland lakes. The Saimaa Lake system in the southeast of the country is the fourth largest lake in Europe.<br />
<br />
By European standards, Finland is very sparsely populated, and around 73% of the country is forested. In the south and southwest, the forest is mainly pine, fir and birch; in Lapland, in the far north, scattered dwarf birch forests give way to Arctic tundra.<br />
<br />
Most of the national forests are managed for timber, which is used for the manufacture of furniture, paper and fibreboards and for domestic heating and warming Finland's two million saunas. Finland's forests are said to be the most sustainably managed in Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>70.9% Lutheran, 1% Finnish Orthodox; there are also Baptists, Methodists, Free Church, Roman Catholics, Jews and Muslims. 26.3% of the population are unaffiliated with any religion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If invited to someone's house for dinner, lateness (over 10 minutes) is seen as a discourtesy.</p>
<p>Shoes are always removed before entering the house and a gift for the host, such as a bottle of wine or a bunch of flowers, is well received. Shoes should be removed when entering someone's home. Shaking hands is customary as a greeting and guests are expected to refrain from drinking until the host or hostess toasts their health with <em>kippis</em> (Finnish) or <em>sk&aring;l</em> (Swedish). When toasting, make eye contact with everyone around the table, and take a sip of your drink; shots of liquor are not expected to downed all-in-one. Do expect your glass to be refilled frequently by the host or hostess.</p>
<p>Most Finns prefer practical, casual clothing, except for special occasions. &lsquo;Alternative&rsquo; fashion, piercings and tattoos are popular among younger Finns; not surprising for a country where heavy metal bands top the charts regularly.</p>
<p>Although renowned for their liberal attitudes, Finns can appear to be rather reserved with strangers, so do not be alarmed if conversations start slowly. This sense of composure will often disappear after a few drinks, or in the sauna.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Juha Sipil&auml; since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Sauli Niinist&ouml; since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Finland&rsquo;s first settlers lived in the region around 120,000-130,000 years ago. During the Iron Age, the land was inhabited by the Finnish Proper, Tavastian, Karelian, and S&aacute;mi cultures. The settlers spoke dialects belonging to the Finno-Ugric group (except S&aacute;mi who speak several distinct Uralic languages), quite different from the Indo-European languages spoken throughout most of the rest of Europe.</p>
<p>After centuries of violent conflict in the region, Finland ended up under Swedish rule around the 14th Century until 1809 when Alexander I of Russia invaded. Finland became a Grand Duchy of Russia and the capital was moved from Turku to Helsinki, closer to St. Petersburg and further away from Swedish influence. The period of Russian rule was marked by famine &ndash; the 1866-1868 famine killed 15% of the population in Finland &ndash; but also a strong nationalist movement, popular after the national epic Kalevala was compiled from folk stories dating back thousands of years. Progressive movements like women&rsquo;s suffrage gained traction quickly; Finland was the first country in the world to implement full universal suffrage in 1906. In the following year the Finnish people elected the world&rsquo;s first female members of parliament. In 1917, Finland finally gained independence from Russia.</p>
<p>Under the Paris Peace Treaties 1947, the Finns were forced to cede most of their Karelian territory to the USSR and pay reparations, resulting in more than 400,000 Karelian refugees being displaced. Since the fall of the Soviet Union there has been some debate over whether Russia should return Karelia to Finland, but this has not yet led to any formal discussions between the two powers.</p>
<p>Since joining the EU in 1995, the focus in Helsinki has switched towards Europe, and also the development of relations with the newly independent Baltic states of the former USSR, with whom there are cultural and linguistic links.</p>
<p>For decades, Finnish domestic politics was dominated by the Social Democratic Party (SDP) and the Centre Party (known as 'Kesk'), which led a long series of coalition governments. In recent years, however, the political landscape in Finland has shifted, with the emergence of the right-wing National Coalition Party (Kokoomus, referred to as 'Kok') and the populist far-right &lsquo;True Finns&rsquo; party, both of whom entered a coalition alongside the Centre Party in 2015, booting the long-standing SDP&rsquo;s into opposition.</p>
<p>Social Democrat Tarja Halonen, Finland&rsquo;s first female president, took office at the beginning of 2000 and remained there until 2012. National Coalition Party&rsquo;s Sauli Niinist&ouml; took over the role has since taken over the role.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Finland has the highest number of heavy metal bands per capita in the world. There are around 2,800 heavy metal bands in Finland.<br />
&bull;	Another thing Finland has in abundance? Saunas. It is estimated there are around two million of them serving a population of 5.5 million &ndash; that&rsquo;s more than one for every three people.<br />
&bull;	The average Finnish person consumes 12kg of coffee per year (compared to an annual world average of around 1.3kg per person). They also drink more milk per capita than anywhere else in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Finland in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7838 6200</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.finemb.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7838 6200</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1230, 1330-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Belgravia<br/>38 Chesham Place<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8HW<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Finland in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 298 5800</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.finland.org/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 298 5800</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1200, 1300-1615.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Embassy Row<br/>3301 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Finland]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+358 9 2286 5100</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-helsinki</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+358 9 2286 5100</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1630.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/> Itäinen Puistotie 17<br/>Helsinki<br/>00140<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Finland is the big surprise of the Nordic countries, a natural wonderland with over 179,000 islands and more trees than people. With miles of empty wilderness, the Finns are uniquely in tune with their natural surroundings. This is a nation where people can flip from office work to foraging for wild mushrooms in a heartbeat.</p>
<p>The culture of the Finns has been shaped by the historic tug-of-war between Sweden and Russia, leaving dotted enclaves such as Russian-tinted Karelia, and the Swedish-speaking regions of &Aring;land and Ostrobothnia. Even the Finnish language is an anomaly, curiously related to Hungarian.</p>
<p>For most, the gateway to Finland is Helsinki. A friendly and surprisingly small capital city, here historic churches rise above tidy public squares and stone wharfs are crowded with market traders and ferryboats. It&rsquo;s probably the best place to encounter Finland&rsquo;s famous party spirit, especially during the light nights of midsummer.</p>
<p>Vast areas are protected by Finland's 40 national parks, providing fantastic opportunities to spot birds, reindeer, elks and bears. Around 10% of Finland is covered by water and 75% of the country is covered by forests, providing a natural adventure playground for trekkers, mountain-bikers, cross-country skiers, dog-sledders, as well as fishing and watersports enthusiasts. No wonder sisu (meaning &lsquo;hardiness&rsquo;) is seen as integral to the Finnish character.</p>
<p>The cosmopolitan south, with its bustling cities and sleek, modern design sensibilities (this is, after all, the home of Alvar Aalto and Marimekko) seems a long way from rugged Lapland, where the S&aacute;mi people have been herding reindeer for millennia. For tourism purposes, Lapland is also the home of Father Christmas, ensuring a busy Christmas season at the Santa theme park near Rovaniemi.</p>
<p>Perhaps Finland's most famous contribution to world culture is the sauna &ndash; with an estimated 2 million of them, there are more saunas than cars in Finland. Enjoying a visit to the sauna, ideally after a bracing dip in a wilderness lake, is practically mandatory for all visitors.</p><p>Finland is the big surprise of the Nordic countries, a natural wonderland with more trees than people and more islands than any other nation in the world. With endless miles of wilderness and 188,000 lakes on their doorstep, the Finns are uniquely in tune with their surroundings. Even committed urbanites retreat to wooden cottages in the country during the brief warm summers to swim and fish in the lakes and gather wild berries and mushrooms in the woods, before unwinding with a sauna and a glass of <em>kossu</em> (Finnish vodka).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
