<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="France" ColCode="fra" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="fr" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[France]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A popular year-round destination, France has an affable climate boasting long hot summers and cool winters, which bring snow to higher ground. Summer (June-August), when it is warm and sunny across much of the country, is peak tourist season. If you&rsquo;re visiting at this time, prepare to face crowds at major sights, attractions, and coastal resorts, particularly along the French Riviera.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Southern France remains balmy throughout spring (March-May) and autumn (September-October), which are decidedly quieter times to visit. Prices are also considerably cheaper. The crowds return during the ski season (December-March), packing out resorts in the Alps and Pyrenees, which offers excellent conditions for skiing.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Northeastern areas have warm summers and colder winters with rainfall distributed throughout the year and snowfall likely in winter.&nbsp;The Atlantic influences the climate of the western coastal areas from the Loire to the Basque region, where the weather is temperate and relatively mild with rainfall throughout the year. Summers here can be very hot and sunny &ndash; sunburn is a risk if you&rsquo;re unprepared.</p>
<p>One of the prettiest natural spectacles occurs in Provence between the last week of June and first week of August, when the lavender fields in The Luberon burst into full bloom.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Light breathable clothing for summer and waterproof winter gear for the mountains all year round. In winter, even the Mediterranean resorts often require a sweater or jacket for the evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main airline connecting towns and cities within France is Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com/" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>). Other options include easyJet (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.easyjet.com">www.easyjet.com</a>), Ryanair (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ryanair.com">www.ryanair.com</a>) and Air Corsica (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aircorsica.com">www.aircorsica.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Car ferries known as &lsquo;bacs&rsquo; connect the larger islands on the Atlantic coast with the mainland; they also sail regularly across the mouth of the Gironde. The island of Corsica is served by ferries operated by Maritima Ferries. Services run from Marseille, Nice and Toulon to Ajaccio, Propriano, Porto-Vecchio, L'Ile Rousse, Porto Torres, and Bastia on the island. Corsica Ferries/Sardinia Ferries (tel: +33 4 9532 9595; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.corsicaferries.com">www.corsicaferries.com</a>) also offers services from Corsica to the mainland. <br />
<br />
There are almost 9,000km (5,592 miles) of navigable waterways in France, and all of these present opportunities for holidays. The main canal areas are in the north (north and northeast of Paris) where most of the navigable rivers are connected with canals; the east, where canals link the Rhine, the Moselle and their tributaries; Brittany and the Loire on the rivers Vilaine, Loire, Mayenne and Sarthe; and Burgundy, where the Sa&ocirc;ne and many old and picturesque canals crisscross the region.  Several other beautiful waterways cannot be forgotten: the Seine (from Auxerre to Le Havre, but sharing space with commercial traffic), the Rh&ocirc;ne (a pilot is recommended below Avignon), and the Midi (including the Canal du Midi, connecting the Atlantic with the Mediterranean) are among the most notable and historic rivers France has to offer.  Each of these waterways offers a variety of scenery, a means of visiting many historic villages and localities, and an opportunity to learn much about rural France at a leisurely pace. <br />
<br />
Cruising boats may be chartered with or without crews, ranging in size from the smallest cabin cruiser up to converted commercial barges (<em>p&eacute;niches</em>), some of which can accommodate up to 24 people, plus crew. Hotel boats (large converted barges with accommodation and restaurant) are also available in some areas, with a wide range of prices and comfort levels. For further information, contact the national or regional tourist board.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>SNCF (tel: 3635, in France only or +33 892 353 535; <a href="http://www.sncf.com" target="_blank">www.sncf.com</a>) operates a nationwide network. AutoTrain (<a href="http://autotrain.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">autotrain.voyages-sncf.com</a>) is a car-carrying rail service running between Paris Bercy and a handful of destinations in the south of France.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within France. The pass covers two journeys free-of-charge in the passenger's country of residence: one journey to and one journey from the border. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail France Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within France. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Cheap fares:</strong>&nbsp;various kinds of tickets in France (including Family and Youth Tickets) offering reductions. In general, the fares charged depend on the day of the week and time of day you&rsquo;re travelling; timetables giving further details are available from SNCF offices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Environmental badges are obligatory for Paris, Lyon and Grenoble. Cars that are licensed abroad also need environmental badges, which can be bought on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.crit-air.fr">www.crit-air.fr</a>.</p>r<p>Motorways and main roads are generally in excellent condition. The bulk of smaller roads are well maintained, but some more remote routes can be in poor condition.</p><p>Almost all regions are served by a bus network, although these tend to operate over relatively short distances and services can sometimes be infrequent.</p><p>Taxis are widely available in all towns and cities. Train stations are the most logical place to find a rank.</p><p>A national driving licence is acceptable. An international sign, distinguishing your country of origin (eg GB sticker or plate), should be positioned clearly on the vehicle. However,  EU nationals taking their own cars to France are strongly advised to obtain a Green Card, although it's not compulsory. You must also carry the car's registration document.</p><p>The minimum age to drive a car in France is 18, and 16 for a motorcycle under 125cc. The minimum age for hiring a car in France ranges from 21 to 25. Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (56mph) outside built-up areas, 110kph (68mph) on dual carriageways separated by a central reservation, and 130kph (81mph) on motorways.</p>
<p>Visitors who have held a driving licence for less than three years may not travel faster than 80kph (56mph) on normal roads, 100kph (62mph) on dual carriageways and 110kph (68mph) on motorways. Drivers are required to carry a breathalyser kit in the vehicle, however you won't be penalised for not carrying one.</p><p>For emergency breakdown services, dial 17 from a roadside box or call 112 from a mobile.</p><p>Car hire is widely available from international and domestic companies. Most of these require you to be over 21 years old and in possession of a licence for at least a year. You may have to pay a surcharge if you&rsquo;re under 25.</p><p>France is passionate about cycling and much of the country lends itself well to exploration by bike. There's a good number of urban and rural bike paths, as well as an extensive network of minor roads with little traffic. Most cities and towns have at least one outlet hiring bikes; some, such as Marseille and Paris, have a large-scale public bikeshare system.</p><p>The minimum age to drive a car in France is 18, and 16 for a motorcycle under 125cc. The minimum age for hiring a car in France ranges from 21 to 25. Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (56mph) outside built-up areas, 110kph (68mph) on dual carriageways separated by a central reservation, and 130kph (81mph) on motorways.</p>
<p>Visitors who have held a driving licence for less than three years may not travel faster than 80kph (56mph) on normal roads, 100kph (62mph) on dual carriageways and 110kph (68mph) on motorways. Drivers are required to carry a breathalyser kit in the vehicle, however you won't be penalised for not carrying one.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Urban public transport is excellent. There are comprehensive public transport systems in all the larger towns and cities.</p>
<p><strong>Paris:</strong> RATP (R&eacute;gie Autonome des Transports Parisiens) (<a href="http://www.ratp.fr" target="_blank">www.ratp.fr</a>) controls the underground (m&eacute;tro), rail (RER) and bus services in and around Paris. The public transport network is split into several different fare zones and a single ticket allows travel on any of the systems within that zone (although interchange is only permitted on the m&eacute;tro and RER, and not on buses). The Metro's network of 16 lines makes it a good way to get about central Paris. The RER (fast suburban services) operates five main lines connecting most areas of the capital. There is also an extensive network of conventional suburban services run by French Railways (SNCF).</p>
<p><strong>Other cities:</strong> There are trams, trolleybuses and an underground in Marseille; trolleybuses, an underground, buses, trams, and two funiculars in Lyon; and a tramway, bus system, and automated driverless trains in Lille. There are excellent tram and bus services in St Etienne, Nantes, Grenoble, Limoges and Nancy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">France</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">marseille</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.10</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">France</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">lyon</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">France</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bordeaux</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.25</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Air France (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.airfrance.com/">www.airfrance.com</a>). Flights to France are cheapest during off-peak periods&mdash;namely spring and autumn&mdash;while summer and ski season tend to see higher prices.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france/bordeaux-airport">Bordeaux Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france/lille-airport">Lille Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france/marseille-provence-airport">Marseille Provence Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france/nice-cote-dazur-airport">Nice Côte d'Azure Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france/paris-roissy-charles-de-gaulle-airport">Paris Charle de Gaulle Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france/strasbourg-international-airport">Strasbourg International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france/toulouse-blagnac-airport">Toulouse-Blagnac Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france/bastia-poretta-airport">Bastia Poretta Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france/nantes-atlantique-airport">Nantes Atlantique Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france/grenoble-isere-airport">Grenoble-Isere Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 1 hour 15 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The construction of the new A&eacute;roport du Grand Ouest, near Nantes in Brittany, has generated plenty of controversy in France. When the facility does open, it is set to handle an annual capacity of 4 million passengers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The construction of the new A&eacute;roport du Grand Ouest, near Nantes in Brittany, has generated plenty of controversy in France. When the facility does open, it is set to handle an annual capacity of 4 million passengers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bordeaux Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bordeaux.aeroport.fr<p>Bordeaux Airport is situated 12km (7.5 miles) west of central Bordeaux, in the Aquitaine region of southwest France.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+33 5 5634 5050</p>]]><b>Lyon-Saint Exupéry Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.lyonaeroports.com<p>Lyon-Saint Exup&eacute;ry Airport is situated 20km (13 miles) east of Lyon's city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>04 2600 7007.</p>]]><b>Marseille Provence Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.marseille-airport.com<p>Marseille Provence Airport is situated 25km (16 miles) northwest of Marseille.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+33 820 811 414</p>]]><b>Paris-Orly Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeroportsdeparis.fr<p>Paris-Orly Airport is located 14km (9 miles) south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+33 170 363 950</p>]]><b>Paris Charles de Gaulle Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.parisaeroport.fr<p>Paris Charles De Gaulle Airport is located 23km (14 miles) northeast of Paris.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+33 1 7036 3950</p>]]><b>Lille Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.lille.aeroport.fr<p>Lille Airport is situated 7km (4 miles) southeast of Lille.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+33 3 2049 6747</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>France is easily reached from the Atlantic Ocean, the English Channel, and the Mediterranean, meaning it has a large number of seaports. Cross-channel ferry services from the UK frequent such ports as Calais (<a href="http://www.calais-port.com" target="_blank">www.calais-port.com</a>) and&nbsp;Le Havre (<a href="http://www.havre-port.net" target="_blank">www.havre-port.net</a>). <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/marseille">Marseille</a> (<a href="http://www.marseille-port.fr" target="_blank">www.marseille-port.fr</a>) is the largest, busiest port in the south.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International trains run from the channel ports and Paris to destinations throughout Europe. For up-to-date routes and timetables, contact SNCF (tel: 3635, in France only or +33 892 353 535; <a href="http://www.sncf.com" target="_blank">www.sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p>Eurostar (tel: +44 03432 186 186, in the UK; <a href="http://www.eurostar.com" target="_blank">www.eurostar.com</a>) is a service provided by the railways of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belgium">Belgium</a>, France, and the UK that operates  direct high-speed trains from London (St Pancras International) to Paris (Gare du Nord) and to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brussels">Brussels</a> (Midi/Zuid). It takes approximately 2 hours 15 minutes from London to Paris and approximately 2 hours and 10 from London to Brussels. Eurostar also runs a direct service from London to Lyon, Avignon and Marseille, as well as a ski train to the Alps in winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail</strong>: offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 30 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows continuous travel across all countries for 15 days, 22 days, or one month, as well as noncontinuous travel for 7, 10, or 15 days in a month, or five days in a 15 day period . The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month to a certain group of countries that are labeled at the same price level. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations, and couchettes.</p>
<p>The pass covers two journeys free-of-charge in the passenger's country of residence: one outbound and one inbound journey. Price reductions are available for travellers under 27 and children under 12 get a free first day of travel when with an adult using an Adult Pass. Eurostar and some ferry routes offer travel discounts. For instance, check out Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail&nbsp;</strong><strong>Pass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries for non-European citizens or residents. Tickets are valid for continuous travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, two months or three months. Tickets for noncontinuous travel can be purchased for five or seven days in one month or 10 or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in two, three, or four bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are available for both first and second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eurotunnel runs shuttle trains for cars, bicycles, motorcycles, coaches, minibuses, caravans and campervans between Folkestone in Kent, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, and Calais. The journey takes about 35 minutes from platform to platform. Fares are charged according to length of stay and time of year and whether or not you have a reservation. For further information, contact Eurotunnel (tel: +44 8443 353 535, in the UK; <a href="http://www.eurotunnel.com" target="_blank">www.eurotunnel.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Card-only telephones are common, which can be used with pre-paid cards bought from post offices and <em>tabacs</em>. Coin boxes are being phased out throughout the country. International calls are cheaper between Mon-Fri 1900-0800 and all day Sat-Sun. Calls can be received at phone boxes that show the sign of a blue bell. Information in English and other languages can be accessed by pressing the button with a two-flags icon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is excellent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is ubiquitous in France; most hotels, restaurants, cafes and shops offer customers free access to their networks. Some larger towns and cities have free hotspots. Access is also available in internet caf&eacute;s, which are found in most towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>France enjoys a free press and has more than 100 daily newspapers (<em>quotidiens</em>), including an increasing number of free newspapers. Most newspapers are in private hands and are not linked to political parties. State-run Radio France runs services for the domestic audience, French overseas territories and foreign audiences. Daily newspapers include <em>Le Monde</em>, <em>Lib&eacute;ration</em>,  <em>France</em><em>-Soir</em>, <em>Le Parisien</em> and <em>Le Figaro</em>. The main English-language daily is the <em>International Herald Tribune</em>. Outside of the Ile-de-France region, the provincial press is the most popular. International newspapers and magazines are widely available, particularly in the larger cities. <br />
<br />
France 2, France 3, France 5 are national, public TV channels; TF1 and M6 are national, commercial TV channels; Arte is a cultural channel originally launched by French and German public channels; LCI (La Cha&icirc;ne Info) is a rolling news channel; TV5 is an international French-language channel and Canal Plus is a national, subscription channel; T&eacute;l&eacute;vision Num&eacute;rique Terrestre is the national digital terrestrial service.</p>
<p>There is only one daily newspaper in Monaco called Monaco-Matin. French papers&mdash;and the tabloid magazines&mdash;also cover news daily from the principality. A weekly publication, the Monaco Hebdo, covers Monaco's current affairs. The Journal de Monaco is an internal government journal published weekly. Other newspapers include Gazette Monaco-C&ocirc;te d'Azur, Monaco Actualit&eacute; and Monte Carlo Soci&eacute;t&eacute;. French newspapers are widely available, as are English books and magazines. The Riviera Reporter, the only English-language magazine for residents in the French Riviera, is published every two months. Riviera Radio is a privately-run English-language network.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Stamps can be purchased at post offices and <em>tabacs</em>. Post normally takes a couple of days to reach its destination within Europe. In Monaco, expect the same rates as France. There are seven different post offices in the city-state - pick up special Mon&eacute;gasque stamps at any of them.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1900, Sat 0900-1200. In smaller towns and villages, post offices may close earlier and at lunch, while in Paris the main office is open 24 hours, but only to send mail in the evenings. In Monaco, the hours are Mon-Fri 0800-1900, Sat 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Bayeux Tapestry</p><![CDATA[<p>The Bayeux Tapestry, which is one of the most historically important, and unusual, chronicles of its day, is located in the town of Bayeux in Normandy. The 70m-long (231ft) tapestry – technically better described as an embroidery – offers a splendidly vivid depiction of the events leading up to the Norman Conquest of England in 1066. It begins with Harold of Wessex's visit to Normandy and his meeting with Duke William in 1064, and culminates with the flight of the English army at Hastings. All the main intervening events are covered in painstaking detail. Although it was almost destroyed in 1792 when French revolutionaries used it as a wagon cover, the whole tapestry (with the exception of the final section, thought to have depicted William's coronation in Westminster Abbey on Christmas Day 1066) has survived to this day and can still be viewed.</p>]]><br/><p>Carcassonne</p><![CDATA[<p>Almost too picture-perfect to be true, the fortified town of Carcassonne is home to a wealth of monuments from different eras. Rising above the plains of the lower valley, it's somewhere for history buffs and gastronomes alike.</p>]]><br/><p>Cave of Lascaux</p><![CDATA[<p>Discovered by chance in 1940 by a group of teenagers, the cave paintings at Lascaux are considered to be among the world's best examples of prehistoric art. The 15,000-year-old images of bulls, horses and reindeer caused a visiting Pablo Picasso to proclaim, "We have invented nothing". After the discovery of the cave, the increasing levels of carbon dioxide emitted by visitors were found to be damaging the paintings and, as a result, the caves were sealed in 1963, following an order from the French Ministry of Cultural Affairs. In order to compensate for the closure, a precise cement replica of the original caves, known as Lascaux II, was opened to the public in 1983; these caves feature the two most important parts of the original caves, the Great Hall of the Bulls and the Painted Gallery.</p>]]><br/><p>Chartres Cathedral</p><![CDATA[<p>Chartres Cathedral is considered by many to be the finest Gothic cathedral in France, if not in Europe. The Sancta Camisia, the cloth that the Virgin Mary is believed to have been wearing when she gave birth to Christ, was once housed in the town of Chartres. The cathedral itself was first built in 1145, but was destroyed by fire in 1194. The Sancta Camisia remained intact, which led a papal representative to convince the spiritually devastated people of Chartres to build a new cathedral on the same foundations. </p>
<p>The result, which took until about 1260 to complete, is a spectacular combination of early and high Gothic, still attracting hordes of visitors every year. Built of limestone, the cathedral, which set the standard for 13th-century architecture, stands 34m high (112ft) and 130m long (427ft). The cathedral is particularly well known for its asymmetrical spires, its 176 stained glass windows and its numerous religious sculptures.</p>]]><br/><p>Chenonceau Castle</p><![CDATA[<p>Standing on the River Cher, the Château de Chenonceau is probably the most celebrated château of the many that are situated in the Loire Valley. Used as a working mill in the early Middle Ages, the château, which was built by Thomas Bohier in 1513, spans the whole width of the river, seeming to float on water. Often referred to as the Château de Femmes and owned by a succession of powerful noblewomen – including Henri II's mistress Diane de Poitiers, the Queen Regent Catherine de Medici and her daughter-in-law Louise de Lorraine – its developing style and décor benefited from their grace and charm. The interior is well known for its elegant 59m-long (194ft) gallery, for the library used by Catherine de Medici, and for the famous guard room. Visitors can also see Francois I's bedroom, Louis XIV's living room and Diane de Poitiers's bedroom. The castle was purchased by Henri Menier in 1913 and is still owned by his descendants to this day.<br /><br /><br />Address: Château de Chenonceau, 37150 Chenonceaux, France</p>]]><br/><p>Château de Versailles</p><![CDATA[<p>The Palace of Versailles is a magnificent royal chateau that acted as the centre of political power in pre-revolutionary France. Today, the super-sized but beautiful structure remains delicately preserved, drawing huge crowds with its opulent apartments and landscaped gardens. It was built during the reign of Louis XIV, the Sun King, at a time during which the monarchy was at the height of its pomp and power. You'll find priceless artwork, regal luxury and flamboyant design touches at every turn. The palace itself is under 30km (20 miles) from Paris, and represents a fascinating insight into the flavours and grand follies of its day.</p>]]><br/><p>Cité des Sciences et de l’Industrie</p><![CDATA[<p>Located on a large urban renewal site devoted to culture and leisure, Cité des Sciences et de l'Industrie was completed in 1986 with a mandate to educate visitors about science and technology. Designed by the architect Adrien Fainsilber and based on five themes, water and earth, the universe, industry, communication, and man and health, the Cité has welcomed approximately 40 million visitors since it first opened its doors to the public on 13 March 1986, coinciding with the arrival of Halley's Comet. Located in the Parc de la Villette, which was formerly a giant abattoir, covering an area of 55 hectares (136 acres), this highly-innovative complex is one of the biggest scientific and cultural centres in the world and is made up of several individual sites. Explora offers visitors activities such as piloting an aeroplane or travelling through the human body; the Géode is a large geodesic dome containing a 1000 sq metre (10,764 sq ft) screen and Cinaxe is a simulator fitted with equipment used to train airline pilots. For children, the Cité des Enfants teaches them how to make a TV show, whilst the Exposition Électricité offers them a chance to learn how electricity is supplied. There is also a 400-tonne (394 ton) submarine in the Submarine Argonaute area, which was the pride of the French Navy during the 1950s and was installed at the Cité in 1989. New exhibitions include L'homme et les Gènes show, which opened in May 2002 and is an introduction to the world of genes, Les Coulisses du Train, which runs until 2 September 2002 and takes visitors behind the scenes of the running of the train, and the spectacular night performance, Poussieres d'Étoiles, which opened in January 2002 and tells the story of the birth of the Universe through giant laser shows and musical creations.<br /><br /><br /><br /><br />Address: Cité des Sciences et de l'Industrie, 30 avenue Corentin-Cariou, 75930 Paris, France</p>]]><br/><p>Claude Monet's House and Water Garden (Maison de Claude Monet et Le Jardin d'eau)</p><![CDATA[<p>The Impressionist painter Claude Monet, who was born in Paris in 1840, spent the latter part of his life in Giverny in Northern France. Monet purchased a house in the village in 1883 and remained there until his death in 1926. Today, visitors can see the renovated house and wander around the beautiful gardens at Giverny. Inside the house, the walls are filled with a collection of Monet's Japanese prints. Visitors can also see a beautiful display of waterlilies in the gardens which greatly inspired the painter and featured in some of his most famous works.<br /><br /><br /> Address: Maison de Claude Monet et Le Jardin d'Eau, Fondation Claude Monet, 27620 Giverny, France</p>]]><br/><p>D-Day Beaches</p><![CDATA[<p>The Allied Landings that took place at dawn on D-Day, June 6 1944, signalled the beginning of the end of World War II. Some 83,000 British and Canadian and 73,000 US troops landed by sea and air along a 64-kilometre (40-mile) stretch of the Normandy coast in northern France. The horrific conditions, with many of the floating tanks sunk before they even reached the beaches, meant that thousands of soldiers never returned. The war cemeteries where many of the soldiers were laid to rest are open to the public, and some contain chapels and memorials. One of the most famous beaches is Omaha Beach, portrayed in Steven Spielberg's film 'Saving Private Ryan', where there is a large American cemetery overlooking the beach at Colleville-sur-Mer.</p>]]><br/><p>Disneyland Resort Paris</p><![CDATA[<p>Opened in 1992, Disneyland Paris, located within the Disneyland Resort Paris, was the Walt Disney Company's first attempt to win the hearts of the Europeans. The park is very much like its American cousin, featuring sections like Mainstreet USA, Discoveryland, Adventureland, Frontierland and Fantasyland, however, enthusiasts rave that the more modern engineering of the French Parks make for a superior experience. Although locals took some time to warm to the park, the resort's success eventually led to Disney opening a second theme park, Walt Disney Studios Park, in March 2002.</p>]]><br/><p>Mont Saint-Michel Abbey (Abbaye du Mont Saint-Michel)</p><![CDATA[<p>Normandy's most iconic sight draws thousands of visitors yearly with its impossibly photogenic setting: Mont Saint-Michel (Saint Michael's Mount) is a rocky island surrounded by tidal waters one kilometre (0.6 miles) off the coast of Normandy. It was founded in 708 by the Bishop of Avranches, who built a chapel there after the Archangel Michael appeared to him in a dream. Construction started in 1023 and finished some 400 years later. Fashioned from granite, its delicate contours are an extension of the shape of the island and encompass a range of architectural styles, from Norman to Gothic. For centuries, the Abbey was a place of pilgrimage but it has also variously served as a prison, a fortress against the English and a monastery.</p>]]><br/><p>Parc Astérix</p><![CDATA[<p>Opened in 1989, <i>Parc Ast&eacute;rix</i> is a giant theme park based on the adventures of the popular cartoon character, Ast&eacute;rix. Located in the heart of protected forest, north of Paris, the park takes visitors on a humorous journey through ancient Gaul, the Roman Empire and the Middle Ages to the 21st century. Visitors can meet the Gauls of prehistoric times, step back in time to Le Moyen-&Acirc;ge (the Middle Ages), travel through Rome and Ancient Greece, and shake hands with the Three Musketeers. There are around 30 permanent rides at the park, as well as regular shows to entertain visitors.</p>]]><br/><p>Planète Futuroscope</p><![CDATA[<p>Located just outside Poitiers in western France, Planète Futuroscope is a giant 53 hectare-theme park (131 acres) with a difference. With 3-D cinemas, giant screens and interactive attractions, the park offers visitors numerous exhibits and shows using the latest audio-visual technologies. Opened in 1987, this space-age park, which features futuristic architecture including silver spheres and crystal cubes, has more than 20 high-tech attractions. These include Plongeurs sans Limite, a chance for visitors to journey down to the great depths of the blue sea with professional divers Pipin Ferreras and Umberto Pelizzari, and Le Tapis Magique (flying carpet), located in a cathedral-like structure, allowing visitors to watch natural delights pass before their eyes in a giant audiovisual display; a particular highlight is a chance to watch the 3000km (1364 mile) journey undertaken by Monarch butterflies migrating from Canada to Mexico. The park is at the cutting edge of information technology and is an educational day out for adults and children alike where they can discover the wonders of earth and space through innovative interactive displays. The park is one of Europe's biggest moving image parks, offering sophisticated entertainment including the nightly Le Miroir d'Uranie nightly show with spectacular light, water and music displays and the Kinémax attraction which, at 35m-high (115ft) and enclosing a 450-seat cinema, is the largest rock-crystal structure in the world. There are many new attractions for 2002 including Métropole Défi interactive 3D game, Destination Cosmos's journey into space and Sur les Traces du Panda, retracing the expedition made by Ruth Harkness in 1936 to save the Giant Panda in China.</p>]]><br/><p>Regional Nature Park of the Volcanoes of Auvergne (Parc Naturel Régional des Volcans d'Auvergne)</p><![CDATA[<p>Covering an area of more than 395,000 hectares (976,085 acres), the <em>Parc Naturel R&eacute;gional des Volcans d&rsquo;Auvergne</em> was created in 1977 and is home to four volcanic massifs: the <em>Cha&icirc;ne des Puys </em>(<em>Puy de</em> <em>D&ocirc;me</em>, 1465m/4792ft high), <em>Monts Dore </em>(<em>Puy de Sancy</em>, 1886m/6188ft high), <em>Monts du C&eacute;zalier </em>(<em>Signal du Luguet</em>, 1551m/5089ft high) and <em>Monts du Cantal </em>(<em>Plomb du Cantal</em>, 1855m/6086 ft high). There are glaciers, lakes and peatland throughout the park, as well as numerous exhibitions of flora, fauna and traditional architecture. Activities include hiking, riding, cycling, hand-gliding and hot-air ballooning. There are numerous other educational centres located within the park.</p>]]><br/><p>Rocamadour</p><![CDATA[<p>Built into limestone cliffs, with its medieval houses clinging precariously overlooking the gorge of the River Alzou, <em>Rocamadour </em>is a major pilgrimage site. The town is famed for being the site where the body of St Amadour was discovered near the town&rsquo;s chapel in 1166, an event which led to a succession of miracles in the town. Dedicated to the Virgin Mary, the town ranks behind Rome, Jerusalem and Santiago de Compostela as a pilgrimage site. Visitors to the town can climb the <em>Grand Escalier</em> (Great Ladder) to the 12th-century<em> Cit&eacute; Religeuse</em> (Religious City) at the top, which consists of seven chapels. Visitors can also climb the <em>Chemin de Croix</em> (Way of the Cross) for exceptional views of the Dordogne from the ramparts of the 14th-century ch&acirc;teau. Other attractions nearby include the <em>Rocher des Aigles</em> birds of prey conservation centre, the <em>For&ecirc;t des Singes</em> monkey sanctuary and the <em>Grottes de Lacave</em> underground caves.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be part of the Tour de France</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The annual sporting showcase that is the Tour de France remains the world&rsquo;s biggest cycling event, and the route itself (which varies each year) always travels through some of the most picturesque parts of the country. Joining the crowds that throng the roadsides makes for a fantastic experience. Rattle those cowbells...</p>]]><p><b>Coo over Carcassonne</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Almost too picture-perfect to be true, the fortified town of Carcassonne is home to a wealth of monuments from different eras. Rising above the plains of the lower valley like some far-fetched storybook citadel, it's a favourite of history buffs &ndash; and with its current spread of restaurants, a first pick for gastronomes too.</p>]]><p><b>Cross the Millau Viaduct</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Designed by British architect Norman Foster, the astonishing Millau Viaduct is today the tallest bridge in the world. Its modernist structure is made all the more impressive by its rural setting, spanning the valley of the River Tarn in the south. You&rsquo;ll need to pay a toll to cross by vehicle.</p>]]><p><b>Cross to Mont Saint-Michel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Normandy's most iconic sight draws countless visitors yearly with its impossibly photogenic setting: Mont Saint-Michel (Saint Michael's Mount) is a rocky island surrounded by tidal waters 1km (0.6 miles) off the coast of Normandy. It was founded in 708 by the Bishop of Avranches, who built a chapel there after the Archangel Michael appeared to him in a dream.</p>]]><p><b>Cycle the Loire Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Is there a better way to take in the medieval chateaux and sparkling wine caves of the Loire region than on two wheels? The gentle pace of life here has drawn countless artists and writers over the years, and plenty of cyclists as well. Bike hire is easily arranged.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Provence</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This long-eulogised region of southeast France is famed both for its breathtaking countryside and its sense of romance, which combine to create one of the most magical corners of the nation. From medieval hilltop villages to purple fields of lavender, Provence is one of the country's most seductive destinations.</p>]]><p><b>Drive the Alsace Wine Route</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s no shortage of enjoyable French wine trails to explore, but the Route des Vins d&rsquo;Alsace&mdash;a gloriously scenic 170km (106 miles) drive through hushed, hilly countryside&mdash;is arguably the most atmospheric of the lot. Wine can be bought and tasted at roadside cellars. Alsace wines are predominantly white &ndash; the area&rsquo;s dry Rieslings are world-class.</p>]]><p><b>Explore past and present in Brittany</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A region with a deeply individual character, Brittany blends a proud Celtic heritage with a trove of vibrant travel attractions, from prehistoric megaliths and lively port cities to dense forests and dramatic coastlines. Its still-keen sense of independence only adds to the overall ambiance – the Breton language, while not widely spoken, is still very much in evidence.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the energy of Marseille</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Simmering with the colourful urban rhythms of the south, Marseille is a coastal city with a multi-layered history and a character that&rsquo;s part Provence, part North Africa. From the lively buzz of the daily portside fish market to the clamorous throng of its football crowds, it&rsquo;s a city with a boisterous, confident identity that remains very much its own.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the opulence of the Château de Versailles</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Palace of Versailles is a magnificent royal chateau that served as the centre of political power in pre-revolutionary France. Today, the super-sized and beautiful structure remains delicately preserved, and represents a fascinating insight into the grand flavours and follies of its day. You&rsquo;ll find priceless artwork, regal luxury and flamboyant design at every turn.</p>]]><p><b>Follow Bardot to St Tropez</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Synonymous with glamour, glitz, and the various other trappings of the jet-set, St Tropez was 'discovered' by Brigitte Bardot in the 1950s and has been a trendy holiday destination ever since. Over the summer months, shiny mega-yachts pack the town's marina, which sits on the gleaming C&ocirc;te d'Azur.</p>]]><p><b>Hike in Corsica</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The island of Corsica is a wonder once visited, never forgotten. Ruffled with mountain ranges and edged by vertiginous cliffs, it's a place of rugged beauty and age-old heritage. Its hiking trails are among the most celebrated in Europe &ndash; particularly the world-famous GR20, a challenging long-distance trek through the hills.</p>]]><p><b>Kayak the Gorges du Verdon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Considered by many to be the most impressive river gorge in Europe (others have it as France's answer to the Grand Canyon), the Gorges du Verdon reaches depths of up to 700m (2,297ft), with steep banks blanketed in greenery. Join a kayak tour to get onto the water.</p>]]><p><b>Lose yourself in Lyon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There's a great deal more to France's second-largest city than its fabled restaurant scene&mdash;although miss that at your peril, foodies.  When you aren&rsquo;t savouring the cuisine,  you&rsquo;ll discover the art museums, vibrant clubbing scene, riverside walks, and historical old town that make this city an alluring destination. Eurostar can whisk you there from London in five to six hours.</p>]]><p><b>Roll up for the Cannes Film Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The C&ocirc;te d'Azur resort of Cannes bursts to life each spring when its iconic film festival comes to town. La Croisette, the town&rsquo;s seafront promenade, becomes an A-list parade of directors, producers and Hollywood actors, while yachts file along the harbour-side. Even if you don&rsquo;t bag a ticket for a screening, it&rsquo;s a spectacle.</p>]]><p><b>See the cave art of Lascaux</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discovered by chance in 1940 by a group of teenagers, the cave paintings of Lascaux are considered to be among the world's best examples of prehistoric art. The 15,000-year-old images of bulls, horses and reindeer caused a visiting Pablo Picasso to proclaim, &lsquo;we have invented nothing&rsquo;.</p>]]><p><b>Sightsee in Paris</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Anywhere that boasts the Louvre, Eiffel Tower, the Arc de Triomphe, Sacr&eacute;-C&oelig;ur, and Notre Dame Cathedral is more than just another city. Equal parts chic, edgy and drop-dead beautiful, Paris is always cosmopolitan, ever-changing, and unmissable.</p>]]><p><b>Ski the Alps</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The French Alps play host to some of the most famed ski resorts in Europe, among them Courchevel, Val-d'Is&egrave;re, M&eacute;ribel and L'Alpe d'Huez. The region as a whole covers a colossal area and offers superb choices for skiers of all levels. At most resorts, the season runs from mid-December to April.</p>]]><p><b>Take to the peaks in Chamonix</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A magnet for winter sport fans, summer hikers, and serious climbers, Chamonix is France&rsquo;s mountain resort <em>par excellence</em>. In addition to the range of opportunities for physical activity, there are plenty of options for those more interested in enjoying the views. As backdrops go, the Mont Blanc Massif takes some beating.</p>]]><p><b>Watch a game of boules</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Few things are as redolent of the France of old as a game of boules (also called p&eacute;tanque, after the sound made when the balls strike each other), in which players attempt to throw metal spheres as close as possible to a small wooden 'jack'. Expect old men, cloth caps, and a respectful hush.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2.47 trillion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transportation equipment, aircraft, plastics, chemicals, pharmaceuticals, iron and steel, and beverages.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, vehicles, crude oil, aircraft, plastics and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Spain, USA,&nbsp;Italy, UK and Belgium.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>France has the seventh-largest economy in the world, after the USA, China, Japan, Germany,&nbsp;the UK and India, and has an annual per capita income of more than US$42,000. It has a wide industrial and commercial base, covering everything from agriculture to light and heavy industrial concerns, advanced technology, and a burgeoning service sector. <br />
<br />
France is also Western Europe's leading agricultural nation with over half of its land area devoted to farming. The country is famously one of the world's leading wine producers. <br />
<br />
French companies are prominent in many industries, particularly steel, motor vehicles, aircraft, mechanical and electrical engineering, textiles, chemicals and food processing. In advanced industrial sectors, France has one of the world's largest nuclear power industries, which meets about three-quarters of the country's energy requirements, and is a world leader in computing and telecommunications. <br />
<br />
The service sector is dominated by tourism, which has long been a major foreign currency earner. <br />
<br />
In May 2009, France officially entered a recession after its GDP shrank by 1.2% in the first quarter, as a result of the global financial crisis. After four quarters of contraction, however, it then returned to a period of growth. <br />
<br />
Paris is one of the world's leading conference cities. Also in demand are the Riviera towns of Nice and Cannes; other cosmopolitan&nbsp;centres include&nbsp; Lyon, Strasbourg, and Marseille.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople should wear conservative clothes. Prior appointments are expected and the use of business cards is usual. While knowledge of French is a distinct advantage in business dealings, it is sometimes considered impolite to start a conversation in French and then have to revert to English.<br />
<br />
Business meetings tend to be formal and business decisions are taken only after lengthy discussion. When conducting business, entertaining is usually held in restaurants, and the first meeting is devoted to establishing a relationship. <br />
<br />
It is customary to address colleagues with the appropriate <em>Madame</em>, <em>Monsieur</em>, <em>Professeur</em> or <em>Docteur</em> followed by the surname and a handshake. The informal word for &lsquo;you&rsquo; - &lsquo;tu&rsquo; - should only be used once the other person has started to use this him/herself. Business cards (preferably in French and English) should be presented.<br />
<br />
After an initial meeting, kissing on the cheek is the norm. Always say goodbye to people one by one at the end of an event or else you will risk the term: <em>filer &agrave; l&rsquo;anglaise</em> (literally &lsquo;to leave the English way&rsquo;). This is not a good thing.<br />
<br />
France has a 35-hour working week and office hours are generally between Monday-Friday 0830/0900-1700/1800, with a one- or two-hour lunch break during the day. Some offices close early on Friday afternoon.<br />
<br />
In Paris, firmness, not rudeness, is in order. Small talk is an essential part of doing business in Paris, so it is wise to do a quick refresher on French politics and culture prior to the meeting and to take your time getting to the talk of business. Smart, conservative dress is recommended. Business lunches, working dinners and breakfast meetings are common. In addition, whoever fixes the meeting is expected to settle the bill. At formal dinners, diners must wait for the most important guest or the host to give the signal to start eating. Conducting business in August (during the Parisian holiday exodus to the south) is best avoided.<br />
<br />
In Southern France, business attire tends to be smart and chic, with light suits a must in the hot summer months.&nbsp;Due to (sometimes) good-natured rivalry, praise of the capital (unless one's colleague is from Paris) should be avoided. Standard business hours in Southern France are Monday to Friday 0830-1200 and 1430-1800. Lunch meetings are common.<br />
<br />
In provincial areas, breakfast meetings are rare. Normally, meetings are fixed for mid-morning or mid-afternoon, while lunch meetings usually only involve colleagues already involved on a joint project.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0900-1200, 1400-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie de Paris</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 0820 012 112
					Website:http://www.ccip.fr/
					Address: ,27 avenue de Friedland,Paris,75382]]><b>Paris Convention &amp; Visitors Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 0892 68 3000 0
					Website:http://en.parisinfo.com/
					Address: ,25 rue des Pyramides 75001 Paris,,]]><b/><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01) 4069 3700
					Website:http://www.acfci.cci.fr/
					Address: ,France,,]]><b>Assemblée des Chambres Françaises de Commerce et d'Industrie</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>From the baking aromas wafting from its traditional village boulangeries to the Michelin-starred fussiness of its gourmet restaurants, France has an almost unparalleled reputation for food.</p>
<p>Crucially, while the archetypal French dish is a fabulously rich preparation, the national cuisine is in truth as varied as the country's landscape, and much of its prestige comes from the quality of its regional specialities. It&rsquo;s not all about the ultra-exclusive eateries either &ndash; many of the choicest gastronomic treats are simple, affordable and delicious. And did we mention the cheese? <em>Bon app&eacute;tit</em>.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bouillabaisse:</strong> Fish stew, usually containing at least three&mdash;but often far more&mdash;types of fish and shellfish. A Marseilles speciality.<br />
<strong>Cassoulet:</strong> Rich haricot bean casserole, often slow-cooked with various meats including duck, goose, and pork sausages.<br />
<strong>Quenelles de brochet:</strong> Pounded pike formed into sausage shapes and usually served with a rich crayfish sauce. Common in Lyon.<br />
<strong>Souffl&eacute; au Grand Marnier:</strong> Traditional light and fluffy dessert flavoured with orange liqueur.<br />
<strong>B&oelig;uf bourgignon:</strong> A Burgundy dish of beef stewed in red wine.<br />
<strong>Raclette:</strong> Melted cheese served with potatoes and meats. Popular in alpine areas in both France and Switzerland.<br />
<strong>Ratatouille:</strong> A vegetable stew with ingredients commonly including aubergine, tomato, and courgette.<br />
<strong>Salade Ni&ccedil;oise:</strong> A salad originating from Nice, with tomato, tuna, and Ni&ccedil;oise olives.<br />
<strong>Cr&ecirc;pes: </strong>A speciality of Brittany. Savoury, buckwheat versions are known as gallettes.<strong><br />
Wine:</strong> The most popular alcoholic drink in France.<br />
<strong>Calvados:</strong> An apple brandy made in Normandy.<br />
<strong>Pastis:</strong> A popular aperitif. Leading brands include Ricard and Pernod.<br />
<strong>Champagne:</strong>&nbsp;This fizzy wine is just reserved for special occasions in France.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 12 to 15% service charge is normally added to the bill in hotels, restaurants, and bars, but it is customary to leave small change with the payment.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nightclubs can be found in every town and city. Their style and music vary widely, and the entrance price will occasionally include a drink. In major cities such as Paris and Lyon, clubs are sometimes free of charge, although drinks are likely to be more expensive. Nightclubs have a fixed closing time of 0500. Theatres, late-night bars, and caf&eacute;s are widespread.<br />
<br />
Most local tourist offices publish diaries of events, available free of charge. In Paris, magazines like <em>L'Officiel des Spectacles</em>, which comes out weekly on Wednesdays, are sold at newspaper kiosks and list upcoming cinema programmes, exhibitions and other entertainment.<br />
<br />
In the provinces, nights out generally revolve around eating and drinking, although discos are found in the more popular tourist spots. Weekend summer festivals in rural areas are another good form of evening entertainment. As in many parts of the continent, binge-drinking isn&rsquo;t traditionally a prominent part of the French culture. That said, there are some fairly ribald drinking dens to be found, and in many smaller towns and villages, the local bars remain integral parts of the community. In some rural regions, it&rsquo;s not uncommon for people to shake the hands of everyone present&mdash;tourists included&mdash;when entering a bar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases include designer clothing, lace, crystal glass, cheese, coffee and, of course, wines, spirits and liqueurs. Le Printemps and Galeries Lafayette are among the most notable large department stores in Paris. For bargain hunters, bric-a-brac, or <em>brocante,</em> is found in a number of flea markets (<em>march&eacute; aux puces</em>) on the outskirts of town, most notably at the Porte de Clignancourt in Paris. Antique centres are also common. Most towns have fruit and vegetable markets on Saturday, while out-of-town hypermarkets sell everything from foodstuffs to electrical equipment.</p>
<p>Individual regions often have particular food or drink products closely associated with the local area. Assuming you can transport these home without too much difficulty (smelly cheese and long plane journeys aren&rsquo;t a great pairing, for example), they make for terrific&mdash;and often cost-effective&mdash;souvenirs. Prime examples include cider and galettes from Brittany, camembert from Normandy, bottles of first-rate fizz from Champagne and macarons from Paris.</p>
<p>The capital city, in fact, offers more or less anything and everything French that you might want. Some of the prices might be a little on the eye-watering side, but you&rsquo;ll find everything from fine art, one-off collectables and perfume to designer shoes, luxury stationery and postcards, and prints of old Paris. Almost every store will offer to gift-wrap bought goods while you wait at the counter. And be aware that some of the city&rsquo;s top-end outlets are seriously exclusive &ndash; you may have to press a buzzer to gain entry.</p><p>Department stores open Mon-Sat 0900-1830. Some shops close 1200-1400. Food shops open 0700-1830/1930. Some food shops (particularly bakers) open Sunday mornings, in which case they will probably close Monday. Many shops close all day Monday, or Monday afternoon. Hypermarkets are normally open until 2100 or 2200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>France&rsquo;s hotels run the full gamut from palatial to poky, with international chains, privately owned properties and some of the most bling-encrusted luxury on the planet. Prices are normally displayed by the entrance and within the rooms themselves &ndash; these include taxes and service, but there&rsquo;s almost always an extra charge for breakfast. Expect to pay significantly more for hotel accommodation in Paris. Local tourist offices are a logical place to approach for information on different hotel options, and almost all properties can these days be booked online. An advance amount is usually required as a deposit and &ndash; regardless of the type of hotel &ndash; it&rsquo;s always sensible to make management aware if you intend to arrive late in day. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Following decades of hotels in France being officially graded from 0-4 stars (with a '4 star deluxe' grading being the equivalent of a 5-star property elsewhere), the country now employs a more standard 5-star system. The majority of hotels in the country are government-rated.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Otherwise referred to as <em>chambres d&rsquo;hotes</em>, France&rsquo;s B&amp;Bs represent some of the most characterful, cost-friendly, and appealing accommodation in the country. Invariably family-run affairs, they&rsquo;re far more common in smaller towns and rural areas than in cities. You&rsquo;ll usually be given the option of taking an evening meal with the hosts (at an extra cost). This can be a superb way to learn more about the local way of life, sample home cooking and yes, even practise your French. There are various websites that will point you towards the best properties. There are various websites to point you towards the best properties. Word of mouth is also responsible for a lot of recommendations. Such is the disparity in cost between urban and rural regions, meanwhile, that you may well find that <em>chambres d&rsquo;hotes</em> offer a charming room for the same price as a single bed in a boxy inner-city budget hotel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>France&rsquo;s hotels run the full gamut from palatial to poky, with international chains, privately owned properties and some of the most bling-encrusted luxury on the planet. Prices are normally displayed by the entrance and within the rooms themselves &ndash; these include taxes and service, but there&rsquo;s almost always an extra charge for breakfast. Expect to pay significantly more for hotel accommodation in Paris. Local tourist offices are a logical place to approach for information on different hotel options, and almost all properties can these days be booked online. An advance amount is usually required as a deposit and &ndash; regardless of the type of hotel &ndash; it&rsquo;s always sensible to make management aware if you intend to arrive late in day. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Following decades of hotels in France being officially graded from 0-4 stars (with a '4 star deluxe' grading being the equivalent of a 5-star property elsewhere), the country now employs a more standard 5-star system. The majority of hotels in the country are government-rated.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>France&rsquo;s hotels run the full gamut from palatial to poky, with international chains, privately owned properties and some of the most bling-encrusted luxury on the planet. Prices are normally displayed by the entrance and within the rooms themselves &ndash; these include taxes and service, but there&rsquo;s almost always an extra charge for breakfast. Expect to pay significantly more for hotel accommodation in Paris. Local tourist offices are a logical place to approach for information on different hotel options, and almost all properties can these days be booked online. An advance amount is usually required as a deposit and &ndash; regardless of the type of hotel &ndash; it&rsquo;s always sensible to make management aware if you intend to arrive late in day. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Following decades of hotels in France being officially graded from 0-4 stars (with a '4 star deluxe' grading being the equivalent of a 5-star property elsewhere), the country now employs a more standard 5-star system. The majority of hotels in the country are government-rated.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;If European visitors or any of their dependants are suddenly taken ill or have an accident during a visit to France, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). Full travel insurance is advised for all travellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you take regular medication, bring it with you in its original container, ideally clearly labelled. If you have a serious medical condition, meanwhile, it&amp;rsquo;s worth also bringing a signed and dated letter from your GP, detailing your condition and medication &amp;ndash; generic names would be best, as French medicines often use different names.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The level of healthcare on offer is generally of a very high, professional standard, with the same applying to dental care. Staff at local pharmacies are trained to be able to advise on minor complaints, so if you don&amp;rsquo;t speak French, it makes sense to carry a relevant phrase book. Pharmacies are recognisable in towns and villages by a green-cross sign outside the door &amp;ndash; the sign flashes when the pharmacy&amp;rsquo;s open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As ever, health insurance is highly recommended. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay at the time for any healthcare you receive&amp;mdash;whether at hospital or a surgery&amp;mdash;and while costs for a straightforward doctor&amp;rsquo;s consultation aren&amp;rsquo;t too stringent, having an insurance policy in place brings real peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an ambulance is needed, 112 is the EU-wide phone number for the emergency services.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;This being France, the only real problems posed by the local food and drink are mild stomach complaints resulting from overindulgence. Tap water is safe to drink (although you&amp;rsquo;ll find a huge amount of bottled water for sale too) and cooked food, assuming it&amp;rsquo;s come from a hygienic kitchen, is certainly no more risky to consume than that of any developed country. Some travellers steer clear of unpasteurised dairy products due to a perceived risk of disease, while others laud the same products for their perceived health benefits. If you&amp;rsquo;re at all unsure, it&amp;rsquo;s probably best to stick to what you&amp;rsquo;re used to.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Visitors to forested areas should consider vaccination for tick-borne encephalitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In more universal terms, sunburn is perhaps the most common complaint among visitors to France, particularly over the summer months &amp;ndash; temperatures are generally higher in the south but it&amp;rsquo;s wise to be cautious across the country. The usual precautions apply: use a generous amount of sunscreen and be sensible about how long you spend in direct sunlight. Be aware that a breezy day can sometimes mask high temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If walking over a long distance in warm weather, it&amp;rsquo;s advisable to carry and drink plenty of water and to wear appropriate clothing, including a sun hat. Blisters can be another problem for hikers. These can often occur if new walking shoes are being worn across a long distance. Ideally footwear should be worn in before the trip.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day 1945 :
							08 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Bastille Day :
							14 July </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Armistice Day :
							11 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>France is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragrance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22%, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into France by persons over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco (if you enter by air or sea) or 40 cigarettes or 20 cigarillos or 10 cigars or 50g of tobacco (if you enter by land).<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers (reduced to &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Items which are either prohibited or require a licence include weapons and ammunition, drugs (other than those prescribed for personal use), live animals, plant products, cultural artefacts and endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol &euro;) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency exchange can be made in most banks and post offices as well as in some large stores, train stations, airports, and exchange offices near major tourist sites. Shops and hotels are prohibited by law from accepting foreign currency. Travellers should check with their banks for details and current rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard, and Visa are widely accepted across the country. If you&rsquo;re eating at a restaurant, check prior to the meal that your card will be an acceptable form of payment. Even in cities, it&rsquo;s advisable to carry a supply of cash with you at all times.</p><p>Cashpoints compatible with international banking networks are located in all towns and cities, as well as airports, major train stations, and other spots. They usually offer an attractive exchange rate. Those banks that still exchange foreign currencies into local money will always charge a transaction fee, so withdrawing money from an ATM usually represents the most logical means of obtaining euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are accepted nearly everywhere in France. In <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/monaco">Monaco</a>, to avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros, US Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Banking hours in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a> are usually from 1000-1700, Monday through Friday. Throughout the rest of France, banks are usually open from 1000-1300 and 1500-1700, Tuesday to Saturday. Banks often close earlier the day before a public holiday. In Monaco, banks are normally open between Mon-Fri 0900-1200 and 1400-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If visas are needed, a form must be filled out for each individual applicant, including children under 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re coming from a non-Schengen country transiting through an airport in France to travel to another airport in France or in the Schengen area, then unless exempt, you&rsquo;re required to have a short-stay Schengen visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>France is a signatory to the 1995 Schengen Agreement.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit/short-stay Schengen visa: &euro;60. This typically covers tourism, business, and family visits for nationals requiring a visa.</p>
<p>Long-stay visa: &euro;99.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay/Schengen visa: up to 90 days within a six-month period. It can be issued for one entry or multiple entries into the Schengen area and can be valid for up to five years.</p>
<p>Long-stay visa: this is a national visa that entitles you, whatever the reason for your stay, to live in France for more than three months. It is not a Schengen visa. Some categories of long-stay visa are valid as residence permits for the first year of your stay in France.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If France is your main destination in the Schengen area, apply to your local French consulate (or consular section at embassy). In the UK, the French authorities have outsourced the visa application process to a company called TLS Contact (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.tlscontact.com/gb2fr">www.tlscontact.com/gb2fr</a>). TLS Contact charges an additional &euro;30 processing fee (or its GBP equivalent). All Schengen visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some categories of long-stay visa are valid as residence permits&nbsp;for the first year of your stay in France: study visas, some work visas, visas for spouses of French nationals and visitors&rsquo; visas. If you are in one of these cases, when you arrive in France, you must send the OFII form to the relevant regional delegation of the Office Fran&ccedil;ais de l'Immigration et de l'Int&eacute;gration, which will give you an appointment for a medical examination and payment of residence fees. After the first year (in the two months before your long-stay visa expires), you must apply to renew your residence permit at the relevant prefecture for your place of residence.</p>
<p>In all other cases, if you are a foreign national holding a long-stay visa marked '<em>carte de s&eacute;jour &agrave; solliciter'</em>&nbsp;(residence permit to be applied for), you must apply to the prefecture for a residence permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Processing times vary according to nationality and visa type. Allow at least 15 days; appointment waiting times vary from one to 10 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If applying for a visa, you&rsquo;ll be asked to detail how you intend to support yourself for the duration of your stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you need to extend your stay in France for reasons of <em>force majeure</em>, you must,&nbsp;before the date of expiry of your visa,&nbsp;submit an application for '<em>prolongation de visa'</em>&nbsp;(visa extension) with documentary evidence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are able to bring pets into the country from within the EU without them being quarantined, so long as the pets are first fitted with an ISO pet microchip and then vaccinated for rabies and other diseases at least 21 days (but no more than a year) prior to travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[46.642003]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[2.337982]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>551,500 sq km (212,935 sq miles) not including overseas territories.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>65,070,433 (UN estimate 2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>119 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Paris.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>France, the largest country in Western Europe, is bordered to the northwest by the English Channel (La Manche), to the northeast by Belgium and Luxembourg, to the east by Germany, Switzerland, and Italy, to the south by the Mediterranean (with Monaco as a coastal enclave between Nice and the Italian frontier), to the southwest by Spain and Andorra, and to the west by the Atlantic Ocean. The country&rsquo;s loose six-sided shape means it often gets referred to by the informal nickname 'L&rsquo;Hexagone'. <br />
<br />
The island of Corsica, southeast of Nice, is made up of two d&eacute;partements. France is home to an astonishing range of scenery, from the mountain ranges of the Alps and Pyrenees to the attractive river valleys of the Loire, Rh&ocirc;ne, and Dordogne, and the flatter countryside of Normandy and the Atlantic coast. The country has some 2,900km (1,800 miles) of coastline.</p>
<p>Away from the mainland and Corsica, there are a number of French-administered overseas departments and regions outside of Europe. These include Guadeloupe&nbsp;an island in the Caribbean; R&eacute;union Island, located in the Indian Ocean just east of Madagascar;&nbsp;French Guiana,&nbsp;on the northeastern coast of South America;&nbsp;Martinique,&nbsp;another island in the Caribbean and Mayotte, an island in the Mozambique  Channel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Approximately 63-66% Christian, specifically 83-88% Roman Catholic, Protestant 14%; Muslim 5 - 10%; Jewish 1%; unaffiliated 4%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Shaking hands and, more familiarly, kissing both cheeks, are the usual forms of greeting. The form of personal address is simply Monsieur or Madame without a surname and it may take time to get on first-name terms. At more formal dinners, the most important guest or host gives the signal to start eating. Mealtimes are often a long, leisurely experience.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Casual wear is common but some clubs, casinos, and exclusive restaurants warrant more formal attire. Evening wear is normally specified where required. Topless sunbathing is tolerated on most beaches but naturism is restricted to certain beaches - local tourist offices will advise where these are. A smoking ban for workplaces and public spaces has been in place since February 2007.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Edouard Philippe since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Emmanuel Macron since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Prior to the French Revolution in 1789, France was a monarchy known for its colourful (and often extravagant) royals &ndash; not least Louis XIV, or the Sun King, who moved his court from Paris to Versailles in the 1680s. The revolution itself brought about a sea change in the way the whole country was structured, shifting power from the church and nobility to the state.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Napoleonic era oversaw the expansion of the French Empire, before defeat at Waterloo in 1815 resulted in the restoration of the monarchy. Napoleon himself was exiled to a South Atlantic island, where he died.</p>
<p>Back in France, the abdication of King Louis-Philippe in 1848 established the formation of the Second Republic, and since then, different heads of state have led the country. In the latter half of the 19th century, much of Paris&rsquo; famous architecture&mdash;including its avenues of Haussmann buildings and the Eiffel Tower&mdash;was constructed.</p>
<p>In the 20th century, France played an important role in both world wars (where notably, the country&rsquo;s surrender to Nazi Germany in 1940 resulted in the temporary Vichy Regime), but the post-war presidency of Charles de Gaulle restored stability. The famous anti-government protests of 1968, however, eventually led to de Gaulle&rsquo;s downfall.</p>
<p>In modern times, Jacques Chirac's reign as French president finally came to an end in 2007 when the ruling party's Nicolas Sarkozy won a decisive victory in the second round of the presidential election. Notable measures taken by his government included boosting growth by reducing taxes.</p>
<p>High unemployment and the financial crisis remained pressing problems, however, and in 2012 Sarkozy failed to be elected for a second term. He was beaten by a relatively small margin by Francois Hollande, who based his campaign on prioritising growth rather than austerity.</p>
<p>Hollande has been faced with challenges of his own, not least when Paris twice came under terrorist attack in 2015. In January, the offices of satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo as well as a kosher supermarket were besieged, before multiple outrages took place in November. History is likely to judge Hollande&rsquo;s spell as leader on the long-term impact of his response to the attacks.<br />
<br />
In 2017, French President Emmanuel Macron assumed office. At age 39, he became the youngest President in the history of France.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Did you know? </strong>    <br />
&bull;	The vital statistics: France has around 1,000 chateaux and roughly 400 kinds of cheese. <br />
&bull;	According to a study carried out by Durex, the French have sex more regularly than any other nationality. <br />
&bull;	King Louis XIX had the shortest reign of any French monarch: 20 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in France]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+33 1 4451 3100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinfrance.fco.gov.uk/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+33 1 4451 3100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1300, 1430-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Paris Cedex<br/>35 rue du Faubourg St-Honoré<br/>08 Paris<br/>75008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[French Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7073 1000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambafrance-uk.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7073 1000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>58 Knightsbridge<br/>London<br/>SW1X 7JT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[French Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 944 6000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambafrance-us.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 944 6000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0845-1230, 1400-1700&lt;br /&gt;
Visa appointments are scheduled from Mon-Fri from 0845-1230. Appointments can be booked online.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>4101 Reservoir Road<br/>Washington<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You could spend a lifetime&rsquo;s worth of holidays in France and still not feel you&rsquo;d done the country justice. It remains the planet&rsquo;s most visited tourist destination, meriting its standing with an almost overwhelming mass of historical treasures, storybook landscapes, and cultural idiosyncrasies.</p>
<p>The teeming glam of Paris makes for one hell of a centrepiece, matching any city on the planet for ambiance, individuality, and set-piece sights. But the real beauty of France, in many ways, lies elsewhere. The country&rsquo;s natural gifts are striking: white sands, hulking mountains, swathes of rolling countryside. It&rsquo;s a land that has inspired dreamers and drinkers, revolutionaries and artists. Little wonder that Francophiles (and it&rsquo;s telling that even the country&rsquo;s devotees have a word to describe them) are found the world over.</p>
<p>You can soak up the A-list beaches of the Cote d&rsquo;Azur, drowse in the timeless greenery of the Loire Valley or gaze up at the monumental peaks of the Alps. Wander the lavender fields of Provence, eat your way round the legendary bistros of Lyon or sample the rugged charm of Corsica. France&rsquo;s cities, coastline, and countryside all have their own endearing rewards, and when taken as a whole, they present a near-perfect visitor package.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s not to say that France is somewhere easily bracketed. When you&rsquo;re walking the moody portside backstreets of Marseille or delving among the sprawling flea markets of Paris, it can be a job to remember that they&rsquo;re a part of the same country as the vineyards of Alsace and the sand dunes of the Atlantic coast.</p>
<p>This diversity, in many ways, is the magic of France. It&rsquo;s why endless magazines, books, and texts have dedicated their works to the joys of the French lifestyle. It&rsquo;s why the national spirit is well-known for its boldness and radiance. And it&rsquo;s one reason why, in a world full of historical wonder and natural beauty, France still draws more tourist attention than anywhere else.</p>
<p>&ldquo;How can one describe a country which has 365 kinds of cheese?&rdquo; once asked former French president Charles De Gaulle. Even today, it's a very good question.</p><p>You could spend a lifetime&rsquo;s worth of holidays in France and still not feel you&rsquo;d done the country justice. It remains the planet&rsquo;s most visited tourist destination, meriting its standing with an almost overwhelming mass of historical treasures, storybook landscapes and cultural idiosyncrasies.  The teeming glam of Paris makes for one hell of a centrepiece, matching any city on the planet for ambiance, individuality and set-piece sights. But the real beauty of France, in many ways, lies elsewhere. The country&rsquo;s natural gifts are striking, with white sands, hulking mountains and swathes of rolling countryside. It&rsquo;s a land that has inspired dreamers and drinkers, revolutionaries and artists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
