<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Gabon" ColCode="gab" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ga" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Gabon]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Equatorial with up to 80% humidity. The dry season is from June to August, and the main rainy season is from October to May. Average temperatures are 25°C (77°F).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight tropical wear, with raincoats advised during the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating domestic flights within Gabon include Nationale Regionale Transport and Allegiance Airways. Note that both airlines are banned from flying within the EU for safety reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferries run regularly along the coast from Libreville to Port Gentil (journey time - 4 hours).</p>
<p>Riverboats ply the Ogou&eacute; River between Port Gentil and Lambar&eacute;n&eacute; (journey time - 10 to 24 hours). Some boats continue on to Ndjol&eacute;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Trans-Gabon Railway<em> </em>is the only railway line in Gabon; it is 410km (254 miles) long and connects Libreville (Owendo station, 10km (6 miles) from the city centre) with Franceville. Stops along the way include Ndjole and Moanda. Plans proposing an extension of the railway to Brazzaville in the Republic of Congo regularly surface.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no road connection between the second-largest city of Port Gentil or any other part of the country.  Check points are common in Gabon and drivers are asked to show passports, driving licence or vehicle registration documents.</p>r<p>Most of the country consists of impenetrable rainforest and the roads are generally of a poor standard.&nbsp;Road travel in the rainy season (October to mid December and mid February to May) is inadvisable.</p><p>And International Driving Permit and international insurance are required.</p><p>Cars may be hired from main hotels and airports, although they tend to be expensive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are extensive share-taxis. There are bus services in Port Gentil and Masuku (Franceville), and share-taxis in other centres. Taxi rates vary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The quickest route to Gabon from the UK or the USA is with Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) via Paris. Other options include flights with Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="http://www.ethiopianairlines.com" target="_blank">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>) via Addis Ababa, Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>) via Casablanca, and Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>) via Istanbul.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 9 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lnew-york-city">New York</a> - 16 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Libreville Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.adlgabon.com<p>The airport is 12km (7 miles) north of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:&nbsp;</strong>Owenda, 10km (6miles) from Libreville. Freight ships to S&atilde;o Tom&eacute; or&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cameroon">Cameroon</a> may take passengers; enquire locally for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>No area codes required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is variable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet is increasingly available; there are a growing number of Internet cafes in Libreville.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mostly, Gabon's media is government controlled and journalistic pressure is subtle but ever-present.<strong><br /></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail from Gabon takes at least one week to Western Europe. Urgent letters should be sent by special delivery to ensure their safe arrival.</p><p>0800-1200 and Mon-Fri 1430-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Explore Bateke and Mayumba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Bateke Plateau, comprising savannah and forest galleries shaped by tumultuous rivers is a known wildlife hotspot. Creatures include forest elephants, buffalos, river hogs, gorillas, panthers, crocodiles, monkeys and parrots. Alternatively, traverse the enchanting Mayumba, a thin strip of land set between sea and lake, where up to 3,000 humpback whales can be seen between July and September.</p>]]><p><b>Gawp at the Presidential Palace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gabon's former president, Omar Bongo, ordered the construction of the Palais Presidential on Libreville's waterfront in the 1970s. Costing an estimated US$800 million, it came close to bankrupting the newly independent nation. Even though visitors are not permitted inside the heavily-guarded palace, you are able to view its spectacular modernist design and take photographs from outside.</p>]]><p><b>Get active on the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The best beaches for peace and quiet are the deserted beaches of Pointe Denis and Ekwata in Gabon's north, and Mayumba and Sette Cama in the south. Both Libreville and Port Gentil have beaches equipped for waterskiing, while Cap Estérias, 35km (22 miles) from Libreville, is a popular water sports centre at weekends. Perroquet and Pointe Denis offer good skin diving.</p>]]><p><b>Go fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Popular among European visitors, many of Gabon's rivers and lakes offer excellent catches, though local fishermen can find the largest variety of fish along the country's 900km (550 mile) Atlantic coast and in the numerous lagoons located at the mouth of the River Ogooué. Equipment can be hired at Port Gentil.</p>]]><p><b>Haggle at Mount Bouet Market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't miss the hustle and bustle of Mount Bouet Market, Libreville's largest market. The hundreds of stalls selling food, textiles, household goods and traditional medicines funnel visitors into narrow maze-like alleys. On the market's outskirts is a more relaxed shopping district, predominantly selling printed clothes.</p>]]><p><b>Study local customs at the National Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The National Museum of Art and Traditions in Libreville, a short stroll from the Presidential Palace, contains some of the most beautiful wood carvings in Africa, especially the indigenous Fang style of carving, which influenced Picasso's figures and busts. The photographs of Gabon in bygone days, and the musical instruments are also worth some time.</p>]]><p><b>Take a forest safari in Lopé National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Easily accessible in the centre of the country, Lopé National Park is Gabon's largest. Its landscape, containing a mixture of savannah and dense forest, provide habitats for lowland gorillas, chimpanzees and forest elephants, as well as a variety of other primates, large mammals and around 350 species of bird which can all be tracked on foot or by car.</p>]]><p><b>Tour Lambaréné’s famed hospital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spanning the Ogooué River, Lambaréné was brought to the world's attention by the lifelong dedication of Albert Schweitzer, a German-French doctor and world-class musician awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1952. Still functioning, the Schweitzer Hospital includes a small museum dedicated to the doctor created from his basic living accommodation.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the craftsmen of M'Bigou</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The villages of M'Bigou and Eteke in Gabon's south are famed for the quality of the normally light grey soapstone extracted from the surrounding hills, and the carvings produced by the craftsmen there that result. The nearby gold mines are also well worth a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Walk the Atlantic coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The winding route leading from Libreville to the beach of Cap Estérias 35km (22 miles) north offers a chance to explore Gabon's natural beauty, such as the forest of giant trees you will pass through. Rocks abound with sea urchins, oysters and lobsters. Cap Estérias itself is a safe place to swim in the ocean.</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at the carved church of St Michael</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The wooden church of St Michael of Nkembo in Libreville is supported by 31 tall and heavily-carved wooden columns, each depicting a scene from Christian and African legend, that were created by a blind Gabonese craftsman. A hall-like structure in comparison to Libreville's other European-style churches, the rich exterior painting depicts St George killing the dragon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$8.3 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, timber, manganese and uranium.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machines and equipment, food, chemicals and construction materials.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, France, Germany, Japan, The Netherlands, UK and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Oil reserves and mineral deposits have allowed Gabon to develop into one of Africa's more successful economies. At US$5,900, Gabon has one of the highest per capita incomes on the African continent.<br /><br />One-third of GDP comes from the oil industry; there are also significant mining operations producing manganese and uranium. There are confirmed deposits of iron ore (which are substantial) and also a number of rare metal ores.<br /><br />There is a small manufacturing base engaged in oil refining and the production of plywood, paints, varnishes and detergents, dry batteries, cement, cigarettes and textiles. Future industrial growth in this sector is likely to be limited by a shortage of skilled labour, high costs and inadequate infrastructure.<br /><br />Meanwhile, agriculture remains important, as it still employs two-thirds of the working population. Gabon produces coffee, sugar cane, rubber and some other cash crops - also cassava and maize for domestic consumption.<br /><br />Both the timber and fishing industries, while making strong contributions to the national economy, may be the subject of future expansion as export earners, although timber production is likely to be limited by environmental concerns. Like all primary producers, Gabon remains vulnerable to fluctuations in commodity prices.<br /><br />Gabon is a member of the Central African Customs and Economic Union (CEEAC) and of the CFA Franc Zone.<br />Further information can be obtained from the Chambre de Commerce, d'Agriculture, d'Industrie et des Mines du Gabon (see <em>Commercial Information </em>below).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits are required. French is the principal language used in business circles. Translators and interpreters are available through the embassy. Strong business ties remain with France despite competition from the USA and Japan.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1200 and 1430-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce, d'Agriculture, d'Industrie et des Mines du Gabon</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 722 064
					Website:
					Address: ,PO box 2234,Libreville,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Gabonese food is a distinctive and delicious blend of traditional African ingredients and French flavours, though it jostles for space on local menus with Senegalese, Cameroonian and Congolese dishes, which are commonly served here.</p><p>Meals typically consist of meat or fish served with stewed vegetables and a sauce, generally sporting very hot chilli flavours. Having maintained strong links with France since independence, French staples such as croissants and baguettes can be found in the cities.</p><p>In more rural areas of the country, dishes tend to be simpler, relying on cassava, rice or yams. Bush meat such as monkey and antelope has been a traditional part of the Gabonese diet.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Braised fish</strong>: Bass or red fish braised with chilli flavours and served with rice or French fries.<br />
<strong>Brochette</strong>: Meat skewered and slow-roasted over an open fire.<br />
<strong>Nyembw&eacute;</strong>: Chicken in a sauce made from the pulp of palm nuts.<br />
<strong>Manioc leaves</strong>: Served wilted in place of spinach, the leaves are a common addition to sauces and stews.<br />
<strong>Atanga</strong>: Also called &lsquo;bush butter&rsquo;, the hard atanga fruit is boiled and the flesh spread on baguettes.<br />
<strong>Mustard chicken</strong>: Cooked with onion, garlic and lemon juice.<br />
<strong>Bouillon de poisson</strong>: Fish stew.<br />
<strong>Beignet</strong>: Deep-fried doughnut, the best are liberally covered in sugar.<br />
<strong>R&eacute;gab</strong>: Recognised throughout the country as the best local lager.<br />
<strong>Plantain fritters</strong>: Deep-fried slices of plantain, as tasty as they sound.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10 to 15% unless service is included in the bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are nightclubs in Libreville with music and bars. Food is often served, although this can be expensive. The African quarter of Libreville is full of fairly cheap places to eat and drink. There are also casinos at several hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Libreville, there are two bustling markets at Akebe-Plaine, Nkembo and Mon-Bouet. Stone carvings can be bought on the outskirts of both, fashioned by a group of carvers who have adapted traditional skills for the tourist market. Crafts from local villages can also be bought from stalls in the streets or from the villagers themselves. African (Fang) mask carvings, figurines, clay pots and traditional musical instruments can also be bought.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1200 and 1500-1900. Some shops close Monday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are private hotels and hotel chains in Libreville and other major cities and towns but, like most of the accommodation in Gabon, they are expensive. Tourist facilities, including tourist camps, are being expanded throughout the country, especially along the coast and in towns close to the national parks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are private hotels and hotel chains in Libreville and other major cities and towns but, like most of the accommodation in Gabon, they are expensive. Tourist facilities, including tourist camps, are being expanded throughout the country, especially along the coast and in towns close to the national parks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are private hotels and hotel chains in Libreville and other major cities and towns but, like most of the accommodation in Gabon, they are expensive. Tourist facilities, including tourist camps, are being expanded throughout the country, especially along the coast and in towns close to the national parks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Travellers in rural areas should take a first-aid kit with anti-tetanus and anti-venom serums. Medical facilities are limited. Comprehensive medical insurance is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Diarrhoeal diseases, including giardiasis, and typhoid fevers are common. Hepatitis E is widespread. Hepatitis B is hyperendemic. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Leishmaniasis and dengue fever can be transmitted by worms and insects. Epidemics of meningococcal disease may occur, particularly in the savannah areas and during the dry season. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Renovation Day :
							12 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Women's Day :
							17 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							06 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Independence Days :
							16 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Gabon without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes or 125 cigars or 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 3L of wine and 1L of spirits.<br />
&bull; 500g of personal jewellery.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include counterfeit goods, child pornography, non-prescription drugs, and unlicensed arms and ammunition.</p>
<p>Plants, animals and their products require certification.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If exporting any goods of cultural significance, you require a certificate from the Ministry of Culture and Communication.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFA (<em>Communauté Financière Africaine</em>) Franc (XAF; symbol CFA) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of CFA10,000, 5,000, 2,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of CFA500, 100, 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1.<br /><br />Only currency issued by the <em>Banque des États de l'Afrique Centrale</em> (Bank of Central African States) is valid; currency issued by the <em>Banque des États de l'Afrique de l'Ouest </em>(Bank of West African States) is not. The CFA Franc is tied to the Euro.<br /><strong><br />Note: </strong>Libreville is one of the most expensive cities in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gabon is part of the French Monetary Area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard and Visa are not widely accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0730-1130, 1430-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Gabon, a passport valid for more than six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry tourist visa: &pound;60; double-entry tourist visa: &pound;110; multiple-entry tourist visa: &pound;200.</p>
<p>Single-entry business visa (UK residents): &pound;80; double-entry business visa: &pound;150; multiple-entry business visa: &pound;280.</p>
<p>Single-entry business visa (non-UK residents): &pound;100; double-entry business visa: &pound;170; multiple-entry business visa: &pound;280.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Depends on how long you request on your application, so can vary from days up to six months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow five working days for visa applications. An express service is available for an additional fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-0.634990]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[11.739019]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>267,667 sq km (103,347 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,763,142 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Libreville.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gabon is bordered to the west by the Atlantic Ocean, to the north by Equatorial Guinea and Cameroon, and to the east and south by the Congo. The 800km-long (500 miles) sandy coastal strip is a series of palm-fringed bays, lagoons and estuaries. The lush tropical vegetation (which covers about 82% of the interior) gives way in parts to the savannah. There are many rivers and they remain the main communication routes along which settlements have grown. Of the 40 or so Bantu tribes, the largest are the Fang, Eshira, Mbele and Okande. Only a small percentage of native Gabonese live in the towns, as the population is concentrated in the coastal areas and the villages along the banks of the many rivers, following a more traditional rural style of life.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>About 60% Christian (mainly Roman Catholic), the remainder follow Muslim and animist beliefs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dance, song, poetry and myths remain an important part of traditional Gabonese life.<br /><br /><strong>Photography: </strong>It is absolutely forbidden to photograph military installations. In general, permission to photograph anything should be requested first, to prevent misunderstandings.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Daniel Ona Ondo since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Ali Bongo Ondimba since 2009.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The oldest human artefacts to have been discovered in Gabon are stone spearheads dating back to 7000 BC, but little more is known about Gabonese prehistory. The earliest of the present inhabitants are the Pygmies who arrived from central Africa in around AD 1100. They were followed into the region over several centuries by various Bantu tribes including the Fang.</p>
<p>Europeans first discovered Gabon in 1474, when the Portuguese sailor Lopez Gonzalvez entered the Gabon estuary. Between the 16th and 18th centuries the region became part of the Loango Kingdom, though from a European perspective trade became the watchword of the next four centuries, with European empires negotiating with coastal tribes for slaves and ivory from the interior. The slave trade ceased in the middle of the 19th century, but not before it had destroyed the social inter-relationships of the tribes it affected.</p>
<p>Land on either side of the Gabon Estuary was annexed peacefully by the French during the mid-19th century as a province of French Equatorial Africa. The Republic of Gabon moved peacefully into independence in 1960 after a three-year period of internal self-government.</p>
<p>A French-style constitution was adopted the following year and L&eacute;on M'ba became Gabon's first president. After seven years of stormy pluralism, the ruling Parti D&eacute;mocratique Gabonais (PDG) declared Gabon a one-party state, but retained broadly pro-Western policies.</p>
<p>Gabon&rsquo;s current president, President Ali Bongo Ondimba, took office in 2009, and is the son of President Omar Bongo &ndash; one of Africa's longest serving heads of state. From 1990, in common with much of the rest of Africa, Omar Bongo&rsquo;s government effected the transformation from a one-party state to a pluralistic political system.</p>
<p>At the heart of the country's policies lie exceptionally close relations with France. In particular, Gabon is a key supplier to France of uranium and a number of other strategic minerals.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Gabon is home to 80% of the world&rsquo;s gorilla population.<br />
&bull;	President Omar Bongo was one of the longest serving heads of state anywhere in the world, with a presidency lasting 42 years.<br />
&bull;	Gabon&rsquo;s rainforests are home to 777 species of bird.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Gabon in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 797 1000</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gabonembassyusa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 797 1000</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2034 20th Street<br/>Washington<br/>20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Gabon in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7823 9986</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7823 9986</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1500&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>27 Elvaston Place<br/>London<br/>SW7 5NL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gabon is bordered by the Atlantic Ocean, Equatorial Guinea, Cameroon and the Congo. The 800km- (500-mile-) long sandy coastal strip is a series of palm-fringed bays, lagoons and estuaries. The lush tropical vegetation (which covers much of the interior) gives way in parts to the savannah.</p>
<p>There are many rivers along which settlements have grown. Many of the Bantu people are concentrated in coastal areas and villages along the banks of the many rivers. The main cities are Libreville, Port Gentil, Lambar&eacute;n&eacute;, Moanda, Oyem, Mouila and Franceville.</p>
<p>The Republic of Gabon moved peacefully into independence (from France) in 1960. President Omar Bongo, who succeeded L&eacute;on M'Ba as president on the latter's death in 1967 is now one of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/africa">Africa</a>'s longest serving heads of state. In 2003, a change of constitution meant that Bongo could run for office as many times as he wanted and Bongo, now in his 70s, is likely to remain as president for life. Gabon's only problem in the region concerns the island of Mbagne which lies in the Corisco Bay, potentially the site of large oil and gas deposits: occupied by Gabon in 1970, it is also claimed by Equatorial Guinea.</p>
<p>But touristic natural resources are likely to centre around features such as stunning white beaches, an abundance of wildlife, including gorillas, panthers, parrots and elephants, and verdant forests.</p><p>Gabon is bordered by the Atlantic Ocean, Equatorial Guinea, Cameroon and the Congo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
