<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Gambia" ColCode="gmb" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="gm" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Gambia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Gambia lies in a region that has arguably the most agreeable climate in West Africa; the weather is subtropical, with distinct dry and rainy seasons. From mid November to early June, coastal areas are usually dry, while the rainy season lasts from late June to October. Inland, the cool season is shorter, and daytime temperatures are very high between March and June. Sunny periods occur on most days, even during the rainy season.</br></br>Most charter flights run from November to May, coinciding with the time of year when the temperature is most pleasant and humidity is low. Christmas and Easter are the two busiest travel periods, whilst the shoulder seasons represent the best times to arrive if you wish to escape the crowds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight or tropical for most of the year, with rainwear for the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are nearly a dozen points where travellers can cross the River Gambia by boat. Vehicle and passenger ferries between Banjul's commercial port and the town facing it across the river mouth, Barra, run at least once an hour in each direction until late evening. Tour operators run adventure and fishing trips using small motor boats or large converted pirogues, and offer day cruises along the river with lunch or dinner and a live band.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving is often difficult and slow. Road conditions, especially inland, are very poor and heavily potholed with tired tarmac. Vehicles often have to weave slowly and dramatically, or drive adjacent to the road on a dirt rack.</p>r<p>In a country with almost 4,000km of road, just 750km are paved. In the districts around Banjul, the main roads are tarmac. Outside the Greater Banjul area, a much-needed highway building and repair programme has been underway for several years: some main roads are newly surfaced but others are in very poor condition. Throughout the country, most minor roads are unsealed.</p><p>The national bus service connects the major cities and towns throughout the day although departures are irregular and journey times often long.</p><p><strong>Bush taxis:</strong> Apart from private taxis, shared taxis (cars known as &lsquo;sept-place&rsquo;, minibuses or vans known as &lsquo;Gelli-gellis&rsquo;) are the only form of public transport between towns and villages. They wait at their starting point until full then travel along fixed routes, stopping wherever passengers want to get on or off. They are not allowed to enter some areas of the tourist coastal region or Cape Point. Fares are fixed.</p>
<p><strong>Private taxis:</strong> There are two types; neither have meters. Tourist taxis are painted green and are licensed by the Gambian Tourist Authority to operate mainly from ranks in the resort areas; each rank has a noticeboard listing tariffs by destination. Local taxis are painted yellow with green stripes and can be hailed in the street; fares are lower and should be agreed in advance. Both types of taxi can travel anywhere in the country.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><p>An International Driving Permit is accepted for up to three months. A temporary licence is available from the local authorities on presentation of a valid national licence.</p><p>Drive on the right and overtake on the left, but beware that drivers often stick to whichever bit of road is in the best condition. There are almost no streetlights, so take care after dark.</p><p>There is no automobile association or official organisation, but there are lots of improvised garages all along major roads where minor repairs can be made.</p><p>Greater Banjul has a few local and international providers. Alternatively the resort areas are best equipped to supply hire vehicles. It is more common to hire a car and a driver for a daily rate, especially for longer journeys. Driving can be difficult due to variable road conditions; some minor roads become impassable during the rainy season (June to October).</p><p>Available to hire at many hotels and resorts, these are a cheap and convenient way to explore the country as the landscape is flat and distances are short. If you get tired, load the bike onto a bus or bush taxi for a small luggage fee.</p><p>Drive on the right and overtake on the left, but beware that drivers often stick to whichever bit of road is in the best condition. There are almost no streetlights, so take care after dark.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bush taxis (shared cars, minibuses or vans) and private taxis are the only form of public transport in Gambian towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gambia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">serrekunda</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gambia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">jufurreh</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00**</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gambia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">basse</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00*</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gambia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">barra</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gambia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bakau</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no direct scheduled flights to The Gambia from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> at present. Most holidaymakers arrive by charter flight. There are competitively priced charter flights available with Gambia Experience (<a href="http://www.gambia.co.uk" target="_blank">www.gambia.co.uk</a>). Brussels Airlines (<a href="http://www.brusselsairlines.com" target="_blank">www.brusselsairlines.com</a>) flies to Banjul from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brussels">Brussels</a>.</p>
<p>Travellers from North America generally fly via Europe or Dakar as there are currently no direct scheduled flights available.</p>
<p>Flights to The Gambia are most expensive from November to February and cheapest from late June to late September.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 6 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 17 hours (including stopovers).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no airport bus to Banjul city centre but there are plenty of private tourist taxis available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no airport bus to Banjul city centre but there are plenty of private tourist taxis available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Yundum International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Gambia isn&rsquo;t very accessible by boat. Although there are freighters sailing to Banjul and it is possible to take a cabin on board one of these, it isn&rsquo;t done regularly or cheaply.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All road borders are shared with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/senegal">Senegal</a> and connections between the two are reasonably efficient. Private taxis can be hired between Dakar (Senegal) and Barra, from which there is a regular ferry service to Banjul. There is a second crossing point at Farafenni, en route from Dakar to Janjangbureh or westwards to Barra.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are telecentres in the major towns but these are under threat from mobiles. The connection is generally good in main urban centres.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good around Banjul and most other towns, but patchy in remote rural areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Email can be accessed in internet cafes in major towns, where the connection is generally reliable but slow.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>State-run <em>Gambia Radio</em> and <em>Television Service (GRTS)</em> broadcasts tightly-controlled news that is heavily pro-government. Private media are severely restricted, with radio stations and newspapers having to pay large licence fees. The government operates the only national television station, <em>Gambia Television</em>; <em>Premium TV Network</em> is a private satellite channel. Radio Gambia transmits programmes in English and local languages.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>A media bill passed in March 2002 was considered a threat to press freedom. The law set up a commission whose powers range from issuing licences to jailing journalists. In 2004, further legislation was introduced allowing for jail terms for journalists found guilty of libel or sedition. The assassination in 2004 of Deyda Hydara, an editor at <em>The Point</em> newspaper opposed to President Jammeh and one of the press law&rsquo;s leading critics, further raised the stakes. Daily Observer and The Point are daily newspapers in English whilst <em>The Independent</em> and <em>Foroyaa</em> are bi-weekly.</p>
<br />
<br />]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The postal service can be slow and unreliable; letters are generally ok but parcels and larger items frequently get lost. The main post office is on Russell Street, Banjul.</p><p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1215 and 1400-1600, Fri 0830-1215 and 1430-1630, Sat 0830-1215.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire bustling Banjul</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the capital, visit the National Museum, which has some interesting ethnographic displays, then admire the colonial architecture in the area near July 22 Square and climb to the top of Arch 22 for great views over the city. Shop in Albert Market, the city's lively open-air bazaar, for an illuminating glimpse of daily life.</p>]]><p><b>Bask on the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gunjur and Kartong are southern Gambia's most pristine beaches and home to a number of excellent eco-retreats. Alternatively visit Kotu, the best beach along Gambia's main resort strip. Be wary, though: the seas can get a little rough.</p>]]><p><b>Do a little dance</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fancy moving your feet to the local beat? Then book a few lessons with a dance teacher, a master of the <em>kora</em> (Gambia's national instrument) or with a drumming instructor who will be able to help you buy a <em>djembé</em> (drum) from a local craftsman.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Abuko Nature Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk through the tropical forest of the Abuko Nature Reserve, which is within easy reach of the main resort areas and has crocodiles, monkeys, forest antelope, reptiles and over 300 bird species. It is best early in the morning.</p>]]><p><b>Get a bird’s-eye view of the country</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Soar over the fields, villages, creeks and beaches of Gambia by going up in a microlight. Short airborne tours and longer trips can be arranged from the microlight base at the airport.</p>]]><p><b>Go birdwatching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Birdwatching is the most popular pastime for visitors to Gambia. Take a boat into the mangrove creeks of the Tanbi Wetlands around the mouth of the River Gambia, head south to the Tanji Reserve, or travel up-country to the world-renowned Bao Bolong Wetland Reserve to spot some of the country's many resident and migrant species.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about the slave trade</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Upriver from Banjul, explore Gambian colonial history by visiting the exhibition of the slave trade at Albreda and Jufureh – twin villages that were made famous by Alex Haley's novel <em>Roots </em>– then cross to James Island, mid-river, to see its ruined fort.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Kiang West National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Trek through this stunning national park, the most diverse ecosystem in Gambia, to see more flora and fauna than anywhere else in the country. So what can you expect to see? Well, monkeys are the star attraction, but you might also catch sight of leopards, warthogs, hyena, hundreds of bird species and much more.</p>]]><p><b>Mess about on the river</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a long-distance boat trip on the River Gambia, the dominant feature of the country. The River Gambia National Park is the most beautiful stretch of riverine vegetation where you can spot monkeys leaping through the foliage, pelicans feasting on fish and hippos relaxing in this peaceful waterway.</p>]]><p><b>Mind your fingers at Katchikali Crocodile Pool</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Meet a friendly croc at this ancient site, sacred to the Mandinka tribe, in the coastal village of Bakau. The crocodiles, though wild, are well fed and docile. Fertility rites are sometimes held here.</p>]]><p><b>Solve the mystery of Wassu stone circles</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In eastern Gambia, catch sight of the fascinating circles of standing stones around Wassu, the most ancient man-made structures in the country, which date back 1,200 years. The origin of these megalithic circles, which stand between 1m (3.2ft) and 2.5m (8.2ft) tall, is shrouded in mystery but they are thought to mark the prehistoric burial grounds of a society long-since vanished.</p>]]><p><b>Take a tour of Makasutu Culture Forest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join a cultural tour of this beautiful forest park, learning about local medicinal plants and woodland fauna, then take a boat trip by dugout canoe and enjoy a spirited display of local-style music and dance in this award-winning eco-attraction.</p>]]><p><b>Take in some live music</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go to a live session from one of Gambia's many excellent local bands, or a concert featuring stars from neighbouring Senegal, home of Youssou N'Dour, Baaba Maal and many other West African greats.</p>]]><p><b>Watch a wrestling match</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gambia's national sport, <em>borreh</em> (wrestling) was in danger of slipping into the history books until it was revived under President Jammeh. The sport now features in most national events and festivals. Similar to Greco-Roman wrestling, contests, played out against a theatrical backdrop, are ferocious and frequently bloody.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2.4 billion (2009).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Peanut products, fish, cotton, palm products and re-exports.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, fuel, machinery and transport equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>India, China, UK and Senegal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The economy of The Gambia is basically agricultural, with groundnuts (nuts, oil and cattle cake) accounting for 50% of total exports. Tourism is a significant generator of foreign exchange. Forestry and fishing are also important and banking is a new growth area. Rice is one of the main staples; some is homegrown but most is imported. There are no viable mineral deposits. The small but fast-growing industrial sector is dominated by agro-industrial activities.<br /><br />Government economic strategy aims both to stimulate agricultural productivity and position The Gambia as a regional hub for trade, finance and telecommunications.<br /><br />Over the last decade, substantial infrastructural progress has been made although wide-reaching investment in roads, public transport and power generation has been sporadic.<br /><br />Overall, the economy has performed fairly well, achieving annual growth since 2000, with 3.5% growth in 2009. However, despite having benefitted from recent IMF, World Bank and African Development Bank debt relief initatives, The Gambia has external debts of US$165 million (2008) and remains heavily dependent on international aid.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businessmen wear jackets and ties for business meetings. A personal approach is important in Gambian business circles. It is advisable to take business cards; their use is appreciated though not universal.<br /></p><p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1600, Fri 0800-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>The Gambia Investment Promotion and Free Zones Agency (GIPFZA)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 437 7377
					Website:http://www.gipfza.gm/
					Address: PO Box 757,GIPFZA House,48A Kairaba Avenue,Serrekunda,]]><b>The Gambia Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 437 8929
					Website:http://www.gambiachamber.com
					Address: PO Box 3382,55 Kairaba Avenue,Serrekunda,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Although there is a thriving local cuisine and lots of fresh produce to try, Western food is available at most tourist hotels and restaurants. Some hotels and restaurants organise Gambian-style barbecue-buffet nights featuring freshly grilled local fish and chicken, spicy stews and rice dishes.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Benachin</em> (also called 'Jollof Rice', a mixture of spiced meat and rice with tomato puree and vegetables).<br />
&bull; <em>Domodah</em> (meat stewed in groundnut puree and served with rice). <br />
&bull; Chicken <em>yassa</em> (chicken cooked with onions, garlic and lime, served with rice or chips).<em> <br />
</em>&bull; <em>Plasas</em> (meat and smoked fish cooked in palm oil with cassava leaves, served with rice or mashed cassava).<br />
&bull; <em>Mafe</em> (meat stew simmered in sauce thickened with ground peanuts). <br />
&bull; <em>Haako</em> (steamed couscous served with a vegetable sauce).  </p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p><br />With only a few exceptions, Gambian bars and restaurants are more frequented by tourists than locals. Many Gambians don't drink alcohol, and most prefer to entertain at home, only eating out when away from home or on business.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tips are discretionary. A 10% service charge is sometimes included in hotel and restaurant bills.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18 but not strictly adhered to as so few people consume alcohol.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gambian nightlife is fairly subdued, and is concentrated in the coastal resorts and in Serrekunda, the largest city. The resort hotels put on regular performances of Gambian drumming, dancing and fire-eating for their guests; the best of these are highly energetic, and audience participation is encouraged. Hotels and restaurants also organise more tranquil musical evenings featuring traditional music played on the kora, a type of 21-stringed West African lute, and the balafon, a xylophone-style instrument.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>Most of the country's nightclubs and bars are found in the tourist hubs of Bakau and the Senegambia area of Kololi, with a few close to the Kotu and Cape Point hotels. Many feature live or recorded Mbalax music, the region&rsquo;s contribution to world music. Jokor, Serrekunda's long-running garden club, and Wow Night Club in Kololi, both draw large crowds of locals and tourists, and are good places to catch West African bands and DJs. Major concerts featuring rap, reggae and African music stars from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/senegal">Senegal</a> and beyond are held at Dream Park in Kololi, and the Independence Stadium in Bakau. Further inland, the small town of Brikama has a low-key but significant music scene.</p>
<br />
<br />]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hunt down souvenirs and local handicrafts in the various <em>bengdulas</em> (craft markets), dotted around Banjul and the resort areas. Banjul's Albert Market and the sprawling commercial heart of the busy town of Serrekunda are particularly colourful places to browse. Popular purchases include colourful batik wall hangings, handmade clothing, woodcarvings, bead jewellery and traditional djemb&eacute; drums. Beaded belts and ladies' handbags are also popular, as are books and albums made from recycled paper and West African handicrafts using straw, beads, leather, cloth or metal. Fajara, Kololi, Serrekunda and Brikama have a few shops and market stalls which supply African tribal curios such as masks and textiles.</p><p>Mon-Thurs 0900-1200 and 1430-1800, Fri-Sat 0900-1200. Some shops may stay open until 2200.</p><p>Haggling is part and parcel of shopping in the markets in The Gambia. Be prepared to barter for the best price. If you don't want to pay the asking price simply walk away. However, if you agree a price, it is very bad manners to change your mind.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>By West African standards, The Gambia has a fairly developed, growing tourist industry. The mainstay are large package-oriented resorts although smaller boutique hotels, are also emerging. The most popular hotels are located in the string of low-key, low-rise beach resorts near Banjul. Standards tend to be modest, but the high-end places have attractive swimming pools, bars, restaurants, shops, sporting facilities, spacious gardens and the option of a room with air conditioning.<br /><br /><strong>Grading: </strong>There is no official accommodation grading system. Tour operators classify properties according to their own criteria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Gambia has a number of small hotels and guest houses. While some offer only the most basic facilties, the best ones have pleasant pools and gardens. These appeal to those looking for something more intimate and authentic than the larger hotels, which are primarily geared towards package tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>By West African standards, The Gambia has a fairly developed, growing tourist industry. The mainstay are large package-oriented resorts although smaller boutique hotels, are also emerging. The most popular hotels are located in the string of low-key, low-rise beach resorts near Banjul. Standards tend to be modest, but the high-end places have attractive swimming pools, bars, restaurants, shops, sporting facilities, spacious gardens and the option of a room with air conditioning.<br /><br /><strong>Grading: </strong>There is no official accommodation grading system. Tour operators classify properties according to their own criteria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>By West African standards, The Gambia has a fairly developed, growing tourist industry. The mainstay are large package-oriented resorts although smaller boutique hotels, are also emerging. The most popular hotels are located in the string of low-key, low-rise beach resorts near Banjul. Standards tend to be modest, but the high-end places have attractive swimming pools, bars, restaurants, shops, sporting facilities, spacious gardens and the option of a room with air conditioning.<br /><br /><strong>Grading: </strong>There is no official accommodation grading system. Tour operators classify properties according to their own criteria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Visitors are advised to bring sunscreen, insect repellent and indigestion/diarrhoea medicines; all of these can prove expensive in The Gambia. The government plays a dominant role in health services but private practices exist in the urban and resort areas. Health insurance is strongly advised. Prescription drugs should be carried in labelled containers.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water in the urban and resort areas is safe. Elsewhere, water for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should be boiled or otherwise sterilised. Fresh milk should be boiled if unpasteurised; powdered or tinned milk is preferable. Avoid unpasteurised dairy products. Meat, fish and vegetables should be cooked, and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Diarrhoeal diseases including giardiasis are common. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in stagnant fresh water. Hepatitis E is widespread. Hepatitis B is endemic. Cholera is a risk, and up-to-date advice should be sought on the most suitable precautions.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Koriteh (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Koriteh itself. Koriteh and Tabaski (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Independence Day :
							18 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Revolution Day :
							22 July </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into The Gambia by travellers over 18 without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of wine or beer.<br />
&bull; Goods up to a value of D1,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gambian Dalasi (GMD; symbol D) = 100 bututs. Notes are in denominations of D100, 50, 25, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of D1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 bututs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a bank/bureau de change (Trust Bank) at the airport (Mon-Fri 0900-1600, Fri 0900-1230). The capital, Banjul, and the nearby towns of Serrekunda, Bakau, Fajara and Kololi have a number of banks where foreign currencies can be exchanged. Exchange bureaux are found in all the main tourist resorts. Some hotels also offer foreign exchange facilities, but tend to charge high commissions. As The Gambia is a cash economy travellers are advised to carry sufficient currency to cover expenses of a planned visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While some mid-range and top-end hotels will accept American Express, MasterCard and Visa if arranged at the beginning of the stay, most local businesses only accept payment by cash or traveller's cheques. ATMs are available in large urban areas, but are few in number and not always reliable. Due to credit card and bank fraud, caution is advised when using credit cards and ATMs.</p><p>ATMs are available in large urban areas and at some banks and some petrol stations in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/gambia/banjul-beach">Banjul</a>, but are few in number and not always reliable. Due to credit card and bank fraud, caution is advised when using credit cards and ATMs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not recommended although AMEX travellers cheques can be changed at some bank branches in Banjul.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1300 & 1600-1800, Fri 0800-1100 (banks in Banjul); Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1600-1800, Sat 0800-1300 (banks elsewhere).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: &pound;40; multiple-entry visa: &pound;60.</p>
<p>Five-year multiple-entry visa for US visitors: US$105.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: six months: multiple-entry visa: 12 months (five years for US visitors).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy) or on arrival. Nationals of Estonia must obtain a visa in advance. US nationals are also advised to obtain a visa in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow two days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For long-stay holidays, travellers must have their passport stamped in the Immigration Office in Banjul or at tourist police stations every 28 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[13.439970]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-15.490999]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>11,295 sq km (4,361 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,054,986 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>174.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Banjul.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Gambia, situated on West Africa's Atlantic coast, is a thin ribbon of land, at no point wider than 50km (30 miles), running east-west on both banks of the River Gambia. In the east, where the river dwindles, the country is barely 15km (9 miles) wide. The smallest and westernmost mainland African nation, The Gambia is essentially an enclave of Senegal with whom it shares 740km (460 miles) of land border. To the west though, The Gambia is bordered by the Atlantic Ocean and has 80km (50 miles) of coastline.</p>
<p>The country is predominantly a low plateau, which decreases in height as it nears the Atlantic coast. The plateau is bisected by the river, and is broken in a few places by low flat-topped hills and by the river's tributaries. The landscape is essentially flat, with the high point just 53m (174ft) above sea level. In the west of the country, near the coast, the river banks are backed mainly by mangrove swamps, while in the inland area, which extends from central Gambia to the eastern border, the river is lined by steep, red ironstone banks covered with tropical forest.</p>
<p>Away from the river, find wooded, park-like savannah, with large areas carpeted by a variety of trees such as baobab, silk-cotton, mahogany and oil palm. On the coast, the river meets the Atlantic with impressive sand cliffs and 50km (30 miles) of beaches, the best of which are broad, palm-fringed and strewn with shells.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Over 90% Muslim, with the remainder holding either Christian or animist beliefs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is a common form of greeting; <em>Salaam aleikum</em> (Peace be upon you) is the traditional greeting. <em>Nanga def</em> (Wolof for: How are you?) is widely used on the coast; <em>Kaira be</em> (Mandinka for: I wish you peace) is widely used inland. Gambians are extremely friendly and welcoming, and, in general, visitors should not be afraid to accept their hospitality. <br />
<br />
You should exercise common sense in their dealings with the persistent would-be guides, known locally as bumsters, who operate in some tourist areas. Many Gambians are Muslim, and their religious customs and beliefs should be respected by guests; however, most understand western customs and the English language. Visitors should remember that the right hand, not the left, must be used for the giving or receiving of food or objects. <br />
<br />
Casual wear is suitable, although beachwear should only be worn on the beach or at the poolside. Only the most exclusive dining rooms encourage guests to dress up for dinner. Despite the effects of tourism, traditional culture in music, dancing and craftsmanship still flourishes in the many villages in up-country Gambia. Travellers are advised not to photograph <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/gambia/banjul-beach">Banjul</a> airport or military bases, and to ask the permission of any locals if wishing to photograph them and their village.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are most commonly used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Adama Barrow since January 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Adama Barrow since January 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The River Gambia has been a busy trading zone since medieval times. During the colonial period, several European powers contested ownership of the river with Britain eventually prevailing, and The Gambia became a British Protectorate in the 1820s, surrounded by the French-ruled Senegal.<br/></p><p>The drive for Gambian independence gained momentum after World War 2 and in 1961 the first universal franchise election was held, with Dawda Jawara winning. The Gambia became the last of Britain's West African colonies to attain full independence, mainly because it was so small and poor that doubts surfaced about its economic viability. A merger with Senegal was suggested but rejected when the issue of how to share power could not be resolved. Eventually, in 1965 The Gambia achieved independence and Jawara became the country's first Prime Minister before assuming the role of President when the country became a republic in 1970 as a member of the Commonwealth.<br/></p><p>A period of hope and relative prosperity matched by an era of political stability followed and with elections conducted every five years, The Gambia is one of the oldest multi-party democracies in Africa. However, dissatisfaction within the military and a failed coup in 1981 led to the establishment of the Senegambia Confederation in 1982, which aimed to unify the political, economic and defence structure of the two countries. The confederation lasted until 1989 when the project was aborted.<br/></p><p>Nonetheless, close relations have remained between the two since the divorce. A bloodless coup in 1994 caught everyone by surprise but was welcomed by the majority of the population and Yahya Jammeh, a military man, assumed control and promptly banned political activity. In response Western governments withdrew support for the country and the tourist industry collapsed, only recovering when Jammeh called elections in 1996, which he duly won. He has been in power ever since.<br/></p><p>Since the turn of the century, The Gambia has had a period of relatively high economic growth backed by a tourist boom and apparent stability. The country retains strong connections with Britain and is one of the few parts of West Africa where English, rather than French, is the official language. Under the surface however, Jammeh has become increasingly repressive.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>&bull; Contemporary Gambian music fuses Western sounds with Sabar, the traditional drumming and dancing of the Wolof and Serer peoples.</p><p>&bull; The River Gambia is navigable deep into the continent, which made it an important and profitable site for the slave trade. Once slave trading was declared illegal in the 19th century the river became a strategic factor in its end.</p><p>&bull; The Gambia is the smallest country on mainland Africa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in The Gambia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(220) 4495 133</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-high-commission-banjul</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(220) 4495 133</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0800-1030 (submission of applications), 1430-1530 (passport collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Fajara<br/>48 Atlantic Road<br/>PO Box 507<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of The Gambia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 785 1399</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gambiaembassy.us</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 785 1399</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0930-1200, 1300-1600; Fri 0930-1300&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>Suite 240, Georgetown Plaza, 2233 Wisconsin Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[ Embassy of the Republic of The Gambia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7229 8066</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gambiaembassy.org.uk/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7229 8066</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Summer: Mon-Thurs 0930-1700, Fri 0930-1300. Winter: Mon-Thurs 0930-1600, Fri 0930-1300&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b> Notting Hill<br/>92 Ledbury Road<br/>London<br/>W11 2AH<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Gambia may be mainland Africa's smallest nation, but it punches way above its weight in terms of attractions. With its glorious low-key beaches, bustling towns that combine colonial architecture and traditional activities with a wealth of wildlife, it's perhaps the most approachable of all West African countries. What's more, its people are a kind and welcoming bunch, for which many know it as The Smiling Coast. <br/></p><p>Virtually enveloped by its much larger neighbour Senegal, a legacy of the colonial carve up of Africa, the shard of land comprising The Gambia still retains its own clear identity. Although this accessible Anglophone country's more obvious draw is perhaps the joy of winter sun at good-value rates, its rich history and fascinating mix of cultures make it hard to pigeonhole. If you escape the sun loungers you will uncover another side of the country, rich in eco-tourism opportunities, wilderness, wildlife and bird watching.<br/></p><p>Inextricably linked to the river Gambia, one of Africa's great waterways, The Gambia comprises a varied landscape, featuring lush tropical forests, swamps, marshes and large areas of wooded savannah. Then there are Gambia's parks, reserves and riverbanks including Kiang West National Park and River Gambia National Park, where you'll see all kinds of wildlife, amongst them monkeys, crocodiles, a small population of hippos and well over 500 bird species.</p><p>Of course, one of the main attractions is the coast. There are only 80 kilometres of shoreline, but the beaches are some of the most stunning in the region.</p><p><br/>Visitors keen to experience West African music and rural culture may head off the beaten track and up-country to simple, traditional villages. All year round you'll find vibrant festivals, events full of traditional drumming, energetic dancing as well as customary wrestling matches. But for many, it is The Gambia's idyllic cocktail of sunny days, warm welcomes and relaxing Atlantic beach resorts that lures them to this little slice of Africa.</p>The Gambia may be mainland Africa's smallest nation, but it punches way above its weight in terms of attractions. With its glorious low-key beaches, bustling towns that combine colonial architecture and traditional activities and wealth of wildlife, The Gambia is the most approachable of all West African countries.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
