<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Germany" ColCode="deu" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="de" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Germany]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Germany is the seventh largest country in Europe, stretching from the Alps, across the North European Plain to the Baltic Sea. Its climate, however, varies little from north to south. Most of Germany has a temperate seasonal climate moderated by the North Atlantic Drift. Overall, Germany is a year-round destination with warm summers and relatively mild winters &ndash; prolonged period of frost is rare. Rain falls throughout the year, with much of Germany experiencing its maximum rainfall over the high summer months.</p>
<p>The highest annual temperatures tend to be in the southwest, where there's almost a Mediterranean feel to the landscape at times and where new heat records are reached almost every year. Unsurprisingly, this is where much of Germany's wine is grown.</p>
<p>May through to September are the most popular months in terms of tourist numbers, and certainly hold the most appeal for visitors aiming to spend significant periods of time outdoors. However, April and October (the shoulder months) also hold real attraction for those who want the promise of mild weather without the tourist levels. The winter holidays are also a big draw in their way, as tourists flock to charming Christmas markets scattered across the country. Peak season for ski areas is from December through to the end of March.</p>
<p><strong>Berlin</strong> is the capital and the largest city in Germany. Geographically it sits in north-eastern Germany and has a temperate continental climate. Berlin's summer is warm with average high temperatures of 23&deg;C (73&deg;F). June and August are rainy too so pack a raincoat with you. Berlin&rsquo;s winter is quite mild with average high temperatures of 3&deg;C (37&deg;F). Home to world-renowned attractions, Berlin rarely witness 'slow' periods at any time of year, though prices tend to be slightly higher over the summer months. For more information, see the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/berlin/weather">weather in Berlin and the best time to go guide</a>.</p>
<p>Located in west Germany in the Rhine-Ruhr area, <strong>Cologne</strong> is one of the warmest cities in Germany due to its low lying position. Spring and autumn are the best times to visit Cologne with temperatures averaging 14&deg;C (57&deg;F) in May and 15&deg;C (59&deg;F) in September. The city is aswarm with visitors during &quot;Crazy Days&quot; (before Shrove Thursday which falls in February or March) where people dress up and participate in balls and parades. For more information, see the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cologne/weather/">weather in Cologne and the best time to go guide</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Frankfurt</strong> is Germany's hub for commerce and transportation. The city occupies both sides of the Main River and is a year-round destination known for its trade fairs. Summer is warm with average high temperatures of 25&deg;C (77&deg;F). Winter is mild, although it can often get to -1&deg;C (30&deg;F) in the evening. For more information, see the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/frankfurt/weather/">weather in Frankfurt and the best time to go guide</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Hamburg</strong> is a major port city in northern Germany with a maritime temperate climate. Due to its location, Hamburg is slightly cooler than Berlin which is about 500km (311 miles) south. August is the warmest month and sees an average high of just 22&deg;C (72&deg;F), while winter is cold (although it is also getting milder with less snowfall due to global warming). The daily mean in January is 1&deg;C (34&deg;F). For more information, see the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hamburg/weather/">weather in Hamburg and the best time to go guide</a>.</p>
<p>For other destinations in Germany, see the following guides:</p>
<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/munich/weather/">Weather in Munich guide</a></p>
<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hanover/weather/">Weather in Hanover guide</a></p>
<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dusseldorf/weather/">Weather in D&uuml;sseldorf guide</a></p>
<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/stuttgart/weather/">Weather in Stuttgart guide</a></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>European clothes according to season with light- to mediumweight in summer, medium- to heavyweights in winter. If you&rsquo;re intending to visit the mountains &ndash; and particularly if you&rsquo;re planning a long-distance hike &ndash; it&rsquo;s best to take waterproof gear and extra layers with you, no matter what the time of year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internal services are operated by Lufthansa (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.lufthansa.com">www.lufthansa.com</a>) and Eurowings (<a href="https://www.eurowings.com">www.eurowings.com</a>) and several other regional airlines. Frankfurt is the main air travel hub, and you can reach all other German airports in an hour or less from here. Given the breadth and general efficiency of the public transport network however, internal flights should not be seen as essential. Their main benefit is to save time.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Regular scheduled boat services operate on most rivers, lakes and coastal waters. Besides scheduled services, special excursions are also available on many navigable waters.</p>
<p>The KD German Rhine Line (tel: +49 221 208 8318; <a href="https://www.k-d.com/de/">www.k-d.com/de/</a>) covers the Rhine and Moselle rivers, and has comfortable ships that operate daily from April to late October. In conjunction with the S&auml;chsische Dampfschiffahrt, the KD also organises cabin cruises on the Elbe between Meissen and the Swiss border, via Dresden.</p>
<p>Lake Constance is served by regular steamers, pleasure boats and car ferries between the German, Swiss and Austrian shores. The Lake Constance Adventure Passes (Bodensee-Erlebniskarte) (<a href="http://www.bodensee.eu/de/darum-buchen">www.bodensee.eu/de/darum-buchen</a>) give free travel on many vessels in the Lake Constance area, as well as discounted admission to attractions. The pass is valid for three days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national rail company Deutsche Bahn (<a href="http://www.bahn.de" target="_blank">www.bahn.de</a>) operates tens of thousands of passenger trains each day. The most famous of these are the Intercity-Express (ICE) services, which reach speeds of up to 300kph (186mph) and run between major cities, both within Germany and internationally. A number of less speedy (but still efficient) inter-city and international trains also run.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A range of Bahncards is available from Deutsche Bahn, offering a number of different discount schemes for travel within Germany, and varying advance purchase discount options are also offered. For visitors not intending to be in the country for months on end, the two most relevant options are the BahnCard 25 (providing 25% discounts) and the BahnCard50 (providing 50% discounts). <br />
<br />
With an InterRail One Country Pass you can choose from unlimited travel on three, four, six or eight days of your choice during the course of a month. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="https://www.raileurope.com/index.html">www.raileurope.com/index.html</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Germany is covered by a busy network of motorways (<em>autobahnen</em>). These can get very crowded on some routes. In general terms however, the quality of roads in Germany tends to be high. All roads, <em>autobahnen</em> and otherwise, are toll free (other than for heavy trucks). Lorries are banned from travelling on <em>autobahnen</em>&nbsp;on Sundays and on Bank Holidays throughout the year from midnight until 2200. Additionally, during the summer holidays in the months of July and August lorries aren't allowed on <em>autobahnen</em> on Saturdays from 0700-2000, making it easier for cars to cover long distances.</p>r<p>Though by no means as time-efficient or lauded as the rail service, Germany&rsquo;s extensive bus network still offers a workable (and reasonably comprehensive) way of exploring some of the country&rsquo;s more remote regions. Local services are run by regional companies, and many timetables stop at the weekends. Eurolines (tel: +44 871 781 8177, in the UK;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.eurolines.com" target="_blank">www.eurolines.com</a>) offers routes from the UK to the larger cities in Germany.</p><p>Almost all German taxis are cream-coloured Mercedes with yellow-and-black signs on their roofs. You&rsquo;re far more likely to find a vehicle at a taxi stand than flag one down.  Fares are metered.</p><p>Insurance is mandatory, and you should also have a full driving licence to hand.</p><p>Traffic signs are international. Speed limits in Germany are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas and 100kph (62mph) on all roads outside built-up areas. Unless otherwise indicated, there is theoretically no maximum speed limit on Autobahns, but 130kph (81mph) is recommended. The minimum driving age is 18. Winter tyres are a legal requirement during periods of snowfall and in case of slippery ice.</p><p>The Allgemeiner Deutscher Automobil Club (ADAC) (emergency tel: 0180 222 2222, in Germany only; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.adac.de">www.adac.de</a>) is the principal national assistance network.</p><p>Self-drive cars are available at most towns, airports, and major railway stations &ndash; a high number of international car hire companies are present in Germany.</p><p>Germany holds real appeal for cyclists. Designated bike paths are commonplace and long-distance routes are widespread. If you&rsquo;re serious about cycle touring however, be aware that the country is a very large one.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Bike hire is easily available. Several leading cities, including Berlin, Frankfurt, Munich and Stuttgart, have a 24-hour interactive bike-hire scheme which tourists can sign up to (<a href="http://www.callabike-interaktiv.de" target="_blank">www.callabike-interaktiv.de</a>).</p><p>Traffic signs are international. Speed limits in Germany are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas and 100kph (62mph) on all roads outside built-up areas. Unless otherwise indicated, there is theoretically no maximum speed limit on Autobahns, but 130kph (81mph) is recommended. The minimum driving age is 18. Winter tyres are a legal requirement during periods of snowfall and in case of slippery ice.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All urban areas have efficient bus services, complemented in a number of larger cities by trams, and underground or suburban trains. In most larger cities, tickets for a local transport journey have to be purchased from ticket machines before boarding the suburban train (<em>S-Bahn</em>), underground (<em>U-Bahn</em>), bus or tram. Ticket inspections are frequent, with on-the-spot fines issued. Taxis are widely available in the main cities, and operate from designated ranks. They can be advance booked by telephone.</p>
<p><strong>Berlin:</strong> The city's excellent public transport includes an extensive network of buses, underground and S-Bahn in three travel zones. In the eastern part of the city, tram services and the ferries of the Berliner Verkehrs-Betriebe, BVG (Berlin Public Transport) (tel: +49 30 19449; <a href="http://www.bvg.de/" target="_blank">www.bvg.de</a>), in conjunction with east Berlin's White Fleet, provide further services. Day and longer period passes are available covering all services. Taxis are generally available throughout the city (tel: +49 30 26 3000; <a href="http://www.quality-taxi.de">www.quality-taxi.de</a>). <br />
<br />
<strong>Frankfurt</strong><strong>:</strong> An extensive tram network and bus services serve the Rhine-Main region, operated under the auspices of the Rhein-Main Verkehrsverbund (tel: +49 69 2424 8024; <a href="http://www.rmv.de/" target="_blank">www.rmv.de</a>). As in Berlin, 24-hour passes for all types of public transport are available, as is a large fleet of cream-coloured taxis. The central taxi booking number is +49 69 230 001. <br />
<br />
<strong>Munich:</strong> The Bavarian capital has some trams, plus comprehensive bus, underground and suburban rail services. Services are operated under the aegis of the M&uuml;nchner Verkehrs-und Tarifverbund (tel: +49 89 4142 4344; <a href="http://www.mvv-muenchen.de/" target="_blank">www.mvv-muenchen.de</a>). Again, taxis are widely available. Taxis can be booked on +49 89 21610. <br />
<br />
<strong>Note:</strong> Pedestrians should be aware that it is technically an offence to cross a road when the pedestrian crossing lights are red, even if there is no traffic on the road. Offenders can risk on-the-spot fines &ndash; in practice, this is unlikely to happen.&nbsp;Adults should set a good example for children not to cross the street when the lights are red.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Germany</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">munich</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.15</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Germany</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">hamburg</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Germany</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">frankfurt</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.05</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.10</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Germany</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cologne</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.05</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.25</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Lufthansa (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.lufthansa.com">www.lufthansa.com</a>). Low-cost carriers flying to German airports from the UK and the United States include&nbsp;Eurowings (<a href="https://www.eurowings.com">www.eurowings.com</a>).&nbsp;</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/berlin-tegel-airport">Berlin-Tegel Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/cologne-bonn-airport">Cologne Bonn Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/duesseldorf-international-airport">Düsseldorf Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/frankfurt-airport">Frankfurt Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/hamburg-airport">Hamburg Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/munich-airport">Munich Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/stuttgart-airport">Stuttgart Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dresden-international-airport">Dresden International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/leipzighalle-airport">Leipzig/Halle Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/muenster-osnabrueck-international-airport">Münster Osnabrück International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nuremberg-airport">Nuremberg Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/paderbornlippstadt-airport">Paderborn/Lippstadt Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/rostock-laage-airport">Rostock-Laage Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/sylt-westerland-airport">Sylt (Westerland) Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland/zurich-international-airport">Zurich Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/zweibruecken-airport">Zweibruecken Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/city-airport-bremen">City Airport Bremen</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany/bodensee-airport-friedrichshafen">Bodensee Airport Friedrichshafen</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/frankfurt">Frankfurt</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 1 hour 30 minutes;&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>&nbsp;- 7&nbsp;hours 40 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The new Berlin Brandenburg Airport is scheduled to open in October 2020, around 18km (11 miles) south of central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/berlin">Berlin</a> itself.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The new Berlin Brandenburg Airport is scheduled to open in October 2020, around 18km (11 miles) south of central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/berlin">Berlin</a> itself.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Berlin-Tegel Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.berlin-airport.de<p>Berlin-Tegel Airport is located 11km (7 miles) northwest of central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/berlin">Berlin</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+49 30 6091 1150</p>]]><b>Cologne Bonn Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.koeln-bonn-airport.de<p>Cologne Bonn Airport is situated 15km (9 miles) southeast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cologne">Cologne</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+49 22 0340 4001.</p>]]><b>Düsseldorf Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.dus.com<p>D&uuml;sseldorf Airport is located 8km (5 miles) north of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/duesseldorf">D&uuml;sseldorf</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+49 211 4210</p>]]><b>Frankfurt Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.frankfurt-airport.com<p>Frankfurt Airport is located 12km (8 miles) southwest of&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/frankfurt">Frankfurt</a> city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+49 180 6372 4636</p>]]><b>Hamburg Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.hamburg-airport.de<p>Hamburg Airport is situated 8km (5 miles) north of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hamburg">Hamburg</a> city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+49 40 50750</p>]]><b>Hannover Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.hannover-airport.de<p>Hannover Airport is situated 11km (7 miles) north of Hanover.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+49 511 9770</p>]]><b>Munich Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.munich-airport.de<p>Munich Airport is located 36km (22 miles) northeast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/munich">Munich</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+49 89 97500</p>]]><b>Stuttgart Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.stuttgart-airport.com<p>Stuttgart Airport is situated 13km (8 miles) south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/stuttgart">Stuttgart</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+49 711 9480</p>]]><b>City Airport Bremen</b><![CDATA[http://www.bremen-airport.com<p>City Airport Bremen is located 3.5km (2 miles) south of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+49 421 55950</p>]]><b>Leipzig/Halle Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.leipzig-halle-airport.de<p>The airport is located in Germany, approximately 15km (9 miles) northwest of central Leipzig, and a similar distance southeast of Halle.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+49 341 224 1155</p>]]><b>Nuremberg Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport-nuernberg.de<p>The airport is located around 5km (3 miles) north of Nuremberg city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(911) 93700.</p>]]><b>Münster Osnabrück International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.flughafen-fmo.de<p>The airport is located 25km (15 miles) north of Münster, and 35km (21 miles) south of Osnabrück.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>02571 943 360</p>]]><b>Paderborn/Lippstadt Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport-pad.com<p>The airport is located around 18km (11 miles) southwest of Paderborn.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+49 295 5770</p>]]><b>Rostock-Laage Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.rostock-airport.de<p>The airport is located 22km (14 miles) south of <a href="i/rostock">Rostock</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+49 1805 007 737.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The north (and only) coastline of Germany is readily accessible by water. The biggest ports are Bremen (<a href="http://www.bremenports.de/" target="_blank">www.bremenports.de</a>), Bremerhaven (<a href="http://www.cruiseport.de">www.cruiseport.de</a>), Hamburg (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hafen-hamburg.de/">www.hafen-hamburg.de</a>), Rostock (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.rostock-port.de/">www.rostock-port.de</a>) and Kiel (<a href="http://www.portofkiel.com">www.portofkiel.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are excellent connections between Germany and other main European cities. For more information, contact Deutsche Bahn (tel: +49 180 699 6633; <a href="http://www.bahn.com" target="_blank">www.bahn.com</a>).</p>
<p>Eurostar (tel: +44 1233 617 57, in the UK; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.eurostar.com">www.eurostar.com</a>) is a service provided by the railways of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belgium">Belgium</a>, the UK and France, operating direct high-speed trains from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> (St Pancras International) to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a> (Gare du Nord) and to Brussels (Midi/Zuid). It takes approximately 2 hours 15 minutes from London to Paris and approximately 2 hours to Brussels (via Lille).</p>
<p>From Brussels, there are direct connections to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cologne">Cologne</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/frankfurt">Frankfurt</a>, and onward high-speed trains to all major German centres. The journey time between Paris and Frankfurt is less than four hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://uk.voyages-sncf.com/en/pass/interrail-passes">uk.voyages-sncf.com/en/pass/interrail-passes</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, Eurotunnel (tel: +44 8443 353 535, in the UK; <a href="http://www.eurotunnel.com" target="_blank">www.eurotunnel.com</a>) runs shuttle trains for cars, bicycles, motorcycles, coaches, minibuses, caravans and campervans between Folkestone in Kent and Calais in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>. The journey takes about 35 minutes from platform to platform.&nbsp;Road access across to Germany is then relatively easy, if a little time-consuming.</p>
<p>For those already on the continent, meanwhile, Germany&rsquo;s central position makes it easily accessible by major roads from almost any direction you care to choose.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Local and international calls can be made from phone boxes in towns and cities. These usually accept both coins and pre-paid cards (available at post offices and other outlets). In larger cities, you&rsquo;ll often be able to make international calls from internet cafes too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with many international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good. It is illegal to use a hand-held mobile telephone while driving. If you&rsquo;re going to be in Germany for a long period of time, consider obtaining a local SIM card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is widely available, often for free in hotels, restaurants, on public transport, airports, train stations and in city centres of bigger cities. Large Internet access centres exist in most main cities and there are many Internet cafes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Each of the country's 16 regions regulates its own private and public broadcasting, and operates public TV and radio services. The country has one of the largest and most diverse TV markets in the world. It&rsquo;s also home to some of the world's largest media conglomerates, such as Bertelsmann and Bauer Media Group<em>. </em>The most influential daily papers include<em> Die Welt, Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung </em>and<em> S&uuml;ddeutsche Zeitung. </em>The most widely read of the weekly publications are<em> Der Spiegel </em>(a current affairs magazine)<em> </em>and<em> Die Zeit </em>(a quality weekly newspaper)<em>. </em></p>
<p>Many major English-language newspapers and international magazines are also available in large cities. Sky Deutschland (previously Premiere) is a pay-TV operator<em>. </em>ARD and ZDF operate the public national TV channels; RTL operates entertainment channels. Deutsche Welle is the international TV service, and operates in a number of different languages; Arte is a Franco-German cultural channel. Deutschlandradio operates national public radio stations, Deutschlandfunk and Deutschlandradio Kultur; Deutsche Welle also broadcasts radio in many languages.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Stamps are available from hotels, slot machines and post offices.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800, Sat 0900-1200. Smaller branches may close for lunch.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Freiburg Cathedral</p><![CDATA[<p>Consecrated in 1513, having taken over 300 years to build, Freiburg Cathedral is a masterpiece of Gothic architecture. The 116-metre (318-ft) high west tower, which soars above the jumbled rooftops of the Black Forest city, was described by Swiss historian Jacob Burckhardt as 'the most beautiful spire in Christendom'and contains the 'Hosanna' bell which dates from 1258; the bell is still rung every Friday at 1100. Visitors can climb the tower for excellent views over Freiburg and the Black Forest. The interior of the cathedral is just as beautiful, the highlight being Hans Baldung Grien's Renaissance High Altar, depicting the life of the Virgin Mary. Münsterplatz, the cathedral square, is a lively venue all year round, but is particularly atmospheric on long summer evenings, when people sit outside cafés enjoying the wine that is produced in local vineyards.</p>]]><br/><p>Heidelberg Castle</p><![CDATA[<p>Situated high above the <em>River Neckar</em>, <em>Heidelberg Castle</em> is one of Germany&rsquo;s most romantic locations. It has had a long and turbulent history since it was first constructed in the early 15th century as a residence for the Palatine princes, the powerful secular rulers who presided over this part of southern Germany during the Holy Roman Empire. Having been totally destroyed during the Thirty Years War, and later by the French in 1689 and 1693, the red sandstone building was struck by lightning in 1764 and even its stones were taken for use in other building projects. All this rebuilding has led to a variety of architectural styles and yet the castle&rsquo;s delapidated air adds to its charm. The best way to reach the site is by cable car. There are excellent views over the university city of Heidelberg and the <em>Neckar Valley</em> from the summit.</p>
<p>Address:&nbsp;Schlossverwaltung, Im Schlosshof 1, 69117 Heidelberg, Germany</p>]]><br/><p>Pergamon Museum (Pergamonmuseum)</p><![CDATA[<p>One of the world&rsquo;s great museums, the <em>Pergamon Museum </em>lies on Berlin&rsquo;s <em>Museumsinsel</em> (Museum Island) complex, which is situated between the River Spree and Kupfergraben. Five museums were built here between 1824 and 1930 to house archaeological treasures and art collections. The last of the five to be built was the Pergamon Museum which was designed by Alfred Messel and houses spectacular works of architectural antiquities, including collections of Greek, Assyrian, Islamic and Far Eastern art.</p>
<p>Address:&nbsp;Bodestrasse 1-3, 10178 Berlin, Germany</p>]]><br/><p>Sanssouci Palace</p><![CDATA[<p><em>Sanssouci Palace</em> was built for Prussian emperor Frederick II as his summer retreat, and its name, which literally means &lsquo;no worries&rsquo; in French, reflects the fact that he intended this as an escape from the pressures of Berlin and married life. The real showpiece of Sanssouci, however, is the park. Visitors can wander through a series of beautifully landscaped gardens, including the <em>Sizilianischer Garten</em> (Sicilian Garden), which is filled with subtropical plants. A series of fountains and terraces leads to other structures within the park, such as the <em>Neue Orangerie</em> (New Orangery) and the <em>Bildergalerie</em> (Picture Gallery), which holds paintings by Renaissance artists, including Caravaggio, Rubens and Van Dyck.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire Dresden’s rise from the ashes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>WWII left Dresden in a sorrowful state, but the city recovered sufficiently to become the spirited and arty destination it is today. It is handsome too, thanks in part to the Dresden Frauenkirche church, which was resurrected beautifully and restored as the skyline-dominating feature it deserves to be. Other must sees in Dresden are the museums in the Zwinger and in the Gr&uuml;ne Gew&ouml;lbe as well as the masterpieces in the Gem&auml;ldegalerie Alte Meister.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise The Rhine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Rhine (spelt Rhein in German) is one of the longest rivers in Europe, and one of its most impressive to boot. Take a cruise from Koblenz past fairytale castles, pretty villages and the imposing Lorelei Rock, legendary home of a siren said to have lured boatmen to their demise.</p>]]><p><b>Cycle the Romantic Road</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Germany has more than 200 long-distance cycle paths that spin from riverside routes and chocolate box villages to major cities and mountain-bike trails. Arguably the most picturesque of the lot is the 350km-long (220 mile) Romantic Road that stretches from Wurzburg (near Frankfurt) to the Austrian border. And yes, tandem bikes are available to hire.</p>]]><p><b>Drink in Frankfurt’s medieval core</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Frankfurt is best known as a financial centre (its gleaming office-block skyline has been coined 'Mainhattan') but there's much to draw cultural tourists too. Its historic core dates back to medieval times and several attractive landmark buildings remain, while its local tipple, <em>ebbelwoi</em> (applewine), should be experienced if not enjoyed. The 13 museums at the Museumsufer in Frankfurt play an important role in the German and European museum sector. Particularly noteworthy are the arts and craft museum, the museum of ethnology and the film museum.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a beer at Oktoberfest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>First held in 1810, Munich's much eulogised festival is a 16-day celebration of Bavarian culture, with top billing afforded to local beers and belly-filling food. Expect fairground rides and live music too. However, if you're planning a visit, be aware that the majority of the festival falls late September, despite its name.</p>]]><p><b>Escape the past in Essen</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Crowned the European Capital of Culture in 2010, Essen has grown from a staid mining city into remarkable example of how industrial infrastructure can be repurposed to artistic effect. Shaft 12 at Zollverein Coal Mine is now a Bauhaus-inspired, UNESCO-listed, design museum, while the city&rsquo;s being European Green Capital 2017 proves a past usurped.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Neuschwanstein Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The archetypal fairytale palace, world-famous Neuschwanstein stands among Alpine foothills in Bavaria. It&rsquo;s the most elaborate of King Ludwig II&rsquo;s castles, with much of its design inspired by Wagnerian operas. And if you think the outside looks dramatic, wait until you see the gilded decor and furnishings that the interior serves up. Avoid a visit to Neuschwanstein during the summer months if you don't want to get stuck in the crowd of the castle's 6000 daily visitors.</p>]]><p><b>Fall in love with Germany’s most romantic town, Heidelberg</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Boasting a glorious woodland setting on the broad Neckar River, Heidelberg draws large numbers of visitors for its formidable renaissance castle, cosy cafes and literature-culture with bookshops, poetry events and academic happenings. Germany&rsquo;s oldest university town is also the birthplace of German Romanticism and is famed for its picturesque panoramas along the riverside Philosophers' Walk (<em>Philosophenweg</em>).</p>]]><p><b>Find adventure in the Bavarian Alps</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Forming a long natural divide along the Austrian border, the Bavarian Alps are a strikingly attractive spectacle. Take in the mountain views from the top of the Zugspitze. It's a panorama you will never forget. Easily reachable from Munich, outdoor enthusiasts will be in their element here with plenty of skiing, hiking and canoeing options. Those more intent on relaxation can unwind and unknot in a slew of top-notch spas.</p>]]><p><b>Find history and hedonism in Berlin</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Blessed with the Brandenburg Gate, Charlottenburg Palace and Reichstag building, Berlin is rich in history, including volatile marks from the 20th century like the F&uuml;hrer Headquarters, the Holocaust-memorial and Berlin Wall. But brightened by street art, sound-tracked by an underground dance scene and thriving creatively, modern Berlin shines for visitors too.</p>]]><p><b>Find the beating heart of Hamburg</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As Germany&rsquo;s second largest metropolis, the northern port city of Hamburg offers rich pickings for tourists. Colourful and cosmopolitan, the city has music at its heart: retrace the steps of The Beatles along the Reeperbahn; enjoy the fervent live scene; or dance to DJs until the small hours. The Speicherstadt&rsquo;s neo-gothic canals are best explored at night. Or enjoy Hamburg's famous fair Hamburger Dom, which takes place in spring, summer and winter.</p>]]><p><b>Indulge your intellect at Weimar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The 1,000-year-old city of Weimar has been home to many great writers, musicians, composers and poets, including Goethe, Luther, Bach, Liszt, Wagner and Schiller. An essential southern stop for any culture vulture, this creative centre experienced its golden age in the 18th and 19th centuries, and remains visually pleasing too.</p>]]><p><b>Sample the Moselle Valley Vineyards</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Getting to know the world-famous wineries of the Moselle Valley is a rewarding way to sample rural Germany. Aside the steep banks of the river Moselle, the culture remains traditional, pace of life slow and its scenery grandly evocative. The white wines here are well worthy of extensive acquaintance as well.</p>]]><p><b>Take your time in the Black Forest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Few parts of Germany&rsquo;s countryside are as storied as the Black Forest: a dense, green mountain range in the southwest. Hiking is the best way to explore the photogenic beauty and sky-high peaks of this national park, while the forest is also home to a large number of small character-rich towns, including Triberg im Schwarzwald, which is home to the world&rsquo;s largest cuckoo clock. The famous Triberger waterfalls, which are close to Triberg, are the highest waterfalls in Germany.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Cologne Christmas Market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The run-up to Christmas sees the towns and cities of the nation come alive with traditional street markets, and nowhere more so than in Cologne (K&ouml;ln). Toys, gingerbread and handmade presents are among the countless festive items on sale, while warming <em>gl&uuml;hwein</em> (mulled wine) forms an integral part of the experience.</p>]]><p><b>Walk the Rennsteig</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its mountain ranges, tidal shores and mighty forests, the size and scope of Germany makes it a hikers' paradise. The historical ridge walk known as the Rennsteig leads for some 170 km (106 miles) through forests and highlands in the centre of the country, and combines rich culture with even richer scenery.</p>]]><p><b>Watch a football match</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Germany's love affair with football reaches its pinnacle at the Allianz Arena, home of Bayern Munich. Snare a ticket and watch one of the continent&rsquo;s top teams in action &ndash; other lively options include Hamburg, Bayer Leverkusen, Hertha Berlin, Schalke 04 and Werder Bremen. Many of the stadia are relatively new, having been built for the 2006 World Cup.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$3.58 trillion (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, chemicals, motor vehicles, iron and steel products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, petroleum products, manufactured goods, metals and motor vehicles.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, The Netherlands, UK, China and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Germany boasts the largest economy in Europe. As a result of the global crisis it contracted 5% in 2009, resulting in the country's worst recession since the Great Depression in the 1930s. It has since emerged from recession - thanks largely to a recovery in the exports on which it relies so heavily &ndash; and has shown real resilience in the storm of the euro crisis. Exports in 2011 reached their highest ever figure, more than &euro;1 trillion.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br />
<br />
In the past two decades the nation's finances have had to readjust to reunification, the former East Germany swallowing up huge sums in modernisation, and still underperforming economically. Those employed in the former West still pay a special &lsquo;solidarity tax&rsquo; on top of their regular income tax, for supporting the eastern states. The inflation rate was recorded at 2.1% in April 2012. <br />
<br />
Germany's population is aging, and this, combined with the high unemployment levels and population movement, has at times placed a heavy burden on the welfare system. The country also has a high immigrant population. The country is known for having a cumbersome bureaucracy, both at national, state and local levels, and this too places a strain on tax resources.<br />
<br />
Germany is by far Europe's leading conventions and exhibitions destination, with large <em>Messen</em> (exhibition and convention centres) in all major cities, and second only to the USA worldwide in terms of events hosted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople are expected to dress smartly; both men and women are expected to wear suits and men should also wear a tie. English is spoken by many businesspeople, but it is an advantage to have a working knowledge of German, or an interpreter.<br />
<br />
Appointments should be made well in advance, particularly in the summer and may be suggested slightly earlier in the day than is often the custom in the UK. Once made, appointment times should be strictly adhered to.<br />
<br />
Always use formal titles such as <em>Herr</em> <em>Doktor</em> or <em>Frau</em> <em>Doktor</em> when addressing business contacts and use 'Sie' for 'you'; never assume that first names can be used, this can offend. It is common to answer the telephone by stating your last name, rather than saying 'hello'.<br />
<br />
Standard business hours are typically Monday to Friday 0800/0900-1600/1700, although these hours can be less, as Germans have some of the shortest working hours in Western Europe. Many offices close early on Friday afternoon. Business lunches are common (the person making the offer is expected to pay), but breakfast meetings are rare. Socialising with work colleagues is very common, and indeed, usually expected, but seldom involves clients. Visitors should remember that when drinking beer, the common toast is '<em>Prost</em>', while with wine it is sometimes the more genteel version, '<em>Zum Wohl</em>'.</p>
<p><br />
Businesspeople in Berlin and Munich sometimes appear more relaxed than their counterparts in other cities, particularly in the north (who favour straight talking), and this can often extend to office etiquette.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600 (many close earlier on Fridays).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>German American Chamber of Commerce in the USA</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (212) 974 8830
					Website:http://www.gaccny.com/
					Address: ,80 Pine Street, 24th Floor,New York,10005]]><b>German Convention Bureau ( Deutsches Kongressbüro )</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (069) 242 9300
					Website:http://www.gcb.de
					Address: ,Kaiserstr. 53,Frankfurt/M,60329]]><b>German-British Chamber of Industry and Commerce in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7976 4100
					Website:http://grossbritannien.ahk.de/
					Address: ,16 Buckingham Gate,London SW1E 6LB,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The archetypal German snack used to be cooked sausage (<em>wurst</em>) with a bread roll. It has been replaced by pizza and sandwiches. You won&rsquo;t have to look far to find pretzels, sauerkraut or schnitzel, of course, but there&rsquo;s genuine reinvention and creativity behind much of the cuisine these days. At home, most Germans love meat dishes like roulades best. Their favourites on second place are pasta, lasagna and pizza.&nbsp;</p>
<p>First-time visitors tend to be taken aback too by the variety of regional specialties, from the fresh seafood of the far north and the lamb dishes of Lower Saxony to the casseroles and stews of Rhineland-Westphalia and the noodle-based cuisine of the southwest.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, expect a dash of Mediterranean flair, no shortage of healthy options and &ndash; perhaps best of all &ndash; prices that compare favourably to other Western European nations. And to wash it down? Beer, of course, although the Germans are also proud and rather fond of their wines.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bratwurst:</strong> Grilled sausage typically made from a combination of pork, beef and/or veal.<br />
<strong>Eisbein mit sauerkraut:</strong> A cured and boiled leg of pork accompanied by mashed potatoes.<br />
<strong>Schw&auml;bische maultaschen:</strong> A large savoury meat-stuffed ravioli from Stuttgart.<br />
<strong>Butterbrez&rsquo;n:</strong> A soft pretzel sliced in two and slathered with butter.<br />
<strong>K&auml;sesp&auml;tzle:</strong> Hot egg noodles tossed with cheese.<br />
<strong>Eintopf:</strong> A hearty, warming stew made by cooking vegetables, pulses and meat in a broth.<br />
<strong>Eierpfannkuchen:</strong> Pancakes commonly served with jam and sprinkled sugar, fruit or cream.<br />
<strong>Schwarzw&auml;lder kirschtorte:</strong> Black Forest gateau &ndash; a cake with layers of chocolate sponge, cherries and whipped cream and lashings of cherry liqueur.<br />
<strong>Lebkuchen:</strong> Gingerbread biscuits typically eaten around Christmas.<br />
<strong>Ebbelwoi:</strong> An apple wine from Hessen.<br />
<strong>Schnapps:</strong> Clear fruit-flavoured brandies available in hundreds of varieties.<br />
<strong>Kirschwasser:</strong> A colourless cherry-flavoured spirit that originates from the Black Forest region.<br />
<strong>Bier:</strong> There are literally thousands of varieties of German beer on offer, from <em>Weissbier</em> (a cloudy light-coloured wheat brew) to <em>K&ouml;lsch</em> (a top-fermented beer brewed exclusively in the Cologne region) to <em>Altbier</em> (a dark copper coloured pour most popular in D&uuml;sseldorf).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Bars can either have table service and/or counter service, although often drinks consumed are simply marked on a beer mat to be paid for on leaving.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It is customary to tip taxi drivers, hairdressers, cloakroom attendants, bar and restaurant staff; a 10% tip is standard.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Germany's nightlife spans the full spectrum from high culture to tankard-clinking shindigs. In all the country's larger towns and cities, visitors will have the choice between theatre, opera (Deutsche Oper Berlin, Hamburgische Staatsoper, Dresden's Semperoper and the National Theatre in Munich being some of the most famous names), bars with live music, and a varied roster of nightclubs. The country is particularly renowned for its electronic music scene, one of the largest of its kind in the world. Hip-hop and heavy metal also have large followings. <br />
<br />
Berlin, in particular, is famous for its large selection of after-hours venues - the up-all-night spirit of the Cabaret years still burns strong. Traditional folk music is found mostly in rural areas. There are numerous bierkellers in the south while small wine cellars are common in the Rhineland Palatinate, Franconia and Baden region. Hamburg's Reeperbahn is the country's best known centre for 'adult' entertainment.</p>
<p>The once-illustrious Love Parade Festival, which originated in Berlin in 1989 and came to symbolise the country&rsquo;s fondness for electronic dance music, was held for the last time in 2010, at the city of Duisburg in the western Ruhr area. The decision to end the event stemmed from the tragic death of 21 festival-goers, caught up in severe overcrowding.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Germany offers the range and variety one would expect from such a large, developed country - if you want it, you'll find it - but special purchases include precision optical equipment such as binoculars and cameras, porcelain, handmade crystal, silver, steelware, Solingen knives, leatherwear, sports equipment, toys from Nuremberg toys fair and Bavarian Loden cloth. Special purchases in eastern Germany include musical instruments, wooden carved toys from the Erzgebirge Mountains and Meissen china (the workshops in Meissen are open to the public). Cuckoo clocks, contrary to popular myth, did not originate in Switzerland, but in the Black Forest region.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>German crafts are, of course, available year<strong>-</strong>round, but you&rsquo;ll find a particularly broad selection during the ubiquitous Christmas markets. The best of the wooden toys have been made with great attention to detail. Expect to also see broad selections of marionettes and carved figurines, as well as candles and festive winter clothing. It&rsquo;s the overall atmosphere, however, that has really helped these markets become such a well-borrowed institution &ndash; an ambiance greatly aided by the mingling smells of hot chestnuts and mulled wine.</p>
<p>High-end designer goods are best sourced in major cities, particularly Berlin. German brand names like Birkenstock, Jack Wolfskin, Hugo Boss and Adidas figure prominently, and while the prices might not be much lower, you&rsquo;re likely to find a broader selection of these goods than in other countries.&nbsp;Across the country, meanwhile, you&rsquo;ll also find that cities cater &ndash; in varying degrees &ndash; to those with alternative lifestyles. In places like Berlin and Hamburg, you&rsquo;ll be able to find a broad range of vintage clothes, independent boutiques and record shops.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Most large shops are open Mon-Fri 0900/1000-2000 and Sat 0900/1000-2000. All shops, except a few bakeries, are closed on Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good selection of hotels in Germany. Ask your travel agency for recommendations. Alongside established upmarket properties and a host of business-friendly chain hotels, <em>Gasthofs</em>, pensions and <em>Hotels garni</em> are (almost always) cheaper alternatives without the usual lounge/restaurant facilities. Wherever you choose to stay, it&rsquo;s more than likely to be acceptably clean, efficiently run and &ndash; with only the cheapest places being exceptions &ndash; able to offer an en suite room with a TV. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong>&nbsp;There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Various types of establishment offer the kind of stay that can be loosely assigned to B&amp;B. Farmstays are perhaps the most notable of these, usually offering an authentic slice of life in the country as well as &ndash; in many cases &ndash; the chance to sample regional produce. Many such farms can be hard, if not impossible, to reach by public transport. Also good to know about are Germany&rsquo;s <em>pensions</em>, which can range from a standard guesthouse to shared accommodation in a city apartment. These can vary greatly in quality, but in almost all cases the very least you&rsquo;ll be assured is service more personal than at a chain hotel. A <em>Gasthof</em>, or <em>Gastst&auml;tte</em>, is a similar option, commonly found in the countryside and generally offering a few rooms above a restaurant. In all the above examples, breakfast usually comes as standard. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>The <em>Urlaub</em> <em>auf</em> <em>dem</em> <em>Bauernhof</em> website (<a href="http://www.bauernhofurlaub.de/" target="_blank">www.bauernhofurlaub.de/</a>) offers information in English about farm holiday possibilities available throughout Germany. A range of guidebooks and accommodation directories can be ordered via the site.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good selection of hotels in Germany. Ask your travel agency for recommendations. Alongside established upmarket properties and a host of business-friendly chain hotels, <em>Gasthofs</em>, pensions and <em>Hotels garni</em> are (almost always) cheaper alternatives without the usual lounge/restaurant facilities. Wherever you choose to stay, it&rsquo;s more than likely to be acceptably clean, efficiently run and &ndash; with only the cheapest places being exceptions &ndash; able to offer an en suite room with a TV. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong>&nbsp;There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good selection of hotels in Germany. Ask your travel agency for recommendations. Alongside established upmarket properties and a host of business-friendly chain hotels, <em>Gasthofs</em>, pensions and <em>Hotels garni</em> are (almost always) cheaper alternatives without the usual lounge/restaurant facilities. Wherever you choose to stay, it&rsquo;s more than likely to be acceptably clean, efficiently run and &ndash; with only the cheapest places being exceptions &ndash; able to offer an en suite room with a TV. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong>&nbsp;There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;For European visitors who are taken ill or have an accident during a visit to Germany, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). For non-EEA citizens, insurance is highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergency telephone number is 112 &amp;ndash; this should be used for requesting an ambulance (Krankenwagen).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall standards of healthcare in Germany are, in most cases, excellent. Hospitals and surgeries are well equipped and staff are proficient. In pharmacies, over-the-counter advice is given and standard medicines are sold. In major cities, you&amp;rsquo;ll usually find at least one 24-hour pharmacy. Elsewhere, most stay open until 1830 on weekdays, opening on Saturday mornings but remaining closed on Sundays. Many pharmacists speak English.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The German obsession with spa waters has been well documented, and significant numbers of people still swear by their restorative health qualities. You should be able to sample them for yourself at any town with Bad or Baden in its title. The city of Baden-Baden, which has some of the oldest known mineral springs in Germany, translates literally as &amp;lsquo;Baths-Baths&amp;rsquo;. Today, many health spas are equipped with sauna worlds, spa areas and fitness areas. While in some health spas children are not allowed, others aim to attract children with animation areas for children and facilities like water slides and current canals.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing to mark out German produce as particularly risky to general health (although it has a partly founded reputation for being fatty). Tap water is also safe to drink.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tick-borne encephalitis is present in forested areas all over Germany except Hamburg, Berlin and Bremen; vaccination is advisable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a risk of tick-borne Lyme disease from March until October. Preventive measures include insect repellents and skin-covering clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the summer months, sunburn can be a problem. The southwest generally draws the highest temperatures. The usual precautions apply: use a generous amount of sunscreen and be sensible about how long you spend in direct sunlight. Be aware that a breezy day can sometimes mask high temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If walking over a long distance in warm weather, it&amp;rsquo;s advisable to drink &amp;ndash; and carry &amp;ndash; plenty of water and wear appropriate clothing, including a sun hat. Blisters can be another problem for hikers. These can often occur if new walking shoes are being worn across a long distance. Ideally footwear should be worn in before the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a counterpoint to the balminess of the summer, German winters can be fairly severe. This is generally truer the further east you travel. If you&amp;rsquo;re arriving during the coldest months of the year, ensure you have adequate clothing. At any time of year, in fact, temperatures can be unpredictable &amp;ndash; even in July and August, it makes sense to have a sweater (and maybe a brolly too) to hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other health problems that inexperienced travellers might reasonably encounter are the various knock-on effects of too much alcohol consumption. The risk, unsurprisingly, is particularly prevalent among those attending Munich&amp;rsquo;s Oktoberfest.&amp;nbsp;Be aware that some beer&amp;rsquo;s ABV levels can be 6 or 7%, so should be treated with respect.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Day of German Unity :
							03 October </p><p>Day of Reformation :
							31 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Repentance Day :
							21 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Germany is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices. There are no allowance restrictions on these tax-free items.</p>
<p>B&uuml;singen and the Isle of Heligoland are treated as being outside of the EU for duty-free purposes.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes, 400 cigarillos, 200 cigars, 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22%, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%, 60L of sparkling wine and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>In Germany, there is no limit on the amount of non-sparkling wine you can import from other EU countries for personal consumption.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Germany by travellers with a minimum age of 17 years without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers (reduced to &euro;175 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unauthorised firearms and ammunition, unapproved fireworks, unconstitutional literature, pornography which is violent or involves children, any food considered a health hazard, narcotics, dangerous dogs, endangered species and counterfeit goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol &euro;) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;5, 2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged at banks, bureaux de change, post offices, airports, railway stations, ports and major hotels at the official exchange rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are widely accepted in most shops, petrol stations, mid- to upmarket restaurants and hotels. All major credit cards are accepted, but it is advisable to carry cash as well. Cheques are very rarely used.</p><p>Cashpoints compatible with international banking networks are located in all towns and cities, as well as airports, major train stations and other spots. They charge a minimum fee for withdrawals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are no longer being used as a payment method in Germany.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0830-1300 and 1400-1600, Thurs 0830-1300 and 1430-1730 in main cities. Main branches do not close for lunch. Bureaux de change in airports and main railway stations are open 0600-2200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If visas are needed, a form must be filled out for each individual applicant, including children under 18. Children travelling alone must supply a letter from both parents authorising them to travel and appointing the person who will be responsible for them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals of certain countries require a transit visa to pass through Germany; check with the consulate for the latest list.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Germany is a signatory to the 1995 Schengen Agreement.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60/&pound;51.40. Nationals of a few countries pay &euro;35/&pound;30.00; check with the consulate for a list.</p>
<p>Children under six years of age, Spouse of EU/EEA national: no fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A Schengen short-stay visa is valid for up to 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If Germany is the main destination of your trip, apply to your local German consulate or embassy. Residents of England, Wales and Northern Ireland requiring a visa should apply to VFS Global (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/germany/uk">www.vfsglobal.com/germany/uk</a>), which charges an additional fee of &pound;19.50. Residents of Scotland and certain parts of northern England must apply to the consulate in Edinburgh. All visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are an EU citizen who wishes to do paid or self-employed work, you do not need a visa or work permit, according to EU regulations. However, if you wish to stay for longer than three months, you should register with the local&nbsp;<em>Einwohnermeldeamt</em> (Residence Registration Office)&nbsp;within a week of finding permanent accommodation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing usually takes at least five working days, but may take longer in some cases.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If applying for a visa, you&rsquo;ll be asked to detail how you intend to support yourself for the duration of your stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend a stay once in the country, you should apply to the <em>Ausl&auml;nderamt</em> (literally &lsquo;Outsider Authorities&rsquo;) office  in the nearest major town.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If travelling with a pet from the UK to Germany, the animal must have a microchip, rabies vaccination certificate and EU pet passport. If being vaccinated for the first time, this should take place at least 21 days before travelling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[51.202004]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[10.381997]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>357,022 sq km (137,846 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>80,679,788 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>226.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Berlin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Germany borders Austria, Belgium, Czech Republic, Denmark, France, Luxembourg, The Netherlands, Poland and Switzerland. The northwest has a coastline on the North Sea while the Baltic coastline in the northeast stretches from the Danish to the Polish border.</p>
<p>The country is divided into 16 states (<em>Bundesl&auml;nder</em>) and has an exceedingly varied landscape. In what was once known as West Germany, the Rhine, Bavaria and the Black Forest stand as the three most famous features, while in the east, the country is lake-studded with undulating lowlands. River basins extend over a large percentage of the region, and some of Europe&rsquo;s most prominent rivers flow through the country. These include the Elbe, the Danube and the Rhine.</p>
<p>The highest point in the country is the 2,962m (9,718ft) peak of Zugspitze Mountain in the Bavarian  Alps. Cable cars run to the summit &ndash; it can also be climbed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Approximately 34% Protestant, 34% Roman Catholic, 5,5% Muslim, with Jewish and other non-Christian minorities. About one third of the population is atheistic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is customary, and it is considered rude to address people by their first name unless invited to do so. Normal courtesies should be observed. Before eating, it is normal to say <em>&quot;guten</em>&nbsp;<em>appetit</em>&quot; to the other people at the table to which the correct reply is <em>&quot;danke, gleichfalls&quot;</em><em> (</em>&ldquo;Thank you, the same to you&rdquo;<em>)</em>. If you&rsquo;ve been invited to eat at a German house, it is customary to present the hostess with unwrapped flowers (according to tradition, you should always give an uneven number, and it is worth noting that red roses are exclusively a lover's gift). <br />
<br />
In shops and other businesses, courtesy dictates that visitors should utter a greeting such as <em>&quot;guten</em> <em>tag&quot;</em> (or <em>&quot;gr&uuml;ss</em> <em>gott&quot;</em> in Bavaria) before saying what it is that they want; to leave without saying <em>&quot;auf</em> <em>wiedersehen</em>&quot; or &quot;<em>tsch&uuml;ss&quot;</em> can also cause offence. Similarly, when making a telephone call, asking for the person you want to speak to without stating first who you are is impolite. Casual wear is widely acceptable, but more formal dress is required for some restaurants, the opera, theatre, casinos and important social functions. Smoking is prohibited where notified and on public transport and in most public buildings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chancellor Angela Merkel since 2005.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Frank-Walter Steinmeier&nbsp;since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The territory that we now know as Germany was for many centuries a loose collection of independent (and often warring) states, occupied by rulers including the Roman Empire, the Holy Roman Empire and the Austrian Habsburgs. Unification was attained after a victory in the Franco-Prussian war of 1871. There followed a period of political, military and economic advancement that placed it as a genuine world power.</p>
<p>Following defeat in WWI, however, the Treaty of Versailles saw the country sliced and diced. Germany was forced to cede parts of its territory to surrounding nations as well as to pay significant reparations &ndash; a punishment that would prove crippling for the already ailing German economy.</p>
<p>It was these dire economic circumstances, amplified by the worldwide economic Depression of 1929 and a growing tide of racism in Europe that gave rise to the emergence of the National Socialist German Workers&rsquo; (Nazi) Party, making Adolf Hitler head of state. His notorious legacy remains a shocking historical blight. Initial military success in WWII ended in further defeat for Germany, although this time, the country&rsquo;s economy recovered more quickly.</p>
<p>After the war, Germany&rsquo;s borders were once again redrawn, and the country and its capital city, Berlin, were divided. For more than 40 years, the communist East Germany was cut off from the US-allied West. In 1989, the Berlin Wall, which separated the eastern districts of the city from the west, started to be dismantled. Reunification took place shortly after in October 1990.</p>
<p>From 1995 onwards, a new leadership under would-be chancellor Gerhard Schr&ouml;der emerged to challenge the long-standing Helmut Kohl Christian Democrat (CDU) government. Schr&ouml;der came to power in 1998, his reign coming to an end amid confusion following September 2005's inconclusive election. Germany faced weeks of uncertainty resulting in a deal that saw Angela Merkel sworn in as Germany's first female chancellor.</p>
<p>Since then, Merkel has guided Germany through the global recession, helping to ensure a quick recovery for the country with stimulus packages. In 2013, she was sworn in for her third four-year term and in 2014, Merkel became the longest serving incumbent head of state in the European Union.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; The elderly in Germany take their downtime very seriously, which is why shopping on Sunday is strictly forbidden.<br />
&bull; Ordering a beer at a bar in Germany? If you don&rsquo;t want to give away your non-native status, be sure to use your thumb to indicate that you want one drink rather than your index finger.<br />
&bull; Oktoberfest, Munich&rsquo;s world-famous beer festival, actually begins in September.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Germany]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>49 (0)30 204 570</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/germany</p><p><b>Tel:</b>49 (0)30 204 570</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Daily except Weds, 0900-1730.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Wilhelmstraße 70/71<br/>Berlin<br/>10117<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Germany in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 298 4000/4224 (visa &amp; passport enquiries) </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.germany.info</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 298 4000/4224 (visa &amp; passport enquiries) </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0800-1145. Visa and passport applications by appointment only.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>4645 Reservoir Road NW<br/>Washington<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Germany in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7824 1300 </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.uk.diplo.de/Vertretung/unitedkingdom/en/Startseite.html</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7824 1300 </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri by appointment only.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>23 Belgrave Square<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8PZ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Misunderstood by many, Germany is one of the most varied and charming countries on the continent. Anyone expecting a homogenous nation conforming to old Teutonic stereotypes is in for a shock.</p>
<p>As a destination, it offers a clutch of truly lovely cities, culture served up in hefty portions and rural scenery so pretty you&rsquo;ll wonder why it isn't on every tourist hit list.</p>
<p>The country occupies a prime position at the heart of Europe &ndash; both literally and figuratively. It is home to the biggest economy on the continent, has more inhabitants than anywhere else in the EU and shares land borders with no less than nine other nations.</p>
<p>It's no surprise, then, that today&rsquo;s Germany is more diverse and cosmopolitan than old stereotypes suggest; mixing time-honoured nationalism and tradition with multicultural modernism and self-confidence.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s the nation&rsquo;s urban highlights that immediately draw the attention. Berlin is the definition of dynamism, having forged a good-time reputation for groundbreaking creativity while still keeping sight of its past.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the likes of Cologne, Munich and Hamburg provide the capital with able support. Not only are they rich in history, whether in the forms of classical music, fine art or medieval architecture, but they also put pay to the notion that Germans don&rsquo;t do gastronomy. These days, you can dine and drink extremely well in Deutschland.</p>
<p>Then there's the beautiful German countryside. From the sky-scraping peaks of the Bavarian Alps and pale cliffs of the Jasmund National Park to the castles of the Rhine and moors of the Mecklenburg Lake District, it's nirvana for hikers, cyclists, boaters, motorists and skiers alike.</p>
<p>Travelling around this country is a piece of Black Forest g&acirc;teau. Costs are manageable, overcrowding is rare and, despite its size, it could not be easier to get from A to B thanks to an incredibly efficient public transport network. Which proves some of those old German stereotypes do hold true.</p><p>Misunderstood by many, Germany is one of the most varied and charming countries on the continent. Anyone expecting a homogenous nation conforming to old Teutonic stereotypes is in for a shock.</p>
<p>As a destination, it offers a clutch of truly lovely cities, culture served up in hefty portions and rural scenery so pretty you&rsquo;ll wonder why it isn't on every tourist hit list.</p>
<p>The country occupies a prime position at the heart of Europe &ndash; both literally and figuratively. It is home to the biggest economy on the continent, has more inhabitants than anywhere else in the EU and shares land borders with no less than nine other nations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
