<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Gibraltar" ColCode="gib" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="gi" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Gibraltar]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Warm throughout the year, with hot summers and mild winters. Summer (May to September) can be very hot and humid. Gibraltar boasts around 300 day's sunshine a year. Temperatures can rise well above 30&deg;C (86&deg;F) between May and September. However the heat and humidity is tempered by sea breezes. Winters are mild with sunshine and temperatures around 17&ordm;C (62&deg;F) and with&nbsp;only occasional rainfall.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights for summer and mediumweights for winter months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>There are plenty of taxis and the driver is required by law to carry and produce on demand a copy of the taxi fares.</p><p>Third-party insurance is compulsory. Valid national driving licences are accepted. A certificate of registration is required. Vehicles must have a national number plate.</p><p>The speed limit is 50kph (31mph), except where otherwise indicated. Seat belts are compulsory and it is compulsory to drive with dipped headlights at night.</p><p>Both self-drive and chauffeur-driven cars are available. Touring outside Gibraltar can also be arranged.</p><p>The speed limit is 50kph (31mph), except where otherwise indicated. Seat belts are compulsory and it is compulsory to drive with dipped headlights at night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Gibraltar Bus Company (<a href="http://www.gibraltarbuscompany.gi" target="_blank">www.gibraltarbuscompany.gi</a>) runs an efficient local bus service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gibraltar</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tangier</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gibraltar</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">malaga</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gibraltar</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">madrid</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">12.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gibraltar</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">london</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating flights to Gibraltar include British Airways (<a href="http://www.britishairways.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Monarch Airlines (<a href="http://www.monarch.co.uk" target="_blank">www.monarch.co.uk</a>), which&nbsp;all operate direct services from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 50 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 11 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Gibraltar Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.gibraltarairterminal.com]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main port:</strong> The port of Gibraltar (<a href="http://www.gibraltarport.com" target="_blank">www.gibraltarport.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>No railway systems operate in Gibraltar; however, the neighbouring towns of San Roque and Algeciras, in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a>, are only a few minutes' drive away and are both serviced by the national rail network of Spain, RENFE (<a href="http://www.renfe.com" target="_blank">www.renfe.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage spans the whole of Gibraltar and a large part of the sea around. Handsets can be hired.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet caf&eacute;s are available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Television and radio services are operated by the Gibraltar Broadcasting Corporation (GBC). The broadcaster's services are partly funded by TV licence fee revenues. Radio and TV stations based in Spain, and broadcasts for British forces in the territory, can be received. Newspapers are in English; some have Spanish sections: The New People, Panorama (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.panorama.gi">www.panorama.gi</a>) and Vox are published weekly; The Gibraltar Chronicle (established 1801) is the only daily (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.chronicle.gi">www.chronicle.gi</a>). The local radio station is Radio Gibraltar, and BFBS Radio Gibraltar is for British forces.<strong><br />
</strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail within Europe takes one to five days. Airmail flights are usually daily.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1630 (0900-1415 in summer), Sat 1000-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Upper Rock Nature Reserve</p><![CDATA[<p>The <em>Upper Rock Nature Reserve</em> is a protected area of great natural beauty perched about 1380ft (421m) above sea level on the limestone peninsular of Gibraltar. Its most famous residents are the <em>Barbary Apes</em>, which have lived on the Rock for hundreds of years as Europe&rsquo;s only free-roaming apes. According to legend, when the apes leave, Gibraltar will cease to be British. The Reserve is also home to many species of bird, such as buzzards and Barbary partridges. Visitors also come to see <em>St Michael&rsquo;s Cave</em>, one of a vast warren of caves containing stalagmites and stalactites, and the <em>Siege Tunnels</em>, which were used as a defence system by the British in the Great Siege (1779-1783) against the French and Spanish. Another popular site in the Reserve is the 14th-century <em>Moorish Castle</em>, which testifies to the diverse history of the peninsular.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire Gibraltar's architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gibraltar's interesting architecture includes the 14th-century keep of the much-rebuilt Moorish Castle; the Shrine of Our Lady of Europe, a mosque before its conversion to a Christian chapel in 1462, which houses the 15th-century image of the Patroness of Gibraltar; and the Lighthouse and Mosque, which blends classic Islamic design with modern facilities.</p>]]><p><b>Explore St Michael's Cave</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located inside the Rock, St Michael's Cave is situated 300m (1,000ft) above sea level, and was known to the Romans for its spectacular stalactites and stalagmites. It is part of a complex series of interlinked caves, including Leonora's Cave and Lower St Michael's Cave. Today, it is used for concerts and ballet. The Upper Galleries, hewn by hand from the Rock in 1782, house old cannons and tableaux evoking the Great Siege (1779-1783).</p>]]><p><b>Feed your brain in Gibraltar Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See a replica of the Gibraltar Skull – the first Neanderthal skull found in Europe (1848) – and caveman tools and ornaments excavated from the Rock's caves. There are also exhibits from the Phoenician, Greek, Roman, Moorish, Spanish and British periods of the Rock's history, a comprehensive collection of prints and lithographs, and a large-scale model of the Rock made in 1865.</p>]]><p><b>Find ghosts in the Convent</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to the Convent at the end of Main Street to see the daily changing of the guards. The convent has been the residence of the governor since 1728, and was formerly a 16th-century Franciscan Monastic house. It is also rumoured that the convent is haunted by the ghost of a nun, known as the 'Lady in Grey'.</p>]]><p><b>Go birdwatching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Birdwatching can be undertaken in spring and autumn, when thousands of migrating birds stop off on their way between their breeding grounds in northern Europe and their wintering areas in Africa. Owls, eagles, harriers, hoopoes, buzzards and black kites join resident species such as peregrine falcons, blue rock thrush and Barbary partridge.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back on Gibraltar’s beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gibraltar has some great beaches to explore. On the east side of the island are Eastern Beach and Catalan Bay. Little Bay, a pebble beach, and Camp Bay/Keys Promenade are on the western coast. Pier fishing facilities are available on the island and scuba-diving, parasailing and water-skiing can also be practised.</p>]]><p><b>Pay a visit to the famous macaque monkeys</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the Apes' Den, take pictures of the famous Barbary apes, which are in fact not apes but macaque monkeys without tails. These are the only wild primates in Europe. The Spanish once said that when the monkeys left Gibraltar, the British would follow. This prompted the British PM to have more apes delivered to the Rock.</p>]]><p><b>Take a guided walk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go on a guided walking tour around the city walls, held every Friday at 1030. The walls and fortifications of the City of Gibraltar were first built by the Moors to defend the country against invasion, and have since been added to by the Spanish and British. A walk along the walls is the best way to get a glimpse into the history of the city and sites.</p>]]><p><b>Take a stroll around Trafalgar Cemetery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Find the town's ancient cemetery just off Main Street, at Southport Gate. Treacherous sea battles took their toll, with many lost lives commemorated here. Browse the intricate and well-kept headstones, some dating back to 1789.</p>]]><p><b>Take the cable car to Ape's Den</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a cable car trip to the top of the Rock. Built in 1966, the Top Station is on the summit of the Rock, from where visitors can see Spain to the north and Africa to the south. The cable car journey stops at the Apes' Den, where the islands' famous primates scamper about.</p>]]><p><b>Watch whales and dolphins</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Bay of Gibraltar is home to a large population of dolphins and whales, and tourists can take boat trips to view these fascinating creatures. It's easy to spot the dolphins (some operators offer guarantees), but the whales – including killer, fin and humpbacks – are a little more aloof.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>£602 million (2009).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum and manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fuels, manufactured goods and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Germany, Greece, Italy, Russia, Spain, Switzerland, Sweden, Turkmenistan, UK and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main sources of income are tourism and offshore financial services, principally banking, insurance and shipping-related services. The industrial economy is based on ship repair, construction and small-scale manufacturing.<br /><br />The British armed forces (historically the main source of revenue through their base facilities on the Rock) sharply reduced their presence from 1994 onwards and now provide less than 10% of GDP. Since then, concessionary tax and corporate facilities for foreign companies have boosted the financial services sector.<br /><br />Since 1998, a substantial gambling industry has developed, servicing punters from throughout Europe (again the consequence of a favourable tax regime) and it now makes a significant contribution to employment and government revenue.<br /><br />The economy as a whole is sensitive to the state of relations with Spain and, in particular, restrictions on border crossings since a significant number of Spaniards have jobs on the Rock. <br />Europort Gibraltar, an 82,000 sq metre (212,000 sq ft) financial complex, offers extensive office and conference facilities in addition to Gibraltar's recently refurbished hotels. St Michael's Cave (see <em>Top Things To See & Do</em>) offers an absolutely unique and scenic location for meetings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>English is normally used for business, but Spanish may be used for business connected with Spain.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700; 0800-1400 in summer.<br /><br /><strong>Government office hours: </strong>Generally Mon-Fri 0845-1315 and 1415-1730, but hours vary according to department and season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Gibraltar Government Office in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7836 0777
					Website:http://www.gibraltar.gov.uk
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Gibraltar Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 78376.
					Website:http://www.gibraltarchamberofcommerce.com
					Address: ,Watergate House,2-6 Casements,PO Box 29]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are bars and bistros throughout the town and at the two marinas, operating under Mediterranean licensing hours and selling British beer. Restaurants cover the whole price range, and offer British dishes as well as French, Spanish, American, Moroccan, Italian, Chinese and Indian cuisine. Typically Gibraltan food is a combination of British, Maltese, Italian and Spanish influences though it is rare to find it in restaurants and caf&eacute;s. Instead there is a cosmopolitan choice of cooking and a thriving caf&eacute; society, particularly in Casemates Square.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Spinach <em>tortilla.<br />
&bull; Calentita</em> and <em>panissa</em> (both are like quiche but are made from chick pea flour).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Normally 10 to 15%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gibraltar does not have a particularly vibrant nightlife, although there are several nightclubs to head to should the mood arise. The casino also serves as a restaurant and nightclub and is open past midnight.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luxury goods are sold in Gibraltar free of VAT and duty so there are bargains to be had on alcoholic drinks, tobacco, silk, linen, cashmere, jewellery, glassware, porcelain, perfumes, electronic and photographic equipment, watches and more. For a local souvenir visit the Gibraltar Crystal Factory. The majority of shops are on or just off Main Street.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0930-1930, Sat 1000-1300. Some shops open Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gibraltar's hotels range from luxury establishments with lounges, terraces, bars and swimming pools, to far more modest affairs. Hotels are inspected annually and given a star or diamond rating. Hostel accommodation is also available in Gibraltar. More information may be obtained from the Gibraltar Tourist Board on request.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gibraltar's hotels range from luxury establishments with lounges, terraces, bars and swimming pools, to far more modest affairs. Hotels are inspected annually and given a star or diamond rating. Hostel accommodation is also available in Gibraltar. More information may be obtained from the Gibraltar Tourist Board on request.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gibraltar's hotels range from luxury establishments with lounges, terraces, bars and swimming pools, to far more modest affairs. Hotels are inspected annually and given a star or diamond rating. Hostel accommodation is also available in Gibraltar. More information may be obtained from the Gibraltar Tourist Board on request.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;UK citizens are entitled to free treatment in public wards at St Bernard's Hospital and at Casemates Health Centre on presentation of a UK passport during stays of up to 30 days. Other EEA nationals are similarly entitled on presentation of a European Health Insurance Card. All other nationals are advised to take out comprehensive travel insurance.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Visitors to forested areas should consider vaccination for tick-borne encephalitis.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Commonwealth Day :
							12 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Spring Bank Holiday :
							28 May </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							11 June </p><p>Summer Bank Holiday :
							27 August </p><p>Gibraltar National Day :
							10 September </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be taken into Gibraltar by travellers aged 17 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 200g of tobacco. <br />
&bull; 1L of spirits or 2L of fortified or sparkling wine.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine. <br />
&bull; 50ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Other articles up to &pound;32.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited or restricted goods include drugs, firearms and ammunition, offensive weapons, explosives, fireworks, indecent or obscene material, fast launches, raw or worked ivory, rigid inflatable boats of 6m or more, or tobacco in commercial quanitities.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pound (GBP; symbol &pound;) = 100 pence. Notes are in denominations of &pound;50, 20, 10 and 5.&nbsp; Coins are in denominations of &pound;2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 pence. The Gibraltar government issues its own banknotes and coinage to be used locally.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourists from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> are strongly advised to change their unspent Gibraltar pounds into UK currency at parity in Gibraltar before departure as UK banks charge for exchanging the Gibraltar Pound.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major cards accepted.</p><p>ATMs are available across Gibraltar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0900-1530, Fri 0900-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A valid passport is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above, except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals in possession of a national ID card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gibraltar is not part of the Schengen area. However, Schengen visa holders from some countries may visit Gibraltar visa-free for up to 21 days, provided they have at least seven days remaining on the visa; check with the Government of Gibraltar for a list of eligible countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British embassies charge &pound;115 for receiving, handling and forwarding visa applications for British Overseas Territories.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nearest British Embassy or High Commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If planning on bringing your pet into Gibraltar, ensure the animal has a valid rabies vaccination certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[36.136031]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-5.349042]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6.8 sq km (2.6 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>32,373 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,179.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gibraltar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Self-governing British Overseas Territory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gibraltar is a large promontory of jurassic limestone, situated in the western entrance to the Mediterranean. The rock is 5km (3 miles) long and the highest point is 426m (1,400ft) above sea level. An internal self-governing British Crown Colony, Gibraltar has given its name to the Bay and the Straits, which it overlooks. Spain is to the north and west, and Morocco is 26km (16 miles) to the south.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic majority, also Church of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/england">England</a>, Church of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland">Scotland</a>, Jewish, Hindu and other minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gibraltar is a strongly traditional society with an attractive blend of British and Mediterranean customs.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are in use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chief Minister Fabian Picardo since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor Edward Davis since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gibraltar derives its name from <i>Gibel Tariq </i>(Tariq's Mountain), which is named after Tariq Ibn Zeyad who led the eighth-century conquest of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a> by a combined force of Arabs and Berbers crossing from Africa.</p>
<p>Gibraltar's unusual status was not acquired until almost 1000 years later, long after the Islamic invaders had been driven out by the Spanish, as a consequence of the 1713 Treaty of Utrecht which brought to an end the War of the Spanish Succession and gave the territory to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Britain</a>. The British interpretation of the treaty moreover, holds that the territory was ceded to them indefinitely. T</p>
<p>he presence of a foreign-owned mini-state on the Spanish mainland has been an irritant to Anglo-Spanish relations ever since. The Spanish dictator, General Franco, launched a campaign in 1963 through the United Nations to reclaim Gibraltar, adding to the pressure by closing the border and severing telephone links. <br />
<br />
Since the death of Franco in 1975 and the return of democracy to Spain, relations between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/madrid">Madrid</a> have improved immensely in every area - except Gibraltar. The current Spanish position was first outlined by Felipe Gonz&aacute;lez, Spain's Socialist premier during the 1980s, when he suggested joint Anglo-Spanish sovereignty. Successive Spanish governments, including the present Zapatero administration, have since refined the proposals, allowing for possible EU or NATO involvement. The British have no major objection, in principle, to the Spanish recovering full sovereignty over the territory - provided they are guaranteed continued access to its military base facilities. The problem is that the Gibraltarians are having none of it: no handover; no joint sovereignty; no Spanish involvement whatsoever.</p>
<p>Domestic politics in Gibraltar are dominated by two main blocs, the ruling centre-right Social Democrats and the opposition alliance of the Socialist Labour Party and the Liberal Party. The Social Democrats formed the present government after their victory under the leadership of Peter Caruana, who was re-elected as Prime Minister for a&nbsp;fourth term at the most recent poll in 2007. On the issue of sovereignty, there are some differences in emphasis, but no essential difference between the basic positions of any of the three parties.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[UK Foreign and Commonwealth Office]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b> (020) 7008 1500 (general enquiries) or 8457 (visa enquiries) or 0210 (services for Britons overseas).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/foreign-commonwealth-office</p><p><b>Tel:</b> (020) 7008 1500 (general enquiries) or 8457 (visa enquiries) or 0210 (services for Britons overseas).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>King Charles Street<br/>Overseas Territories Department<br/>London<br/>SW1A 2AH<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Gibraltar Government Office in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 452 1108</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gibraltar.gov.gi</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 452 1108</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Suite 1100<br/>1156 15th Street,NW<br/>Washington<br/>20005<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gibraltar is full of surprises: from its lively population of Barbary macaques (monkeys) to its sub-tropical climate, this little British enclave on the Mediterranean is awash with wonders.</p>
<p>The Rock, as Gibraltar is known, is a monolithic peninsula riddled with curious caves and tunnels. Atop its limestone base thrives unique vegetation and many species of migrating birds, which combined with glorious views and stimulating walks make Gibraltar a popular destination for nature enthusiasts.</p>
<p>The town itself is densely concentrated on the western side of the rock; those with an interest in history should visit the Gibraltar Museum for an insight into Gibraltar's heritage of Moorish, Spanish and British rulers, while foodies will enjoy sampling fresh seafood and colourful Spanish dishes.</p>Gibraltar is full of surprises: from its lively population of Barbary macaques (monkeys) to its sub-tropical climate, this little British enclave on the Mediterranean is awash with wonders.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
