<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Greece" ColCode="grc" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="gr" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Greece]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greece has a warm Mediterranean climate. In summer, dry hot days are often relieved by stiff evening breezes, especially in the north, on the islands and in coastal areas. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/athens">Athens</a> can be stiflingly hot, with temperatures occasionally exceeding 40&deg;C (104&deg;F) in July. Winters are mild in the south but much colder in the mountainous north, where it is not uncommon to see snow and temperatures plummeting to well below zero. November to March is the rainy season, most notably on the Ionian islands.</p>
<p>If you are planning a beach holiday, the sea is warm enough to swim from June through September, and hardier types will also manage in May and October. Seaside hotels are generally open from Easter through to late-October, as are water sports facilities.</p>
<p>Spring and autumn are the ideal seasons for hiking and mountain biking, when the days are sunny but not unreasonably hot. Spring sees the Greek countryside dappled with wild flowers, while in autumn the trees take on russet hues.</p>
<p>Although few people think of Greece as a winter destination, it is in fact possible to ski and snowboard here. Two of the most popular mountain ski resorts are Arahova (near Delphi) and Kalavrita (on the Peloponnese), both much loved by wealthy Athenians, and therefore also well provided with cosy hotels and authentic rustic eateries with blazing log fires.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothes (cotton is best) during summer months, including protection from the midday sun and sunglasses. Light sweaters are needed for evenings, especially on the islands. Waterproofs are advised for spring and autumn. Winter months can be quite cold, especially in the northern mainland, so normal winter wear will be required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Olympic Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.olympicair.com">www.olympicair.com</a>) and Aegean Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aegeanair.com">www.aegeanair.com</a>) operate domestic flights in Greece.  Major routes include Athens-Thessaloniki and Athens-Heraklion (on Crete).</p>
<p>For many people, travelling from Athens to the islands by ferry is far more enjoyable than flying, though if time is an issue, flights are quicker for more distant islands such as Corfu, Crete and Rhodes. Through summer, advance bookings are recommended. Private charter flights are also available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is both cheap and easy to travel around the islands. There are ferry services (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.greekferries.gr">www.greekferries.gr</a>) on many routes, with services most frequent during the summer. The main ports in Attica are Piraeus and Rafina, although there are regular services to the islands from the smaller ports of Alexandroupolis, Igoumenitsa, Kavala, Kyllini, Patras, Thessaloniki and Volos.</p>
<p>You can buy tickets from the shipping lines' offices located around the quaysides or online. In major ports the larger companies have offices in the city centre. There are two classes of ticket (First Class and Economy Class) which offer varying degrees of comfort; cabins can be booked for the longer voyages or those wishing to avoid the sun. Most ships have restaurant facilities. During high season it is wise to buy tickets in advance, as inter-island travel is very popular.</p>
<p><strong>Routes from Piraeus:</strong> Piraeus offers frequent services to most islands in the following groups: Argo-Saronic, Cyclades, Dodecanese and the northeast Aegean, plus Crete and several mainland ports.</p>
<p>Check sailing times either with individual lines, the Greek National Tourism Organisation, or in Piraeus. <br />
<br />
<strong>Routes from Rafina:</strong> There are ferries to nearby Evia from Rafina, plus to some islands in the Cyclades, the Dodecanese, and the northeast Aegean.</p>
<p><strong>Other routes:</strong> Several other routes between the mainland ports and the islands are also covered.</p>
<p><strong>Hydrofoil:</strong> A hydrofoil service, also called the Flying Dolphins (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hellenicseaways.gr">www.hellenicseaways.gr</a>), offers a fast and efficient service from Piraeus, travelling to many of the nearby islands. Although this is somewhat more expensive than travelling by ferry, journey times are cut drastically. The company also serves some other routes. For further information on various ferry and hydrofoil timetables, see the Greek Travel Pages (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.gtp.gr">www.gtp.gr</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Yachts:</strong> Numerous types of yachts and sailing vessels can be chartered or hired with or without crews. 'Flotilla holidays' are popular, and the Greek National Tourism Organisation has a full list of companies running this type of holiday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Athens has one main railway station, Larissa. Train information and tickets are available from the Hellenic Railways Organisation (OSE) (tel: 14511, in Greece only; <a href="http://www.trainose.gr" target="_blank">www.trainose.gr</a>). The most efficient service runs north-south, from Athens to Thessaloniki.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Greece. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Balkan Flexipass:</strong> offers five, 10 or 15 days' unlimited rail travel within one month in Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina, Bulgaria, Greece, Macedonia (Former Yugoslav Republic of), Montenegro, Romania, Serbia and Turkey. Available from Rail Europe (<a href="http://www.raileurope.com" target="_blank">www.raileurope.com</a>) to anyone residing outside these countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greece's motorway network has been significantly upgraded over the past decade or so. Motorways and some bridges incur a toll. In rural areas, and especially on the islands, many roads are narrow, twisty and poorly surfaced.</p>
<p>Beware that roads up steep mountains may involve hairpin bends and plummeting cliffs with no guardrails. To reach some of the more isolated beaches you may have to negotiate unsurfaced tracks &ndash; in which case it's often better to walk.</p>r<p>All Greece&rsquo;s main cities and many small destinations too are connected by an extensive network of long-distance buses, which almost always prove more efficient than the train. Major routes include Athens-Thessaloniki and Athens-Patras. The private companies involved operate under the umbrella of KTEL (tel: 14505, within Greece only; <a href="http://www.ktel.org" target="_blank">www.ktel.org</a>).</p><p>In Athens, taxis are safe, plentiful and cheap. It is common practice to share the ride (but not the cost) with other passengers going in a similar direction. The same applies for other major cities. On the more commercial islands, such as Santorini, taxis can be expensive and also difficult to find during peak season. On the less touristy islands, taxis are cheaper but often scarce.</p><p>A national driving licence is acceptable for EU nationals. You must carry your car registration documents at all times. Nationals of non-EU countries may need an International Driving Permit and should contact ELPA.</p><p>The minimum age for driving is 18. Children under 10 must sit in the back seat. Seat belts must be worn. There are fines for breaking traffic regulations. The maximum speed limit is 110-130kph (68-81mph) on motorways, 90kph (56mph) on non-urban roads and 50kph (30mph) in built-up areas. It is illegal to carry spare petrol in the vehicle, and to use a mobile phone (without hands-free) while driving. It is also illegal to use your horn in built-up areas except in cases where there is immediate danger.</p><p>ELPA (Automobile and Touring Club of Greece; tel: +30 210 606 8800; <a href="http://www.elpa.gr" target="_blank">www.elpa.gr</a>). Emergency breakdown services can be contacted toll-free by dialling 10400.</p><p>Most major international car hire firms operate throughout Greece, with offices at airports, ferry ports and in all major cities. The legal age for hiring a car is 21.</p><p>Greeks can be erratic drivers and big cities are risky for cyclists. That said, the Greek countryside offers superb terrain for mountain bikers. Various companies hire out bikes, and organise guided and self-guided tours of anything from a half-day to one week. The most popular regions for cycling are the island of Crete and the Peloponnese, both of which offer cycling paths, rural back roads and stunning mountain scenery.</p><p>The minimum age for driving is 18. Children under 10 must sit in the back seat. Seat belts must be worn. There are fines for breaking traffic regulations. The maximum speed limit is 110-130kph (68-81mph) on motorways, 90kph (56mph) on non-urban roads and 50kph (30mph) in built-up areas. It is illegal to carry spare petrol in the vehicle, and to use a mobile phone (without hands-free) while driving. It is also illegal to use your horn in built-up areas except in cases where there is immediate danger.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Athens:</strong> Athens city centre is well served by frequent buses and trolleybuses, and its reliable underground system extends out to the airport. You can buy tickets from Transport for Athens (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.oasa.gr">www.oasa.gr</a>) at various booths and kiosks situated around the city as well as at underground stations.</p>
<p>The tram system in Athens cuts through the city from Syntagma Square right through to the coast and runs a pleasant route from Peace and Friendship Stadium (in Neo Faliro) all the way to the most southern point of Glyfada. Trams connect with the Metro at Syntagma, Neos Kosmos and Neo Faliro.</p>
<p>Athens' large fleet of yellow taxis are extremely cheap by European standards. If you hail a taxi down in the street, it's not unusual to share the ride with other passengers going in a similar direction. Drivers are obliged to run a meter. Prices go up between midnight and 0500.</p>
<p><strong>Thessaloniki:</strong> The city centre is well served by frequent buses. Tickets can be purchased from <em>periptera</em> (kiosks). A new metro system opened is expected to be completed by 2018. Taxis in Thessaloniki are dark blue and white. As in Athens, they are cheap and plentiful.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Greece</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">thessaloniki</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Greece</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">rhodes</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.55</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Greece</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">crete</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Greece</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">corfu</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">11*</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greece's main carriers are Olympic Air (<a href="http://www.olympicair.com" target="_blank">www.olympicair.com</a>) and Aegean Airlines (<a href="http://www.aegeanair.com" target="_blank">www.aegeanair.com</a>). Other airlines operating flights from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>).&nbsp;The cost of flights to Greece peaks in July and August when most Europeans take their holidays. Throughout the rest of the year prices vary according to demand.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece/athens-eleftherios-venizelos-international-airport">Athens Eleftherios Venizelos International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece/corfu/corfu-ioannis-kapodistrias-international-airport">Corfu Ioannis Kapodistrias International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece/chania-international-airport">Chania International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece/thessaloniki-international-airport">Thessaloniki International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece/heraklion-international-airport-nikos-kazantzakis">Heraklion International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece/kos-island-international-airport-hippocrates">Kos Island International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece/mykonos-island-airport">Mykonos Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece/rhodes-diagoras-airport">Rhodes Diagoras International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/athens">Athens</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 3 hours 40 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 10 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Athens Eleftherios Venizelos International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aia.gr<p>Athens Eleftherios Venizelos International Airport is located 33km (20 miles) southeast of central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/athens">Athens</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+30 210 353 0000</p>]]><b>Rhodes Diagoras International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.rhodes-airport.org/<p>Rhodes Diagoras International Airport is located near the north coast of Rhodes, about 15km (9 miles) to the southwest of Rhodes city, near the village of Paradisi.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+30 2241 088 700</p>]]><b>Corfu Ioannis Kapodistrias International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.hcaa.gr<p>Corfu Ioannis Kapodistrias International Airport is located around 3km (1.8 miles) to the south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/corfu">Corfu</a> town, on the eastern part of the island.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+30 2661 089 600</p>]]><b>Heraklion International Airport - Nikos Kazantzakis</b><![CDATA[http://www.hcaa.gr<p>Heraklion International Airport is located 5km (3 miles) east of the city of Heraklion.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+30 2810 397 129</p>]]><b>Kos Island International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.hcaa.gr<p>Kos Island International Airport is located 26km (16 miles) to the west of the town of Kos.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+30 22420 56000.</p>]]><b>Mykonos Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.jmk-airport.gr<p>Mykonos Airport is located 4km (2.5 miles) southeast of the town of Mykonos.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+30 22890 22327</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greece&rsquo;s main port for international ferry arrivals is Patras (<a href="http://www.patrasport.gr" target="_blank">www.patrasport.gr</a>), with daily overnight services from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/venice">Venice</a>, Ancona, Brindisi and Bari in Italy. The main port for internal passenger arrivals is Athens&rsquo; port, Piraeus (<a href="http://www.olp.gr" target="_blank">www.olp.gr</a>), with dozens of daily ferry and catamaran departures for the Greek islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national railway company is Hellenic Railways Organisation Ltd (OSE) (tel: 14511, in Greece only;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.trainose.gr" target="_blank">www.trainose.gr</a>).</p>
<p>A good way to travel from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> is to take the Eurostar through the Channel Tunnel, from London to either <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brussels">Brussels</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a>, both of which have onward connections to Greece (via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a>, then an overnight ferry). The journey takes an average of around 48 hours. The Man in Seat 61 provides all the options (<a href="http://www.seat61.com/Greece.htm" target="_blank">www.seat61.com/Greece.htm</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to ferry cars and caravans across to one of the major ports of entry. Points of overland entry are from the Former Yugoslav Republic of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/macedonia">Macedonia</a> via Evzoni (550km from Athens), and Niki (630km from Athens); from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bulgaria">Bulgaria</a> via Promahonas (610km from Athens); from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey">Turkey</a> via Kastanies (920km from Athens) or Kipoi (840km from Athens).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The best way to call home is from a call centre or internet café – public telephones are scarce and those that exist tend be on noisy street corners.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is excellent on the mainland and islands, but occasionally disappears in more rural locations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is widely available in Greece and in most establishments it is free to customers. Internet cafes in the cities and on the main islands of Crete, Kos, Mykonos and Rhodes, also offer Internet access.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A free press operates in Greece, although material deemed offensive to the president or religious beliefs can lead to the prosecution of editors and publishers. It was only in the late 1980s that the virtual monopoly of state-run broadcasters came to an end, with the introduction of new commercial TV services. Peak-time TV schedules are dominated by news, domestically made variety programmes, comedies and game shows. <br />
<br />
The country hosts about 1,700 private radio and TV stations, many of which are unlicensed, since broadcasting in Greece is relatively unregulated by European standards. An attempt made in 2001 to regulate the FM dial in Athens resulted in a political row. There are numerous daily newspapers in Athens including <em>Eleftherotypia</em>, <em>Kathimerini</em> and <em>Ta Nea</em>; <em>Athens News</em> is published weekly in English. Foreign-language newspapers are available in all the main tourist destinations, though on the more remote islands they may be a day out of date.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All letters, postcards, newspapers and periodicals will automatically be sent by airmail. Airmail to the rest of Europe takes five days; six to North America; seven to Australia.</p><p>In Athens, the main post office on Syntagma Square is open Mon-Fri 0730-2000, Sat 0730-1400 and Sun 0900-1330. Most smaller offices work Mon-Fri 0730-1400 only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Epidaurus</p><![CDATA[<p>The fourth-century BC Sanctuary of Asclepius at Epidaurus was once an important healing centre as well as a religious centre and spa – today it is a UNESCO world heritage site. It boasts a well-preserved 1400-seat theatre, which comes alive every summer with theatrical performances. There is also a small excavation museum near Epidaurus, which was built between 1902 and 1909, and contains many remains from the sanctuary.</p>]]><br/><p>Knossos</p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the extensive ruins of Knossos, a 3,000-year-old frescoed Minoan Palace, home to Europe's earliest civilisation. Discovered by British archaeologist Arthur Evans in 1900, it was subsequently excavated and partially reconstructed. Finds from the site are displayed in the Archaeological Museum in the nearby Venetian-style port town of Iraklio, on Crete.</p>]]><br/><p>Mycenae</p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the treasure trove that is Mycenae on the Peloponnese. This hilltop citadel of private dwellings and shrines, surrounded by Cyclopean Walls, was the powerful Mycenaeans' capital from about 1600 BC to about 1100 BC. Golden treasure, including the 'Mask of Agamemnon' and 'Nestor's Cup', was found here. Today the highlight at Mycenae, which is one of the most popular attractions in Greece and a UNESCO world heritage site, is the much-photographed Lion Gate.</p>]]><br/><p>Samaria Gorge</p><![CDATA[<p>From May through September, keen hikers tackle Crete's gruelling Samaria Gorge. This dramatic, high-sided, rocky canyon, runs 18km from Xiloskalo, at an altitude of 1200m, down to the tiny village of Agia Roumeli, on the coast, making it the longest gorge in Europe. Thanks to its outstanding natural beauty, it is on the UNESCO world heritage 'tentative' list.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Athens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Begin with the UNESCO-listed Acropolis rock, home to the magnificent fifth-century BC Parthenon, then stroll down to the Ancient Agora, once Athens' civic, political and commercial centre. Be sure to check out the ultra-modern New Acropolis Museum, displaying ancient finds from the Acropolis site, and opened in summer 2010. Don't miss the world-class National Archaeological Museum, packed with ancient marble statues, jewellery and ceramics.</p>]]><p><b>Birdwatching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are 11 wetlands of international importance in Greece, and over 190 'important bird areas'. The most impressive include the Nestos Delta in Thrace and the Prespa Lakes in Macedonia. Expect to see herons, storks, pelicans and eagles.</p>]]><p><b>Corfu’s Old Town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fortified by the Venetians, this charming medieval sea port is protected by two castles – the hilltop Old Citadel and the seaward New Fortress. The UNESCO-listed old town is packed with 19th-century neo-classical mansions, many housing quaint tavernas and souvenir shops at ground level. The Spianada, a vast green space designed by the French, with a music pavilion and a cricket field, is overlooked by the arcaded Liston, home to several elegant cafes.</p>]]><p><b>Delphi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover Delphi, believed by the ancients to be the centre of the world. This fascinating pagan religious complex, set on a stunning hillside site, comprises classical temples, a theatre and a stadium. Numerous finds are displayed in the excellent Delphi Archaeological Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the Cyclades</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Santorini's whitewashed towns of Ia and Thira, built on a cliff overlooking the caldera, a circular depression in the sea created when a volcanic eruption blew the centre out of the island around 1600 BC. Expect stunning sunsets, black sand beaches, boutique hotels and gourmet cuisine. Mykonos, known for its glamorous, hedonistic nightlife, attracts celebrities and fashionistas in equal measure as well as a notable gay community.</p>]]><p><b>Epidaurus</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Sanctuary of Asclepius at Epidaurus was once an important healing centre as well as a religious centre and spa. Built in the fourth century BC, the sanctuary was dedicated to the healer god, Asclepius, and boasts a well-preserved 1400-seat theatre, which was designed by Polycleitus, who built similar buildings at Olympia and Delphi. The theatre is the most famous of all the ancient theatres in Greece and comes alive every summer with theatrical performances. There is also a small excavation museum near Epidaurus, which was built between 1902 and 1909, and contains many remains from the sanctuary.</p>]]><p><b>Hellenic Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Do not miss the Hellenic Festival (<a href="http://www.greekfestival.gr" target="_blank">www.greekfestival.gr</a>), Jun-Sep, which sees music, dance and theatre performances held in the second-century AD Odeion of Herodes in Athens, as well as classical Greek dramas in the fourth-century BC amphitheatre in Epidaurus.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Greek Islands are home to countless stunning beaches. These range from the glamorous party beaches of Paradise and Psarou on Mykonos, to the more sedate family-orientated pine-scented golden sands of Koukounaries on Skiathos. Other joys include the white pebbles and turquoise waters of Myrtos, backed by plummeting cliffs on Kefalonia's dramatic west coast, and the isolated beach of Vai, sheltered by Europe's largest palm grove, on Crete.</p>]]><p><b>Karst caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Greece is home to some 6,000 karst caves, the majority in Crete. Over 20 show caves are open for guided tours, the largest and most impressive being Perama, which is filled with stalagmites and stalactites. Some were used in antiquity as sites of worship, then later housed churches and monasteries, or even became used as hideaways during Greece's struggles for independence.</p>]]><p><b>Knossos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the extensive ruins of Knossos, a 3,000-year-old frescoed Minoan Palace, home to Europe's earliest civilisation. Finds from the site are displayed in the Archaeological Museum in the nearby Venetian-style port town of Iraklio, on Crete.</p>]]><p><b>Lake Plastira</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the work of man of nature combined at Lake Plastira in Kardista. Surrounded by hills covered in oak and chestnut trees, a wander round the glistening waters and awe inspiring views are sure to leave your senses soothed.</p>]]><p><b>Meteora</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On the edge of a flat plain in Thessaly, Central Greece, the Meteora is Greece's second most important group of monasteries after Mount Athos. From the 11th century onwards, when the first hermits settled here, 24 Orthodox monasteries were built atop bizarre rocky pinnacles overlooking the plain. Today, six monasteries, several decorated with late-Byzantine frescoes, are open to the public.</p>]]><p><b>Monemvasia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Slow down in the old fortified Byzantine town of Monemvasia. The town can only be reached by a single causeway after an earthquake in 375 AD caused it to split from the mainland. Cars are not allowed in the old town, but romantic boutique hotels, starry nights and fine food most certainly are.</p>]]><p><b>Mount Athos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stand tall on Mount Athos, also known as 'Holy Mountain', in the east of the Chalcidice peninsula. Home to 20 Orthodox monasteries, some 1000 monks and an invaluable collection of frescoes and religious art, it dates from 1045 and is now a UNESCO world heritage site. Although it is part of Greece, it has a special self-governing status. Women and children are banned, and men who wish to visit it need to make a complicated application for permission.</p>]]><p><b>Mycenae</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the treasure trove that is Mycenae. This hilltop citadel, surrounded by Cyclopean Walls, was the powerful Mycenaeans' capital. Golden treasure, including the 'Mask of Agamemnon', was found here.</p>]]><p><b>Olympia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dedicated to the father of the gods, Olympian Zeus, Olympia is the birthplace of the Olympic Games, which were first held here in 776 BC. Situated on the Peloponnese, the site boasts many ancient buildings, including the Heraeum, the Stadium and the Hippodrome where ancient horse races were held. There was also a Palaestra, or wrestling school, and a Gymnasium where competitors were obliged to train for at least a month. Today, visitors to Olympia come to see the Temple of Zeus, which once contained a gold and ivory statue of Zeus, and the nearby Archaeological Museum, which contains many artefacts from Olympia, including a collection of marble statues and bronzes. It is a UNESCO world heritage site.</p>]]><p><b>Rhodes’ Old Town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rhodes' medieval old town is a UNESCO world heritage site - explore the car-free cobbled back alleys after dark for a truly unforgettable medieval experience. The Order of St John of Jerusalem occupied the city from 1309 to 1522, and bequeathed it with the 4km-long city walls, the Palace of the Grand Masters and the Street of the Knights. It subsequently fell to the Ottoman Turks – their traces include Islamic architecture such as the Mosque of Soliman and the Great Hamam.</p>]]><p><b>Sailing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its endless blue seas and countless islands, Greece is a sailor's paradise. The majority of charter companies are based in Athens – from here a one-week sailing trip might take you to the islands of Aegina and car-free Hydra, while a two-week tour could include Mykonos and the southernmost of the Cyclades, Santorini. Alternatively, set sail from bases on Corfu or Lefkada to explore the turquoise waters of the Ionian.</p>]]><p><b>Samaria Gorge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the flowers bloom at Samaria Gorge on Crete. A visual treat at any time of year, but a veritable explosion of colour during spring whether hiking through it or admiring from afar.</p>]]><p><b>Watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The shallow, fast-flowing rivers of mainland Greece offer excellent facilities for water-based adventure sports such as rafting, kayaking and canoeing. Sea-kayaking and scuba diving are also becoming popular on the islands. Greece has numerous thermal springs, spas and hydrotherapy centres to help sooth any aches and pains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$312 billion (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food and beverages, manufactured goods, petroleum, chemicals and textiles.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, transport equipment, fuels and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Italy, Cyprus, Bulgaria, UK, Russia, China and France.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While agricultural accession to the EU brought new focus to the Greek economy, particularly industrial sectors, in 2009 the Greek economy went into recession, contracting by 2%. Although Greece's financial struggles can be explained in part by the conditions that have affected the rest of the world, there are other factors that have contributed which are particular to the country.</p>
<p>The failure to address a growing budget deficit, falling state revenues and increased government expenditure have meant that Greece required the biggest bailout in recent history from the EU and IMF. The financial assistance has come with conditions and the new austerity measures, including dramatic cuts in public spending and increased taxes which have seen protests in the streets of Athens and anger amongst the country&rsquo;s unions. The ratings agency S&amp;A has already downgraded Greek debt, meaning Greece is now a viewed as highly risky place to invest. Unemployment in stood at 17% in May 2011 and was expected to increase. Inflation stood at 2.4% in July 2011. Further austerity measures imposed in 2011 included a massive privatisation scheme and the talk of possible default should Greece fail to appease its creditors.</p>
<p>Regardless of Greece's current financial situation, since the 1980s tourism has played an increasingly important part in the economy and it now accounts for 16% the country's GDP.</p>
<p>Greece has many convention centres and hotels with conference facilities. It also has ships equipped for 'floating conferences', sailing between the islands. For further enquiries, contact the Greek National Tourism Organisation (see Important Addresses).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most Greek companies close completely through August for their annual summer holidays. Punctuality is expected for meetings, although a Greek host may keep a business visitor waiting for a short time. French, German and English are often spoken as well as Greek. It is usual to shake hands to greet a business contact but embracing and kissing colleagues is not uncommon, although not upon first acquaintance. Business cards are exchanged after introductions have been made. Business attire is relatively formal; men and women are expected to wear suits and men should also wear ties. More casual wear is sometimes acceptable during the summer but local businesspeople tend to dress conservatively.</p>
<p>Hospitality is an important part of Greek culture and visiting businesspeople may well be taken to lunch. Greeks do not drink excessively but they will appreciate it if foreigners show enthusiasm to sample Greek wines and spirits. Almost everyone smokes, so visitors should not be surprised by endless offers of cigarettes. Gifts from abroad are well received but not expected, unless a visitor is invited to a colleague's home, in which case a gift of wine, sweets or flowers is usual.</p>
<p>In Athens, the working day is fairly flexible. In general, offices are open Monday to Friday 0830-1630, although shops and banks may have different hours (smaller organisations still close for a siesta in the afternoon during summer).</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Athens Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (ACCI)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 106 71 ,210 360 4815
					Website:http://www.acci.gr/
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Eating out is national pastime in Greece. For an informal snack, try an ouzeri, where you can join locals for small platters of savoury appetisers and a glass or two of aniseed-flavoured ouzo. Visit a <em>mezedopolio</em> to feast on a selection of tasty mezes (similar to Spanish tapas) which you might accompany with a flask of <em>rakija</em> (a potent spirit made from distilled grapes) or a carafe of <em>hima</em> (barrel wine).</p>
<p>For a more hearty meal, try a <em>taverna</em>, serving generous portions of traditional Greek favourites, often in a rustic (or pseudo-rustic) setting &ndash; the best ones have open log fires and stage occasionally live music. A <em>psarotaverna </em>is a taverna that specialises in fish and seafood. Last but not least, an <em>estiatorio</em> is a full blown restaurant, where service will be a little more formal and the menu will probably include a choice of both Greek and international cuisine, as well as quality bottled wines.</p>
<p>Greek food tends to be very simple, rarely involving sauces but with full use of local seasonal produce, olive oil and charcoal grills &ndash; just as people have been eating in outlying villages for many centuries. However, Athens and some of the more fashionable islands such as Santorini and Mykonos have seen the arrival of fusion cuisine and so-called modern taverna fare (involving lighter dishes with more subtle flavours and artistic presentation).</p>
<p>Restaurant hours are normally 1200-1500 for lunch and 2000-2400 for dinner. Opening hours vary according to the region and local laws &ndash; many establishments in popular holiday destinations stay open all day through the summer. Waiter service is usual.</p>
<p>Those with a sweet tooth should head for a <em>zaharoplasteio</em> (cake shop), where a vast array of syrup-drenched Turkish-inspired goodies such as baklava and slices of chocolate-coated cakes like Black Forest gateaux are displayed behind glass counters. You can choose pieces individually and then have them put in a box to take away &ndash; if it&rsquo;s a gift they&rsquo;ll tie it with a brightly coloured silk ribbon.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Dolmades (stuffed vine leaves).<br />
&bull; <em>Gemista</em> (tomatoes, peppers and courgettes, stuffed with rice and oven-baked).<br />
&bull; <em>Gigantes</em> (big butter beans baked in a rich tomato sauce with olive oil).<br />
&bull; Moussaka (aubergine casserole with minced lamb, cinnamon, red wine and olive oil). <br />
&bull; Calamari (deep-fried rings of squid) or htapodia (octopus). <br />
&bull; Souvlaki (spit-roasted meat, generally pork or chicken). <br />
&bull; Stifado (a rich beef stew with caramelised onions, cinnamon and cloves).<br />
&bull; <em>Kokkinisto</em> (a rich stew of either beef, pork or chicken cooked with red wine and tomatoes).<br />
&bull; <em>Horiatiki</em> (Greek salad: feta cheese, tomato, cucumber, green peppers, black Kalamata olives and fresh olive oil).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>12 to 15% is usual.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>16.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greece's nightlife is centred in main towns and resorts with late-night bars, dance clubs and live concerts. Athens' nightlife is among the best in Europe, with many local tavernas, particularly in the Plaka area, and <em>ouzeris</em> (typical Greek bars), plus a plethora of trendy bars and small clubs in the fashionable night-time districts of Psirri and Gazi playing international music.</p>
<p>In summer, many of Athens&rsquo; big clubs move out of the centre to the beaches at Voula, Vouliagmeni and Varkiza, for big open-air cocktail bars, DJ-music and endless sea views. Nightclubs featuring live Greek <em>bouzouki</em> music are also extremely popular in both Athens and Thessaloniki &ndash; think glitzy clientele throwing carnations and dancing on the tables.</p>
<p>Through summer, the Cycladic islands of Mykonos and Santorini are also noted for their exceptionally glamorous and up-market nightlife, while Corfu, Zakynthos (Zante), Rhodes and Ios attract youngsters in search of cheap alcohol and all-night discos. Couples in search of a romantic escape would do better to head for lesser known islands such as Milos, Folegandros, Patmos or Ithaca.</p>
<p>Greece has some casinos, such as the Mount Parnes Casino in Athens, the Casino Achilleon in Corfu and the Casino Rodos at the Grande Albergo delle Rose in Rhodes. For more highbrow entertainment, regular classical music concerts and international theatrical performances are held at the stunning open air second-century AD Odeon of Herodes Atticus in Athens during the Hellenic Festival (Jun-Sep).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases include lace, jewellery, metalwork, pottery, knitwear, rugs, leather goods, local wines and spirits, olive oil and objects made from olive tree wood. Athens is the centre for luxury goods, and local handicrafts and international brand names and high street stores. The Sunday morning flea market in Monastiraki, below the Acropolis, is crowded in high season. Athens' Central Market, a series of halls lined with colourful stalls plying fresh seafood, meat, fruit and vegetables, is also well worth a look in. Regional specialities include silver from Ioannina; ceramics from Sifnos and Skopelos; embroidery and lace from Crete, the Ionian Islands, Rhodes and Skiros; alabaster from Crete; furs from Kastoria; and flokati rugs from the Epirus region. Other popular buys include olive oil based eco-friendly toiletries (soaps, shampoos, face creams etc), and mastiha products (cosmetics made from mastic resin, produced on the island of Chios).</p><p>These vary according to the season, location and type of shop, but a rough guide follows: Mon, Wed, and Sat 0900-1430; Tues, Thurs and Fri 0900-1430 and 1730-2030. Most holiday resort shops stay open until late in the evening. In Athens, several big new shopping malls in the suburbs are open Mon-Fri 1000-2100, Sat 0900-2000.</p><p>(a) Visitors should be aware that many 'antiques' sold to tourists are fake; information on exporting antiques can be found at <a target="_blank" href="http://www.law-archaeology.gr">www.law-archaeology.gr</a> (b) Non-EU citizens can get a refund on Greek VAT (which stands at 23%) on purchases worth more than &euro;120; the process is fairly complex, but well worth it. Ask store owners and tourist information offices for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Greece can vary greatly both among the islands and on the mainland, from luxury and chain hotels, to chic boutique hotels with personalised service, and those aimed at the package market complete with outdoor pools and meals all-inclusive. Booking for the high season (Jul-Aug) is essential. The highest concentrations of 4-star and 5-star hotels are to be found in Athens and on the islands of Santorini, Mykonos, Rhodes and Crete. Hotels are graded using the international star system, though visitors should note that standards are not always the same from one country to the next. Beware also that hotel rooms (and bathrooms) in Europe tend to be smaller than those in the US. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The equivalent of a B&amp;B, a Greek pension offers basic accommodation with breakfast but no restaurant as such. They are usually family-run and purpose-built, and found mainly on the coast and islands, offering a cheaper alternative to a <em>xenodoheio</em> (hotel).</p>
<p>Likewise, a <em>xenona</em> is a guesthouse, set in an old traditional mansion or villa furnished with antiques and rugs. They are more atmospheric and found mainly in the mountains, and may have extras such as log fires in the bedrooms, and occasionally their own restaurants. They tend to be popular with wealthy Athenians during the winter weekends and over the Christmas and New Year holiday period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Greece can vary greatly both among the islands and on the mainland, from luxury and chain hotels, to chic boutique hotels with personalised service, and those aimed at the package market complete with outdoor pools and meals all-inclusive. Booking for the high season (Jul-Aug) is essential. The highest concentrations of 4-star and 5-star hotels are to be found in Athens and on the islands of Santorini, Mykonos, Rhodes and Crete. Hotels are graded using the international star system, though visitors should note that standards are not always the same from one country to the next. Beware also that hotel rooms (and bathrooms) in Europe tend to be smaller than those in the US. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Greece can vary greatly both among the islands and on the mainland, from luxury and chain hotels, to chic boutique hotels with personalised service, and those aimed at the package market complete with outdoor pools and meals all-inclusive. Booking for the high season (Jul-Aug) is essential. The highest concentrations of 4-star and 5-star hotels are to be found in Athens and on the islands of Santorini, Mykonos, Rhodes and Crete. Hotels are graded using the international star system, though visitors should note that standards are not always the same from one country to the next. Beware also that hotel rooms (and bathrooms) in Europe tend to be smaller than those in the US. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Members of the European Economic Area (EEA) and Switzerland are entitled to free emergency medical treatment providing they have a European Health Insurance Card (EHIC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visitors from outside the EU are strongly advised to take out travel medical insurance before visiting Greece. Respective consulates and Athens-based embassies can help visitors find hospitals and doctors in Greece, should the need arise. Note that most Greek doctors speak basic English. If you plan to do any &amp;lsquo;extreme&amp;rsquo; sports, such as scuba diving whilst on holiday, you should also look into extra insurance cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For minor problems, it may be sufficient to visit a pharmacy &amp;ndash; pharmacists in Greece are highly qualified and can offer advice and medication for mild conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emergency care, in the case of accidents, is provided free of charge to all nationalities at public hospitals. However, be aware that there is a certain degree of corruption within the Greek healthcare system. Even in public hospitals, doctors often expect under-the-table payments from patients in return for priority treatment, and sometimes receive kickbacks for referring patients to private institutions. Public hospitals are frequently understaffed, so it is not unusual for family members to bring patients meals from home and sometimes even stay overnight to help with basic nursing care. Private hospitals usually require the proof of adequate insurance or cash before admitting foreign patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the Greek health care system is heavily concentrated in Athens (and to a lesser extent Thessaloniki), so that people from the islands and rural areas usually have to visit to the capital to see consultants and receive treatment for more serious ailments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For emergencies, ring 166 (public ambulance).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is drinkable in Athens and other cities &amp;ndash; in fact, in areas where the local water is good, bars and restaurants are obliged by law to provide customers with glasses or jugs of tap water free of charge upon request. So don&amp;rsquo;t be ashamed to ask. However, visitors should be wary of drinking tap water in remote areas, and on many islands &amp;ndash; even if the locals do it. Bottled water is widely available and prices are strictly controlled on the mainland and islands. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Visitors to forested areas should consider getting the vaccination for tick-borne encephalitis three months before their date of travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mosquito-borne illness West Nile fever occurs occasionally. Travellers are advised to protect themselves from mosquito bites.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Independence Day :
							25 March </p><p>Orthodox Good Friday :
							06 April </p><p>Orthodox Easter Monday :
							09 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Orthodox Whit Monday :
							28 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Ochi Day :
							28 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 200 cigars or 400 cigarillos or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits (over 22%), 20L of spirits (under 22%), 90L of wine and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you're arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Greece by travellers over 17 years of age:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 100 cigarillos or 250g of tobacco (if arriving by air).<br />
&bull; 40 cigarettes or 20 cigarillos or 10 cigars or 50g of tobacco (if arriving by other means).<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of spirits up to 22% volume.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine.<br />
&bull; 16 L of beer.<br />
&bull; Gifts up to a value of &euro;430 if arriving by sea or air or &euro;300 if arriving by other means (reduced to &euro;150 for children under 15).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The import of soil (as well as plants) and certain animals is restricted. The import of meat, meat products, milk and milk products from outside the EU is also restricted. Firearms, explosive and drugs are very tightly controlled.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The export of antiquities is prohibited without the express permission of the Archaeological Service in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/athens">Athens</a>; those who ignore this will be prosecuted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol €) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of €500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of €2, 1 and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency can be exchanged at all banks, savings banks and bureaux de change. Exchange rates can fluctuate from one bank to another.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard, Visa and other major credit cards are widely accepted (although less so in petrol stations).</p><p>ATM's are widely available in all cities and towns, on the mainland and the islands. They are generally reliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major currencies are widely accepted and can be exchanged easily at banks. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros, Pounds Sterling or US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1430, Fri 0800-1400. Banks on the larger islands tend to stay open in the afternoon and some during the evening to offer currency exchange facilities during the tourist season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Australian, Canadian, US and EU passport holders do not require transit visas. Other nationals should check with the consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greece is a signatory to the 1995 Schengen Agreement.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The cost for a Schengen Visa type A, C (Airport Transit visa, Short Stay visa) is &euro;60.</p>
<p>The cost for a Schengen Visa type D (long-stay) is &euro;90 for students and &euro;180 for others.</p>
<p>For Russians, the cost is &euro;35.</p>
<p>For citizens from Albania, Bosnia-Herzegovina, FYROM, Georgia, Moldova, Montenegro, Serbia and Ukraine who do not have a biometric passport, the cost is &euro;35.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consular section of their nearest Greek Embassy. In the UK, nationals requiring a visa can apply via the Greece Visa Application Centre (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/greece/unitedkingdom">www.vfsglobal.com/greece/unitedkingdom</a>); an additional service charge of &pound;16.80 applies. All visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you're an EU national and are staying more than 90 days, you have to apply in person to the Aliens Department office (in Athens) or at your nearest police station (in districts outside Athens) for a Registration Certificate (<em>Veveoisi Engrafis</em>), which is valid indefinitely. To obtain this, you need to show the passport you used when entering the country and provide a statement from your employer (if you're here for work), or a marriage or birth certificate (if you're here because of family ties).</p>
<p>If you're from the USA, you can apply for a temporary residence permit, valid from three to six months. These are issued by your local Aliens police office, but only if you can show evidence that you have a compelling reason to prolong your stay in Greece.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing time is usually five to 14 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Australian, Canadian, US and EU passport holders do not need to prove access to funds when entering Greece for tourism.</p>
<p>Schengen visa applicants do need to prove sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa holders can only extend their visas in exceptional circumstances, such as <em>force majeure</em> or for humanitarian reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets travelling to Greece from other EU countries need a microchip for identification, an EU pet passport, and stamp to prove they have been vaccinated against rabies (within between four weeks and one year of date of entry into Greece). Pets arriving from outside the EU need a health certificate completed by a vet in either Greek or English.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[38.300986]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[23.741034]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>131,957 sq km (50,949 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>10,919,459 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>81.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Athens.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greece is situated in southeast Europe, bordering Albania, Macedonia and Bulgaria to the north, Turkey to the east and the Mediterranean Sea to the south and west.</p>
<p>The mainland consists of the following regions: Central Greece, Peloponnese, Thessaly, Epirus, Macedonia (which, incidentally, borders the country Republic of Macedonia, also known as the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia or FYR Macedonia) and Thrace. High mountains, fertile plains, pine forest and scrub-covered foothills are all found on the Greek mainland.</p>
<p>The largest mountain range is the Pindus, which runs north-south through central mainland Greece, and separates the regions of Thessaly and Epirus. The highest mountain is Olympus, which soars 2,917m (9,570ft) - according to Ancient Greek mythology, this is where the 12 Olympian Gods resided.</p>
<p>The islands account for one-fifth of the country's land area. The majority are thickly clustered in the Aegean between the Greek and Turkish coasts. The Ionian Islands are the exception; they are scattered along the west coast in the Ionian Sea, looking (both geographically and culturally) towards Italy.</p>
<p>The Aegean archipelago includes the Dodecanese, lying off the Turkish coast, of which Rhodes is the best known; the northeast Aegean group, including Chios, Ikaria, Lemnos, Lesvos and Samos; the Sporades, off the central mainland; and the Cyclades, comprising 39 islands (of which only 24 are inhabited). Crete, the largest island (with an astounding 1,000km/621miles of coastline and a population of some 650,000), is not included in any formal grouping.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>98% Greek Orthodox, with Muslim, Roman Catholic and Jewish minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greeks are very aware of their strong historical and cultural heritage. Traditions and customs differ throughout Greece, but overall a strong sense of unity prevails. The Greek Orthodox Church has a strong traditional influence on the Greek way of life, especially in more rural areas. The throwing back of the head is a negative gesture. Dress is generally casual. Smoking is prohibited on public transport and in public buildings.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Prokopis Pavlopoulos since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greece is often referred to as the birthplace of European civilisation. The period from 700BC saw the rise of the great city states of Athens, Corinth and Sparta, frequently engaged in long struggles for supremacy, and uniting only when faced with the common threat of invasion by the Persian Empire. The zenith was reached in the fifth century BC when Athens became the cultural and artistic centre of the Mediterranean, producing magnificent works of architecture, sculpture, drama and literature – 2500 years later, you can still see the splendid Parthenon crowning the Acropolis rock in the city centre, the classical marble sculptures on display in the National Archaeological Museum, and even the ancient tragedies written by Euridipes and performed in the Odeon of Herodes Atticus during the Athens Summer Festival.</p><p>Athens lost her empire through a mutually destructive struggle with Sparta. The nation was then forcibly united under Alexander the Great and after defeating the sagging military might of Persia in a number of major battles, the expansion of the empire spread Greek influence through the East as far as India and Egypt. The empire fragmented after Alexander's death in 323 BC, and the fall of Greek hegemony was completed when the country came under the sway of Rome. Long periods under the yoke of the Byzantine and then the Ottoman empires followed until a bitter war of independence lead to a free state being declared in 1829. In 1833, the unpopular Bavarian-born King Otto was installed and Greece became a monarchy, ruled by a predominantly Danish royal family, until 1973.</p><p>After liberation from the Germans at end of World War 2, Greece descended into civil war, with pro-Communists fighting right-wing monarchists, until in 1949, Communism was outlawed. From 1967 to 1974, Greece endured the rule of an oppressive right-wing junta before a new constitution was enacted and returned the country to parliamentary rule.</p><p>Since 2009 Greek politics have been dominated by the debt crisis, which has seen off a succession of coalition governments until the left-wing Syriza party swept to victory in January 2015 and was returned again with a diminished majority in a second election later in the year. It continues to govern in coalition with independent parties.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>&bull; Greece is the birthplace of the Olympics Games, first recorded in 776BC at Olympia. It also hosted the inaugural modern Summer Olympics in 1896 and again in 2004.</p><p>&bull; The principal gods of Ancient Greek mythology were the 12 Dodekatheon who lived on Mount Olympus ruled over by Zeus.</p><p>&bull; The Greek merchant navy is the largest in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Greece in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7229 3850 (visa section) or 09065 540 744 (24-hour visa information line)</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.greekembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7229 3850 (visa section) or 09065 540 744 (24-hour visa information line)</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1A Holland Park<br/>London<br/>W11 3TP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Greece in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 939 1300/6 (consular section). </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mfa.gr/washington</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 939 1300/6 (consular section). </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Opening hours: Mon and Thurs 0930-1300, 1400-1600; Tues, Wed and Fri 0930-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2217 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Greece]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(210) 7272 600.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukingreece.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(210) 7272 600.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri, 0830-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1 Ploutarchou Street<br/>106 75 Athens<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A flavourful melting pot of sparkling nightspots, fresh seafood, sizzling Mediterranean passion and mythical legend, Greece is a fascinating and enchanting destination.</p>
<p>The country has long held appeal for travellers, who decamp to its shores to lounge on beaches, explore ancient relics and take advantage of the legendary Grecian hospitality.</p>
<p>Yet despite its popularity, there is still an undiscovered feel to parts of Greece with Mount Olympus, the Peloponnese coast and some of the more remote islands slipping, for now at least, under the radar of mass tourism.</p>
<p>The first port of call for most visitors is Athens, the country&rsquo;s stunning capital, which combines a modern centre with the stark ancient beauty of the Parthenon and a position overlooking a cerulean stretch of the Saronic Gulf.</p>
<p>Like the rest of the country, Athens was built on a classical civilisation that produced some of the world&rsquo;s greatest thinkers, philosophers and poets.&nbsp;The ancient Greeks also brought the world democracy, which locals cheerfully remind visitors about, and a pantheon of deities, who are celebrated through statues and local folklore.</p>
<p>Everywhere has its own legend; from the tiny island of Ithaca, home to the wanderer Odysseus, to the rugged stretch of the Peloponnese, the onetime playground of divine beings.</p>
<p>While modern Greeks might not be hitting the intellectual heights of Pericles, the country remains one of Europe&rsquo;s leading holiday destinations, thanks largely to its gorgeous collection of islands, which are scattered like confetti across the Mediterranean Sea.</p>
<p>Greece boasts 1,400 islands in all, amongst them Rhodes, which was home to the ancient Minoan culture and, legend has it, the terrifying Minotaur. Today it is better known for its stunning beaches, charming seaside towns and lively nightlife.</p>
<p>The islands of Corfu, Crete and Santorini are also established hangouts for sun-seekers and merrymakers, while Kos has begun to attract deities of a very modern kind &ndash; the world&rsquo;s rich and famous. Ultimately, though, in democratic Greece, everyone is welcome.</p><p>A flavourful melting pot of sparkling nightspots, fresh seafood, sizzling Mediterranean passion and mythical legend, Greece is a fascinating and enchanting destination.&nbsp;The country has long held appeal for travellers, who decamp to its shores to lounge on beaches, explore ancient relics and take advantage of the legendary Grecian hospitality.&nbsp;Yet despite its popularity, there is still an undiscovered feel to parts of Greece with Mount Olympus, the Peloponnese coast and some of the more remote islands slipping under the radar of mass tourism.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
