<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Greenland" ColCode="grl" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="gl" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Greenland]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greenland has an Arctic climate, but owing to the size of the country there are great variations in the weather. As the climate graph shows, winters can be severe and the summers comparatively mild, particularly in areas which are sheltered from the prevailing winds. Precipitation, mostly snow, is moderately heavy around the coast. The north of the country, and much of the interior, enjoys true Arctic weather, with the temperature only rising above freezing for brief periods in the summer.<br /><br />Conditions in all parts of the country can become hazardous when there is a combination of a low temperature and a strong wind. Local advice concerning weather conditions should be followed very carefully. Nevertheless, the summer months are suitable for a wide range of outdoor activities.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good-quality windproof and waterproof clothes, warm layers and moulded sole shoes at all times of the year; also some slightly thinner clothes - it is important to be able to change clothing during a day's climbing as temperatures can vary greatly during one day. Sunglasses and protective sun lotion are strongly advised. In July and August, mosquitoes can be a problem, especially inside the fjords and so a mosquito net can prove indispensable. Extra warm clothes are necessary for those contemplating dog-sledge expeditions. Extra clothes are not always available for hire in Greenland.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Greenland (<a href="http://www.airgreenland.com" target="_blank">www.airgreenland.com</a>) serves all towns on the west coast, from Nanortalik in the south to Thule/Qaanaq in the north. The frequency of departure on all routes is variable, and it's advisable to make reservations well in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is generally cheaper to sail than to fly. Arctic Umiaq Line (tel: +299 349 190; <a href="http://www.aul.gl" target="_blank">www.aul.gl</a>) operates services along the west coast between Qaqortoq and Ilulissat. In addition, all villages are served by local boats connecting them with the nearest town, but space may be limited. Boats in some towns may be available for hire, with a skipper.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dog sledges:</strong> These can be hired for the day, or for longer periods. Sledging is possible in all towns on the east coast and on the west coast north of the polar circle. It is important to remember that sledge dogs are usually only semi-tame. This is just one reason why dog sledges should be given right of way at all times. Take particular care, as they are almost totally silent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Greenland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">south_greenland</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Greenland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">east_greenland</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Greenland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">disko_bay</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Air Greenland (<a href="http://www.airgreenland.gl/" target="_blank">www.airgreenland.gl</a>). The only direct flights to Greenland are either from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/copenhagen">Copenhagen</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/denmark">Denmark</a>, or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/reykjavik">Reykjavik</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iceland">Iceland</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> The Arctic weather conditions in Greenland may cause delays and interruptions in transport services or changes to planned itineraries. Visitors are advised to leave enough time for possible disruptions to flights and check with their airline or tour operator before flying.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 15 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Nerlerit Inaat Airport </b><b>Tel: </b><b>Nuuk Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Kulusuk Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Kangerlussuaq (Søndre Strømfjord)</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Pituffik Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Narsarsuaq Airport</b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes. There are no telephone boxes in Greenland, but calls can be made from hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handsets can be hired at <em>TELE Greenland</em> shops (in all cities). A deposit is required. Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is limited to main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet cafes in many towns. Access is available in some public libraries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greenland produces its own stamps which are popular among collectors. Post from Greenland takes about four to five days to reach Europe.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the architecture of Qaqortoq</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The largest town in South Greenland is home to a small Inuit Museum, which includes an exact copy of a turf house. The town square is surrounded by some of the most well-preserved buildings of the colonial era, dating back 200 years. Examples of a unique art project called Stone and People, where sculptures are carved into granite, can also be found throughout the town.</p>]]><p><b>Befriend the locals in Nuuk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An ever-popular destination for visitors, Nuuk ranks as one of the world's smallest capitals. With a population of about 15,000, the "city" was founded in 1728 by Norwegian missionary Hans Egede as the very first town of Greenland. Its colourful, wooden houses are overlooked by the snow-capped Sermitsiaq Mountain, which provides a beautiful backdrop to the town.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the world's largest national park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Northeast Greenland National Park has bragging rights to being the world's largest and most northerly national park. Nearly four times the size of the United Kingdom, the park is home musk oxen, polar bears, walruses and myriad other species. The area is ideal for expedition trips in kayaks or on dog sledges. Permits are required to enter the park.</p>]]><p><b>Don your hiking boots</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hiking is one of Greenland's big draws. The tourist board has published colour-coded hiking maps and guides for Qaqortoq, Narsaq and Narsarsuaq in South Greenland and Ammassalik in the east. The scenery is unremittingly beautiful and accommodation comes in the form of mountain huts, which are available in the Narsaq and Qaqortoq peninsulas, as well as Vatnahverfi.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the macabre Greenland National Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Nuuk's major attractions, this morbid museum is home to the mummified remains of a group of women and children, who were thought to have died in about 1475 when their boat capsized. The museum is in the oldest part of the city where buildings date back to 1728.</p>]]><p><b>Go whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many different species of whale can be found along Greenland's coasts. Try the area around Qeqertarsuaq, Aasiaat and Qasigiannguit, where, with a bit of luck, you might spot gigantic fin whales. Depending on the season, you may also get to see minke, beluga and humpback whales.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the icebergs of Disko Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>North Greenland, and in particular the area around Disko Bay, is one of the most popular destinations for travellers. That's thanks largely to the magnificent icebergs, which, during the summertime, glisten in the midnight sun.</p>]]><p><b>Scale the heights of Nanortalik</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Greenland's southernmost town, Nanortalik, is surrounded by the so-called Nanortalik Skyscrapers; the steep peaks and sheer mountain faces that rise from shimmering fjords. The area is a paradise for climbers and hikers but Ketil Mountain and Ulamertorsuaq should only be attempted by experienced hands. If you've not a head for heights, then the fishing and kayaking is also good here.</p>]]><p><b>See the sights on a snowmobile</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A vehicle for recreation and leisure, snowmobiles are ubiquitous in Greenland, and renting one is a great way to discover the country's beautiful scenery in winter. Not a cheap leisure activity, but one that's guaranteed to give you a huge adrenaline buzz.</p>]]><p><b>Soak up the scenery in Ilulissat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ilulissat (meaning "iceberg") is the gateway to Disko Bay and the whole of northern Greenland. Ilulissat boasts many modern as well as traditional buildings surrounded by breath-taking scenery. The explorer Knud Rasmussen was born here in 1879 and the house where he grew up has been transformed into the interesting Knud Rasmussen Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Take a dog sled ride</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Inuit have been living with their dogs and using their sledges for thousands of years, and taking a dog-sled trip will give you an insight into their culture. This is a popular activity in Eastern Greenland and north of the Arctic Circle, with tours available for all levels and durations. Best months for this are from February to April.</p>]]><p><b>Travel back to the Viking Age</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Narsarsuaq and Qassiarsuk in southern Greenland are situated in the area first settled by the Viking Eric the Red 1,000 years ago. Many ruins from this epoch still survive and these Viking vestiges are popular with history buffs and hikers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$1.7 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fish and fish products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transport equipment, manufactured goods, food and petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, Denmark, Japan, Norway and Sweden.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greenland withdrew from the European Community (now the European Union) in February 1985 over the issue of the fisheries policy. EU member states are allowed to fish within Greenland's maritime exclusion zone in exchange for an annual cash payment; this compensates, in part, for the loss of development aid which Greenland would otherwise have received. It also enjoys preferential access to EU markets.<br /><br />Although there are plans to develop the island's mineral deposits of iron ore, uranium, zinc, lead and coal, the economy ultimately depends on large subsidies from the Danish central government. The KNI (Royal Greenland Trade Department) organises transport, supplies and production in the country.<br /><br />In November 2008, Greenland voted to become a separate country within the Kingdom of Denmark (Self-Rule Act). A new era of self-rule came into effect in June 2009. The self-rule agreement gives Greenlanders the right to self-determination and more control over its natural reserves, as well as making Greenlandic the official language.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits should be worn. A knowledge of Danish is extremely useful.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700 or 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cultural Conference Centre in Katuaq</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: +299 32 33 00.
					Website:http://www.katuaq.gl
					Address: ,,Nuuk,PO Box 1622]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels have restaurants of a good standard, where Danish food and Greenland specialities are served. Prices are similar to Denmark.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; Reindeer meat (caribou). <br />&bull; Whale meat.<br />&bull; Musk ox.<br />&bull; Fowl. <br />&bull; Shrimps and fish.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Service charge is usually added to the bill. Tips are not expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pubs are open to people over the age of 18 and some have discos or live bands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol, tobacco, fruit and vegetables are expensive. Special purchases include bone and soapstone carvings, skin products and beadwork. &quot;The Board&quot; is the local term for <em>Kalaaliavaq</em>, the markets that can be found in all Greenlandic towns. Here you can buy the day's harvest such as seal, whale, musk, reindeer, fish and berries straight from the hunter, fisherman or picker. They are usually situated close to the town's port.</p><p>Mon-Thurs 1000-1730, Fri 1000-1800 and Sat 0900-1300. Smaller grocery shops and kiosks may open for longer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are hotels in the major towns, but no public accommodation in Scoresby Sund, Thule or Upernavik. All reservations should be made in advance; contact Greenland Tourism <em>or</em> Greenland Tourism in Copenhagen (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>) for information.<br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> A star-grading system is in place. Hotels are classified by Greenland Tourism, and gradings are roughly equivalent to those in Denmark.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are hotels in the major towns, but no public accommodation in Scoresby Sund, Thule or Upernavik. All reservations should be made in advance; contact Greenland Tourism <em>or</em> Greenland Tourism in Copenhagen (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>) for information.<br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> A star-grading system is in place. Hotels are classified by Greenland Tourism, and gradings are roughly equivalent to those in Denmark.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are hotels in the major towns, but no public accommodation in Scoresby Sund, Thule or Upernavik. All reservations should be made in advance; contact Greenland Tourism <em>or</em> Greenland Tourism in Copenhagen (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>) for information.<br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> A star-grading system is in place. Hotels are classified by Greenland Tourism, and gradings are roughly equivalent to those in Denmark.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are hospitals and dentists in all towns. Although medical services are generally free, medical insurance is advisable, particularly as charges are made for dental treatment. Travellers are also advised to bring their own medicines and prescribed drugs, as these can often be difficult to obtain in Greenland.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p/><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B is endemic. Tuberculosis may occur. Extreme cold during the winter months is another potential risk to travellers. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Below are listed Public Holidays for the January 2014-December 2015 period.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Maundy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Great Prayer Day :
							27 April </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>National Day :
							21 June </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>New Year's Eve :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Greenland without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic beverages over 22% volume or 2L of fortified wine (up to 22% volume).<br />
&bull; 2.25L of table wine.<br />
&bull; 2L of beer.<br />
&bull; 2L of soft drinks.<br />
&bull; 50ml of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Cosmetics and toiletries up to a value of kr1,000.<br />
&bull; 4kg of coffee or tea.<br />
&bull; 4kg of chocolate or confectionery.<br />
&bull; 5kg of meat, meat products or poultry.</p>
<p>Alcohol allowances are for travellers aged over 18 only.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics, most live animals (other than guide dogs), and pistols or fully- or semi-automatic weapons. To bring a hunting rifle to Greenland, you need to obtain a permit from your airline, but hunting is only permitted on special hunting trips organised by a certified tour operator.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Products made of whale tooth.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Danish Krone (DKK; symbol kr) = 100 øre. Notes are in denominations of kr1,000, 500, 200, 100 and 50. Coins are in denominations of kr20, 10, 5, 2 and 1, and 50 and 25 øre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cheques drawn on Danish banks can be cashed at banks and cash can also be exchanged. Postal cheques can be cashed at all post offices. <em>Grønlandsbanken</em> (PO Box 1033, DK-3900 Nuuk; tel: 70 1234; <a href="http://www.banken.gl/" target="_blank">www.banken.gl</a>), has branches in Nuuk, Sisimiut, Oaqortoq, Ilulissat and Maniitsoq. <em>KNI/POST</em> represents the bank in other towns and villages. There is no banking service in Søndre Strømfjord at present.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are restricted to the major towns and most hotels. Some major towns, like Ilulissat, have ATMs.</p><p>Some major towns, like Ilulissat, have ATMs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cheques in major currencies may be exchanged as indicated in the currency exchange section above. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling or US Dollars. However, exchanging traveller's cheques in Greenland has been reported to be problematic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0930-1530; Fri 0930-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for&nbsp;at least three months beyond  the length of stay in Greenland is required by all nationals referred to in  the chart above, except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or valid national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although Denmark is a signatory to the 1995 Schengen Agreement, only Schengen visas issued specifically for travel to Greenland are valid (see above).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<div class="field-items">
<div class="field-item odd">
<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60/&pound;48 (&euro;35/&pound;28 for nationals of a few countries; check with the consulate).</p>
<p>A normal Schengen visa is not valid for travel to Greenland. Nationals requiring visas for Greenland must have a Schengen visa issued by a Danish mission with the wording 'Valid for Greenland' in the comments section on the visa.&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Danish Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<div class="field-items">
<div class="field-item odd">
<p>Applications for visas for Denmark should be completed in 15 days, but in some cases they may take 30 to 60 days.</p>
</div>
</div>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applicants for Schengen visas must prove sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[74.349976]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-41.090027]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,166,086 sq km (836,330 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>56,196 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>0.03 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nuuk (Godth&aring;b).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Self-governing part of the Kingdom of Denmark.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greenland is the world's biggest island. The surrounding seas are either permanently frozen or chilled by cold currents.</p>
<p>The inland area is covered with ice, stretching 2,500km (1,500 miles) north-south and 1,000km (600 miles) east-west. In the centre, the ice can be up to 3km (2 miles) thick.</p>
<p>The ice-free coastal region, which is sometimes as wide as 200km (120 miles), covers a total of 410,449 sq km (158,475 sq miles), and is where all of the population is to be found. This region is intersected by deep fjords which connect the inland ice area with the sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Evangelical Lutheran Church of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/denmark">Denmark</a> majority, with small groups of Roman Catholics and other Protestant denominations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Life is generally conducted at a more relaxed pace than is usual in northern Europe, as exemplified by the frequent use of the word <em>immaqa</em> - 'maybe'. Until recently, foreign visitors were very rare. The name of the country in Greenlandic is <em>Kalaallit Nunaat</em>, meaning 'Land of the People'.<br /><strong><br />Photography:</strong> Throughout the country there is a ban on taking photographs inside churches or church halls during services. A UV or skylight filter and a lens shade should always be used. In winter, the camera must be polar-oiled. It is advisable to bring your own film. Film cannot always be developed in Greenland.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used, sometimes with a third grounding pin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Kim Kielsen since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Margrethe II since 1972.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The first European settlements of Greenland were established on the west coast in the 10th-century. Responsibility is usually credited to Eric the Red, reputedly the son of a Norwegian chieftain banished from his home in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iceland">Iceland</a> for murder. The colonists accepted Norwegian sovereignty around 1260, which lasted until the marginal lifestyle of the settlements finally led to their collapse in the 16th-century. The territory was then unoccupied by Europeans until <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/denmark">Denmark</a> took possession of it during its own phase of colonial expansion in the early 18th century. It became an integral part of the Danish realm in 1953. A referendum in 1979 approved internal autonomy within the Kingdom of Denmark: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/copenhagen">Copenhagen</a> retains control of defence, foreign policy and constitutional matters. Subsequently, a new 21-member parliament was set up, since expanded to 31 seats. In 1982, in another referendum, the population voted by a narrow majority to leave the EC (as it then was) which they had joined as part of Denmark in 1972. Greenland is now an overseas territory in association with the EU, which provides certain trade privileges and access to EU aid. Another source of conflict between Greenland and Denmark has been the presence of a major American military radar installation at Thule in the north, which may be involved in a future <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> missile defence system. While most of the population would prefer it removed, the Danish Government says that it is bound by treaty obligations. The issue led to the collapse of Greenland's coalition Government in March 1987. This was an alliance of the social-democratic <I>Siumit</I> (Forward)  the political party which grew from the nationalist opposition movement to European membership back in the 1970s  and the leftist <I>Inuit Ataqatigiit </I>(IA, Inuit Brotherhood), which seeks full independence. These two, plus the conservative <I>Atassut</I> (Solidarity) party, are the main political parties. Coalition governments have controlled the Government for the last 20-odd years. These have been generally stable, but 2003 has proved to be an exception. The December 2002 election had returned Siumut as the largest party, forming a coalition Government with IA under the premiership of Siumut leader Hans Enoksen. However, the Government fell after a month under farcical circumstances, relating to the activities of a faith-healer apparently hired to purge Government offices of evil spirits. Siumut and Enoksen remained in power, with Attasut as its coalition partner, but this Government was also short-lived. It collapsed after eight months following a dispute over miscalculation of the territory's budget. The Inuit Brotherhood later rejoined Siumut in Government. With Siumut winning 10 of the 31 available seats in the November 2005 election, they will again need to form a coalition to remain in government.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Royal Danish Embassy in the USA ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234 4300. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://usa.um.dk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234 4300. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>3200 Whitehaven Street, NW<br/>Washington DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Royal Danish Embassy in the UK ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7333 0200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.denmark.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7333 0200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1630 and Fri 0900-1600; consular enquiries Mon-Fri 1500-1600 (telephone).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>55 Sloane Street<br/>London<br/>SW1X 9SR<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Remote Greenland is the world's biggest island, while the sea that surrounds it is either permanently frozen or chilled by the mainly cold currents. In the centre of the country, ice can be up to 3km (2 miles) thick. No wonder that most of the population huddles around the ice-free coastal region. Indeed, the name 'Greenland' is a bit of a misnomer, although there are sheep-laden green fields in the south.</p><p>Those wondering why anyone would want to inhabit such unforgiving terrain are ignoring the beautiful sights that Greenland grants. The arctic nights in the winter concoct a wondrous continuous twilight. In the far north of the country, complete darkness is coupled with the spectacular Northern Lights during the coldest months. While Greenland may not be top of many travellers' bucket lists, where else can you visit such raw and unspoilt landscapes?</p><p>The profusion of snow creates the perfect conditions for activities such as dog sledging and tour cruises, which interweave in and out of Greenland's dazzling array of fjords, mountains, islands and icebergs. You can even go kayaking in the waters, though best to play it safe. The wildlife does not disappoint, either: there is an abundance of whales, seals and birds in the area.</p><p>There are hardly any roads on the island, so expect to fork out for boat travel, or even helicopter journeys. The upshot is that glacial vistas, yawning fjords and soaring mountains are all there for the taking. Definitely bring a camera.</p><p>Although Greenland's appeal rests with its wondrous nature, there are a few thousand Greenlanders living on the sparsely populated island, and on the western coast they offer up a handful of picturesque villages. Mostly living in brightly painted wooden cottages, Greenlanders may have a reputation for being rather closed, but give them time and space, and you will discover a truly compelling culture, one that fuses both Inuit and Danish heritage.</p><p>With transport options and tourism agencies having improved travelling conditions of late, there's never been a better time to visit Greenland.</p>Remote Greenland is the world's biggest island, and the sea that surrounds it is either permanently frozen or chilled by the mainly cold currents.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
