<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Grenada" ColCode="grd" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="gd" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Grenada]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Grenada's climate is tropical. The dry season runs January-May, and the rainy season runs June-December. The average temperature is 28°C (82°F).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical lightweights and waterproofs, especially for the rainy season. Cool summer clothing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>SVG Air (<a href="http://www.grenada-flights.com" target="_blank">www.grenada-flights.com</a>) runs flights between Grenada and Carriacou.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Colourful motor boats operate a water-taxi service between Grand Anse Beac and St George's.</p>
<p>Osprey Lines (<a href="http://www.ospreylines.com" target="_blank">www.ospreylines.com</a>) runs a ferry service from from Grenada to Carriacou, Petite Martinique and back.</p>
<p>A large number of yachts and boats are available to charter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Grenada has a good road network.</p>l<p>Most main roads are in good condition but they are narrow and winding.</p><p>Taxis are the most efficient means of transport. They are available from the airport, the Carenage and most hotels. Mandoo's Tour &amp; Taxi Service (<a href="http://grenadatours.com" target="_blank">grenadatours.com</a>)&nbsp;is a fully insured sightseeing and taxi service.</p><p>To drive in Grenada, you have to obtain a Grenadian driving permit (for a fee) by presenting a valid national driving licence at the police station on the Carenage.</p><p>There's a choice of several car hire companies in Grenada. In July and August (high season), you have to book cars for a minimum of three days. You usually need to be at least 25 years old to hire a car.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local buses operate Monday to Saturday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Grenada</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">grenville</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Grenada</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">carriacou</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Airways<em>&nbsp;</em>(<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) flies to Grenada from the UK with a stop in St Lucia. You can also fly to Antigua and Barbuda with British Airways or Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) and take a connecting flight with LIAT (<a href="http://www.liat.com" target="_blank">www.liat.com</a>).&nbsp;American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com/" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>) flies direct from Miami and JetBlue (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>) has a direct flight from New York.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/grenada/point-salines-international-airport">Maurice Bishop International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours 45 minutes (including short stop in St Lucia); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 4 hours 45 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a> - 3 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Maurice Bishop International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.mbiagrenada.com<p>Maurice Bishop International Airport is situated 7km (4 miles) southwest of Grenada's capital, St George's.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 473 444 4555</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>St George's, considered the most picturesque port in the Caribbean, is a port of call for many cruise lines. More than half of tourist arrivals are cruise-ship passengers. There is a daily shuttle boat service to Carriacou and Petite Martinique; boats can be hired for access to Isle de Ronde. Check at a local tourist office for times and fares.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>No area codes are in use. Coin and telephone card payphones are available. Telephone cards can be purchased at the offices of <em>Cable & Wireless Grenada</em> and from other agents. International dialling is available from most hotel rooms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming is available to all mobile phones that are TDMA digital network compatible. Contact <em>Cable & Wireless</em> in Grenada for further details. Coverage is variable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet is widely available throughout Grenada; there are Internet cafes in St George's.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Grenada's media are free, as is stipulated in law. No daily newspapers exist, and weeklies are privately owned and freely criticise the government. All newspapers are in English. They include <em>Grenada Times</em>, <em>Grenada Today </em>and <em>The Grenadian Voice</em>.The Grenada Broadcasting Network, jointly owned by the Caribbean Communications Network and the government, runs Klassic Radio, SUN FM and GBN TV.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main post office is in St George's (on Lagoon Road).</p><p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1600, Fri 0800-1630 (closed weekends).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the exhibits at Carriacou Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A good first stop would be to discover Grenada's history at the Carriacou Museum in Hillsborough, where there's an impressive collection of Amerindian artefacts and mementoes dating back to 18th century when the islands were occupied by the French and British.</p>]]><p><b>Bask on the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its swaying palms and white sandy shores, Grand Anse is one of Grenada's best beaches. Levera Bay and Morne Rouge are also stunning, but to bask away from the crowds head to the deserted beaches on the southern coast. Like surfing? Then take your board to Levera Bay, which has fine swells.</p>]]><p><b>Bathe under the waterfalls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Grenada's most spectacular waterfalls are the 15m (50ft) Annandale Falls and Mount Carmel Waterfall, which cascades into clear pools below. You can swim in several of the islands' rainforest pools and lakes, many of which are formed by waterfalls, such as the Concord Falls.</p>]]><p><b>Dazzle your senses on a spice tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fill your nostrils with sweet aromas on Spice Island, which is home to Gouyave Nutmeg Processing Station, the largest nutmeg processing factory on the island. The nearby Dougaldston Estate also offers heady aromas and spice trivia on their tours. If you like what you smell, pick up some samples as you exit through the gifts hop.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a glass of Caribbean rum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Quaffing rum is a time-honoured tradition in the Caribbean, particularly on Grenada. Discover how rum is made on a guided tour of one of the island's main rum distilleries. At the Grenada Sugar Factory in St George, guided tours include a tasting and opportunity to purchase its rum products.</p>]]><p><b>Go for a very fun run</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Make sure you're on Grenada on a Saturday, to watch a fortnightly event known as hashing. Participants meet at a designated rum shop, run around the island following a trail of flour or paper, before returning to the rum shop to undo all the exercise.</p>]]><p><b>Have a reef encounter while diving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Grand Anse beach is the starting point for diving trips to nearby reefs and islands. One of the best dive sites is Molinière Reef, which is about 5km (3 miles) from St George's. Carriacou, in the Grenadines, also offers excellent diving. Keen snorkellers should head to White Island Marine Park and Martin's Bay, close to Grand Anse.</p>]]><p><b>Join in Carnival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>August is carnival time on Grenada and everyone is welcome to join in. It's a riot of colour and fun, with lively street parties, street theatre, steel bands and calypso competitions that all go on well into the early hours of the morning.</p>]]><p><b>Set sail for adventure</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Yacht races and regattas are held throughout the year on Grenada. The Sailing Festival in February is the biggest and attracts yachtsmen from all over the world. The sailing regatta in Tyrell Bay on Carriacou is also popular. The Grenadine islands are a popular sailing destination.</p>]]><p><b>Sign up for an ecology day out</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See Grenada's oyster beds, reached along a trail from Tyrrel Bay, followed by a short boat ride to the middle of one of the most pristine ecosystems in the region: La Sagesse Nature Reserve, which is a protected bird sanctuary with rivers, mangroves and salt lakes.</p>]]><p><b>Take a dip in the lucky springs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The River Sallee's boiling sulphur springs can be seen bubbling in a number of holes north of Lake Antoine, leaving orange and yellow hues on the surrounding landscape. They are of spiritual importance for various religious sects and a natural wishing well. Don't forget to throw in a coin before you leave.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hike in Grand Etang</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Grand Etang National Park and Forest Reserve contains numerous marked trails, with gentle half-hour walks or expeditions of several hours. The park contains a wealth of interesting flora and fauna, and there are spectacular flower displays depending on the season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$657 million (2008).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Nutmeg, bananas, cocoa, fruit and vegetables and mace.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, manufactured goods, machinery, chemicals and fuel.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Trinidad & Tobago, The Netherlands, Germany and UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Grenada relies on tourism as its main source of foreign exchange, especially after Hurricanes Ivan (2004) and Emily (2005) severely damaged the nutmeg industry, which was previously a key driver of economic growth. The agricultural sector, particularly nutmeg and cocoa cultivation, has recovered from the hurricanes, and the tourism sector has seen substantial increases in foreign direct investment.<br /><br />Strong performances in construction and manufacturing have contributed to growth in national output but economic growth is expected to slow in 2009 because of the global economic crisis. As a result of Hurricanes Ivan and Emily, Grenada is saddled with debt. Public debt-to-GDP is nearly 110%, leaving the government limited room for social spending. Unemployment stands at 12.5%.<br />There are 11 hotels offering meeting facilities, seating from 25 to 160 persons. For details, contact Grenada Board of Tourism (see <em>Contact Addresses).</em></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All correspondence and trade literature is in English.<br /></p><p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1500; Fri 0800-1700. Government offices are generally open Mon-Fri 0800-1600 but are closed 1200-1300 for lunch.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Grenada Chamber of Industry and Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 440 2937
					Website:http://www.grenadachamber.org
					Address: St George's,PO Box 129,Grenada,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels and restaurants offer international cuisine, serving a large variety of tropical fish and English, Continental, American and exotic West Indian food. Bars are stocked with the most popular wines and spirits, local beers and various brands of whisky, rum and brandy.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Seafood, such as crabs and <em>lambi</em> (conchs).<br />
&bull; <em>Calaloo</em> (a leafy vegetable similar to spinach) soup. <br />
&bull; <em>Oildown</em> is the national dish consisting of stew made with salted meat, breadfruit, onion, celery, carrot, <em>daheen</em> (a root vegetable grown locally) and dumplings all slowly steamed in coconut milk until the liquid is absorbed.<br />
&bull; Rotis are curry-spiced wraps made from pastry or bread and filled with beef, chicken, or vegetables.<br />
&bull; Nutmeg ice cream.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 10% service charge is added by most hotels and restaurants. If no charge is added, it is customary to leave a 10% tip. There is also an 8% government tax to pay at hotels and restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Home to the vibrant calypso and reggae music, Grenada offers a good mix of local and international restaurants and bars. Many resorts provide night-time entertainment, such as discos, organised shows and cabarets. The Reno Cinema in St George (tel: 440 5368) hosts many multicultural events as well as showing films. The Grenadian Jazz Society holds concerts several times a year in a number of hotels. Carnival takes place in towns across Grenada in the second week of August.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases include leather crafts, jewellery, spices, straw goods and batik (printed cotton and other fabrics). St George's market is the centre of island life. There are a number of duty-free shops selling quality goods from all over the world. A market near Grand Anse beach has scores of vendors selling crafts and spices.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600, Sat 0800-1300. Supermarkets are usually open Mon-Sat 0900-1900. Craft and souvenir shops will open Sundays and bank holidays especially if cruise ships are in port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many high-quality luxury resorts on the islands that offer wedding packages and will make all the necessary legal arrangements. These resorts offer excellent facilities for weddings, watersports, dining and excursions.<br />Grenada offers a variety of modern, luxurious hotels, graded from 1 to 5 stars. An 8% government tax is added to all hotel and restaurant bills, and a 10% service charge is added to the bill by many hotels and restaurants. Contact the Grenada Board of Tourism for details and exact price listings (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is bed and breakfast accommodation and several guest houses, some of which offer self-catering facilities. Guest houses are not graded.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many high-quality luxury resorts on the islands that offer wedding packages and will make all the necessary legal arrangements. These resorts offer excellent facilities for weddings, watersports, dining and excursions.<br />Grenada offers a variety of modern, luxurious hotels, graded from 1 to 5 stars. An 8% government tax is added to all hotel and restaurant bills, and a 10% service charge is added to the bill by many hotels and restaurants. Contact the Grenada Board of Tourism for details and exact price listings (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many high-quality luxury resorts on the islands that offer wedding packages and will make all the necessary legal arrangements. These resorts offer excellent facilities for weddings, watersports, dining and excursions.<br />Grenada offers a variety of modern, luxurious hotels, graded from 1 to 5 stars. An 8% government tax is added to all hotel and restaurant bills, and a 10% service charge is added to the bill by many hotels and restaurants. Contact the Grenada Board of Tourism for details and exact price listings (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There is a general hospital in St George's (tel: 440 2051) and small hospitals in Mirabeau and Carriacou. Health insurance is strongly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and relatively safe, but there is still some risk of diarrhoea, particularly in rural areas. Bottled water is available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Immunisation against hepatitis B is sometimes recommended. There is a high prevalence of HIV/AIDS. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Independence Day :
							07 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Emancipation Day :
							06 August </p><p>Carnival :
							13 August </p><p>Thanksgiving Day :
							25 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Grenada by travellers aged 18 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of wine or spirits.<br />
&bull; 300ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of EC$300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics, arms and ammunition (unless you obtain a police licence), fruit and vegetables.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics and unlicensed arms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>East Caribbean Dollar (XCD; symbol EC$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of EC$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of EC$1, and 50, 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.<br /><br /><strong>Note:</strong> The East Caribbean Dollar is tied to the US Dollar. The US Dollar is accepted everywhere, but change might be given in EC$.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Barclays Bank, Grenada Bank of Commerce, Grenada Co-operative Bank, National Commercial Bank and Scotia Bank are all found on the island. It is advised to exchange currency at banks to obtain the most favourable exchange rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, Mastercard and Visa and other major cards are accepted by most shops, car hire companies and hotels. ATMs are available, mostly in St George's.</p><p>ATMs are available, mostly in St George's.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted by most banks. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1500, Fri 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months from the date of departure is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above wishing to visit Grenada.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa on arrival: EC$100; multiple-entry visa on arrival: EC$250. Nationals requiring a visa on arrival must obtain a pre-clearance letter from the embassy or high commission before travel. There is a US$10 fee for the letter plus mailing costs.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Single-entry visa in advance: US$100/&pound;65; multiple-entry visa in advance: US$250.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Varies according to individual circumstances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>High commission or embassy (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow around seven days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing your pet into Grenada, you must have an import permit issued by the Veterinary Officer of the Ministry of Agriculture in Grenada. Your pet must have a valid rabies vaccination certificate and a certificate of health issued by a vet within two weeks prior to departure. Application forms for import permits are available from embassies/high commissions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[12.196014]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-61.640018]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>344 sq km (132 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>107,327 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>321.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saint George&rsquo;s.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Grenada is located in the Caribbean. The island is of volcanic origin and is divided by a central mountain range. It is the most southerly of the Windward Islands.</p>
<p>Its agriculture is based on nutmeg (one third of the world's nutmeg supply comes from Grenada), cocoa, sugar cane and bananas. Tropical rainforests, gorges and the stunning beauty of dormant volcanoes make this a fascinating and diverse landscape with some of the finest beaches in the world. Carriacou and some of the other small islands of the Grenadines are also part of Grenada.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic 53%, Anglican 14%, smaller Protestant denominations 33%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local culture reflects the island's history of British and French colonial rule and, of course, the African cultures imported with the slaves - African influence is especially noticeable on the island of Carriacou in the Big Drum and in Grenada with the Shango dance. The Roman Catholic Church also exerts a strong influence on the way of life. Local people are generally friendly and courteous. Dress is casual and informal but beachwear is not welcome in town.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Keith Mitchell since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General C&eacute;cile La Grenade since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For a small island, Grenada has had a turbulent history. The earliest known inhabitants were Arawak Indians, who were then displaced by Caribs some time before AD 1300. The first serious attempt at settlement by Europeans was in 1609, but the Caribs resisted fiercely and it was not until 1650 that the French were able to claim the island. It remained a French colony until taken by the British in 1783. Grenada was an important centre in the slave trade between Africa and the sugar plantations of the West Indies. With the emancipation of slaves and the disintegration of the plantation system, the majority of islanders came to depend on a few local industries and their own smallholdings. <BR/><BR/>Radical politics have been a hallmark of Grenadian society since the early 1950s when trade union organisation, promoted by Eric Gairy, a firebrand ex-teacher, took root among the workforce. Gairy ultimately led Grenada into independence from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> in February 1974, and subsequently won three elections for the premiership. Not all were content with Gairy's regime, however, and among his opponents was the New JEWEL Movement (Joint Endeavour for Welfare, Education and Liberation), a group of mainly young, educated left-wingers led by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/grenada/point-salines-international-airport">Maurice Bishop</a>. In the spring of 1979, the NJM deposed Gairy in a bloodless coup. The <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> believed that the NJM was determined to turn Grenada into a mini-Cuba, and from 1980 onwards increased political pressure against the Government. The question of how to respond to this, and other issues, split the NJM leadership, and led to the military coup of October 1983 in which Bishop was killed. The coup provided a pretext for the US invasion and the restoration of the pre-NJM system of government under the tutelage of the USA. Four existing political parties allied to form the New National Party (NNP), under the leadership of the veteran politician Herbert Blaize, to keep out Eric Gairy who was still on the scene. At the general election in December 1984, the NNP won handsomely. The NNP has dominated Grenadian politics ever since, and won the most recent election held in November 2003, where it swept the board for the House of Representatives. Party leader Keith Mitchell is now into his third term as Prime Minister. Mitchell's government continues the NNP tradition of very close relations with the USA, although a sharp drop in financial support led Mitchell, along with other East Caribbean leaders, to seek economic assistance elsewhere. The Organisation of East Caribbean States plays an important part in Grenada's foreign policy. A proposed political union comprising the member of the organisation has aroused fierce opposition because of historic inter-island rivalries, although its supporters (who include the Mitchell government) feel it essential to the future prosperity and security of the region.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Grenada in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 2561</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.grenadaembassyusa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 2561</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1701 New Hampshire Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Honorary Consul in Grenada]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(1) 473 440 8844</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-high-commission-barbados</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(1) 473 440 8844</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>PO Box 38<br/>St George's<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Grenada High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7385 4415.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.grenadahclon.co.uk/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7385 4415.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; 1000-1400 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Archer Road<br/>The Chapel<br/>London<br/>W14 9QH<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As far as paradise islands go, few come more beautiful than Grenada. A mountainous and volcanic landscape gives the country one of the loveliest environments in the Caribbean, with crater lakes, rainforests and coastal mangrove plantations giving way to white sand beaches, and brilliant blue waters filled with coral reefs. What's not to like?</p><p>Grenada is known as the Spice Island for good reason. Nutmeg, cloves, cinnamon, ginger and vanilla are just a few of the scented gems found here. When it comes to food, Grenadians like it particularly hot and spicy. Pepper pot is a favourite – meat cooked with lots of garlic, onions and, you guessed it, pepper. As well as fragrant spices, music is also an important part of life on Grenada, with the calypso tunes dancing over the island evoking Grenadians' African origins.</p><p>Many will, of course, be drawn to Grenada for its beaches. They are several dozen of them, immaculate and well-preserved, while digging a bit deeper will bring you to isolated coves where it'll be just you and the sea. Bring your snorkelling gear – there are plenty of colourful fish species to be glimpsed.</p><p>If there's only so much lounging on a beach you can tolerate, pick up one of the many nature trails running across the island that'll take you through wilderness brimming with wildlife. Expect to see rare birds in the rainforest and monkeys in the loftier terrain. You're also likely to cross one or two spice plantations, whose beguiling aromas are one of the trademarks of Grenada.</p><p>The capital, St George's, is a pretty city boasting one of the finest beaches in the Caribbean, Grand Anse. Meanwhile, day trips to neighbouring islands come highly recommended for those keen on sailing, diving and fishing. For unassailable tranquility, spend some time on the islet of Carriacou, whose simple, idyllic way of life is sure to charm. In fact, on the whole of Grenada, there are no colossal resorts, meaning peace, quiet and nature are largely the order of the day, along with a friendly and welcoming population.</p>A mountainous and volcanic landscape gives Grenada one of the loveliest environments in the Caribbean, with crater lakes, rainforests and coastal mangrove plantations giving way to white sand beaches, and brilliant blue waters filled with coral reefs.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
