<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Guadeloupe" ColCode="glp" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="gp" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Guadeloupe]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guadeloupe enjoys warm weather throughout the year with the main rainy season occurring from June to October. Showers can, however, occur at any time although they are usually brief. The humidity can be exceedingly high at times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights with warmer top layers for the evenings; showerproofs are advisable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Cara&iuml;be (<a href="http://www.aircaraibes.com/" target="_blank">www.aircaraibes.com</a>) and LIAT (<a href="http://www.liat.com" target="_blank">www.liat.com</a>) connect Guadeloupe with the smaller islands in the group. There are domestic airports on the islands of La D&eacute;sirade and Marie-Galante.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>L'Express des Iles (<a href="http://www.express-des-iles.com/" target="_blank">www.express-des-iles.com</a>) provides services from Guadeloupe to Martinique, Dominica and St Lucia. It's also one of several ferry companies which connect Basse-Terre and Grande-Terre&nbsp;with the smaller Guadeloupian islands of Les Saintes, Marie-Galante and D&eacute;sirade.</p>
<p>Ferries to les Saintes, Marie-Galante and D&eacute;sirade depart from&nbsp;Pointe-&agrave;-Pitre. Ferries to the &Icirc;les des Saintes also depart from Trois-Rivi&egrave;res and there are daily ferries to Marie-Galante and D&eacute;sirade from Saint-Fran&ccedil;ois.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>Roads are paved and tend to be in good condition. Drivers do tend to drive fast and tailgating is common. Traffic rules and signage are the same as in France.</p><p>Guadeloupe has a reasonable bus network, but it is generally the slowest way to get around. Most bus routes start and end in Pointe-&agrave;-Pitre. The destination of buses is usually displayed in bus windows. Bus stops have blue signs which depict a bus.</p><p>Taxis are available in all the main towns and can also be found outside the airport at most times. Always check the fare with the driver before getting in, and remember that fares are significantly higher between 2100 and 0700 daily and on Sundays and holidays.</p><p>For stays of 20 days or less, a valid driving licence is needed. For longer stays, an international driver's permit is necessary. Car hire companies can provide drivers with emergency contact information.</p><p>Renting a car is the easiest way to explore Guadeloupe. Most of the major car hire firms are represented, and prices are reasonable. You need a valid passport, driving licence and international driving licence, and a credit card in the name of the principal driver. Drivers must be at least 21 years of age. Most of the larger hotels also offer car hire services.</p><p>Cycling is particularly popular on Guadeloupe. Roads tend to be in good condition and drivers tend to give cyclists a wide berth.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Air Cara&iuml;bes (<a href="http://www.aircaraibes.com/" target="_blank">www.aircaraibes.com</a>). Air <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>), Corsairfly (<a href="http://www.corsairfly.com" target="_blank">www.corsairfly.com</a>) and XL (<a href="http://www.xl.com/en/index.cfm?lang=EN" target="_blank">www.xl.com</a>) also fly direct from Paris to Guadeloupe. Norwegian (<a href="http://www.norwegian.com" target="_blank">www.norwegian.com</a>) offers direct flights from the USA.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London - 12 hours (including stopover); New York - 4 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Pointe-à-Pitre International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport  is 3km (2 miles) from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pointe-pitre">Pointe-à-Pitre</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pointe-pitre">Pointe-&agrave;-Pitre</a> in Grande-Terre is a point of call for international cruise operators. Many ships ply routes between Guadeloupe,&nbsp;Antigua, Saint-Martin, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominica">Dominica</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/martinique">Martinique</a>, and also connect with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida/miami-international-airport">Miami</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/san-juan">San Juan</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/puerto-rico">Puerto Rico</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Good internal network. There are no area codes. Phonecards (<em>télécartes</em>) are necessary to make calls from public telephones.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile phones work in most areas on the island and there is good coverage. Analogue networks are compatible with most US handsets, which can be activated on the island by dialling 0 or by registering online.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in Internet cafes at Saint-Francois, Sainte Anne, Mare-Gaillard and Pointe-à-Pitre; there are also terminals in some larger post offices and public buildings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail takes about one week to reach Europe. Postal rates are the same as metropolitan France.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask on the beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From black, volcanic sands to sweeping icing sugar shores, Guadeloupe boasts some of the finest beaches in the Caribbean. Topless bathing is acceptable but do expect roving eyes. For sundowners Plage de la Perle on Grand-Terre is hard to beat with its golden sand, rustling palm trees and ramshackle beach bars. For quieter shores explore Sainte-Anne on Grand-Terre.</p>]]><p><b>Climb an active volcano</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike up La Grande Soufrière, an active volcano, which tops out at 1,467m (4,813ft) and offers a tough climb. However, the panorama that greets visitors at the summit makes it well worth the effort – from the top it is possible to see the verdant peaks of the surrounding islands. The last significant rumble was in 1976.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the ruins of sugar plantations</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discovered by Christopher Columbus in 1493, the island of Marie-Galante was divided into sugar plantations by the French. Relics of these plantations dot the island, but perhaps the most interesting ruin can be found at the Murat Plantation, which was the workplace of 207 African slaves. Visitors can see the remains of a windmill and look around the plantation house.</p>]]><p><b>Get wet at Carbet Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Carbet Falls, located on Basse-Terre, is a series of three spectacular waterfalls in the foothills of La Grande Soufrière. Only experienced and confident hikers should attempt trekking to the first or third waterfall (where a refreshing dip awaits hardy pilgrims), but the second waterfall is easily accessible to all.</p>]]><p><b>Go scuba diving along the west coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The best dive sites can be found along Guadeloupe's west coast. The small fishing village of Anse Duché has a sunken shipwreck named L'Augustin to explore and there are several sites surrounding the Pigeon Islets, which form part of the Réserve Cousteau. The Grand Cul-de-Sac Marin Nature Reserve, a protected marine reserve in the north, also boasts large coral reefs.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the National Park of Guadeloupe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The National Park of Guadeloupe boasts some 300km (188 miles) of marked trails, most of which are located in the rainforest. This balmy jungle is home to more than 100 species of orchids, 11 species of bats and several rare species of bird. The park is also home to a volcano, a mountain and a waterfall.</p>]]><p><b>Imbibe ancient art</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Parc Archeologique des Roches Graves near Trois-Rivières is home to many of the rock carvings made by ancient tribes such as the Arawaks that once inhabited the Guadeloupe Islands. The park also has a beautiful tropical garden and visitors can enjoy spectacular views across the Les Saintes archipelago.</p>]]><p><b>Infiltrate a French fort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fort Louis Delgrès, on Basse-Terre, was built in 1650 by French Governor Charles Houel. The fort was the target of frequent attacks by the British Navy, which briefly seized it in 1759. It was eventually decommissioned in 1904 and classified as a national monument in 1977. For the full history, tour with a official guide on Fridays.</p>]]><p><b>Join the Carnival revelry</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Guadeloupe Carnival, the most eagerly anticipated event of the year, takes place in the weeks before Ash Wednesday and is a jamboree of epic proportions. Islanders dress up in colourful costumes, parade through the streets and dance until the small hours – for the best part of six weeks. It's worth going out your way for.</p>]]><p><b>Kayak through the mangroves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The protected mangrove swamps of Guadeloupe abound with migratory birds, including pelicans, kingfishers and herons. These species are best viewed by taking a kayaking expedition through the mangrove forests, which are located along the western coast of the country. Kayak Canyon Guadeloupe hire kayaks by the day, while there are plenty of hiking trails through the swamps.</p>]]><p><b>Quaff the local tipple</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Guadeloupe's famous rum institution, Musée du Rhum, explains how the sugarcane spirit is produced and, more importantly, offers visitors a taste of the local brew. There are around 15 rums to choose from, all of which are produced by the distillery next door. </p>]]><p><b>Stroll around the colonial capital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pointe-à-Pitre is the commercial capital of Guadeloupe and is characterised by its colourful colonial buildings, bustling markets and lively inhabitants. The centrepiece of the city is the Place de la Victoire where more than 850 people were beheaded by guillotine during the French Revolution. Today, people socialise, shop and watch the world go by.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Creole Ecological Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ecomusee Creole de la Guadeloupe can be found just outside the commune of Sainte-Rose on Basse-Terre. It boasts a botanical garden which contains fragrant exhibitions relating to the herbs, fruits and vegetables grown on Guadeloupe. The exhibition explores the medicinal properties of the local flora and relates the history of the islands and the different ethnic groups living on them.</p>]]><p><b>Walk above the forest canopy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As well as boasting a zoo and botanical gardens, the Parc Zoologique et Botanique de la Guadeloupe, located on Basse-Terre, has a network of lofty rope bridges, which are suspended above the forest canopy. The views are excellent, but you will need a head for heights.</p>]]><p><b>Walk amongst the dead in Morne-a-l'Eau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Morne-à-l'Eau, on the island of Grande-Terre, there is an extraordinary, amphitheatre-like cemetery where narrow pathways weave between enormous crypts. Some crypts are extravagant affairs (many were designed by architects for rich families) but all are covered in black and white tiles. The chequered façades on these sepulchres represent the intermingled African and European cultures of Guadeloupe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$9.7 billion (2006 estimate).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Bananas, sugarcane, rum and vanilla.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, fuel, vehicles, consumer goods and construction materials.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a> and Netherlands Antilles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guadeloupe's economy revolves around agriculture, light industry and tourism. Bananas and sugar are the main exports, accounting for approximately one-third of total foreign earnings. Coffee, cocoa and vanilla are the other main cash crops. In recent years the export of bananas has been threatened by regional competition and the phasing out of preferential European quotas.</p><p>Tourism, especially ecotourism, is also becoming increasingly important. There is a growing number of cruise ship visitors. The islands have been suffering because of the economic downturn, which has kept tourists away. Unemployment hit 23% in 2012 (compared with 10.2% in France) and Guadeloupe's economy is kept afloat by public salaries and credits from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a>.</p><p>France supplies most of the island's imports and takes three-quarters of its exports. In February 2009, France announced a $730 million financial aid package to be shared between all of its Overseas Territories.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It can get very hot and humid in Guadeloupe so lightweight suits are recommended for business meetings. Much of Guadeloupe's business is connected to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> and customs tend to be similar, albeit more relaxed, than in France.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1400-1800 and most businesses close on Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie de Pointe-à-Pitre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (590) 937 600
					Website:http://www.pointe-a-pitre.cci.fr/
					Address: 97110 Pointe-à-Pitre,Rue Félix Eboué,Guadeloupe,]]><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie de Basse-Terre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (590) 994 444
					Website:http://www.basseterre.cci.fr/
					Address: ,6 Rue Victor Hugues,97100 Basse-Terre,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Guadeloupian cuisine features many Creole specialities, but there is also a strong French influence. Seafood appears on most menus, and curry dishes are also popular. Spices and herbs are used generously, and local fruit such as the star-shape carambole, giraumon (a type of pumpkin) and malanga (a type of root) are also common ingredients. Guadeloupe has numerous patisseries and cafés serving French pastries with a Creole twist. The more formal restaurants will require appropriate dress.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><em>&bull; Cabri </em>(goat, used in various dishes)<br />
<em>&bull; Matete </em>(a hot crab curry)<br />
<em>&bull; Blaff </em>(seafood cooked in a seasoned soup)<br />
<em>&bull; Ouassou</em> (spring water shrimp)<br />
<em>&bull; Callaloo</em> (a soup made with bacon and spinach-like greens)<br />
<em>&bull; B&eacute;b&eacute;l&eacute; </em>(an offal-based soup)<br />
<em>&bull; Accras</em> (fritters made from cod or vegetables)<br />
&bull; Stuffed crab<br />
&bull;<em> </em>Lobster</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Restaurant tips are normally around 15 %.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>No evening in Guadeloupe is complete without listening to the soothing sounds of Biguine, a type of music which fuses 19th-century French ballroom dance steps with African rhythms. Although many believe Biguine to be a <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/martinique">Martinique</a> invention, Guadeloupians proudly claim they introduced it to the world. Zouk, a fast, carnival-style type of music, which originated in Guadeloupe and Martinique, is equally popular.</p><p>As night falls on Guadeloupe, many restaurants and bars morph into live music venues. As well as Biguine and Zouk, jazz is also popular on the islands.</p><p>The Zoo Rock Café (tel: in Gosier is a restaurant and bar which has an outdoor terrace area and holds regular themed nights. Music fans will love Auberge de la Vieille Tour, Le Gossier, Grande-Terre (tel: +590 590 842 323; <a href="http://www.auberge-vieille-tour.fr" target="_blank">www.auberge-vieille-tour.fr</a>), which serves up a fine selection of rum and delicious salt fish fritters to the sound of live jazz.</p><p>The Marina Pointe-à-Pitre is home to a smorgasbord of bars, nightclubs and restaurants, which overlook the limpid natural harbour between Grande-Terre and Basse-Terre. Expect extended happy hours, live music and is-that-the-time-already revelry that goes on well into the early hours.</p><p>For those that fancy a flutter, there are two casinos in Guadeloupe – Casino Gosier-les-Bains in Gosier and Casino de St-François in St-François. Both are on Grande-Terre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For souvenirs and local handicrafts, the best place to shop is the Village Artisanal (<a href="http://www.village-artisanal.com" target="_blank">www.village-artisanal.com</a>), which opened in 2013 and showcases the best in Guadeloupian produce. Located on Grande-Terre's La Pointe des Châteaux peninsula, this market is home to a range of boutiques, plus a restaurant.</p><p>Pointe-a-Pitre is good for high street shopping; the stores in Center Saint-John Perse sell everything from perfume and jewellery to cosmetics. Emporiums selling similar products can be found down the Frébault, Nozières, and Schoelcher Street.</p><p>The best markets in Pointe-a-Pitre can be found on the harbour side. Spices, flowers and local handicrafts can all be purchased here.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700, Sat 0900-1300 (closed on Sunday).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good selection of hotels throughout all the five islands of Guadeloupe, ranging from first-class beach resorts to country inns. Hotel rates are usually inclusive of taxes. A standard charge of US$1.50 per day is levied by many hotels. Additional service charges can range between 15 and 30% depending on the time of year. Package prices range from all inclusive to room-only.<br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> Guadeloupe uses the star grading system, with properties rated from <strong>1-4 stars</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good selection of hotels throughout all the five islands of Guadeloupe, ranging from first-class beach resorts to country inns. Hotel rates are usually inclusive of taxes. A standard charge of US$1.50 per day is levied by many hotels. Additional service charges can range between 15 and 30% depending on the time of year. Package prices range from all inclusive to room-only.<br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> Guadeloupe uses the star grading system, with properties rated from <strong>1-4 stars</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good selection of hotels throughout all the five islands of Guadeloupe, ranging from first-class beach resorts to country inns. Hotel rates are usually inclusive of taxes. A standard charge of US$1.50 per day is levied by many hotels. Additional service charges can range between 15 and 30% depending on the time of year. Package prices range from all inclusive to room-only.<br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> Guadeloupe uses the star grading system, with properties rated from <strong>1-4 stars</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health care is of a good standard, but health insurance is advisable to cover costs as the reciprocal health agreement between the &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom"&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france"&gt;France&lt;/a&gt; may not apply in Guadeloupe. There is a University Hospital Centre in &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pointe-pitre"&gt;Pointe-à-Pitre&lt;/a&gt;, on Grande-Terre, and a hospital on Basse-Terre as well as a number of clinics.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is chlorinated and whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available and is advised for the first few weeks of stay. Drinking water outside main cities and towns may be contaminated and sterilisation is advised. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafoods and fruit are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. The sap of the manchineel tree is toxic and causes burns to the skin. Travellers should avoid contact with its leaves and fruit, and should not stand under the tree when it is raining. These trees, which look similar to apple trees, are often marked with a red sign on the trunk.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Ash Wednesday :
							14 February </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							08 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Abolition Day :
							27 May </p><p>Bastille Day :
							14 July </p><p>Schoelcher Day :
							21 July </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Armistice Day :
							11 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Guadeloupe by travellers over the age of 17:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of spirits up to 22% volume.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine.<br />
&bull; 16L of beer.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of &euro;1,000 if arriving from mainland <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> or another EU country.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of &euro;430 if arriving from a non-EU country (or &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are restrictions on the import of unauthorised firearms, counterfeit goods, plants and flowers, and endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unauthorised firearms and endangered species.</p>
<p>You must obtain an authorisation certificate to export goods of cultural value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since January 2002 the Euro (€) has been the official currency for the French Overseas Departments, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/french-guiana">French Guiana</a>, Guadeloupe, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/martinique">Martinique</a> and Réunion. Notes are in denominations of €5, 10, 20, 50, 100, 200 and 500. Coins are in denominations of 1, 2, 5, 10, 20 and 50 cents, and 1 and 2 euros. For further details, see <em><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a></em> section.<br /><br />US Dollars are accepted but change might be given in Euros.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All banks and most hotels will change traveller's cheques and foreign currency. All the major French banks are represented on the island. There are bureaux de change in all of the main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted. ATMs are available in every town.</p><p>ATMs are available in every town.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted in most places. Their use may qualify visitors for discounts on luxury items. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> and Canadian Dollar cheques are also accepted in some places.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1400-1600, some are open Sat 0800-1300 (closed Wednesday afternoons).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes/1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A valid passport is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above, except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a national ID card. However, be aware that some airlines may require you to carry a passport to board your flight.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals who do require a visa can only enter Guadeloupe on a Schengen visa if it is marked on the visa sticker; you must advise the consulate/TLScontact that you are planning on visiting Guadeloupe when you apply.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay/Schengen visa: &euro;60; long-stay visa: &euro;99.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay/Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period; long-stay visa: valid for stays of over three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>French Consulate (or consular section at embassy). In the UK, the consulate has outsourced the visa application process to TLScontact (<a href="http://www.tlscontact.com/gb2fr" target="_blank">www.tlscontact.com/gb2fr</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 15 days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EU nationals staying longer than three months must register at the pr&eacute;fecture to apply for a&nbsp;<em>carte de s&eacute;jour</em>. Other nationals require a long-stay visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[16.254014]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-61.455987]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,705 sq km (658 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>470,547 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>236.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Basse-Terre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guadeloupe is an Overseas Department of France and as such is an integral part of the French Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guadeloupe comprises the larger islands of Basse-Terre and Grande-Terre (separated from Basse-Terre by a narrow sea channel) and three smaller islands. Basse-Terre has a rough volcanic relief whilst Grande Terre features rolling hills and flat plains. All the islands have beautiful white or black-sand palm-fringed beaches. There are lush mountainous areas with stunning and unspoiled tropical scenery.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority are Roman Catholic, with a minority of predominantly Evangelical Protestant groups.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The atmosphere is relaxed and informal. Casual dress is accepted everywhere, but formal dress is needed for dining out and nightclubs.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two rounds plugs are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President of the Departmental Council Josette Borel-Lincertin since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Emmanuel Macron since 2017, represented locally by Prefect Philippe Gustin since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When the Arawaks settled on present day Guadeloupe in 300AD, they dubbed their newfound territory &lsquo;Karukera,&rsquo; meaning, rather appropriately, &lsquo;the island of beautiful waters.&rsquo;</p>
<p>It was these waters &ndash; know today as the Caribbean Sea &ndash; that sustained the Arawaks, who eked out simple lives, living off the daily catch.</p>
<p>They had a good run, but when a rival ethnic group know as the Cara&iuml;bes arrived in the 8th century, they exterminated the Arawaks in a merciless slaughter, claiming a land that had been peaceful for centuries.</p>
<p>In 1493, Christopher Columbus became the first European to land on Guadeloupe. His expedition left behind no settlers, but the Spanish soon started to stake their claim to the archipelago and attempted to colonise the island. But the fearsome Cara&iuml;bes stood their ground and repelled them.</p>
<p>Cue the French, who succeeded where the Spanish failed by colonising Guadeloupe in 1635, eliminating the Cara&iuml;bes in the process. The French quickly established Guadeloupe as one of the leading players in the booming sugar industry, but while the motherland enjoyed the sweet taste of success, African slaves toiled relentlessly in the plantations.</p>
<p>The outbreak of the French Revolution in 1789 brought tumult to Guadeloupe. The republicans and monarchists fought bitterly and by 1793 a slave rebellion had broken out. The British took advantage of the chaos and seized the island the following year, but it was back in French hands by the end of 1794.</p>
<p>Well, sort of. Guadeloupe was largely under the control of slaves, until 1802 when Napoleon Bonaparte sent forces to retake the island and reinstate slavery. His forces killed an estimated 10,000 people.</p>
<p>The British seized the island again in 1810 and Guadeloupe spent the next six years being occupied by the Brits, Swedes and, finally, the French. In 1848, the French Parliament voted for the Abolition Decreet; brought in by Viktor Schoelcher, it signalled the end of slavery on Guadeloupe.</p>
<p>In 1946, Guadeloupe became a French Overseas Department. It uses the Euro and is a member of the European Union, through <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>. An independence movement, most active in the eighties, still simmers beneath the surface.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; Though cultivated for centuries by natives, Christopher Columbus discovered the pineapple for Europe when he landed on Guadeloupe in 1493.<br />
&bull; Guadeloupe host an annual festival dedicated to goats, which includes a goat fashion parade.<br />
&bull; Christopher Columbus named the island Santa Maria de Guadalupe in honour of the eponymous monastery in the Spanish town of Guadalupe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[French Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7073 1000. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambafrance-uk.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7073 1000. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>58 Knightsbridge<br/>London<br/>SW1X 7JT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[French Embassy in the USA ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 944 6000. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambafrance-us.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 944 6000. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Visa appointments are available Mon-Fri 0845-1200. Appointments can be booked online.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>4101 Reservoir Road NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A butterfly-shaped archipelago in the Caribbean Sea, Guadeloupe is a picture of tropical island idyll – no wonder the French are reluctant to let it go.</p><p>Known as Karukera to the original Caraïbe inhabitants, this French overseas region might share the same attributes as other coveted <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/caribbean">Caribbean</a> destinations – white powdery beaches, vertiginous mountains and dazzling coral reefs – but Guadeloupe's Franco-Caribbean culture sets the archipelago apart from its neighbours.</p><p>Ascribed by Jacques Cousteau as one of the world's premier diving destinations, Guadeloupe was at the front of the queue when they were giving out natural beauty; from the lofty heights of La Grande Soufrière volcano to the resplendent reefs of the Pigeon Islets, this archipelago is exquisite on the eye.</p><p>Comprising eight islands and numerous small islets, Guadeloupe's varied typography is a big draw for adventure travellers, who come to trek the terrain, ride the waves and cycle through a slice of paradise.</p><p>But the archipelago is also a hit with more sedentary travellers, who while away lazy days on sandy shores and quaff rum in ramshackle beach bars to the rousing rhythms of Guadeloupian beguine.</p><p>Each island, of course, has its own character, but few travellers have time to visit them all. Most base themselves on one of the two main islands – Basse-Terre and Grande-Terre – which are linked by dense mangrove swamps rich in wildlife.</p><p>These two islands are home to Guadeloupe's main resorts; they are where most of the hotels and evening entertainment can be found; where you can eat at the best restaurants; and fall out of the best bars.</p><p>They are also home to the archipelago's leading historical attractions, including forts, defunct sugar plantations and museums, which, between them, trace the DNA of modern day Guadeloupe and explain how it remains an unlikely member of the European Union.</p>Guadeloupe comprises the butterfly-shaped islands of Basse-Terre and Grande-Terre and the nearby smaller islands of La Desirade, Marie-Galante and Les Saintes.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
