<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Guam" ColCode="gum" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="gu" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Guam]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Temperatures are pretty constant. Only on rare occasions does the temperature dip below 21.1°C (70°F) or above 32.2°C (90°F). Average humidity is 66% but easterly trade winds of 6.4k-19.3 kph (4-12 mph) offset the dampness. The wet season is July through November, with transitional months being June and December. The best time to visit is Jan-May, the dry season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Casual, lightweight attire is recommended for most times, but a rain jacket and an umbrella is always useful, especially during the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fares are metered. Taxis are available near major shopping centres and at hotels.</p><p>An International Driving Permit or a US licence is required.</p><p>Available through most major companies. Hire can be arranged at offices throughout the island including the airport and hotel lobbies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guam Mass Transit Authority operates buses to most villages in Guam. Trolleys connect hotels and shopping centres.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From the USA and Europe, Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) are the&nbsp;major carriers to Guam. Other airlines serving Guam include China Airlines (<a href="http://www.china-airlines.com" target="_blank">www.china-airlines.com</a>), Japan Airlines (<a href="http://www.jal.com/" target="_blank">www.jal.com</a>) and Philippine Airlines (<a href="http://www.philippineairlines.com" target="_blank">www.philippineairlines.com</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guam/guam-international-airport">Antonio B Won Pat Guam International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 16 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 20 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Antonio B. Won Pat Guam International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.guamairport.com<p>Antonio B. Won Pat Guam International Airport is situated 6km (4 miles) northeast of Hagåtña, Guam's capital.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 671 642 4636</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Apra Harbour is the principal port in Guam. There are no ferry services. It is mostly a port of call for shipping lines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Direct dial overseas telecommunications facilities are available to all overseas points 24 hours a day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Wi-Fi hotspots provided by <em>IT&E</em> situated at the International Airport, Micronesia Mall and some other locations. Internet cafes can be found in the Tumon area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The English-language daily newspaper is <em>The Pacific Daily News</em>. Kuam is a commercial TV channel,<em> </em>K57 (KGUM) is commercial radio station and KPRG is a public radio station.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>(Main) Mon-Sat 0800-1500. The Guam Main Facility branch is open Mon-Fri 0930-1700, Sat 1300-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Discover a world of watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Guam's beautiful waters lend themselves to an array of water-based activities, including jet skiing, windsurfing, kayaking and fishing. A recent addition to the watersports scene is snuba diving, which combines the freedom of snorkeling with scuba. Or enjoy seeing marine life using a Seawalker, which is a unique helmet filled with air.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Guam’s underwater world</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the world's leading dive destinations, underwater attractions include WWII wrecks, colourful coral reefs and marine life aplenty. Lucky divers may spot the spinner dolphin, which inhabits the island's shallow bays. The island also has plenty of reputable dive schools, which are perfect for beginners.</p>]]><p><b>Get back to nature in Gef Pago Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This living museum in Inarajan Village focuses on the traditions and lifestyle of the Chamorros. Demonstrations reveal how natives made sea salt, wove rope and how coconut was more than just food; husks served as insect repellent, fire starters and insulation.</p>]]><p><b>Get close, but not too close to Two Lovers Point</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Local legend says that two, star-crossed lovers leapt 115m (378ft) to their deaths from this vantage point. We don't suggest you do the same, of course, but we do highly recommend you check out this vantage point's fine views of Tumon Bay.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about Guam’s tumultuous history</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The South Pacific Memorial Park, just outside Hagåtña, commemorates those killed in WWII, and the nearby War in the Pacific National Historical Park is the location of five battle sites with a museum exhibiting war photos and relics. Guam Museum is also well worth a visit: its exhibits showcase Chamorro culture and tell the story of Sgt. Shoichi Yokoi, a Japanese soldier, who hid in rural Guam until 1972, unaware the war was over.</p>]]><p><b>Relax in Latte Stone Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the crumbling remains of the ancient Chamorro people, which sit in the manicured surrounds of Latte Park. Other notable green spaces include Merizo Pier Park, in the south, which has fine views across the ocean. It's also worth venturing to the dark sands of Talofofo Bay Beach Park, which is located at the mouth of the Talofofo River and is renowned for its surf.</p>]]><p><b>See the Spanish legacy in Hagåtña</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spain ruled Guam for 333 years and Hagåtña, the capital, has many colonial buildings in the charming old town. The city is an unlikely foodie hotspot, with many fine restaurants, while the city's pubs, cocktail bars and clubs cater for hedonists. Culturally, there are a number of attractions nearby including Guam Museum.</p>]]><p><b>See the view from Apra Harbour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From this vantage point, one glimpses the harbour just like the Japanese soldiers did when the Americans invaded the island. A commemorative monument lists those who died during the three-year Japanese occupation. Today the harbour is a busy cruise and cargo ship port.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll around the Namo Falls Botanical Garden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Namo Fall Botanical Gardens in Agat is a popular spot for some wild swimming. Bathers can paddle in pools beneath two waterfalls, called Guella and Guello ("grandmother" and "grandfather"). If you don't fancy getting wet, take a stroll through the beautiful botanical gardens, which abounds with orchids, bougainvillea, mango trees and much more.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hike</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For the best views of the island climb Mount Lamlam, which is the highest point on Guam at 406m (1,334ft). And here's a bit of trivia for you to consider on the way up: the distance between the summit and nearby Mariana Trench is the greatest elevation change on Earth over such a short distance.</p>]]><p><b>Visit WWII battle sites</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This park consists of six different WWII battle sites where war relics, caves, foxholes and tunnels still exist. A must when visiting the park is the T Stell Newman Visitor Center, which features the award-winning movie, Liberating <em>Guam: The U.S. Comes Back</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$3.6 billion.</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Re-exports of petroleum-based products, construction materials, fish, food and beverage products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum and petroleum products, food and manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Japan, Singapore, Korea (Rep), Hong Kong and the Philippines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guam's economy depends largely on the US military. The island is a vital staging post for operations through the Pacific region. Tourism ranks second. In 2008, Guam received 1,179,246 visitors, 90% came from Japan.<br /><br />Though crops, including maize, cassava, bananas and coconuts, are grown for domestic consumption, Guam is an important re-export centre for distribution of goods throughout the Pacific, particularly to Micronesia.<br /><br />The Guam government would like to attract more foreign investment, principally from Asia. It has been examining the country's potential as an offshore financial centre, but there is a great deal of Pacific competition. And, such a move is not favoured by Guam's tax laws.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Guam Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 472 6311
					Website:http://www.guamchamber.com.gu
					Address: Ada Plaza Center,173 Aspinall Avenue,Suite 101,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>A wide selection of restaurants features American, Chinese, European, Filipino, Indonesian, Japanese, Korean and Mexican food. Guamanian cooking is very similar to Spanish cuisine. Expect to see American franchises like McDonalds, KFC, Hooters, Hard Rock Caf&eacute;, as well as the upscale Roy's in the Hilton Hotel.<br />
<br />
A local favourite, the seaside Jeff's Pirate Cove (tel: 789 2683/1582) serves everything from breakfast, steaks and fresh seafood, to local delicacies.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Finadene sauce (often served with barbeque).<br />
<em><em>&bull;</em> Kelaguen</em> (chopped chicken, lemon juice, grated coconut and hot peppers).<br />
<em><em><em>&bull;</em> </em>Apigigi </em>(dessert of coconut milk and tapioca which is wrapped and grilled in a banana leaf).<br />
<em><em><em><em>&bull;</em> </em></em>Mahha Titiyas </em>(coconut tortillas).<em><br />
<em><em><em><em>&bull;</em> </em></em></em>Guyuria </em>(deep-fried cookie with sugar glaze).<br />
<em><em><em><em><em>&bull;</em> </em></em></em>Bunelos </em>(banana donuts).<br />
<em><em><em><em><em>&bull;</em> </em></em></em>Buchi-Buchi </em>(fried pumpkin).<br />
<em><em><em><em><em>&bull;</em> </em></em></em>Pastit </em>(flaky crusted Chamorro dessert with pumpkin or papaya).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10 to 15% is standard. Where a 10% service charge has already been added to the bill, tipping is optional.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A range of nightclubs feature music and dancing. Major hotels frequently stage shows with musicians from the USA mainland, or local performers including the<em> </em>Guam Symphony &amp; Choral Society. There are a number of cinemas in Tamuning, including at least one 14-screen cinema, most showing recent USA films. Dinner<strong> </strong>shows featuring the traditional dances are held nightly in several hotels. There are also facilities that specialise in Chamorro and other forms of Micronesian Island dances. The Tumon Bay SandCastle is a world class performance and entertainment facility and has a multilevel New York-style disco. Many hotels also have discos and/or the popular karaoke bars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Find mega malls like Aga&ntilde;a Shopping Centre and Guam Premier Outlets, Micronesia Mall and DFS Galleria<em>,</em> and the world's largest K-Mart (open 24/7)<em>.</em> <br />
<br />
Hotels in Tumon Bay also have their own speciality shops, or within walking distance. Weekend bargain hunters willing to rise early can visit the Dededo flea market at 0600 to find deals on a hotchpotch of items. <br />
<br />
Because of the island's duty-free status, there are often good buys on watches, perfume, jewellery, alcohol, china, stereo equipment and cameras. Though it appears that there is no sales tax, a 4% tariff  is built into the price.</p><p>Generally Mon-Sat 1000-2100, Sun 1200-1800 but hours do vary from centre to centre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lodgings include all-inclusive resorts, bed-and-breakfasts, plus moderately priced and upscale hotels. A number of business hotels and family style accommodation are located in Hagåtña, Maite, Tamuning and Mangilao. As the island is small, most of these properties are close to the airport. Tumon Bay is the Island's premier resort destination.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lodgings include all-inclusive resorts, bed-and-breakfasts, plus moderately priced and upscale hotels. A number of business hotels and family style accommodation are located in Hagåtña, Maite, Tamuning and Mangilao. As the island is small, most of these properties are close to the airport. Tumon Bay is the Island's premier resort destination.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lodgings include all-inclusive resorts, bed-and-breakfasts, plus moderately priced and upscale hotels. A number of business hotels and family style accommodation are located in Hagåtña, Maite, Tamuning and Mangilao. As the island is small, most of these properties are close to the airport. Tumon Bay is the Island's premier resort destination.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is strongly advised, owing to the high cost of health care. There is one civilian hospital, the Guam Memorial Hospital, and a number of private clinics, as well as some medical facilities run for US military personnel. For emergencies dial 911.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water is chlorinated, and relatively safe to drink. Dairy products, local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe for consumption. There is, however, a risk of bio-intoxication from raw or cooked fish or shellfish.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B and tuberculosis occur; vaccination is sometimes advised. Dengue fever and Japanese encephalitis can occur in epidemics. Jellyfish may pose some threat.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Martin Luther King, Jr. Day :
							2018<br/>15 January </p><p>Presidents' Day :
							19 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Memorial Day :
							28 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							04 July </p><p>Liberation Day :
							21 July </p><p>Labour Day :
							03 September </p><p>Columbus Day :
							08 October </p><p>All Soul's Day :
							02 November </p><p>Veterans' Day :
							11 November </p><p>Thanksgiving Day :
							22 November </p><p>Lady of Camarin Day :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>See the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> section for duty-free allowances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics and deadly weapons are prohibited. The import of plants, fruit and animals is restricted and must be accompanied by the appropriate documentation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar (USD; symbol US$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of US$100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of US$1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents. For exchange rates and currency restrictions, see the <em><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a></em> section.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous US and international banks on the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major credit and charge cards are widely accepted on Guam. ATMs are available at the airport, some hotels, shopping malls and grocery stores. <em>Cirris</em>, <em>Plus</em> and <em>Star </em>allow international financial transactions.</p><p>ATMs are available at the airport, some hotels, shopping malls and grocery stores.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are accepted but avoid additional exchange rate charges, by getting them in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 1000-1500, Sat 1000-1300. Hours may vary slightly, and many mall bank outlets are open 1000-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/2</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/4</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/2/3</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/2/3</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A valid passport is required by the nationals referred to above.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<p><strong>1.</strong> US citizens are required to carry a passport. However, in certain cases, a US citizen&nbsp;may be able to enter Guam from the US mainland or a US territory with proof of citizenship and a valid photo ID card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Please see the USA passport &amp; visa section for types and costs of visas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[13.123973]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[144.694004]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>544 sq km (210 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>172,094 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>297 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hag&aring;t&ntilde;a.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US External Territory (unincorporated).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaped like a footprint, and surrounded by a coral shelf, Guam's northern end is a plateau of rolling hills and cliffs rising 152m (500ft) above sea level. The island narrows in the middle, and the expanding southern half undulates with mountains and valleys cut by streams and waterfalls. The most sheltered beaches are on the western coast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christian; 85% Roman Catholic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Western customs are the norm, although one must also keep in mind the traditions of the Japanese who make up around 90% of the island's tourists. A native practice, the 'Eyebrow,' is unique: Islanders say hello, recognize someone or build a connection simply by lifting eyebrows and jerking their head back.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. American two-pin (flat) or grounded three-pin plugs are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Governor Eddie Calvo since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Donald Trump since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guam is the largest and most southerly island of the Marianas Islands, which were occupied by the Chamorro Indians from 1500 BC. It was claimed by the Spanish in 1565 and ruled by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/madrid">Madrid</a> until the Spanish-American War of 1898. The Spanish governor was unaware of the war and, when a <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> frigate entered Hagåtña harbour with guns blazing, he apologised to the captain for not having a reciprocal salute ready. He surrendered the island the next day. <BR/><BR/>US rule was interrupted by the Japanese invasion of 1941, to be reinstated after fierce fighting three years later. The island has been an important US strategic base since then. Its facilities were provisionally earmarked for substantial expansion following the US withdrawal from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/philippines">Philippines</a>. However, the end of the Cold War and the overall retrenchment of the American military have forced the government of Guam to look to other means for its long-term future (see <I>Business Profile</I>). <BR/><BR/>Politics on the island are based on the US system: the most recent gubernatorial election in November 2010 was won by the Republican Eddie Calvo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the United States of America in the UK ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7499 9000 or 0904 245 0100. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.usembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7499 9000 or 0904 245 0100. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1730 (Only applicants with visa appointments admitted).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>24 Grosvenor Square<br/>London<br/>W1A 1AE<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guam is a vibrant, tropical paradise, complete with powdery beaches, and coral reefs teeming with underwater life. Away from the beach, find historic buildings in the bustling capital, Hagåtña, swinging nightlife in Tumon and a melting pot of Asian, European, Pacific Rim and American cultures.</p><p>Those looking to get active can lace up those walking boots and climb Mount Lam Lam, or hop on a jet ski and whizz over the surrounding crystal clear waters. Guam is the largest and most southerly island of the Marianas Islands and has been an important US strategic base since World War II.</p><p>The most populated island in Micronesia, this unincorporated US territory is full of American accents, and sadly the Chamorro language is less spoken today than it once was. Glamorous, modern Tumon Bay is where most of the hotels are, and it's pretty commercial with duty-free shopping being the order of the day.</p><p>There is much more to Guam, though. It's a thoroughly multicultural island for one thing, and Chamorro culture is starting to be pushed more than it has been in recent decades. There are many pretty villages to explore, while a singular local cuisine is being celebrated more.</p><p>If you leave Tumon Bay behind, you'll find Guam full of rustic settlements, with many immaculate, secluded beaches, and a few glorious waterfalls. Don't pass up opportunities to meet the locals on your travels, either, who are known for their charm and warmth towards visitors, and are increasingly passionate about making their traditional culture as prominent as it used to be.</p><p>The US' somewhat overbearing presence in Guam is perhaps best typified by its military base, which dominates the north of the island. Even so, the area harbours a spectacular coastline of palm trees and turquoise waters, so don't miss it.</p>Guam is a vibrant, tropical paradise, complete with powdery beaches, and coral reefs teeming with underwater life.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
