<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Guatemala" ColCode="gtm" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="gt" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Guatemala]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala&rsquo;s weather is eternally comfortable: neither too hot nor too cold. Its seasons tend to be divided into the dry season and the wet season, although the temperature,which averages 22&deg;C (72&deg;F) across the country, varies more according to altitude than by season. November through to April is the dry season and in the mountainous central region (Guatemala City, Antigua, Lake Atitlan, Chichicastenango, Cob&aacute;n and the highlands) it is an ideal climate for outdoor pursuits with average temperatures of 18&deg;C (64&deg;F). It also coincides with the festivals of Semana Santa, Day of the Dead, the Burning of the Devil and the Saint Thomas festival in Chichicastenango.</p>
<p>The rainy season runs from May to October which can hinder travel in more remote areas where roads are not well maintained, with Pet&eacute;n receiving the most amount of rainfall. In higher climes, near the centre of the country, the rainy season, running from May to September, is characterised by clear skies after abundant rainfall in the afternoons and evenings. This means that travel during this time can be extremely pleasant, with less crowds and cooler temperatures. Temperatures can fall sharply at night.</p>
<p>The coastal regions and the northeast are hot throughout the year with an average temperature of 20&deg;C (68&deg;F) sometimes rising to as much as 37&deg;C (99&deg;F), although the Pacific coast has more unpredictable weather and rain is possible year round.</p>
<p>The busiest time of the year for tourism is between December and May when the dry season and festivals mean that much of the accommodation can be booked long in advance (especially in Antigua during Semana Santa). This is also a popular time for language learning and many North Americans come to study in the schools in towns such as Antigua and Xela.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothing. Jacket or light woollens for the evening. Waterproof jacket during rainy season. Hiking boots for outdoor activities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala&rsquo;s domestic flight network is fairly limited, the main route being Guatemala City to Flores. Avianca (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.avianca.com/">www.avianca.com</a>) and TAG Airlines (<a href="http://www.tag.com.gt" target="_blank">www.tag.com.gt</a>)&nbsp;run daily flights. Except for high seasons such as Semana Santa it isn&rsquo;t necessary to book these too far in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Regular boats operate between Puerto Barrios and Livingston. There are also frequent services along the Rio Dulce, as well as on the bigger lakes, in particular between villages on Lake Atitl&aacute;n.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of travel within Guatemala is by road, and major highways connect the main cities. Most travel is by bus and the most popular are the colourful, ex-US school buses called <em>camionetas</em>, but known by visitors as chicken buses. They are cheap and efficient, but the driving conditions can be erratic, schedules somewhat flexible and conditions hot and cramped for longer journeys.</p>
<p>Ex-Greyhound buses known as Pullmans operate longer journeys between main cities, and provide a better level of comfort. Private shuttle minibuses operate on the main tourist routes.</p>r<p>There is an extensive road network and the main highway network has had a major make-over and is now in good quality. Many of the more rural roads can be poorly maintained however.</p><p>Taxis in Guatemala City are metered, and it is preferable to call one from a hotel. In other areas, be sure to negotiate the fare before setting off. Three-wheeled tuk-tuk taxis have become common, especially in smaller towns.</p><p>A national licence is valid for one to three months, but an International Driving Permit is recommended.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn at all times. Speed limits vary depending on the condition of the road but they are rarely enforced.</p><p>PROVIAL patrols the major highways (tel: 1520, in Guatemala only). Alternatively, call the police (tel: 120) or the fire brigade (tel: 123).</p><p>Travelling by car is a good way to access more remote areas but driving conditions are not for the faint-hearted. International and local car hire firms have offices in Guatemala City. Four-wheel drive vehicles are an asset.</p><p>Cycling is common and it is possible to rent mountain bikes in places such as Antigua, Panajachel and Quetzaltenango.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn at all times. Speed limits vary depending on the condition of the road but they are rarely enforced.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most Guatemalan cities are small enough to walk around, but Guatemala City and major towns have limited, but cheap regular bus services. Travellers are advised to use radio-dispatched taxis or taxis from hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main airline is Avianca (<a href="http://www.avianca.com" target="_blank">www.avianca.com</a>), which has direct flights from Guatemala City&rsquo;s La Aurora International Airport to Colombia, Costa Rica, El Salvador and Honduras, with&nbsp;connections to many US, Central and South American destinations.</p>
<p>There are regular flights from North America: United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) has daily flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/houston">Houston</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>; American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>) flies daily from Dallas Fort Worth and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a>; and Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) flies daily from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/atlanta">Atlanta</a>.</p>
<p>There are no direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>; connections are generally via the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> or with Iberia (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.iberia.com/">www.iberia.com</a>) from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/madrid">Madrid</a> direct to Guatemala City.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 15 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 5 hours 20 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For those wanting to visit the Tikal ruins, the airport in Flores has a handful of international flights with TAG Airlines (<a href="http://www.tag.com.gt" target="_blank">www.tag.com.gt</a>) to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belize-city">Belize City</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$30, usually included in the fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For those wanting to visit the Tikal ruins, the airport in Flores has a handful of international flights with TAG Airlines (<a href="http://www.tag.com.gt" target="_blank">www.tag.com.gt</a>) to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belize-city">Belize City</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Flores Mundo Maya International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 3km (2 miles) from Flores and is located one hour from the UNESCO Tikal Archaelogical Park.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>La Aurora International Airport </b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 6km (4 miles) south of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Santo Thom&aacute;s de Castilla , Puerto Quetzal and Puerto Barrios are the main ports. Further information is available from the Guatemala Port Authority (<a href="http://www.cpn.gob.gt/" target="_blank">www.cpn.gob.gt</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no passenger services in Guatemala.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are road routes into Guatemala from all its neighbours. From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico">Mexico</a> the main crossings are at Ciudad Hidalgo and Talism&aacute;n (both near Tapachula) and between Comit&aacute;n, Mexico, and Huehuetenango, Guatemala. From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/honduras">Honduras</a> the main crossing is at El Florido, which leads from Cop&aacute;n, and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/el-salvador">El Salvador</a>, it is at San Cristobal. From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belize">Belize</a> the main border crossing is at Melchor de Mencos.</p>
<p>Guatemala is on the 47,958km (29,800-mile) Pan-American  Highway. It is possible to drive across the borders in privately owned vehicles, but it is essential to take caution. Poor road conditions, limited services, crime and corrupt border crossings are all hazards. Drivers must show their original driving licence and vehicle registration papers.</p>
<p>Long-distance buses connect the main Central American and Mexican cities, and direct executive coaches are of high standard with bathrooms and air conditioning. Tica Bus Company (tel: +502 2473 3737; <a href="http://www.ticabus.com" target="_blank">www.ticabus.com</a>) has services running the length of Central America, while Pullmantur (tel: +502 2495 7000; <a href="http://www.pullmantur.com" target="_blank">www.pullmantur.com</a>) and Hedman Alas (tel: +502 2362 5072; <a href="http://www.hedmanalas.com" target="_blank">www.hedmanalas.com</a>) connect Guatemala with San Salvador, Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula. Tourist shuttle buses also run between Copan Ruinas, Honduras and Antigua, Guatemala.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Most public phone booths accept phone cards, and internet cafes are offer the best value international calls. There are no area codes in Guatemala.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. It is possible to buy cheap pay-as-you-go phones from local companies. The main ones are Tigo and Claro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The internet is widely available and Wi-Fi is common in tourist areas. Internet cafes can be found in even the smallest towns. Connection speeds to vary but in the main cities is usually fast and reliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala has a free press and journalists openly criticise government policies. However, they may face intimidation because of their reporting, such as anonymous threats. Media is dominated by privately-run outlets. Four of the country's national TV channels share the same owner and have been accused of being pro-government. The main press publications include <em>Diario Centroam&eacute;rica</em>, <em>La Hora</em>, <em>El Peri&oacute;dico</em>, <em>Prensa Libre</em>, <em>Siglo Veintiuno </em><em>and La Cronica</em>. <em>Central America Report</em> is an English-language publication. <em>Canal 3 Radio-TV Guatemala</em>,<em> Teleonce</em>,<em> Televisiete</em> and<em> Trecevisi&oacute;n </em>are Guatemala&rsquo;s main commercial television channels. <em>La Voz de Guatemala</em> is a government-owned radio station while <em>Emisoras Unidas de Guatemala</em>, <em>Radio Continental</em>, <em>Radio Nuevo Mundo</em> and<em> Radio Panamericana </em>are commercial stations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Regular airmail to Europe takes 10-14 days, and 7 days to the United States. Courier companies such as FedEx and DHL can be found in most cities.</p><p>These vary but in major cities are generally between 0800 and 1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Tikal</p><![CDATA[<p>The wonders of Guatemala's most famous archaeological site are hidden deep within the rainforest where 70m (230ft) high pyramids poke through the canopy – once home to an estimated 100,000 Maya. The UNESCO World Heritage Site contains more than 3000 structures including temples and palaces and is home to many species of wildlife including monkeys, anteaters and tapirs.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Careen through the jungle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Thrill-seekers can get their kicks with a canopy tour, which involves flying through the jungle via a series of cables. Guatemala's rainforests are the perfect place to try this adrenaline-inducing activity and there are various opportunities for canopy tours around Antigua and Tikal.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Mayan pyramids</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala's most famous archaeological site, Tikal, is hidden deep within the rainforest where 70m (230ft) high pyramids poke through the canopy. Once home to an estimated 100,000 Maya, the UNESCO World Heritage Site contains more than 3,000 structures including temples and palaces as well as many species of wildlife, among them monkeys, anteaters and tapirs.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Quetzaltenango</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Known more commonly as Xela, the city of Quetzaltenango (Guatemala's second biggest) is ringed by three towering volcanoes and shelters a predominantly Mayan population. Use it as a base to discover nearby Mayan hamlets as well as for hikes to sacred lakes, sulphur pools and cloud forests.</p>]]><p><b>Embark on a jungle adventure</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala's great outdoors are easily accessible at Ixpanpajul Nature Park. This pocket of protected subtropical rainforest is ideal for hiking, biking, horse riding and even canopy touring. You may even encounter some of the park's many feathered inhabitants or a cheeky monkey or two cavorting in the canopy alongside you.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy Caribbean costal living</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Livingston is a colourful, lively town on the Caribbean coast and exudes all the charm of its Garifuna residents. It can only be reached by boat along the Río Dulce, giving it an isolated, island feel. Thatched cabins, hammocks and rustic beachside bars and restaurants serve traditional, hearty cuisine and belt out music with a hip-swaying beat.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the highlands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the unique highlands region of Western Guatemala (known in Spanish as El Altiplano), inhabited by the greatest number of modern-day, indigenous Mayan groups – many of whom still speak the languages and uphold the sacred rituals of their ancestors. Great mountain passes and unspoilt beauty bolster the region's appeal.</p>]]><p><b>Get to know Guatemala City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Most travellers don't linger in Guatemala's sprawling, traffic-clogged capital. But if you can withstand the fumes and frenzy, there are some enticing hidden gems to uncover, including Parque Central (bordered by the National Palace and the Cathedral), the enormous relief map in Minerva Park, and the city's wonderful art and archaeology museums, specifically the National Museum of Archaeology and Ethnology.</p>]]><p><b>Hike an active volcano</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Despite a series of recent eruptions, the highly active Volcan Pacaya is still one of the most hiked volcanoes in the country. Red hot molten lava slowly pours down the summit and huge dust and lava fields create an impressive landscape. The volcano can be hiked in an afternoon with an organised tour from nearby Antigua.</p>]]><p><b>Lounge on black sands at Monterrico</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Escape to the Pacific Coast's Monterrico, which offers remote black sand beaches and a laidback atmosphere. Spot sea turtles nesting on the volcanic sand and arrange to get involved with release programmes arranged by conservation organisations. Horse riding along the beach, visiting the mangrove swamps and learning Spanish are other popular activities in this region.</p>]]><p><b>Purchase local handicrafts</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Survey superb craftsmanship throughout Guatemala at towns like Jocotenango (renowned for its ceramics) and San Antonio Aguascalientes (feted for textiles). Salamá is a good place to buy silver, clay and leather handicrafts, while Momostenango (City of Altars) is the place to go for traditional handwoven ponchos.</p>]]><p><b>See the shimmering Lake Atitlán</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the world's most ancient lakes, the glistening surface of Lake Atitlán is framed by three volcanoes: Tolimán, Atitlán and San Pedro. Go waterskiing, swimming, boating or scuba-diving and visit some of the small towns and villages that dot the shore, such as the bohemian San Pedro de la Laguna and the Mayan Panajachel.</p>]]><p><b>Shop for souvenirs at Chichicastenango Market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This mountaintop Mayan town is most famous for its colourful market. On Thursdays and Sundays, indigenous vendors pile into the main plaza and adjacent streets to sell handicrafts, textiles, food, flowers, pottery, medicinal plants, animals and household and farming items. It provides a wonderful insight into the local culture.</p>]]><p><b>Swim in the turquoise pools of Semuc Champey</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Semuc Champey Natural Park is one of Guatemala's most pristine beauty spots. Turquoise pools and waterfalls cascade down to a 300m (984 ft) limestone bridge, under which passes the Cahabón River, and activities include caving, tubing and hiking amidst the unspoilt jungle in the heart of Lanquín.</p>]]><p><b>Take to the water</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala's waterways are ideal for adventurers: Río Dulce and Lakes Izabal and Atitlán are a windsurfer's paradise, with the latter also popular for altitude diving. Fast-moving rivers, such as El Cahabón, El Chiquibul, El Motagua, La Pasión and El Usamacinta, are ideal for boating and shooting rapids, while the Cahabón River near Semuc Champey is prime tubing territory.</p>]]><p><b>Travel the Río Dulce by boat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a boat trip from Livingston along the Río Dulce, which wends its way through steep cliffs, dense vegetation and lakes to Amatique Bay. Its waterways pass through mangroves, lagoons and the natural hot springs of the Chocón Machacas Biosphere. Keep an eye out for manatees splashing about as you float along.</p>]]><p><b>Walk the cobblestone streets of Flores</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Flores, situated on an island in the middle of Lake Peten Itza, is used as the main gateway to Tikal, but the tiny town is well worth visiting in its own right. A jumble of red-roofed buildings, which houses bountiful craft shops and cafés, it is the perfect place to enjoy sunset over the lake.</p>]]><p><b>Wander colonial Antigua</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a trip to the former capital, Antigua, with its colonial buildings, huge central square and lively festivals. Despite the damage wrought by countless earthquakes, floods and fires, Antigua remains one of the country's most beautiful cities where multi-coloured, single-storey buildings, tropical gardens, plazas, fountains and cobbled streets create a postcard-perfect image.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$79.97 billion (2012).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Coffee, sugar, crude oil, clothing, fruit and vegetables.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fuel, machinery and transport equipment, grain, fertilisers and mineral and chemical products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, El Salvador, Honduras, Mexico and the EU.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala boasts the largest economy in Central America. Agriculture, prinicipally coffee, sugar cane and bananas, accounts for over 13% of GDP and 38% of the labour force. The main agricultural exports are coffee, sugar, bananas, and vegetables including non-traditional products such as cut flowers, fruit and winter vegetables.<br />
<br />
Light manufacturing and food processing, principally aimed at the domestic, US and Central American markets, also play an important role in the economy. Additionally, the government has identified tourism as a major growth sector.<br />
<br />
Guatemala's main trading partner is the USA. The two countries ratified the US-Central American Free Trade Agreement (CAFTA) in 2005. The agreement came into force in July 2006 and while it has helped improve investment, concerns over security, a lack of skilled workers and poor infrastructure still deter foreign investment in the country. <br />
<br />
Economic growth has been steady in the past few years, with annual growth reaching 3% in 2012, with an inflation rate of 3.8%. The unemployment rate was estimated as 4.1% in 2011, although more than half the country is below the national poverty line (13% of which are classified as being of extreme poverty). <br />
<br />
Guatemala has the facilities and hotel infrastructure for conventions, conferences and business meetings. The Centro Cultural Miguel Angel Asturias and other modern conference centres are available for such events, often quite close, or accessible to Guatemala's beauty spots.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guatemalan businesspeople tend to be rather formal and conservative. Normal courtesies should be observed and appointments should be made. Punctuality is appreciated and business cards can be useful.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1800, Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cámara de Comercio de Guatemala (Chamber of Commerce)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 2253 5353
					Website:http://www.negociosenguatemala.com/
					Address: Guatemala City,10A Calle 3-80,Zona 1,,]]><b>Cámara de Industria (Chamber of Industry)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 2331 9191
					Website:http://www.industriaguate.com
					Address: 01004 Guatemala City,Ruta 6,9-21,Zona 4,Edificio Cámara de Industria,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala&rsquo;s cuisine tends to have distinctive regional variations. Many of the dishes have descended from Mayan ancestry combined with Spanish and Mexican influences. The country&rsquo;s cuisine relies on the core staples of corn tortillas, black beans and white rice, which are generally served alongside meat and fish, although soups and stews also feature heavily in the local diet.</p>
<p>All dishes tend to include some meat, which makes life tough for vegetarians, but fish and seafood are found in coastal regions. Many dishes are spicy thanks to the fiery chillies, which are found in most kitchens.</p>
<p>Popular drinks include fruit juices and beer. Despite producing some of the world&rsquo;s best coffee, it&rsquo;s hard to get a decent cup; most of the good stuff is exported and local coffee tends to be served weak and sweet. Guatemalan rum, however, ranks among the best in the world.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Tamales:</strong> Corn dough stuffed with a variety of meats, fruits and nuts, and wrapped in banana leaves.<br />
<strong>Kaq ik:</strong> A turkey soup seasoned with samat, a herb from the Alta Verapaz region.<br />
<strong>Pepian:</strong> A rich, spicy stew made from chicken, beef or pork with tomatoes, tamales, peppers, chillies and tortillas.<br />
<strong>Empanadas:</strong> A Central American staple made from flour or corn pastries filled with meat and/or potatoes.<br />
<strong>Tapado:</strong> A spicy fish stew popular in the Garifuna-inhabited Caribbean coast.<br />
<strong>Caldo:</strong> A rustic stew made with beef (<em>caldo de res</em>) or chicken (<em>caldo de pollo</em>) and Guatemalan vegetables such as <em>g&uuml;icoy</em> and <em>g&uuml;isquil</em> (types of squash).<br />
<strong>Chiles rellenos:</strong> Peppers stuffed with vegetables, meat and cheese.<br />
<strong>Fiambre:</strong> Salad of pickled vegetables and cured sausage, eaten on All Saint&rsquo;s Day.<br />
<strong>Frijoles:</strong> Black refried beans &ndash; a staple in many Guatemala dishes.<br />
<strong>Guacamole:</strong> Mashed avocado with onions and spices.<br />
<strong>Flan:</strong> A wobbly custard desert that comes in several flavours including caramel, orange and coconut.<br />
<strong>Gallo:</strong> This straw-coloured lager is Guatemala&rsquo;s national beer.<br />
<strong>Licuados:</strong> Fresh fruit juices blended with water or milk to make a kind of fruit shake.<br />
<strong>Quetzalteca:</strong> An extremely potent raw cane spirit.<br />
<strong>Ron Centenario Zacapa:</strong> A locally made, award-winning rum that is internationally acclaimed.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Lunch is often eaten in a <em>comedor</em> (diner-style restaurant), which offer a <em>comida corrida</em> or <em>menúejecútivo</em> – a cheap, set-meal.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is normal in restaurants where service has not been included.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Guatemala   City in particular, there are nightclubs with modern music and dance, featuring national and international artists. Guatemala is the home of <em>marimba</em> music, which can be heard at several venues. In the cities, the <em>marimba</em> is a huge, elaborate xylophone with large drum sticks played by four to nine players. There are regular concerts throughout the country. There are also theatres with numerous plays in English and other cultural performances. Films with English and Spanish subtitles are often shown in major towns. The &ldquo;Zona Viva&rdquo; in Zone 10 in Guatemala City is the main hub of entertainment where hotels, nightclubs, cafes, bars, dance clubs, restaurants, boutiques and art galleries cluster.</p>
<p>Outside of the capital the nightlife is more low-key and bars in places such as Antigua, Flores and the villages around Lake  Atitlan such as Panajachel and San Pedro de la Laguna tend to be relaxed with a fun, lively atmosphere.&nbsp;Quetzaltenango (Xela) has a lively nightlife scene with plenty of bars and nightclubs, and in the Garifuna towns such as Livingstone local bands play traditional music combined with the ever-popular reggae.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For those in search of crafts and local products Guatemala has some of the best shopping in Central America. Markets are best for local products and are as much a sightseeing experience as a shopping one. The Central Market and Craft Market in Guatemala City, the market in Quetzaltenango, and the famous Chichicastenango market (twice weekly) are the best places to find traditional, authentic crafts and meet local artisans. The slightly bohemian, Mayan villages around Lake Atitlan are also a good place to find souvenirs and local handicrafts, as are the street vendors in Antigua and Panajachel. <br />
<br />
Craft-making in Guatemala has a long heritage and different styles and designs are produced in different regions. Textiles tend to show these regional differences the most clearly and the ornately decorated, brightly colours weaves make for superb purchases. <br />
<br />
There is so much to choose from that it is difficult to decide what to buy, but there are wonderful colourful textiles, Mayan jewellery, jade and wood carvings, leather goods, hammocks, blankets, ceramics and basketry. Ceramics can be purchased cheaply in many places including Villa de Chinautla, San Luis Jilotepeque and Rabinal. Cob&aacute;n is the cheapest place to buy silverware. <br />
<br />
Bargaining is necessary in the markets or anywhere where prices aren&rsquo;t fixed, and this should be done in a light-hearted and respectful manner. Vendors expect to haggle, so start at half the asking price and work up to an agreed price from there. <br />
<br />
Modern shopping malls can be found throughout the country, and many have international chain shops and restaurants. Guatemala City contains many modern shopping centres. Gran Centro Comercial Los Proceres, Galerias La Pradera, Plaza Cemaco and Geminis International Mall are all located in Zone 10. Other malls include Tikal Futura, Peri-Roosevelt Shopping Mall and the Century Shopping Centre.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0930-1930. Malls are also open on Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel standards, prices and facilities vary considerably throughout the country, but in general tend to be of good quality, especially in the tourist areas. There are many first-class hotels in Guatemala City, and Antigua also has a good selection of smaller, boutique hotels which offer high quality services and excellent restaurants and bars.</p>
<p>However, the majority of the country&rsquo;s hotels are small to mid-sized establishments that are comfortable and welcoming even if not brimming with mod-cons. Chichicastenango, Cob&aacute;n, Panajachel (near Lake Atitl&aacute;n), Puerto Barrios and Quetzaltenango have a reasonable selection of this type of hotel&nbsp;Elsewhere accommodation tends to be a bit more limited and rustic, although prices do reflect this. Registered hotels are required to display room rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Inexpensive guest houses are found in all the main towns and tourist areas. Guatemalan people are very hospitable and it is a good way to understand more of the local culture. Rooms tend to be comfortable but quite simple and a hearty breakfast of pancakes or eggs is common.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel standards, prices and facilities vary considerably throughout the country, but in general tend to be of good quality, especially in the tourist areas. There are many first-class hotels in Guatemala City, and Antigua also has a good selection of smaller, boutique hotels which offer high quality services and excellent restaurants and bars.</p>
<p>However, the majority of the country&rsquo;s hotels are small to mid-sized establishments that are comfortable and welcoming even if not brimming with mod-cons. Chichicastenango, Cob&aacute;n, Panajachel (near Lake Atitl&aacute;n), Puerto Barrios and Quetzaltenango have a reasonable selection of this type of hotel&nbsp;Elsewhere accommodation tends to be a bit more limited and rustic, although prices do reflect this. Registered hotels are required to display room rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel standards, prices and facilities vary considerably throughout the country, but in general tend to be of good quality, especially in the tourist areas. There are many first-class hotels in Guatemala City, and Antigua also has a good selection of smaller, boutique hotels which offer high quality services and excellent restaurants and bars.</p>
<p>However, the majority of the country&rsquo;s hotels are small to mid-sized establishments that are comfortable and welcoming even if not brimming with mod-cons. Chichicastenango, Cob&aacute;n, Panajachel (near Lake Atitl&aacute;n), Puerto Barrios and Quetzaltenango have a reasonable selection of this type of hotel&nbsp;Elsewhere accommodation tends to be a bit more limited and rustic, although prices do reflect this. Registered hotels are required to display room rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are both public and private medical facilities in Guatemala City, but state-run hospitals tend to be under-funded and can be unhygienic. Private clinics should be used where possible. Medical care outside of the capital is more limited. Comprehensive travel and medical insurance is strongly advised. Travellers should carry evidence of their insurance at all times, as doctors may be reluctant to treat them otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The tap water in Guatemala is not safe to drink and water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Bottled water is recommended. Milk may be unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The tap water in Guatemala is not safe to drink and water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Bottled water is recommended. Milk may be unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;br /&gt;Other risks: Vaccinations are sometimes advised for tuberculosis and hepatitis B. There is a risk of malaria in rural, lowland areas such as Alta Verapaz, Baja Verapaz, El Petén and San Marcos, and anti-malarial drugs should be considered. Take appropriate action to avoid getting bitten by mosquitoes, especially between dusk and dawn. Dengue fever is endemic in Guatemala, also contracted through mosquitoes. Affected areas include Escuintla, the Pacific coast towns, Zacapa and Petén. Rabies occurs; if you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay. There are also often outbreaks of cholera in the country, although this rarely affects travellers. Avoid touching animals as rabies is widespread, and in case of being bitten get medical help immediately.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Below are listed Public Holidays for the January 2014-December 2015 period.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Holy Saturday :
							31 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Army Day :
							30 June </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							15 September </p><p>Revolution Day :
							20 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Eve :
							24 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>New Year's Eve :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Guatemala by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 500g of tobacco in any form.<br />
&bull; 5L of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; 2kg of confectionery.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Meat, fish, vegetables, fruit, dairy items, unlicensed ammunition or weapons, and pornographic media or literature.</p>
<p>Plants must be accompanied by phytosanitary certificates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fruits and vegetables, Mayan artefacts (unless purchased at reputable stores with a certificate) and any products made from endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Quetzal (GTQ; symbol Q), named after the national bird of paradise. Notes are in denominations of Q200, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of Q1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 centavos. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars are widely used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Quetzal is extremely difficult to obtain outside Guatemala or exchange after leaving Guatemala, and visitors are strongly advised to exchange local currency before departure. It may be difficult to negotiate notes which are torn. Unused local currency can be exchanged at the bank at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express and Visa are accepted, whilst Diners Club and MasterCard have a more limited acceptance. ATMs are common throughout the country.</p><p>ATMs are common throughout the country, although care should be taken as there are frequent scams and robberies. It is best to use ATMs inside banks and shopping centres.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted by most banks and good hotels, although visitors may experience occasional problems. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Opening times vary, but generally Mon-Fri 0900-1900; Sat 0900-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Guatemala, a passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Children under 18 years old travelling with a valid passport do not need special permission from their parents to enter or leave Guatemala.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no transit visa for Guatemala and visitors passing through the country must obtain a tourist visa if required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry tourist visa: US$25; multiple-entry tourist visa: US$50; multiple-entry business visa: US$50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visas are valid for 90 days from the date of issue. Business visas are valid for 180 days from the date of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can apply for a two-year temporary residency visa, but the process is somewhat lengthy (up to a year) and there is a lot of paperwork involved. It is possible to apply personally but hiring a lawyer certainly speeds up the process. In addition to certified and notarised copies of travel documents, applicants need a Guatemalan guarantor.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals who do require a visa must provide proof of sufficient funds with their application.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For stays exceeding 90 days, you should apply to the General Directorate of Migration in Guatemala (<a href="http://www.migracion.gob.gt" target="_blank">www.migracion.gob.gt</a>) for an extension or you risk having to pay a fine for overstaying.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pet dogs and cats require a veterinarian health certificate, plus an import permit from the nearest Guatemalan embassy or consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[15.478030]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-90.156015]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>108,889 sq km (42,042 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>16,672,956 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>137 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala City.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional Democratic Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala is the third largest country in Central America and shares borders to the north and west with Mexico, to the southeast with El Salvador and Honduras, to the northeast with Belize and the Caribbean Sea, and to the south with the Pacific Ocean. The landscape is predominantly mountainous and heavily forested, with narrow coastal plains and tropical, humid lowlands blanketed in rainforests, coffee and banana plantations.</p>
<p>A string of volcanoes rises above the southern highlands along the Pacific, four of which are still active. Within this volcanic area are basins of varying sizes which hold the majority of the country's population. The region is drained by rivers flowing into both the Pacific and the Caribbean; however one basin west of the capital has no river outlet and thus has formed Lake Atitl&aacute;n, which is ringed by volcanoes. To the northwest, bordering on Belize and Mexico, lies the low undulating tableland of El Pet&eacute;n, 36,300 sq km (14,000 sq miles) of almost inaccessible wilderness covered with dense hardwood forest. This area covers approximately one-third of the national territory, yet contains only 40,000 people.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>About 60% of the population are Catholic. Most of the remaining population are Protestant with a smaller percentage of the population having indigenous Mayan beliefs. Some indigenous communities hold services combining Catholicism with pre-Columbian rites.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala is the most populated of the Central American republics and is the only one which is predominantly Indian, although the Spanish have had a strong influence on the way of life. Full names should be used when addressing acquaintances, particularly in business. Dress is conservative and casual wear is suitable except in the smartest dining rooms and clubs.<br /><strong><br />Photography: </strong>Locals are often suspicious of foreigners taking photographs, particularly of young children. Before approaching children for photos, or even just to talk to them, you should check with an an adult that this is acceptable. However, if you are in any doubt, refrain from doing so. You may be asked to pay a small amount of money to take photographs of both children and adults.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>115-125 volts AC, 60Hz. There are some regional variations. Plugs are the flat two-pin American type; if your plug has a third grounding pin, you'll probably need an adaptor.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Jimmy Morales since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Jimmy Morales since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala is steeped in Mayan history and many aspects of the ancient civilization have endured to this day. The Mayans were dominant through much of Central America from 2000 BC until the 15th century AD when the Europeans arrived.</p>
<p>The region was soon conquered by Spanish conquistador, Pedro de Alvarado, in 1524. It wasn&rsquo;t until the early 19th century however, that the Spanish conceded independence to their American colonies, principally Mexico, into which Guatemala was briefly incorporated in 1822.</p>
<p>Guatemala enjoyed comparative stability, punctuated by brief periods of upheaval, under a series of dictators who were content to keep the country under a quasi-feudal regime underpinned by a small clique of land-owning families.</p>
<p>The government of Colonel Arbenz Guzman attempted various land reforms in the early 1950s, but was overthrown by a US-backed invasion led by military opponents. The country then slid into a state of almost perpetual civil war between a series of right-wing military governments and various leftist guerrilla movements.</p>
<p>Guatemala&rsquo;s successful transition from military to civilian government began in 1985, when the new constitution was put into effect. The centre-right Partido Democracia Cristiana Guatemalteca (PDCG) formed the majority party in the new National Congress, staying in control until 1995 when they came up against serious challenges from the Plan por el Adelantamiento Nacional (National Advance Party, PAN), and the Frente Republicano &ndash; Guatemalteco (FRG).</p>
<p>A period of political musical chairs ended in 1995 with a FRG/PDCG coalition in control. Only then did the government admit that its predecessors, especially the Rios Montt regime, were responsible for massive human rights abuses. A UN-sponsored investigation concluded in 1999 that the army was responsible for 90% of the estimated 200,000 killings thaty occurred during the conflict. Efrain Rios Montt is currently standing trial for genocide.</p>
<p>The complicity of American governments in the counter-insurgency campaign was also highlighted, and drew an apology from US president Bill Clinton. In recent years, Guatemalan politics has continued to be plagued by scandal, and in 2015, former President Otto P&eacute;rez Molina was forced to resign after evidence surfaced of his involvement in a customs corruption ring.</p>
<p>Widespread distrust of the political establishment led to the election of former TV comedian and first-time politician Jimmy Morale, who has promised to stamp out corruption. Just how he will go about that remains unclear.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; The name Guatemala is derived from an Indian phrase meaning &lsquo;land of trees&rsquo;.<br />
&bull; Though Spanish is the official language, it isn&rsquo;t the only one: there are at least 21 Mayan languages, a couple of non-Mayan indigenous languages and Garifuna, which is spoken by communities on the Caribbean coast.<br />
&bull; Despite its relatively small size, Guatemala is home to 33 volcanoes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Guatemala in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7351 3042</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://reinounido.minex.gob.gt</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7351 3042</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>13 Fawcett Street, West Brompton<br/>London<br/>SW10 9HN<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Guatemala in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 745 4952. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://guatemalaembassyusa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 745 4952. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2220 R Street<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guatemala humbly has it all: from colonial towns to Mayan ruins, great mountain lakes to vibrant religious festivals, sandy beaches to exotic jungles. Often visitors to the country find they leave enlightened; civilisations they believed long gone are found thriving, Tomb Raider landscapes they thought fantasy are shown to be real.</p>
<p>Antiquity is at the heart of Guatemala, and the country is home to many spectacular Mayan archaeological sites, most significantly the vast UNESCO World Heritage Site of Tikal, where great towers peep through the rainforest canopy and monkeys swing past the sprawling ancient plazas. The pine-forested hills of the highlands are home to many Mayan communities, whose indigenous beliefs, traditional dress, religious practices and craftsmanship, flourish. Indeed, Guatemala has around 21 different ethnic groups, speaking some 23 languages giving it a distinctive culture like nowhere else in the region.</p>
<p>Although Guatemala boasts some truly stunning cities &ndash; most notably Antigua, an upmarket colonial town surrounded by smouldering volcanoes &ndash; Guatemala&rsquo;s real joy is its nature. The great Lake Atitlan in the highlands is a place of rare beauty and offers various adventure activities ranging from scuba diving to fishing.</p>
<p>On the other side of the country, the vast and remote region of Peten houses the country&rsquo;s thickest jungle, home to long-abandoned Mayan ruins that few get to see. Elsewhere, gargantuan lakes, lava-oozing volcanoes, black sandy beaches, natural hot springs and roaring rivers combine to form the most geographically diverse destination in Central America.</p>
<p>Though consistently beautiful, Guatemala is a nation of contrasts; a place where Catholic churches exist alongside Mayan temples, where rugged highlands give way to tropical jungles, and where the legacy of its ancient civilisations is as evident as its modern, Latin American culture.</p>
<p>Despite stories of high crime rates and volatile politics, most visitors encounter nothing but warmth and hospitality from its people, as well as epic landscapes that make them wonder why they didn&rsquo;t visit sooner.</p><p>Guatemala humbly has it all: from colonial towns to Mayan ruins, great mountain lakes to vibrant religious festivals, sandy beaches to exotic jungles. Often visitors to the country find they leave enlightened; civilisations they believed long gone are found thriving, Tomb Raider landscapes they thought fantasy are shown to be real.</p>
<p>Antiquity is at the heart of Guatemala, and the country is home to many spectacular Mayan archaeological sites, most significantly the vast UNESCO World Heritage Site of Tikal, where great towers peep through the rainforest canopy and monkeys swing past the sprawling ancient plazas. The pine-forested hills of the highlands are home to many Mayan communities, whose indigenous beliefs, traditional dress, religious practices and craftsmanship, flourish.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
