<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Guinea" ColCode="gin" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="gn" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Guinea]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is tropical and humid with a wet and a dry season. Guinea is one of the wettest countries in West Africa. The monsoon season with a southwesterly wind lasts from June to November; The dry season with a northeasterly <em>harmattan</em> lasts from December to May.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical wear, lightweight and natural fabrics throughout the year. A light raincoat or umbrella is needed during the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parts of Guinea's railway network have been upgraded, but the only passenger service is the Conakry Express, a commuter service in the capital.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>The roads between Conakry (via Kindia) and Kissidougou and from Bok&eacute; to Kamsar are both paved. However, many roads are in poor condition and the minor roads are often overgrown with bush.&nbsp;Livestock and pedestrians create road hazards, so extra caution is to be taken while driving at night.</p>
<p>Travel by road is often impossible in the rainy season (May to October). Expect to encounter checkpoints throughout the country; bribes are often expected.</p><p>These are available, although fares should be negotiated in advance. Bush taxis usually cover smaller distances than buses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guinea has no public transport but there are local vans which pick people up along many routes. Buses and taxis operate cheaply within Conakry, but are poorly maintained and tend to be overcrowded.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating flights to Guinea include Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) from Paris and Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>) from Casablanca. Both offer connecting flights from London and New York.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 8 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 18 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Conakry International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 15km (10 miles) southwest of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Areas around international border crossings often have a substantial military presence, and it can take some time to travel between countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The communication is relatively poor and outgoing international calls must be made through the operator. Limited telephone and fax lines are usually available 1800-0600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several mobile phone operators. No roaming agreements have been declared.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes are available in Conakry and Souleyman.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous post offices in the capital.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask on an island beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Îles de Los, off the Kaloum Peninsula some 10km (6 miles) southwest of Conakry, are easily accessible by boat from the capital. Good beaches can also be found at the Île de Roume and Île de Kassa. They make a popular daytrip for people escaping the city at the weekends.</p>]]><p><b>Find the source of the Niger River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An expedition to the source of the Niger makes an interesting excursion from Faranah. The mighty river flows from Foroknia north to Bamako. If you want to seek the source, it's best to take a local guide on this adventure as the area is sacred to some local people and should be traversed sensitively.</p>]]><p><b>Haggle for handicrafts</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Not far from Conakry is the town of Kindia, renowned for its quality cloth and weaving. Visitors can stop by an indigo dyeing centre and make some purchases at the cloth market in the centre of town. In another nearby town, Katikan, open-air markets sell a range of handicrafts.</p>]]><p><b>Hike in the hills</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Known as the land of fruit, faith and freedom, the Fouta Djalon highlands are renowned for their picturesque hills, which offer superb views and are ideal for hiking. The highest point is Mount Loura at 1,515m (4,970ft). Mamou, a nearby town, has some good facilities and excellent street food.</p>]]><p><b>Learn the secrets of the Kakimbon Caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Kakimbon Caves in the village of Ratoma, now a suburb of Conakry, are the source of many interesting legends and are bestowed with great religious significance by the local Baga people. With a local guide it is possible to explore the caves and learn their legends.</p>]]><p><b>Party like a local in Faranah</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If Guinea has a party town, it's probably Faranah. When the sun sets, this town buzzes with people frequenting the area's many cafes and restaurants. Its great mosque, villas, boulevards and markets also make this an interesting stop for visitors.</p>]]><p><b>Spot some wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are no national parks in Guinea, but wildlife can be observed in the northeast savannahs between the Tinkisso River and the Mali border, in the foothills of the Fouta Djalon highlands and in the southeast of the country. Forest elephants and chimpanzees live in Guinea, but wildlife is under threat from mining, logging and the bush meat trade.</p>]]><p><b>Take in some culture in the capital, Conakry</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Conakry is located on the island of Tumbo and is connected to the Kaloum Peninsula by a pier. The botanical gardens, with impressive Kapok trees, are worth a visit. The Cathedral, built in the 1930s, is also well worth viewing. The National Museum, houses a collection of masks, statues and musical instruments. The Palais du Peuple is a large, Chinese-built auditorium home to two ballet troupes.</p>]]><p><b>Watch a waterfall</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Approximately 150km (93 miles) outside Conakry is the picturesque Le Voile de la Mariée. Amid lush vegetation the River Sabende plunges over a 70m-high (229ft) rock into a deep pond. Also worth visiting is the lofty Kinkon Falls in Pita, between Dalaba and Labé, which are most impressive in the rainy season between May and October.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$3.4 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Aluminium, gold, diamonds, coffee, fish, bauxite and agricultural products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, metals, transport equipment, textiles and grain.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Côte d'Ivoire, USA, Cameroon, China, Korea (Rep) and Russia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Given its resources, Guinea should not be suffering its current impoverished condition in which the annual per capita income is US$363 (2005). The majority of the population is engaged in subsistence agriculture, producing cassava and rice as staples, plus fruit, palm, groundnuts and sometimes coffee as cash crops. Fisheries have undergone major growth in the last 10 years.<br /><br />The main part of the industrial economy is mining. Guinea has huge reserves of bauxite (perhaps one-quarter of the world's total) which account for more than 90% of export earnings; there are also substantial diamond deposits. Guinea also boasts massive hydroelectric power potential, some of which has been tapped.<br /><br />The country's economic progress has, however, been hampered by the absence of the necessary legal, corporate and governmental machinery, allied to corruption and maladministration. For the time being, Guinea will continue to depend on substantial foreign aid, principally from France, although it is also deriving growing benefit from burgeoning regional co-operation: Cameroon, for example, processes much Guinean bauxite ore to produce aluminium.<br /><br />Guinea is a member of both the Mano River Union (withLiberia and Sierra Leone) and of the Gambia River Development Organisation (with The Gambia and Senegal). The country is also a member of the West African economic community, ECOWAS. <br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Appointments should be made in advance. Lightweight suits and ties are worn by some business visitors, but these are not essential. A knowledge of French is helpful.<br /></p><p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1630, Fri 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce d'Industrie et d'Agriculture de Guinée</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 454 516,454 517
					Website:
					Address: ,BP 545,Conakry,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Restaurants, except in the capital where Western-style food is available, generally serve local dishes. Most commonly Guinean food is rice and sauce, which may include pieces of meat or fish or both. Food can be eaten with a spoon or with your hands and is sometimes served in one big bowl for everyone to share.</p>
<p>Larger hotels, mostly in the capital, have reasonable restaurants where a wide variety of alcoholic beverages are served. Conakry has several French p&acirc;tisseries selling coffee and cakes. The lively bars and club in Conakry mostly don't get going until the small hours.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Jollof rice: </strong>Cooked with palm oil, tomato paste and onions. Often served with vegetables, meat or fish.<br />
<strong>FouFou:</strong> A sticky white mass made with cassava flour usually eaten with your hands as an accompaniment to soup.<br />
<strong>Cassava leaf sauce:</strong> A dark green sauce made from chopped cassava leaves, which may contain meat, fish or both, is served with rice.<br />
<strong>Potato leaf sauce:</strong> Similar to cassava leaf sauce but made with the leaves of sweet potato plants.<br />
<strong>Groundnut sauce:</strong> A sweet and spicy peanut based sauce that might include meat or fish served with rice.<br />
<strong>Yassa chicken:</strong> Common in other parts of West Africa too, this is chicken cooked in a sauce made with onions and tomatoes.<br />
<strong>Fried plantain: </strong>Delicious sweet pieces of plantain deep-fried. Usually served as a side dish.<br />
<strong>Patates:</strong> Fried sweet potatoes served as a roadside snack.<br />
<strong>Smoked fish:</strong> Usually served with various sauces (made from peanuts, okra or tomatoes) and rice.<br />
<strong>Ginger Drink: </strong>A very refreshing juice made from fresh ginger, lime and sugar.<br />
<strong>Jus de Bissap:</strong> A juice made with dried hibiscus flowers and sugar.<br />
<strong>Palm wine:</strong> It is commonly made in rural areas and best served fresh. Alcohol levels depend on how long it has been left to ferment.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>At smarter places a 10% service charge may be included in the bill. If not a small tip would be much appreciated.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although there are theatres, nightclubs and cinemas, Guineans prefer to make their own entertainment. In the streets people can often be seen gathered together to dance, sing and play traditional musical instruments or home-made guitars. Conakry is a dynamic centre for music and the singing of the Kindia people is renowned. There is also an open air <strong>cinema</strong> in the small town of Mamou.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although department stores in the major cities are poorly stocked, local markets sell a unique display of goods. Special purchases include brightly coloured, distinctive Guinean clothes, woodcarvings, leather rugs in bold black-and-white designs, skins, locally-produced records, calabashes and jewellery. Gueckedou is well known for its enormous market where travellers can buy absolutely anything.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Conakry there are a few fairly expensive hotels of a good standard. In addition, the city centre also has a number of good-value hotels with basic, but adequate, facilities. Outside the city centre, accommodation gets sparser, but there are hotels available, for instance in Labé, Katikan, Kindia and Dalaba. Visitors are advised to book in advance and obtain written confirmation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are available in most of the major towns; enquire locally.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Conakry there are a few fairly expensive hotels of a good standard. In addition, the city centre also has a number of good-value hotels with basic, but adequate, facilities. Outside the city centre, accommodation gets sparser, but there are hotels available, for instance in Labé, Katikan, Kindia and Dalaba. Visitors are advised to book in advance and obtain written confirmation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Conakry there are a few fairly expensive hotels of a good standard. In addition, the city centre also has a number of good-value hotels with basic, but adequate, facilities. Outside the city centre, accommodation gets sparser, but there are hotels available, for instance in Labé, Katikan, Kindia and Dalaba. Visitors are advised to book in advance and obtain written confirmation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is essential. Travel insurance which covers travellers for repatriation to their country is advisable. There are rudimentary medical, dental and optical facilities in Conakry. Medical facilities are poorly equipped and extremely limited. Some private facilities provide a better range of treatment options, but are still well below global standards. There are no ambulance or rescue emergency services available. Doctors and hospitals expect immediate cash payment for health services.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Diarrhoeal diseases are common. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Hepatitis C and E are widespread. Hepatitis B is hyperendemic. Epidemics of meningococcal disease may occur, particularly in the savannah areas and during the dry season. Dengue fever and tuberculosis both occur. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							02 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Guinea without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 1,000 cigarettes or 250 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of alcoholic beverage (opened).<br />
&bull; A reasonable quantity of perfume.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guinea Franc (GNF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of GNF5,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of GNF25, 10, 5 and 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels will accept some foreign currencies in payment. Inter-bank fund transfers are frequently difficult, if not impossible, to accomplish.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Limited acceptance. Guinea has a cash economy. ATMs are not available.</p><p>ATMs are not available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Euros. These are only accepted in some banks and hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1230 and 1430-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Guinea, a valid passport is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: US$160; multiple-entry visa: US$320.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: up to six months; multiple-entry visa: up to a year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas usually take up to three days to process. You can pay twice the usual fee for a same-day or next-day service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[10.967005]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-10.921974]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>245,857 sq km (94,926 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>12,947,122 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>47.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Conakry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Republic of Guinea is located in West Africa and bordered to the northwest by Guinea-Bissau, the north by Senegal and Mali, the east by C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire, the south by Liberia and the southwest by Sierra Leone. Guinea's many rivers supply water to much of West Africa. The River Niger flows north from the southern highlands into Mali before turning south again through Niger and Nigeria. The coastal plain is made up of mangrove swamps, while inland are the Fouta Djalon hills which form several distinct ranges and plateaux over the whole of western Guinea. In the northeast, savannah plains of the Sahel region stretch into Mali. To the south are mountains known as the Guinea Highlands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the population are Muslim, with animist and Christian minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although Muslim customs are less strict than in the Arab world, beliefs and traditions should be respected by tourists. Casual dress is acceptable. Street crime is relatively common. It is important to greet people and ask them how they are before starting a conversation. Guineans always use titles when addressing others, so the visitor should do likewise (Monsieur, Madame, Mademoiselle etc). <strong>Photography:</strong> A permit (applied for in advance) has to be obtained from the <em>Ministère de l'Intérieur et de la Sécurité</em> when photographing Government buildings, military and transportation facilities or public works. It is inadvisable to photograph buildings at present, and visitors should always ask local people if they want to photograph them.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Ibrahima Kassory Fofana since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Alpha Cond&eacute; since 2010.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Modern Guinea formed part of the Ghana Empire and was then incorporated into the <a href="http://i/mali">Mali</a> Empire, which dominated the region between the 13th and 15th centuries. Portuguese explorers arrived during the mid-15th century and over the next 300 years they, along with the British and the French, made Guinea the centre of a major slave trade.</p>
<p>In 1849, the French declared the Boke region a French protectorate. Then in 1895, the French incorporated the Boke province, the heart of the Guinea republic today, along with adjacent territory, into French West Africa. The region was a single entity comprised mostly of modern-day francophone West Africa, and governed from Dakar.</p>
<p>After the departure of the French political power was assumed by the Democratic Party of Guinea-African Democratic Rally. By 1983, the regime's extreme mismanagement and repressive behaviour had driven an estimated two million people into exile. When the president, Sekou Tour&eacute;, died in 1984 the army immediately seized power in a bloodless coup led by Colonel Lansana Cont&eacute;.</p>
<p>The Cont&eacute; government straight away set about improving badly damaged political and economic links with its West African neighbours. In 1989 Cont&eacute; unveiled plans for a gradual move towards democratic government. Presidential elections were held in 1993 and won by Cont&eacute;.</p>
<p>In February 1996, Cont&eacute; survived an attempted coup, after which he assumed personal control of the country's armed forces. Cont&eacute; was elected for a third term as President in December 2003 (after first holding a referendum in 2001 that officially removed the two-term limit on presidency). He remained in power until his death in 2008 after which Moussa Dadis Camera seized power in a coup and declared himself the head of a military junta.</p>
<p>In 2009 soldiers brutally attacked a protest killing 157 people and raping women in the streets. Later that year Camera was shot in the head in an assassination attempt and flown out of the country for medical care.</p>
<p>Elections were eventually held in 2010 and won by Alpha Conde. Conde survived a coup attempt in 2011 and was re-elected in 2015.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; The jazz band, Bembeya Jazz National, formed in Guinea after independence and became world-renowned for their Afrobeat rhythms.<br />
&bull; Guinea was the only former French protectorate, which refused to join the French Community on independence.<br />
&bull; There are 24 different ethnic groups in Guinea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Republic of Guinea in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>020 7316 1861.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>020 7316 1861.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1200 (lodge applications) and Mon-Fri 1400-1500 (visa collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>258 Belsize Road<br/>London<br/>NW6 4BT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Guinea in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 986 4300.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://guineaembassyusa.com/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 986 4300.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0930-1600&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2112 Leroy Place<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so Guinea might not be the stuff bucket lists are made of. Tarnished by the Ebola crisis and long-term political instability, it is a country most people stay away from. But for travellers who like being far, far from the beaten track, Guinea has many enticements.</p>
<p>A land of remote hills, virgin rainforests and plunging waterfalls, this wild, West African nation is home to some mesmerising landscapes. If you like to immerse yourself in Mother Nature, you&rsquo;ll love Guinea.</p>
<p>But don&rsquo;t expect an easy time of it. The country has been mired in political instability and outbreaks of violence, and it was here that the first person died from Ebola in 2014. It is also an exceptionally poor country and beyond the capital, Conakry, it is not an easy place to travel: corruption is rife and the ubiquitous military checkpoints intimidating.</p>
<p>Conakry is a lot of fun, though. The city has a lively nightlife and a reasonable number of international standard restaurants serving predominantly French cuisine. Its hotel scene is hardly blazing a trail &ndash; accommodation ranges from small guesthouses to slightly run down international chains &ndash; but the city has a certain charm.</p>
<p>If chaotic Conakry wears you thin, hop on a ferry to Iles de Los, a small archipelago floating just off the coast. The antitheses to the bustling capital, these islands are blessed with clean sandy beaches, simple guesthouses and a relaxed vibe, which feels a world away from Conakry.</p>
<p>Beyond the capital Guinea is rarely visited by tourists due to the difficulty in getting around. Public transport is crowded, uncomfortable and slow, but avoids hassle from police officers, which you are likely to attract if driving your own car.</p>
<p>Guinea certainly isn&rsquo;t for everyone, but those with a curious mind and sense of adventure will be richly rewarded.</p><p>Okay, so Guinea might not be the stuff bucket lists are made of. Tarnished by the Ebola crisis and long-term political instability, it is a country most people stay away from. But for travellers who like being far, far from the beaten track, Guinea has many enticements.</p>
<p>A land of remote hills, virgin rainforests and plunging waterfalls, this wild, West African nation is home to some mesmerising landscapes. If you like to immerse yourself in Mother Nature, you&rsquo;ll love Guinea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
