<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Guinea Bissau" ColCode="gnb" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="gw" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Guinea-Bissau]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is tropical, with a wet season from June to October. The dry season is from December to April, with hot winds from the interior. Humidity is high from July to September. Temperatures vary with altitude and distance from the coast.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical lightweight cotton clothes and raincoat for the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most towns are accessible by ship. Riverboats can reach almost all areas; there are ferries from Bissau, Bolama, Bubaque Island, Catio and Enyud&eacute; (often irregular owing to tides) and Bissau to Bafat&aacute;, calling at smaller towns en route. Coast-hopping ferries go from the north coast to Bissau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Road quality is poor, as are driving standards. During the rainy season (June to October), some roads can become impassable. Avoid driving at night.</p>r<p>There are local and long-distance taxis and buses (the latter offer limited services).</p><p>An International Driving Permit is recommended, although it is not legally required. A temporary driving licence is available from local authorities on presentation of a valid UK driving licence.</p><p>Expensive and limited to Bissau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>) flies to Guinea-Bissau from Casablanca and offers connections from London and New York.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 8 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a href="new-york-city">New York</a> - 28 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Osvaldo Vieira International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 11km (7 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main port:&nbsp;</strong>Bissau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Outgoing international calls must go through the operator. It is difficult to find public telephones or to receive international calls. Telephone services are also expensive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some networks operate. No roaming agreements have been announced yet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Very limited Internet access is available in Bissau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since the overthrow of Kumba Yala in 2003, the media scene has been less repressive. The lack of a reliable power supply is still a problem. Private radio stations operate alongside the state-run broadcaster. There are few private newspapers, essentially due to financial constraints rather than to Government interference.<strong><br /></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a limited postal service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Camp on an uninhabited island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go really off the beaten track to the Bijagós archipelago, a group of small islands that are largely uninhabited and rarely visited by foreigners. With a bit of negotiation you can arrange boat transport and find yourself camping on a deserted beach.</p>]]><p><b>Catch a glimpse of a chimpanzee</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Cantanhez Natural Park in Jemberem, a community-based conservation project established to protect birds, monkeys and chimpanzees (although there is some debate as to whether they are actually present in the country or not). You can arrange a guided tour through the local chief.</p>]]><p><b>Celebrate Carnival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Every year in February or early March, Guinea-Bissau celebrates Carnival with street dancing and processions. It is a good opportunity to see the ethnic diversity of the country displayed through different groups of costumed dancers and musicians. The locals certainly know how to throw a party.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a beautiful beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Feeling adventurous and yearning for sandy shores? Then make tracks for the town of Varela, on the border with Senegal. The journey there requires bumping along a 50km-long (31mile) dirt road from São Domingos, but it is well worth it when you finally reach this slice of paradise. There is a small hotel offering good food, a beautiful beach, a pine forest and very few tourists.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Bissau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the relaxed atmosphere and faded glory of Bissau, the capital. There are plenty of cafes from which to sit with a coffee and watch the world go by. The Portuguese quarter, with its winding streets and colourful Mediterranean-style houses, is a fine place to while away a lazy afternoon.</p>]]><p><b>Go deep-sea fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The unspoiled island of Bubaque, also in the Bijagós archipelago, is accessible by ferry from Bissau and offers accommodation. Fishing is a popular activity for visitors and it is possible to catch tarpon and barracuda.</p>]]><p><b>Spot a saltwater hippo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Orango island, also in the Bijagós archipelago, is home to what is thought to be West Africa's largest population of marine hippos. Take a boat trip to Anor lagoon and with luck you can see the rare hippos. There is an eco-lodge on the island or camping can be arranged.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in time in Cacheu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It was in Cacheu that Francis Drake and John Hawkins fought against the Portuguese in 1567. The small square fortress on the river dating from the 16th Century was restored in 2004 and contains some well-preserved guns.  The town is picturesque and is a good place to enjoy sunsets over the water.</p>]]><p><b>Visit a turtle nesting site</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Joao Vieira-Poilao Islands Marine National Park, which can be found in the Bijagós archipelago, is an important nesting site for green turtles. Hawksbill, leatherback and olive ridley turtles are also present here. There are various campaigns to give more protection to turtles in Guinea-Bissau – join the good fight.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the ruins of Guinea-Bissau’s original capital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the easier islands to reach in the Bijagós archipelago is Boloma, the original capital of Guinea-Bissau. There are some attractive ruins and several good beaches to see here. There is no accommodation but, if you have your own kit, camping is possible.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$329 million (2006).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cashew nuts, shrimp, peanuts, palm kernals and sawn lumber.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, machinery and transport equipment and petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>India, China, EU, Uruguay and Senegal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rice is the staple food in this poor, largely subsistence economy. The main cash crops are groundnuts, cashew nuts and palm kernels. Timber is the only significant industry. An attempt to revive cotton production has received EU assistance; sugar refining and fishing have also undergone major development. Planned developments of oil and bauxite deposits have not progressed as far as had been hoped.<br /><br />Guinea-Bissau is a member of the West African Economic Community (ECOWAS) and joined the CFA Franc Zone in May 1997. Since then, the country has been recovering from internal conflicts which cut economic output by up to one-third and damaged much of the country's already limited infrastructure. In the short term, Guinea-Bissau will continue to rely on large quantities of foreign aid, of which it is among the highest per capita recipients in the world. <br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits are advised. A knowledge of Portuguese is useful as only a few executives speak English. Visits during Ramadan should be avoided.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b/><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Guinea-Bissau's few hotels and restaurants offer excellent food, though some places are expensive. The food in Guinea-Bissau is African in nature but has been influenced by the Portuguese. Rice is a staple near the coast and in the interior staples are cassava, yams and maize. Generally the seafood is very good. Cashew nuts are abundant and grown for export.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Jollof rice:</strong> Rice cooked with palm oil, tomato paste and onions, to which other vegetables and meat or fish are added.<br />
<strong>Egusi soup:</strong> Soup thickened with the ground seeds of squashes. It usually contains green vegetables and sometimes tomatoes and onions.<br />
<strong>Yassa chicken:</strong> Common across West Africa, this dish features chicken cooked in an onion and tomato sauce.<br />
<strong>Fried cassava:</strong> Deep-fried yucca or cassava makes a tasty treat.<br />
<strong>Fish stew:</strong> A Portuguese inspired dish of seafood in a salty broth.<br />
<strong>Avocados with tuna:</strong> A salad of avocado, tuna and tomatoes.<br />
<strong>Grilled prawns:</strong> Particularly common by the coast.<br />
<strong>Ravias:</strong> Portuguese inspired cinnamon cookies, often sold in bakeries.<br />
<strong>Cashew nuts:</strong> Delicious and plentiful in season, sometimes made into juice.<br />
<strong>Cana de cajeu:</strong> Rum made from the fruit of the cashew.<br />
<strong>Palm wine:</strong> Commonly made in rural areas. Alcohol levels depend on how long it has been left to ferment. It tastes better than it smells.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is an acceptable amount, although not encouraged.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>None specified.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Locally-made artefacts and carvings can be found in the markets. There are also some modern shops in Bissau.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1230 and 1430-1830.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A range of hotels is on offer, some of international standard and others that are small and inexpensive. Accommodation should be booked in advance. Tariffs are liable to change at any time, therefore confirmation of booking is essential.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A range of hotels is on offer, some of international standard and others that are small and inexpensive. Accommodation should be booked in advance. Tariffs are liable to change at any time, therefore confirmation of booking is essential.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A range of hotels is on offer, some of international standard and others that are small and inexpensive. Accommodation should be booked in advance. Tariffs are liable to change at any time, therefore confirmation of booking is essential.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are extremely limited and medicines often unavailable. Doctors and hospitals often expect immediate cash payment for health services. Health insurance covering repatriation is essential. Most doctors work in the public service and have their private clinic in the afternoon and evening. There are few specialists. Several foreign aid agencies have their own doctor and medical facilities, including the French Mission and the Swedish Embassy. There is also a UN clinic. All these clinics will receive visitors in an emergency, but none have surgical facilities.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Diarrhoeal diseases are common. Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Hepatitis E is widespread. Hepatitis B is hyperendemic; vaccination is sometimes recommended. Tuberculosis occurs. Epidemics of meningococcal disease may occur, particularly in the savannah areas and between December and June. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given above are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Korité, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Many restaurants are closed during the day and there may be restrictions on smoking and drinking. Some disruption may continue into Korité itself. Korité and Tabaski may last anything from two to 10 days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods can be imported into Guinea-Bissau without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; A reasonable quantity of tobacco products.<br />
&bull; A reasonable quantity of perfume in opened bottles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFA (<em>Communauté Financière Africaine</em>) Franc (XOF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of XOF10,000, 5,000, 2,500, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of XOF250, 100, 50, 25, 10 and 5.<br /><br />Guinea-Bissau is part of the French Monetary Area. Only currency issued by the <em>Banque des Etats de l'Afrique de l'Ouest</em> (Bank of West African States) is valid; currency issued by the <em>Banque des Etats de l'Afrique Centrale</em> (Bank of Central African States) is not. The CFA Franc is tied to the Euro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US currency in small denominations is the most useful for exchange. Inter-bank fund transfers are frequently difficult and time-consuming to accomplish.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted in the capital, but very limited use outside of Bissau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are rarely accepted. They can sometimes be cashed at banks. There is a fixed rate of commission on all transactions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0730-1430.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Guinea-Bissau, a passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>
<p>A yellow fever vaccination certificate is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay single-entry visa: &euro;61.45; three-month multiple-entry visa: &euro;70.45; six-month multiple-entry visa: &euro;88.32; one-year multiple-entry visa: &euro;100. All visas also incur a &euro;2.50 transaction fee.</p>
<p>If you obtain a visa from the embassy in Senegal, the fee is reported to be XOF20,000 (approximately &euro;30) for a double-entry 30-day visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: 30 days; multiple-entry visa: up to one year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). For UK travellers, the nearest consulate is in Paris. It's also possible to obtain a visa at Guinea-Bissau's embassies in Portugal or neighbouring countries such as Senegal.</p>
<p>You may also be able to apply for an e-visa at <a href="http://www.rgb-visa.com" target="_blank">www.rgb-visa.com</a>, although the service is reported to be unreliable.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[11.903983]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-15.162975]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>36,125 sq km (13,948 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,888,429 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>47.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bissau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guinea-Bissau (formerly Portuguese Guinea) is located in West Africa, and is bordered to the north by Senegal and to the south and east by the Republic of Guinea. It encompasses the adjacent Bijag&oacute;s Islands and the island of Bolama. The country rises from a coastal plain broken up by numerous inlets through a transitional plateau to mountains on the border with Guinea. Thick forest and mangrove swamp cover the area nearest to the Atlantic Ocean. Savannah covers the inland areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mainly animist and Muslim. There is a small minority of Roman Catholics and other Christians.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Casual wear is widely accepted. Social customs should be respected, particularly in Muslim areas. Petty thievery and pickpocketing are increasingly common, particularly at the airport, in markets and at public gatherings. Homosexuality is illegal.<br /><br /><strong>Photography:</strong> Visitors should request permission from security personnel before photographing military or police installations.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Limited electricity supply on 220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Aristides Gomes&nbsp;since April 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Jos&eacute; M&aacute;rio Vaz since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guinea-Bissau was carved from Portuguese-occupied West Africa in 1886, after an agreement between colonial powers to fix boundaries in the region. The Portuguese had been present since the mid-15th century and had established a substantial slave trade.</p>
<p>The territory was administered jointly with Cape Verde until 1879, after which it was treated as a separate entity and known as Portuguese Guinea until independence.&nbsp;Guinea-Bissau suffered a protracted war of independence (1963-1974), led on the rebel side by Amilcar Cabral, a highly respected figure inside the country, who was supported by Cuba.</p>
<p>In 1974 a military coup in Portugal, itself partly the result of heavy losses sustained by the army in Guinea-Bissau, brought about a sudden withdrawal of the colonial authorities.</p>
<p>The newly independent country functioned as a one-party state for the next 25 years with Joao Vieira, leader of the African Party for the Independence of Guinea and Cape Verde (PAIGC), at the helm.</p>
<p>In 1994 the government began a process of political reform, which led to multi-party elections. The PAIGC secured a clear majority in the National People's Assembly and Vieira secured the presidency.&nbsp;The Vieira administration was unable to tackle the country's poor and worsening economic situation. It also became embroiled in disputes with Senegal over territorial waters and alleged support for secessionist rebels in the Senegalese region of Casamance.</p>
<p>The Casamance guerrillas' main supporter in Guinea-Bissau was Brigadier Ansumane Mane, a politically ambitious officer who in 1998 staged a rebellion against his own government. Vieira survived the attempted coup, but in 1999 Mane finally took power. From this point onwards the history becomes one of coup and counter coup.</p>
<p>Elections took place six months later, and the PAIGC lost to the Party for Social Renewal (PRS), led by Kumba Yala. But he was also incapable of tackling the country's enormous problems and was overthrown by the military in 2003.</p>
<p>In 2005, Joao Vieira, the former military ruler toppled in the 1999 rebellion, returned from exile in Portugal and was re-elected president only to be killed in a coup in 2009.&nbsp;Yet another coup followed in 2012 when Manuel Serifo Nhamadjo was installed as interim president. Jose Mario Vaz was elected President in May 2014 while the people of Guinea-Bissau hoped for stability.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Portuguese is the official language, but a kind of Creole, which developed during the slave trade, is more widely spoken.<br />
&bull; Guinea-Bissau made its Olympic debut in the 1996 Atlanta Games competing in wrestling.<br />
&bull; Guinea-Bissau has one of the worst drug trafficking problems in Africa and is used as a staging point for cocaine between South America and Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the UK in Senegal]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+221 33 823 26 66</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-dakar</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+221 33 823 26 66</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon &amp;ndash; Thu 0800 &amp;ndash; 1630; Fri 0800 &amp;ndash; 1230&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>20, rue Docteur Guillet<br/>Dakar<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of France in Guinea-Bissau]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+245 955 393 280</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://gw.ambafrance.org/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+245 955 393 280</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Bairro de Penha - Avenida Combatente of Liberdade of Patria<br/>Bissao<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Guinea-Bissau in France]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+33 1 48 78 36 69</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.diplomatie.gouv.fr/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+33 1 48 78 36 69</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1300, 1430-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>94 Rue Saint-Lazare<br/>Paris<br/>75009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Guinea-Bissau in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(301) 947 3958.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(301) 947 3958.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>P.O. Box 33813<br/>Washington<br/>20033<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the United States of America in Senegal]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+221 33 879 40 00</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://sn.usembassy.gov/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+221 33 879 40 00</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon &amp;ndash; Thu 0800 &amp;ndash; 1730; Fri 0800 &amp;ndash; 1300&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>B.P. 49, Route des Almadies<br/>Dakar<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Though better known for its military coups and government crises, Guinea-Bissau&rsquo;s swashbuckling charm, faded grandeur and stunning natural assets prove some things are above politics.</p>
<p>Sandwiched between Senegal and Guinea, this diminutive nation has a decidedly Latin vibe and is one of the few African countries to celebrate Carnival. Every February there is a riotous display of colour and culture when the streets of Bissau, the capital, are overrun with dancers festooned in traditional garb. They strut their stuff to drum beats that could raise the dead and rumbustious applause from adoring crowds.</p>
<p>Bissau&rsquo;s roads are potholed and the electricity supply is erratic, but the dilapidated capital has rugged, timeworn charm. The grandeur of its Portuguese past is well behind it: like an aged model the city&rsquo;s colonial beauty has faded, but there&rsquo;s still a twinkle in its eye and an affable spirit that captivates visitors. It&rsquo;s small and easy to navigate, too, with a few lively bars and restaurants serving up a traditional slice of local life.</p>
<p>For nature lovers the Bijag&oacute;s Archipelago, which floats just off the coast, is a unique highlight. It is in this UNESCO-listed national park that visitors can search for rare pygmy hippos, which wallow in limpid lagoons. They&rsquo;re not the only attraction: the ocean around the 88-island archipelago is home to sharks, manatees and turtles, not mention myriad migratory birds, which holiday here during the European winter. Pack your binoculars.</p>
<p>Travelling in Guinea-Bissau is not always easy, but for those with a sense of adventure and an open mind it can be extremely rewarding. Political instability and poverty may have beset this small nation, but the joie de vivre of its inhabitants endures and the country remains quietly brilliant.</p><p>Though better known for its military coups and government crises, Guinea-Bissau&rsquo;s swashbuckling charm, faded grandeur and stunning natural assets prove some things are above politics.</p>
<p>Sandwiched between Senegal and Guinea, this diminutive nation has a decidedly Latin vibe and is one of the few African countries to celebrate Carnival. Every February there is a riotous display of colour and culture when the streets of Bissau, the capital, are overrun with dancers festooned in traditional garb. They strut their stuff to drum beats that could raise the dead and rumbustious applause from adoring crowds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
