<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Guyana" ColCode="guy" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="gy" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Guyana]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guyana's climate is warm and tropical throughout the year. The rainfall is generally high for most of the year, as is the humidity. December to January and May to June are the rainy seasons, while in coastal areas the climate is tempered by sea breezes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only reliable means of travelling into the interior is by air. Domestic airlines include Air Services Limited (<a href="http://www.aslgy.com" target="_blank">www.aslgy.com</a>) and&nbsp;Trans Guyana Airways (<a href="http://www.transguyana.net" target="_blank">www.transguyana.net</a>), which both use small propeller aircraft. The most popular domestic route is between Georgetown&rsquo;s domestic Ogle Airport and Kaieteur Falls Airstrip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guyana has 1,077km (607 miles) of navigable inland waterways, the most notable being the Essequibo, Demerara and Berbice rivers which are all navigable by oceangoing vessels. Government steamers connect with the interior up the Essequibo and Berbice rivers, but services can be irregular owing to flooding and lack of boat captains.</p>
<p>The government also runs a coast-hopping service from Georgetown to several northern ports. Smaller craft operate where there is sufficient demand throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no scheduled rail services in Guyana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>All-weather roads are concentrated in the eastern coastal strip, although there is a road inland as far as the Brazilian border and a bridge linking the two countries.</p>
<p>The coastal road linking Georgetown, Rosignol, New Amsterdam and Crabwood Creek (Corentyne) is fairly good, but road conditions are generally poor. Because of Guyana's many rivers, most journeys of more than a few miles outside the capital involve ferries. Avoid driving at night.</p><p>At night, it is advisable to travel by taxi. Vehicles are plentiful. There is a standard fare for intercity travel; night fares are extra. For longer trips, fares should be agreed before departure. A 10% tip is usual in taxis. Travellers are advised to only use taxis from reputable companies and not to hail one from the roadside.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is recommended. A one-month local driving permit can be obtained from the Licence and Revenue Office in Georgetown, after showing a valid foreign licence.</p><p>Drink driving, not wearing a seatbelt and using a mobile phone whilst driving are all illegal in Guyana and failure to comply could result in a fine. Speed limits are hardly enforced in Guyana, and some drivers do not stop at traffic lights.</p><p>If you break down you should contact your hire company as the country does not have a national recovery service.</p><p>There is limited availability from local and international firms in Georgetown. Hiring age is 21.</p><p>Drink driving, not wearing a seatbelt and using a mobile phone whilst driving are all illegal in Guyana and failure to comply could result in a fine. Speed limits are hardly enforced in Guyana, and some drivers do not stop at traffic lights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guyana has a limited public bus service, which, although frequent, is not very reliable or safe for travellers. Taxis are the most common form of transport across this small country, but a price should be agreed upon before departure. Taxis are most certainly the safest form of transport for tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Caribbean Airlines (<a href="http://www.caribbean-airlines.com" target="_blank">www.caribbean-airlines.com</a>) flies direct to Guyana from New York and Miami. If travelling from the UK, the easiest way to reach Guyana is to fly to the USA and take a connecting flight from there.</p>
<p>Flights to Guyana are cheapest between October and February, and most expensive from May to August.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 18 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 5 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a G$4,000 (US$20) departure tax which must be paid in cash in the local currency, US Dollars, Canadian Dollars or Pounds Sterling at the Guyana Revenue Authority booth after check-in. Transit passengers up to 48 hours, and children under seven years of age are exempt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Georgetown Airport </b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 40km (26 miles) from the city (journey time - 45 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Canawaima Ferry Service operates between Moleson Creek, Guyana and South Drain, Surinam. Private yachts can sail to Guyana, but they must be cleared at the port of Bartica.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no passenger rail services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/surinam">Surinam</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/venezuela">Venezuela</a> are in dispute and are often closed, but motorists can enter Guyana via road from those countries. Travelling on the roads is difficult in Guyana as most roads are just dirt tracks.</p><p>The highway between Cheddi Jagan Airport and Georgetown should not be used late at night due to false police roadblocks resulting in armed robbery of both taxis and private cars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Network providers include <em>Cel Star Guyana Inc </em>and <em>Guyana Telephone</em> <em>and Telegraph Company</em> <em>(GT&T)</em> (website: <a href="http://www.gtt.co.gy" target="_blank">www.gtt.co.gy</a>). Mobile phones can be hired from <em>GT&T</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes are available in Georgetown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post offices are found across the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Absorb the ambiance in Georgetown</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A visit to Guyana guarantees that every visitor will pass through the colonial capital of Georgetown. 19th century stilted wooden houses line the streets and old Dutch canals line the roads. Guyana is centred around this city, and all aspects of unique Guyanese life focuses on Guyana. Remnants of British, Dutch, Creole and French heritage is apparent on every street across the city. Georgetown is really the only city in Guyana.</p>]]><p><b>Admire the capital’s UNESCO listed City Hall</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The 19th century Gothic revival city hall dominates Georgetown's skyline, with its' towering spire and gothic inspired colonial façade ensuring that no other building in the country can come anywhere close to this. The hall was designed by the famous European architect Igantius Scholes in 1887, and was added to the UNESCO World Heritage list in 1995.</p>]]><p><b>Go shopping in Stabroek Market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stabroek Market, situated in the heart of Georgetown, is famous for its colonial white and brown towering clock and for its friendly vendors. All types of wares are available inside the market, ranging from locally produced jewellery, clothing, sugars, syrups and alcohols. It is easy to get lost in the market, and pickpockets are rife.</p>]]><p><b>Go to court</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As with most of Georgetown's buildings, the Victoria Law Courts, named after Queen Victoria, was designed in a colonial wooden style, with its bright red roof and beech coloured wooden beams. The building has been a courthouse since British colonial times, and has seen some of the country's most notorious criminals tried here.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the awesome Kaieteur Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try not to leave Guyana without visiting Kaieteur Falls in Kaieteur National Park. Situated on the Potaro River, it ranks with Iguazú, Niagara and Victoria in scale and beauty. The national park is situated on the Guiana Shield, a plateau that is one of the world's oldest and most remote geological formations located in a bio diverse rainforest.</p>]]><p><b>Reel in a giant fish</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Game fishing is becoming more popular in Guyana's many inland waterways, however the best place to do this has to be in the Rewa River. Guests must acquire a fishing permit, but rewards are great, with the grand prize being an Arapaima Gigas, the world's largest freshwater fish, or maybe even a Piranha may take the bait.</p>]]><p><b>Salute Queen Victoria</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Standing guard just outside of the Victoria law courts stands the statue of the woman who gave her name to so many of Georgetown's buildings, streets and monuments, Queen Victoria. The green hued statue depicts a smartly dressed and crowned Queen Victoria standing proud overlooking her former colonial capital.</p>]]><p><b>Satisfy your sweet tooth in Demerara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The world's last traditional wooden distilling coffey can be found inside the vast sugar distillery in Demerara, where the world famous Demerara sugar gets its name. Visitors have the chance to see how sugar as we know it was made from the sugar canes that have allowed the Caribbean to prosper for centuries. At the end of the hour long tour there is a chance to sample sugars in the souvenir shop.</p>]]><p><b>Sneak a peek at State House</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Now home to the President of Guyana, this former Governor's house is one of very few gated mansions in the whole of Guyana. The green and white wooden house with its Georgian sash frames and Demerara windows was built in 1858 and has been a base for power ever since.</p>]]><p><b>Stay with an indigenous tribe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Surama, set in savannah surrounded by forest-covered mountains, is home to the Amerindian community of the Macushi tribe, which welcomes tourists. The village of approximately 230 is now based around the award winning eco-lodge of Surama eco-lodge. The lodge was voted the best hotel in Colombia, Guyana and Venezuela by National Geographic and has been awarded a Caribbean Tourism Organisation Excellence in Sustainable Tourism award.</p>]]><p><b>Take a tour of the Roy Geddes Steel Pan Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>World famous for his steel pan music, the Roy Geddes museum houses a wide variety of local and Caribbean steel pan instruments, and photographs highlighting Roy's successful musical career. The steel pan was the only non-electronic musical instrument to be produced in the 20th century, and Roy Geddes wants everyone to know why he loves them so much.</p>]]><p><b>Take a walk on the wild side</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Iwokrama rainforest is one of Guyana's largest and most dense, and a rainforest canopy walkway allows visitors to walk above and amongst the towering trees densely packed together with accompanying wildlife and fauna. The views from the walkway out across the forest are spectacular.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind in the Botanical Gardens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps the most famous garden in Guyana, and home to the kissing bridge where young couples can be found at all times of day, this quiet city centre sanctuary is a must see. Guyana's first Governor, President and Executive President are all buried here next to the pond, and a gold clock pays homage to George Samuel Jenman, a superintendent of the gardens from 1879.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Guyana National Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Guyana's only museums, and by far the largest, this building houses some of the world's most important artefacts, both from Europe and the Americas. In 1864 a fire destroyed all of the original collections, including British gemstones, indigenous woods and animal specimens; today the museum houses a collection of artefacts from all corners of the world, including locally collected rainforest specimens.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the world’s tallest wooden church</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Anglican cathedral of Guyana, located at the heart of Georgetown is unmistakably colonial in style. It is the tallest wholly wooden church in the world and was designed by Sir Arthur Blomfield in 1892. Inside the cathedral, with its Gothic arches and wooden pews, hangs a dazzling chandelier which was donated by Queen Victoria when she ascended to the throne.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2.85 billion (2012).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Sugar, gold, bauxite/aluminium, rum and timber.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Manufactured goods, machinery, petroleum, clothing and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Belgium, Canada, Cuba, UK and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Agriculture allows Guyana to be self-sufficient in sugar, rice, vegetables, fruit, meat and poultry. It is also a major exporter of sugar and rice. Although 80% of the land area is covered by forest, timber has only very recently assumed any economic significance (subject to internationally supported restrictions on logging)</p><p>Bauxite mining is the main industry, and responsible for one-third of export earnings. The mining sector also produces gold and diamonds, almost all of which are exported. Gold production has increased sharply since the opening of a new mining complex in 1992. Imported oil meets most of the country's energy requirements, although Guyana and Suriname have begun joint exploration projects</p><p>Since 1997, many formerly state-owned assets and industries have been sold, and deregulation measures introduced, as part of that programme. A major obstacle to Guyana's future economic progress is a shortage of trained personnel, especially in the fields of management and technical expertise; the emigration rate remains high, and only serves to compound this long-term problem.</p><p>Guyana has a particularly high GDP in relation to other Central-South American countries, with a figure in 2012 of 3,583 USD per capita. Guyana is a founding member of the regional trading bloc CARICOM.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Appointments should be made prior to meetings and punctuality is appreciated. Business cards are useful. The pace of business and general attitudes are very Caribbean-orientated, so slow paced and relaxed. Suits are not a requirement, but gifts are much appreciated.</p><p>It is, however, wise to bear in mind that the country is very much part of South America, the ties with the Caribbean being more a hangover from British colonial days than a reflection of Guyanese popular consciousness.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Georgetown Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 225 5846
					Website:http://www.georgetownchamberofcommerce.org
					Address: 156 Waterloo Street,PO Box 10110,North Cummingsburg,]]><b>Guyana Manufacturer's Association</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 227 4295
					Website:http://www.gma.org.gy
					Address: ,National Exhibition Centre,Sophia,]]><b>Ministry of Tourism, Industry and Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 226 2505
					Website:http://www.mintic.gov.gy
					Address: ,229 South Road,Georgetown,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The food in hotels and restaurants reflects the range of influences on Guyanese society. On the menus of most restaurants you will often find chicken, pork, steak and, most commonly, shrimp.</p><p>The best Chinese food in the country can be found in Georgetown. Guyanese food, just like the population, is a melting pot of influences from Britain, the Netherlands, India and Africa. Most of the ingredients used in Guyanese dishes and drinks are produced domestically as the country's climate is perfect for rice, livestock and root plants.</p><p>It is best to drink bottled water in Guyana as the tap water is known to be contaminated in some areas of the country. In Georgetown tap water is generally safe to drink, but bottled water is cheap, and it is better to err on the side of caution.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><em>&bull; Foo-foo </em>(plantains made into cakes and deep fried in oil until golden brown and crispy)<br />
<em>&bull;  Metagee </em>(yam, plantain, breadfruit, cassava and salted meat or fish all slowly boiled in a creamy coconut milk with extra tomatoes, palm oil, hot chili, garlic and onions)<br />
<em>&bull; Split pea soup </em>(A pea based soup with bacon strips, split peas, animal fat, chicken stock, yams, peppers and eddoes)<br />
<em>&bull; Pepperpot</em> (a Amerindian meat stew with cassava extract and hot pepper sauce)<br />
<em>&bull;Guyanese style rice</em> (a local take on Chinese fried rice)</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Generally all foods are washed thoroughly prior to cooking in restaurants and hotels, however street food is not necessarily of the same quality.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% at hotels and restaurants is expected. For truly exceptional service 20% should be the maximum.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Both young and old enjoy partying the night away in Guyana, Georgetown in particular, as pubs and clubs are not found anywhere else in the country. Georgetown has an abundance of western style nightclubs with copious amounts of alcohol on tap and music blaring all night long; however jazz clubs, Latin discos and karaoke bars are just as popular.</p><p>For a true cultural immersion head over to the regionally famous Ignite Bar where reggae combines with Indian and Soca music, and people from all walks of life party side by side. Many locals drive up to the bar, order their alcoholic drinks, and then sit in the car parks with loud music rocking their cars; this is definitely a unique and unforgettable nightlife experience.</p><p>As Guyana sits at the crossroads between the western world and Latin America, it is no wonder then that Latin discos are popular, where couples dance until the early hours to the slow beats of the tango and salsa. Nightclubs and pubs are great places to meet new friends, but you should ensure that, as in clubs around the world, drinks are never left unattended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopping is a favourite pastime in Guyana, especially in the capital of Georgetown, where some of the world's purest gold and diamonds can be found. As one of the sugar producing capitals of the world, the town of Demerara sells all number of unique sugar related paraphernalia, ranging from different tasting bags of sugar to sugar distilling equipment.</p><p>Street markets are commonplace across the country and haggling for gifts and souvenirs is expected. Handmade slippers, paintings, sculptures, leather goods, key rings, and bead crafts are available at all Georgetown markets, but prices vary from stall to stall, so it is best to search around for the cheapest goods rather than jumping in and buying the first one found.</p><p>Although most of the markets in Georgetown are only open until around 1200, uniquely to South American countries, the Stabroek and Bourda markets are open 24 hours per day, seven days a week. Shopping in Georgetown in particular, but across the country, is generally of high quality and the sellers are very friendly.</p><p>For fixed prices there is an abundance of new shopping malls and super stores across the major towns and city across Guyana. At Georgetown's Cheddi Jagan International Airport there are several duty free shops offering tax free locally produced spirits, rums, gifts, and cigarettes, but many tourists could actually haggle for lower prices in the many markets across the country.</p><p>It is absolutely essential to ensure that receipts and correct documentation are retained, otherwise visitors may experience difficulty when clearing customs.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300-1630, Sat 0800-1200. Stabroek and Bourda markets are open 24/7.</p><p>Please check that you have been given the correct change before leaving shops, as sellers are notorious for short changing buyers. Ensure that you are buying genuine leather products, as faux leathers are increasingly imported into the Americas and are being passed off as genuine in Guyana's street markets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Georgetown range from good to reasonable. There are no high-season charges. Nature lovers can stay in cabins at the interior resorts and camps. As power cuts are common, it is advisable to take a torch.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Georgetown range from good to reasonable. There are no high-season charges. Nature lovers can stay in cabins at the interior resorts and camps. As power cuts are common, it is advisable to take a torch.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Georgetown range from good to reasonable. There are no high-season charges. Nature lovers can stay in cabins at the interior resorts and camps. As power cuts are common, it is advisable to take a torch.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Comprehensive health insurance is recommended. Hospital treatment in Georgetown is free, but doctors will charge for an appointment. Medical care and prescription drugs are limited and sanitary conditions are poor in many medical facilities. Travellers are advised to bring prescription medicines sufficient for their length of stay.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated in main cities, and whilst relatively safe may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is readily available and is advised for the first few weeks of the stay. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B and D are highly endemic in the Amazon basin and precautions should be taken. Tuberculosis occurs. Jungle yellow fever may be found in forest areas. Dengue fever and American trypanosomiasis (Chagas disease) may occur. Rabies occurs. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>(a) Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.<br /><br />(b) Hindu festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Republic Day (Mashramani) :
							23 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Indian Arrival Day :
							05 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							26 May </p><p>CARICOM Day :
							02 July </p><p>Emancipation Day :
							01 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods can be imported into Guyana by travellers aged 18 years or over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 227g of tobacco (including cigarettes and cigars).<br />
&bull; 758ml of spirits.<br />
&bull; 758ml of wine.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of US$100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include counterfeit currency, indecent or obscene publications, matches containing white phosphorus, and opium.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guyanese Dollar (GYD; symbol G$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of G$1,000, 500, 100 and 20. Coins are in denominations of G$10, 5 and 1. US Dollars are widely accepted throughout Guyana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Banks offer exchange facilities. Bureaux de change (cambios) offer free conversion of currencies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted by most larger hotels, restaurants, car hire and tour operators.</p><p>Foreign cards are now accepted at a few bank ATMs including the Scotia Bank and Santander in Guyana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted but not recommended for those who may wish to change money in a hurry. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars. Visitors are advised to bring traveller's cheques to cover the entirity of their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1230 and Friday 1500-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Guyana, a passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry tourist visa: &pound;20; multiple-entry business visa: &pound;80.</p>
<p>Single-entry tourist visa on arrival: US$25; multiple-entry business visa on arrival: US$140.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry tourist visa: one month; multiple-entry business visa: up to five years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy or high commission). Travellers requiring a visa who are unable to apply at a Guyanan mission may obtain a visa on arrival; see <a href="http://www.moha.gov.gy">www.moha.gov.gy</a>&nbsp;for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The processing time required for a visa application for Guyana depends on whether the application has to be referred to the authorities in Guyana.</p>
<p>Generally, applicants should contact the embassy or high commission at least one week in advance of travel.</p>
<p>If a passport is to be returned by a courier service, pre-paid arrangements must be made by the applicant.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your stay, you must contact the Ministry of Home Affairs in Georgetown before your current visa expires. A maximum of two extensions of stay are allowed of one month each.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[5.096968]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-59.047972]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>214,969 sq km (83,000 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>770,610 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Georgetown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guyana lies in the northeast of South America, bordered by Venezuela to the west, Surinam to the southeast and Brazil to the south. It is bordered by the Atlantic Ocean to the north and east. The word 'Guiana' (the original Amerindian spelling) means 'land of many waters' and the name was well chosen, for there are over 1,600km (965 miles) of navigable rivers in the country. The interior is either high savannah uplands (such as those along the Venezuelan border, called the Rupununi, and the Kanuku Mountains in the far southwest), or thick, hilly jungle and forest, which occupy over 83% of the country's area. The narrow coastal belt contains the vast majority of the population, and produces the major cash crop, sugar, and the major subsistence crop, rice. The country has 322km (206 miles) of coastline. More than 25% of the population lives in or near Georgetown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>50% Christian, 33% Hindu, less than 10% Muslim.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hospitality is important to the Guyanese and it is quite common for the visitor to be invited to their homes. Informal wear is widely acceptable, but men should avoid wearing shorts.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC in Georgetown and 240 volts AC elsewhere, 50-60Hz. American-style (two flat pins with or without grounding pin) and British-style plugs (three square pins) are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Moses Nagamootoo since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President David Granger since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Modern day Guyana is built on the legacy of European imperialists, who made their first foray into the region in 1499, when Alonso de Ojeda sailed up the Essequibo.</p>
<p>Prior to the arrival of the Spanish, the Arawak and Carib people had been fighting for control of the region, but when the Spanish arrived, the victorious Carib warriors proved defenceless against the heavily armed Europeans, who discovered the area had no gold and gave the land back to the natives.</p>
<p>In 1616 the newly independent Dutch founded a trading post in current day Guyana and rapidly expanded their settlements inland, changing their original aim from trading with the natives, to conquering them.</p>
<p>For more than 170 years the Dutch named the colony Essequibo and used it mainly as a trading base for locally grown tobacco, exporting some 15,000 kilos in 1623. When the Dutch West India Company took complete control of the colony, business changed from trading tobacco to trading African slaves, until the Berbice slave uprising of 1763, during which time plantations rapidly fell to the Africans.</p>
<p>The British and French marched in to quash the uprisings from neighbouring colonies, thus laying the path for an eventual majority British population. During the French Revolutionary Wars, when Napoleon&rsquo;s forces occupied the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/netherlands">Netherlands</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Britain</a> conquered all Dutch colonies in the Americas, including Guyana.</p>
<p>This British control was legitimised by the signing of the London Convention of 1814, at which <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> agreed to allow Britain to control the newly unified British Guiana. Successive Governors of the colony repeatedly complained to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> about the lack of able bodied workers to complete grand public works, so paid workers were imported from British India in their shiploads, thus resulting in an un-proportionately sized Indian population calling Guyana home.</p>
<p>In 1950, Indian-Guayanese Cheddi Jagan and Afro-Guyanese Forbes Burnham founded the first political party in the country, the Progressive People&rsquo;s Party (PPP) which campaigned for independence from Britain, which was granted in 1966.</p>
<p>After independence, Forbes Burnham was elected to power, but his premiership saw border disputes with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/venezuela">Venezuela</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/surinam">Suriname</a> grow. Burnham took Guyana from a pro-imperial right-wing to a left-leaning pro-communist country, developing ties with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cuba">Cuba</a>. Successive left-wing governments neglected Guyana&rsquo;s potential oil and gas reserves until Desmond Hoyte took power and embraced the free market, elections and independent media.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; There are more Indian descendants in Guyana than in some of the northern states of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>.<br />
&bull; During Jagan&rsquo;s premiership, the country was blighted by strikes and rioting, often attributed to covert CIA operations from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> who were trying to prevent Guyana from turning communist.<br />
&bull; In 1978, American religious cult leader Jim Jones and 909 followers (including 300 children), of the People&rsquo;s Temple committed mass suicide in Jonestown, Guyana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Guyana in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 6900.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.guyana.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 6900.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2490 Tracy Place<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guyana High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7229 7684.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.guyana.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7229 7684.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1730 (except national and UK holidays); Mon-Fri 0930-1430 (consular enquiries).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Bayswater Road<br/>3 Palace Court<br/>London<br/>W2 4LP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guyana might not be on everyone's bucket list, but with its unspoiled rainforests, golden beaches, sweeping savannahs and meandering rivers, this little-known South American nation offers rich rewards for those daring enough to visit.</p><p>Wild and welcoming in equal measure, Guyana's attractions range from the awesome natural splendour of Kaieteur Falls, to the charming, stilted wooden houses of its capital, Georgetown.</p><p>Jungle trekking, freshwater fishing and wildlife watching are the big draws, and while few succeed in sighting the country's famously elusive jaguar's, nature lovers will have the opportunity to spot giant anteaters, giant otters and, sticking with the supersize theme, arapaima, the world's largest freshwater fish.</p><p>In many ways a trip to Guyana is a jump back in time, a refreshing tonic in a world of instant gratification and constant connectivity. But while the country's tourist infrastructure is almost non-existent, ATMs scarce and holidaymakers rarer than the wild cats that roam the rainforests, pioneering travellers certainly won't be left wanting.</p><p>One of the few Caribbean countries that is not an island, multicultural Guyana has more in common with the West Indies than it does South America; from the English and Creole spoken on the streets to the curry dishes served on dinner tables.</p><p>Guyanese culture and cuisine reflect the ethnic makeup of the country, which consists of Indian, African and European people, who were brought over to the Caribbean by Dutch and British colonialists. There is also a substantial Amerindian population, which distinguishes it from other parts of the Caribbean.</p><p>Travellers looking for a destination with a difference, a country well off the tourist trail, will find Guyana a joy to discover. It's by no means cheap to fly there and exploring the country will require a strong sense of adventure and a willingness to forsake creature comforts. But that's a small price to pay for what Guyana gives in return.</p><p>Guyana's attractions range from the 19th-century stilted wooden houses of its capital, Georgetown, to the awesome natural splendour of the towering Kaieteur Falls along the Potaro River, five times the height of Niagara.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
