<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Haiti" ColCode="hti" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ht" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Haiti]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical, with intermittent rain throughout the year. Much cooler temperatures exist in hill resorts and there is a high coastal humidity.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical, lightweight wear; rainwear and warm clothing for hill regions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>This is often the quickest (and easiest) way to get around Haiti. <a href="https://fdmsecure.com/tortug/servlet/FareStructureServlet">Tortug&rsquo; Air</a> (tel: +509 2812 8000) and Sunrise Airways (tel: +509 2811 2222; <a href="http://www.sunriseairways.net" target="_blank">www.sunriseairways.net</a>) offer various domestic routes between them. Planes can also be chartered from Missionary Aviation Fellowship (<a href="http://www.mafhaiti.org" target="_blank">www.mafhaiti.org</a>) which flies to 15 airstrips in Haiti.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no functioning railway in Haiti.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Route Nationale highways are generally fairly decent, but road quality elsewhere is unreliable at best and terrible at worst.</p><p>Air-conditioned and comfortable tourist-style buses run between Port-au-Prince and Les Cayes in the south and to Cap Haitien in the north. Capital Coach Line (tel: +509 2813 1880; <a href="http://www.capitalcoachline.com" target="_blank">www.capitalcoachline.com</a>), San Souci Tours (tel: +509 3743 4646) and Transport Chic (+509 3741 2489) are the main operators.</p><p>Three kinds of taxis operate in Port-au-Prince; <em>motosiklet</em> (or motorbikes) that dart deftly and dangerously in and out of traffic; <em>publiques</em> (or public taxis) that are basically battered cars with a red ribbon hanging from the driver&rsquo;s mirror to indicate availability; and private cabs such as Nick&rsquo;s Radio Taxi (tel: +509 2948 7777).</p>
<p>Braver travellers can also use tap taps, the elaborately painted vehicles that have practically come to symbolise Port-au-Prince. Though colourful, they can be very crowded, and foreign visitors are generally advised not to use them. A local joke asks how many people can get in one tap tap. The answer: 'one more'.</p><p>An International Driving Permit or current licence from your home country is required.</p><p>Hire cars are available in Port-au-Prince, P&eacute;tionville and at the airport. They can also be booked via hotels. Petrol can be scarce outside Port-au-Prince and sometimes even within the capital.</p>
<p>Secom (tel: +509 2942 2940; <a href="http://www.secomhaiti.com" target="_blank">www.secomhaiti.com</a>) greets clients at the airport with a hired car. Though a 4-wheel drive costs nearly double a saloon, it's a better choice because of road conditions. A UK driving licence is good for three months. All hired cars' registration numbers begin with 'LO'.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buses run every hour or so between Port-au-Prince and Jacmel. They depart from near the football stadium on rue Oswald Durand.</p>
<p>Buses run twice a day to Jeremie from Grand Rue in downtown Port-au-Prince. For Cap Haitien, take a bus from Barriere Bouteille on the north side of Port-au-Prince.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no direct flights to Haiti from the UK, but connections are available with American Airlines via New York or Miami (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>) and Delta via Atlanta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>).&nbsp;JetBlue (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>) flies daily to Port au Prince from New York and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/fort-lauderdale">Fort Lauderdale</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London - 15 hours; New York - 4 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cap-Haïtien International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/haiti">Haiti</a>'s second international airport and is approximately 10km (6 miles) from the town.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Port-au-Prince International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 13km (8 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports are Port-au-Prince and Cap-Ha&iuml;tien.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The southern border crossing into Haiti from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominican-republic">Dominican Republic</a> is near Malpasse/Jimani on the road linking Port-au-Prince and Santo Domingo. In the north, the crossing is at Ouanaminthe/Dajabon.</p><p>The crossings close at dusk so it&rsquo;s worth getting there in good time. Caribe Tours (<a href="http://www.caribetours.com.do" target="_blank">www.caribetours.com.do</a>)&nbsp;and Capital Coach Line (<a href="http://www.capitalcoachline.com" target="_blank">www.capitalcoachline.com</a>) offer coach services between Port au Prince and Santo Domingo in the Dominican Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes. The internal service, operated by <em>Telecommunications d'Haïti (Teleco)</em>, is reasonable. There are telephone booths in the towns which take cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>No roaming agreements have been declared. Handsets can be hired locally.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes can be found in towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Radio is Haiti's most important source of information. There are more than 250 private radio stations.<strong><br /></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes up to one week. The main post office in Port-au-Prince, Cité de l'Exposition, is in place d'Italie.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-2000, Sat 0830-1200. Letters posted after 0900 will not be despatched until the following working day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With their elaborate latticework, vibrant Voodoo patterns and decorative wooden shutters, Haiti's characterful gingerbread houses are a faded reminder of more prosperous times. But they might also be a taste of the future – city planners are considering building more after seeing how resilient they were in the 2010 earthquake. A Haitian take on 19th century French holiday homes, visitors can find these magnificent properties scattered around Port au Prince.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the many charms of Jacmel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its faded colonial charm and excellent local handicrafts, the town of Jacmel is worthy of exploration. The residents' irrepressible creativity has found new expression along the Boulevard du Bord de Mer: the oceanfront has been festooned with colourful murals and mosaics executed by local artists. It's perfectly possible to do a day tour out of Port au Prince, seeing Jacmel's sights and leaving after lunch.</p>]]><p><b>Escape the mainland</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Secluded and staggeringly beautiful, the satellite island of Ile-a-Vache offers exquisite, crowd-free beaches and upmarket resorts for those who really want to escape. Transfers are available from the seaport of Les Cayes on mainland Haiti.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Citadelle Laferriére</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This UNESCO-listed fortress is the largest in the Americas and it's hard not to be awed by the grandiose structure, which sits atop a mountain so steep they call it the Bonnet l'Eveque (or bishop's hat). Below the citadel are the ruins of King Henri's palace, San Souci, designed as a Versailles of the Caribbean.</p>]]><p><b>Have a night out in Pétionville</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The hillside suburb of Pétionville in Port au Prince is chock full of bars, restaurants and galleries. This is the beating heart of the local nightlife, though visitors should be wary of street crime as well as open manhole covers.</p>]]><p><b>Hike in National Parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The national parks of La Visite and Parc Macaya offer bountiful hiking opportunities. It's difficult, but not impossible if you have a good guide, all the gear and five days to spare, to get to the top of Pic Macaya, Haiti's second highest mountain. Parc Macaya also has other, more do-able trails.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bathers are spoiled for choice in Haiti, which is surrounded by stunning beaches. However, for something truly special, visit the small coastal town of Port Salut, which has seemingly endless stretches of pure white sand and barely a soul in sight.</p>]]><p><b>Imbibe Haitian art</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Art is deeply engrained in Haitian culture, reflecting the country's African roots and European influences. Tragically, the art world suffered devastating losses in the 2010 earthquake, which destroyed galleries and museums across the country – some works will never been seen again. However, the brilliant Museum of Haitian Art has a fine collection of paintings and crafts, showcasing the talents of local artists.</p>]]><p><b>Take in epic vistas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For spectacular views over Port au Prince, the gorgeous Gulf of Gonave and its white sandy beaches, head for the lofty suburb of Boutillier, high in the mountains. If you fancy hanging around, head to the restaurant at the top, which offers hearty fare and a feast for your eyes.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind in Cap Haïtien</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On Christmas Eve 1492, Christopher Columbus ran aground on the north coast of Hispaniola near the present-day city of Cap Haïtien. There are worse places to be marooned. Nestling at the foot of lush green mountains and surrounded by several fine beaches, Cap Haïtien has a more laidback air than the capital and features many fine, colonial-style buildings. A short drive away is the charming village of Milot.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Iron Market in Port au Prince</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Built in France, the canopy of the Iron Market was made for a train station in Cairo. However, when that fell through it was redirected to Haiti in 1891 where it stood until the 2010 earthquake. After an ambitious restoration project the market reopened in 2013 and is home to some 900 hawkers who ply their trade in anything from fruit to souvenirs.</p>]]><p><b>While away the day in Noailles</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A village of artists in the suburb of Croix des Bouquets – half an hour northeast of Port au Prince – Noailles resounds with the banging of mallets and the clanging of chisels as whole streets of artisans transform sheet metal into intricate works of art.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$7.9 billion (2012).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Apparel, oils, cocoa, mangoes, coffee.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, manufactured goods, machinery and transport equipment, fuels, raw materials.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, EU</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With an average annual income of $760 per head, Haiti is the poorest country in the Americas. Vast disparities exist between the incomes – and lifestyles – of rich and poor. The World Bank estimates that 80% of the population lives on less than $2 a day and more than half on less than $1.</p><p>More than half of all Haitians work in the services sector. However, nearly 40% depend on agriculture, mainly small-scale subsistence farming, which leaves them especially vulnerable to the effects of natural disasters, which some claim are exacerbated by Haiti's widespread deforestation.</p><p>Currently, international donor assistance and remittances from the Haitian Diaspora (which average over a billion dollars per year) represent almost half the national budget and approximately 20% of GDP. Most of Haiti's external debt was forgiven in 2009 and the rest, after the 2010 earthquake.</p><p>The damage caused by the 7.0 magnitude earthquake – Haiti's worst in 200 years – caused its GDP to contract roughly 5%. As well as killing upwards of 316,000 people and leaving more than 1.5 million people homeless, the disaster also damaged more than 300,000 buildings, including key infrastructure such as government offices, schools, hospitals and courts. Reconstruction costs are estimated to be $11.5 billion.</p><p>The UN, US and other countries, along with various international and non-governmental organizations, are helping Haiti rebuild, but it is a massive undertaking marked by significant challenges such as high unemployment, the shortage of skilled labour and high energy and security costs.</p><p>Attempts by the government to attract foreign investment, re-build the tourism industry and boost agricultural productivity are starting to bear fruit, but it will be a long road to recover.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is usual to wear a suit for business meetings. English is not widely spoken, but local tour operators can put visitors in touch with reliable French or Creole translators if required.</p><p>Typically Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre Franco-Haïtienne de Commerce et d'Industrie</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 223 8404
					Website:
					Address: Holiday Inn Plaza,Suite 327,Port-au-Prince,]]><b>Chambre Haïtienne de Commerce et d'Industrie</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 222 2475 ,223 0786
					Website:
					Address: ,BP 982,Port-au-Prince,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Haitian food brings the best of Africa, France and the Caribbean together on a plate. Creole and French cuisine are the most widely available, but there's a variety of other cuisines on offer too, including Lebanese, Japanese and American.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Griot </em>(fried pork)<br />
&bull; <em>Pikliz </em>(Spicy Haitian coleslaw)<br />
&bull; <em>Banan peze </em>(fried green plantain)<br />
&bull; <em>Cabri boucane </em>(grilled goat)<br />
&bull; <em>Tasso </em>(preserved beef, goat or turkey, fried or grilled)<br />
&bull; <em>Lambi nan sos kreyol </em>(Conch in Creole sauce)<br />
&bull; <em>Marinade de Lambi </em>(Conch fritters)<br />
&bull; <em>Akra </em>(fritters made out of Malanga, a root vegetable)<br />
&bull; <em>Diri ak djondjon</em>(rice and black mushrooms)<br />
&bull; <em>Diri kole </em>(rice and beans)<br />
&bull; <em>Pate </em>(savoury pastries stuffed with chicken, beef, cheese and smoked or unsmoked fish</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 10 to 15% tip is expected, but check your bill to see if it has already been included.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18 years</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Haitians love nothing more than jigging to live music and visitors will be spoilt for choice when it comes to a night out. Especially at the weekend when bars, restaurants and hotels crank up the volume and host live bands, which play away until the carefree hours of the morning.</p>
<p>One of the hottest tickets in town is a table at the Oloffson Hotel, Avenue Christophe 60, Port au Prince (tel: +509 2223 4000; <a href="http://hoteloloffson.com" target="_blank">www.hoteloloffson.com</a>), which plays host to vodou-inspired band RAM every Thursday night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors generally head for the historic Iron Market, which has tonnes of tat as well as some excellent local handicrafts. These include paintings in the <em>naïf </em>style for which Haiti is famous, straw hats and metalwork.</p><p>Sales tactics in the Iron Market can be overly aggressive and some prefer the more genteel environs of the Comite Artisanal Haitien, 29 Rue 3, Pacot (<a href="http://www.cahaiti.com" target="_blank">www.cahaiti.com</a>), a cooperative which represents more than 200 artisans and groups across the country. Prices are fixed, unlike at the Iron Market, and consumers can leave knowing their purchases have provided fair wages for local artisans.</p><p>If it's local art you're after, head to Kay Atizan 3 Rue Magny, Petionville (tel: +509 3456 6989), an art gallery that sells handicrafts at reasonable prices.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300-1600, Sat 0800-1200.</p><p>Opening hours can vary. Some shops in Petionville open 0900 to 1800. Some stay open half-day Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation is limited in Haiti. Existing facilities include modest small inns, guest houses and palatial-style hotels. The majority of accommodation is in Port-au-Prince and Pétionville, while the beach hotels are north of the capital on the road to St Marc or west towards Petit-Gonâve.<br /><br />Accommodation is also to be found in Cap-Haïtien, Les Cayes, the Gonâve Bay area, Jacmel and the Petit-Gonâve beach area. Swimming pools and air conditioning are essential in central hotels where the heat can become severe. All resorts offer substantial reductions between 16 April and 15 December. A 10% room tax is added to all hotel bills. <br /><strong><br />Note: </strong>It is vital to make reservations well in advance for the Carnival period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation is limited in Haiti. Existing facilities include modest small inns, guest houses and palatial-style hotels. The majority of accommodation is in Port-au-Prince and Pétionville, while the beach hotels are north of the capital on the road to St Marc or west towards Petit-Gonâve.<br /><br />Accommodation is also to be found in Cap-Haïtien, Les Cayes, the Gonâve Bay area, Jacmel and the Petit-Gonâve beach area. Swimming pools and air conditioning are essential in central hotels where the heat can become severe. All resorts offer substantial reductions between 16 April and 15 December. A 10% room tax is added to all hotel bills. <br /><strong><br />Note: </strong>It is vital to make reservations well in advance for the Carnival period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation is limited in Haiti. Existing facilities include modest small inns, guest houses and palatial-style hotels. The majority of accommodation is in Port-au-Prince and Pétionville, while the beach hotels are north of the capital on the road to St Marc or west towards Petit-Gonâve.<br /><br />Accommodation is also to be found in Cap-Haïtien, Les Cayes, the Gonâve Bay area, Jacmel and the Petit-Gonâve beach area. Swimming pools and air conditioning are essential in central hotels where the heat can become severe. All resorts offer substantial reductions between 16 April and 15 December. A 10% room tax is added to all hotel bills. <br /><strong><br />Note: </strong>It is vital to make reservations well in advance for the Carnival period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance providing cover for repatriation in the event of serious illness is strongly recommended. Medical facilities are fairly good. The local herb tea is said to be good for stomach upsets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the continuing cholera outbreak from 21 October 2010, The Foreign  Office advises caution over water and food sources. Tourists are advised to drink only boiled or bottled water, to avoid ice in drinks, to eat  only well-cooked food and to avoid salads. If you suffer from diarrhoea  consult a doctor immediately.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B occurs. Seasonal meningococcal meningitis has been reported. Outbreaks of dengue fever occur in the area. HIV/AIDS is also a serious problem. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Independence Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Ancestors' Day :
							2018<br/>02 January </p><p>Carnival :
							12 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Pan-American Day :
							14 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Flag and University Day :
							18 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Anniversary of the Death of Dessalines :
							17 October </p><p>United Nations Day :
							24 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>All Soul's Day :
							02 November </p><p>Battle of Verti̬r̩s Day :
							18 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods can be imported into Haiti by travellers over the age of 18 without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 1kg of tobacco products.<br />
&bull; 2 bottles of alcoholic drinks (up to 750ml each).<br />
&bull; Goods with a total value not exceeding HTG2,500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms (except sporting guns, which require a permit).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gourde (HTG) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of HTG500, 250, 100, 50, 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of HTG5 and 1, and 50, 20, 10 and 5 centimes. Most establishments price items in the unofficial currency, the Haitian Dollar (1 Haitian Dollar = HTG5). <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> currency also circulates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollars are accepted and exchanged everywhere. Other foreign currencies are accepted for exchange only by some banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are widely accepted. At least one local bank chain has ATMs in Port au Prince, but they are frequently out of order and there have been reports of over charging accounts.</p><p>At least one local bank chain has ATMs in Port au Prince, but they are frequently out of order and there have been reports of over charging accounts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Apart from at banks, these are often difficult to exchange. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1500-1700. Some banks open Sat 0900-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months from the date of entry to Haiti is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above. Foreign nationals not requiring a visa must pay a tourist fee set at USD$10 on arrival at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry tourist visa: US$25. This type of visa is valid for three months with only one entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Processing time varies, but nationals requiring visas should apply at least one month before the departure date.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign nationals wishing to stay for more than 90 days must obtain a Residence Permit from the Department of Immigration and Emigration (DIE) that is valid for a fiscal year (01 October to 30 September).</p>
<p>Foreign nationals wishing to extend their stay beyond 90 days must obtain a permit from the Department of Immigration and Emigration (DIE).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[19.089967]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-72.438020]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>27,750 sq km (10,714 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>10,848,175 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>360.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Port-au-Prince.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Haiti is situated in the Caribbean and comprises the forested mountainous western end of the island of Hispaniola, which it shares with the Dominican Republic. Its area includes the &Icirc;le de la Gon&acirc;ve, in the Gulf of the same name; among other islands is La Tortue off the north peninsula. Haiti's coastline is dotted with magnificent beaches, between which stretches lush subtropical vegetation, even covering the slopes which lead down to the shore. Port-au-Prince is a magnificent natural harbour at the end of a deep horseshoe bay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The official religions are Roman Catholicism (75%) and Voodooism (70%); most Haitians practise both. Voodooism is a polytheistic folk religion, manifested by a series of complex ritual drawings, songs and dances. It is an African religion, and not incompatible with a shared belief in Christianity. There are Protestant minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Informal wear is acceptable, although beachwear should be confined to the beach or poolside. Only the most elegant dining-rooms encourage guests to dress for dinner.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without round grounding pin) are used; you may need an adaptor if your device has a third pin however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Jean-Henry C&eacute;ant since August 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Jovenel Mo&iuml;se since February 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In 1492 Christopher Columbus became the first European to discover the island of Hispaniola, which has since been divided between the countries of Haiti and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominican-republic">Dominican Republic</a>. The Spanish colonised this new land, brutally supplanting the Arawak Indian inhabitants, and using the island to launch their conquests of the Caribbean and Central America</p>
<p>By the 16th century, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a>'s European rivals began challenging for control of Santo Domingo and in 1697 they ceded the western half of the island to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>, which now forms modern day Haiti.</p>
<p>The French turned their new territory into a major centre for the slave trade, but their control of Haiti was brought to an end in 1804 by what became <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haitian_Revolution" target="_blank">the only successful slave rebellion ever to take place</a>.</p>
<p>The 19th century in newly independent Haiti was characterised by political and social unrest. Dictators came and went but none had the wherewithal to unite the country's two main ethnic groups: the mulattos and the blacks. And then Jean-Pierre Boyer entered the scene. One of the leaders of the Haitian Revolution, he became president in 1818 and presided over a period of relative calm.</p>
<p>Having consolidated power in Haiti, in 1822 Boyer occupied neighbouring Dominican Republic which had recently declared independence from Spain. He met little resistance and the territories remained unhappily married until 1844.</p>
<p>Spiralling debt and a devastating earthquake in 1842 tipped Haiti back towards instability, which culminated in a <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/8460185.stm" target="_blank"><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> occupation in 1915</a>. Concerned by their financial exposure in Haiti, the US invaded the country and stayed until 1934; a period in which Haitian&rsquo;s human rights were sacrificed on the altar of economic development.</p>
<p>The US left Haiti much as they found it: politically unstable. Dictatorships, military juntas and economic malaise defined the decades that followed, culminating in the arrival of a UN stabilisation mission, which was sent to Haiti in 2004 and remains there to this day.</p>
<p>It took two years before calm returned to Haiti&rsquo;s streets. Rene Preval returned as president while the UN dealt with gangs that made the security situation difficult. And then a devastating act of nature brought further destruction to the embattled nation. Estimated to have killed up to 220,000 people, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2010_Haiti_earthquake" target="_blank">the 2010 earthquake</a> brought death and unimaginable misery to millions of Haitians and rebuilding has been the country&rsquo;s focus ever since.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; Haiti is the first and only country in the world whose independence came from a successful slave rebellion.<br />
&bull; Haiti is the only country in the world where voodoo is an official religion.<br />
&bull; There are more mountains in Haiti than on any other Caribbean island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Haiti in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 4090.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.haiti.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 4090.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1600 (embassy), Mon-Fri: 0900-1300, Sat: 0900-1230 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2311 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Haiti is a country guaranteed to shock and awe. Tragedy-scarred but tenacious, this small Caribbean nation has great beauty and great need. Boasting verdant mountains, white sandy beaches and plenty of African spontaneity, Haiti might be financially poor, but it is rich in natural beauty, culturally affluent.</p>
<p>Sharing the island of Hispaniola with the Dominican Republic, Haiti has all the hallmarks of a classic Caribbean destination. And so it was, in the 1960s and 70s, when the wealthy flocked here to relax in the tropical climate, tread upon powdery beaches and explore vertiginous mountain ranges.</p>
<p>However, decades of political instability and a series of natural disasters devastated Haiti&rsquo;s tourist industry, and saw the country go from the travel sections of newspapers straight to the front pages.</p>
<p>But, slowly, holidaymakers are returning. Led by the luxury end of the market, new hotels are opening all the time in Port au Prince, which is a sign of how the tide is finally turning. As well as new hotels, numerous tourism development projects are also underway.</p>
<p>Haiti&rsquo;s unique selling proposition as a Caribbean destination is its history and culture. It has a vibrant arts scene, irresistible fusion cuisine and many talented musicians, who pack out bars and clubs with their unique brand of African, European and Caribbean beats.</p>
<p>However, travelling around Haiti is not always easy. The country&rsquo;s infrastructure has not recovered from decades of instability and the devastating earthquake of 2010.</p>
<p>Political uncertainty endures, too; the United Nations&rsquo; Stabilization Force for Haiti &ndash; known by its French acronym MINUSTAH &ndash; is still here ten years after it was sent in to restore political order.</p>
<p>In the short term, then, the best option for those travelling to Haiti is to use the services of a known tour operator. This might not feel particularly adventurous, but it will take the hassle out of visiting a nation that is still finding its feet after years in the wilderness.</p><p>With its mountainous scenery and tropical climate, Haiti, which shares the island of Hispaniola with the Dominican Republic, has the basic ingredients of a holiday destination.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
