<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Honduras" ColCode="hnd" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="hn" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Honduras]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is tropical with cooler, more temperate weather in the mountains with temperatures ranging from 16&deg;C (61&deg;F) to 20&deg;C (68&deg;F). The north coast is very hot with rain throughout the year, and though the offshore breezes temper the climate, the sun is very strong. The dry season is from November to April and the wet season runs from May to October.</p>
<p>Despite their proximity to the mainland the Bay Islands have a slightly different, subtropical climate. The temperatures along the Caribbean coast and island range from 24&deg;C (75&deg;F) to 34&deg;C (93&deg;F) and, in contrast to the mainland, the rainy season in the Bay Islands is from July to January, with the rainiest months being October through early January. The remainder of the year is usually very dry. The southern Pacific  Coast tends to be hot and dry with temperatures between 28&deg; (82&deg;F) to 32&deg;C (90&deg;F).</p>
<p>The Caribbean hurricane season is between June and November and although the Bay Islands and Caribbean coast of Honduras are outside the typical hurricane path, they do often receive the tail end of tropical storms or hurricanes during this time.</p>
<p>The main high season in Honduras is between January and June, although this extends to September for the Bay Islands. The intense rainy season can hinder much travel, and roads are often blocked due to rock slides and flooding. Activities such as kayaking and white water rafting are best done after the height of the rainy season, and while scuba diving centres in the Bay  Islands are open year-round, the high season is in the dry season. Whale shark sightings off the islands can be done year-round but chances are higher in March and April. Semana Santa is the busiest time of the year for the islands and accommodation should be booked long in advance. In La Moskitia region, the drier seasons of February to May and August to November are the best for travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens; warmer clothes are recommended between November and February and in the mountains. Waterproofs are needed for the wet season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Avianca (<a href="http://www.avianca.com" target="_blank">www.avianca.com</a>) and Aerol&iacute;neas Sosa (<a href="http://www.aerolineasosahn.com" target="_blank">www.aerolineasosahn.com</a>) operate daily services linking Tegucigalpa, San Pedro Sula and other principal towns. Aerol&iacute;neas Sosa runs services to the Bay Islands which connect in La Ceiba. It is not usually necessary to book these in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferries operate between ports on the Pacific and Caribbean coastlines. The Roatan Ferry (<a href="http://www.roatanferry.com" target="_blank">www.roatanferry.com</a>) sails from La Ceiba to the Bays Islands of Roatan and Utila twice daily (journey time - 70 to 75 minutes).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are only three railways and they are isolated, unreliable and limited. Visitors can take a trip from San Pedro Sula on a banana train, and, with some planning, to Cuero y Salado National Park on a coconut train.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of travel within Honduras is by road. Major highways connect the main cities, but driving conditions tend to be fast and erratic and there is heavy commercial traffic.</p>r<p>An all-weather road exists from Tegucigalpa to San Pedro Sula, Puerto Cort&eacute;s, La Ceiba and towns along the Caribbean coast, as well as to the towns around the Gulf of Fonseca in the south. Otherwise road conditions are poor.</p>
<p>During the rainy season, even highways may be closed due to rockslides and flooding. Travellers are advised not to drive at night as many vehicles drive without lights on, streets are badly illuminated and animals wander onto the road.</p><p>There are several coach companies offering short- or long-distance travel between major destinations. Prices and conditions vary from budget options to executive class coaches.</p>
<p>Transporte Rey Express (tel: +504 2237 8561 or 2516 2014; <a href="http://www.reyexpress.hn" target="_blank">www.reyexpress.hn</a>) runs between Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula. Diana Express (tel: +504 509 4886; <a href="http://transportedianaexpress.jimdo.com" target="_blank">http://transportedianaexpress.jimdo.com</a>) runs between Tela, San Pedro Sula and La Ceiba. and Hedman Alas (tel: +504 2516 2273; <a href="http://www.hedmanalas.com" target="_blank">www.hedmanalas.com</a>) is an executive service that connects all the main cities and Guatemala.</p><p>Taxis are not metered, and run on a flat rate within the cities. For all other journeys, be sure to negotiate the fare before setting off. Tipping is not common practice.</p><p>Both international and foreign driving licences are accepted for up to 90 days.</p><p>All drivers and passengers must wear a seatbelt. No vehicles involved in an accident can be moved until the Transit Authority arrives. You should carry identification, including your driving licence, passport copies, and your vehicle registration while driving.</p><p>In the event of an accident call the Transit Authority on 199.</p><p>Self-drive cars are available at the airport.</p><p>Cycling in Honduras is uncommon for visitors and there are few places to rent a bike. Tela, La Ceiba and the Bay Islands have mountain bike rental outfits.</p><p>All drivers and passengers must wear a seatbelt. No vehicles involved in an accident can be moved until the Transit Authority arrives. You should carry identification, including your driving licence, passport copies, and your vehicle registration while driving.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Honduras</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sta_rosade_copaacuten</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Honduras</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">puerto_corteacutes</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Honduras</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">comayagua</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Honduras</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bay_islands</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00*</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) flies direct from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/houston">Houston</a> to Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula, while American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>) operates flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/miami">Miami</a> to Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula. Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) flies from&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/atlanta">Atlanta</a>&nbsp;to Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula.There are no direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>; connections are generally via the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.</p>
<p>Avianca (<a href="http://www.avianca.com" target="_blank">www.avianca.com</a>)&nbsp;offers flights from Honduras to Costa Rica, El Salvador and Guatemala, with onward connections to other destinations in North, Central and South America.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Tegucigalpa: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - at least 17 hours (including stopovers); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 6 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/houston">Houston</a> - 3 hours 10 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$45, which should be included in the air fare. If not, you need to pay in cash or by credit card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Golosón International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Juan Manuel Gálvez International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>San Pedro Sula International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Tegucigalpa Toncontín International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 5km (3 miles) southeast of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Honduras&rsquo; main ports are Amapala, El Henecan, La Ceiba, Puerto Cort&eacute;s, and Roat&aacute;n. Passenger ferries operate shuttles between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belize">Belize</a> and Puerto Cortes, and many small, private vessels enter Honduras from the USA and other parts of Central America and the Caribbean.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no rail services between Honduras and neighbouring countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main road routes into Honduras are from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guatemala">Guatemala</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nicaragua">Nicaragua</a> and El Salvador. It is possible to drive across the borders but long-distance buses are the most common form of travel.</p>
<p>From Guatemala the most popular borders are Corinto (Puerto Cortes) and El Florido (Copan). Crossing with a vehicle is usually straightforward and involves a small fee and presentation of paperwork, although very few rental agencies permit their cars to cross borders.</p>
<p>From Nicaragua the main border crossing is Guasaule, Honduras to Somotillo, Nicaragua. Entering Honduras by car you are asked to fumigate the vehicle and to present all relevant paperwork (car licence, driving licence and passport) and purchase insurance and a standard tourist card.</p>
<p>Long-distance bus companies are of high quality and offer executive coaches, meals, air conditioning and televisions. Hedman Alas (tel: +504 2516 2273; <a href="http://www.hedmanalas.com" target="_blank">www.hedmanalas.com</a>) runs from several destinations in Honduras to Guatemala City and Antigua. Tica Bus (<a href="http://www.ticabus.com" target="_blank">www.ticabus.com</a>) has routes from San Pedro Sula to Managua, Nicaragua, and from Tegucigalpa to Managua and San Salvador.</p>
<p>Local minibuses stop at the borders from where you can get a connection on the other side. Some private minibus shuttles offer routes from Cop&aacute;n Ruinas to Guatemala.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The international dialling code for Honduras is 504. Direct dial international calls are available in major towns and the Bay Islands, but in other areas it may be necessary to call the international operator on 193. Call centres, hotels and pay phones are widely available. There are no area codes within Honduras. There is relatively good mobile phone reception throughout the country, and pay-as-you-go phones can be bought cheaply from major operators such as Tigo, Claro, Hondutel and Digicel. Foreign mobile phones must be quad-band to be used in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies. Coverage is generally good along the coasts and around major towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes exist in major towns and Wi-Fi is becoming more common in major urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The media is restricted by punitive defamation laws which, in certain cases, require journalists to reveal their sources. Journalists tend to exercise self-censorship in order to avoid offending the political or economic interests of the media bigwigs, and cases of journalists accepting bribes from officials who wish to influence coverage are not unknown.</p>
<p>Daily newspapers are in Spanish and privately owned. They include <em>El Heraldo</em>, <em>La Prensa</em>, <em>El Tiempo</em> and <em>La Tribuna</em>. The weekly <em>Honduras This Week</em> is published in English. Televicentro operates Telesistema Hondureno, Canal 5 El Lider and Telecadena 7 y 4. Other networks are: CBC Canal 6, Vica TV and SOTEL Canal 11. Radio America and Radio HRN are both privately-owned national radio stations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes between four and seven days.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1200 and 1400-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Celebrate Easter in Comayagua</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If heritage and history are your thing, you'll love Comayagua. The first capital of Honduras is a masterpiece of Spanish colonial architecture: cobbled streets, tiny plazas, whitewashed houses and grand churches, all of which frankly upstage rather tatty Tegucigalpa. The best time to visit is during the unique and fervent celebrations of Easter week (Semana Santa).</p>]]><p><b>Climb Copán’s magnificent ruins</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ancient city of Copán is one of the wonders of the Maya world, a major testament to this advanced culture, most notable for its intricately carved stelae. Highlights of the ruins include the magnificent Acropolis, the Great Plaza, and the Court of the Hieroglyphic Stairway. Base yourself in the charming nearby town of Copán, with its cobbled streets and excellent hotels and restaurants.</p>]]><p><b>Discover La Mosquiitia, Central America’s Amazon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This vast and untamed wilderness is characterised by tropical forests, swamps, rivers and mangroves, and is one of the premier ecotourism destinations in the Americas. At its heart is the Rio Plátano Biosphere Reserve, a UNESCO World Heritage Site teeming with wildlife. Jump aboard a motorised dugout canoe and embark on a safari, staying in a straw-roofed hut in a riverside indigenous village.</p>]]><p><b>Fly through the forest canopy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try canopy touring: a series of cables are fixed from tree to tree and, attached to a pulley while wearing a harness, you can 'fly' through the rainforest's canopy. Honduras' abundance of thick rainforests and jungles provide ideal opportunities for thrill-seeking canopy tours, with numerous circuits on the Bay Islands, Copán and Sambo Creek, on the north coast near La Ceiba.</p>]]><p><b>Get to know the local wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Honduras' wildlife refuges and national parks offer an exciting, unspoiled landscape, a multitude of flora and fauna, and huge biodiversity including rare mammals such as jaguars, pumas, ocelots, anteaters and tapirs. Tropical and pine forests, mountains, coastal wetlands and huge rivers create a wonderful opportunity for eco-tourism, with high-quality accommodation and expert local guides.</p>]]><p><b>Go birdwatching on Lake Yojoa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Honduras' largest freshwater lake is a magnet for hundreds of species of birds and considered the country's premier birding destination. Flanked by the highway between Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula, the lake is surrounded by coffee plantations, hot springs, caves and waterfalls; and there are plenty of hiking and fishing opportunities along its shores. Lakeside restaurants also serve up some of the tastiest fish dishes in the region.</p>]]><p><b>Hike in Pico Bonito National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take advantage of the excellent hiking on offer in Pico Bonito National Park, near La Ceiba on the north coast. It offers dense green jungle, steep mountainsides, sparkling waterfalls and world-class birding. Pico Bonito itself is a challenging, climb, but there are plenty of gentler hikes through the vast park.</p>]]><p><b>Hop aboard a wildlife boat safari</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nature guides lead boat tours along the winding canals of the Cuero y Salado Wildlife Refuge on the edge of the Pico Bonito National Park, which provides a wildlife habitat for monkeys, alligators and manatees, and some 200 species of birds. Drift through these vast wetlands that lead all the way to the Caribbean Sea and don't forget your binoculars.</p>]]><p><b>Relive the pirate history of Trujillo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Play at being a pirate in Trujillo on Honduras' gorgeous Caribbean coast. Once a thriving port and a former capital of colonial Honduras, Trujillo is today home to many old Spanish buildings, a fascinating pirate history and superb tropical beaches. Nearby are several traditional Garifuna villages and the city is surrounded by national parks.</p>]]><p><b>Scuba dive over coral reefs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The crystalline waters and pristine coral reefs of the Bay Islands provide some of Central America's best dive sites. The islands are one of the world's top destinations for learning to dive, with warm, calm waters and high quality, reasonably priced dive centres. And if you already have your PADI certificate, you can also take courses in underwater photography, cave diving and instructor training.</p>]]><p><b>Splash out in the Bay Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The exotic archipelago of the English-speaking Bay Islands is famed as one of the world's premier diving destinations and home to some of Honduras' top beach resorts. Hilly, tropical Guanaja and Roatán are protected by a great coral reef. Backpackers' favourite Utila has sandy beaches ringed by tiny cays shaded by palm trees. There are several smaller islands worth visiting, including the Cayos Cochinos.</p>]]><p><b>Swim with whale sharks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Bay Islands are considered one of the best locations to spot the world's largest fish, the whale shark. Measuring up to 10m (33ft) in length, these gentle, plankton-eating creatures glide through the waters and it is possible to slip gently into the water and swim alongside them. The Utila Whale Shark and Oceanic Research Centre runs excursions all year round, with the highest numbers seen in March and April.</p>]]><p><b>Tackle the white-water rapids</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience some of Central America's best white-water rafting along the Cangrejal River, near La Ceiba. The steep terrain of the Pico Bonito National Park creates raging rivers and waterfalls, the most spectacular of which is the Cangrejal. Several outfits offer jungle lodges and rafting experiences outside of rainy season, with the wettest months from August to December.</p>]]><p><b>Take on Tegucigalpa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Admire the view across Tegucigalpa, the temperate capital city, from the site of its Christ of the Picacho monument, set atop the eponymous mountain to the north. Be sure to take a look around the city itself too; it has a certain rough-edged charm, especially the old historical centre with its colonial buildings and winding stone streets.</p>]]><p><b>Try spelunking in Talgua Caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Also known as the 'Caves of the Glowing Skulls', because of the sparkling reflection off the human bones found here, these caves in the northeast near Catacamas are a spelunker's paradise. The caves have been used by various ethnic groups since pre-Colombian times and are rich in Maya archaeology. Hire a guide as they are well hidden but worth seeking out.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$18.4 billion (2013).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Apparel, coffee, bananas, shrimp, lobster, cigars and timber.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fabric, machinery, chemicals, petroleum and plastic and paper articles.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Guatemala, Mexico, Germany and China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The economy of Honduras, the second poorest country in Central  America, relies on agriculture and timber. Light industry produces a variety of consumer goods and there is a small mining industry. The economy draws heavily on various forms of US-sponsored aid. Inflation is 5.2% (2012) and annual growth 3.5% (2012). Growth is dependent on the US economy, the continued export of non-traditional products such as melons and shrimp, and the reduction of the high crime rate. Almost 60% of the country&rsquo;s population lives below the poverty line. <br />
<br />
Honduras suffers from massive unemployment and extremely uneven distribution of wealth. Export earnings have been badly hit in recent years by low world prices and slack demand within the Central American Common Market, of which Honduras is a member. Almost half of the country&rsquo;s economic activity is tied to the USA and the US-Central America-Dominican Republic Free Trade Agreement (CAFTA-DR) which came into force in 2006 and helped increase foreign investment. However, political and physical instability, along with crime and corruption still pose problems to future growth.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is customary to address a professional person by his or her title, particularly on first meeting or during early acquaintance. Businesspeople are generally expected to dress smartly and some dining rooms require men to wear a jacket. There are very few local interpreter or translation services available. Though many businesspeople throughout the country also speak English, correspondence should be in Spanish.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1400-1700, Sat 0800-1100.<br /><br /><strong>Government offices:</strong> Mon-Fri 0830-1200 and 1300-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cámara de Comercio e Industrias de Tegucigalpa</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 232 4200
					Website:http://www.ccit.hn
					Address: Apdo 3444,Bulevar Centroamérica,Tegucigalpa,]]><b>Cámara de Comercio Hondureño-Americana</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 232 7043
					Website:http://www.amcham.hn2.com
					Address: Apdo 1838,Sección Comercial Hotel Honduras Maya,Tegucigalpa,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>While Honduras isn't famed for its cuisine, there are some very tasty local dishes that are worth trying, including distinct regional varieties. There is a decent choice of restaurants and bars in Tegucigalpa, San Pedro Sula and other cities, where fast food plays an increasingly big role.</p><p>Beans, rice and tortillas are a staple of many dishes, while plantains are cooked in a surprising numbers of ways. Pork is widely eaten, as is chicken and beef. Fish and seafood are staples in coastal areas and the Bay Islands, where the Garifuna (Black Carib) add chilli and coconut milk to their spicier dishes.</p><p>The main meal of the day is lunch and is often a 'plato típico' of beef, refried beans, tortillas, sour cream, pickled cabbage, rice and fried plantain. Although Honduran food isn't generally spicy, most local restaurants keep a bottle of hot sauce on the table.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Plato t&iacute;pico:</strong> A mixed platter of steak, plantain chips, pickled cabbage, beans, rice sour cream and tortillas; translates as &lsquo;typical dish&rsquo; and variations using all or some of these ingredients are found in any eatery in the country.<br />
<strong>Baleadas:</strong> Flour tortillas filled with refried beans, a hard, crumbly cheese, sour cream and often pickled onions. Avocados, scrambled eggs or meat can be added. These are a common staple of the country.<br />
<strong>Enchiladas:</strong> A flat corn tortilla, fried and topped with ground beef or pork, cheese and a non-spicy tomato sauce.<br />
<strong>Pastelito:</strong> A folded, deep-fried flour or corn tortilla filled with beef or chicken, rice and/or potatoes and spices.<br />
<strong>Tamales:</strong> Fresh corn cakes sometimes served with cheese, chillies or raisins.<br />
<strong>Sopa de caracol:</strong> Conch soup, made with coconut milk, conch (or crab or fish), cassava, green plantains and coriander.<br />
<strong>Yojoa fish:</strong> Spiced, fried whole fish from Yojoa Lake; a popular delicacy served fresh at lakeside stalls and restaurants.<br />
<strong>Anafres:</strong> Black bean stew with melted cheese, served with corn chips. Named after the clay pot in which it&rsquo;s cooked; commonly eaten as a starter or light meal.<br />
<strong>Pinchos:</strong> Kebab skewers, of meat or fish, with vegetables.<br />
<strong>Tapado:</strong> Fish and seafood stew, a Garifuna speciality, popular in the Bay Islands.<br />
<strong>Licuados:</strong> Milkshakes made from fruits such as mangoes, pineapples, watermelons and bananas.<br />
<strong>Beer:</strong> Mostly blonde lagers, including <em>Port Royal</em>, <em>Imperial </em>and <em>Barena; Salva Vida </em>is a more malty alternative.<br />
<strong>Rum:</strong> the most popular local spirit, with Flor de Ca&ntilde;a one of the best labels, also Pirate&rsquo;s Grog from the Bay Islands.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Service is included in most restaurant bills. In hotels, cafes and restaurants, 10% of the bill is customary where service is not included.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Honduras has a vibrant nightlife and locals love to dance and have a good time. Music bars and clubs can be found in the main cities, and Tegucigalpa and other tourist spots have many of the best-known clubs in the country. There are also casinos in the major cities, plus many bars, some of which offer happy hours.</p>
<p>Reggaeton music pours out of the rustic, Caribbean-themed bars in Roatan and Utila, many of which have been built on wooden jetties perfect for watching the dramatic sunsets with a rum in hand. Trujillo also has a good selection of beachfront bars. San Pedro Sula has its share of bars and dance clubs, and there are some more international, low-key bars in hotels, along with a handful of arts centres.</p>
<p>It is worth remembering however, that crime is a serious problem in Honduras and at night, tourists are prime targets for criminals. Don't go out with large sums of cash, don't wear fancy jewellery or watches, and be careful not to consume too much alcohol. The Bay Islands are considered safer than the mainland but care should still be taken, especially in Roatan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From air conditioned shopping malls to traditional markets and big name mega stores Honduras has a wide variety of shops. For visitors to the country, the best shopping is undoubtedly at the local markets where artisans and local craftsmen offer their wares at extremely affordable prices.</p>
<p>Copan is a centre for crafts and bohemian-style shops and stalls have artists displaying everything from jade jewellery to colonial-style paintings, wooden carvings and accessories. At other markets, such as the Guamilito Market in San Pedro Sula and San Isidro Market in Tegucigalpa, typical craft items include woodcarvings, cigars, leather goods, straw hats and bags, Guatemalan hand woven fabric, Lenca pottery and paintings. Traditional Garifuna crafts can be found in Tela and the Bay Islands which reflect their coastal heritage and utilise items such as wood, seashells and coconuts.</p>
<p>Some haggling is common in craft markets, although in general bartering is not part of Honduran culture. Start at half the initial asking price and light-heartedly barter to an agreed price from there.</p>
<p>In addition to crafts, markets are the centre of local life where everything from fruit and vegetables to household items to clothes can be found.</p>
<p>Malls are gaining popularity with middle class Hondurans and a range of international brand shops can be found within. Another popular shopping venue is bus stations, and in major terminals such as San Pedro Sula there are plenty of shops selling cheap clothes, shoes and costume jewellery.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1330-1800; Sat 0800-1700.</p><p>Refrain from buying anything made of coral (especially black coral) as the reefs are protected. Be very cautious when buying anything made from animal products unless 100% certain that it is not from an endangered species. Souvenirs made from turtle shells, endangered birds and mammals are unfortunately for sale.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Honduras vary considerably in style, comfort and price. Good quality hotels are available in both Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula, which are used mainly by business travellers. International chains such as Marriott, Crowne Plaza and Hilton are represented with standards equal to the USA and UK. The tourist office (www.letsgohonduras.com/) can supply lists of hotels with accommodation details.</p>
<p>In Roatan, resort-style hotels of high quality are commonplace and attract mainly North American tourists. Throughout the rest of the country however, hotels can be somewhat rustic and simple, with limited facilities and lower standards of comfort. With the exception of the Bay Islands, most hotels in Honduras don&rsquo;t have peak season rates, although prices in Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula are higher during the week. During the Semana Santa holidays when Hondurans visit the Bay Islands in great numbers accommodation prices more than double and are booked up months ahead. <strong><br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong></strong>Hotels are split into three categories (upper, middle and lower) according to standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are some excellent B&Bs in Honduras that cater mainly to budget travellers, most of which are found in tourist areas. These can range from wooden beachside inns to jungle lodges. In Honduras these tend to be very hospitable and offer a basic but comfortable selection of amenities. With safety as a constant concern, it is advisable to check that your bed and breakfast has good quality gates, locks and security measures.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Honduras vary considerably in style, comfort and price. Good quality hotels are available in both Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula, which are used mainly by business travellers. International chains such as Marriott, Crowne Plaza and Hilton are represented with standards equal to the USA and UK. The tourist office (www.letsgohonduras.com/) can supply lists of hotels with accommodation details.</p>
<p>In Roatan, resort-style hotels of high quality are commonplace and attract mainly North American tourists. Throughout the rest of the country however, hotels can be somewhat rustic and simple, with limited facilities and lower standards of comfort. With the exception of the Bay Islands, most hotels in Honduras don&rsquo;t have peak season rates, although prices in Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula are higher during the week. During the Semana Santa holidays when Hondurans visit the Bay Islands in great numbers accommodation prices more than double and are booked up months ahead. <strong><br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong></strong>Hotels are split into three categories (upper, middle and lower) according to standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Honduras vary considerably in style, comfort and price. Good quality hotels are available in both Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula, which are used mainly by business travellers. International chains such as Marriott, Crowne Plaza and Hilton are represented with standards equal to the USA and UK. The tourist office (www.letsgohonduras.com/) can supply lists of hotels with accommodation details.</p>
<p>In Roatan, resort-style hotels of high quality are commonplace and attract mainly North American tourists. Throughout the rest of the country however, hotels can be somewhat rustic and simple, with limited facilities and lower standards of comfort. With the exception of the Bay Islands, most hotels in Honduras don&rsquo;t have peak season rates, although prices in Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula are higher during the week. During the Semana Santa holidays when Hondurans visit the Bay Islands in great numbers accommodation prices more than double and are booked up months ahead. <strong><br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong></strong>Hotels are split into three categories (upper, middle and lower) according to standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is recommended. The main hospitals are in Tegucigalpa and San Pedro Sula. However all the large towns have a hospital. Mosquito nets are recommended for coastal areas to minimise the risk of malaria and dengue fever. There are scuba diving recompression chambers on the islands of Roatan and Utila.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should first be boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised in rural areas and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled. Avoid meat and dairy when eating from markets or street vendors.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Dengue fever and American trypanosomiasis (Chagas disease) may occur. Hepatitis B is present. HIV/AIDS is a growing problem.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Below are listed Public Holidays for the January 2014-December 2015 period.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Maundy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Holy Saturday :
							31 March </p><p>Day of the Americas :
							14 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							15 September </p><p>D :
							12 October </p><p>Armed Forces Day :
							21 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Honduras without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 500g of tobacco in any form.<br />
&bull; 5L of wine or spirits.<br />
&bull; 2kg of confectionery.<br />
&bull; Goods up to a total value of US$500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include meat, fish, vegetables, fruit, dairy items, unlicensed arms and ammunition, and pornographic media or literature. Spearfishing is illegal and scuba divers may therefore not enter the country with spear guns.</p>
<p>Plants may be brought in with appropriate phytosanitary certificates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is prohibited to take any genuine archaeological items out of the country. Likewise, the coral reefs are protected and therefore you cannot take corals out of Honduras.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lempira (HNL; symbol L) = 100 centavos. Notes are in denominations of L500, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 centavos, although smaller coins are rarely used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pounds Sterling cannot normally be exchanged; visitors should therefore take US Dollars, which are easily exchanged in banks, major hotels, airports and bureaux de change. The bureaux de change usually offer a quicker service and better rate than banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted. Some banks offer cash withdrawal with Visa or Mastercard.</p><p>Found throughout the country, and most accept foreign cards. For safety reasons many operate a locked door system which uses a card to enter and it is advised to use machines in shopping centres and busy areas and only during the day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1600 (some banks open until 1800). Some branches open Sat 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months from the date of arrival in Honduras is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no transit visa for Honduras and visitors passing through the country must obtain a tourist visa if required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry tourist/business visa: US$30; multiple-entry tourist visa: US$60.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visas are valid for 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Those who wish to stay in Honduras for a limited amount of time need to obtain a Special Permanent Residency visa. All applications must be filed by a local lawyer and it can be a lengthy process. Applications are handled by the Honduran Immigration Service (Direcci&oacute;n General de Migraci&oacute;n y Extranjer&iacute;a) and are valid for five years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals who do require a visa must provide proof of sufficient funds with their application.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pet dogs and cats require a veterinarian health certificate, plus an import permit from the Secretar&iacute;a de Agricultura y Ganader&iacute;a. In addition, dog owners must provide a certificate of vaccination against rabies, distemper and hepatitis.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[14.973972]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-86.267005]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>112,090 sq km (43,278 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>8,189,501 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>78 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tegucigalpa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Honduras shares borders in the southeast with Nicaragua, in the west with Guatemala, and in the southwest with El Salvador. To the north lies the Caribbean, with which it has 669 km (416 miles) of coastline and to the south, the Pacific  Ocean. The interior of the country comprises a central mountain system running from east to west, cut by rivers flowing into both the Caribbean and Pacific. The lowlands in the south form a plain along the Pacific coast, while the highest point in the country is Cerro Las Minas at 2,870m (9,416 ft) above sea level.</p>
<p>The Gulf of Fonseca in the southwest contains many islands which have volcanic peaks. The large fertile valleys of the northern Caribbean lowlands are cultivated with banana plantations. However, large areas of land in Honduras are unsuitable for cultivation. The majority of the population lives in the western half of the country, while the second-largest concentration of people is in the Cort&eacute;s area which extends northwards from Lake Yojoa towards the Caribbean.</p>
<p>Along the Caribbean shore is the virtually uninhabited La Moskitia Coast. The Bay Islands, which consist of Roatan, Utila and Guanaja (along with Cayos Cochinos) are located to the north of the country, a few miles off the coast of La Ceiba. They are low-lying islands, surrounded by many cays, and are part of the Mesoamerican Barrier Reef.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic majority (97%), Protestant minority (3%).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Honduras has several distinct ethnic groups of which 90% are mestizo (mixed Amerindian and European), 7% Amerindian, 2% black and 1% white. There <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/i/ski/are">are</a> strong Spanish influences, but the majority of the population is mestizo, mainly leading an agricultural way of life with a low standard of living. Many rural communities can still be found living a relatively unchanged, traditional lifestyle.</p>
<p>Social courtesies should be observed. It is customary for a guest at dinner or someone's home to send flowers to the hostess, either before or afterwards. Conservative casual wear is widely acceptable with dress tending to be less conservative in coastal areas. Beachwear and shorts should not be worn away from the beach or poolside. Hotels, restaurants and shops include a 12% sales tax on all purchases. There is a strong sense of community, and religious and local festivities hold great importance in Honduran life with traditional music, costume and customs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. American-style flat two-pin plugs (with or without grounding pin) are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Juan Orlando Hern&aacute;ndez since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Juan Orlando Hern&aacute;ndez since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Maya civilisation reached modern-day Honduras around AD 500, and dominated the region for the next 300 years, after which several different local ethnic groups took their place.</p>
<p>Contact with Europeans began soon after Christopher Columbus landed in 1502 and during the early 1520s the region was subjugated by a variety of conquistador expeditions, each of which laid claim to a part of it. Only after the discovery of gold and silver deposits in the 1540s was some order imposed on the region.</p>
<p>Once the deposits were exhausted at the end of the 16th century, Honduras became a colonial backwater and remained so until the collapse of the Spanish Empire in the Americas in the early-19th century. During the early 20th century, Honduras was governed by a series of caudillos, notably President Tiburcio Carias Andino who dominated the country during the 1930s and 1940s.</p>
<p>While the peaceful environment that Carias Andino created allowed for social and economic progress, this was at the price of serious internal repression and kowtowing to powerful foreign interests. From the late 1950s onwards, weak civilian governments prompted the army to assume a greater role, launching several coups.</p>
<p>During the 1980s, Honduras was the main base for the US-backed 'Contra' rebels fighting the Sandinista government in Nicaragua. Soon after the end of that war in 1989, national elections were held. The two parties, the Partido Nacional (PN) and the Partido Liberal (PL), fought for the presidency, which was won by the PN candidate Rafael Leonardo Callejas.</p>
<p>The 1990s, however, were dominated by the PL, which gained control of the presidency and legislature in 1994 and in 1997. In 1998, Hurricane Mitch swept violently across Honduras causing devastating damage. Almost 15,000 people died, 80% of the transportation infrastructure was destroyed and the resulting damage cost some US$3.8 billion.</p>
<p>PL leader Manuel Zelaya Rosales emerged the victor in the 2005 elections, defeating Porfirio Lobo of the PN. However, in 2009, following Zelaya&rsquo;s call for a change to the constitution, the army ousted him and Roberto Micheletti took over. In 2009 , following sustained pressure from international bodies including the Organization of American States and the United Nations, democratic general elections were held, resulting in victory for Lobo.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The term &lsquo;Banana Republic&rsquo; was coined by US writer O. Henry, inspired by the United Fruit Company&rsquo;s powerful control of Honduran exports in the early 20th century.<br />
&bull;	Mosquitia, in eastern Honduras, is known as the &lsquo;Little Amazon&rsquo;, because of its having the largest tract of prime rainforest north of the actual Amazon Basin.<br />
&bull;	Following a World-Cup preliminary football match Honduras and El Salvador declared what was subsequently known as the &lsquo;Football War&rsquo;, which lasted 100 hours and resulting in the expulsion of some 130,000 illegal Salvadoran immigrants from Honduras.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Honduras in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 966 7702 or 737 1972 (consular section). </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.hondurasemb.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 966 7702 or 737 1972 (consular section). </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0800-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Suite 4M<br/>3007 Tilden Street,NW<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Honduras in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7486 4880. </p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7486 4880. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>115 Gloucester Place<br/>London<br/>W1U 6JT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Guatemala]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>2380 7300.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/guatemala</p><p><b>Tel:</b>2380 7300.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0730-1230, 1330-1630; Fri 0730-1130.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Edificio Torre Internacional, Nivel 11, 16 Calle 0-55, Zona 10<br/>Guatemala City<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The second-largest country in Central America &ndash; and also one of the poorest &ndash; Honduras is once ugly and beautiful. Behind the reefs and rainforests, it has the unfortunate claim to being the murder capital of the world and the high crime risk means visitors should be cautious at all times. Some may advise against visiting altogether, but to do so would be to miss out &ndash; for Honduras has much to offer those adventurous enough to visit.</p>
<p>The Bay Islands are perhaps the country&rsquo;s biggest drawing card. The archipelago offers some of the best diving in Central America, not to mention the chance to swim with dolphins and come face to face with whale sharks. The less adventurous can lounge in hammocks and soak up the party vibe, if that sounds too wild.</p>
<p>Back on the mainland, sweeping Caribbean beaches are scattered with charming towns such as Trujillo, with its pirate history, and traditional Garifuna villages, whose Afro-Caribbean culture is an integral part of the national identity. The great Pico Bonito National Park boasts jaguars, monkeys and countless bird species, while the Rio Pl&aacute;tano Biosphere Reserve, a UNESCO World Heritage Site, teems with exotic wildlife and indigenous communities.</p>
<p>In the midst of all this nature, Honduras&rsquo; cities are easily forgotten and although soaring crime rates in the likes of San Pedro Sula keep visitors away, it would be a shame to miss out on the colonial architecture of the capital city Tegucigalpa, the Semana Santa celebrations in Comayagua or the lively carnival in La Ceiba.</p>
<p>It may be troubled, but Honduras is a passionate nation, where religion, tradition and family values are the backbone of society and where a love for the national football team can unite even ardent enemies. It is a country where tortillas and beans are served with every meal, where hips swing to Latino beats and the national beer is called Salva Vida, meaning &ldquo;lifesaver.&rdquo; It is a country of untamed beauty and wild tropical adventure. Just tread carefully.</p><p>The second-largest country in Central America &ndash; and also one of the poorest &ndash; Honduras is once ugly and beautiful. Behind the reefs and rainforests, it has the unfortunate claim to being the murder capital of the world and the high crime risk means visitors should be cautious at all times. Some may advise against visiting altogether, but to do so would be to miss out &ndash; for Honduras has much to offer those adventurous enough to visit. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
