<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Hungary" ColCode="hun" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="hu" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Hungary]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hungary has a mild continental climate. There are four distinct seasons, with a very warm summer from June to August where temperatures can rise to as high as 35&deg;C (95&deg;F). Spring and autumn are mild, while winters are very cold, as low as -10&deg;C (14&deg;F), and not a good time to visit rural areas &ndash; although city breaks are enjoyable at any time of year. The south of the country around P&eacute;cs is a little warmer on average, although the region still experiences snowfall in winter. Annual rainfall is an average of 6cm (23 inches) and is relatively evenly distributed throughout the year, with snowfall common in winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights for summer, medium weight clothing for spring and heavier clothing for autumn and winter. Waterproofs can prove useful at any time of year. Long-sleeved shirts, trousers, boots and hats should be worn to protect exposed skin in forested, grassy and lakeside areas in summer to prevent bites from ticks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no scheduled domestic flights within Hungary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are regular MAHART (tel: +36 1 484 4013; <a href="http://www.mahartpassnave.hu" target="_blank">www.mahartpassnave.hu</a>) ferry services on the Danube from spring to late autumn linking Budapest with Szentendre, V&aacute;c, Visegr&aacute;d and Esztergom. On Lake Balaton, Balaton Shipping Co. (tel: +36 84 312 144; <a href="http://www.balatonihajozas.hu" target="_blank">www.balatonihajozas.hu</a>) operates ferries between most of the major towns on the lake from April to October.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Services are operated by M&Aacute;V (tel: 06 40 494 949, in Hungary only or +36 1 444 4499; <a href="http://www.mav.hu" target="_blank">www.mav.hu</a>). All main cities are linked by efficient services and the most popular tourist rail routes are Budapest-Kecskem&eacute;t-Szeged and Budapest-Si&oacute;fok-Lake Balaton. Supplements are payable on express, EuroCity (EC) and InterCity (IC) trains, with reservations compulsory for the latter.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Hungary. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Hungary Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Hungary. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Cheap fares:</strong>&nbsp;available for groups, children, students, families, pensioners and people with certain disabilities. Season tickets are also available. The Hungary Card (<a href="http://www.hungarycard.hu" target="_blank">www.hungarycard.hu</a>) offers discounts on rail, bus, taxi and MAHART ferry services, as well as accommodation, restaurants, museums and road tolls.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hungary has a modern and efficient road system. Tolls are payable on some roads and all motorways.</p>r<p>Most roads in Hungary are of good quality.</p><p>Regular coach services connect towns throughout the country. Most run via one of Pest&rsquo;s three major bus stations: N&eacute;pliget, Stadion and &Aacute;rp&aacute;d. The national bus company is Vol&aacute;nbusz (tel: +36 1 382 0888; <a href="http://www.volanbusz.hu/en" target="_blank">www.volanbusz.hu/en</a>), which also represents Eurolines, while Orangeways (tel: +36 30 182 6630; <a href="http://www.orangeways.com" target="_blank">www.orangeways.com</a>) operates services to surrounding countries.</p><p>Taxis, which can be found in all major towns and cities, are reliable and reasonably priced.</p><p>Pink format EU licences are accepted. An International Driving Permit is required if an EU licence is not held.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (50mph) on main roads and 130kph (75mph) on motorways. Seat belts must be worn. Children of 16 years and under must sit in the rear and child seats are compulsory. It is obligatory to keep headlights dipped when driving, and the use of handheld mobile phones is prohibited. There is a zero tolerance policy concerning drink driving &ndash; it is illegal to have any level of alcohol in the bloodstream when driving.</p><p>Magyar Aut&oacute;club (the Hungarian Automobile Club) (tel: 188, in Hungary only; <a href="http://www.autoklub.hu" target="_blank">www.autoklub.hu</a>) operates a 24-hour emergency breakdown service.</p><p>International and local car hire firms are located in all of Hungary's main towns and at Budapest Ferenc Liszt International Airport. The minimum age for car rental is 21 years.</p><p>You can hire bikes from some hotels in Budapest and outlets such as Budapest Bike (tel: +36 30 944 5533; <a href="http://www.budapestbike.hu" target="_blank">www.budapestbike.hu</a>) and Yellow Zebra (tel: +36 1 269 3843;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.yellowzebrabikes.com" target="_blank">www.yellowzebrabikes.com</a>).</p>
<p>As rural Hungary is fairly flat, getting around the countryside by bike is reasonably easy. Between towns, busy highways should be avoided in favour of quieter country roads. Heavy traffic in Budapest city centre can make cycling challenging, but there are dedicated cycle paths around the city as well as cycle lanes that run along the Danube.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (50mph) on main roads and 130kph (75mph) on motorways. Seat belts must be worn. Children of 16 years and under must sit in the rear and child seats are compulsory. It is obligatory to keep headlights dipped when driving, and the use of handheld mobile phones is prohibited. There is a zero tolerance policy concerning drink driving &ndash; it is illegal to have any level of alcohol in the bloodstream when driving.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost all towns and cities in Hungary have a well-established and efficient public transport system that consists of buses, and occasionally trolley buses. Budapest, Debrecen, Szeged and Miskolc also have trams.</p>
<p><strong>Budapest:</strong> Budapest Travel Limited (BKV) (tel: +36 1 325 5255; <a href="http://www.bkv.hu" target="_blank">www.bkv.hu</a>) operates buses, trolleybuses, trams and underground trains in the capital. Tickets must be purchased in advance and validated for travel. The city also has a night bus service and a suburban railway (HEV). Day passes and season tickets are available.</p>
<p><strong>Debrecen:</strong> The Public Transport Company of Debrecen (DKV) (tel: +36 52 502 640; <a href="http://www.dkv.hu" target="_blank">www.dkv.hu</a>)&nbsp;operates buses, trams and trolleybuses in Hungary's second city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Hungary</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">szeged</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.20</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Hungary</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">miskolc</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.55</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Hungary</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">lake_balaton</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Hungary</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">debrecen</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.40</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to Hungary from the UK&nbsp;are operated by British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>),&nbsp;easyJet (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.easyjet.com">www.easyjet.com</a>), Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) and Wizz (<a href="http://www.wizzair.com" target="_blank">www.wizzair.com</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hungary/budapest-ferihegy-airport">Budapest Ferenc Liszt International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/budapest">Budapest</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 25 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 11 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Budapest Ferenc Liszt International Airport</b><![CDATA[https://www.bud.hu<p>Budapest Ferenc Liszt International Airport is located 23km (14.3 miles) southeast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/budapest">Budapest</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+36 1 296 7000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Danube River runs through the country west to east passing through Budapest and is navigable all of the way. In addition to Budapest, a few other minor ports are located on the River Danube, but services to/from these do not connect to neighbouring countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>M&Aacute;V (tel: 06 40 494 949, in Hungary only or +36 1 444 4499; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.mav.hu">www.mav.hu</a>) operates Hungary's rail network. International routes include direct trains from Belgrade, Berlin, Ljubljana, Vienna and Zurich.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (www.eurail.com).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Anyone driving from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> has to travel via the Channel Tunnel (tel: +44 8443 353 535, in the UK; <a href="http://www.eurotunnel.co.uk" target="_blank">www.eurotunnel.co.uk</a>).</p>
<p>Coming from northwest Europe, the M1 motorway from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vienna">Vienna</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bratislava">Bratislava</a> enters Hungary just before the city of Gy&ouml;r and continues on to the Hungarian capital. The main route from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia">Croatia</a> in the southwest follows the south shore of Lake Balaton to become the M7 motorway that leads to Budapest. The M5 motorway leads south from Budapest to Szeged, from where there are nearby border crossings to both <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/serbia">Serbia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/romania">Romania</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Most public telephones use phone cards, which can be purchased from newsagents, hotels and post offices. The area code for Budapest is: 1. If dialling beyond the capital or to mobile phones, callers must prefix the number with the national dialling code: 06, and then the two-digit area code.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with major international mobile phone companies. Coverage is generally good. A local prepaid SIM card may be bought relatively inexpensively to make and receive calls within Hungary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is ubiquitous and often free in hotels, restaurants and bars. There are internet caf&eacute;s in most towns, and some libraries have free terminals. Connections are generally good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is generally a high level of freedom in Hungary's media. The country's private broadcast media compete with state-run radio and TV. Public radio services  compete with numerous local radio stations and national commercial services. Hungary's national and local newspapers are independent and privately owned, some by foreign groups and investors. </p>
<p>National dailies include <em>Magyar H&iacute;rlap</em>, <em>N&eacute;pszabads&aacute;g</em> and <em>Blikk</em>. Hungary&rsquo;s main TV broadcasters are <em>Magyar Telev&iacute;zi&oacute;</em> (operating two channels) and <em>Duna TV</em> (satellite). Private TV stations include <em>TV2</em> and <em>RTL Klub</em>. Public radio broadcasters include <em>Magyar R&aacute;di&oacute;</em> (operating <em>Kossuth</em>, <em>Petőfi</em> and <em>Bart&oacute;k</em> networks, plus <em>Radio Budapest</em>, an external service). Private radio broadcasters include <em>Danubius Radio</em>, <em>Est</em> and <em>Juventus</em>. A number of English-language newspapers are published in Hungary; these include the <em>Budapest Business Journal</em>, <em>Budapest Times</em>, the <em>Budapest Sun</em> and <em>The Hungarian Quarterly</em>. The monthly <em>Where Budapest</em> has useful listings for shopping, dining and entertainment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Hungarian postal system is reasonably efficient and reliable. Airmail takes three days to one week to reach other European destinations.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1800, Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Buda Castle Palace</p><![CDATA[<p>Located in Budapest's picturesque Old Town, Buda Castle Palace was first inhabited by King Béla of Hungary during the 13th century. The king, who fled to the Adriatic Sea in 1241 following the Mongol invasion, returned to live in the palace, building a stronghold to protect the palace from further attack. Over a period of 700 years, the palace was home to many royal residents, including King Lajos the Great, King Matthias I and King Charles III. Today, the palace is home to a number of museums, including the Ludwig Museum, the Hungarian National Gallery and the Budapest History Museum.<br /><br /><br />Address: I Budvári Palota, Dísz tér 17, Budapest, Hungary</p>]]><br/><p>Budapest Central Synagogue</p><![CDATA[<p>Budapest Central Synagogue is the largest synagogue in Europe and the second largest in the world after the Emanuel Synagogue in New York. Completed in 1859, it was built in a Moorish-Byzantine style by the Austrian architect Ludwig Förster. The building was partly destroyed by bombing campaigns during World War II, but has been the subject of much renovation to restore its two shining Moorish domes to their former brilliance. The Jewish Museum next door recounts the horrors of the Holocaust and displays exhibits dating as far back as the Middle Ages. The museum, which was built between 1931 and 1936, stands on the former home of Theodor Herzl, who was the founding father of Zionism and responsible for developing the idea of a modern Jewish state.<br /><br />Address: Nagy Zsinagóga, VII. Dohány utca 2, Budapest, Hungary</p>]]><br/><p>Caves of Aggtelek</p><![CDATA[<p>The Caves of Aggtelek are located in the Aggtelek National Park  in northeastern Hungary, bordering Slovakia. Aggtelek was the  country's first national park that was set up to protect its geological  formations. Formed in shallow seas during the Triassic Period over 200  million years ago, the park lies on limestone bedrock that is prone to  karstification - the natural creation of caverns and sinkholes. There  are over 260 caves that have been formed in this way in the park. The  Aggtelek National Park also contains the ruins of the H&aacute;romhegyi P&aacute;los church and monastery near Martonyi  village. The Caves of Aggtelek were  declared a UNESCO World Heritage site in 1995.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Brace yourself for brandy at Kecskemét</b></p><![CDATA[<p>En route to Szeged from Budapest, Kecskemét is an attractive town with several museums and a fine selection of art nouveau architecture. At the centre of Hungary's fruit growing region, the town is renowned for its many varieties of <em>pálinka</em> (fruit brandy). "In small amounts a medicine, in large amounts a remedy," the locals tend to slur.</p>]]><p><b>Discover both halves of the capital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Buda's elevated cobbled streets and take in the spectacular view of the Danube from the Fisherman's Bastion. In Pest, admire the Hungarian Parliament and Museum of Applied Arts, or unearth the treasures at the Hungarian National Museum. Fans of Socialist-era statuary should take a trip out to the suburbs to visit Memento Statue Park.</p>]]><p><b>Explore a former European Capital of Culture, Pécs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pécs, the fifth largest city in the country, is also home to one of the oldest universities in Europe and has many fine examples of architecture from the Ottoman period, most notably the 16th-century mosque of Gázi Kászim Pasha. The UNESCO World Heritage-listed Early Christian Necropolis is also located here, alongside many fine examples of Habsburg period buildings.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the architecture of Eger</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pay a visit to Eger in northern Hungary, one of the country's oldest and most colourful cities, which boasts around 200 historical monuments that include a castle, a 14-sided Ottoman minaret and a classically-finished basilica, complete with outstanding frecos, domed ceiling and mighty columned entrance.</p>]]><p><b>Find fine fishing at the River Tisza</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fish in the River Tisza, regarded as one of Europe's premier angling spots. At points, wide and wild, it can seem like you have the whole river to yourself.  Accommodation for anglers is readily available, and guides can be hired if required. Species such as carp, bream, pike, trout and tench are abundant.</p>]]><p><b>Get to know glorious Györ</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the northwest of Hungary, close to the Slovakian and Austrian borders, Györ has cobbled pedestrian shopping streets and an attractive baroque city centre. Just an hour and a half by train from Budapest, the city makes for a pleasant day trip from the capital.</p>]]><p><b>Hark back to Hungary's rural heritage at Hollókő</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel back in time at Hollókő, a UNESCO World Heritage-listed ethnographic village. Spread over 145 hectares (358 acres), the settlement has been deliberately preserved as an example of life before the agricultural revolution. Northeast of Budapest, there is around 60 wattle and daub houses and the substantial remnants of a 13th-century castle.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the heights of Hungary</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go hiking in Hungary's mountainous northeast region. The Zemplén, Bükk and Mátra ranges northeast of Budapest are popular for their stunning verdant landscapes, with the latter containing Hungary's highest peak, Kékes (1,014m/3,327ft). For easier terrain, head to the hills north and south of Lake Balaton.</p>]]><p><b>Keep your hawk's eye peeled at Hortobágy National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go birdwatching in Hortobágy National Park, a vast area of grassland in eastern Hungary. Designated a World Heritage Site in 1999, around 350 species have been spotted here, including storks, warblers, eagles, herons and rare great bustards. Motorised vehicles are not allowed in some parts of the park, while other parts require a guide.</p>]]><p><b>Luxuriate in Budapest's beautiful baths</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax at one of Budapest's thermal springs and medicinal baths, of which there are over 100 in the city. The elegant Gellért Baths, with a domed hall and frescoed ceilings, are the most famous. Other good options include the Király Medicinal Baths, which date from the Middle Ages; the historic Rudas Medicinal Baths; and Széchenyi Baths' splendid outdoor pools.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the Great Plain on horseback</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take to the saddle and explore the Great Hungarian Plain. Head to Puszta, home to several stud farms and the infamous "Putszta Five" technique, where a single rider stands to gallop five horses simultaneously. Excursions along horse riding trails can be arranged through riding schools all over the country. Worry not: saddles are included.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out Szeged for a spot of sunshine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Hungary's sunniest city is the lively university town of Szeged. Straddling the Tisza River, this cultured city is home to many fine churches and a pleasant, pedestrianised cafe culture. Each summer, below the twin-towered Dóm tér, its main square transforms into a large open-air theatre.</p>]]><p><b>Sink your teeth into Sopron</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head west to the delightful medieval cities of Sopron and Kőszeg. Sopron boasts 240 listed buildings, including the 12th-century Firewatch Tower, Storno House and the Gothic Goat Church, while Kőszeg's Jurisics tér contains a treasure-trove of baroque, renaissance and Gothic architecture. With over 300 clinics, Sopron is also the self-proclaimed 'dental capital of the world'.</p>]]><p><b>Sip Hungary’s famous Bull's Blood wine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spend time exploring the Szépasszony Valley vineyards, one of the country's numerous wine regions, where Hungary's famous Bikavér (Bull's Blood) wine can be sampled. Some of the country's very best reds can be found around Villány in the far south, whilst Miskolc in the northeast (part of the Tokaj region) is famous for its distinctive dessert wines.</p>]]><p><b>Soak yourself healthy in Hévíz thermal lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Soak away the stress in the large thermal lake at Hévíz near Lake Balaton. The soothing waters, which rarely drop below 23°C (73°F) in winter and 33°C (91°F) in summer, will certainly leave you feeling refreshed – some even consider them to have health-giving properties.</p>]]><p><b>Stay outside for culture at Sóstói Open-Air Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get a taste of the rural Hungary of old at the Open-Air Museum at Sóstói, a suburb of the city of Nyíregyháza in eastern Hungary. The architecture here preserves the rural traditions and culture of the region and the museum also holds several festivals each summer.</p>]]><p><b>Take a beach break at Lake Balaton</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lake Balaton in Hungary's Transdanubian region is Central Europe's largest freshwater lake. Visit one of the resorts that surround the shores such as Siófok, popular with the young for its beaches and nightlife; or the more sedate market town of Keszthely, with its elegant Festetics Palace. Lake Balaton also has plentiful sandy beaches that bustle in summer.</p>]]><p><b>Travel around the Danube Bend</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the historic towns along the Danube Bend. Szentendre is famous for its south European atmosphere, large artists' colony and numerous museums. Visegrád has a small castle and the remains of an early Renaissance palace. Esztergom is home to the impressive Basilica of the Blessed Virgin Mary Assumed Into Heaven and St Adalbert, Hungary's tallest building.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$147.9 billion (2011 estimate).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, manufactured goods and food.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, manufactured goods, fuels and electricity.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Austria, Romania, Italy, Russia, Slovakia, France, UK and China (PR).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hungary has few natural resources other than bauxite, natural gas and some oil. For this reason, it relies heavily on foreign trade, which accounts for half of its GDP.</p>
<p>The country has a fairly well-developed industrial economy concentrated in chemicals, plastics, pharmaceuticals, fertilisers, computers and telecommunications, mining, construction and aluminium (from bauxite deposits). It has also traditionally been an exporter of agricultural produce, particularly fruit and vegetables, maize and wheat, sugar beet, potatoes and livestock.</p>
<p>EU membership was a high priority for the Hungarian government, and the country achieved this goal on 1 May 2004. Hungary&rsquo;s economy underwent a serious blow during the international financial crisis of 2008 resulting in an estimated growth of just 0.8% in 2010. In 2011, unemployment ran at an estimated 10%, while GDP growth was estimated to continue at a rate of just 0.8%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business etiquette is much the same as elsewhere in Europe and the USA. Upon meeting, shake hands (one waits for women to offer their hands), then say your full name (Hungarians give their surname first, then their forename). Visitors should also shake hands on leaving. Giving and receiving gifts is common.</p>
<p>Hungarian is a difficult language, but a few words will go a long way.  As so few foreigners speak the language, most locals engaging in international business will speak some English, although Hungarian translators are usually available on request and can be booked through travel agents. Businesspeople are expected to dress smartly, with suits the standard dress for men. Business cards are widely exchanged. The best months for business visits are September to May. Appointments should always be made and punctuality is essential.</p>
<p>Hungarians are generally friendly and hospitable and it is usual for business visitors to be invited to lunch or dinner in a restaurant. Hungarian businesspeople prefer to do business with people they know and trust, so it is worth taking the time to build relationships. This is particularly true of the older generation.</p>
<p>Standard working hours are 0800 to 1630 Monday to Thursday, often finishing early in the afternoon on Friday.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Hungarian Investment and Trade Development Agency (ITDH)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 472 8100
					Website:http://www.itd.hu/
					Address: ,Andrássy út 12,Budapest,1061]]><b>Hungarian Convention Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 488 8640
					Website:http://www.hcb.hu/
					Address: ,Hold utca 1,Budapest,1054]]><b>Budapest Kereskedelmi és Iparkamara (Budapest Chamber of Commerce and Industry)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 488 2000
					Website:http://www.bkik.hu/
					Address: ,Krisztina Krt 99,Budapest,1016]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Hungarian food is probably best known for its generous use of paprika, but its influences come from far and wide, including France, Turkey, other Central European countries and neighbouring Serbia. In addition to paprika; sour cream and garlic also feature widely in Hungarian cuisine. The most popular meat is generally pork, with chicken a close second. As Hungary is landlocked, fish do not play a large part in the Hungarian diet, although freshwater species such as carp are quite commonly used.</p>
<p>Wine is taken seriously in Hungary, and the country&rsquo;s many vineyards produce a wide range of distinctive wines that range from full-bodied reds made from the native K&eacute;kfrancos grape to rich, sweet whites such as Tokaj.</p>
<p>There is a large choice of places to eat in Hungary that range from inexpensive <em>snackb&aacute;r</em> or <em>b&uuml;f&eacute;</em> (self-service establishments) to fine dining eateries. <em>Cukr&aacute;szda</em> (patisseries), serving cakes and pastries, and <em>k&aacute;v&eacute;h&aacute;z</em> (coffee shops) are also popular. Elegant Vienna-style coffee houses serving coffee and rich pastries are common in the capital. Gerbeaud, a refined but busy Art Nouveau institution, is Budapest's most famous coffee house.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>Many of Hungary&rsquo;s most famous dishes rely on a generous dash of red paprika, although Hungarian goulash tends to be quite different from that served under the same name in Western Europe.</p>
<p>&bull; <em>Hal&aacute;szl&eacute;</em> (a spicy soup made with freshwater fish and paprika).<br />
&bull; G<em>uly&aacute;s</em> (Hungarian goulash is a hearty beef, capsicum and paprika soup; Western goulash is called <em>p&ouml;rk&ouml;lt</em> or <em>tok&aacute;ny</em>). <br />
&bull; <em>Gundel palacsinta</em> (pancake served with walnuts, raisins, lemon rind, chocolate sauce and rum). <br />
&bull; <em>Paprik&aacute;s csirke</em> (paprika chicken).<br />
&bull; <em>Kolb&aacute;sz</em> (sausage spiced with paprika).<br />
&bull; <em>Ty&uacute;kh&uacute;sleves</em> (chicken soup with vegetables and pasta).<br />
&bull; <em>J&oacute;kai bableves</em> (kidney bean soup).<br />
&bull; <em>Hortob&aacute;gyi h&uacute;sos palacsinta</em> (&lsquo;Hortobagy pancake&rsquo; &ndash; pork or chicken in a thin pancake and baked with paprika and sour cream).<br />
&bull; <em>Galuska</em> (egg dumplings).<br />
&bull; <em>T&ouml;lt&ouml;tt k&aacute;poszta</em> (stuffed cabbage).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are no fixed licensing hours. Minors are allowed to go into bars but will not be served alcohol. Most bars in Budapest offer table service. <em>Eg&eacute;szs&eacute;gedre!</em> is the Hungarian equivalent of &lsquo;Cheers!&rsquo;</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tips of 10 to 15% are expected in restaurants, although simply rounding up the bill is acceptable for taxi fares and for small bills in bars and caf&eacute;s. Don't leave the money on the table in restaurants; tell the waiter or waitress the amount you wish to pay, including the tip. If you say &lsquo;thank you&rsquo; when paying a bill it will be assumed that you do not want any change back.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Budapest is by far the country's biggest centre for nightlife, having a wealth of clubs, bars, discos, music clubs and casinos, with a large concentration on VII Liszt Ferenc t&eacute;r and IX R&aacute;day utca.</p>
<p>For opera, ballet and classical music in opulent surroundings, head to the magnificent Hungarian State Opera House (tel: (1) 814 7100; <a href="http://www.opera.hu" target="_blank">www.opera.hu</a>), which stages regular performances throughout the year. Tickets are very reasonably priced for the quality offered and may be bought online or at the box office by the entrance.</p>
<p>Jazz fans are also well catered for in the Hungarian capital, with several specialist jazz clubs staging both Hungarian and foreign talent. Music clubs offer rock, hip hop and electronic music, with the most popular venues tending to change quite frequently.</p>
<p>The capital also has a large number of crowded nightclubs geared to dancing that have resident DJs playing electronic house music. In the warm summer months, some clubs make use of outdoor venues next to the Danube River. Up-to-date listings can be found in English-language publications Where Budapest or the Budapest Sun.</p>
<p>Although on a smaller scale, the nightlife in the larger cities and university towns of Debrecen, Gy&ouml;r and Szeged is also lively. During the summer months, the popular Lake Balaton resort of Si&oacute;fok has sufficient nightlife for it to be dubbed &lsquo;the party capital of Hungary&rsquo;. Cinemas in major towns show many films in their original language with Hungarian subtitles. Western Hungary, in particular, has a lot of very good wine cellars that open late.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Popular Hungarian souvenirs include embroideries, Herend and Zsolnay porcelain, wooden toys and national dolls. If you&rsquo;re in search of bargains, try Budapest&rsquo;s Ecseri Flea Market or the so-called 'Chinese Market' near Kerepesi Cemetery, which both offer a wealth of antiques and bric-a-brac items.</p>
<p>Hungary is a good place to buy food and drink gifts such as sausages and spicy salami, bags of paprika, tinned goose liver, caviar, wines and spirits. The best salami comes from Szeged in the south. Caviar is relatively inexpensive here, but comes from Russia rather than Hungary. Paprika comes in seven strengths, ranging from mild to hot, and can be bought in special presentation bags, making them ideal as presents for those at home. Budapest&rsquo;s markets are excellent places to buy these food products; the best of these is the Great Market Hall in central Pest, which has food and fresh produce downstairs and handicrafts upstairs, all contained in magnificent art nouveau surrounds.</p>
<p>Hungary has more than 20 regional wines, including Bikav&eacute;r (Bull&rsquo;s Blood) from Eger and sweet Tokaji Asz&uacute; (contained in long-necked bottles), which make good gifts. Bottles of <em>p&aacute;linka</em> (fruit brandy) &ndash; in particular the apricot brandy from Kecskem&eacute;t &ndash; are also very popular items.</p><p>Most shops are open Mon-Fri 1000-1800 or 1900 and Sat 1000-1300. Shopping centres have longer hours and are open Mon-Sat 1000-2000; some are also open on Sundays. Food shops are open Mon-Fri 0700-1800 and Sat 0700-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide choice of hotels in Hungary, ranging from barely acceptable to luxury establishments. Some date from the communist era, but a growing number have been built to modern standards since the fall of the Berlin Wall. Budapest has by far the widest choice of options, with several elegant 5-star international standard hotels, as well as many comfortable mid-range and boutique options. Elsewhere, there is generally a decent choice of places to stay throughout the country, with plenty of bed and breakfast style accommodation available at pensions in more rural areas.</p>
<p>The Hungary Card (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hungarycard.hu">www.hungarycard.hu</a>) provides discounts from 10 to 20% on, among other things, selected accommodation, including hotels, guest houses and youth hostels. The card is available from the Tourinform service (tel: (1) 438 8080; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.tourinform.hu">www.tourinform.hu</a>) throughout Hungary.</p>
<p>The Hungarian National Tourist Office (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.gotohungary.co.uk">www.gotohungary.co.uk</a>), which issues a brochure with listings of hotels, guesthouses and hostels, can be contacted for further information.</p>
<p><br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normally called pensions or <em>panzi&oacute;k</em>, these are available almost everywhere in the country, even in small villages, and they sometimes resemble small, mid-range hotels. Paying-guest accommodation is an inexpensive and excellent way of getting to know the Hungarian people. Rooms should be reserved well in advance wherever possible.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide choice of hotels in Hungary, ranging from barely acceptable to luxury establishments. Some date from the communist era, but a growing number have been built to modern standards since the fall of the Berlin Wall. Budapest has by far the widest choice of options, with several elegant 5-star international standard hotels, as well as many comfortable mid-range and boutique options. Elsewhere, there is generally a decent choice of places to stay throughout the country, with plenty of bed and breakfast style accommodation available at pensions in more rural areas.</p>
<p>The Hungary Card (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hungarycard.hu">www.hungarycard.hu</a>) provides discounts from 10 to 20% on, among other things, selected accommodation, including hotels, guest houses and youth hostels. The card is available from the Tourinform service (tel: (1) 438 8080; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.tourinform.hu">www.tourinform.hu</a>) throughout Hungary.</p>
<p>The Hungarian National Tourist Office (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.gotohungary.co.uk">www.gotohungary.co.uk</a>), which issues a brochure with listings of hotels, guesthouses and hostels, can be contacted for further information.</p>
<p><br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide choice of hotels in Hungary, ranging from barely acceptable to luxury establishments. Some date from the communist era, but a growing number have been built to modern standards since the fall of the Berlin Wall. Budapest has by far the widest choice of options, with several elegant 5-star international standard hotels, as well as many comfortable mid-range and boutique options. Elsewhere, there is generally a decent choice of places to stay throughout the country, with plenty of bed and breakfast style accommodation available at pensions in more rural areas.</p>
<p>The Hungary Card (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.hungarycard.hu">www.hungarycard.hu</a>) provides discounts from 10 to 20% on, among other things, selected accommodation, including hotels, guest houses and youth hostels. The card is available from the Tourinform service (tel: (1) 438 8080; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.tourinform.hu">www.tourinform.hu</a>) throughout Hungary.</p>
<p>The Hungarian National Tourist Office (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.gotohungary.co.uk">www.gotohungary.co.uk</a>), which issues a brochure with listings of hotels, guesthouses and hostels, can be contacted for further information.</p>
<p><br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;If European visitors or any of their dependants are suddenly taken ill or have an accident during a visit to Hungary, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). Full travel insurance is advised for all travellers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of an emergency, round-the-clock healthcare is available in Budapest from F&amp;ouml;nix SOS Ambulance (tel: (1) 200 0100; &lt;a href="http://fonixmed.com" target="_blank"&gt;www.fonixmed.&lt;/a&gt;com), which also has its own ambulance service. The R&amp;oacute;zsakert Medical Centre in Budapest (tel: (1) 391 5903) offers a private healthcare service with American-trained doctors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emergency dental care may be had at SOS Dental Service (tel: (1) 269 6010 or (30) 383 3333 in Budapest, which is open 24 hours a day. Many visitors make use of Hungary&amp;rsquo;s private dental services, which are highly professional are very affordable in comparison to other countries. Several companies offer holiday packages in which extensive dental treatment is combined with a city break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many visitors travel to Hungary to make use of the country&amp;rsquo;s numerous thermal baths, which are claimed to be beneficial for a wide variety of chronic complaints, in particular for dermatological conditions and arthritis.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food in Hungary is as safe to eat as anywhere in Western Europe, but places where cooked food is allowed to cool before reheating are usually best avoided. Tap water is safe to drink throughout the country. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tick-borne encephalitis is present in forested, grassy or lakeside areas during the warmer summer months. Insect repellent containing 30-50% DEET can help prevent bites, and long-sleeved shirts, long trousers, boots and hats should be worn to protect exposed skin. Vaccination is advised for campers and hikers visiting densely-forested areas outside the capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rabies, although on the decrease, is also present. In the unlikely event of being bitten seek medical advice without delay. The sun can be surprisingly strong in summer and precautions should be taken to avoid sunburn. Mosquitoes are present by water in summer and can sometimes be a nuisance, although they carry no risk of disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prevalence of HIV for adults in Hungary is estimated to be less than 0.1% of the adult population, a little lower than that in the UK. However, normal precautions to avoid exposure to HIV should always be taken.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Anniversary of 1848 uprising against Austrian rule :
							15 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>St Stephen's Day :
							20 August </p><p>National Day :
							23 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Eve :
							24 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hungary is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragrance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22%, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%, 90L of wine (including a maximum of 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Hungary by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco (if arriving by air).<br />
&bull; 40 cigarettes or 20 cigarillos or 10 cigars or 50g of tobacco (if arriving by other means).<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers (reduced to &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Meat or milk products and potted or rooted plants from outside the EU. Pornography, drugs and unlicensed weapons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Raw meat or milk products, potted or rooted plants. You can must obtain a licence to export cultural goods which are more than 50 years old or have a commercial value of more than Ft50,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hungarian Forint (HUF; symbol Ft). Notes are in denominations of Ft20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 2,000, 1,000, and 500. Coins are in denominations of Ft200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. A large number of commemorative coins in circulation are legal tender.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency can be exchanged at hotels, banks, post offices, bureaux de change, airports, railway stations, travel agencies and some restaurants throughout the country. Automatic&nbsp;exchange machines are available in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/budapest">Budapest</a> and other main tourist centres.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to withdraw cash by credit card at many post offices. American Express, Cirrus, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted. Credit and debit cards can be used to withdraw money from ATMs, which are found throughout the country.</p><p>Credit and debit cards can be used to withdraw money from ATMs, which are reliable  and widely available throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted in most post offices and banks. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take travellers cheques in Euros or US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1700, Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Children under 18 must provide a birth certificate if applying for a Schengen visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airport transport visas are required for certain nationalities to pass through the international transit area of Budapest Ferenc Liszt International Airport even without entering Hungarian national territory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hungary is part of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60/&pound;44. Children below the age of 12 years and beneficiaries of bilateral visa agreements pay &euro;35/&pound;26. Visas are free of charge for children under six years of age.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visas are valid for 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa applications should be made to the consular department of the nearest Hungarian embassy. A list of embassies is available on the Hungarian government's Consular Services website (<a href="http://konzuliszolgalat.kormany.hu/en">http://konzuliszolgalat.kormany.hu/en</a>).&nbsp;Those wishing to apply for a visa to visit Hungary are required to make an appointment in advance. In the UK, nationals requiring visas can apply via the Hungary Visa Application Centre (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/hungary/uk" target="_blank">www.vfsglobal.com/hungary/uk</a>); an additional service charge of &pound;24 applies. All visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications should be made to the Office of Immigration and Nationality (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.bmbah.hu">www.bmbah.hu</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing usually takes at least 15 working days, but can take longer in some cases.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa applicants need to show proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa holders can only extend their visas in exceptional circumstances, such as <em>force majeure</em> or for humanitarian reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you're bringing a pet to Hungary from another EU country, your animal requires a pet passport, microchip and valid rabies vaccination certificate. Animals from outside the EU need a veterinary certificate, microchip and rabies vaccination.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[47.165994]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[19.417977]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>93,028 sq km (35,918 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>9,821,318 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>106.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Budapest.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parliamentary Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hungary is situated in Central Europe, sharing borders to the north with Slovakia, to the northeast with Ukraine, to the east with Romania, to the south with Croatia and Serbia, and to the west with Austria and Slovenia.</p>
<p>Despite much of the country lying lower than 200m (656ft), there are several ranges of hills, chiefly in the north and west. The country&rsquo;s highest point is K&eacute;kes in the Matra Mountains northeast of Budapest, which is 1,014m (3,327ft) high. Other, relatively low, mountain ranges include the North Hungarian Mountains, the Transdanubian Mountains and Mecsek north of P&eacute;cs. The lowest point, near Szeged in southern Hungary, is just 77m (253ft) above sea level.</p>
<p>The Great Hungarian Plain, which stretches northeast from the Danube to the foothills of the Carpathian Mountains, east to the mountains of Transylvania in Romania, and south to the Fru&scaron;ka Gora range in Serbia, covers more than half of Hungary&rsquo;s total territory. It is flat and low-lying throughout, never exceeding more than 183m (591ft) in height. The Little Hungarian Plain is similar, but much smaller, and lies in northwest Hungary next to the Austrian and Slovakian borders.</p>
<p>Two major European rivers run through Hungary, the Danube and the Tisza. The former flows through Budapest on its way to the Black Sea via Croatia, Serbia, Bulgaria and Romania. The River Tisza, which has its source in Ukraine, flows south through Hungary into Vojvodina in northern Serbia, where it joins with the Danube. Both rivers are navigable in Hungary. Smaller rivers include the R&aacute;ba, Szamos, S&iacute;o and the Drava, which largely defines the Croatian border.</p>
<p>Hungary has no coastline, but the country is home to Lake Balaton in west-central Hungary, which is sometimes referred to as the &lsquo;Hungarian Sea&rsquo;. Lake Balaton is a regionally important freshwater lake, the largest in Central Europe, with a surface area of 592 sq km (229 sq miles). At 78km (48 miles) long and up to 14km (9 miles) wide, it&rsquo;s Hungary&rsquo;s largest recreational area and a popular destination for both summer swimming and winter sports. Hungary also has two much smaller lakes: Lake Velence, which is a bird reserve, and Lake Fert&ouml;, which straddles the Austrian border near Sopron.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christianity: 52% Roman Catholic, 16% Calvinist, 3% Lutheran, 2.6% Greek Catholic and a small number of other Christian, Eastern Orthodox and Jewish minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When meeting a Hungarian, handshaking is customary and both first name and surname should be used. At a meal, toasts are usually made and should be returned. Gifts such as flowers, chocolates, or a bottle of good quality wine are acceptable for hosts as a token of thanks &ndash; particularly when invited for a meal. Smoking, although popular in Hungary, is prohibited on public transport in towns and public buildings. English is quite widely spoken in tourist areas, but some knowledge of German can also prove useful.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Viktor Orb&aacute;n since 2010.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President J&aacute;nos &Aacute;der since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hungary was first colonised by nomadic Magyars from southern Russia in the ninth century, but had previously been occupied by Celts, Romans, Slavs and Avars. The Magyars created a unified kingdom under their ruler Árpád that would last almost a thousand years until a brutal Mongol invasion devastated the kingdom at the end of the 13th century.</p><p>The Kingdom of Hungary slowly re-established itself as a leading European power and when the Mongols abandoned Europe a new threat came in the shape of Ottoman Turks who were defeated at the end of the 15th century by Matthias Corvinus, a powerful military leader and a patron of the arts. His successor was less successful, and Hungary fell under Ottoman rule during the 16th century and was not able to re-establish its independence until 1718, forming an alliance with Austria as part of the Habsburg Empire ruled by a Magyar aristocracy.</p><p>Despite several uprisings in the mid-19th century, the country remained essentially a feudal state until the end of World War 1 when, in 1918, it finally dissolved its union with Austria. Hungary sided with Nazi Germany during World War 2 until 1944 when German troops occupied the country. Following the Russian invasion in January 1945, Hungary became a short-lived republic before joining the Warsaw Pact as a Soviet-style socialist state in 1949.</p><p>Declining living conditions and widespread political purges eventually led to the Hungarian Revolution of 1956 under Prime Minister Imre Nagy, in which Hungary attempted withdrawal from the Warsaw Pact. The uprising was soon quashed with the support of Soviet army units, leaving an estimated 20,000 dead and nearly a quarter of a million Hungarians exiled. Despite this brutal suppression of freedom, Hungary was considered one of the most liberal countries in the Eastern Bloc particularly after 1968 and the introduction of the New Economic Mechanism, allowing a significant role to be taken by private enterprise.</p><p>During the 1980s the political situation relaxed still further, and with the collapse of the Soviet Union in 1989 Hungary was free to begin the transition to a pluralistic political system. The first free elections were held in the spring of 1990. Hungary joined NATO in 1999 and became a full European Union member in 2004. The political landscape is dominated by the conservative Hungarian Civic Union, Fidesz, which holds a near supermajority in the National Assembly.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>&bull; Hungary has a rich heritage of folk dance that date back at least as far as the Middle Ages.</p><p>&bull; The Romans brought the spa to Hungary, a land of thermal water.</p><p>&bull; Unicum, a liquor made from a blend of 40 herbs, is traditionally drunk before or after a meal.<br/> </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Hungary in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7201 3440 (embassy) or (020) 7235 5218 (consular).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mfa.gov.hu/kulkepviselet/UK</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7201 3440 (embassy) or (020) 7235 5218 (consular).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1200 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>35 Eaton Place<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8BY<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Hungary in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 362 6730. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://washington.kormany.hu</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 362 6730. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1230 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3910 Shoemaker Street<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Culturally and linguistically distinct from all of its immediate neighbours, Hungary is very much the &lsquo;odd one out&rsquo; in Central Europe, but for all the most honourable reasons.</p>
<p>This is a nation whose capital, Budapest, can hold up a mirror to classical Vienna; it&rsquo;s a world of well-preserved castles, seductively good wines and quiet stoic pride; a landscape of low-lying mountains, oak forests and thermal springs.</p>
<p>The Romans were the first to make use of the hot waters, originally for medicinal purposes. Today, the pursuit is relaxation and over time the bathhouses have grown into splendid architectural affairs, most notably in Budapest.</p>
<p>The capital is an elegant, stylish and lively city made up of two separate settlements clustered on either side of the Danube River: hilly Buda has a wealth of graceful Habsburg and neoclassical buildings, while sprawling Pest is its commercial centre with a generous scattering of art nouveau architecture and an ad-hoc party scene.</p>
<p>The city has long been the focus of Hungary&rsquo;s artistic, musical and literary community and is by far the best place in the country for a choice of bars, restaurants and nightclubs.</p>
<p>Smaller cities are equally architecturally fascinating and deserving of a visit in their own right: P&eacute;cs for its museums; Eger for it&rsquo;s fortifications and infamous Bull&rsquo;s Blood Wine; and Gy&ouml;r whose grand Basilica houses the golden herm of L&aacute;szl&oacute;.</p>
<p>Beyond these urban centres, Hungary&rsquo;s bathes in natural delights. South west of Budapest is Lake Balaton, Central Europe&rsquo;s largest body of freshwater, where locals spend hot summers cooling off in waters that average 20&deg;C (68&deg;F).</p>
<p>In winter, Hungary freezes, and thrill seekers head north to the Bakony Hills for the chance to ski through the forests before unwinding with a dip in the thermal spa.</p>
<p>It may be landlocked, but Hungary is a country content on ploughing its own furrow no matter what seeds its neighbours are sewing and is all the better for it.</p><p>Culturally and linguistically distinct from all of its immediate neighbours, Hungary is very much the &lsquo;odd one out&rsquo; in Central Europe, but for all the most honourable reasons.</p>
<p>This is a nation whose capital, Budapest, can hold up a mirror to classical Vienna; it&rsquo;s a world of well-preserved castles, seductively good wines and quiet stoic pride; a landscape of low-lying mountains, oak forests and thermal springs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
