<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Iceland" ColCode="isl" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="is" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Iceland]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iceland's climate is tempered by the Gulf Stream. Summers are mild and winters rather cold. The colourful Aurora Borealis (Northern Lights) are best seen between November and February. In June and July, there are nearly 24 hours of daylight in Reykjav&iacute;k, while in the northern part of the country the sun barely sets at all.</p>
<p>Winds can be strong and gusty at times and there is the occasional dust storm in the interior. Snow is not as common as the name of the country would seem to suggest and, in any case, does not lie for long in Reykjav&iacute;k; it is only in northern Iceland that skiing conditions are reasonably certain. However, the weather is very changeable at all times of the year, and in Reykjav&iacute;k there may be rain, sunshine, drizzle and snow in the same day. The air is clean and free of pollution.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights in warmer months, with extra woollens for walking and the cooler evenings. Medium- to heavyweights are advised in winter. Waterproofing is recommended throughout the year. Umbrellas are not recommended because rain is very often accompanied by wind.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Iceland (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.airiceland.is">www.airiceland.is</a>) and Eagle Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.eagleair.is">www.eagleair.is</a>) run domestic services to all major airports within Iceland from Reykjav&iacute;k&rsquo;s city airport, linking up with air or bus connections in over 40 towns. Air Iceland also flies to Greenland and the Faroe Islands.</p><p>If you&rsquo;re in Iceland for a short amount of time, flying can be a great way to see the different areas of the country and it doesn&rsquo;t have to be expensive. You can take a bus one way and fly the other; this mode of transport also allows you to see the country by air, which can be singularly dramatic. Both internal airlines offer day tours of the country as well as day trips, guided tours and scheduled flights. You need a passport to travel to Greenland or the Faroe Islands from Iceland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are ferry links to the Westman Islands off the southwest coast served by Herjolfur ferries (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.herjolfur.is">www.herjolfur.is</a>). S&aelig;fari (<a href="http://www.landflutningar.is/saefari" target="_blank">www.landflutningar.is/saefari</a>) offers scheduled trips from Grimsey Island in the Arctic Circle to the north of Iceland, while Seatours (<a href="http://www.seatours.is" target="_blank">www.seatours.is</a>) offers journeys around the Westfjords from Stikkisholmur on the Snaefellsjokull peninsula.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no trains in Iceland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>A major road, the Route One, which links all the main towns and runs in a circular route around the island, rings Iceland. Outside Reykjav&iacute;k, roads are often quiet and empty; sheep and horses can be hazardous, as can weather conditions, but driving itself is usually relaxed.</p>
<p>There are roads serving all settlements, but outside major settlements, they can be gravel rather than tarred. Every year, lesser-used roads through the central highlands of the country are re-marked by the first vehicles to drive the route.</p>
<p>Most mountain roads are only open in summer, and some of them can only be used by 4-wheel-drive vehicles.</p>
<p>The Icelandic Tourist Board provides maps, and a helpful online guide (in both brochure and video format) to driving in Iceland.</p>
<p>For information on road conditions, contact the Icelandic Road and Coastal Administration (tel: +354 522 1100 or 1777, in Iceland only; <a href="http://www.road.is" target="_blank">www.road.is</a>).</p>
<p>Additionally, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.safetravel.is">www.safetravel.is</a> offers advice about driving and other activities in the country, particularly for those veering off main routes.</p><p>The BSI bus station in Reykjav&iacute;k is the hub for buses in the country. Routes are available to take you everywhere (they are much more frequent in the summer than the winter) including tourist packages, flight and bus links and scheduled routes. Reservations are not always necessary and you can buy tickets from the driver. Check BSI (<a href="https://www.bsi.is/" target="_blank">www.bsi.is</a>) for bus schedules and routes.</p><p>Available from all hotels and airports and downtown areas of Reykjav&iacute;k and Akureyri.</p><p>A valid national driving licence.</p><p>Speed limits are 30kph (19mph) in residential areas, 50kph (31mph) in urban areas, while outside towns they are 90kph (56mph) on paved roads and 80kph (50mph) on gravel roads. Driving under the influence of alcohol is prohibited. It is obligatory to use headlights at all times of the day and night, and to wear seatbelts, both in the front and back seats.</p><p>Remote areas of Iceland have poor mobile and GPS reception; it is always advisable to tell someone where you are going and when you will return and to take a map. Some roads receive few passersby, so you should be prepared in the event of an emergency. Costs for breakdown recovery can be high. Check details thoroughly with your car hire company.</p><p>Services are available from Reykjav&iacute;k, Akureyri and many other towns.</p><p>Iceland has some appeal to cyclists; the quiet roads and scenery have made it popular with touring European cyclists and several cycle tour options are available. Cycle hire is available in Reykjav&iacute;k by the day as well as for longer-term rental.</p><p>Speed limits are 30kph (19mph) in residential areas, 50kph (31mph) in urban areas, while outside towns they are 90kph (56mph) on paved roads and 80kph (50mph) on gravel roads. Driving under the influence of alcohol is prohibited. It is obligatory to use headlights at all times of the day and night, and to wear seatbelts, both in the front and back seats.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of Iceland&rsquo;s cities are easy to drive round and easier to walk around. Parking is usually easy and there is little traffic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Iceland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">saudakrokur</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Iceland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">isafjoumlrdur</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Iceland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">houmlfn</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.65</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Iceland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">akureyri</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.55</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Icelandair (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.icelandair.com">www.icelandair.com</a>) operates direct flights year-round to Reykjav&iacute;k from multiple cities in the UK, Europe and North America.&nbsp;WOW Air (<a href="http://www.wowair.com" target="_blank">www.wowair.com</a>) also flies direct to Reykjav&iacute;k from the UK and the USA.&nbsp;Other airlines operating non-stop flights to Iceland from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>).</p>
<p>There are also some highly seasonal flights from Europe to Akureyri, in the north of Iceland.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iceland/keflavik-international-airport">Keflavik International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>&nbsp;- 3 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 5 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prices and frequency of flights vary considerably depending on the time of year. Winter (apart from Christmas and New Year) is the cheapest time to go, with the least regular flights. June is the most expensive, with a wider choice of flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prices and frequency of flights vary considerably depending on the time of year. Winter (apart from Christmas and New Year) is the cheapest time to go, with the least regular flights. June is the most expensive, with a wider choice of flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Keflavík International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.kefairport.is<p>Keflav&iacute;k International Airport is located on the Reykjanes peninsula, a short drive from the centre of Keflav&iacute;k (Reykjanesbaer), and 50km (31 miles) southwest of the capital Reykjavik.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+354 425 6000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main port is Sey&eth;isfj&ouml;r&eth;ur, on Iceland&rsquo;s east coast.</p><p>From Sey&eth;isfj&ouml;r&eth;ur, it takes 8-9 hours to reach Reykjav&iacute;k by bus. There are bus routes from the port to all of Iceland&rsquo;s major towns. Tourist information is available at the ferry port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public telephones are increasingly hard to locate, but can be found at the post office in central Reykjav&iacute;k as well as other roadside areas. Skype is a good option for calling abroad cheaply. The majority of Icelanders use mobile phones.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with many international companies. Coverage is good. Pre-paid GSM phonecards, which travellers can use with their own GSM phones, can be purchased at petrol stations around the country. GSM phones may also be rented at several locations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes can be found, especially in Reykjav&iacute;k, and Wi-Fi is widely available in hotels and hostels throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Icelandic National Broadcasting Service (RUV) is a public-service broadcaster owned by the state, which runs national radio and TV services. The RUV has to promote the Icelandic language, history and culture. There is guaranteed press freedom. <br />
<br />
In terms of printed press dailies include <em>Fr&eacute;ttabla&eth;i&eth;</em> and <em>Morgunbla&eth;i&eth;</em>, whilst <em>Vi&eth;skiptabla&eth;i&eth;</em> is a business paper. <em>Baejarins besta</em> provides West Fjords local news and <em>Iceland Review</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.icelandreview.com">www.icelandreview.com</a>) is an English-language magazine focusing on all aspects of Icelandic life, and also has news. <em>The Reykjav&iacute;k Grapevine</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.grapevine.is">www.grapevine.is</a>) is free and has listings and up to the minute information on the city in English. It is available widely in cafes and shops.</p>
<p>St&ouml;&eth; 2 is the main private television station but other ones include Sj&oacute;nvarp S&iacute;mans, whilst The Icelandic National Broadcasting Service operates the public network Sj&oacute;nvarpi&eth;. In terms of radio, Bylgjan is the main private station. The Icelandic National Broadcasting Service operates two national networks and four regional stations of public radio.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is an efficient airmail service to Europe.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1630. The post office in Kringlan shopping centre is open on Saturdays 1000-1800. Some offices open Mon-Fri 1000-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Geyser (Geysir)</p><![CDATA[<p>Until 1916, Geysir, located 125km (78 miles) northeast of Reykjavik, was one of the world's great geysers, spouting boiling water and steam 60-80m (165-220ft) into the air at three-hourly intervals. Mysteriously, it fell dormant (some say due to hundreds of tourists filling its chamber with objects) and has come to life only once since then, in 1935. The smaller Strokkur geyser nearby makes up for its big brother's silence by erupting every five to ten minutes. The entire area is a geothermal park, with belching mud pits, hissing steam vents, hot and cold springs, warm streams and primitive plants. The Geysir Center offers visitors year-round exhibitions on geothermal activity, and also contains a folk museum with displays on the history of the area and Icelandic flora and fauna.</p>]]><br/><p>Golden Waterfall (Gullfoss)</p><![CDATA[<p>Located just a few kilometres from Geysir, <em>Gullfoss</em> (Golden  Waterfall) is the most dramatic section of the Hvita River (White River)  in southern Iceland. In the midst of lush vegetation, white water  thunders down a 32m (105ft) drop into a narrow canyon 70m (192ft) deep  and 2.5km (1.5 miles) long. The site was bought by the Icelandic  government to prevent foreign investors from turning it into a  commercial site, and the footpath is opened each morning by a local  farmer to allow visitors to see the waterfall from a viewing platform.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bathe in the Blue Lagoon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The milky turquoise waters of the Blue Lagoon are perfect for a good, long soak. Located in a lunar-like landscape of lava fields, the lagoon is renowned for its health benefits and mineral-rich, geothermal seawater, which have made it one of the most visited locations in Iceland.</p>]]><p><b>Cast out for trout</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Iceland&rsquo;s pristine streams and rivers are well-stocked with fish of all kinds. Salmon, in particular, is abundant though licences for popular salmon rivers are extremely expensive. Opt to fish for trout or arctic char for a fraction of the price.</p>]]><p><b>Celebrate New Year's Eve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Gamlarskvold (New Year's Eve celebrations) are a sight to behold; hundreds of bonfires blaze across Reykjavík and Icelanders start the New Year with a literal bang at the stroke of midnight, when thousands of fireworks go off simultaneously, setting ablaze the crystal clear sky.</p>]]><p><b>Climb to the top of Hallgrímskirkja</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visible from much of Reykjav&iacute;k, the eye-catching white church of Hallgr&iacute;mskirkja, whose design was inspired by the Icelandic landscape, is not easily overlooked. The interior, by contrast, is surprisingly plain though the views from the top of its tower are spectacular.</p>]]><p><b>Dine at Reykjavík's restaurants</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Reykjavík's restaurants are the best place to experience superb Icelandic cuisine. Home-grown organic lamb, salmon and lobster are perennial favourites, and offerings from the sea are second to none. For the adventurous, traditional Icelandic food, which could include anything from grilled puffin and seabird's eggs to boiled sheep's head, has made a resurgence, but it's not for the faint-hearted.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the wonders of Lake Myvatn</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Brave the midges and discover an eerie landscape of bubbling mud flats, volcanic craters, fumaroles, lava fields and grassy shoals teeming with waterfowl at Lake Myvatn ('Lake Midge'), one of the most popular tourist destinations in the country. The Myvatn Nature Baths nearby are northern Iceland's equivalent to the Blue Lagoon, a natural geothermally-heated outdoor lagoon.</p>]]><p><b>Escape to the Westfjords</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This spectacular setting of rugged coastline, known as the Westfjords, is home to some of the most isolated villages in the country. Of particular note is Latrabjarg, the westernmost point of Europe and at 400m (1,312ft) high, the largest known bird cliff on Earth.</p>]]><p><b>Lace up your boots for hikes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Iceland's hiking is incredible. From Skaftafell National Park to the Westfjords, from the highlands to the Sn&aelig;fellnes Peninsula, breathtaking vistas lurk round every bend. The Laugavegurinn, from Landmannalaugar to &THORN;&oacute;rsm&ouml;rk, is the country&rsquo;s most famous long-distance hike, taking you through glaciers and valleys to an area of hot springs.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about Icelandic life</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Check out the excellent folk museum in the tiny village of Skogar, where historic buildings, crafts, tools and equipment recall an older way of life on the island. Follow it up with a stroll on one of the nearby black sand beaches on the south coast near Vik.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at otherworldly landscapes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Jokulsarlon, a glacial lagoon is a favourite with photographers and film crews (the film <em>Die Another Day</em> was shot here). Little wonder why; giant floating icebergs make for a surreal landscape and crowds of seals can be seen fishing at the mouth of the lagoon in winter.</p>]]><p><b>Ride a snowmobile over a glacier</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Few things can elicit more of a heart-thumping thrill than a skidoo (snowmobile) ride across a glacier. An unbeatable adrenaline rush is guaranteed when speeding through the immaculate white wilderness, which stretches as far as the eye can see - a highlight of any trip to Iceland.</p>]]><p><b>Search for the Northern Lights</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of nature's most awesome spectacles, the Northern Lights are visible from September to mid-April. The ever-shifting, glowing patterns of light that twist and turn restlessly in the sky are created by electrically-charged particles that make the thin air shine with a rainbow of colours.</p>]]><p><b>See the Golden Waterfall (Gullfoss)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located just a few kilometres from Geysir, <em>Gullfoss</em> is the most dramatic section of the Hvita River. In the midst of lush vegetation, white water thunders down a 32m (105ft) drop into a narrow canyon 70m (230ft) deep and 2.5km (1.6 miles) long. When the sun shines, the sediment in the glacial water causes it to glow, hence its name.</p>]]><p><b>Spot whales</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The waters around Iceland are home to a variety of cetaceans and are among the best whale-watching destinations in the world. Embark on a boat trip out to sea and look for minke, blue, fin, humpback, sperm and killer whales; all are frequently sighted just off the coast.</p>]]><p><b>Spy feathered fliers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Birdwatchers and nature lovers flock to the Westman Islands every spring to view the returning puffins who come here to nest after a long winter at sea. In August, millions of baby puffins leave their nests for the very first time to test their wings.</p>]]><p><b>Trek colourful Landmannalaugar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Landmannalaugar is the pearl of the central highlands region. This eerily colourful landscape of green, yellow, red and orange rhyolite hills is dotted with many hot pools and trickling streams, making this a definite must for walkers and artists alike.</p>]]><p><b>Trot across Icelandic landscapes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Icelandic horse may look fluffy and cute, but these spirited steeds are hardy and powerful, perfectly adapted to the rugged terrain. Riding them over lava fields or deserted beaches is a rewarding experience. Call them ponies and be prepared to face the wrath of the locals.</p>]]><p><b>Venture north to Akureyri and the Arctic Circle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The buzzy city of Akureyri, 60km (37 miles) south of the Arctic Circle, enjoys a superb setting at the head of Eyjafj&ouml;r&eth;ur, the longest fjord in the country. A bit further north and well worth exploring is the island of Grimsey, the only bit of Iceland, strictly speaking, in the Arctic Circle.</p>]]><p><b>Watch geysers spurt</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Until 1916, Geysir, located 125km (78 miles) northeast of Reykjavik spouted boiling water and steam high up into the air at regular intervals. Mysteriously, it fell dormant and rarely comes to life since then. A man-made tunnel in 1935 and an earthquake in 2000 have brought it to life. Head to the smaller Strokkur geyser nearby, which makes up for its big brother's silence by erupting every five to ten minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$23 billion (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fish and fish products, aluminium and alloys, agricultural products, medicinal and medical products, and ferro-silicon.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, petroleum products, foodstuffs and textiles</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>EU, China, Switzerland, Norway, Brazil, and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iceland made headlines around the world in October 2008 when the country&rsquo;s three banks suffered an economic collapse. Iceland was hit hard by the global recession, and as a result the Icelandic government had to step in and seize control of the country's biggest banks in a rescue operation that sent shockwaves around the island and beyond.</p>
<p>Until that point Icelanders enjoyed a per capita income that was amongst the highest in the world at US$21.3 billion (2007)/US$17.64 billion (2008 estimate). The country had been in a positive economic period; in 2007 economic growth was at 2.5% and unemployment at a very low 1%. Latest figures for 2017 showed unemployment at 2.8%. The future is uncertain but the country has started to rally and with increasing numbers of tourists visiting for some of the best Northern Lights shows of recent times, as well as volcano tourism, there have been some positive signs.</p>
<p>Iceland is short of raw materials and so relies heavily on foreign trade; exports of goods and services account for more than one-third of GNP. The largest proportion of these derives from fishing, Iceland's most important export (around 40% of its export earnings). The economy is therefore particularly susceptible to fluctuating fish prices and maintains a broad fisheries exclusion zone of 320km (almost 200 miles) to protect its earnings. The government remains opposed to EU membership, primarily because of concern about losing control over their fishing resources.</p>
<p>Aluminium smelters are playing an increasingly big part in Iceland's economy, and have polarised Icelanders in recent years. While some argue that the pristine nature of the interior should be preserved at all costs, others think it should be tapped to regenerate areas where traditional industries are no longer viable.</p>
<p>There are several large hotels in Reykjav&iacute;k equipped for conferences and business meetings, while smaller conferences may be held at venues outside the capital. The new Icelandic National Concert and Conference Centre, also known as Harpa, offers state of the art conference facilities and aims to encourage European and North American businesses to meet mid-Atlantic.  As well as a large 750-seater lecture hall, the centre has a world-class concert hall attracting international musicians and performers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople are expected to dress smartly. Local businesspeople are conservative but very friendly and most speak English. Previous appointments are not generally necessary, although visits between May and September should be planned in advance as many local businesspeople travel abroad at this time.<br />
<br />
When meeting a business counterpart in Iceland, a handshake is the normal form of greeting. Although an Icelander's second language is generally Danish, a very high proportion of the population is fluent in English. Characteristically, Icelanders can be quite reserved but very direct. Visitors are often invited into homes (especially if on business) and bringing a gift for the host is the norm (a bottle of foreign wine is always welcomed). Instead of surnames, the majority of Icelanders use the system of patronymics. The first name of the father is used plus son (<em>son</em>) or daughter (<em>d&oacute;ttir</em>) instead of a surname. Because of this, the telephone directory is listed by first name.<br />
<br />
Standard office hours are Monday to Friday 0900-1700 (although many firms alter this to 0800-1600 during the summer).</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600 (summer) and 0900-1700 (winter).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Iceland Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 510 7100
					Website:http://www.chamber.is/
					Address: 7th floor,House of Commerce,Kringlan 7,103]]><b>Iceland Convention and Incentive Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 562 6070
					Website:http://www.icelandconvention.com
					Address: Reykjavík,Lækjargötu 3,Iceland,101]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Icelandic cuisine owes much to Scandinavian and European influences. As New Nordic cuisine has risen in prominence in recent years, so too has the profile of Iceland&rsquo;s food with many experimental chefs cooking up a storm in Reykjav&iacute;k&rsquo;s restaurants. Fresh fish can be had all year round - Icelanders eat mostly haddock, cod, plaice, halibut, herring and shrimp, but Icelandic salmon, lobster and Arctic char are also very good. The lamb, which is reared locally, is free range, organic and extremely tasty.</p>
<p>Vegetarians are catered for but be aware that much of the greenery is imported into the country &ndash; it doesn&rsquo;t grow well here. Home-grown vegetables are typically reared in greenhouses heated by the natural steam from geysers. It&rsquo;s one reason why food can be more expensive than you would expect.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pylsur:</strong> Hot dogs made from lamb, beef and pork with optional accompaniments of onions, mustard and tomato ketchup.<br />
<strong>Har&eth;fiskur:</strong> A dried fish snack, often cod, haddock or ocean catfish, is usually dipped in salted butter.<br />
<strong>Kj&ouml;ts&uacute;pa:</strong> A lamb soup made with cabbage, root vegetables and occasionally a handful of oats or rice.<br />
<strong>Skyr:</strong> A smooth and creamy kind of yoghurt made from pasteurised skimmed milk.<br />
<strong>Hangikjot:</strong> Smoked lamb typically served with b&eacute;chamel sauce at Christmas.<br />
<strong>Svi&eth;:</strong> A sheep&rsquo;s head cut in half, singed (to remove the hair), de-brained and boiled.<br />
<strong>P&ouml;nnuk&ouml;kur:</strong> Thin pancakes rolled up with jam, powdered sugar and/or cream.<br />
<strong>R&uacute;gbrau&eth;:</strong> A moist and slightly sweet rye bread.<br />
<strong>Brennivin:</strong> A potent variation of aquavit made from potatoes.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Apart from most hotels, restaurants and bars, alcohol is sold in state liquor stores throughout Iceland and is not available in supermarkets.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Service charges are included in most bills and extra tips are not expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>20.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of nightclubs, bars, cafes and cinemas in Iceland, most of them in the capital. Icelandic nightlife is particularly vibrant from June to August when there is nearly 24 hour daylight.</p>
<p>Reykjav&iacute;k has a strong caf&eacute; and bar through the year and you can find live music most nights of the week. The classic <em>runtur</em> or pub crawl around the city starts late, from at least 2200, and takes in the many pubs and bars along Laugavegur. For a more sophisticated evening, the city&rsquo;s more upmarket hotels all have bars and restaurants that are popular with well-heeled locals. Outside the capital, there is much less choice.</p>
<p>Leading theatres are the National Theatre and the Reykjav&iacute;k City Theatre. During July and August there is an attractive light entertainment show in English called 'Light Nights' (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.lightnights.com">www.lightnights.com</a>) with traditional Icelandic stories and folk songs.</p>
<p>Harpa, the Icelandic National Concert and Conference Centre, is housed in an iconic building designed by pre-eminent Scandinavian architects and internationally acclaimed (and half-Icelandic) artist &Oacute;lafur El&iacute;asson. The centre, which cost US$100 million is the home of the Icelandic Symphony Orchestra and the Icelandic Opera and attracts regular touring classical and rock acts from both sides of the Atlantic as well as local acts, theatre, comedy and opera. In general, Iceland has a vibrant music scene that has produced, amongst others, internationally acclaimed artists Bj&ouml;rk and Sigur R&oacute;s.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fluffy, earth-coloured Lopi wool blankets and coats, jackets, hats, handknits and thick patterned jumpers are synonymous with Iceland; increasingly, small collectives are creating cutting edge and modern versions of the traditional knitwear to appeal to younger visitors. Several local potters hand-throw earthenware containers in natural colours. Crushed lava is a common addition to highly glazed ceramic pieces, which are popular as souvenirs. The duty-free shop at Reykjav&iacute;k Airport sells all of these products, along with wallets made from fish skin, copies of the Icelandic sagas in translation, Brennivin, the country&rsquo;s unique spirit, and coffee table photography books.</p>
<p>Laugavegur is Reykjav&iacute;k's main shopping street, where you will find unique fashion stores, jewellers, tourist shops selling plastic Viking hats and stuffed puffins, and quirky Scandinavian interior design boutiques. The shops along Sk&oacute;lav&ouml;r&eth;ust&iacute;gur are good for art lovers, with plenty of small boutiques selling small and affordable pieces of art and craft. Kringlan is Reykjav&iacute;k's largest shopping mall, located just outside the centre. Bargain hunters should visit the indoor Kolaporti&eth; market in Reykjav&iacute;k, held every weekend, where great buys on handmade Icelandic jumpers, food and toys can be found.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800; Sat from 1000-1500. Most shops close on Sundays, and many shops also close on Saturdays during the summer (Jun-Aug). Some supermarkets are open seven days a week until 2300.</p><p>Shoppers can claim back tax spent on items in Iceland before they depart. The tourist office has forms as does the branch of Landsbankinn bank in the departures lounge of Reykjavik Airport. Keep all your receipts to get around 15% of the money you have spent on goods (not services or food) back.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Reykjav&iacute;k offers a good choice of hotels, from budget to five-star. Elsewhere, the choice is more limited, with only a handful of luxury hotels outside the capital and often little choice in rural areas. Hotels, however, have good standards of cleanliness and comfort and some are world-class in their design.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Classification for all accommodation types in Iceland is voluntary and ranges from 5 star (luxurious) to 1 star (basic). It is managed by the Icelandic Tourist Board. Visitors should look for a blue and red sign near the entrance for the current grading. For further details on accommodation contact the Icelandic Tourist Board.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are available in the larger towns. Rooms are also available in private houses with breakfast included in the cost. These can include so-called &lsquo;sleeping bag accommodation&rsquo; where for a reduced cost, you can stay in someone&rsquo;s private house with your own sleeping bag (they provide a bed).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Reykjav&iacute;k offers a good choice of hotels, from budget to five-star. Elsewhere, the choice is more limited, with only a handful of luxury hotels outside the capital and often little choice in rural areas. Hotels, however, have good standards of cleanliness and comfort and some are world-class in their design.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Classification for all accommodation types in Iceland is voluntary and ranges from 5 star (luxurious) to 1 star (basic). It is managed by the Icelandic Tourist Board. Visitors should look for a blue and red sign near the entrance for the current grading. For further details on accommodation contact the Icelandic Tourist Board.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Reykjav&iacute;k offers a good choice of hotels, from budget to five-star. Elsewhere, the choice is more limited, with only a handful of luxury hotels outside the capital and often little choice in rural areas. Hotels, however, have good standards of cleanliness and comfort and some are world-class in their design.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Classification for all accommodation types in Iceland is voluntary and ranges from 5 star (luxurious) to 1 star (basic). It is managed by the Icelandic Tourist Board. Visitors should look for a blue and red sign near the entrance for the current grading. For further details on accommodation contact the Icelandic Tourist Board.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Iceland is a very safe country to visit. There are no serious health conditions associated with the country and no inoculations are required for entry. The emergency number for medical assistance is 112 (24 hours). For European visitors who are taken ill or have an accident, free or reduced-cost treatment is available - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). The EHIC gives access to state-provided medical treatment only. Icelandic healthcare is of a high Western standard. In each town you will find an &lt;em&gt;Apotek&lt;/em&gt; (pharmacy) which has a green plus sign outside it.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Icelandic water is safe to drink and there is no need to buy bottled water. There are no specific food or drink risks in the country.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Weather and risky behaviour in unpredictable terrain is the largest health risk to the traveller in Iceland. Weather changes quickly and the temperatures can be more extreme than elsewhere in the world, so you must be prepared if embarking on hiking trails or extreme pursuits. Bring warm clothing, check weather reports and leave messages with your hotel or hostel about where you are going and when you expect to be back. Remote areas in the Highlands can have no mobile phone coverage and are not regularly visited so you must be prepared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safe Travel (&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.safetravel.is"&gt;www.safetravel.is&lt;/a&gt;) allows you to leave travel plans online, suggests equipment lists and has road and weather information. If you plan to pursue extreme sports or outdoors activities in the country, be sure that your insurance covers them. If you have an accident, helicopter transport might be necessary to one of the country&amp;rsquo;s main hospitals in Reykjav&amp;iacute;k or Akureyri.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The country is seismically active, but there is little risk to the traveller as long as local information is heeded. Hikers who disregarded warning information from the police about walking routes near active volcanoes in recent years have suffered the consequences. Volcanic activity is monitored closely and warnings are posted so it is very unlikely that you will encounter an entirely unexpected eruption. Be sure to stick to well-marked paths in volcanically active areas of national parks (and even in well-known tourist areas such as those around Geysir) as the unstable ground can be dangerous, and frequent small earthquakes can weaken ground substantially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Car crashes are the other serious threat to health in the country. Drive safely, obey all traffic laws and do not drink and drive. Be sure that you have read and understood the local traffic laws as many are posted on signs in Icelandic only; take a map with you as GPS can be unpredictable, and let people know where you are going and when you should be expected to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iceland&amp;rsquo;s animals do not present much risk; horses can bite but it is rare. In the summer, some areas including Myvatn in the north can suffer from midges. Cover up and take repellent to solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Maundy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>First Day of Summer :
							19 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>National Day :
							17 June </p><p>Commerce Day :
							06 August </p><p>Christmas Eve :
							24 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p><p>New Year's Eve :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Iceland by persons over 18 years of age (tobacco products) or 20 years of age (alcoholic beverages) without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 250g of other tobacco products. <br />
&bull; 1L of spirits and 0.75L of wine and 3L of beer; or 3L of wine and 6L of beer; or 1L of spirits and 6L of beer; or 1.5L of wine and 12L of beer; or 18L of beer. <br />
&bull; 3kg of food not exceeding ISK 25,000. Meat products are allowed as long as they&rsquo;ve been canned or boiled. Salting, smoking or drying meats without boiling them is unacceptable. Bacon, sausages (including salami and any kind of smoked uncooked sausages), pork, poultry and uncooked eggs and milk is not permitted.<br />
&bull; Icelandic residents may bring goods up to the value of ISK 88,000, unless under 12, in which case they can bring goods for half that amount.</p>
<p>Visitors may bring conventional medicines suitable for personal needs during their stay to cover up to a maximum of 100 days. Customs officers can request a doctor's certificate if appropriate.</p>
<p>You can find complete customs information at <a href="https://www.tollur.is/english/individuals/customs/traveling-to-iceland/duty-free-imports/" target="_blank">www.tollur.is</a>.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include uncooked meats and meat products, uncooked milk and eggs, snuff, various weapons, narcotics and dangerous drugs.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include telecommunications equipment (other than your mobile phone), angling gear and riding clothing (which require disinfection certificates), used riding gear, firearms and ammunition (which require a police permit), live animals, plants, and medicines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Protected plant species, birds, birds' eggs, eggshells and nests.</p>
<p>You must obtain permission from the Icelandic Museum of Natural History to export objects of historical or archaeological value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Icelandic kr&oacute;na (ISK; symbol kr) = 100 aurar. Notes are in denominations of  kr&oacute;na 5,000, 2,000, 1,000, 500 and 10,000. Coins are in denominations of kr&oacute;na 100, 50, 10, 5 and 1 and feature Iceland&rsquo;s many native fish species. It is often difficult to get Icelandic money abroad, though not impossible; there are several ATMs and banks at the airport on arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged in all major banks in Iceland. Most hotels also provide their guests with exchange services, which may cost more.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted. American Express is not as common.</p><p>ATMs (known as Hra&eth;banki in Icelandic) are available throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted, although mainly in key urban areas. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0915-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes/1/2</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for the duration of stay (EU travellers) or three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years (non-EU travellers)&nbsp;is required by nationals referred to in the chart above. This does not apply to travellers from:&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>1.</strong>&nbsp;Austria, Belgium, Bulgaria, Cyprus, the Czech Republic, Estonia,&nbsp;France, Germany, Greece, Hungary,&nbsp;Italy, Latvia,&nbsp;Lithuania, Luxembourg, Malta, the Netherlands, Poland, Portugal, Romania,&nbsp;Slovakia, Slovenia&nbsp;and&nbsp;Spain,&nbsp;who a can enter Iceland with a national ID card.</p>
<p><strong>2.</strong> Denmark, Finland or Sweden, who do not require a passport to enter Iceland if arriving directly from another Nordic country. Remember however that airlines may require a passport before allowing you to board the plane.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Any adult travelling with children may be required to show evidence of parental/custodial rights. You may need a letter of consent if the child is travelling with only one parent, depending on where you are travelling from.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Certain nationals (not those listed above) require a transit visa; check with the consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iceland is part of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: free for children under 6, &pound;35.00 for children 6-12, &pound;53.00 for all other children and adults.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visas are valid for a maximum of 90 days in each six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Icelandic embassies and consulates (other than the embassy in Beijing) do not issue visas. Icelandic visas are usually issued by the embassies of Denmark, Norway or Sweden; check the Directorate of Immigration's website (<a href="http://www.utl.is">www.utl.is</a>) for a list of embassies representing Iceland abroad. The Danish Embassy issues Icelandic visas in the UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas typically take up to 15 days to process from the date received at the embassy; in some circumstances they can take up to 60 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applicants for Schengen visas must provide proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You cannot usually extend a Schengen visa unless you have proof of <em>force majeure</em> or humanitarian reasons preventing you from leaving the territory. In these situations, you need to contact the Directorate of Immigration with a letter justifying the need for extending your visa.</p>
<p>EU/EEA nationals can stay in Iceland for three months without a permit and up to six months without if looking for employment. After this, you must register at the National Registry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To import a pet into Iceland, you need to obtain a permit from the Icelandic Food and Veterinary Authority (<a href="http://www.mast.is">www.mast.is</a>). The animal must be microchipped and vaccinated against rabies, unless the pet has spent at least six months in a rabies-free country before arrival in Iceland. You must book a spot for your animal at a quarantine facility; all pets must remain in quarantine for four weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[63.646259]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-19.006348]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>103,000 sq km (39,769 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>334,252 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Reykjavik.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iceland, one of the most volcanically active countries in the world, is a large island in the North Atlantic close to the Arctic Circle.</p>
<p>The most significant of its seismic features is found at &THORN;ingvellir National Park along the Almannagja fault. This rift in the rock shows the direct point on the earth where the Mid-Atlantic Rift runs through the island, where the North American and Eurasian tectonic plates are moving apart at an average of 2cm per year. The dramatic valley is clear on the land here, and is also visible in nearby &THORN;ingvellir Lake where divers visit the Silfra rift to see the crack between the tectonic plates in more detail.</p>
<p>Equally, volcano tourism is big business, with walking routes near the Eyjafjallajokull volcano, helitours over it and scenic trips to nearby Hekla, its hitherto most famous volcano, all popular.</p>
<p>Almost 80% of Iceland is uninhabited, the population being concentrated on the coast, in the valleys and in the plains of the southwest and southeast of the country. More than half the population lives in or around Reykjav&iacute;k, the capital. Akureyri in the north is the country&rsquo;s second largest city.</p>
<p>The whole of the central highland plateau of the island is a beautiful but barren and uninhabitable moonscape - so much so that the first American astronauts were sent there for pre-mission training.</p>
<p>Eleven percent of the island is covered by three large glaciers. Iceland's highest and most extensive glacier is Vatnaj&ouml;kull; at 8,100 sq km (3,127 sq miles), it is the largest in Europe, although it is now reported to be melting. Vatnaj&ouml;kull National Park, established in 2008, is Europe&rsquo;s largest national park, encompassing its namesake glacier as well as volcanoes, waterfalls and wetlands.</p>
<p>There are several smaller glaciers in the country, including Snaefellsjokull, visible from Reykjav&iacute;k, which sits atop an ancient cone volcano and was the setting for Jules Verne&rsquo;s <em>Journey to the Centre of the Earth</em>. Only 1% of the land in Iceland is cultivated, with 20% used for grazing sheep, Icelandic horses and cattle.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lutheran, with a Catholic minority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors will find Iceland is a classless society with a strong literary tradition. Handshaking is the normal form of greeting. An Icelander is called by his first name because his surname is made up of his father's Christian name plus 'son' or 'daughter' (eg John, the son of Magnus, would be called John Magnusson, while John's sister, Mary, would be known as Mary Magnusd&oacute;ttir). People are addressed as <em>Fru</em> (Mrs) and <em>Herra</em> (Mr). Visitors will often be invited to homes, especially if on business, and normal courtesies should be observed. Icelanders pay careful attention to their appearance and, as for most Western countries, casual wear is widely acceptable although unsuitable for smart and social functions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Katr&iacute;n Jakobsd&oacute;ttir since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Gudni J&oacute;hannesson since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The island was settled by the Norse seafarers in the ninth century; they established the world's first known republic and parliament in about AD 930. The original seat of this democratic system may be found at &THORN;ingvellir, about an hour's drive from Reykjav&iacute;k, where the original Viking settlers used a natural amphitheatre, formed by a cliff wall, as an assembly.</p>
<p>In the mid-13th century the islanders submitted to the authority of the King of Norway, and when Norway came under the control of Denmark in 1380, Iceland did too. In 1814, Norway became independent, but Iceland remained a Danish territory. In 1840 it was granted its own constitution &ndash; effectively allowing internal self-government. Full independence was granted in 1918, although it was not until 1944 that Iceland became a fully independent nation with its own head of state.</p>
<p>Contemporary Icelandic politics display the customary Western European spectrum of political parties, although a notable feature has been the influence of women within the main parties (Independence, Progressive, and Social Democratic). One of Iceland's most famous political figures of recent times is also a woman, Vigdis Finnbogadottir, who served four consecutive terms as President between 1980 and her resignation in 1996. She was replaced by Olafur Grimsson, who broke Finnbogadottir&rsquo;s record, beginning his fifth term as President in 2012, who in turn was replaced by Gu&eth;ni Th. J&oacute;hannesson in 2016.</p>
<p>The Parliament (Al&thorn;ingi) has generally been dominated by coalition governments. These were of a broadly centre-right persuasion until the mid-1970s, when the left began to gain more power until the election of a centre-right government in 2013.</p>
<p>The great economic collapse of the country in 2008 caused Icelanders to rise up in arms against what they viewed as a corrupt government. After highly visible protests, the then Prime Minister stepped down and the government collapsed. A new coalition government was created and the country&rsquo;s economic and political situation has stabilised.</p>
<p>Icelandic foreign policy is dominated by two factors: fishing and relations with Atlantic powers. Iceland is a member of Nato, the Nordic Council and of the Council of Europe. Ties with Nato have been loosening since before the end of the Cold War &ndash; in May 1985, the <em>Al&thorn;ingi</em> declared Iceland a 'nuclear-free zone' &ndash; and this process has accelerated with the closure of a large Nato base at Reykjavik.</p>
<p>Iceland applied for membership to the European Union in 2009, but the Eurosceptic government elected in 2013 decided to annul the bid in 2015.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Iceland introduced a universal ban on alcohol in 1915, which was, over the years, slowly relaxed. Beer, however, remained illegal until March 1989.<br />
&bull;	Surveys suggest more than half of Icelanders refuse to rule out the existence of the supernatural <em>hulduf&oacute;lk</em> (hidden people).<br />
&bull;	There are no surnames in Iceland. Rather, people adopt the first name of their father of mother as a last name, adding the suffix <em>son</em> (meaning son) or <em>d&oacute;ttir</em> (meaning daughter).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Iceland in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7259 3999.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.iceland.is/iceland-abroad/uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7259 3999.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1630. There is currently no Icelandic tourist board in the UK, but the embassy can deal with all enquiries.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Knightsbridge<br/>2A Hans Street<br/>London<br/>SW1X 0JE<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Iceland in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 265 6653</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.iceland.is/iceland-abroad/us/wdc</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 265 6653</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>#509<br/>2900 K. Street NW<br/>Washington<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A small dot in the Atlantic between Scandinavia and America, Iceland has built an impressive tourist industry from its abundant natural wonders. Even financial collapse during the global economic crisis failed to hold back &ldquo;the land of fire and ice&rdquo; for long, and visitors are once again flocking to its wilderness parks and dramatic landscapes.</p>
<p>The fire in question, of course, comes from Iceland&rsquo;s abundant volcanoes, which burst periodically into life, with sometimes costly consequences for European aviation. Elemental forces bubble just below the surface across the island, heating the water in Iceland&rsquo;s taps and swimming pools, and creating otherworldly landscapes of twisted lava and rainbow-coloured mineral sands.</p>
<p>Volcanic tourism is big news, with trips to bubbling fumaroles, live lava flows and perhaps the world&rsquo;s most reliable geyser at Geysir, which blows its top every four to eight minutes. Thermal springs surface everywhere, providing hot spots on the nation&rsquo;s beaches and heating the waters of the iconic Blue Lagoon, a surreal open-air swimming pool surrounded by a landscape of tortured black lava.</p>
<p>Ice is Iceland&rsquo;s other big draw (the clue is in the name) &ndash; more specifically, the dramatic glaciers which slice down towards the coast, calving icebergs into eerie lagoons. Glacier tours, by snowmobile, on foot, or on the back of a tiny Icelandic pony, are an integral part of the Iceland experience. In places, you can even tick off a glacier and a volcano on a single trip.</p>
<p>What lures many people back to Iceland a second or third time is the quirky nature of the Icelandic people. Eccentric, creative and fiercely independent, the Icelanders are simply a lot of fun to be around, particularly during the endless days of summer, when the <em>runtur</em> bar crawl rages through the streets of Reykjav&iacute;k, the island&rsquo;s miniature capital city.</p>
<p>So come trek a lava-field, gaze on a glacier, spot a whale or a puffin, sample one of Europe&rsquo;s strangest national cuisines, and brave the snows in winter to glimpse the northern lights in their full glory, undimmed by light pollution in the least densely populated nation in Europe.</p><p>A small dot in the Atlantic between Scandinavia and America, Iceland has built an impressive tourist industry from its abundant natural wonders. Even financial collapse during the global economic crisis failed to hold back &ldquo;the land of fire and ice&rdquo; for long, and visitors are once again flocking to its wilderness parks and dramatic landscapes.</p>
<p>The fire in question, of course, comes from Iceland&rsquo;s abundant volcanoes, which burst periodically into life, with sometimes costly consequences for European aviation. Elemental forces bubble just below the surface across the island, heating the water in Iceland&rsquo;s taps and swimming pools, and creating otherworldly landscapes of twisted lava and rainbow-coloured mineral sands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
