<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="India" ColCode="ind" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="in" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[India]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The weather is mainly hot most of the year with significant variations from region to region. The coolest weather lasts from around the end ofNovember to the beginning of March, with fresh mornings and evenings, and mostly sunny days. The really hot weather, when it is dry, dusty and unpleasant, is between March and June. Monsoon rains occur in most regions in summer anywhere between June and early October.</p>
<p><strong>Western Himalayas:</strong> Srinagar is best from March to October; July to August can be cold and damp in winter. Shimla is higher and therefore colder in winter. Places like Gulmarg, Manali and Pahalgam are usually under several feet of snow from December to March and temperatures in Ladakh, which is a high-altitude desert, can be extremely cold. The mountain passes of Ladakh are accessible from July to October.</p>
<p><strong>Northern Plains:</strong> Cities like <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/delhi">New Delhi</a>, Varanasi, Lucknow and Patna experience an extreme range of temperatures and are typically warm from April to mid-June, falling to almost freezing at night in winter between November and February. Summers are hot with monsoons between June and September.<br />
<br />
<strong>Central India:</strong> Madhya Pradesh state escapes the very worst of the hot season, but monsoons are heavy between July and September. Temperatures fall at night in winter.</p>
<p><strong>Western India:</strong> November to February is most comfortable, although evenings can be fairly cold. Summers can be extremely hot with monsoon rainfall between mid June and mid September.</p>
<p><strong>Eastern India:</strong> Weather in states like Orissa (which is flood-prone) are defined by cooler weather from October to February, scorching heat from March to May and unavoidable drenching from the monsoons from June to October.</p>
<p><strong>Southwest:</strong> The most pleasant weather is from November to March. Monsoon rains fall anywhere between late April and July. Summer temperatures are not as high as Northern India although humidity is extreme. The coast benefits from some cooling breezes. Inland, Mysore and Bijapur have pleasant climates with relatively low rainfall.</p>
<p><strong>Southeast: </strong>Tamil Nadu experiences a northeast monsoon between October and December and temperatures and humidity are high all year. The hills can be cold in winter.</p>
<p><strong>Northeast:</strong> March to June and September to November are the driest and most pleasant periods. The rest of the year has extremely heavy monsoon rainfall.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air carriers service all major Indian cities and most large towns. Domestic carriers include Air India (<a href="http://www.airindia.com" target="_blank">www.airindia.com</a>), GoAir (<a href="http://www.goair.in" target="_blank">www.goair.in</a>), IndiGo (<a href="http://www.goindigo.com" target="_blank">www.goindigo.com</a>), Jet Airways (<a href="http://www.jetairways.com" target="_blank">www.jetairways.com</a>) and SpiceJet (<a href="http://www.spicejet.com" target="_blank">www.spicejet.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are ferries from Kolkata (Calcutta) and Chennai (Madras) to Port Blair in the Andaman Islands. Contact the Shipping Corporation of India (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.shipindia.com/">www.shipindia.com</a>) for details. There are also services from Kochi and Calicut to the Lakshadweep Islands (<a target="_blank" href="http://lakport.nic.in/">http://lakport.nic.in</a>). Services are often seasonal, and are generally suspended during the monsoon. There is a seasonal catamaran service from Mumbai (Bombay) to Goa. One particularly attractive boat journey is the 'backwaters' excursion in the vicinity of Kochi in Kerala. Several local tours are available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Indian internal railway system is state-run by Indian Railways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.indianrail.gov.in/">www.indianrail.gov.in</a>). There are seven classes of travel: first-class air conditioned, first-class sleeper, second-class air conditioned, second-class, sleeper class, third-class air conditioned and air conditioned chair car. Major trains carry restaurant cars.</p>
<p><strong>Special trains:</strong> The Palace on Wheels (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.palacesonwheels.com">www.palacesonwheels.com</a>) is a luxury train especially popular with foreign tourists. Tariff includes cost of travel, full catering and conducted sightseeing tours. Itinerary: Delhi-Jaipur-Jaisalmer-Jodhpur-Ranthambore-Chittorgarh-Udaipur-Bharatpur-Agra-Delhi.</p>
<p>The<strong> </strong>Golden Chariot (<a href="http://www.goldenchariottrain.com" target="_blank">www.goldenchariottrain.com</a>) is a luxury train journey through Karnataka and includes a stop in Goa.</p>
<p>The Deccan Odyssey (<a href="http://www.deccan-odyssey-india.com" target="_blank">www.deccan-odyssey-india.com</a>) offers an eight-day jaunt through Maharashtra, pausing in Goa.</p>
<p>The Fairy Queen is the oldest steam engine in the world. The journey is a two-day round trip from Delhi to Alwar. Guests are taken to Sariska Tiger Reserve for a jeep safari and stay overnight in a hotel.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>The Darjeeling Himalayan Railway operates from New Jalpaiguri/Kurseong to Darjeeling. It climbs 2,100m (6,890ft).</p>
<p><strong>Other trains:</strong> The Rajdhani Express<strong> </strong>trains are deluxe super-fast trains connecting Delhi with a plethora of centres including Mumbai, Kolkata, Chennai (Madras), Bengaluru (Bangalore), Bhubaneswar, Secunderabad, Thiruvananthapuram, Ahmedabad and Ajmer.</p>
<p><strong>Shatabdi Express: </strong>Super-fast trains connecting major and secondary city centres. Snacks and meals are provided.</p>
<p><strong>Konkan Express: </strong>This route is Mumbai-Goa-Mangalore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Indrail</strong><strong> Pass</strong><strong>:</strong> enables unlimited rail travel for a specific period. Advance reservation is essential. You can purchase Indrail passes in the UK from SD Enterprises Ltd (tel: +44 20 8903 3411, in the UK; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.indiarail.co.uk/">www.indiarail.co.uk</a>). You can also buy passes in India at all main railway stations and authorised agents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A modern expressway links Delhi with Agra, where the Taj Mahal is situated; this has reduced travel times by road from five hours to around 3 hours.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> Travel in rural areas during the monsoon season can be hazardous and care should be taken. Monsoon rains cause flooding and landslides that can cut off some towns and villages for days at a time.</p>l<p>Outside the major cities main roads and other routes are often poorly maintained and congested with poor visibility and inadequate warning markers.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required. If importing your vehicle into India, get the latest documentation requirements from the Indian embassy in your home country.</p><p>Self-drive cars are not as widely available as chauffeur-driven ones. Driving around India is not recommended due to the erratic nature of driving standards and the heavy traffic.</p>
<p>There are a large number of chauffeur-driven tourist cars (some air conditioned) available in the main tourist centres. These unmetered tourist cars are usually cheaper than taxis if booked for an extended period of time. Shop around for the best deals and hire from a reputable firm.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taxis and auto rickshaws are available in large cities and fares should be charged by the kilometre. They do not always have meters but, where they do, visitors should insist on the meter being flagged in their presence. Fares change from time to time and therefore do not always conform to the reading on the meter, but drivers should always have a copy of the latest fare chart available for inspection. Kolkata (Calcutta), Delhi, Mumbai and Chennai (Madras) have metro systems.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">India</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">port_blair</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.05</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">c</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">India</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">mumbai</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">28.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">17.30a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">India</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kolkata</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">30.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">18.00b</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">India</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">chennai</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">45.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">32.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The major national airline in India is Air India &nbsp;(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.airindia.com">www.airindia.com</a>). There are also several commercial Indian airlines that have added international destinations to their schedules such as Jet Airways (<a href="http://www.jetairways.com" target="_blank">www.jetairways.com</a>)&nbsp;and IndiGo (<a href="http://www.goindigo.in" target="_blank">www.goindigo.in</a>). British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) fly direct to India from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>.</p>
<p>Prices are steady throughout the year but become more expensive in June, July and December.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/kolkata-netaji-subhas-chandra-bose-international-airport">Kolkata Netaji Subhas Chandra Bose International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/chennai-madras-meenambakkam-international-airport">Chennai International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/mumbai-chhatrapati-shivaji-international-airport">Mumbai Chhatrapati Shivaji International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/lal-bahadur-shastri-international-airport">Lal Bahadur Shastri International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/gaya-airport">Gaya Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/kempegowda-international-airport">Kempegowda International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/hyderabad-rajiv-gandhi-international-airport">Kempagowda International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/hyderabad-rajiv-gandhi-international-airport">Hyderabad Rajiv Gandhi International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/goa-international-airport">Goa International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/trivandrum-international-airport">Trivandrum International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/ahmedabad-airport-sardar-vallabhbhai-patel-international-airport">Sadar Vallabhbhai Patel International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/new-delhi-indira-gandhi-international-airport">New Delhi Indira Gandhi International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>: to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/delhi">Delhi</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;8 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kolkata-calcutta">Kolkata (Calcutta)</a> - 13 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chennai-madras">Chennai</a> (Madras) - 10 hours;&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mumbai-bombay">Mumbai (Bombay)</a> - 9 hours.</p>
<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>: to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/delhi">Delhi</a> is 14 hours; Kolkata (Calcutta) - 18 hours 40 minutes (including stopover); Chennai (Madras) - 18 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); Mumbai - 15 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Mumbai Chhatrapati Shivaji International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.csia.in<p>Mumbai Chhatrapati Shivaji International Airport is located 30km (19 miles) north of central Mumbai.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+91 22 6685 1010</p>]]><b>New Delhi Indira Gandhi International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.newdelhiairport.in<p>New Delhi Indira Gandhi International Airport is located 16km (10 miles) southwest of central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/delhi">Delhi</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+91 124 337 6000</p>]]><b>Kolkata Netaji Subhas Chandra Bose International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.kolkatainternationalairport.com<p>Kolkata Netaji Subhas Chandra Bose International Airport is located at Dum Dum, 18km (11 miles) to the northeast of central Kolkata.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+91 33 2511 8036</p>]]><b>Chennai International Airport</b><![CDATA[https://www.chennaiairport.com/<p>Chennai International Airport is located in Meenambakkam, 21km (13 miles) southwest of central Chennai.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+91 44 2256 0551</p>]]><b>Trivandrum International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aai.aero<p>Trivandrum International Airport is located 4km (2.5 miles) west of central Thiruvananthapuram (formerly Trivandrum), the capital of the Indian state of Kerala in the south of the country.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+91 471 250 1591</p>]]><b>Kempegowda International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bengaluruairport.com<p>Kempegowda International Airport is situated 40km (25 miles) from Bengaluru, in Devanahalli.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+91 1800 425 4425</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Indian Railways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.indianrail.gov.in">www.indianrail.gov.in</a>) runs most international services.</p>
<p>Connections to Pakistan:<strong> </strong>From India you can cross into <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pakistan">Pakistan</a> at the international Attari/Wagah border. There are bus and train services between India and Pakistan. Approaching the border away from the official crossing point may be dangerous.</p>
<p>Connections to Nepal: The most practical and popular route to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nepal">Nepal</a> is by train to Raxaul (Bihar) and then by bus to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kathmandu">Kathmandu</a> or by train to Gorakphur (or bus if coming from Varanasi) and then by bus to Kathmandu crossing the border at Sunauli; also, by train to Nantanwa (UP) and then by bus to Kathmandu/Pokhara, or Bhairawa to Lumbini for Pokhara. It is also possible to make the crossing from Darjeeling and Sikkim by bus to Kathmandu across the southern lowlands.</p>
<p>Connections to Bhutan: The best way of reaching <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bhutan">Bhutan</a> by land is by bus/train to Siliguri, then bus to Phuentsholing.</p>
<p>Connections to Bangladesh: The most convenient route to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangladesh">Bangladesh</a> is Kolkata (Calcutta) to Dhaka by bus. Another route is from Darjeeling via Siliguri, then train or bus from Jalpaiguri to Haldibari, or bus to Changrabandha.</p>
<p>It may be possible to cross the border between India and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/myanmar">Myanmar</a>, but it's reported that you need a permit for this crossing, so it may not be straightforward.</p>
<p>There is currently no land frontier open between India and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> (PR), other than a crossing between India and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tibet">Tibet</a> for religious pilgrims.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is limited to major towns but is increasing all the time.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The internet can be reliably accessed from an increasing number of hotels and from internet cafés across the country, many now with Wi-Fi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The state's TV monopoly was broken in 1992, resulting in a boom of private channels. News and entertainment shows are especially popular and a number of 24-hour news channels operate in India. India&rsquo;s cable TV market is one of the world&rsquo;s largest. Public TV is run by Doordarshan, while STAR Plus, owned by News Corporation, is one of the most popular private channels. Private radio stations were sanctioned in 2000, but only public All India Radio is allowed to broadcast news. Newspaper circulation has risen, thanks to a growing middle class, as has the number of Internet users to over 100 million. Many newspapers are in English; the most important include <em>The Economic Times</em>, <em>The Hindu</em>, <em>Hindustan Times</em>, <em>Indian Express</em>, <em>Punjab Kesari</em>, <em>Deccan Herald</em>, <em>The Statesman</em>, <em>The Pioneer</em> and <em>The Times of India</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mail services are generally good, but delivery times are variable. Airmail service to Western Europe or the US takes up to two weeks.</p><p>Regional variations, but generally Mon-Sat 1000-1300 and 1330-1630 in bigger towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Ellora Temple Caves</p><![CDATA[<p>The Ellora Temple Caves consist of 34 separate religious shrines carved into the actual rock of a basaltic hill and containing a wealth of sculptural and architectural treasures. Carved between the fourth and ninth centuries AD, the caves represent three separate faiths: Buddhism, Jainism and Hinduism. The 16 Buddhist Caves are the oldest in the group. The Jain Caves illustrate the non-violent, ascetic beliefs of this religion, depicting scenes of pastoral beauty and images such as lotus flowers. In terms of stylistic ambition, the Hindu Caves outdo their neighbours – one cave alone, the Temple of Kailasa, covers twice the area of the Parthenon in Athens and took 100 years to complete. Dedicated to Lord Shiva, this temple is the largest monolith in the world and is undoubtedly the most visited site at Ellora.</p>]]><br/><p>Ghats at Varanasi</p><![CDATA[<p>Varanasi, which was created by Lord Shiva, is one of the oldest and holiest cities in India and home to the most famous ghats (steps leading down to the river) in the country. Worshippers flock to these ghats every day to bathe in the holy River Ganges and then worship at the many temples lining the riverbank. Huge crowds of pilgrims gather to take part in this ancient ritual which involves making offerings (puja) to the rising sun and is often watched by tourists who come to photograph this incredible sight.</p>]]><br/><p>Kaziranga National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Kaziranga National Park was set aside as a game sanctuary in 1926 and became a national park in 1974. It's made up of 688 sq km (266 sq miles) of breathtaking land, containing rainforests, mighty rivers, sprawling grasslands and herds of wild elephant. It is best known for its thriving population of one-horned Indian rhino, which is the largest in the world. The rhino's natural enemy, the tiger, also lives in the park along with many other typical species of Indian wildlife. Visitors can use jeeps or cars to travel around the park or can opt for a more traditional mode of transport on the back of an elephant. The park has been included on the UNESCO World Heritage List since 1985.</p>]]><br/><p>Palace of the Winds (Hawa Mahal)</p><![CDATA[<p>Built in 1799, <em>Hawa Mahal </em>is the most stunning sight in the city of Jaipur. The palace, part of a huge complex, overlooks one of Jaipur&rsquo;s main streets and was originally constructed to offer women of the court a vantage point, behind stone-carved screens, from which to watch the activities taking place in the bazaar and the surrounding streets. For this purpose, it was designed with over 900 niches, and the entire building is shaped like a crown adorning Lord Krishna&rsquo;s head. The site offers superb views of the city, including the many old palaces and houses which were painted ochre-pink, the colour of hospitality, by the Rajputs, for the 1853 visit of Prince Albert.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the artistry of Ajanta and Ellora</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The stunning rock-cut cave temples at Ajanta and Ellora are the crowning glory of Indian religious art. The temples of Ellora were hewn by Buddhist, Hindu and Jain stone-carvers from the 5th to the 10th century, but nearby Ajanta is even older, with exquisite murals that may date back as far as the 2nd century BC.</p>]]><p><b>Bend to the power of Yoga</b></p><![CDATA[<p>India is the birthplace of yoga, one of the world's best-loved traditional therapies. At ashrams and yoga retreats across India, you can learn the fine art of yoga from the people who invented it, or at least their direct descendants. Head to Haridwar or Rishikesh in the Uttarkhand hills to discover yoga at its spiritual source.</p>]]><p><b>Delve into Delhi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>India's capital is a riot of sounds, smells and sensations. Eight separate capitals have risen up on this site over the centuries, ruled by a string of empires. The heart of the city is Old Delhi, which overflows with forts, mosques and maze-like bazaars; south of the old city, New Delhi was laid out in wide avenues by the colonial architect Lutyens.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the belief in India’s temples</b></p><![CDATA[<p>India overflows with temples, from modern marvels like Delhi's Akshardham to the timeless glory of the erotic temples of Khajuraho. Amritsar's Golden Temple is the most sacred site for the Sikh religion, while the temples at Ranakpur are thronged by Jain pilgrims. In the east, Konark is one of India's treasures, built in the shape of a vast stone chariot.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the flow of the River Ganges</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The mighty River Ganges is a direct channel to the divine for India&rsquo;s 1.06 billion Hindus. At the wondrous city of Varanasi, one of India's holiest Hindu pilgrimage towns, the riverside ghats are mobbed by pilgrims and holy men performing ritual ablutions and prayers as the sun rises and sets over the sacred river.</p>]]><p><b>Find Bollywood in Bombay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Delhi may have the history and architecture, but Mumbai (formerly Bombay) is India's capital of fashion, film, finance and fun. Mumbai is a city of phenomenal contrasts, where India's tallest skyscrapers rise against a backdrop of ramshackle bazaars and slums. Attractions include ancient cave temples, colonial monuments, fine dining restaurants, the movie studios of Bollywood and the world's busiest train stations.</p>]]><p><b>Find peace in Kashmir</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Troubled Kashmir manages to be both India's most serene spot, and sometimes its most dangerous. When things are peaceful, the legendary Kashmir Valley is mesmerising, with its ancient mosques, Mughal gardens and houseboats drifting over its serene lake. Because of the security situation, many opt instead for neighbouring Ladakh, which moves to the peaceful refrain of Buddhist temple bells.</p>]]><p><b>Head for the hills</b></p><![CDATA[<p>India's hill stations are a bizarre facsimile of England, transported to the forested highlands of India. In towns such as Shimla (Himachal Pradesh), Darjeeling (West Bengal), Ooty (Tamil Nadu), Kodaikanal (Tamil Nadu), you'll find grand colonial hotels, whitewashed churches and dainty teahouses set against a spectacular backdrop of Himalayan peaks.</p>]]><p><b>Join the fun at a Hindu festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The 330 million deities of Hinduism are celebrated in all their vivid glory at festivals such as Durga Puja (September/October) in Kolkata (Calcutta), where thousands of rainbow-coloured idols are immersed in rivers and pools. Other must-see celebrations include Holi, the festival of colours (March), Diwali, the festival of light (October/November), and the Kumbh Mela, the largest human gathering on Earth.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back on India’s beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mumbai (Bombay) has Juhu and Chowpatty, and Chennai (Madras) has Marina Beach, but the best beaches of all are down in the south. Goa offers some of the nation's top strips of sand, while Kerala offers an even steamier version of the tropical south. Then there are the beaches of the Andamans – pure tropical perfection.</p>]]><p><b>Move to Indian rhythms</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From the show-tunes of Bollywood to the haunting melodies of the sitar and <em>shehnai</em> (Indian oboe), Indian music has a way of getting into the blood. You'll hear it everywhere, from temple courtyards and dinner shows to buses and marketplaces, where the singers of the latest movie soundtracks are treated with the kind of adulation normally reserved for Beyonce and Beiber.</p>]]><p><b>Roam through Rajasthan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From the glorious capital, Jaipur, to the Blue City of Jodhpur and the White City of Udaipur, Rajasthan is awash with desert fortresses, terrific temples and the palaces of Maharaja. For the ultimate Rajasthani experience, head for the desert city of Jaisalmer, where camel safaris into the Thar Desert offer a little taste of what life was like in India's glorious past.</p>]]><p><b>Sample serene Buddhist India</b></p><![CDATA[<p>When the Dalai Lama fled Tibet, he found sanctuary, along with the exiled Tibetan administration, in Dharamshala in Himachal Pradesh. Today, Tibetan Buddhist communities thrive across India, from the high-altitude deserts of Ladakh to the mountains of Himachal Pradesh and Sikkim and remote Arunachal Pradesh in the far northeast, offering a whole different take on Indian spirituality.</p>]]><p><b>Sample the steamy south in Kerala</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For a complete break from India's urban grit, cruise along the tropical backwaters of Kerala, pausing en route to visit country villages and scattered temples and beaches. On board, you can sample one of India's best-loved cuisines, with delicious seafood cooked in coconut curries. For something really unique, see Kerala's <em>kathakali </em>dancers perform their elaborate routines.</p>]]><p><b>Seek the perfect brew in India’s northeast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover where the humble cuppa comes from on a tour of one of India's tea plantations, which spread out like a green carpet around Darjeeling, Assam and the Nilgiri Hills of south India. On a plantation tour, you'll meet workers picking tea in a landscape of vivid green and get a chance to sample India's finest brews.</p>]]><p><b>Seek tigers in India’s national parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>India boasts more than 100 national parks, 500 wildlife sanctuaries and 18 biosphere reserves, providing a much-needed home for rare tigers, Asiatic elephants, one-horned Indian rhinos and more. Among the best-known reserves are Keoladeo Ghana National Park (Rajasthan), Ranthambore National Park (Rajasthan), Kanha National Park (Madhya Pradesh), Corbett Tiger Reserve (Uttarakhand) and Sunderbans Tiger Reserve (West Bengal).</p>]]><p><b>Soak up the atmosphere in artistic Kolkata</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Where Mumbai is all razzle and dazzle, Kolkata exudes an air of calm sophistication. India's capital of the arts is a fascinating collection of bustling bazaars, sprawling parks, and grand, decaying colonial monuments that once housed the government of British India, where life moves to the same timeless rhythms as the turgid Hooglhy River.</p>]]><p><b>Splash down in the Andaman Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For the real tropical paradise experience, there's really only one choice. Floating off the east coast of India, the Andaman Islands are densely forested, ringed by sand and fringed by coral reefs teeming with tropical fish. This remote archipelago is also home to Adivasi tribal people whose ancient way of life endures despite the challenges of modernisation.</p>]]><p><b>Take a desert safari</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mughal India was the crowning glory of the Islamic world, and while other empires stole the thunder, the ancient cities of north India still swim with the romance of <em>Arabian Nights</em>. For the full experience, get out into the India's sprawling deserts on camel back from Jaisalmer, and camp beneath an unbelievably clear panorama of stars.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the Taj</b></p><![CDATA[<p>India's Golden Triangle offers a mesmerising circuit through Delhi, Jaipur and Agra, but it's the Taj Mahal that everyone comes to see. Described as the greatest monument ever built for love, it's perhaps the most aesthetically perfect building on earth, constructed from gleaming white marble by the heart-broken Mughal emperor, Shah Jahan, for his favourite wife.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind on the sand in Goa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Although less mellow than in the happy-be-go-lucky days of the 1960s, the hippy hangouts of Goa have evolved into India's favourite seaside resorts. The occasional full moon party can still be found in places such as Anjuna, but today, the focus is more on sunbathing, sipping local spirits and sampling the Portuguese-influenced cuisine of the coast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2.264 trillion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Textiles, gems and jewellery, technology services, chemicals and leather manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, machinery, gems, iron, steel, fertiliser and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, United Arab Emirates, Hong Kong,&nbsp;China, UK,&nbsp;Germany and Singapore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roughly 58% of the population is involved in agriculture, both subsistence (mainly cereals) and cash crops, including rice, tea, rubber, coffee and cotton.</p>
<p>India's main industrial development has been in engineering, iron and steel, chemicals, electronics and textiles. Since the 1990s, trade has been liberalised, the sprawling public sector cut back, and some state-owned industries sold off.</p>
<p>India ranks among the top ten in the world by gross national product. The economy has resumed its healthy growth rate, currently at around 7.1% per annum, while inflation is at 3%. The unemployment rate hovers around 9%. Further improvements to the national infrastructure and basic services are now seen as the priority for central and regional governments.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>English is widely used in commercial circles, so there is little need for translation services. Indian businesspeople welcome visitors and are generally very hospitable. The common spoken greeting &lsquo;namaste&rsquo;, is normally accompanied by placing both hands together, as if in prayer, and tilting the head forward. Indian women may prefer not to shake hands, although men are comfortable with it. Unless invited to address a person by their first name, use Mr/Mrs/Dr and the surname. Business cards are an important part of networking. A suit is considered the proper form of business attire. Business hours are generally 0930-1730.</p>
<p>Corporate entertaining is important but bear in mind the cultural etiquette. Indians only eat with the right hand. The left hand is used for less savoury actions, such as removing shoes. Gifts and business cards should be accepted with the right hand or both hands at the same time, as a sign of respect.</p>
<p>If you're invited to an Indian home for dinner, you may not eat until after 2300. However, once dinner is over, the party is at an end, the guest may depart without giving offence. Shoes should be removed when entering a private home and try to avoid pointing your feet at anyone. It is customary to wash one's hands before and after a meal.</p>
<p>Drinking, especially at lunchtime, should be avoided until visitors are certain of the host's opinion. Even then, alcohol should always be consumed in moderation.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0930-1730, Sat 0930-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>The Associated Chambers of Commerce and Industry of India (ASSOCHAM)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 110 048,(011) 4655 0555
					Website:http://www.assocham.org/
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FICCI)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 110 001,(011) 2373 8760
					Website:http://www.ficci.com/
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Indian food is world-renowned for its tantalising flavours, spiciness and enormous variety. Many of the spices we now take for granted &ndash; pepper, cardamom, turmeric &ndash; hail from India&rsquo;s plains and jungles. The flavour of each Indian dish is a carefully judged balance of herbs, seasonings and spices, and each cook carefully maintains their own recipe for <em>garum masala </em>&ndash; literally &lsquo;hot mix&rsquo;.</p>
<p>Rice is the foundation stone of Indian cooking, but you&rsquo;ll also find many kinds of bread, from light, flat <em>chapattis </em>to fat, roasted <em>naan</em>. As often as not, Indian meals are served as <em>thalis</em>, with rice, <em>sabzi</em> (vegetables), soups, and side orders, all served on a single plate.</p>
<p>The north of India specialises in meaty stews and kebabs, while the south favours highly spiced vegetarian curries and <em>dosas</em> (rice-flour pancakes). Head to Bengal or the beaches of Goa and Kerala to sample India&rsquo;s finest seafood.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dhal: </strong>Lentils; there are dozens of varieties and they come stewed, fried or ground up into flour as an essential ingredient for pastries and fritters.<br />
<strong>Pakora:</strong> Deep-fried vegetables in lentil-flour batter, a favourite portable snack.<br />
<strong>Samosa:</strong> Triangular pastry parcels, stuffed with potato and pea curry.<br />
<strong>Thali: </strong>A platter of rice, chapattis, vegetable curries, meat dishes and more; in many parts of India, this is a just described a &lsquo;meal&rsquo;.<br />
<strong>Naan: </strong>India&rsquo;s favourite bread, cooked in the tandoor (clay oven).<br />
<strong>Tandoori chicken: </strong>A Punjabi speciality, spiced chicken marinated in yoghurt, cooked in the tandoor.<br />
<strong>Paneer: </strong>Soft Indian curd cheese cooked in sauces or spiced and grilled.<br />
<strong>Jalebi: </strong>Deep-fried batter in sweet syrup, poured out in a nest of orange squiggles.<br />
<strong>Dosa: </strong>A pancake made from fermented rice-flour batter, serve with curry dips or stuffed with vegetables curry, originally from the south.<br />
<strong>Chai: </strong>Sweet, strong Indian tea, best sampled from roadside <em>chai-wallahs</em>.<br />
<strong>Kingfisher:</strong> India&rsquo;s most popular lager.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Bottled water is recommended for visitors but make sure the bottles are properly sealed. Alcohol is mainly served at mid- and upper-range restaurants in the larger towns and cities known as &ldquo;resto-bars&rdquo;; in budget eateries, it's usually only found at non-vegetarian restaurants which have a liquor licence. Bars on the lower end of the scale are generally male and seedy.</p>
<p>As of April 2017, alcoholic beverages may no longer be sold within a radius of 500m of national roads.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10 to 15% is usual in restaurants that impose no service fee; optional where service fee is added to bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18-25 (depending on the state) and is also illegal in some states.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Apart from some of the major cities, such as Mumbai (Bombay), Delhi and Kolkata (Calcutta), India has generally little nightlife as the term is understood in the West. In those cities with a flourishing nightlife, expect to find swanky bars, nightclubs and a vibrant performing arts scene. In many larger towns and tourist centres there are cultural shows featuring regionally-diverse performances of Indian dance and music. Delhi also hosts film festivals throughout the year. The famous Raj Mandir cinema (which resembles a large, flamboyant wedding cake) in Jaipur is the place to experience Bollywood films as they were made to be seen: in public and with large helpings of audience interaction. Goa is the only state with casinos – gambling is highly restricted in India – and it also still merits its reputation as the party state with world-class clubbing and beach gatherings de rigour during peak season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Each region has its own specialities, each town its own local craftspeople and its own particular skills, often passed down from generation to generation. For fabrics, silverware, carpets, leatherwork, gems and antiques, India is a shopper's paradise. <br />
Bazaars and well-organised melas can be found in cities and many regional hotspots &ndash; Chennai, Hyderbad, Bangalore.</p>
<p>Shopping is as varied as India&rsquo;s topography. There are specialised wholesale markets for specific items like spices, coffee and tea in Old Dehli&rsquo;s Chandni Chowk or in Jaipur where there are single streets allotted to one item like clothing, chappals and jewellery. Prices are not usually visible and bargaining is the norm at most local bazaars. Be aware, there is a tourist premium affixed to many items. If you are uncomfortable with bargaining, many tourist spots across India will have state-run emporia where reasonable prices can be found such as Delhi&rsquo;s Baba Kharak Singh Marg or Aparant network of outlets in Goa. Cash is the usual form of payment. It sometimes helps to have a local with you when shopping who can help you discern quality and good prices.</p>
<p>India has one of the world's largest carpet industries and exquisite Persian rugs can be found nationally. If you prefer to shop direct head to Jammu &amp; Kashmir and Leh to pick up hand woven carpets and pashmina shawls. Shahtoosh shawls may be on sale but it is illegal to buy or sell them so avoid. Other goods include pickles, spices, Indian tea, perfumes, soap, handmade paper, incense, puppets and musical instruments.</p>
<p>The best time to shop is around festival time at Diwali, which generally runs from late October to early November. This is high season and many retailers from around the country will converge at the large melas in major cities to sell their goods.</p>
<p>Shopping can also have charitable benefits if you buy directly from the producers at the bazaars. Alternatively, there are a few non-governmental organisations (NGOs) supported through items they make and sell in their own shops. Try the Craft Revival Trust site (www.craftrevival.org) which lists information about the history of crafts around India and has a directory of where to buy direct from producers or other NGOs that run craft outfits.</p>
<p>There is a veto on the export of antiques, art objects over 100 years old, livestock, animal skins, products made from animal skins, live plants, human skeletons, illicit drugs, weapons, ivory, products made from ivory, animal horns, endangered shells, antiques, gold and silver bullion.</p><p>Shopping hours are Mon-Sat around 0930-1900 in most large stores; variable hours in bazaars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in India offer the whole gamut of possibilities, from premier 5-star establishments and Heritage Hotels (converted historic palace buildings) to budget backpacker affairs and delightful back-to-basics beach huts. Modern and boutique hotels are available in all large cities and popular tourist centres. Business people are also well catered for. To experience full-on lavishness there are a number of palace hotels in Rajasthan and Shimla. Hotel services in the luxury and business range are comparable with other major cities and therefore can be very pricey particularly during tourist high season which runs from early October to February. However, even if you are not staying in 5-star hotels you can still enjoy some of the luxury by booking in a spa service or have a meal at one of the restaurants.</p>
<p>Hotel bills may be subject to a 10% expenditure tax, 7-15% luxury tax and a variable service charge.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in India range from 5-star deluxe, 5- and 4-star hotels, which are fully air conditioned with all luxury features, 3-star hotels, which are functional and have air-conditioned rooms, to 2- and 1-star hotels, which offer basic amenities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfasts are increasingly popular alternatives offering a more personal and local touch. The Government of India&rsquo;s Ministry of Tourism (<a href="(http://tourism.gov.in/sites/default/files/082720140204879_0.pdf) " target="_blank">tourism.gov.</a>) has an updated, but not very user-friendly, list of approved B&amp;Bs across India in two categories - gold and silver. There are set guidelines for owners to gain approval in each category.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in India offer the whole gamut of possibilities, from premier 5-star establishments and Heritage Hotels (converted historic palace buildings) to budget backpacker affairs and delightful back-to-basics beach huts. Modern and boutique hotels are available in all large cities and popular tourist centres. Business people are also well catered for. To experience full-on lavishness there are a number of palace hotels in Rajasthan and Shimla. Hotel services in the luxury and business range are comparable with other major cities and therefore can be very pricey particularly during tourist high season which runs from early October to February. However, even if you are not staying in 5-star hotels you can still enjoy some of the luxury by booking in a spa service or have a meal at one of the restaurants.</p>
<p>Hotel bills may be subject to a 10% expenditure tax, 7-15% luxury tax and a variable service charge.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in India range from 5-star deluxe, 5- and 4-star hotels, which are fully air conditioned with all luxury features, 3-star hotels, which are functional and have air-conditioned rooms, to 2- and 1-star hotels, which offer basic amenities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in India offer the whole gamut of possibilities, from premier 5-star establishments and Heritage Hotels (converted historic palace buildings) to budget backpacker affairs and delightful back-to-basics beach huts. Modern and boutique hotels are available in all large cities and popular tourist centres. Business people are also well catered for. To experience full-on lavishness there are a number of palace hotels in Rajasthan and Shimla. Hotel services in the luxury and business range are comparable with other major cities and therefore can be very pricey particularly during tourist high season which runs from early October to February. However, even if you are not staying in 5-star hotels you can still enjoy some of the luxury by booking in a spa service or have a meal at one of the restaurants.</p>
<p>Hotel bills may be subject to a 10% expenditure tax, 7-15% luxury tax and a variable service charge.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in India range from 5-star deluxe, 5- and 4-star hotels, which are fully air conditioned with all luxury features, 3-star hotels, which are functional and have air-conditioned rooms, to 2- and 1-star hotels, which offer basic amenities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Good healthcare facilities, sometimes meeting Western standards, are available in all major cities, but facilities in rural areas are often limited. Travellers are strongly advised to take out full comprehensive medical insurance before departing for India. It is advisable to bring specific medicines from the UK. There are state-operated facilities in all towns and cities and private consultants and specialists in urban areas.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On leaving India:&lt;/strong&gt; Visitors leaving for countries which impose health restrictions on arrivals from India are required to be in possession of a valid certificate of inoculation and vaccination.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should first be boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is often unpasteurised and should be boiled. Avoid dairy products likely to have been made from non-boiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Do not eat salads, vegetables should be cooked and peel your own fruit. Don't eat street vendor food unless it is piping hot. Tap water is not safe to drink, rely on bottled water which is widely available. However, do check the seal on bottled water.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations are sometimes advised for hepatitis A and B, Japanese encephalitis, tuberculosis (for infants), polio and typhoid. Dengue and malaria are both caused by mosquito bites and are prevalent in hot and humid conditions. There are occasional, seasonal outbreaks of dengue fever. Travellers should vigilantly protect themselves against mosquito bites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were confirmed cases of the Zika virus in the western state of Gujarat in late 2016; travellers should take the necessary precautions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malaria prevention is strongly recommended so use insect repellent and wear protective clothing. Obtain anti-malarial medicine from your doctor before travelling. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Even seasoned travellers may find themselves at the mercy of travellers&amp;rsquo; diarrhoea. Hygiene standards vary. If possible, travel around with soap or antibacterial gel in order to clean your hands. The culprits that cause diarrhoea are often the microorganisms found in local water supplies, so decrease your chances by drinking bottled or boiled water. You can have alcoholic drinks but say no to ice. Drink carbonated beverages or those with only boiled water like coffee and tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carry rehydration solution packets, Pepto Bismol or Imodium in case you are afflicted.  Before your travel, seek medical advice about what to take for self-treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wear adequate sunscreen or do like the locals to beat the heat and avoid the sun between 1200 and 1600 when it is at its harshest; don a cotton kameez to keep covered and cool. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; All visitors aged between 18 and 70 years of age wishing to extend their visa for one year or more are required to take an AIDS test.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Only the secular holidays of Republic Day, Independence Day and Mahatma Gandhi's Birthday are universally observed. <br /><br />(a) Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given above are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.<br /><br />(b) Hindu festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Republic Day :
							2018<br/>26 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Independence Day :
							15 August </p><p>Mahatma Gandhi's Birthday :
							02 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into India by non-resident travellers over 18 without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 100 cigarettes or 25 cigars or 125g of tobacco. <br />
&bull; 2L of spirits or wine.<br />
&bull; Gifts and souvenirs to the value of Rs8,000 (US$125).<br />
&bull; Reasonable quantities of medicines.</p>
<p>Import by non-residents is only permitted if the national has entered India for a stay of not more than six months within a 12-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include narcotics, pornography, counterfeit and pirated goods, and antiquities.</p>
<p>Restricted items include firearms and ammunition, live birds and animals, endangered species, gold and silver (other than ornaments), and Indian currency. Indian residents only may import up to Rs25,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include narcotics, pornography, counterfeit and pirated goods, and antiquities.</p>
<p>Restricted items include firearms and ammunition, live birds and animals, endangered species, and Indian currency. Indian residents only may export up to Rs25,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rupee (INR; symbol Rs) = 100 paise. Notes are in denominations of Rs2,000, 500, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of Rs5, 2 and 1, and 50, 25, 20, 10 and 5 paise.</p>
<p>The Indian government's decision to take 500 and 1,000 rupee notes out of immediate circulation in November 2016 caused widespread cash shortages, although a different 500 rupee note was later introduced. Updates can be found on the Reserve Bank of India's <a href="http://www.rbi.org.in">website</a>.</p>
<p><strong><br />
Note:</strong> The import and export of local currency is prohibited. Sometimes smaller vendors will not take bills larger than Rs 500. It is best to carry a range of rupee notes if you are shopping at bazaars and local markets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency can be changed at banks, airports or authorised money changers. Many hotels also have facilities to change money but this is a more expensive option. It is illegal to exchange money through unauthorised money changers. US Dollars and Pounds Sterling are the easiest currencies to exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In major cities, the full cadre of banks cards are generally accepted including debit cards, American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa. However, in smaller towns and villages, choice is generally narrowed to cash or MasterCard and Visa.</p><p>24 hour ATM machines can be found in all the major cities and most large towns. Visa, MasterCard, Cirrus, Maestro and Plus are amongst the most commonly accepted cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers cheques are increasingly hard to cash in India and are no longer recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 1030-1530; Sat 1030-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A machine-readable passport valid for at least 180 days and with at least two blank pages is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>e-Tourist Visa: up to US$100, depending on nationality.</p>
<p>UK nationals: transit visa: US$72; tourist visa: US$153; business visa: US$222.</p>
<p>US nationals: transit visa: US$40; tourist visa: US$100; business visa: US$133.</p>
<p>Other nationals listed in the chart above: transit visa: $US17;&nbsp;tourist visa: US$100 (up to six months), US$185 (up to one year); business visa: fees vary according to nationality.</p>
<p>All visa applications are subject to a non-refundable service charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>e-Visa: 60 days from the date of arrival, with double entry for tourist and business visas and triple entry for medical visas. The duration cannot be extended.</p>
<p>Transit: valid for three months for a maximum stay of 15 days.</p>
<p>Tourist/business for UK nationals: valid for single or multiple entries within one year (maximum stay of 180 days per visit).</p>
<p>Visa validity for other nationals varies according to nationality.</p>
<p>Visas issued by the embassy/VFS Global&nbsp;are valid from the date of issue <em>not</em> your date of departure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consular section at your nearest embassy or high commission. For UK nationals, India has outsourced its visa application services to VFS Global (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.vfsglobal.com</a>); all applicants must make an appointment to visit an application centre in person. In the USA, India&rsquo;s visa application services are handled by Cox and Kings Global Services (<a href="http://www.in.ckgs.us" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.in.ckgs.us</a>).</p>
<p>Those eligible for an e-Tourist Visa can apply online (<a href="https://indianvisaonline.gov.in/visa/tvoa.html" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">https://indianvisaonline.gov.in/visa/tvoa.html</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>e-Tourist Visas are usually issued immediately or within a few hours.</p>
<p>Straightforward applications through VFS Global in the UK take at least three to five working days, but others may take longer, depending on the applicant's nationality.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa extensions are not available in India, unless in extreme circumstances (eg medical emergency).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An incoming passenger can import up to two pets at one time. These include all domestic animals such as dogs, birds, cats etc, subject to producing the required health certificate from their country of origin. Pets are still liable for the usual quarantine checks upon arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[22.670976]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[79.143997]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3,287,263 sq km (1,269,219 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,326,801,576 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>382 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Delhi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>India shares borders to the northwest with Pakistan, to the north with China, Nepal and Bhutan, and to the east with Bangladesh and Myanmar. To the west lies the Arabian Sea, to the east the Bay of Bengal and to the south the Indian Ocean. The Andaman and Nicobar Islands are Indian territory but lie off the coast of Thailand in the Bay of Bengal. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sri-lanka">Sri Lanka</a> lies off the southeast coast, and the Maldives off the southwest coast. <br />
<br />
The far northeastern states and territories are all but separated from the rest of India by Bangladesh as it extends northwards from the Bay of Bengal towards Bhutan. India is separated from the rest of Asia by mountain ranges, forest, and desert -the Himalayan mountain range in the north, the Thar Desert in the west and the Chin Hills and Patkai ranges in the east. The Indus River runs through the northern disputed territory of Jammu &amp; Kashmir. The most sacred of rivers, the Ganges, is in the east.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>About 80% Hindu, 14% Muslim, with Sikh, Christian, Jain, Parsi and Buddhist minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The traditional Hindu greeting is to fold the hands, tilt the head forward and say namaste. Indian women generally prefer not to shake hands. All visitors are asked to remove footwear when entering places of religious worship. Most Indians also remove their footwear when entering their homes; visitors should follow suit. Many Hindus are vegetarian and many, especially women, do not drink alcohol. Most Sikhs and Parsis do not smoke. Women are expected to dress modestly and men should also dress respectfully. Women should not wear short skirts and tight or revealing clothing, although there is a more casual approach to clothing in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india/goa-international-airport">Goa</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs have either two or three round pins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Ram Nath Kovind since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>India was home to one of the oldest civilisations, which rose in the Indus Valley in the 3rd millennia BC. The intervening 5,000 years have seen hundreds of invasions and the rise and fall of myriad empires, from the Muslim Mughals who built the Taj Mahal, to the Portuguese &ndash; the first European powers to arrive and the last to leave, in 1961 &ndash; and the French, who carved out their own Indian enclave at Puducherry (Pondicherry).</p>
<p>But the most well-known of India&rsquo;s colonisers were the British, who came as traders in the 17th century, and, through the machinations of the East India Company, managed to take over the entire subcontinent. Under British rule, railways were built, great cities rose and government was centralised, but the maharajas and sultans were reduced to servants of the empire, and India became an engine to further the fortunes of a foreign power.</p>
<p>The Indian Mutiny in 1857 marked the transition of power to the British monarchy, and also the beginning of organised resistance to British rule. While India fought alongside <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Britain</a> in two world wars, intellectuals and spiritual leaders were sowing the seeds of rebellion. These ideas were crystallised by one man: Mahatma Gandhi, a former lawyer who preached a doctrine of equality to be gained through passive resistance.</p>
<p>In 1942, Gandhi launched the &lsquo;Quit India&rsquo; campaign, which started with gestures of defiance like making salt from seawater and ended with Indian Independence in 1947. Tragically, communal tensions between Hindus and Muslims led to India being wrenched apart, with Muslim areas separating to become West and East Pakistan (now <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangladesh">Bangladesh</a>). Millions died in the process and Gandhi himself was killed by a Hindu zealot in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/delhi">Delhi</a> in 1948.</p>
<p>Nearly 70 years later, and the consequences of Partition are still being felt, with India and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pakistan">Pakistan</a> existing in an almost constant state of war or near-war over the disputed territory of Kashmir. Communal violence is still a regular problem, as is political violence by separatist guerrillas and Pakistani insurgents.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, in other areas, India is boldly marching forwards. India has become a major technology hub, and the Indian economy is predicted to overtake <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> by the middle of the century. The Indian prime minister, Narendra Modi, is spearheading reforms and speeding development, despite accusations of bias towards the Hindu community.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	India is the world&rsquo;s largest democracy, with 814 million eligible voters. <br />
&bull;	Many of the most common terms in the English language are from India, including shampoo, jungle, mugger, dinghy, loot and bungalow. <br />
&bull;	India was the source of all the world&rsquo;s diamonds until the discovery of diamond deposits in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brazil">Brazil</a> in the 18th century.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in India]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(011) 2419 2100</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinindia.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(011) 2419 2100</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1300 / 1400-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Chanakyapuri<br/><br/>New Delhi<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of India in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 707 4693 (Consulate) (202) 939 7000 (Chancery).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.indianembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 707 4693 (Consulate) (202) 939 7000 (Chancery).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1800; consular section Mon-Fri 0930-1230, 1630-1715.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2536 Massachusetts Ave NW<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission of India in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7836 8484 or (020) 7632 3123 (out of office hours).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.hcilondon.net</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7836 8484 or (020) 7632 3123 (out of office hours).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0915-1745.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Aldwych<br/>London<br/>WC2B 4<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>India is a beautiful and bamboozling place, an endlessly fascinating country that is often challenging and always surprising.</p>
<p>Stretched between the golden beaches of the Indian Ocean and the snow-capped peaks of the Himalayan mountains lies an incredible tapestry of natural and man-made wonders &ndash; astounding temples, mystical monasteries, frenetic cities, pristine national parks, lavish palaces, lost kingdoms, mesmerising markets and some of the world&rsquo;s most iconic monuments.</p>
<p>Visiting India is an assault on the senses. Sights, sounds, smells and sensations are all experienced at maximum intensity. On day one, it can feel intimidating, but by the end of the first week, the noise and chaos will seem like an ordinary part of life. The sensory stimulation becomes strangely addictive.</p>
<p>India is one of the world's great melting pots, where an incredible diversity of cultures, religions and ethnicities live in surprising harmony. Presided over by an extraordinary array of gods and deities, one-sixth of the planet's population can be found here, living in anything from high-rise apartments and inner city shantytowns, to simple huts in remote villages where life has hardly changed in centuries.</p>
<p>You could spend a lifetime exploring the relics left behind by ancient empires and the country's dramatic landscapes, which range from tiger-filled jungles to frozen Himalayan deserts.&nbsp;On the first trip, almost everyone finds time for the so-called Golden Triangle, zipping from the colonial capital, Delhi, to the Taj Mahal at Agra, then on to Jaipur, the colourful capital of Rajasthan.&nbsp;With more time to spare, you can discover 36 UNESCO-listed sights, from creaking mountain railways and ancient fortresses to mangrove forests and temples overflowing with multi-armed deities.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t expect to absorb all India has to offer in one visit; the country is best appreciated like a buffet table, with repeat visits to sample the next tantalising platter. And with India&rsquo;s legendary cuisine, rest assured that on every trip, you&rsquo;ll eat like a Maharaja.</p><p>India is a beautiful and bamboozling place, an endlessly fascinating country that is often challenging and always surprising.   Stretched between the golden beaches of the Indian Ocean and the snow-capped peaks of the Himalayan mountains lies an incredible tapestry of natural and man-made wonders &ndash; astounding temples, mystical monasteries, frenetic cities, pristine national parks, lavish palaces, lost kingdoms, mesmerising markets and some of the world&rsquo;s most iconic monuments.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
