<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Indonesia" ColCode="idn" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="id" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Indonesia has a tropical climate which is highly variable from area to area. The eastern monsoon brings the driest weather (June to September), while the western monsoon brings the main rains (December to March). Rainstorms occur all year. Higher regions are cooler. Temperatures average between 23&deg;C (73&deg;F) and 28&deg;C (82&deg;F) all year, but this tends to be humid heat, with humidity varying from 70% to 90%. Peak time for tourists to travel is in June, July and August, although prices will be higher; those travelling in the shoulder seasons of May and September could get lucky with both weather and prices.</p>
<p>Muddy roads can be a deterrent to travel in the wet season. Keep in mind that during local holidays public transport can be clogged, accommodation hard to find in holiday areas and businesses close.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bring lightweight clothing with rainwear; cottons and silks will be most appropriate. Warmer clothes are needed for cool evenings and upland areas, thicker cottons and woollen garments may work best. Smart clothes such as jackets are required for formal occasions, and it is regarded inappropriate to wear brief clothes anywhere other than the beach or at sports facilities. Women should observe the dress code in Muslim areas that requires shoulders and legs to be kept covered.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Indonesia has a good domestic flight network linking most of the larger towns to Jakarta. Domestic operators include Garuda Indonesia (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.garuda-indonesia.com/">www.garuda-indonesia.com</a>), AirAsia&nbsp;(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.airasia.com/">www.airasia.com</a>) and Lionair (<a href="http://www.lionair.co.id" target="_blank">www.lionair.co.id</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong><em> </em>Padang Bai and Benoa (Bali), Tanjung Priok (Jakarta), Belawan (Medan) and Sekupang (Batam).</p>
<p>PELNI (tel: +62 21 162; <a href="http://www.pelni.co.id" target="_blank">www.pelni.co.id</a>), the state-owned shipping company, has good standard passenger liners serving all the main ports across the archipelago. ASDP (Kapal Ferry Cepat. tel: +62 21 191, <a href="http://www.indonesiaferry.co.id">www.indonesiaferry.co.id</a>)<em> </em>operates fast boats on a small number of routes.</p>
<p>Foreign cruise liners also operate on an irregular basis. Luxury cruise ships offer trips to various destinations, including the eastern islands (leaving from Bali).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The train operator in Indonesia is PT Kereta Api (tel: +62 22 423 0031;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.kereta-api.co.id/" target="_blank">www.kereta-api.co.id</a>; the website doesn't have an English version, so use <a href="http://en.tiket.com">http://en.tiket.com</a> for information and to book tickets). There are three classes of travel, Eksecutif (Executive), Bisnis (Business) and Ekonomi (Economy), but first-class exists only on principal expresses. There is some air-conditioned accommodation. Children under three travel free in economy and business without taking a seat, and pay 10% of adult fare in executive class; children aged three to 10 pay half fare in economy and business and full rate in executive.</p>
<p>In Sumatra, trains run between Medan and Tanjong Balai and Medan and Rantu Prapet in the north, and Palembang and Panjang in the south, but are unreliable. An extensive rail network runs throughout Java. The modern, air-conditioned Argo Bromo Anggrek service, which is Eksecutif class only, with refreshments included, links Jakarta and Surabaya; it departs daily and nightly.</p>
<p>There are also other express services. Between Jakarta and Bandung there is a train every one to two hours, Eksecutif class (journey time - about 3 hours) and then thrice-daily trains on to Surabaya.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travelling around the Indonesian islands by car is variable, with much depending on which island you are on. Self-drive is possible, but be aware that the standards of driving and road conditions can be quite poor.</p>l<p>Around half of the road network is paved and there are good road communications within Java and, to a lesser extent, on Bali and Sumatra. The other islands have poor road networks.</p><p>Widely available in cities and towns. <em>Ojek</em> (motorcycle taxis) are available in cities and towns and they congregate at road junctions. The driver should provide a helmet and you must agree on the fare before starting the journey.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required. If you don&rsquo;t have this, it is possible to get a temporary tourist driving licence issued in Denpasar.</p><p>Speed limits are usually 30-40kph (19-25mph) on inner city streets, 60-70kph (37-43mph) on inner-city streets and 80-100kph (50-62mph) on motorways. Seatbelts must be worn.</p><p>Available from a number of international and local companies. It is also possible to hire cars with a driver but you're expected to pay for your chauffeur&rsquo;s food and accommodation.</p><p>Many visitors hire scooters and motorbikes but care should be taken to ensure you hire vehicles from a reputable dealer, have correct documentation and are aware of the risks - accidents are all too frequent. Helmets are compulsory.</p><p>Speed limits are usually 30-40kph (19-25mph) on inner city streets, 60-70kph (37-43mph) on inner-city streets and 80-100kph (50-62mph) on motorways. Seatbelts must be worn.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jakarta is the only city with an established conventional bus service of any size, and it has a comprehensive network. Elsewhere <em>bemos</em> (minibuses) are the main way to travel around. Rickshaws include the motorised <em>bajaj</em>, which seats two passengers, with the driver in front; and the <em>becak</em>, which is pedal-powered by a rider sitting behind two passengers. However, the latter are banned from Jakarta city. Fares should be negotiated in advance.</p>
<p>Motorcycles and bicycles can be hired; for motorcycles, an International Driving Permit is recommended and a helmet should be worn. <em>Bemos</em> and <em>opelets</em> are communal minibuses; fares should be negotiated in advance. Chauffeur-driven cars are widely available and advisable as the standard of driving is poor.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Indonesia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">yogyakarta</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.05</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">12.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Indonesia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">medan</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.25</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">30.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Indonesia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">denpasar</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">25.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Garuda Indonesia (<a href="http://www.garuda-indonesia.com/" target="_blank">www.garuda-indonesia.com</a>). There are no direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jakarta">Jakarta</a>. Airlines offering flights to Indonesia with one stopover include Emirates (<a href="http://www.emirates.com" target="_blank">www.emirates.com</a>), Etihad Airways (<a href="http://www.etihad.com" target="_blank">www.etihad.com</a>), Malaysia Airlines (<a href="http://www.malaysiaairlines.com" target="_blank">www.malaysiaairlines.com</a>), Qatar Airways (<a href="http://www.qatarairways.com" target="_blank">www.qatarairways.com</a>), Singapore Airlines (<a href="http://www.singaporeair.com" target="_blank">www.singaporeair.com</a>) and Thai Airways (<a href="http://www.thaiairways.com" target="_blank">www.thaiairways.com</a>). If travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, you also need to stop at another Asian city en route, such as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hong-kong">Hong Kong</a>, Narita or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/taipei">Taipei</a>.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/indonesia/jakarta-soekarno-hatta-international-airport">Jakarta Soekarno Hatta International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/indonesia/denpasar-ngurah-rai-airport">Denpasar Ngurah Rai Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jakarta">Jakarta</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 16 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 23 hours (including stopover).</p>
<p>To Denpasar, Bali: from London - 17 hours (including stopover); New York - 23 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ngurah Rai Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bali-airport.com<p>Denpasar Ngurah Rai International Airport is located roughly 14km (8.7 miles) south of Denpasar, close to the Kuta resort area.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+62 361 935 1011</p>]]><b>Jakarta Soekarno-Hatta International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.soekarnohatta-airport.co.id<p>Jakarta Soekarno-Hatta International Airport is located 20km (12 miles) northwest of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jakarta">Jakarta</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+62 21 550 5179.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports within Indonesia are Belawan (Medan), Dumai and Padang on Sumatra, with both Belawan and Dumai served by ferries from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malaysia">Malaysia</a>. It is also possible to travel by boat from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a> to Batam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no international trains in Indonesia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As Indonesia is made up of islands it is not possible to drive from mainland Asia and any journey must involve air or ferry travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Many hotel lobbies have public phones which take credit cards and phone cards. State-operated phone booths or offices (Telkom) and privately-owned companies (known as wartel, warpostel or warparpostel), which work on a pay-as-you-leave basis, can be found in towns and cities throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage may be limited to main towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafés in all major cities and tourist destinations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Media freedom increased considerably after the end of President Suharto's rule in 1998, during which the now-defunct Ministry of Information monitored and controlled domestic media and restricted foreign media. <em>Kompas</em> and <em>Pos Kota</em> are mass-circulation dailies, whilst English-language newspapers include <em>The Jakarta Post</em> and the weekly <em>Tempo</em> magazine. Televisi Republik Indonesia (TVRI) is a public broadcaster that operates two networks. Several provinces have their own stations. Other private stations operate such as Metro TV and Surya Citra Televisi Indonesia (SCTV). Radio Republik Indonesia (RRI) is a public broadcaster that operates six national networks, regional and local stations, and the external service, Voice of Indonesia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to western Europe, the USA and Australia takes about 10 days. An express service is available.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600, Sat 0800-1300 (hours may be longer in city centres).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Prambanan Temple Complex</p><![CDATA[<p>The Prambanan Temples form the largest temple complex on Java. Constructed around AD 900, the compound was deserted soon after it was completed, possibly due to the eruption of nearby Mount Merapi. It was restored in 1953 and now forms one of the world's great Hindu shrines, with the site dominated by the imposing figures of the three main temples: the Brahma Temple, the Vishnu Temple and the Shiva Temple. Also do not miss nearby Borobudur, probably the largest Buddhist sanctuary in the world, which contains more than 5km (3 miles) of relief carvings.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the spires of Prambanan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Close to Yogyakarta, the Prambanan Temples form the largest temple complex on Java, constructed around AD 900. The compound was deserted soon after it was completed, possibly due to the eruption of nearby Mount Merapi, but the temples have been impressively restored. The site is dominated by the imposing spires of the Brahma Temple, the Vishnu Temple and the Shiva Temple.</p>]]><p><b>Be bowled over by Borobudur</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Indonesia is studded with the ruins of ancient civilisations, but perhaps the grandest of all is might Borobudur, a 9th-century Buddhist temple rising above the plains of central Java. Topped by hundreds of perforated stupas, the temple is a representation of the Buddhist universe, and its walls are covered in intricately carved bas-reliefs.</p>]]><p><b>Chill on the Gili Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Just off the northwestern tip of Lombok, these three irresistible islands boast deep-water coral reefs, beachfront bungalows, miles of white sand and bucketfuls of serenity. It's easy to find a quiet spot to unwind, but if you need more action, all-night dance parties are close by on Trawangan.</p>]]><p><b>Climb a volcano</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dozens of volcanoes soar above the landscape of Indonesia, and many can be climbed on jungle treks. Mount Bromo on Java is the most visited of Indonesia's volcanoes, but other popular volcano experiences include the Kawah Ijen crater lake, boat trips to Krakatoa, and hikes on Gunung Agung in Bali, Gunung Rinjani on Lombok island, and Keli Mutu on Nusa Tenggara Barat.</p>]]><p><b>Connect with Muslim Indonesia at the Istiqlal Mosque</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The modern Istiqlal Mosque in Jakarta is one of the largest in the world, with room to accommodate up to 120,000 of the faithful. It's the national mosque for the entire archipelago, and a monumental piece of modern architecture. Non-Muslim visitors are welcome and guides will show you round the complex.</p>]]><p><b>Dive the reefs of Pulau Bunaken</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Indonesia's coastline is said to contain 15% of the world's coral reefs, providing spectacular opportunities for scuba diving and snorkelling. Bunaken National Park and Lembeh Strait, both in North Sulawesi, are magnificent; a mind boggling 300 types of coral and 3,000 species of fish await beneath crystal-clear waters.</p>]]><p><b>Meet the old man of the forest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Indonesian Borneo and Sumatra are two of the last refuges of the endangered orang-utan, whose name literally means 'man of the forest'. You can get up close to these fascinating creatures at rehabilitation centres on Sumatra and Kalimantan that rescue orphaned, injured and captive orang-utans and return them to their natural habitat.</p>]]><p><b>Meet the tribal people of Torajaland</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Torajaland, known as the 'Land of the Heavenly Kings', on Sulawesi, is one of the best places to encounter Indonesia's fascinating tribal culture. Toraja villagers live in dramatic buffalo horn-shaped wooden stilt houses and still practice the custom of burying their dead in vertical cliffside tombs, with rituals that include feasts for the mummified remains.</p>]]><p><b>Navigate the Mahakam River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The great Mahakam River in Kalimantan, Borneo, is feed by a network of jungle rivers running from the mountainous interior to the coast. Starting from the port city of Samarinda, tours follow the river deep into the jungle, where tribal communities live in villages of traditional longhouses and have largely preserved their traditions.</p>]]><p><b>Paddle through Ujong Kulon National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The elusive and highly endangered Javan rhino still survives in the remote swamps of isolated Ujong Kulon National Park at the extreme southwestern tip of Java. The best way to explore is by dugout canoe, which is an incredibly atmospheric way to see the jungle, and hopefully creep up on a rare rhino.</p>]]><p><b>Roam the rainforest in Sulawesi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gorgeous Sulawesi is a land of high mountains, misty valleys, hidden lakes, tribal villages and fascinating national parks both above and below the water. On land, top sights include Bantimurung Nature Reserve, home to thousands of exotic butterflies, and the geysers and hot springs at Lahendong and Leilem. Offshore, diving on Sulawesi's coral reefs is the main attraction.</p>]]><p><b>Search for the Komodo dragon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Komodo and the Rinca islands are home to a living legend – the Komodo dragon, the world's largest lizard and a close relative of the dinosaurs. Komodo Dragons can grow up to 3m (10ft) in length and weigh up to 70kg, and you can see them close up at Komodo National Park. But don't get too close – humans have been injured and worse by dragons in the past.</p>]]><p><b>See Indonesia’s Hindu side on beautiful Bali</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Despite decades of tourist development, Bali remains a vision of tropical beauty. Take your pick from stunning beaches, jungle-covered volcanoes, beach bars and surf spots in Kuta or a kaleidoscope of Hindu temples harking back to the earliest civilisations on the Indonesia archipelago. The Balinese people are famously warm and friendly, perhaps the best part of a visit here.</p>]]><p><b>See a traditional puppet show</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Puppetry is a rich tradition in Indonesia, and marionette shows are still a vibrant part of the culture. You can see shows throughout Java, where intricately carved <em>wayang golak </em>and <em>wayang kulit </em>puppets act out stories based on well-known legends from Indonesia history; performances can sometimes last all night.</p>]]><p><b>See how sultans live their lives in Yogyakarta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Sultan's Palace in Yogyakarta is a masterpiece of understated Javanese architecture, and still home to the sultan and his family. This Javan city is famous for its traditional architecture, and the <em>kraton </em>(palace) is just one example. Just outside the city is the imposing Candi Prambanan, a 9th-century Hindu palace crowned by 47m (154ft) towers.</p>]]><p><b>Seek tribal encounters in Samosir</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An inhabited island in the middle of Lake Toba, Samosir is the surviving crater of a vanished volcano, 900m (3,000ft) above sea level in Sumatra. The island is home to the Batak people, an ancient tribe who preserve many of their ancient traditions. The island is dotted with traditional buildings and visitors explore from the gateway town of Tuktuk.</p>]]><p><b>Surf Indonesia’s big breaks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spectacular waves break all around the islands of Indonesia, providing a watery playground for surfers. The best surf spots are in Bali, Flores, Java, Lombok, Sumatra, Sumba and Sumbawa, but the best-known surfing beaches, such as Ulu Watu on Bali, can get very crowded. For experienced surfers, organised trips to isolated breaks are widely available.</p>]]><p><b>Take a jungle trek</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A trek through the Indonesian rainforest is an essential Indonesian experience, and Irian Jaya, Kalimantan and Sumatra offer some of the most remote and untouched rainforest on earth. Top trails include trips to Bukit Barisan National Park, a remote and beautiful peninsula in Sumatra, and the Muller Mountain in Kalimantan.</p>]]><p><b>Tour the temples of Pura Besakih</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Do not miss Bali's Pura Besakih, a temple complex set high on the volcanic slopes of Gunung Agung. Founding in the 10th century, this massive complex comprises of more than 30 temples, and is the setting for great ceremonial splendour on festival days.</p>]]><p><b>Watch the waves break over Tanah Lot</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel to the Sea Temple of Tanah Lot on the west coast of Bali (a short drive from Kediri), for one of the most photogenic sights in Indonesia. Jutting from a rock formation into the sea, the temple is reputedly guarded from evil intruders and demons by poisonous sea snakes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$878.2billion (2013).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil, gas, electrical appliances, textiles and rubber.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, chemicals, fuel and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Japan, Singapore, USA, China and Korea (Rep).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following the Asian economic crisis in 1997, the economy stabilised again by 1999 and, since 2000, has resumed steady annual growth, which was at 5.9% in 2008. And in October 2006, Jakarta paid off its outstanding IMF debt, incurred during the crisis, four years ahead of schedule. From 2010 to 2012, the economy grew by 6%, whilst unemployment had decreased slightly since 2008 to 6.1% in 2012.   </p>
<p>Oil and natural gas are the most important raw materials produced by Indonesia. Tourism has become a major industry and vital source of foreign exchange, although it suffered in the wake of the Bali bomb attacks, as well as the tsunami. Poverty and lack of infrastructure are still major challenges which remain to be solved by the government. The cutting of state fuel subsidies in May 2008 led to a 29% rise in the price of fuel, but Indonesia continues to have some of the cheapest fuel prices in the world, despite a push to increase prices in 2013. As tourism is one of Indonesia&rsquo;s biggest industries and there are hotels and centres to cater for conferences in all the major towns across the islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business dealings should be conducted through an agent and tend to be slow. Punctuality is expected but be aware that your host may be running late and this is quite common. Business cards are widely used and it is polite to take great interest in any card that is received. It is conventional to greet by shaking hands and giving a slight bow with the head on meeting. The same bow of the head should be made when taking your leave. Literature should be in English, but prices should be quoted in US Dollars as well as Pounds Sterling.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700 or 0800-1600.  <strong>Government office hours:</strong> Mon-Fri 0800-1600 and Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Jakarta Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 380 8091
					Website:
					Address: ,Jalal Majapahit 18-20,Jakarta 10160,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Whilst Indonesia cooking has some similarity to the cuisines of nearby Thailand and Malaysia, its history as a key stop on the spice route means the diet has been highly influenced by the trading empires of Spain, the Netherlands, Portugal and China.</p><p>The staple diet for most Indonesians is <em>nasi </em>(rice), but this is swapped on some islands with other starchy foods such as noodles, corn, sago, cassava and sweet potatoes. Coconut milk is used extensively in sauces and soups.</p><p>Indonesians like their food highly spiced, with an emphasis on ingredients such as lime leaves, lemongrass, tamarind, cloves, cinnamon and chilli. Be wary of the tiny and fiery hot red and green peppers included in salads and vegetable dishes. Seafood is a regular feature on menus and many dishes are flavoured with shrimp paste, known as <em>terasi </em>or <em>belacan</em>.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Rijsttafel:</strong> A Dutch-invented smorgasbord of 12 various meat, fish, vegetable and curry dishes.<br />
<strong>Nasigoreng: </strong>Considered the national dish it consists of fried rice, flavoured with spices and usually eaten with accompanying vegetables.<br />
<strong>Ayam goreng:</strong> Fried chicken, a national staple.<br />
<strong>Soto</strong>: Traditional soupy broth with rice cakes and noodles, often with chicken or beef.<br />
<strong>Sambal</strong>: A fiery chilli sauce condiment served with every dish.<br />
<strong>Bakso</strong>: Indonesian meatballs usually made from chicken or beef.<br />
<strong>Sate</strong>: Skewers of beef, fish, pork, chicken or lamb, cooked on hot coals and dipped in peanut sauce.<br />
<strong>Rendang:</strong> A speciality of Sumatra; a densely spiced coconut curry with lime leaves and buffalo meat.<br />
<strong>Gado-gado</strong>: A Javan salad of raw and cooked vegetables with peanut and coconut milk sauce.<br />
<strong>Babi guling</strong>: A roast suckling pig, a delicacy from Bali.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is normal unless service charge is already included in a restaurant bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21 (from December 2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[Jakarta has the biggest nightlife scene, with nightclubs featuring international singers and bands. There are also plenty of cinemas, and some English-language and subtitled films are shown. The beach town of Kuta on Bali is also a good spot for nightlife, albeit of the backpacker variety.<br />
<br />
Dancing is considered an art, encouraged and practised from very early childhood, and dances are based on ancient legends and stories from religious epics. Dances include the <em>Legong</em>, a slow, graceful dance of divine nymphs; the <em>Baris</em>, a fast moving, noisy demonstration of male, warlike behaviour; and the <em>Jauk</em>, a riveting solo offering by a masked and richly costumed demon. Many consider the most dramatic of all to be the famous <em>Cecak </em>(Monkey Dance) which calls for 100 or more very agile participants. Larger hotels, particularly in Bali, put on dance shows accompanied by the uniquely Indonesian Gamelan Orchestras. <br />
<br />
Throughout the year, many local moonlight festivals occur; tourists should check locally. Indonesian puppets are world famous and shows for visitors are staged in various locations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re the type of person to always come back with a souvenir, Indonesia will be heaven. In terms of souvenirs and trinkets, the &nbsp;markets here can&rsquo;t be beaten. Some of the best buys are batik cloth (a kind of patterned fabric), ikat fabrics (textile made using a sort of tie-dye technique), woodcarvings and sculpture, silverwork, woven baskets and hats, bamboo articles, <em>krises</em> (small daggers), paintings and woven cloth. If shopping at stalls and small shops within the <em>pasar </em>(market), bartering might be necessary, but keep it light-hearted and playful if you can.</p>
<p>If you prefer to your shopping within the slightly more cloistered hallways of an air-conditioned mall, the main urban centres of Jakarta are your best bet. Tourists can find an array of international brands at places like Plaza Indonesia, arts and handicrafts at stores within Grand Indonesia Shopping  Town, and luxury brands are easily accessible, catering for the emergent middle-class and expatriate population. Malls are also a good place to pick up food, whether in the form of a rejuvenating meal at one of the many food carts, or smaller souvenirs to take away.</p><p>Mon-Sun 0900-2100; some shops have shorter hours on Sundays. Most local markets open either very early in the morning or at dusk. In the smaller towns, shops may close between 1300 and 1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels, from deluxe to budget, can be found in most towns across the country, while international hotels are generally found in major towns and tourist areas. Most choice can be found in Jakarta and on Bali, with the &nbsp;international hotel scene varying widely, from corporate behemoths to the laid back luxury on offer at Nihiwatu on Sumba.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s something to suit every budget in Indonesia, with even high-end hotels seeming comparatively bargainous in terms of value for money. Whilst high hotel taxes are charged (10% service, plus 11% government tax), depending on the hotel, these will simply be rolled up into the final bill. Resort hotels on Bali vary from international class, luxury hotels to beach cottages. Most hotels include pools and will supply leisure equipment for an additional fee. Wi-Fi is readily available, even in rural areas, although the connection may be slow. <br />
<strong><br />
<strong>Grading:</strong></strong> All hotels are graded according to facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cheap guesthouses with no air conditioning and shared basic Indonesian-style bathrooms are popular with visitors for short stays. There are also beach and lakeside chalets. On Sumatra it is possible to stay in a reproduction of a traditional <em>batak</em> house with its distinctive high, pointed roof.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels, from deluxe to budget, can be found in most towns across the country, while international hotels are generally found in major towns and tourist areas. Most choice can be found in Jakarta and on Bali, with the &nbsp;international hotel scene varying widely, from corporate behemoths to the laid back luxury on offer at Nihiwatu on Sumba.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s something to suit every budget in Indonesia, with even high-end hotels seeming comparatively bargainous in terms of value for money. Whilst high hotel taxes are charged (10% service, plus 11% government tax), depending on the hotel, these will simply be rolled up into the final bill. Resort hotels on Bali vary from international class, luxury hotels to beach cottages. Most hotels include pools and will supply leisure equipment for an additional fee. Wi-Fi is readily available, even in rural areas, although the connection may be slow. <br />
<strong><br />
<strong>Grading:</strong></strong> All hotels are graded according to facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels, from deluxe to budget, can be found in most towns across the country, while international hotels are generally found in major towns and tourist areas. Most choice can be found in Jakarta and on Bali, with the &nbsp;international hotel scene varying widely, from corporate behemoths to the laid back luxury on offer at Nihiwatu on Sumba.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s something to suit every budget in Indonesia, with even high-end hotels seeming comparatively bargainous in terms of value for money. Whilst high hotel taxes are charged (10% service, plus 11% government tax), depending on the hotel, these will simply be rolled up into the final bill. Resort hotels on Bali vary from international class, luxury hotels to beach cottages. Most hotels include pools and will supply leisure equipment for an additional fee. Wi-Fi is readily available, even in rural areas, although the connection may be slow. <br />
<strong><br />
<strong>Grading:</strong></strong> All hotels are graded according to facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No***]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A and B<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A and B"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Zika virus is a risk in Indonesia. Because Zika infection in a pregnant woman can cause serious birth defects, women who are pregnant should not travel to Indonesia. All travelers should strictly follow steps to prevent mosquito bites and sexual exposure to Zika virus during and after the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health insurance to include emergency repatriation cover is strongly advised. Adequate routine medical care is available in all major cities, but emergency services are generally inadequate outside major cities. The best public hospitals are found in Jakarta, where the ratio of medical staff to general population is much higher and clinics catering specifically to foreigners can be found. Doctors and hospitals often expect immediate cash payments before any treatment is given, so it is advised that you have travel insurance before travelling to Indonesia. The number for medical emergencies is 119; for ambulance services call 118. Although medical costs are relatively cheap, drugs can be expensive.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Drinking bottled water is advised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations for tuberculosis, meningitis and Japanese B encephalitis are sometimes recommended. There is a real risk of heatstroke; visitors to Indonesia should avoid the midday sun, remember to drink lots of water and apply sun cream. Travellers should also take care to acclimatise slowly when travelling to high-altitude areas, to avoid altitude sickness.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>(a) Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.<br /><br />(b) Buddhist festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							17 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Indonesia by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 25 cigars or 100g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; Gifts up to a value of US$250 per person or US$1,000 per family.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted goods include narcotics, firearms and ammunition, air guns, sharp weapons, explosives, pornography, animals, fish, plants, films and video recordings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is forbidden to take tortoise shells, crocodile skins or ivory out of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rupiah (IDR; symbol Rp). Notes are in denominations of Rp100,000, 50,000, 20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 2,000 and 1,000. Coins are in denominations of Rp1,000, 500, 200, 100 and 50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although there should be no difficulty exchanging major currencies in the main tourist centres, problems may occur elsewhere. Watch out for on the street money changers who may try to trick visitors out of their cash. The easiest currency to exchange is the US Dollar. Do not accept notes with a lot of visible wear and tear as these may not be accepted by merchants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard, Visa, Diners Club and Eurocard are widely accepted in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jakarta">Jakarta</a> and the main tourist areas. In more remote areas, it is best to carry cash in small denominations. ATMs are available in towns and at airports.</p><p>ATMs are available in cities and larger towns but be aware that many have a maximum withdrawal limit which can be as high as Rp3,000,000 or as low as Rp400,000. This can be overcome by putting your card again but be careful as you may be hit with a bank fee each time.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's not recommended to take traveller's cheques to Indonesia as they are becoming more and more difficult to exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1400; Fri 0800-1200; Sat 0800-1100 (some branches).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Indonesia, a passport valid for at least six months from the date of entry is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: US$35.</p>
<p>Advance visas: tourist/business visa: &pound;40; multiple-entry business visa: &pound;80.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: 30 days; tourist/business visa: 60 days; multiple-entry business visa: one year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Either on arrival at a designated port of entry or in advance at the consulate (or consular section of embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For visits of up to one year, you must apply to the nearest Indonesian Embassy for a temporary stay permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you apply in advance, visa processing usually three to five days from receipt, but it can take up to two months for nationals whose applications need to be referred to the Immigration Office in Indonesia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend a 30-day visa on arrival for a further 30 days at a cost of US$35.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-2.955980]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[119.521017]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,922,570 million sq km (742,308 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>260,581,100 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>133.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jakarta.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Indonesia lies between the mainland of South East Asia and Australia in the Indian and Pacific oceans. It is the world's largest archipelago state. Indonesia is made up of five main islands - Sumatra, Java, Sulawesi, Kalimantan (part of the island of Borneo) and Irian Jaya (the western half of New Guinea) - and 30 smaller archipelagos.</p>
<p>In total, the Indonesian archipelago consists of about 17,508 islands; 6,000 of these are inhabited and stretch over 4,828km (3,000 miles), most lying in a volcanic belt with more than 300 volcanoes, the great majority of which are extinct. The landscape varies from island to island, ranging from high mountains and plateaux to coastal lowlands and alluvial belts.</p>
<p>The high incidence of volcanoes in Indonesia is due to its location along a stretch of the Pacific Ring of Fire. The collision of various tectonic plates mean that around 90% of the world&rsquo;s earthquakes occur within this area, with Indonesia suffering from frequent earthquakes and volcano eruptions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a Muslim majority of approximately 90%, with Christian, Hindu (mainly in Bali) and Buddhist minorities. Freedom of religion is enshrined in the constitution.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Social courtesies are often fairly formal. Using a few words of the local language will be appreciated. When drink or food is served, it should not be touched until the host invites the guest to do so. Never pass or accept anything with the left hand, as this is seen as unclean. Public displays of affection between men and women are frowned upon, and kissing in public will attract a great deal of unwanted attention. </p>
<p>Touching a stranger of the same sex while in conversation is very common. Smiling is a cultural tradition and Indonesians smile frequently, even in an uncomfortable or difficult situation. Visitors should avoid losing their temper as saving face is very important in Indonesian culture; tourists should avoid putting others in a situation where they may feel embarrassed or ashamed. Both men and women should take care to dress in an appropriate way for their surroundings &ndash; whilst a more casual attitude may be fine in Bali, Aceh is rather more conservative and you may be expected to cover up a little more.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz but 127 volts is still used in some areas. Plugs used are European-style with two circular metal pins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Joko Widodo since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Joko Widodo since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The discovery of the remains of &lsquo;Java Man&rsquo; suggest that Indonesia was inhabited by early humans as early as 1.5 million years ago, but little evidence remains of early tribal civilisations. In the 7th century, Indonesia fell under the influence of the Srivijaya kingdom, bringing Hinduism and Buddhism to the islands for the first time.</p>
<p>Islam arrived in the 13th century, and Java and Sumatra became powerful sultanates, while other islands continued to follow Hindu, Buddhist and Animist traditions. The Portuguese were the first Europeans to settle in Indonesia in 1512, establishing trade posts for valuable spices such as nutmeg and cloves.</p>
<p>A century later, under the auspices of the Dutch government, the Dutch East India company moved in, establishing the city of Batavia (now <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jakarta">Jakarta</a>), taking over major trade routes, and eventually establishing colonial rule over the archipelago.</p>
<p>The start of the 20th century saw the beginnings of an Indonesian independence movement known as Sarekat Islam, which gained huge popularity, despite suppression from the Dutch colonial regime. The Japanese invasion in WWII lead to the withdrawal of the Dutch, but some four million Indonesians died as a result of occupation.</p>
<p>The subsequent surrender of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a> at the end of the war lead the then-president Sukarno to pronounce Indonesia&rsquo;s independence on 17 August 1945, but democracy was quickly replaced by an increasingly authoritarian regime with power residing ultimately with the president and a series of appointed councils. To unify this disjointed collection of kingdoms and sultanates, the Sukarno regime launched a massive propaganda campaign based on concepts of national heroes and national identity.</p>
<p>In 1965, General Suharto seized control in a military coup and brutally suppressed opposition in a reign lasting until 1998. The independent islands of West Irian (part of New Guinea) and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/east-timor">East Timor</a> were annexed and landless peasants from Muslim majority islands were strategically settled on other islands.</p>
<p>Eventually opposition to Suharto&rsquo;s rule reached a critical level during the East Asian Financial Crisis. Suharto was forced to step down in 1998 after elections were won convincingly by Megawati Sukarnoputri, daughter of former president Sukarno. Since then, the islands have seen relative stability, despite challenges ranging from rampaging forest fires, terrorist attacks, the 2004 tsunami and East Timor gaining independence in 2002.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know? </strong><br />
&bull;	There are more than 150 volcanoes in Indonesia, and 127 of them are still active. <br />
&bull;	Indonesia is the most populous Muslim nation in the world. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Indonesia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+62 21 2356 5200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinindonesia.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+62 21 2356 5200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0730-1600; Fri: 0730-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Jl Patra Kuningan Raya Blok L5-6<br/>Jakarta<br/>12950<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Indonesia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 775 5200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofindonesia.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 775 5200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1700. Consulate: Mon-Thu 0900-0100, Fri 0900-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2020 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Indonesia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7499 7661. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.indonesianembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7499 7661. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700 (general and tourist enquiries); Mon-Fri 0930-1230, 1430-1600 (visa applications) and Mon-Fri 0930-1200, 1430-1600 (visa collections).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>38 Grosvenor Square<br/>London<br/>W1K 2HW<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Draped languidly across the equator, Indonesia is a series of emerald jewels scattered across a broad expanse of tropical sea. This is one of the world&rsquo;s great adventures in waiting &ndash; hidden away in dense jungles on secret islands are tribes almost untouched by the outside world and animals hardly known to science.</p>
<p>The third most populous nation on earth has an incredible legacy of peoples, cultures and geography just waiting to be explored. The archipelago boasts more than 18,000 islands, from tiny islets not much bigger than a palm tree to the mighty expanse of Borneo, shared with the Malaysian provinces of Sabah and Sarawak and the kingdom of Brunei.</p>
<p>Many come specifically to discover their own island paradise, complete with white-sand beaches, swaying palms and emerald waters. Offshore are some of the world&rsquo;s best dive sites, swarming with huge sunfish, giant rays, sharks, porpoises, turtles and a blindingly colourful array of tropical fish.</p>
<p>For others, the attraction is cultural. A fascinating range of civilisations have grown up on these tropical islands, from animist tribes in remote jungle villages to the elaborate Hindu kingdoms of Bali and Java. In Indonesia, timeless temples jostle for space with golden-domed mosques and beach resorts crowded with sun-seekers and surfers. The surf resort of Kuta has become one of the world&rsquo;s favourite tropical escapes, and the beach party raves through till dawn every day of the week.</p>
<p>For some, Kuta is the very vision of Asia. For others, the true escapes lie elsewhere, on the volcanic islands that drift eastwards towards Australia. Here are towering volcanoes to be climbed, national parks to be explored and tropical rainforests to be trekked. You might even get lucky and meet an orang-utan on Sumatra or the world&rsquo;s largest living reptile on the island of Komodo, home to the eponymous Komodo dragon.</p>
<p>Best of all, flights and ferries link all of the islands, so you can island-hop right across the archipelago, stopping only when you find your own perfect piece of Southeast Asia.</p><p>Draped languidly across the equator, Indonesia is a series of emerald jewels scattered across a broad expanse of tropical sea. This is one of the world&rsquo;s great adventures in waiting &ndash; hidden away in dense jungles on secret islands are tribes almost untouched by the outside world and animals hardly known to science.</p>
<p>The third most populous nation on earth has an incredible legacy of peoples, cultures and geography just waiting to be explored. The archipelago boasts more than 18,000 islands, from tiny islets not much bigger than a palm tree to the mighty expanse of Borneo, shared with the Malaysian provinces of Sabah and Sarawak and the kingdom of Brunei.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
