<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Iran" ColCode="irn" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ir" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Iran]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The size of Iran means that can temperatures can vary hugely, depending on which corner of the country you find yourself in. Days can be incredibly hot between May and October, particularly in the desert regions and along the Gulf Coast, while the mountain ranges of the north become freezing over winter. <br />
<br />
Nights can be especially cold. In general terms, major cities like Tehran, Esfahan and Tabriz have seasons broadly equivalent to those in Mediterranean Europe. Iran has a relatively low rainfall, but is prone to earthquakes. Those travellers hoping to ski will find most action between November and March, while it&rsquo;s advisable for all visitors to look into timings of festivals like Ramadan before booking a trip. <br />
<br />
In Tehran, lightweight clothing is worn from April to October while mediumweights are advised from November to March. Be reminded, however, that dress should always err on the side of conservatism, particularly for women &ndash; the wearing of headscarves is obligatory in public.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical attire is worn from April to October. Mediumweights are advised from November to March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iran Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.iranair.com/">www.iranair.com</a>) runs services to Abdan, Ahwaz, Esfahan, Kish, Mashhad, Shiraz, Tabriz, Tehran and Zahedan and other major cities. Aseman Air<em> </em>(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.iaa.ir/">www.iaa.ir</a>) also runs services to the major cities. The vast size of Iran often makes internal flights the most practical method of transport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>RAJA Trains (tel: 1539, in Iran only; <a href="http://www.raja.ir/default.aspx?Culture=en-US&amp;page=home" target="_blank">www.raja.ir</a>) runs a comprehensive internal rail network. Major intercity trains operate on five main regional routes: Azarbaijan route (Tehran - Jolfa); Golestan route (Tehran - Gorgan); Hormozgan route (Tehran - Bandar-e-Abbas); Khorasan route (Tehran - Mashhad); and Khozetan route (Tehran - Khorramshahr). There are many areas in the mountains and the desert which can only be reached by rail. There are some air-conditioned trains, and sleeping and dining cars on many trains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>The road network is extensive, but the quality is unreliable.&nbsp;The two main roads, the AH1 and AH2, link the Iraqi and Pakistani borders and the Afghan and Turkish borders.</p><p>Available in all cities. The urban taxis (orange or blue) carry several passengers at a time and are much cheaper than the private taxis which only carry one person. Unofficial taxis should be avoided; use only legitimate taxis or those ordered through legitimate agencies. Group taxis for up to 10 people are available for intercity travel. Prices are negotiated beforehand and tipping is not necessary.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is recommended. Personal insurance is required. All motorists entering Iran must possess a Carnet de Passage and an International Certificate of Vehicle ownership.</p><p>Available in most cities and from airports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tehran has an extensive bus network and a modern metro system.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Iran (Islamic Republic Of)</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">mashhad</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">14.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">15.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Iran (Islamic Republic Of)</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kerman</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">20.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">18.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Iran (Islamic Republic Of)</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">esfahan</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Iran (Islamic Republic Of)</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">b_abbas</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.55</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">28.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Iran (Islamic Republic Of)</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ahvaz</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">17.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">19.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Iran Air<em>&nbsp;</em>(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.iranair.com">www.iranair.com</a>). If travelling from the UK, you can fly to Tehran nonstop with British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) or Lufthansa (<a href="http://www.lufthansa.com" target="_blank">www.lufthansa.com</a>) via Frankfurt or Vienna, or Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>) via Istanbul.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tehran-imam-khomeini-international-airport">Tehran Imam Khomeini International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 6 hours (nonstop) or 8 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 17 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Airways will cease it's service to Tehran on 22 September 2018. Its final return flight will be on the following day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Airways will cease it's service to Tehran on 22 September 2018. Its final return flight will be on the following day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Tehran Imam Khomeini International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://ikia.airport.ir<p>Tehran Imam Khomeini International Airport is located 30km (19 miles) southwest of the city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+98 21 5100 6015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main port was Khorramshahr until its destruction during the war with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iraq">Iraq</a>. Following reconstruction, the port was reopened to ship traffic in 1992. Imam Khomeini<strong>&nbsp;</strong>is located in the northwestern edge of the Persian Gulf and near Iraq. The ports of Abbas and Bushehr are to be found in the Persian Gulf and Nowshahr and Bandar-a Anzali on the Caspian Sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>RAJA Passenger Trains (<a href="http://www.raja.ir" target="_blank">www.raja.ir</a>) operates passenger services from Tehran to Ankara in conjunction with Turkish Railways.&nbsp;In addition, Golden Eagle Luxury Trains (<a href="http://www.goldeneagleluxurytrains.com" target="_blank">www.goldeneagleluxurytrains.com</a>) operate bi-annual luxury train tours between Moscow and Tehran.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For details of political conditions governing access, contact the embassy.&nbsp;If you plan on driving your own car over the border into Iran, you must obtain a Carnet de Passage by contacting the embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Telephone booths are yellow.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone operators but visitors are advised to check with their service provider before travelling. Coverage is limited to urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet caf&eacute;s in Tehran and all other major cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The struggle for influence and power in Iran is played out in the media. What was once a relatively free press is frequently the subject of censorship. Many pro-reform publications have been closed and reformist writers and editors jailed. The conservative judiciary has also campaigned against the liberal media. Television is the leading medium for news, although broadcasters are more restricted than the press in print and online. In fact, the 1979 Iranian Constitution instituted a law that said all broadcasting must be government-operated, and in 1994 the state banned the use of satellite television. Conservative daily papers include Kayhan and Resalat. Etemaad, which had an anti-Ahmadinejad stance, was closed in 2010. The main English-language papers are Iran News, Iran Daily and Tehran Times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe can take at least two weeks. There are 10 main post offices in Tehran. Post boxes are yellow. Stamps can be bought at some cigarette kiosks.</p><p>Generally Sat-Thurs 0730-1500, but some main post offices stay open until 2100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the majesty of Golestan Palace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Arguably Tehran's key sight, Golestan was the royal home of the Qajar dynasty. The palace complex within the old city walls dates back to the Safavid dynasty, right at the beginning of Islamic Persia, but it took on its current shape largely in the 19th century with a blend of traditional Islamic architecture and Western influences.</p>]]><p><b>Bask in the glittering expanse of Imam Square</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Esfahan's breath-taking centrepiece is one of the largest public squares in the world, fringed by a glittering array of blue-mosaic mosques and palaces. Wander the gardens, gawp at the architecture and take time to absorb the atmosphere of this UNESCO-listed marvel.</p>]]><p><b>Bling-watch at the National Jewels Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From ancient Persia to the 19th-century Qajar dynasty, this country has been subject to many extravagant reigns. Tehran's National Jewels Museum showcases some of the most opulent regalia you're likely to encounter anywhere in the world, including an ornamental world globe made from more than 50,000 different precious stones.</p>]]><p><b>Cross the bridges of Esfahan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The bridges that cross Esfahan's Zayandeh River wouldn't look out of place in a book of fairytales, with many of them dating back to the golden era of the 1600s. The 33-arched Si-o-Seh Bridge is unmissable, while the Khaju Bridge, which is split over two levels, is similarly majestic.</p>]]><p><b>Follow the old trade route to India via Kerman</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Initially founded as a military outpost and subsequently established as a key trading post for those passing to and from India, Kerman has some interesting museums, a number of imposing mosques and – predictably – a gloriously hugger-mugger bazaar.</p>]]><p><b>Go rug shopping</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It hardly needs to be said, but there is literally no better place in the world to go shopping for Persian rugs, and throughout the city bazaars you'll find no shortage of different vendors. It's best to throw yourself into the full experience – take tea, choose a favourite and barter with a smile.</p>]]><p><b>Go undercover at the US Den of Espionage</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The name may make you want to laugh and cry at the same time, but this unusual museum is important for being the site of the former US Embassy in Tehran, where diplomats were once held hostage for over a year as depicted in the hit 2012 film <em>Argo. </em>Today the complex is perhaps best known for the sobering anti-Western murals daubed on its walls.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the ski slopes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You may never have heard of skiing in Iran, but it's increasingly a big deal here. There are four downhill areas near Tehran alone, and costs are generally far lower than in Europe. The season in the Alborz Mountains lasts roughly from November until late March.</p>]]><p><b>Imbibe a little shisha culture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hubbly-bubbly, shisha, hookah, narghile: call it what you like, the omnipresent water-pipes still form an important part of local culture. It might not be overly healthy, but ordering a pipe and watching the world go by is a quintessential Iranian experience.</p>]]><p><b>Meet the troglodytes of Meymand</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Meymand is a troglodyte settlement carved into a range of hills near the south coast. It's estimated that people have inhabited the area for more than 3,000 years, and to this day, residents still live in natural and manmade caves.</p>]]><p><b>Sample the urban charms of Tabriz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Step back in time to 15th-century Persia by visiting Tabriz with its covered Qaisariyeh Bazaar and striking Kabud (Blue) Mosque, which was first built in 1465 before being destroyed by an earthquake &ndash; it has since been faithfully restored. One of Iran's largest cities, it is amongst the country's most important industrial centres.</p>]]><p><b>Scuba dive off tropical islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get up close to virgin coral and colourful marine life in the waters off Qeshm Island in the south. Nearby Kish Island is another good option for scuba-diving enthusiasts – the diving school offers a range of PADI courses.</p>]]><p><b>See an Iranian football match</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The legendary Tehran derby between Esteghlal and Persepolis is the most fiercely contested football match in the Middle East. It's a day when the entire country splits its allegiance between red and blue. Pick a side and then join more than 90,000 Iranians for a day of singing, sporting prowess and emotion.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out a desert oasis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the miniscule oasis village of Garmeh, surrounded by date palms and centred around a small spring. Don't expect any fancy hotels – this is all about welcoming locals and desert-village life, and as a chance to experience the profound quiet of the desert, it's second to none.</p>]]><p><b>Take tea Iranian-style</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Chances are high that as you make your way around the country, you'll be invited to locals' homes for tea on a fairly regular basis – Iranians are a very hospitable bunch. Forget any natural reserve and say yes, as it may well be the most rewarding thing you do in Iran.</p>]]><p><b>Venture into the past in Yazd</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the country's oldest cities through which Marco Polo is believed to have travelled, Yazd is still characterised by winding lanes, wind towers, earth-sculpted buildings and an evocative atmosphere of ages past.  Don't miss the princely Amir Chakhmaq Complex.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the City of Roses, Shiraz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The City of Roses, as Shiraz is known, is synonymous with poetry, flowers and – somewhat ironically, given the nationwide alcohol ban – wine. It's long been one of the Islamic world's most celebrated cities, and there's still plenty to see, including historic mosques, pretty vineyards and exquisite public gardens.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the unique Jameh Mosque</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Another of Esfahan's exquisite attractions, the Jameh Mosque (not to be confused with the mosque of the same name in just about every city in the country) is a masterpiece of Islamic design. A UNESCO World Heritage Site, it was started in the 9th century and renewed continually over the centuries, taking a little bit from each phase of mosque design.</p>]]><p><b>Wander the grand town of Kashan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An oasis city with a laid-back vibe, Kashan experienced lavish 19th-century building works during the illustrious Qajar era, and much of the grandeur still remains. The covered bazaar is atmospheric, and full of locally produced pottery and rugs. Visit in April, when the many rose bushes are in full bloom.</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at ancient Persepolis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For many visitors, Persepolis is the over-riding reason to come to Iran. A short drive from Shiraz, Persepolis was once the ceremonial capital of the Achaemenid Empire, also known as the First Persian Empire, from the 6th to 4th centuries BC. The vast spread of deserted columns, stairways and gateways is a stirring sight.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$412.3 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, chemical and petrochemical products, carpets, cement, ore, fruits and nuts.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Industrial raw materials and intermediate goods, capital goods, food, other consumer goods and technical services.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Japan, China, Turkey, India, South Korea and United Arab Emirates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iran's main sources of income are its huge oil and gas deposits, which are among the world's largest. It also has viable deposits of coal, magnesium ores and gypsum.<br />
<br />
The agricultural sector is important, although output has been depressed by drought and migration of rural labour to the cities. Government policy has promoted the agricultural and light industry in order to reduce the economy's dependence on oil and increase the influence of the private sector - about 80% of economic activity is state controlled. Annual growth is about 4.3% (2006) with unemployment at 15% (2007). The rate of inflation in 2006 was estimated at 12%.<br />
<br />
Economic policy is dominated by the fundamental difference of approach between the elected government and the ruling clergy. Iran has developed important new links with the newly independent states of central Asia as well as Turkey and China but, more importantly, existing trade with traditional partners in Europe, Japan and the Middle East have been restored.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most Iranian businesspeople speak English and are polite and conservative in manner and expect an appropriate response from visitors. Exchanging business cards is normally restricted to senior people. Appointments should be made and punctuality is expected for business meetings. Business gifts are quite acceptable.</p><p>Sat-Wed 0800-1600, Thurs 0800-1230 (some offices may close all day).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Trade Promotion Organisation of Iran</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 21919
					Website:http://www.iranexporters.org/
					Address: Tadjrish,PO Box 1148,Tehran,]]><b>Iranian Trade Association in the USA</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (619) 368 6790
					Website:http://www.iraniantrade.org
					Address: San Diego,PO Box 927743,CA 92192,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Rice is the staple food and the Iranians cook it in style, eating it with wheat bread, yoghurt, lamb and aubergines. Typical Persian flavours are subtle, with cinnamon, cloves, turmeric, cardamom and saffron all delicately blended.</p>
<p>Garlic and lime also feature heavily. Many Iranians make their own yoghurt, which can be used as an ingredient in many dishes or as a cool and refreshing drink. Kebabs, served either in oven-fresh bread or with rice, tend to dominate menus, but there's plenty more besides. Vegetarianism is uncommon, but visitors will often find meat-free options.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Chelokhoresh</strong>: Rice topped with vegetables and meat in a nut sauce.<br />
<strong>Polo sabzi</strong>: Pilau rice cooked with fresh herbs.<br />
<strong>Polo chirin</strong>: Sweet-sour saffron-coloured rice with raisins, almonds and orange.<br />
<strong>Adas polo</strong>: Rice, lentils and meat.<br />
<strong>Morgh polo</strong>: Chicken and pilau rice.<br />
<strong>Chelokababs</strong>: Rice with skewered meats cooked over charcoal.<br />
<strong>Kofte</strong>: Minced meat formed into meatballs.<br />
<strong>Koftegusht</strong>: Meatloaf.<br />
<strong>Abgusht</strong>: Mutton and chickpea stew.<br />
<strong>Fesenjan</strong>: Pomegranate walnut stew.<br />
<strong>Bademjan</strong>: Aubergine and tomato stew.<br />
<strong>Doogh</strong>: A cold drink made from yoghurt and mineral water.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In large hotels, a 10% to 15% service charge is added to the bill. In restaurants, it is usual to leave small change.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Illegal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While the shops offer a wide selection of quality goods, local items can be bought in the many bazaars. Purchases include hand-carved, inlaid woodwork, carpets, rugs, silks, leather goods, mats, tablecloths, gold, silver, glass and ceramics. Bargaining is customary. There are restrictions on which items may be taken out of the country.</p><p>Generally shops and bazaars are open between 0830 and 2030, except on a Friday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are hotels in almost all towns, including several 5-star ones in Tehran. Student and budget accommodation is available in small hotels, and many cheap hotels run on a model similar to hostels. Villas are also popular. Iranians often invite travellers into their homes, so staying in the homes of local people, although far from typical, is not uncommon. For more information contact the Iranian Society of Travel Agents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are hotels in almost all towns, including several 5-star ones in Tehran. Student and budget accommodation is available in small hotels, and many cheap hotels run on a model similar to hostels. Villas are also popular. Iranians often invite travellers into their homes, so staying in the homes of local people, although far from typical, is not uncommon. For more information contact the Iranian Society of Travel Agents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are hotels in almost all towns, including several 5-star ones in Tehran. Student and budget accommodation is available in small hotels, and many cheap hotels run on a model similar to hostels. Villas are also popular. Iranians often invite travellers into their homes, so staying in the homes of local people, although far from typical, is not uncommon. For more information contact the Iranian Society of Travel Agents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health facilities are limited in remote areas. Medical insurance is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated, and whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available and is advised for the first few weeks of the stay. Pasteurised milk is available; unpasteurised milk should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present in southwestern Iran; avoid swimming and paddling in stagnant water. Travellers&amp;rsquo; diarrhoea is relatively common. Diarrhoeal diseases are common. Hepatitis B occurs. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Iran without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.</p>
<p>Importing alcohol is illegal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include alcoholic drinks, narcotics, gambling devices, weapons and ammunition, explosives, counterfeit goods, anti-Islamic publications, and publications, photos and films considered to be against the religious and national dignity of Iran.</p>
<p>Restricted items include animals, fish, plants, medicines (other than those prescribed for personal use), and telecommunications equipment.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All prohibited imports are also banned from export, along with antiquities and cultural artefacts.</p>
<p>The export of gold is restricted to 150g and the export of silver is restricted to 3kg.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iranian Rial (IRR; symbol Rs) = 100 dinars. Notes are in denominations of Rs 100,000, 50,000, 20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 2,000, 1,000, 500, 200 and 100. Coins are in denominations of Rs 5,000, 2,000, 1,000, 500, 250, 100 and 50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is advisable to bring hard currency for exchange purposes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard is accepted in some places, but credit cards should emphatically not be relied on as the sole means of payment. Be aware too that if the card was issued in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, it may not be usable due to the US trade embargo.</p><p>ATMs can be used only by holders of local bank accounts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is not possible to exchange travellers' cheques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sat-Wed 0800-1600, Thurs 0800-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Iran, a passport valid for six months beyond the length of stay, and with two blank pages, is required by the nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>UK nationals: tourist visa: US$265; double-entry visa: US$400.</p>
<p>US nationals: tourist visa: US$90; double-entry visa: US$135.</p>
<p>Canadian nationals: tourist visa: US$75; double-entry visa: US$110.</p>
<p>Australian nationals: tourist visa: US$105; double-entry visa: US$155.</p>
<p>Visas for many EU nationals (other than British nationals) are US$75 for single-entry visas and US$110 for double-entry visas, but prices vary according to nationality, so check with the consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). The consular section of the Iranian Embassy in the UK has reopened. Residents of the USA need to contact the Iranian Interests Section of the Embassy of Pakistan in Washington, DC.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas usually take around 15 days to process.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[32.405318]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[54.475708]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,648,195 sq km (636,371 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>81,801,633 (UN estimate July 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>50 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tehran.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Islamic Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iran is located in the Middle East, bordered to the north by Turkmenistan, Azerbaijan, Armenia and the Caspian Sea, the east by Afghanistan and Pakistan, the south by the Persian Gulf and the Gulf of Oman, and the west by Iraq and Turkey. The centre and east of the country are largely barren undulating desert, punctured by <em>qanats </em>(irrigation canals) and green oases, but there are mountainous regions in the west along the Turkish and Iraqi borders and in the north where the Elburz Mountains rise steeply from a fertile belt around the Caspian Sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>According to the Iranian government, which does not officially recognise the existence of non-religious Iranians, 90-95% of the population associate with the Shia branch of Islam, while 5-10% associate with the Sunni and Sufi branches of Islam. The remaining 0.6% are non-Islamic religious minorities, including Baha&rsquo;is, Mandeans, Yarsanis, Zoroastrians, Jews, and Christians.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors should avoid contentious political subjects in conversation. In general, &ldquo;liberal&rdquo; Western influences are discouraged by authorities. Handshaking is customary, but not with members of the opposite sex. It must be remembered that intimate relations between non-Muslim men and Muslim women is illegal, and may incur imprisonment. Iranians are incredibly hospitable and like to entertain. It is customary to be offered tea, and guests are expected to accept hospitality. Dress should generally be conservative and discreet &ndash; women should cover their heads in public and wear loose clothing. During Ramadan, smoking, eating and drinking in public are prohibited between sunrise and sunset.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Hassan Rouhani since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Supreme Leader Grand Ayatollah Ali Hosseini Khamenei since 1989.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The history of Iran is bound up in the rise and often-chaotic fall of successive ruling groups. In the 6th century BC, the first Persian Empire was founded by Cyrus the Great, which was overthrown by Alexander the Great some 200 years later, after which came a long chain of invasions from Arabs, Turks and Mongols, among others. Islam arrived in the 7th century.</p>
<p>It wasn&rsquo;t until the heights of the Safavid dynasty in the late 1500s that the Persian Empire could really be said to have regained greatness. The period was marked by lengthy wars with the Ottomans and opulent buildings, many of them religious, as the Shia form of Islam was cemented in the country.</p>
<p>By the 19th century, European influence was beginning to be felt strongly, exacerbated after the discovery of oil in the early 1900s. In the 1970s, the economic mismanagement and secular lifestyle of the ruling Shah was a catalyst for the 1979 popular revolution, spearheaded by Ayatollah Khomenei, and Iran became an Islamic Republic. A lengthy war with Iraq followed after Saddam Hussein sought to capitalise on Iranian instability by suddenly invading, and relations remain complicated between the two countries.</p>
<p>Nearly four decades since the revolution, the regime of the Ayatollah endures, and Iran remains a powerful force in the region. For more than a decade, Washington and Tehran were at odds over Iran's suspected development of nuclear weapons, but the very real possibility of war between the two powers rapidly ebbed away when the moderate President Hassan Mahmoud Rouhani was elected in 2013, replacing the more hardline President Ahmadinejad.</p>
<p>Since then, a surprising detente has taken place between the US and Iran, with an end to economic sanctions and a groundbreaking treaty over Iran's nuclear programme recently struck. Relations between Iran and a number of other Western powers have also begun to normalise, giving hope that the country can regain its status on the world stage.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Neckties were banned in Iran in 1979 after the Islamic revolution.<br />
&bull; Iran is thought to have built the earliest known windmills.<br />
&bull; In 2013, Iran announced it would put a Persian cat in space.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Interests Section of the Islamic Republic of Iran in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 965 4990.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.daftar.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 965 4990.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0800-1630&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>c/o The Embassy of Pakistan, 1250 23rd Street NW, No. 200<br/>Washington<br/>20037<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Iran in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 0207 225 4208.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.london.mfa.ir</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 0207 225 4208.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Knightsbridge<br/>16 Prince's Gate<br/>London<br/>SW7 1PT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iran ought to be one of the world&rsquo;s most treasured travel destinations, blessed as it is with extraordinary historical sites, exquisite landscapes and a fascinating culture. But international tensions and a tough domestic regime have prevented that from being the case &ndash; it has remained a destination for the intrepid.</p>
<p>Things are changing, though. Since the election of a moderate president in 2013 and the gradual thawing of relations with the West, this once out-of-bounds country has started to open up. No one&rsquo;s pretending that its current leadership can&rsquo;t be shockingly hard-fisted in matters of civic law. But most foreigners are likely to find their preconceptions shattered. They will find Iranians warm and friendly, keen to practice their English and quick with the tea invites.</p>
<p>Rich Persian heritage dating back 3,000 years is evident throughout the country. Historical sights like the ancient ruins of Persepolis and the still-glorious former capital of Isfahan are abundant. Iran has a distinct cultural identity too, with its predominately Shia-Muslim population, which sets it apart from most nations in the Islamic world.</p>
<p>Parts of the country are very conservative, but Tehran will strike many visitors as extremely modern. Despite the image perpetuated of religious dogma, in the capital women walk around in skinny jeans and make-up, while couples openly hold hands. There&rsquo;s a lively caf&eacute; culture and a youth culture comparable to Mediterranean countries. Persian cuisine can be sampled in countless traditional and more contemporary restaurants.</p>
<p>Ancient Persia has the potential to attract millions of tourists per year, but it's the modern reforming Iran that could be of as much interest. Flashpoint travel advice should be heeded and tourists still won&rsquo;t be flocking to the country on a whim. But those who do travel will find street-level Iran to be almost unrecognisable from the Iran making headlines around much of the world.</p><p>Iran ought to be one of the world&rsquo;s most treasured travel destinations, blessed as it is with extraordinary historical sites, exquisite landscapes and a fascinating culture. But international tensions and a tough domestic regime have prevented that from being the case &ndash; it has remained a destination for the intrepid.</p>
<p>Things are changing, though. Since the election of a moderate president in 2013 and the gradual thawing of relations with the West, this once out-of-bounds country has started to open up. No one&rsquo;s pretending that its current leadership can&rsquo;t be shockingly hard-fisted in matters of civic law. But most foreigners are likely to find their preconceptions shattered.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
