<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Iraq" ColCode="irq" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="iq" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Iraq]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Summers are very hot and dry but cooler in the mountains in the north and east. Winters are mild with some rain in central and southern Iraq but cold in the north.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Long, loose clothing in natural fabrics is advised for summer months. Medium-weights are advised during the winter.  <br /><br />Modest dress is advised, especially for women - upper legs and arms, shoulders and cleavage should be covered. A headscarf can be useful for extra coverage, and is essential for visiting mosques.<br /><br />In Iraqi Kurdistan dress for women is very western; in the towns in the north at least half of the women do not wear headscarves and wear western fashions though this does not include short skirts, shorts or obvious cleavage.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iraqi Airways (<a href="http://www.iraqiairways.com.iq" target="_blank">www.iraqiairways.com.iq</a>) has domestic flights between Baghdad, Basra, Suleimaniya and Erbil.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rail services are operated by Iraq Republic Railways. The only route currently in operation is between Baghdad and Basra.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travel by road is not wholly recommended at present, due to the continuing threat of carjacking, robbery and random attacks; these have often occurred on highways 1, 5, 10 and 15.&nbsp;It is recommended to travel in convoys of at least four per vehicle in daylight hours only.&nbsp;Road closures must also be expected.</p>
<p>Improvised Explosive Devices (IEDs) and/or mines are used on some roads. Some cars do not use lights at night and some urban street lighting may be broken.&nbsp;Road congestion is a problem.</p>
<p>Principal routes are from Baghdad to Kirkuk, Arbil and Zakho; Baghdad to the Jordanian frontier; Baghdad to Kanaquin (Iranian border); Baghdad to Hilla and Kerbela; and Baghdad to Al Basrah and Safwan (Kuwait border).</p>r<p>Services are available both in cities and for transit. Fares should be negotiated in advance. Metered taxis charge twice the amount shown on the meter. Tipping is not necessary.</p><p>International Driving Permit required. Third-party insurance is necessary.</p><p>Available at the airport and in Baghdad.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Baghdad has a few buses, a commuter train and share-taxis running. Buses are poorly maintained and they are often involved in accidents. Services are irregular and frequently change route. Bus tickets should be pre-purchased at kiosks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iraqi Airways (<a href="http://www.iraqiairways.com.iq" target="_blank">www.iraqiairways.com.iq</a>) fly from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> Gatwick to Baghdad. Iraqi Airways also operates flights between Baghdad and all regional cities.</p>
<p>There are now regular scheduled direct flights on an increasing number of international and regional airlines into Baghdad, Basra, Irbil and Sulemaniyah.</p>
<p>Lufthansa (<a href="http://www.lufthansa.com" target="_blank">www.lufthansa.com</a>) flies to Erbil from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/frankfurt">Frankfurt</a>&nbsp;or Vienna.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iraq/erbil-international-airport">Erbil International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Average flight time from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> to Baghdad International is 5 hours 35 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 15 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no departure tax.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Baghdad International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.baghdad-airport.com/<p>The airport is 18km (11 miles) south of the city (journey time - 20 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Erbil International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://erbilairport.com<p>The airport is located 6km (4 miles) northwest of central Erbil.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+964 66 281 0000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no international rail links at present.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements with several international mobile phone companies exist. There is good coverage in major cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafés are springing up across Iraq, especially in Baghdad.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There has been a surge of media outlets since the downfall of Saddam Hussein. Hundreds of publications and dozens of radio and TV stations are now available. Newspapers printed in Iraq include <em>Al-Sabah</em>, sponsored by state-run Iraqi <em>Media Network. </em>During Saddam's dictatorship, satellite TV was banned in Iraq, but now is extremely popular especially <em>Al-Aribiya,</em> <em>Al-Jazeera</em> and <em>BBC Arabic Television</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All mail may take several weeks to process and is inadvisable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the Al-Kadhimiya Mosque</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Marvel at the elaborate Al-Kadhimiya Mosque in Baghdad &ndash; one of the most important religious shrines in Iraq. This spectacular building has four gold-coated minarets and two domes. The current building dates back to the Ottomans in 1515 AD, although the original shrine is dated to the 8th century. Unfortunately, in recent years the site has been the target of numerous terrorist attacks.</p>]]><p><b>Be amazed by the Islamic architecture of Karbala</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join the pilgrims travelling to Karbala, 100 km south of Baghdad. It's the spiritual home of Shi'ia Muslims who make pilgrimages to the impressive mosque housing the shrine of Hussein. The monuments there are amongst some of the finest in the Islamic world.</p>]]><p><b>Be in awe of the ancient city of Ur</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ancient Sumerian city of Ur is one of the most impressive archaeological sites in Iraq, with its earliest buildings dating back to around 21st century BC. Archaeological excavations have revealed the remains of the Great Ziggurat, one of the most breath-taking structures of the ancient world.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise through The Marshes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Marshes are situated along the Shatt El-Arab waterway and are best explored by boat to experience the locals who live on man-made islands in beautiful dwellings woven in latticework from reeds.</p>]]><p><b>Enter the Kurdistan capital of Erbil</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Erbil is the capital and seat of the Kurdistan Regional Government in Northern Iraq. In strolling the city, you will be treading in the footsteps of Alexander the Great who defeated Darius III in the battle of Gaugamela here. The Erbil Museum marks this battle and houses a collection of Sumerian and Abbasid artefacts.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Iraq's past at the National Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Iraq National Museum finally reopened in 2015 after 12 years of not being opened due to a looting during the US invasions. The wealth of archaeological artefacts brings the ancient world of the Babylon to life, and is almost unrivalled in the region.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the pretty canals of Basra</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once called the "Venice of the East", Basra's canals are lined with elegant 19th-century houses. Have a stroll on the lush island across from the Shatt Al-Arab Hotel where families picnic Basra remains the main seaport for large commercial ships and tankers as well as traditional dhows.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the ruins of Babylon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An hour south of Baghdad is the historical site of Babylon and its legendary Hanging Gardens. Dating back to around 2300 BC, Babylon was a political and religious centre over several successive empires, the peak of which was the reign of Nebuchadnezzar II. Unfortunately, not much remains of the glorious palaces and temples of ancient Babylon.</p>]]><p><b>Haggle in the Baghdad Bazaars</b></p><![CDATA[<p>After being a no-go area for some years, the famous city bazaars have started to come to life again. Head to the colourful bird market Souk al-Ghazal and observe the famed pigeon fanciers buy birds, exchange tips and relax at local cafés.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the Arch of Ctesiphon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sitting east of Baghdad along the Tigris River, the Arch of Ctesiphon is built of mud brick and is probably the most spectacular archaeological remnant of a city that was captured variously through the century by the Romans, Byzantine Empire, Parthians and Sassanians. Erected in the 6th century, it was a remarkable feat of engineering for its time.</p>]]><p><b>Relax in the Kurdish mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The foothills and mountains ring every town in Iraqi Kurdistan and in the spring and summer they are cool and beautiful places to escape the heat and dust of the towns. In the new Korek Mountain Resort, it's even possible to go skiing.</p>]]><p><b>Sample Baghdad's glory days at Abbasid Palace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Overlooking the Tigris River, the Abbasid Palace is one of the finest surviving examples of 13th century Baghdad. It is one of the oldest buildings in the city, representing a period when Baghdad was a centre of education as well as trade.</p>]]><p><b>See Assyrian bas-reliefs in Ninevah</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If Mosul becomes accessible once more, it's essential to visit the bas-reliefs of Ninevah, the third capital of Assyria. Located on the Tigris River in the suburbs of modern Mosul, Nineveh was a centre of worship for the goddess Ishtar, an Assyrian capital and reached its height around 700 BC.</p>]]><p><b>See the golden dome of Najaf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Najaf - air distance is about 146km; driving distance is about 190km - south of Baghdad, is another of the Shi'ia holy cities and famous for the mosque of Al-Haidariya, crowned with a resplendent golden dome made of gold tiles and minarets each made of 40,000 gold tiles. There are few more stunning sights in the Middle East.</p>]]><p><b>See the pre-Islamic wonders of Mosul</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At the time of writing, Mosul is under the control of Islamic State, but if the town becomes accessible again, you can visit the ruined city of Nineveh, while many pre-Islamic artefacts can be found in the Mosul Museum. Wander through the old city and explore mosques, churches and castles. The centre of town is famous for narrow streets of beautiful 19th century houses.</p>]]><p><b>Visit The Green Zone</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't miss visiting the vast fortified zone in the centre of Baghdad. You'll find various Iraqi government ministries in this heavily guarded area, as well as Western embassies and several ostentatious palaces, notably the Republican Palace, built by Saddam and his family.</p>]]><p><b>Wander the early Islamic ruins of Samarra</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Designated a World Heritage Site by UNESCO in 2007 due to its well-preserved ruins and history, Samarra represented the power of the vast Abbasid Empire. The 9th century Great Mosque and minaret are some of the most impressive early Islamic ruins in Iraq.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>USD $171.5 billion (2016 est.)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, crude materials (excluding fuel), food, live animals, gold, lubricating products, tropical fruits.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, medicine and manufactured goods, cars, raw iron bars and insulated wire.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Turkey, Syria, Italy, China, India and Spain.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iraq's economy is dominated by the oil sector, which has traditionally provided over 90% of foreign exchange earnings. The military victory of the US-led coalition in March/April 2003 resulted in the shutdown of much of the economic administrative structure. <br />
<br />
Although a comparatively small amount of capital was damaged during the hostilities, looting, insurgent attacks, and sabotage have undermined efforts to rebuild the economy. These have also prevented Iraq from reaching projected export volumes, but total government revenues have been higher than anticipated due to inflated oil prices. <br />
<br />
In 2005, unemployment stood at 27%. Iraq's economic prospects will depend on the government's ability to control inflation, to implement structural reforms, and to develop the private sector.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Formal courtesies are expected and traditional whenever you meet in Iraq for personal or business reasons. Business cards are routinely exchanged and these are often printed in Arabic and English or in Kurdish and English if you are in Iraqi Kurdistan (the majority of Iraqi Kurds do not read or speak Arabic). Directness and brevity in business meetings can be considered rude; meetings usually begin with a general conversation and many pleasantries which also serve the purpose to assess character of everyone concerned.</p><p>Saturday-Wed:- 8:00-1:00 and 2:00-5:00, Thursday:- 8:00-1:30. Friday is the weekly day of rest when offices tend to be closed. During the month of Ramadan, hours are reduced.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Federation of Iraqi Chambers of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 888 8850
					Website:
					Address: Mustansir Street,PO Box 11348,Baghdad,]]><b>orphan</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7215 8893
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Baghdad Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 887 6211
					Website:
					Address: Al-mustansir Street,PO Box 24168,Almsarif,Baghdad,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>In effect, Iraqi cuisine dates back 10,000 years &ndash; how many countries can say that? Today, Iraq's traditional fare reflects centuries of Arab, Turkish, Persian and Syrian influence, making for one of the most vivid culinary scenes in the Middle East. Mezza, or the various appetisers and salads, typically comes first, followed by many dishes involving lamb and rice, as well as grilled fish and elaborate dishes involving stuffed vegetables.</p>
<p>Citrus fruits grow abundantly in Iraq and feature a lot in the country&rsquo;s cuisine. Grilled kebabs that have been marinated with lemon, garlic and various spices are common, as are select stews, falafel, and a wraps of grilled meat, which are known as gauss, similar to doner kebab.</p>
<p>For those who flick straight to the dessert menu, Iraq shares much in common with the rest of the region &ndash; expect plenty of moreish baklava and other super-sweet pastries infused with nuts and syrup.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dolma</strong>: Vine leaves, cabbage, lettuce, onions, aubergine, marrow or cucumbers stuffed with rice, meat and spices.<br />
<strong>Tikka</strong>: Small chunks of mutton on skewers grilled on a charcoal fire.<br />
<strong>Quozi</strong>: Small lamb boiled whole and grilled, stuffed with rice, minced meat and spices and served on rice.<br />
<strong>Masgouf</strong>: Fish from the Tigris, typical of areas along the river.<br />
<strong>Gauss</strong>: Grilled-meat wrap.<br />
<strong>Bamieh</strong>: Lamb, okra and tomato stew.<br />
<strong>Quzi</strong>: Lamb with rice, raisins, almonds and spices.<br />
<strong>Falafel</strong>: Fried chickpea patties served in a pitta with amba (spicy sauce derived from picked mango) and salad<br />
<strong>Kubbah</strong>: Minced meat mixed with rice or bulgur and spices<br />
<strong>Masg&ucirc;f</strong>: Grilled fish with tamarind and pepper<br />
<strong>Maqluba</strong>: A rice-based dish with lamb, aubergine and tomatoes<br />
<strong>Arak</strong>: A clear, colourless, unsweetened aniseed-flavoured distilled alcoholic drink.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Normal limit is 10% to 15%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Baghdad was once famous for its nightlife, with first-class restaurants and all-night clubs where music and sometimes alcohol flowed. Now Iraqi liquor sellers and drinkers are forced underground. Much of the alcohol sold is counterfeit and the price is often more than doubled due to the difficulty in obtaining it. Members-only clubs in Baghdad are currently the only relatively safe havens for socialising, protected by high walls, guards and members lists. Most people stay home at night after 1800 because it is too dangerous to be out. Iraqi cinema and music<strong> </strong>is on the up, however.<br />
<br />
In late 2009 a series of raids on night clubs in Baghdad closed down many of these premises, even those which had licenses. These raids, allegedly with the backing of Iraqi Prime Minister Nouri al-Maliki appear to be part of an increasingly conservative crackdown. Other targets include controls on internet caf&eacute;s, where the government has blocked certain websites and new restrictions on the media and book publishers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The long-established town markets sell copperware, silver, spices, carpets and brightly coloured rugs. In Baghdad the copper market is a centre of noisy activity with coppersmiths beating their pots into shape.</p><p>Sat - Thurs 09:00 to 18:00, or to 17:00 during summer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation is mainly for business travellers. Hotel accommodation is limited and bookings should be made in advance. Small hotels are also available for low budgets, but with a lower standard of facilities. Hotels usually require payment in foreign currency, cash only. A 10% service charge is usually added to the bill.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation is mainly for business travellers. Hotel accommodation is limited and bookings should be made in advance. Small hotels are also available for low budgets, but with a lower standard of facilities. Hotels usually require payment in foreign currency, cash only. A 10% service charge is usually added to the bill.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation is mainly for business travellers. Hotel accommodation is limited and bookings should be made in advance. Small hotels are also available for low budgets, but with a lower standard of facilities. Hotels usually require payment in foreign currency, cash only. A 10% service charge is usually added to the bill.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Iraq's health system has suffered from years of neglect and war. Only limited facilities are available and evacuation by air ambulance may be required; therefore, insurance should have provision for this. Doctors and hospitals often expect immediate cash payment for services.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present: avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water; swimming pools which are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. Diarrhoeal diseases are common. Vaccinations are sometimes advised for tuberculosis and hepatitis B.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Army Day :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Baghdad Liberation Day :
							09 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Republic Day :
							14 July </p><p>Ceasefire Day (End of Iran-Iraq War) :
							08 August </p><p>National Day :
							03 October </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Iraq without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 25 cigarillos or 10 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits.<br />
&bull; 2L of fortified wine.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 8L of beer.</p>
<p>Residents of Iraq may import goods up to the value of ID500,000 within a 72-hour period. There is no specific value for non-residents, provided the goods are for personal use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include magazines, films and videos 'contrary to public norms', arms and ammunition, explosives and narcotics.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include non-military explosives, industrial materials used in explosive devices such as fertiliser, and fowl or poultry products from countries with outbreaks of avian influenza.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited exports include magazines, films and videos 'contrary to public norms', historical artefacts, arms and ammunition, explosives and narcotics.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Restricted exports include non-military explosives, certain foodstuffs (eg sugar, tea and wheat), animals (excluding household pets), bar soap and detergents (other than for personal use), and certain manufactured goods (eg steel and wood), and date palm seedlings and shoots.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iraqi Dinar (IQD; symbol ID) = 20 dirhams = 1,000 fils. Notes are in denominations of ID25,000, 10,000, 5,000, 1,000, 500, 250 and 50. Coins are in denominations of ID100 and 25. <br />
<br />
<strong>Note:</strong> This information is subject to frequent change in the current conditions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency can be used at special duty-free shops in Baghdad up to a value of US$200. To obtain this concession, goods must be purchased within 20 days of arrival and passports must be produced.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One of the main Iraqi banks, Warka Bank, has 350 ATMs in 120 branches across Iraq in most cities and towns. The location of their ATMs are listed on their website: <a href="http://www.warka-bank.com" target="_blank">www.warka-bank.com</a>.<br />
<br />
<strong>Note:</strong> The banking and financial infrastructure has been disrupted and is in the process of rebuilding. Hotels usually require payment in foreign currency.</p><p>One of the main Iraqi banks, Warka Bank, has 350 ATMs in 120 branches across Iraq in most cities and towns. The location of their ATMs are listed on their website: <a href="http://www.warka-bank.com" target="_blank">www.warka-bank.com</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers cheques are not generally accepted in Iraq, though it is sometimes possible to do a deal with some merchants in city bazaars. Be warned that the rate will not be a good one. There are also Western Union branches available in main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sunday to Friday 08:00-12:30, Saturday 08:00-12:00. Banks close at 10:00 during Ramadan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Iraq, a passport valid for at least six months from the date a visa is issued is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: &pound;30; multiple-entry visa: &pound;75.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: up to three months from the date of issue; multiple-entry visa: six months to a year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow four to eight weeks for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must be able to provide proof of sufficient funds to cover your stay in Iraq.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[33.044986]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[43.797012]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>438,317 sq km (169,235 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>37,547,686 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>89 per km2</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Baghdad.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Democratic republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iraq shares borders with Turkey, Iran, the Gulf of Oman, Kuwait, Saudi Arabia, Jordan and the Syrian Arab Republic. There is also a neutral zone between Iraq and Saudi Arabia administered jointly by the two countries. Iraq's portion covers 3,522 sq km (1,360 sq miles). The country's main topographical features are the two rivers, the Euphrates and the Tigris, which flow from the Turkish and Syrian Arab Republic borders in the north to the Gulf in the south. The northeast is mountainous, while the country in the west is arid desert. The land surrounding the two rivers is fertile plain, but the lack of effective irrigation has resulted in flooding and areas of marshland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Islam. Muslims make up 95% of the population, with considerably more Shiites than Sunni. Others are Christians who belong to various sects, including Chaldeans, Assyrians, Syrian and Roman Catholics, Orthodox Armenians and Jacobites. Other religious minorities are the Yezidis and the Sabaeans, or Mandeans, who are followers of John the Baptist.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Owing to a long and varied history, Iraq is a culturally rich country. Today, traditional Islamic culture predominates, with Koranic law playing an active role in the day-to-day life of the country, and visitors should be careful to respect this and act accordingly. Visitors should always address their hosts by full name and title. Traditional Arab hospitality is followed as a rule, in accordance with religious law. Conservative and discreet dress should be worn in observance of local Islamic laws.<br /><br />Social conventions in Iraqi Kurdistan are more flexible. This northern region of Iraq has been semi-autonomous since 1991. Many women wear western fashions and no headscarves. <br /><br /><strong>Photography:</strong> There is a need for extreme caution when photographing anything of a sensitive nature. This includes photographs of local people (the Muslim religion does not allow the representation of human or animal images in any form); and, most importantly, any government installations, buildings or indeed anything else that may be considered off-limits to visitors. If in any doubt, do not take a photo.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Various two- and three-pin plugs are in use. Electricity supplies are unreliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Adel Abdul Mahdi since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Barham Salih since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mesopotamia &ndash; the core of modern Iraq &ndash; was at the heart of the Sumerian, Babylonian and Assyrian empires between the 7th century BC and 100 AD. After brief spells under the rule of the Romans and the Sassanids, Iraq was subject to the Arab conquest in 633 AD.</p>
<p>Later, the Arab Caliphate took control of the territory during the late 12th and early 13th centuries before being dislodged by the Mongols. At the end of the 14th century, Iraq was conquered and subsumed into the empire ruled by Timur (also known as Tamerlane). The Turks were the next imperial invaders, ruling from the early 16th century until the collapse of the Ottoman Empire.</p>
<p>In 1920, Iraq was placed under a League of Nations mandate administered by the UK, whose forces had occupied most of the country. The country achieved independence in 1932, but British forces intervened once again in 1941 to combat a pro-Nazi coup.</p>
<p>In 1958, the ruling Hashemite Dynasty was overthrown by a group of radical army officers inspired by the example of Gamal Abdel Nasser in Egypt, and led by Brigadier Abdul al-Karim Kassem. The new regime failed to consolidate its position, however, and relied on a precarious coalition of forces, which quickly disintegrated. Kassem was killed in 1963 during another coup.</p>
<p>In 1968, Iraq's final coup in recent history brought to power the Ba'ath Party. In 1979, after a power struggle within the Ba'ath Party, Vice President Saddam Hussein took over as president and party leader. Saddam's main objectives were to establish his country as the undisputed leader of the Arab world and to overcome the Arabs' two principal enemies in the Middle East: Iran and Israel. With Iran in chaos, he launched a full-scale invasion in 1980. The Iraqis failed to win and the fighting went on until 1988.</p>
<p>The Iraqi economy was crippled by the war and had incurred an enormous foreign debt, much of which was owed to neighbouring Kuwait; a dispute over oil reserves provided the pretext for the Iraqi invasion of Kuwait in 1990. This led to the Gulf War, after which no-fly zones were established by the US and UK. In 2003, a US-led coalition went to war again in Iraq and, finally ousted Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>Since then, Iraq has struggled to rebuild its economy, as well as a workable democracy. After the eventual departure of US troops in 2011, Iraq became embroiled in Syria's civil war, and the radical-Islamist Daesh has seized huge swathes of the country. The fighting shows little sign of letting up.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Iraq in Arabic means &lsquo;the fertile&rsquo;.<br />
&bull; Noak&rsquo;s ark is believed to have been built in modern-day Iraq.<br />
&bull; The traditional music of Iraq, <em>maqam</em>, is based on Arabic poetry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Iraq in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 483 7500.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.iraqiembassy.us</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 483 7500.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Monday &amp;ndash; Friday, 10:00am &amp;ndash; 2:00pm&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1801 P Street<br/>Washington<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Iraq in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7590 7650</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://mofamission.gov.iq/en/UKLondon</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7590 7650</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 09:30-13:00.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>21 Queen Gate<br/>London<br/>SW7 5JE<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Iraq may be synonymous with strife, a land of dusty, dubious conflicts, but what you don&rsquo;t see in the mainstream media are the country&rsquo;s many attributes: its fantastic birdlife, shimmering oases, turquoise rivers, fertile valleys, UNESCO World Heritage Sites and stunning cityscapes. Some of the world&rsquo;s oldest societies came out of this ancient land and many refer to the region as the &lsquo;cradle of civilisation.&rsquo;</p>
<p>But despite its glorious past, the country has little to celebrate at present. Most of Iraq&rsquo;s political, social, physical and economic infrastructures were destroyed by the US-led invasion in 2003. Successful elections and the withdrawal of troops in 2009 seemed to herald Iraq&rsquo;s road to recovery and there were reasons to be optimistic: despite continuing violence, tourism had climbed back up to an impressive two million people a year by 2013 and plans were afoot to increase that number threefold.</p>
<p>The government even announced that it would restore the Arch of Ctesiphon, the world&rsquo;s biggest arch made of bricks, and what remains of the ancient Persian capital of the same name. Also revealed were plans to repair the damage done to the southern marshes, which Sadam Hussein drained, and use its status as a bird haven to create a centre for eco-tourism.</p>
<p>Since 2013, though, the security situation has rapidly deteriorated, culminating with the Islamic militant group ISIS seizing large swathes of territory in the north in 2014. The Iraqi government has since pushed back against the insurgency, but the situation remains highly volatile with no end in sight.</p>
<p>Despite government warnings to avoid travelling to the country, a few adventure tour companies are still taking small groups to Iraq, albeit not the north. If and when the country finally stabilises, there&rsquo;s little doubt that tourists will return in greater numbers to the &lsquo;cradle of civilisation&rsquo;. But until then, travel to Iraq is strongly advised against.</p><p>Iraq may be synonymous with strife, a land of dusty, dubious conflicts, but what you don&rsquo;t see in the mainstream media are the country&rsquo;s many attributes: its fantastic birdlife, shimmering oases, turquoise rivers, fertile valleys, UNESCO World Heritage Sites and stunning cityscapes. Some of the world&rsquo;s oldest societies came out of this ancient land and many refer to the region as the &lsquo;cradle of civilisation.&rsquo;</p>
<p>But despite its glorious past, the country has little to celebrate at present. Following a brief spell of optimism in 2013, after foreign troops had left,&nbsp;the situation has rapidly deteriorated, culminating with the Islamic militant group ISIS seizing large swathes of territory in the north in 2014. Consequently, travel to Iraq is strongly advised against.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
