<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Ireland" ColCode="irl" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ie" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Ireland]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ireland's relatively temperate climate is due to mild southwesterly winds and the effects of the Atlantic Gulf Stream. Summers are warm &ndash; only rarely getting unpleasantly hot &ndash; while temperatures during winter are much cooler, although it&rsquo;s far from common for the temperature to drop below freezing and snowfall is rare. Spring and autumn are very mild, with rainfall expected all year round. </p>
<p>The other chief characteristic of the climate, however, is its unpredictability. You might be basking in balmy T-shirt weather one week, then wrapping up to stave off the chill the next &ndash; all the while with an umbrella to hand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights during summer with warmer mediumweights for the winter. Rainwear is advisable throughout the year. If you find yourself lacking anything essential on arrival, of course, all key centres are well stocked with clothing outlets, with the larger cities particularly good in terms of picking up high quality outdoor equipment. And it's worth remembering that certain clothing items which are more commonly seen as souvenirs – hand-knit Aran sweaters, for example – can be practical purchases for the trip itself.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Aer Arran (<a href="http://www.aerarann.com" target="_blank">www.aerarann.com</a>) and Aer Lingus (<a href="http://www.aerlingus.com" target="_blank">www.aerlingus.com</a>)&nbsp;run domestic routes. Given the size of the country however, internal flights are rarely essential.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferry services run to the Aran Islands with Aran Island Ferries (<a href="http://www.aranislandferries.com" target="_blank">www.aranislandferries.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rail services in Ireland are run by Iarnr&oacute;d Eireann (Irish Rail)<em> </em>(tel: 1850 366 222, in Ireland only or +353 1 836 6222; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.irishrail.ie">www.irishrail.ie</a>) and express trains run between the main cities. There are two classes of accommodation, with restaurant and buffet cars on some trains. Discounts are available for families, students and schoolchildren.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Ireland. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Ireland Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Ireland. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ireland has a comprehensive road network. Getting from A to B by road might look relatively straightforward, but it&rsquo;s always advisable to have a detailed road map or, better still, sat nav. Be aware that many signposts list place names in both Irish and English.</p>l<p>Main roads are of a high quality. Minor roads can vary in standard, with some remote stretches being potholed.</p><p>Bus Eireann (tel: 1850 836 611, in Ireland only; <a href="http://www.buseireann.ie" target="_blank">www.buseireann.ie</a>) has a comprehensive network of routes across the country.</p><p>Service is available in all cities and towns and at hotels, rail and bus stations and taxi stands. You can find metered taxis in Dublin, Cork, Galway and Limerick, but elsewhere may have to agree on a fare beforehand.</p><p>EU nationals taking cars into the Republic of Ireland should have registration documents with them as proof of ownership.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (30mph) in towns and cities, 80-100kph (50-62mph) on non-urban roads and 120kph (75mph) on motorways. Seat belts should be worn at all times.</p><p>AA Ireland (+353 1 617 9950; <a href="http://www.aaireland.ie" target="_blank">www.aaireland.ie</a>).</p><p>Car hire is available from all airports and seaports, as well as major hotels. All international hire companies are represented in Ireland, as well as local operators. Drivers must be 21 or over. A full licence from the driver's home country is required, and the driver is normally required to have had at least two years' experience.</p>
<p>It is advisable to book hire cars in advance, especially in the peak season, and a child seat should be ordered in advance also. Advise the car hire company if you're planning to drive the car into Northern   Ireland.</p><p>Ireland is generally bike-friendly and can make for a superb touring destination. You can hire bikes in most cities, and many towns, with ease.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (30mph) in towns and cities, 80-100kph (50-62mph) on non-urban roads and 120kph (75mph) on motorways. Seat belts should be worn at all times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major cities have decent, well-priced public transport networks. The emphasis is usually on buses or suburban rail. Dublin also has its own tram system.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Ireland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">shannon_airport</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Ireland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">limerick</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.10</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Ireland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kilkenny</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.45</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Ireland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cork</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.40</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier is Aer Lingus (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aerlingus.com">www.aerlingus.com</a>) but many of the low-cost airlines including easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com/" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com/" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) fly to Ireland. Airlines flying to Ireland from the USA include&nbsp;Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>).</p>
<p>As with many European destinations, flights to Ireland are generally at their most expensive during the peak holiday months (particularly high summer) and at festive periods.&nbsp;Due to the number of low-cost flights into Ireland from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> and elsewhere in Europe, it&rsquo;s worth searching as far in advance as possible for a cheap fare. It can be common for the taxes added onto a flight to exceed the base fare.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>The major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland/cork-airport">Cork Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland/dublin-airport">Dublin Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland/shannon-airport">Shannon Airport</a>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dublin">Dublin</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 1 hour 20 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 6 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is an airport development fee of &euro;10 at Ireland West Airport Knock, payable by everyone over 12 years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Dublin Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.dublinairport.com<p>Dublin Airport is located approximately 11km (6.8 miles) north of central&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dublin">Dublin</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+353 1 814 1111</p>]]><b>Shannon Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.shannonairport.ie<p>Shannon Airport is situated 24km (15 miles) northwest of Limerick and 90km (56 miles) south of Galway.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+353 61 712 000</p>]]><b>Cork Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.corkairport.com<p>Cork Airport is located 8km (5 miles) to the south of central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cork">Cork</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+353 21 431 3131</p>]]><b>Knock International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport  is 11km (7 miles) north of Claremorris (County Mayo) and receives scheduled international flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> only.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports accessible by ferry are Dublin (<a href="http://www.dublinport.ie" target="_blank">www.dublinport.ie</a>), Rosslare (<a href="http://rosslareeuroport.irishrail.ie" target="_blank">rosslareeuroport.irishrail.ie</a>), Galway (<a href="http://www.galwayharbour.com" target="_blank">www.galwayharbour.com</a>), <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cork">Cork</a> (<a href="http://www.portofcork.ie" target="_blank">www.portofcork.ie</a>) and Dun Laoghaire (<a href="http://www.dlharbour.ie" target="_blank">www.dlharbour.ie</a>). In addition to conventional ferry crossings, many ferry companies offer high-speed services as well as upgraded, state-of-the-art craft on many Irish sea routes. Fares will vary by season and promotional offers are available.</p><p>The Swansea to Cork route was stopped in 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rail links serve Ireland from key ferry ports, as well as from Northern Ireland. It usually takes just over two hours to travel from Belfast to Dublin by rail.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If travelling from the UK to Ireland or vice versa, it is possible to buy a SailRail ticket which combines the price of the train and ferry journey from any station in Britain to any in Ireland. Prices are fixed and dependent on specific routes but can be good value for money. See <a href="http://www.seat61.com/ireland">www.seat61.com/ireland</a> for details.</p>
<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are various road crossings from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/northern-ireland">Northern Ireland</a>, the most commonly used being the road between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belfast">Belfast</a> and Dublin, which south of the border becomes the M1 Motorway.</p><p>Speed limit and distance signs are in kilometres in Ireland. The same signs are quoted in miles in Northern Ireland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public payphones are still found in major towns and cities, but widespread mobile usage means these are becoming less common. Private payphones can sometimes be found in hostels, bars and internet cafes. It's advisable to use a pre-paid phone card where possible.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a broad range of international mobile phone carriers, and coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet is readily available, and internet caf&eacute;s exist in nearly every town.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national public broadcaster Radio Telefis Eireann (RTE) dominates the radio and TV sector. It provides a comprehensive service in both English and Irish. British public and private terrestrial TV acts as a rival interest.</p>
<p>The Irish print and broadcast media operate freely within the confines of the law. Broadcasting is regulated by a commission appointed by the Department of Communications. The Competition Authority safeguards against unfair competition in the press sector. Cross-media ownership is permitted within certain limits - press groups may own up to 25% of local radio and TV stations.<br />
<br />
There are several daily newspapers published in Dublin, including the <em>Irish Independent</em> and <em>The Irish Times; The Irish Examiner </em><em>is based in Cork</em>. British dailies and Sunday papers are widely available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An Post (<a href="http://www.anpost.ie" target="_blank">www.anpost.ie</a>) is the state-owned provider of postal services. It gives the option of a premium Express Post International service for mail going overseas.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1730/1800; Sat 0900-1300. Sub-post offices close at 1300 one day a week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Aran Islands</p><![CDATA[<p>The stunning Aran Islands - located approximately 48km (30 miles) out from the mouth of Galway Bay in the Atlantic Ocean - are famous for their prehistoric and Christian monuments, including the spectacular Dún Aengus fort. The islands are criss-crossed with stone walls and visitors can enjoy cliff-top walks and remote coastal scenery.</p>]]><br/><p>Bantry House</p><![CDATA[<p>Overlooking Bantry Bay in the south west of Ireland, Bantry House is a spectacular stately home that's been open to the public since 1946. Originally called Blackrock, the house was built in the 17th century as the ancestral home of the Earls of Bantry and is still lived in today by their descendants. The house was extended several times during the 18th century and gradually acquired an extensive collection of tapestries, paintings, furniture and artefacts that had been collected during their travels all over the world. Today, Bantry House consists of approximately 40 hectares (100 acres) of land of which approximately half is landscaped gardens and accessible woodland. Parts of the house can be rented out for weddings and private functions.</p>]]><br/><p>Bunratty Castle</p><![CDATA[<p>Bunratty Castle is the most complete and authentic medieval fortress in Ireland, featuring 15th and 16th century furnishings, tapestries, and artwork. A Folk Park lies in the grounds of the castle, with over 30 buildings making a 'living' village. A nightly medieval banquet enables guests to experience what it was like to be entertained in the castle's heyday.</p>]]><br/><p>Cliffs of Moher</p><![CDATA[<p>The majestic Cliffs of Moher are one of Ireland's most awe-inspiring natural attractions, towering 213m (700 ft) above the Atlantic Ocean. They've featured in everything from Harry Potter films to Westlife videos. The cliffs host a rich array of birdlife, including puffins, shags, kittiwakes and razorbills.</p>]]><br/><p>Dingle Peninsula</p><![CDATA[<p>Located on the western tip of County Kerry, the dramatic Dingle Peninsula is a popular diversion off the Ring of Kerry tourist trail. It is made up of the Macgillicuddy's Reeks mountain range, a series of granite peaks that rise out of the Atlantic. Walking, cycling and dolphin-spotting are among its most popular draws.</p>]]><br/><p>Dublin Zoo</p><![CDATA[<p>First opened in 1830 with animals supplied by London Zoo, Dublin Zoo covers a 173-hectare (70-acre) site at Phoenix Park and houses a wide variety of animals, including red panda, South American birds, Arctic fox, otter, elephants, and even a pack of grey wolves. Within the zoo is City Farm, which has a special children's corner and a flock of Galway sheep.</p>]]><br/><p>Fota Wildlife Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Located just a few miles outside Cork, Fota Wildlife Park opened in 1983 as a joint project between the Zoological Society of Ireland and the University of Cork. It's primary objective was the conservation of wildlife and today the zoo is home to over 70 species of exotic wildlife including giraffes, zebra, antelope and ostrich which are all free to roam together within the park as they would in their natural habitats in the wild. Of all the animals in the zoo, only the resident cheetahs are in conventional enclosures. The entrance ticket to Fota Wildlife Park also includes entrance to the Fota Aboretum containing a fine collection of plants and trees from around the world.</p>]]><br/><p>Glendalough</p><![CDATA[<p>Glendalough is a beautiful glacially sculpted valley in County Wicklow. During Ireland's 'Golden Age' (AD 500-900), a reclusive monk - St Kevin - established a monastic settlement here; the ruins and the valley views make for a memorable afternoon on a sunny day.</p>]]><br/><p>Killarney National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Killarney National Park covers over 10,000 hectares (25,000 acres) of woodland, lakes, mountains, parks and gardens in the far southwest of Ireland. It was Ireland's first national park and was founded in 1932. Popular sports include trout fishing in the three lakes, boating at Ross Castle, walking and cycling.  Muckross House, a Victorian mansion completed in 1843, is open to the public as is its working farm and the beautiful landscaped gardens.</p>]]><br/><p>Our Lady of Knock (Ireland’s National Marian Shrine)</p><![CDATA[<p>Located in County Mayo, the National Shrine of Our Lady of Knock marks the site where, on August 21 1879, it is said the Virgin Mary, St. Joseph and St. John the Evangelist appeared at the church's south gable. The main pilgrimage season is from the last Sunday in April until the second Sunday in October.</p>]]><br/><p>RDS Arena</p><![CDATA[<p><i>Dublin</i>'s <i>RDS</i> (<i>Royal Dublin Society</i>) <i>Irish International Convention and Exhibition Centre</i> is the country's premier venue for meetings, conferences, exhibitions, trade shows, entertainment and sporting events. The Society itself was founded in 1731 to promote the development of agriculture, arts, science and industry in Ireland. The arena measures over 20,000 sq m (215,280 sq ft) and regularly hosts the city's major events and exhibitions.</p>
<p>Address:&nbsp;Merrion Road, Ballsbridge, Dublin 4, Ireland</p>]]><br/><p>Ring of Kerry</p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the iconic Ring of Kerry, a stunning, 180km (112-mile) scenic drive around the Iveragh Peninsula. Visitors can travel in either direction (although tour buses should travel anti-clockwise) on the circular route which passes through Kenamare, Sneem, Waterville, Cahersiveen, Kells, Glenbeigh and Killorglin, with specific sights of interest in each location.</p>]]><br/><p>Rock of Cashel</p><![CDATA[<p>Sitting high on a limestone base, the Rock of Cashel (also known as the Cashel of the Kings) is one of Ireland's most spectacular castle complexes. Its origins date back to the fourth century, and King Aengus was baptised here by St Patrick, Ireland's patron saint, in the fifth century. Visitors also come to see the Hall of the Vicars Choral and the 28-metre (92-foot) Round Tower.</p>]]><br/><p>Waterford Crystal Visitor Centre</p><![CDATA[<p>Waterford is famous the world over as the home of beautiful crystal designs. The <em>Waterford Factory </em>was opened in 1783 by George and William Penrose, and bowls, vases and ornaments continue to be made on the site. The crystal mix is transformed into glass in a 1200&ordm;C (2192&ordm;F) furnace before being blown and decorated with deep engravings by skilled workers. Visitors to the centre can watch the glass being formed into decanters, bowls and wine glasses and learn about the unique production techniques used at Waterford, through audiovisual displays and chatting to the craftsmen in their workshops. Many of the most prestigious pieces of Waterford Crystal, which have been presented to celebrities and politicians, are on display in the <em>Gallery</em>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Address:&nbsp;Kilbarry, Cork Road, Waterford, Ireland</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Circle the Ring of Kerry</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the iconic Ring of Kerry, a stunning, 180km (112-mile) scenic drive around the Iveragh Peninsula. Visitors can travel in either direction (although tour buses should travel anti-clockwise) on the circular route which passes through Kenamare, Sneem, Waterville, Cahersiveen, Kells, Glenbeigh and Killorglin, with specific sights of interest in each location.</p>]]><p><b>Dilly-dally on the Dingle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located on the western tip of County Kerry, the dramatic Dingle Peninsula is a popular diversion off the Ring of Kerry tourist trail. It is made up of the Macgillicuddy's Reeks mountain range, a series of granite peaks that rise out of the Atlantic. Walking, cycling and dolphin-spotting are among its most popular draws.</p>]]><p><b>Drive the Wild Atlantic Way</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Looking for a road trip worth the name? Start the ignition in County Donegal, point the car south and keep going. The Wild Atlantic Way hugs the coastline for some 2,500 km (1,550 miles), snaking past nine counties and taking in all manner of wild bays and time-burnished villages en route.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Kilkenny</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The medieval, alley-threaded city of Kilkenny is renowned for its theatres, galleries and history-steeped buildings, most notably its bulky castle and its atmospheric Gothic cathedral. The city's pubs and nightlife are best enjoyed during one of its yearly festivals, which include the superb Cat Laughs comedy festival and the Kilkenny Arts Festival.</p>]]><p><b>Gaze up at the Rock of Cashel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sitting high on a limestone base, County Tipperary's Rock of Cashel (also known as the Cashel of the Kings) is one of Ireland's most spectacular castle complexes. Its origins date back to the 4th century, and King Aengus was baptised here by St Patrick, Ireland's patron saint, in the 5th century.</p>]]><p><b>Head out to the islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ireland's islands range from the genteel, garden-patterned Garinish in County Cork to the wild and wonderful Tory off the shores of County Donegal. The Aran Islands – reachable from Galway – are the most popular, known for their geological formation and historic monuments. Many islands are also rich in old-time culture, with a lot of locals speaking Irish as their first language.</p>]]><p><b>Kiss the Blarney Stone</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set in the Cork countryside, Blarney Castle is home to the famous Blarney Stone. Situated high in the battlements of the castle, the stone is thought to be half of the Stone of Scone. Those that kiss it are said to inherit the gift of eloquent speech – although you'll need to contort yourself upside-down to plant it with a smacker.</p>]]><p><b>Look out from the Cliffs of Moher</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The majestic Cliffs of Moher are one of Ireland's most awe-inspiring natural attractions, towering 213m (700ft) above the Atlantic Ocean. They've featured in everything from Harry Potter films to Westlife videos. The cliffs host a rich array of birdlife, including puffins, shags, kittiwakes and razorbills.</p>]]><p><b>Lose yourself in Killarney National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Killarney National Park covers over 10,000 hectares (25,000 acres) of oak woodland, lakes, mountains, parks and gardens in the far southwest of Ireland. It was Ireland's first national park when it was founded in 1932, and its population of red deer, cormorants, salmon and trout helped it to be designated a UNESCO Biosphere Reserve in 1982.</p>]]><p><b>Pay your respects to Our Lady of Knock (Ireland’s National Marian Shrine)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located in County Mayo, the National Shrine of Our Lady of Knock marks the site where, on 21 August 1879, it's said the Virgin Mary, Joseph and St. John the Evangelist all appeared to two dumbstruck young women at the church's south gable. It still attracts hordes of pilgrims.</p>]]><p><b>Raise a glass at the Guinness Storehouse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dublin's Guinness Storehouse is a brewery-turned-museum dedicated to Ireland's most famous export. Arthur Guinness first began brewing the 'black gold' on the site in 1759, with the present-day building used for fermenting and storing Guinness until the 1980s. Tours explain the brewing process and conclude with a free pint in the Gravity Bar, which offers lofty views across the city.</p>]]><p><b>Slow down at Glendalough</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Glendalough is a beautiful glacially sculpted valley in County Wicklow. During Ireland's 'Golden Age' (AD 500-900), a reclusive monk, St Kevin, established a monastic settlement here; the ruins and the forest views make for a memorable sight on a sunny day. The area's name translates, accurately enough, as 'Valley of the Two Lakes'.</p>]]><p><b>Spend time in Cork</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Grand Georgian parades, craic-filled pubs and a laidback vibe make the southern city of Cork a viable rival to Dublin for the title of Ireland's most immersive metropolis. Some locals smilingly refer to it as 'The People's Republic of Cork' and the place unquestionably has a spirit of its own, not to mention a bucket load of cultural attractions.</p>]]><p><b>Step into the past at Bunratty Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>County Clare's Bunratty Castle is the most complete medieval fortress in Ireland, featuring 15th- and 16th-century furnishings, tapestries, and artwork. A Folk Park lies in the grounds, recreating buildings including a school and post office. Regular 'medieval banquets' are held to give guests a taste of what it was like to be entertained in the castle's heyday.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Kilmainham Gaol</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get to grips with the hard edge of Irish history with a visit to Dublin's Kilmainham Gaol, where rebels against British rule were incarcerated from the late 1700s until the 1920s. Chillingly, it's also where the leaders of the 1916 Easter Rising were executed – the tour takes in the bleak yard where they were put to death.</p>]]><p><b>Walk the Wicklow Way</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Ireland on foot by walking one of the country's 31 designated long-distance paths. One of the best known is the Wicklow Way, which runs from the Dublin suburbs to County Carlow in the southeast. Other notable options include the Connemara Way &ndash; full of sweeping, silent hill scenery &ndash; and the historic Kerry Way, which makes use of old driving paths.</p>]]><p><b>Wander St Stephen’s Green</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a stroll around Dublin's most popular city square, where landscaped parklands hold everything from the WB Yeats Memorial Garden to a bust of James Joyce. Some of the city's finest hotels overlook the square, and it remains an integral part of Dublin's fabric.</p>]]><p><b>Watch traditional Gaelic sports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The thrill of a game of Gaelic football – a mix between rugby, football and American football (without pads) – is an unmissable experience.  So too is the ancient game of hurling, where players use a hurley (wooden stick) to hit a <em>sliotar</em> (small ball) into the opponents' goalposts. Both sports are vociferously followed at the top level.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$195.9 billion (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, computers, chemicals, pharmaceuticals, and animals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Data processing equipment, transport equipment, grains, textile yarns, and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK, US, Belgium, France and Germany.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not so long ago Ireland's economy was characterised as the 'Celtic Tiger', the country having transformed itself from a struggling nation into one of the most prosperous in Europe. <br />
<br />
After a long growth spurt, however, this economic boom came to a halt in 2008 as a result of the global economic downturn, suffering greatly. The property bubble was particularly inflated here. The global recession saw the Irish economy slump severely, with Ireland recently accepting an &euro;85bn bail-out from the IMF and EU in order to shore up the country&rsquo;s balance sheet. A modest return to growth was seen in 2011, but Ireland&rsquo;s woes very much continue to be felt and a stringent four-year National Recovery Plan will be in force until 2014. &nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business style is informal; first names are used and although suits are worn, jackets are often taken off. Above all, visitors should avoid treating their Irish hosts as anything other than the modern Europeans that they are. Small talk, leading to trust, is an important element, so plenty of time should be allowed to complete a deal. Irish wit is fast flowing and engaging and is evident in most business situations. Discussion of Irish political issues is best avoided. It is advisable to steer clear of business visits in the first week of May, during July, August and at Christmas or New Year.<br /><br />
In Dublin, due to traffic congestion during rush hour, breakfast meetings are growing in popularity. Lunch meetings are frequent, although meeting in a pub or bar (from around 1730 onwards) for a few beers and/or for dinner (at around 2000) is also common.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700/1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Long gone are the days when a meal in Ireland was something to be faced with trepidation. Irish produce is increasingly well regarded, with special focus given to its local meat, poultry and seafood products &ndash; Dublin Bay Prawns and Skeaganhore Duck being two specific examples.</p>
<p>The coastal waters and inland lakes and rivers offer a trove of fresh fish, including salmon, trout, lobster, mussels, periwinkles and, of course, oysters &ndash; a foodstuff Guinness could almost have been created to accompany.</p>
<p>Local ingredients are at the heart of the culinary boom which has taken hold of Ireland in the last decade or so. Those in search of genuinely good food won&rsquo;t have to search too far to be well rewarded &ndash; Dublin in particular has a significant number of Michelin stars.</p>
<p>Cookery schools have sprung up around the country, offering classes all year round, ranging from professional training to smaller, informal courses run by enthusiastic chefs in rural restaurants. Soda bread, Dublin coddle (pork stew) and Irish stew are among the dishes that can be perfected.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dublin Bay prawns:</strong> Otherwise known as langoustines. <br />
<strong>Oysters:</strong> Usually served with soda bread, and accompanied by Guinness.<br />
<strong>Irish stew:</strong> Now mostly made with lamb or juicy beef, and usually served with potatoes, stock, onions, carrots and garlic.<br />
<strong>Crubeens:</strong> Pigs' trotters, typically battered.<br />
<strong>Colcannon:</strong> A mixture of mashed potatoes and cabbage cooked together.<br />
<strong>Wild salmon:</strong> Look out for it on menus from April to June.<br />
<strong>White pudding:</strong> Similar to black pudding, and a common component of full Irish breakfasts.<br />
<strong>Dublin coddle:</strong> A leftover dish, commonly with sausage, bacon, potato and onion.<br />
<strong>Guinness:</strong> The stout is omnipresent across most of the country.<br />
<strong>Irish coffee:</strong> Strong black coffee, brown sugar and whiskey with cream.<br />
<strong>Whiskey:</strong> Popular brands include Jameson, John Powers Gold Label, Hewitts, Midleton, Old Bushmills, Paddy, Reserve and Tullamore Dew.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>The customary tip in Ireland is 10-12%. Many hotels and restaurants add this in the form of a service charge indicated on the menu or bill. It is not customary to tip in bars unless you have table service.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18, although some bars will insist that patrons are over 21 and carry ID.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most towns in Ireland have clubs, bars and pubs with live music. It is still reasonably common to find pubs holding a <em>seis&uacute;n</em> (a live session of traditional Irish music) &ndash; if you hit the right pub on the right night, the experience can be a hugely enjoyable one. Despite the informal, improvised nature of the music, the sessions themselves are usually scheduled, so ask around wherever you happen to be staying. They take place in villages, towns and cities, and usually last several hours.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>For those after some electronic entertainment, the dancehalls and discos of previous eras have now been replaced with clubs similar to those found throughout the UK and western Europe. Special events and themed nights often take place at large attractions such as the medieval banquet at Bunratty Castle in the Shannon region, and there&rsquo;s a good choice of theatres and cinemas.</p>
<p>Ireland is also a rewarding place for gig-goers. Cities like Dublin and Cork attract more than their fair share of touring and home-grown bands. Check websites like <a href="http://www.totallydublin.ie" target="_blank">www.totallydublin.ie</a> and <a href="http://www.corkgigs.ie" target="_blank">www.corkgigs.ie</a> for listings.</p>
<p>On a more basic note, the best of Ireland&rsquo;s pubs remain quite wonderful places to while away an evening over a pint or five. Where there are stone floors, peat fires and pints of the black stuff, there are good times to be had.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ireland does souvenirs well. Special purchases include hand-woven tweed, hand-crocheted woollens and cottons, sheepskin goods, gold and silver jewellery, Aran knitwear, linen, pottery, Irish crystal and basketry.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;ll find no shortage of rather less classy knick-knacks too, particularly in the heavily touristed areas. If you want nothing more than to fill your luggage with leprechaun hats, inflatable shamrocks and poor-quality U2 T-shirts, there&rsquo;ll be opportunity aplenty.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Slightly more meaningful gifts might include a copy of James Joyce&rsquo;s <em>Ulysses</em> from an Irish bookshop, a bottle of Jameson or Bushmills whiskey from their home distilleries, or Irish salmon.</p>
<p>In more general shopping terms, Ireland has a lot to offer. Pre-credit crunch, Dublin&rsquo;s Henry Street was said to be the busiest shopping street in Europe, and the capital is still a great place to hunt around for fashion items and one-off crafts. Yes, there are familiar global chain stores throughout the centre, but you&rsquo;ll also uncover some superb independent shops selling high-quality locally sourced goods.</p>
<p>Cork and Galway, too, are further examples of cities with strong shopping potential. There&rsquo;s an arty spirit in a great number of Ireland&rsquo;s larger settlements, in fact, which usually translates into at least a handful of specialist outlets, whether focused on music, antiques or leisurewear.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1730/1800. Many towns have a late night opening on Thursday or Friday until 2000/2100 and smaller towns may have one early closing day a week. On Sunday, main shopping centres and some of the larger department stores open 1200-1700/1800. Many smaller supermarkets in towns and villages also open.</p><p>Under the 'Retail Export Scheme', it is possible to claim VAT back on some goods bought in Ireland on leaving the EU. For further information, contact the VAT Interpretation Branch, Stamping Building, Dublin Castle, Dublin 2 (tel: (1) 674 8858; <a href="http://www.revenue.ie/" target="_blank">www.revenue.ie</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ireland is home to a dizzying range of different accommodation options, with centres like Dublin able to offer everything from the most idiosyncratic guest-house to the glitziest pleasure palace. In short, there&rsquo;s generally something for all budgets. Around 850 hotels are inspected, approved and graded by F&aacute;ilte Ireland, the Irish Tourist Board  (<a href="http://www.failteireland.ie" target="_blank">www.failteireland.ie</a>). Since the start of the economic crisis, however, it&rsquo;s often been possible to find some impressive deals, particularly if you shop around well in advance. </p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> F&aacute;ilte Ireland registers and grades hotels from 5-star (highest) to 1-star (lowest).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost 300 guest houses, not to mention a huge number of  other B&Bs, are registered and inspected by Fáilte Ireland, from 4-star (very high standard) to 1-star (clean and comfortable), and ranging from converted country houses to purpose-built accommodation. Meals can be from bed and breakfast to full board.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ireland is home to a dizzying range of different accommodation options, with centres like Dublin able to offer everything from the most idiosyncratic guest-house to the glitziest pleasure palace. In short, there&rsquo;s generally something for all budgets. Around 850 hotels are inspected, approved and graded by F&aacute;ilte Ireland, the Irish Tourist Board  (<a href="http://www.failteireland.ie" target="_blank">www.failteireland.ie</a>). Since the start of the economic crisis, however, it&rsquo;s often been possible to find some impressive deals, particularly if you shop around well in advance. </p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> F&aacute;ilte Ireland registers and grades hotels from 5-star (highest) to 1-star (lowest).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ireland is home to a dizzying range of different accommodation options, with centres like Dublin able to offer everything from the most idiosyncratic guest-house to the glitziest pleasure palace. In short, there&rsquo;s generally something for all budgets. Around 850 hotels are inspected, approved and graded by F&aacute;ilte Ireland, the Irish Tourist Board  (<a href="http://www.failteireland.ie" target="_blank">www.failteireland.ie</a>). Since the start of the economic crisis, however, it&rsquo;s often been possible to find some impressive deals, particularly if you shop around well in advance. </p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> F&aacute;ilte Ireland registers and grades hotels from 5-star (highest) to 1-star (lowest).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical and dental facilities are of a high standard across the country. For minor illnesses and ailments, pharmacists are trained to offer advice and sell over-the-counter medication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If suddenly taken ill or involved in an accident during a visit to Ireland, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available for European travellers - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). Comprehensive insurance is advised for all other nationals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a pre-existing illness, it&amp;rsquo;s sensible to carry a signed letter from your home doctor with details of your condition.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Levels of hygiene are of a high standard in Ireland, so travellers should only take precautions that they would do in any other developed country. There&amp;rsquo;s no more danger of being served contaminated or undercooked food in Ireland than anywhere else. A statutory, independent, science-based body, the Food Safety Authority of Ireland, is tasked &amp;ldquo;to take all reasonable steps to ensure that food produced, distributed or marketed in the State meets the highest standards of food safety and hygiene reasonably available.&amp;rdquo; The only real problems posed by the local food and drink are mild stomach complaints resulting from overindulgence. As in any other country, junk food and fast food isn&amp;rsquo;t hard to come by. An over-reliance on fish and chips or the omnipresent &amp;ldquo;fry&amp;rdquo; (heaped breakfasts of bacon, fried eggs, black pudding, white pudding and so on) isn&amp;rsquo;t recommended. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tap water is generally fine to drink, although stories in recent years have suggested that in some areas the levels of fluoride might be risky, particularly to bottle-fed babies. Bottled water is readily available.  And while it might be novel to be sampling Guinness in its home country, being in Ireland by no means makes you immune from crippling hangovers and related after-effects.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Ireland is not a risky destination in which to travel. A lack of temperature extremes means that sunstroke is rarely a problem, although you should be aware that summer temperatures can occasionally reach well over 25&amp;deg;C. In these cases, the usual precautions apply: use a generous amount of sunscreen and be sensible about how long you spend in direct sunlight. Be aware that a breezy day can sometimes mask high temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hikers or cyclists travelling over long distances are perhaps the most at risk from the weather, good or bad. In warm weather it&amp;rsquo;s advisable to drink &amp;ndash; and carry &amp;ndash; plenty of water and wear appropriate clothing, including headwear. In bad weather, have waterproof clothing to hand and, if possible, inform others where you&amp;rsquo;re intending to travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blisters can be another problem for hikers. These can often occur if new walking shoes are being worn across a long distance. Ideally footwear should be worn in before the trip.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>St Patrick's Day :
							18 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Bank Holiday :
							07 May </p><p>Bank Holiday :
							04 June </p><p>Bank Holiday :
							06 August </p><p>Bank Holiday :
							29 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>St Stephen's Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ireland is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragrance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% volume, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>However, you can only import up to 300 cigarettes from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia">Croatia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hungary">Hungary</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/latvia">Latvia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lithuania">Lithuania</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/romania">Romania</a>. There is no limit on other tobacco products from these countries, provided they are for your own personal use.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Ireland by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 (reduced to &euro;215 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drugs, indecent or obscene goods, and certain foodstuffs. In addition, if arriving from outside the EU, you cannot import plants or bulbs, live or dead animals, poultry, birds or eggs, hay or straw, and meat and dairy products.</p>
<p>To import firearms and ammunition, fireworks and explosives, or domestic pets, you must obtain a licence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a> symbol €) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of €500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of €2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in banks, airports and bureaux de change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard and Visa are all widely accepted. ATMs are available everywhere, catering for Cirrus and Maestro symbols.</p><p>ATMs are available everywhere, catering for Cirrus and Maestro symbols.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted throughout Ireland. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros, Pounds Sterling or US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1630. In <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ireland/dublin-airport">Dublin</a>, banks stay open Thurs until 1700; there are also late opening nights in other parts of the country, but the day will vary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>2</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Ireland, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by the nationals referred to in the chart above, except:</p>
<p><strong>1.</strong>&nbsp;UK nationals&nbsp;travelling direct from the UK.</p>
<p><strong>2.</strong> EU nationals holding a valid national ID card. EU nationals are only required to produce evidence of their EU nationality and identity in order to be admitted to any EU member state. This evidence can take the form of a valid national passport&nbsp;or&nbsp;national identity card.</p>
<p>Ireland is classed as part of the Common Travel Area of the UK, which is why UK nationals don&rsquo;t need to take a passport. It remains advisable to take one though, and airlines and ferry companies nearly always require some form of photographic ID. It&rsquo;s a good idea to check with the individual company prior to a trip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If visas are needed, a form must be filled out for each individual applicant, including children under 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas are required by some nationals; check with the embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ireland is not part of the Schengen area and Schengen visas are not valid.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: &euro;25; single-journey visa: &euro;60; multiple-journey visa: &euro;100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-journey visas: up to three months. Multiple-journey visas are usually only issued to visitors who have previously held two Irish visas and have observed the conditions of these visas. The validity is longer, but they are only intended for short trips and cannot be used for back-to-back trips of 90 days each.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All applications for Irish visas must be made initially using the online Visa Application System (AVATS) at <a target="_blank" href="http://www.visas.inis.gov.ie">www.visas.inis.gov.ie</a>. On completion of the online form, applicants are then advised where to submit their application, which will either be the Irish Embassy or Consulate in their home country, or directly to the Irish Naturalisation and Immigration Service in Dublin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Processing times vary according to individual applications. Visa applications submitted in person to the Irish Embassy in the UK take around seven working days to process. Postal applications usually take around 15 working days, but can take up to six weeks during busy periods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visa applicants are expected to show bank statements to prove they have sufficient funds for the duration of their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Non-EEA nationals wishing to stay in Ireland for longer than three months have to register with the Garda National Immigration Bureau. There is a fee of &euro;300 to register.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets entering Ireland from within the EU require a passport or certificate showing the pet&rsquo;s ID, a subsequent rabies vaccination with the first vaccination at least 21 days prior to entry, and (for dogs) specific tapeworm treatment. Those pets coming from outside the EU are designated either high-risk or low-risk, depending on which country they arrive from. Both require the pet to have detailed proof of ID and good health. Check <a target="_blank" href="http://www.agriculture.gov.ie">www.agriculture.gov.ie</a> for further information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[53.183021]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-8.198990]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>70,182 sq km (27,097 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,713,993 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>69.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dublin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Republic of Ireland lies in the north Atlantic Ocean and is separated from Britain by the Irish Sea to the west. The northeastern part of the island (Northern  Ireland) is part of the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>There are four provinces: Leinster, which covers the eastern portion of the country around Dublin; Munster, which covers the south; Connacht, which covers the west of Ireland; and Ulster, which is predominantly in Northern Ireland but also covers the northern tip of the Republic.</p>
<p>Ireland has a central plain surrounded by a rim of mountains and hills offering some of the most varied and unspoilt scenery in Europe. Inland you&rsquo;ll find bogs, moors, forests, lakes, mountains and wetlands. Quiet sandy beaches, semi-tropical bays warmed by the Gulf Stream, and rugged cliffs make up the 5,600km (3,500 miles) of coastline.</p>
<p>For those who really want to make the most of the coastal scenery (and are keen to see a bit of Northern Ireland too), a full loop of the island &ndash; sticking close to the sea at all times &ndash; can be done with ease in a couple of weeks.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Together, the landscape and the offshore waters provide a good habitat for a wide variety of wildlife. Seals and dolphins are spotted regularly, while the Cork coast even offers the chance to whale-watch over the summer months.</p>
<p>There are numerous rivers in Ireland, the longest of which &ndash; the River Shannon, at 360 km (224 miles) in length &ndash; is also seen as one of the country&rsquo;s most picturesque. Other notable waterways include the River Liffey, which flows from the Wicklow Mountains to the Irish Sea, through the centre of Dublin.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic 84%, the remainder being Protestant, with Jewish and Islamic minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Irish are renowned as an affable, easy-going people, whose conversation is liberally dosed with humour, irreverence and - if you listen carefully - a <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a><em>beal bocht</em>, an Irish expression that translates as 'the poor mouth'. It refers to a kind of modesty where the speaker is careful to talk themselves down and never reveal how well he or she is actually doing. In short, the Irish don't really like a show-off.</p>
<p>Arguably the best place to observe and engage with the Irish is in the pub, still a centre of social interaction in Ireland, especially in smaller communities throughout the country. A meal in an Irish home is usually a substantial affair and guests will eat well. Dinner is the main meal of the day and is now eaten in the evening. Casual dress is widely acceptable, but people will often dress up for smart restaurants and social functions. Handshaking is usual, and modes of address will often be informal. Smoking is banned in all public enclosed/working spaces, including pubs, bars and restaurants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>(Prime Minister) Leo Varadkar since June 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Michael D Higgins since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An unswerving commitment to Catholicism on the part of the majority, and the frequent uncertainty and instability governing Anglo-Irish relations, are key features of Irish history.</p>
<p>It was a war between Irish chieftains and the Vikings which first led to English involvement. In 1169-70, Richard of Clare, Earl of Pembroke (nicknamed Strongbow), was invited over by an Irish chieftain to help protect his interests. Instead, Strongbow conquered almost the entire country with only a tiny force of archers and mounted knights.</p>
<p>Many Norman families subsequently moved across the Irish Sea, effectively colonising the country. Thus followed the notorious &lsquo;800 years&rsquo; of English rule. Repeated and largely unsuccessful efforts from the 14th century onwards were made to bring the island under Irish control.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s turbulent political life then took a new twist after the English Civil War, when the Irish rose in favour of the deposed monarchy in 1649. The victorious Oliver Cromwell led an army across the Irish Sea and ruthlessly quashed the rebellion.</p>
<p>The Act of Union in 1801 incorporated England, Scotland, Wales, and the whole of Ireland into the United Kingdom. However, the grossly inadequate response of the government to the potato famine of 1845 and 1846 highlighted its lack of interest in the welfare of the Irish people, and, after prolonged uprisings, Irish Home Rule was granted in 1920. The terms of independence stipulated that Ireland be partitioned into two parts.</p>
<p>In the northern provinces, where most Protestants had settled three centuries earlier, there was fierce opposition to the prospect of being ruled by a Catholic majority. Six of the nine counties of the historic province of Ulster therefore remained in the United Kingdom, and the other 26 counties became the Irish Free State.</p>
<p>The ensuing civil war in the south between supporters and opponents of the agreement gave rise to the country's two main political parties, Fianna F&aacute;il and Fine Gael. In 1937, the Irish Free State was given full sovereignty within the Commonwealth. In 1949, the 26 counties became a republic. Since the 1970s, Ireland has been governed alternately by Fianna F&aacute;il and a coalition of Fine Gael and the smaller Labour Party.</p>
<p>Recent political agenda has been dominated by the challenge to the orthodox morality of the Catholic Church, especially on the contentious issues of abortion and divorce. A milestone was marked in 2015 when Ireland became the first country in the world to legalise gay marriage by popular vote.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The Aran Islands still host an annual <em>Father Ted</em> festival. <br />
&bull;	The longest place name in the country is claimed by County Galway&rsquo;s Muckanaghederdauhaulia.<br />
&bull;	Arthur Guinness signed a 9,000-year lease for the St James&rsquo; Gate brewery in 1759.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Ireland in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 462 3939</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofireland.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 462 3939</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300, 1400-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2234 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Ireland]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(1) 205 3700</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.britishembassyinireland.fco.gov.uk/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(1) 205 3700</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700. (Public counters for visa enquiries, by appointment only, are 0900-1230 and 1330-1530; passport office opening hours are Tues and Thurs 0900-1230 and 1400-1600).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Ballsbridge<br/>29 Merrion Road<br/>Dublin<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Ireland in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 2171 (embassy); (020) 7373 4339 (passport office)</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofireland.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 2171 (embassy); (020) 7373 4339 (passport office)</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1700 (0930-1200 for visa lodge applications; 1430-1600 for visa collections; 0930-1630 for passport section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>17 Grosvenor Place<br/>London<br/>SW1X 7HR<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ireland is one of the globe&rsquo;s most singular travel destinations, a feisty, twinkling country far more famous for the sum of its parts than for any specific sight or attraction. Its landscapes are raw, its cities are animated and its history holds endless tales of adversity. Tying all this together is the Irish character, a fabled combination of bright-eyed bonhomie and bar-room banter: there&rsquo;s good reason why the planet&rsquo;s full of Irish pubs.</p>
<p>Lovable Dublin falls naturally as the most popular option for first-time visitors, although for all the capital city&rsquo;s stately architecture and riverside charm, it only partly hints at what the wider country has to offer. The real spirit of today&rsquo;s nation might be up for debate &ndash; it&rsquo;s as likely to be found in a Connemara village as a Cork street scene &ndash; but searching for it is hugely enjoyable.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s often said that there are two Irelands. Despite its economic woes, 21st-century Ireland is a modern destination, full of fresh creativity. At the same time, of course, it&rsquo;s somewhere rooted in the strongest of traditions, a country marked by humour, hospitality and more than the occasional late night. The craic of legend isn&rsquo;t generally hard to find.  </p>
<p>With all this in mind, it&rsquo;s perhaps no surprise that Ireland caters for such a broad range of interests. Those in search of windswept hikes, Celtic relics and fiddle-and-song pubs will be well sated, but so too will those looking for on-trend gastronomy, family-friendly attractions or slick hotels. The country may be small but its cultural impact worldwide continues to be enormous, and this is due to far more than just a romantic notion of how it used to be.</p>
<p>Various icons and images enjoy close associations with Ireland (see everything from craggy peninsulas to pints of Guinness) but the real beauty of the country is the fact that it transcends every clich&eacute; that people throw at it. Its potential for adventure &ndash; for real, blood-pumping adventure &ndash; is all too often overlooked, while for those who just want to take it easy, the options are copious.</p><p>Ireland is one of the globe&rsquo;s most singular travel destinations, a feisty, twinkling country far more famous for the sum of its parts than for any specific sight or attraction. Its landscapes are raw, its cities are animated and its history holds endless tales of adversity. Tying all this together is the Irish character, a fabled combination of bright-eyed bonhomie and bar-room banter: there&rsquo;s good reason why the planet&rsquo;s full of Irish pubs.<br />
Lovable Dublin falls naturally as the most popular option for first-time visitors, although for all the capital city&rsquo;s stately architecture and riverside charm, it only partly hints at what the wider country has to offer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
