<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Israel" ColCode="isr" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="il" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Israel]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israel generally has two seasons &mdash; summer (Apr-Sep) and winter (Oct-Mar). Israel shows a typical Mediterranean climate. Summers can be very hot, especially in the south. The Red Sea resort of Eilat has a good climate for beach holidays all year round.<br />
Winters in Israel can be cool, with temperatures being between 17-22&ordm;C (63-72&ordm;F) on average during the day and 10-15&ordm;C (50-59&ordm;F) at night. Occasional light rain in winter is possible, particularly in Jerusalem, though recent years have seen insufficient rain. Snow is rare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothes for warmer months are required. Medium weights are recommended for winters, although on the Red Sea coast they are unlikely to be necessary during the day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Domestic flights focus on routes linking Eilat to Tel Aviv and Haifa. Arkia (<a href="http://www.arkia.co.il" target="_blank">www.arkia.co.il</a>), Israir (<a href="http://www.israir.co.il" target="_blank">www.israir.co.il</a>) operate regular flights between these cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Boat tours operated by Kinneret Sailing Company (tel: +972 4 665 9800) run across the Sea of Galilee from Tiberias to Kibbutz Ein Gev.<br />
A tourist ferry operated by Acre Queen Cruises runs daily between Haifa and Acre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israel Railways (<a href="http://www.rail.co.il" target="_blank">www.rail.co.il</a>) has several lines running from Nahariya in the north, along the Mediterranean coast past Acre, Haifa, Netanya and Herzliya to Tel Aviv. From there it is possible to continue to the airport, or change to Jerusalem.  From Tel Aviv lines continue south to Ashkelon and Beersheba. You can buy tickets from station kiosks or ticket machines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Israel has an excellent road network, although congestion is a problem in urban areas. Navigating is easy with road signs in Hebrew, Arabic and English.</p><p>Buses are the top mode of transport in Israel and offer reliable, comfortable services. The main long-distance bus company is Egged (<a href="http://www.egged.co.il" target="_blank">www.egged.co.il</a>), and there are regional companies serving urban areas such as Dan (<a href="http://www.dan.co.il" target="_blank">www.dan.co.il</a>) in Tel Aviv. However, services to rural areas are sparse.</p>
<p>You can buy intra-city bus tickets at bus stations or from the driver. Long-distance bus tickets are available from Egged&rsquo;s website or at bus stations. While most don&rsquo;t need to be booked in advance, services to Eilat get booked up during the summer months.</p><p>Taxis are metered, and can be booked by phone or hailed from the street. Taxis operate during Shabbat, but are more expensive. Another type of taxi is the &lsquo;<em>sherut</em>&rsquo; (shared taxis). These minibuses follow the routes of the bus lines but can be hailed from anywhere.</p><p>Full driving licence and insurance are required.</p><p>The speed limit is 90-120kph (60-75mph) on motorways, 80kph (50mph) on intercity roads and 50kph (31mph) within towns. It is illegal to drive without a seatbelt and hands-free kits must be used for talking on mobile phones.</p><p>In case of breakdown contact your car rental service.</p><p>Most major car hire companies are represented in Israel as well as several local companies, notably Eldan (<a href="http://www.eldan.co.il" target="_blank">www.eldan.co.il</a>). To rent a car, drivers must be at least 21 and hold an international driving licence and credit card.</p><p>There are many places, both in rural areas and cities, where you can rent bicycles. There are plenty of cycle paths including the National Bicycle Trail that traverses the country.</p><p>The speed limit is 90-120kph (60-75mph) on motorways, 80kph (50mph) on intercity roads and 50kph (31mph) within towns. It is illegal to drive without a seatbelt and hands-free kits must be used for talking on mobile phones.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Egged bus company (<a href="http://www.egged.co.il" target="_blank">www.egged.co.il</a>) provides frequent local services in all the main towns except the Tel Aviv area, where Dan (tel: +972 3 639 4444; <a href="http://www.dan.co.il" target="_blank">www.dan.co.il</a>) runs the city's transportation system. Taxis are widely available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Israel</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">jerusalem</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Israel</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">haifa</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Israel</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">eilat</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is El Al (<a href="http://www.elal.com" target="_blank">www.elal.com</a>), but other Israeli airlines include Arkia (<a href="http://www.arkia.com/" target="_blank">www.arkia.com</a>) and Israir (<a href="http://www.israir.co.il" target="_blank">www.israir.co.il</a>). Major airlines link Tel Aviv&rsquo;s International Airport to many world cities. Aside from El Al, airlines operating direct flights from the UK to Israel include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>). Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) fly direct from the USA.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/israel/tel-aviv-ben-gurion-international-airport">Tel Aviv Ben Gurion International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tel-aviv"> Tel Aviv</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 4 hours 45 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 10 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>El Al does not offer flights departing or arriving in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tel-aviv">Tel Aviv</a> during Shabbat (Friday evening and Saturday).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the price of an airline ticket. An exit fee is charged at road border crossings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>El Al does not offer flights departing or arriving in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tel-aviv">Tel Aviv</a> during Shabbat (Friday evening and Saturday).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Tel Aviv Ben Gurion International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.iaa.gov.il<p>Tel Aviv Ben Gurion International Airport is located 20km (12 miles) southeast of Tel Aviv and 50km (31 miles) west of Jerusalem.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+972 3 975 2386.</p>]]><b>Eilat Central Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.iaa.gov.il<p>The airport is in the centre of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israel&rsquo;s maritime passenger industry is rather limited. Private vessels arriving in Israel can use one of many marinas, the largest being Haifa and Ashdod. Others include Eilat, Ashkelon, Herzliya and Tel Aviv.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite having borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/syrian-arab-republic">Syria</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lebanon">Lebanon</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jordan">Jordan</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/egypt">Egypt</a> and the Palestinian Territories of Gaza and the West Bank, it is only possible to cross into Israel from Jordan, Egypt and the West Bank.&nbsp;Crossing overland into Israel from Jordan and Egypt is fairly straightforward.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Egypt: Israel and Egypt have a border crossing linking Eilat with Taba, Egypt. Please note that the Taba border crossing is occasionally closed.</p>
<p>Jordan: Jordan and Israel share three border crossings &ndash; the Yitzhak Rabin/Wadi Araba Border Crossing near Eilat, the Allenby Border Crossing/King Hussein Bridge near&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jerusalem">Jerusalem</a> and the Jordan River Crossing/ Sheikh Hussein Bridge in the Galilee.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For more information and operating hours of Israel&rsquo;s border crossings, visit <a href="http://www.iaa.gov.il/en-US/borders/Pages/default.aspx" target="_blank">www.iaa.gov.il/en-US/borders/</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>All hotels offer direct dial phones, but these can be pricey. Calling cards can be bought from newsagents and used in phone booths, or newsagent coin-operated phones. The international dialling code for Israel is +972.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile phone connections are excellent, even in rural areas, and roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. It is possible to rent mobile phones or SIM cards in the Tel Aviv airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet is widely available and Wi-Fi is commonly found in caf&eacute;s and hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israel has vibrant and exceptionally diverse media, produced in Hebrew, Arabic, English and Russian, expressing all viewpoints and spanning the entire political spectrum. All publications are privately owned, and there is no state interference with editorial. News in English is broadcast on radio and TV several times daily. The main daily newspapers are <em>Ha'aretz</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.haaretzdaily.com">www.haaretzdaily.com</a>), <em>Ma'ariv</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nrg.co.il">www.nrg.co.il</a>) and <em>Yedioth Aharonoth</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ynetnews.com">www.ynetnews.com</a>). The main English-language daily is the <em>Jerusalem Post</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.jpost.com">www.jpost.com</a>).<br />
<br />
Most Israeli households subscribe to cable or satellite TV, with a big package of foreign news networks, including Sky, BBC World, CNN and Al-Jazeera. The Israel Broadcasting Authority operates public TV Channel 1, and there are several commercial terrestrial channels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post office branches can be widely found throughout the country. Postal services include registered mail, express, EMS and poste restante. FEDEX and DHL are also represented. Airmail to Europe or the US takes up to one week.</p><p>May vary but are generally Sun-Tues and Thurs 0800-1200 and 1530-1830, Wed 0800-1330 and Fri 0800-1200. All post offices are closed on <em>Shabbat</em> (Saturday) and holy days, although central telegraph offices are open throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Dead Sea</p><![CDATA[<p>Lying 400m (1320ft) below sea level and spanning the border between Israel and Jordan, the Dead Sea is a natural wonder. It contains more minerals and salt than any other stretch of water in the world, and thus it is possible to float on top of the water. Its natural properties make it a prime centre for spa treatments and relaxation therapies and there are a number of resorts in the area. The Dead Sea has strong Biblical connections: here the Dead Sea Scrolls, the oldest Biblical documents known to be in existence, were discovered at Qumran were found and King Herod built his palace of Masada.</p>]]><br/><p>Masada</p><![CDATA[<p>The cliff-top palace of Masada was built by King Herod and offers breathtaking views of the Dead Sea and Negev Desert. It also holds an important place in the history books and hearts of Jews as the last remaining Jewish stronghold in of the Roman-controlled land.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Baha’i Shrine and German Colony, Haifa </b></p><![CDATA[<p>Taking pride of place in the heart of Israel&rsquo;s third largest city are the Baha&rsquo;i Shrine and German Colony. The golden-topped Baha&rsquo;i Shrine of the Bab, founder of the Baha&rsquo;i Faith, stands atop an iconic hill that overlooks Haifa and is adorned by the perfectly manicured Persian Gardens. At the hill&rsquo;s foot, you&rsquo;ll find the German Colony, the beautifully restored cultural centre of the city.</p>]]><p><b>Beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With four coasts to choose from, Israel has an impressive variety of beaches. Sandy beaches line the Mediterranean Coast, notably Tel Aviv and north of Netanya, while the Red Sea offers access to colourful coral reefs. The Sea of Galilee&rsquo;s beaches are ideal for picnics and the Dead Sea offers a unique and restorative experience.</p>]]><p><b>Coral reefs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The waters off Eilat are rich in coral and perfect for some underwater sightseeing. Scuba or snorkel on underwater trails, take a submarine tour, or just marvel at the scene through the windows of the Eilat's amazing Underwater Observatory.</p>]]><p><b>Dead Sea</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lying 400m (1320ft) below sea level and spanning the border between Israel and Jordan, the Dead Sea is a natural wonder. It contains more minerals and salt than any other stretch of water in the world, and thus it is possible to float on top of the water. Its natural properties make it a prime centre for spa treatments and relaxation therapies and there are a number of resorts in the area. The Dead Sea has strong Biblical connections: here is where the Dead Sea Scrolls, the oldest known Biblical documents, were discovered, and where King Herod built his palace of Masada.</p>]]><p><b>Desert tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A trip into the Negev desert is a must-do. There are tours by jeep, on foot, or on horseback from the desert town of Mitzpe Ramon and from the Red Sea resort of Eilat.</p>]]><p><b>Dome of the Rock</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The intricately beautiful Dome of the Rock stands high on Temple Mount (<em>Har HaBayit</em> in Hebrew, <em>Haram esh-Sharif</em> in Arabic) in Jerusalem and is spiritually significant for both Jews and Muslims.</p>]]><p><b>Hezekiah's Tunnel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The spooky Hezekiah's Tunnel (<a href="http://www.cityofdavid.org" target="_blank">www.cityofdavid.org</a>), a 500m (1,649ft) underground passage, looks like the perfect set for an Indiana Jones film. The tunnel serves to bring spring water to the Pool of Siloam, mentioned in the Bible as the place where Jesus healed a blind man. You'll need shorts, sandals and a strong flashlight.</p>]]><p><b>Israel Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Israel Museum in Jerusalem (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.imj.org.il/">www.imj.org.il</a>) houses the country's principal collection of impressive archaeological discoveries and ancient art. These include the Dead Sea Scrolls, which are displayed in a grand wing known as the Shrine of the Book. A trip to the museum will open your eyes to Israel&rsquo;s long and complex history.</p>]]><p><b>Jerusalem Archaeological Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The newly reconstructed Hulda Steps, once the main entrance to the Temple, are in the Jerusalem Archaeological Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.archpark.org.il/">www.archpark.org.il</a>), a few paces from Western Wall Plaza. Its Davidson Center includes a virtual reconstruction of a visit to the Temple 2,000 years ago. Experience Christianity at its most profound, at the Church of the Holy Sepulchre, traditionally believed to be the site of the Crucifixion. A complex of different shrines, it is the heart of the Christian Quarter.</p>]]><p><b>Jerusalem's Old City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Jerusalem's Old City is a living museum of religious buildings and historical intrigue. Be sure to visit the Christian Church of the Holy Sepulchre, the Jewish Western Wall and the Islamic Dome of the Rock - some of the world&rsquo;s most significant buildings. Explore the bustling markets and narrow lanes of the four Old City Quarters.</p>]]><p><b>Kibbutz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>These intriguing collective settlements can be found all over Israel and many offer accommodation facilities for tourists. They give great insight into the local kibbutz life and are unique to the country. Several kibbutzim offer workshops or, as with Israel&rsquo;s first kibbutz, Degania Alef, a small museum.</p>]]><p><b>Markets</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Exploring the traditional markets is a definite highlight of a trip to Israel. Fling yourself into Tel Aviv's Carmel Market, brimming with spices and fresh produce; try the traditional dishes in the Mahane Yehuda food market in Jerusalem; or haggle for anything from souvenirs to jewellery along the narrow streets of Jerusalem&rsquo;s Old City.</p>]]><p><b>Masada</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The cliff-top palace of Masada was built by King Herod and offers breathtaking views of the Dead Sea and Negev Desert. It also holds an important place in the history books and hearts of Jews as the last remaining Jewish stronghold when the Romans controlled the land.</p>]]><p><b>Mea She'arim</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Jerusalem's Mea She'arim district is home to Israel's largest community of strictly observant Orthodox Jews who keep all their East European dress and traditions alive. Go there for a stroll and it'll feel like you're in pre-war Europe.</p>]]><p><b>Mount of Olives, Jerusalem </b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dominated by church spires and the white tombs of the Jewish cemetery is the Mount of Olives. Christianity, Judaism, and Islam meet once again where significant events of each religion&rsquo;s past played out. The Garden of Gethsemane, Dome of the Ascension, and Tomb of the Virgin Mary are top pilgrimage sites.</p>]]><p><b>Museum of the Jewish Diaspora</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Music, textiles, reconstructions and film footage at the Museum of the Jewish Diaspora (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.bh.org.il/">www.bh.org.il</a>) convey the cultural diversity of the Jewish people during the 2,000 years of worldwide diaspora. Have fun while learning about Israel's kaleidoscope of history at the fascinating seafront ruins of Caesarea (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.caesarea.org.il/">www.caesarea.org.il</a>), once a great Roman city, with later Byzantine and Crusader sections. Wander marked paths or visit the Caesarea Experience multimedia presentation.</p>]]><p><b>National parks and reserves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Israel&rsquo;s historic treasures and breathtaking landscapes are protected in over 70 national parks and nature reserves (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.parks.org.il/">www.parks.org.il</a>). Remains of once grand cities such as Bet She&rsquo;an and Caesarea are true archaeological highlights, while the Ein Gedi and Yehudiya nature reserves offer natural beauty and opportunities for hiking.</p>]]><p><b>Nazareth </b></p><![CDATA[<p>Known as Jesus&rsquo; childhood home and the scene of Mary&rsquo;s annunciation, Nazareth attracts scores of pilgrims from around the world. In this predominantly Arab Christian city, where tiny, cobbled lanes weave between churches, mosques and a busy souk, you&rsquo;ll find the grand Basilica of the Annunciation looming proud.</p>]]><p><b>Old City of Acre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Acre&rsquo;s Old City is a jumble of buildings dotted by minarets and church spires, and encompassed by a great citadel and imposing walls. Crusaders, Ottomans, Napoleon, the British Mandate authorities and Jewish freedom fighters combine to form a colourful past, while today Acre is a lively Arab city, with a bustling market and quaint fishing port.</p>]]><p><b>Orchestral shows</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go to a performance by the Israeli Philharmonic Orchestra, or the New Israel Opera, or one of several other great orchestras in Tel Aviv which draw audiences from all over the world.</p>]]><p><b>Ramon Crater </b></p><![CDATA[<p>This unique geological phenomenon is located in the heart of the barren Negev Desert. It was formed after an ancient sea that once covered this region retreated. Today it measures a vast 45km (28miles) long, 8km (5miles) wide, and 500m (1640ft) deep and provides for some astounding views and a wealth of hiking opportunities.</p>]]><p><b>Sea of Galilee </b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Sea of Galilee is a large lake in Israel&rsquo;s beautiful Jezreel Valley that is as picturesque as it is historically important. The shores are dotted with churches commemorating Jesus&rsquo; miracles and baptism, while Tiberias&mdash;one of Judaism&rsquo;s four holy cities&mdash;is a popular tourist destination for young Israelis.</p>]]><p><b>Via Dolorosa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Via Dolorosa in Jerusalem's Old City traces the traditional path Jesus walked from judgment to crucifixion. The nine 'stations' along the route lead to five more in the Church of the Holy Sepulchre.</p>]]><p><b>Western Wall Plaza</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Encounter Jewish faith and resilience in the immense, animated Western Wall Plaza (<a href="http://www.thekotel.org" target="_blank">www.thekotel.org</a>), below Temple Mount. Go on a Western Wall tunnel tour, which takes you to portions of the wall now buried deep beneath the city.</p>]]><p><b>Yad Vashem Holocaust Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The impressive and moving Yad Vashem Holocaust Memorial Museum in Jerusalem was built in remembrance of the six million Jewish people who perished in the Holocaust. A visit to Yad Vashem (<a href="http://www.yadvashem.org" target="_blank">www.yadvashem.org</a>) is crucial to understanding the history of the country. The museum is extensive and contains many displays and exhibits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$319 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>High-tech equipment, computer software, cut diamonds, agricultural products, chemicals and textiles.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Raw materials, military equipment, rough diamonds, fuel and grain.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Belgium, Germany, Switzerland and UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israel has a diverse and sophisticated manufacturing economy with real growth rate at 4.7%. High technology is the largest sector with the rest of the industrial sector concentrated on engineering, aircraft, electronics, chemicals, biotechnology, textiles and food-processing. </p>
<p>Agriculture is relatively small but there has been considerable investment in tourism, which is sensitive to political developments.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There is a labour force of about 4 million and unemployment stands at 4%. Israel's per capita income of US$37,400 (2016) places it within the top 30 highest-earning nations.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israel has an informal approach to business etiquette with smart-casual style clothing for meetings. Israelis tend to be direct and to-the-point, and plain speaking is appreciated.</p>
<p>English is spoken well by businesspeople and is used out of politeness if non-Israelis are present. Social interaction is important, and relaxed lunch meetings or outings may be used to develop trust.</p>
<p>As Hebrew is read right to left, books, leaflets or folders will also open in reverse. Women should wait until a man offers his hand to shake as many religious men do not touch women.</p><p>Business hours are Sun-Thurs 0830-1700. On Fridays, businesses shut at 1230 or 1300 for Shabbat, which starts at sundown on Friday and continues until Saturday evening. Some are closed for the whole of Friday and Saturday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Israel Trade Fairs and Convention Center</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Federation of Israeli Chambers of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:http://www.chamber.org.il/
					Address: 84 Haashmonaim Street,PO Box 20027,Tel Aviv,67132]]><b>Jerusalem International Convention Centre (JICC)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:http://www.iccjer.co.il/
					Address: PO Box 6001,Binyaney Ha'ooma,Jerusalem,91060]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Israel&rsquo;s diverse population is reflected in its varied culinary styles, and food forms an integral part of life, from socialising to family gatherings to religious events. From top gourmet restaurants to sumptuous street food, the country&rsquo;s wonderfully varied tastes and styles are one of the highlights of a trip. Most restaurants are moderately priced and of high quality, although street food is a great cheap option. Table service is the norm, except at fast food outlets. Places catering for tourists usually have menus in both Hebrew and English.</p>
<p>Restaurants, caf&eacute;s and bars rise and fall with popularity and it is not uncommon to see queues down the street for some of Tel Aviv&rsquo;s most popular eateries. Kosher and non-Kosher restaurants can be found throughout the country, although more secular cities such as Tel Aviv have considerably fewer kosher restaurants than Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Caf&eacute; culture is huge and there is little that Israelis would rather do than sip lattes or strong Arabic coffee in one of the outdoor caf&eacute;s. Funky, artistic, chic or cosy, caf&eacute;s are the place to be seen. All serve food that range from hearty breakfasts to sandwiches and light lunches.</p>
<p>Bars serve high quality food until the small hours and stock all international brands of spirits and soft drinks. Alcohol is expensive however, including local brand beers.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Falafel</em> (deep-fried balls of mashed chickpeas and herbs) in a pita bread, with hummus (ground chickpeas), tahini (sesame seed sauce) and salads. <br />
&bull; Salads, which include savoury vegetable dishes served cold, such as aubergines. <br />
<em>&bull; Shishlik</em> (charcoal-grilled meat on a skewer). <br />
<em>&bull; Shwarma</em> (slices of grilled meat served in a pita bread with salad).<br />
&bull; Ashkenazi classics like <em>cholent</em> (Shabbat meat stew) and <em>gefilte fish</em>, a white fish dish.<br />
<em>&bull; Burekas </em>(small pastry parcels) eaten on Friday mornings. They can be stuffed with mushroom, cheese, potato or spinach.<br />
<em>&bull; Shakshuka </em>(a brunch or breakfast dish consisting of tomatoes, onions and eggs eaten with pita).<strong><strong><br />
<br />
</strong></strong></p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>The Hebrew word <em>kosher</em> means conforming to Jewish religious laws. There are several detailed rules &ndash; not eating dairy in the same meal as meat and avoiding pork and shellfish are the most significant to visitors. Eateries in Israel will display a kosher certificate denoting whether they abide by these rules. In Tel Aviv many restaurants and caf&eacute;&rsquo;s do not serve kosher food, although in cities such as Jerusalem most will be kosher.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Israelis tip 12-15% in restaurants and cafes. Often this is added to the bill, but if service was not satisfactory you can ask to have it removed.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israelis love to let their hair down and as such bars and nightclubs can be found in most cities. Israel's club scene in&nbsp;Tel Aviv and Jerusalem&nbsp;draws DJs from the USA aand Europe. Tel Aviv in particular has a wealth of entertainment, though you&rsquo;ll find rock, jazz, folk, and pop music clubs in all the main cities and resorts. Israeli folklore and dance shows can also be seen everywhere, especially in the kibbutzim. Nightlife in Jerusalem is a little more muted but there are a few good clubs, including the legendary Haoman 17 (<a href="http://www.haoman17tlv.co.il" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.haoman17tlv.co.il</a>). <br />
<br />
Particularly prominent in Israeli life are classical music, ballet, opera, and theatre, which are mainly based in Tel Aviv. The city is home to nearly half of Israel&rsquo;s performing arts centres, including the mainstream Habima Theatre (<a href="http://www.habima.co.il" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.habima.co.il</a>) and the contemporary Suzanne Dellal Centre (<a href="http://www.suzannedellal.org.il" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.suzannedellal.org.il</a>). The New Israel Opera (<a href="http://www.israel-opera.co.il" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.israel-opera.co.il</a>) performs at the Tel Aviv Performing Arts Center. The Israeli Philharmonic Orchestra (<a href="http://www.ipo.co.il" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.ipo.co.il</a>) performs primarily at the Charles R Bronfman Auditorium. </p>
<p>Cinema is extremely popular in Israel and many cinemas screen three daily shows of international and local films.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide choice for shoppers in Israel. High quality shopping malls, designer boutiques, traditional markets, antique shops and high street shops all have their place. Contrary to a widespread belief among visitors, bargaining is not common in Israel except in the markets. One of the highlights of visiting Israel is a trip to one of these very animated markets (<em>shuks</em>) of tremendous cultural diversity, notably the Carmel Market in Tel Aviv or Mahane Yehuda Market in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Dead Sea products are one of the country&rsquo;s most famous exports and it is therefore unsurprising that many tourists enjoy shopping for them at hugely lowered costs. All big pharmacies sell Dead Sea products, and there are specialised shops in most cities and amidst the spa hotels along the Dead Sea. Gold and silver jewellery, Judaica, Christian religious items, and arts and crafts are also popular keep-sakes and are sold in specialist shops mainly in the old cities or craft markets such as the Nachalat Binyamin Market in Tel Aviv.</p>
<p>Tourists benefit from a zero rate of VAT on many goods and services. In addition, when buying from souvenir and specialist shops displaying a Ministry of Tourism sign, especially jewellers and luxury goods stores, it is possible to obtain a VAT refund. When making your purchase simply ask for a Tax Refund Invoice and then, when leaving the country, take the invoice to the tax refund desk at the airport or port for the refund.</p><p>Sun-Fri 0800-1900, although many Jewish-run shops will close mid-afternoon on Friday in preparation for Shabbat, while Arabic stores are closed on Fridays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israel&rsquo;s hotels are plentiful and of high quality. They range from small luxury, art-deco boutique hotels to large chain hotels, and much in between. Many of the big, international hotel chains are represented throughout the country including Hilton, Sheraton and more recently Leonardo, as well as national chains such as Fattal, Isrotel, Rimonim and Dan. About 380 hotels are members of the Israel Hotel Association. Prices vary according to season and region, and it is best to book months in advance for the high season (usually July to August, though this varies according to the region) and for religious holiday periods.<br />
<br />
Spa hotels and resorts are big business in the country, and luxury hotels offering in-room Jacuzzis, spa clinics and (especially along the Dead Sea) treatment centres are of exceptionally high quality.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Across Israel, many private families have converted their homes into bed &amp; breakfasts, known as <em>zimmers</em>. Some are simple rooms with a shared bathroom while others are private bungalows with kitchenettes, jacuzzi baths and all mod cons. Zimmers (<a href="http://www.zimmeril.com/" target="_blank">www.zimmeril.com</a>) can be found throughout the country in some of the most picturesque locations, but can be expensive. Weekday prices tend to be considerably cheaper.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israel&rsquo;s hotels are plentiful and of high quality. They range from small luxury, art-deco boutique hotels to large chain hotels, and much in between. Many of the big, international hotel chains are represented throughout the country including Hilton, Sheraton and more recently Leonardo, as well as national chains such as Fattal, Isrotel, Rimonim and Dan. About 380 hotels are members of the Israel Hotel Association. Prices vary according to season and region, and it is best to book months in advance for the high season (usually July to August, though this varies according to the region) and for religious holiday periods.<br />
<br />
Spa hotels and resorts are big business in the country, and luxury hotels offering in-room Jacuzzis, spa clinics and (especially along the Dead Sea) treatment centres are of exceptionally high quality.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israel&rsquo;s hotels are plentiful and of high quality. They range from small luxury, art-deco boutique hotels to large chain hotels, and much in between. Many of the big, international hotel chains are represented throughout the country including Hilton, Sheraton and more recently Leonardo, as well as national chains such as Fattal, Isrotel, Rimonim and Dan. About 380 hotels are members of the Israel Hotel Association. Prices vary according to season and region, and it is best to book months in advance for the high season (usually July to August, though this varies according to the region) and for religious holiday periods.<br />
<br />
Spa hotels and resorts are big business in the country, and luxury hotels offering in-room Jacuzzis, spa clinics and (especially along the Dead Sea) treatment centres are of exceptionally high quality.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Israel has excellent medical facilities and tourists may go to all emergency departments and first-aid centres. However, any form of medical treatment can be expensive. Health centres are marked by the red Star of David on a white background. Medical insurance is recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is safe to drink throughout Israel. Bottled water is widely available and is advised for the first few weeks of the stay. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. All local meat, fish and vegetables are considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Rabies&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is present. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Only the first and last days of Pesach and Sukkot are national holidays, but there may be some disruption on intermediate dates. Jewish festivals always commence on the evenings before the dates given below.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Israel without incurring customs duty (alcohol and tobacco can only be imported by persons aged 18 years and over):</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 250g of tobacco products. <br />
&bull; 1L of spirits and 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 1/4L of cologne or perfume.<br />
&bull; Gifts and other goods to the value of US$200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted items include firearms, plants, raw meat, bananas, pineapples, raw material, counterfeit currency or documents, and knives not intended for professional use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Shekel (ILS; symbol ₪) = 100 agorot (singular, agora). Notes are in denominations of ₪200, 100, 50, and 20. Coins are in denominations of ₪10, 5, 2 and 1, and 50 and 10 agorot.<br />
<br />
<strong>Note:</strong> Many hotels, tour companies, car rental agencies and other tourist services quote their prices in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars.  It is customary to tip 12-15% in restaurants and caf&eacute;s. Tipping in bars is appreciated but not expected, and it is the norm to round up to the nearest shekel in taxis. Bargaining is done only in open markets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major currencies can be exchanged for shekels at the airport, banks, post offices, many hotels or licensed exchange booths in most towns and cities. To exchange travellers&rsquo; cheques you will need to show your passport. All public services such as banks and post offices are closed on Shabbat. At the end of your trip it is possible to change money from shekels back to your currency of choice, only at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major credit cards are accepted.</p><p>ATMs are widely available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are widely accepted. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sun-Fri 0830-1200 and Sun, Tues, Thurs 1600-1800 although these can vary slightly between banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Israel as a tourist, a passport valid for a minimum of six months from the date of entry is required by the nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An A/1 temporary resident visa can be issued to those who are eligible for immigration under the Law of Return.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You may need to provide proof of sufficient funds when entering Israel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A visitor who wishes to extend his visit must submit an application at one of the regional population administration offices of the Ministry of the Interior.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israel does not quarantine healthy pets who meet the following requirements: pets must have a 15-digit ISO pet microchip, and must be vaccinated against rabies at least 30 days (but not more than one year) before travel. More than 30 days after vaccination, your pet must have a blood titer test. Within 10 days of travel, the Israel Veterinary Certificate must be completed and stamped by the country of origin. Pets under the age of three months cannot be brought into Israel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[31.607983]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[34.817996]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>20,770 sq km (8,019 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>8,796,200 (Israel Central Bureau of Statistics estimate 2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>395 per sq km</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jerusalem.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parliamentary republic</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israel is on the eastern Mediterranean, bordered by Lebanon and Syria to the north, the Palestine National Authority (West Bank) and Jordan to the east, and Egypt to the south. Gaza, a small coastal strip between Israel and Egypt, is claimed by the Palestine National Authority, but under de facto rule by the militant group Hamas.</p>
<p>Although relatively small in size, Israel contains a great variety of terrain and four climate zones. The north of the country is the fertile hill region of Galilee, rising to Mount Hermon and Golan in the northeast. The lush Plain of Sharon runs along the coast, while inland a range of hills and uplands run into the relatively barren and stony areas of the east. The country stretches southwards through the Negev Desert to Eilat, on the Red Sea. The Dead Sea (the lowest point in the world) sits on Israel&rsquo;s eastern border along the great Syrian-African Rift Valley. Israel's largest freshwater lake, the Kinneret (also known the Sea of Galilee), is an important source of drinking water for the country and a significant religious destination for Jewish and Christian pilgrims.</p>
<p>Owing to its location on climatic and geographical crossroads, where the northern steppes of Europe meet the Syrian-African Rift Valley, Israel has a surprisingly varied flora and fauna. It has an estimated 2,867 species of flora and approximately 100 species of mammals. The country is also a crucial stop-over on the great bird migrations as they make their way north and south twice a year. The Israel Nature and National Parks Authority is responsible for more than 70 national parks and more than 200 nature reserves in Israel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>76% Jewish, 17% Muslim, with small numbers of Christians, Druze and other minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israelis are usually very informal but with the European style of hospitality. Israelis are typically blunt and direct in speech, which should not be misinterpreted as rudeness. Visitors should observe normal courtesies when visiting someone's home and should not be afraid to ask questions about the country, as most Israelis are happy to talk about their homeland, religion and politics. The expression <em>shalom</em> (peace) is used for hello and goodbye.</p>
<p>Dress is casual, but in the holy places of all religions, modest attire is worn. For places such as the Western Wall, male visitors are given a smart cardboard <em>yarmulke </em>(skull cap) to respect the religious importance of the site. Businesspeople are expected to dress smartly, or at least in smart casual style, although ties are often not worn. The most expensive of restaurants and nightclubs may expect a similar standard. If formal evening-wear is required this will be specified on invitations.</p>
<p>It is considered a violation of Shabbat<em> </em>(Sabbath, on Saturday) to smoke on that day. There is usually a sign to remind the visitor of this, and to disregard the warning would be regarded as discourteous.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with three round pins (plug type H) are standard; many European two-pin plugs (type C) fit the sockets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu since 2009.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Reuven Rivlin since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Jewish people trace their ancestry to Abraham who settled in the land of Canaan around the 17th century BCE. They controlled much of the area despite clashes with the neighbouring Assyrians and Philistines, until being overrun by Alexander the Great in the fourth century BCE. By 100 CE Jerusalem was under Roman rule, before it was occupied by Arabs and then retaken during the Christian First Crusade. The Christians established several states, including the Kingdom of Jerusalem, which survived until 1291 when the area fell under the Mamluks and subsequently the Ottoman Empire.</p>
<p>The country then experienced a lengthy decline as the Jews spread across Europe, North Africa, the Middle East and, later, the Americas. Most countries today have a community descended from Jewish settlers and most have suffered some form of persecution. As the Ottoman years ended after the British conquest, the country saw great numbers of Jews arriving to create a Jewish homeland.</p>
<p>The aspiration of the Zionist movement to re-establish a separate Jewish nation was recognised by the British government in 1917, following Britain&rsquo;s occupation of Palestine.  A League of Nations mandate entrusted the region to the British, who granted Jews and Arabs the right to run their own affairs, but the British struggled to balance their commitment to the two populations. After World War II the UN favoured the creation of a separate Jewish state in Palestine.</p>
<p>The Arabs refused to accept this, but the expiry of the mandate and pressure from Jewish immigrants&mdash;many of which had moved to Palestine after the war&mdash;forced the British to withdraw. In May 1948, Israel declared independence, sparking the Arab-Israeli War. Israel took control of three-quarters of Palestine, leaving the West Bank between Jerusalem and the River Jordan occupied by the Jordanian army. In 1964, the anti-Zionist Palestine Liberation Organisation was formed and three years later regional tensions erupted into the Six Day War, which ended in Israel&rsquo;s capture of Jerusalem, Judea, Samaria, Gaza, the Sinai Peninsula and the Golan Heights. After the bloody Yom Kippur War in October 1973, Sinai was returned to the Egyptians.</p>
<p> Many thousands of Palestinians were displaced during these conflicts. Since 2012, the United Nations has legally recognised the existence of the State of Palestine within the West Bank and the Gaza Strip, but the area remains under Israeli occupation. </p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong></p>
<p>&bull;  Israel&rsquo;s official languages are Hebrew and Arabic, although English is still widely used on road signs and by speakers.</p>
<p>&bull; Israel consistently rates low in the Global Peace Index. In 2017 it ranked 144th out of 163 countries.</p>
<p>&bull; Israel&rsquo;s top literary award, the Sapir Prize, is made each June during Hebrew Book Week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Israel]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+972 3 725 1222</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-tel-aviv</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+972 3 725 1222</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1600, Fri 0800-1330.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>192 HaYarkon Street<br/>Tel Aviv<br/>6340502<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Israel in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 364 5500</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.israelemb.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 364 5500</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0930-1300, Fri 0930-1030.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>3514 International Drive NW<br/>Washington DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Israel in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7957 9500</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://embassies.gov.il/london/Pages/default.aspx</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7957 9500</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1600, Fri 0800-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2 Palace Green<br/>London<br/>W8 4QB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Israel has always been an alluring destination. From biblical times to present day, this slice of holy land in the Eastern Mediterranean has long attracted visitors. It has attracted turmoil, too, and Israel remains a politically sensitive country.&nbsp;Nevertheless, its appeal for visitors is enormous and the day-to-day issues facing residents have little effect on those coming to appreciate its astounding historic relics, impressive religious sites and exquisite natural beauty.</p>
<p>Home to the Mount of Olives, the Sea of Galilee and the ancient port of Jaffa, it&rsquo;s hard to go anywhere in Israel without stumbling upon a place of religious significance. None, though, compare to the holy city of Jerusalem. Sacred to Jews, Muslims and Christians alike, this ancient metropolis is claimed by both Israel and Palestine and its status remains one of the core issues of the Israeli-Palestine conflict.</p>
<p>Jerusalem's stunning skyline belies the ugly political landscape, with its beautiful bell towers, striking minarets and the golden dome of the Al-Aqsa Mosque. Split into Arabic, Jewish and Christian quarters, this cultural melting pot translates into a sumptuous culinary scene, as well as a feast for the eyes.&nbsp;Visually, Tel Aviv seems a world away. Israel&rsquo;s commercial and political heart is a city of glistening skyscrapers, thronging streets and sandy beaches; of contemporary art galleries, excellent restaurants and hedonistic inhabitants. Quite a contrast, then, to neighbouring Jaffa, a historic port city of sprawling markets, cobbled docks and crumbling city walls. This juxtaposition of old and new is typical in Israel, where ancient cities like Nazareth and Acre exist alongside modern metropolises such as Haifa and Eilat.</p>
<p>Israel&rsquo;s landscapes are equally diverse. Mountains, deserts and fertile valleys can all be found in this sliver of the Middle East, while the Dead Sea, Red Sea, Sea of Galilee and Mediterranean coastlines offer everything from unique geological spectacles to seaside holiday resorts.</p>
<p>If you can read beyond the headlines and see past the politics, in Israel you will find a beautiful and beguiling nation quite unlike anywhere else on Earth.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><p>Israel has always been an alluring destination. From biblical times to present day, this slice of holy land in the Eastern Mediterranean has long attracted visitors. It has attracted turmoil, too, and Israel remains a politically sensitive country.&nbsp;Nevertheless, its appeal for visitors is enormous and the day-to-day issues facing residents have little effect on those coming to appreciate its astounding historic relics, impressive religious sites and exquisite natural beauty.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
