<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Italy" ColCode="ita" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="it" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Italy]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Italy is characterised by a Mediterranean climate with hot, dry summers and cool, wet winters.  July is the hottest month with temperatures up to 30C (86F), and January is the coldest month.  It is a great destination to visit year round, particularly if taking a city break, though for the warmest and most reliable weather April to June is the prime tourist season. Most Italians take their holiday in July and August so prices, and crowds, can soar during these months, which are also the hottest of the year. If you&rsquo;re keen to avoid the main scrum of peak season but still bank on mild weather, late September to October is a good choice.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothes are worn during the summer, except in the mountains. Winter demands light to mediumweights in the south, but warmer clothes elsewhere. Alpine wear is advised for winter mountain resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alitalia (<a href="http://www.alitalia.com">www.alitalia.com</a>), Air Italy (<a href="http://www.airitaly.com">www.airitaly.com</a>), Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com">www.ryanair.com</a>) and Easyjet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com">www.easyjet.com</a>) run domestic flights in Italy.</p><p>Italy has many regional airports offering good coverage of the whole peninsula. While flying may be the best option when travelling the length and breadth of the country, shorter routes are better served by the high-speed train network.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports</strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;Ancona (<a href="http://www.porto.ancona.it">www.porto.ancona.it</a>), Brindisi (<a href="http://www.porto.br.it)">www.porto.br.it)</a>, Cagliari (<a href="http://www.porto.cagliari.it">www.porto.cagliari.it</a>), Civitavecchia&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.civitavecchiaport.org">www.civitavecchiaport.org</a>), Genoa, Livorno (<a href="http://www.porto.livorno.it">www.porto.livorno.it</a>), Naples (<a href="http://porto.napoli.it">porto.napoli.it</a>), Palermo (<a href="http://www.portpalermo.i">www.portpalermo.i</a>t) and Venice (<a href="http://www.port.venice.it">www.port.venice.it</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Ferries:</strong> A number of car and passenger ferries operate throughout the year linking Italian ports. Regular boat and hydrofoil services run to the islands of Capri, Sardinia, Sicily and the Aeolian Islands. There are also some links along the coast.</p>
<p>Operators include Tirrenia (tel:  +39 02 76028132; <a target="_blank" href="https://www.tirrenia.it/">www.tirrenia.it</a>) and SNAV (tel: +39 081 428 5555;&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.snav.it/">www.snav.it</a>). Ferries also operate on the main lakes of Garda, Maggiore, Como and Iseo and are run by Navigazione Laghi (tel: 800 551 801 in Italy only; <a href="http://www.navigazionelaghi.it" target="_blank">www.navigazionelaghi.it</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trenitalia (tel: +39 06 6847 5475; <a href="http://www.trenitalia.com" target="_blank">www.trenitalia.com</a>) runs a nationwide network with reasonably priced fares calculated by distance travelled, and there are a number of excellent reductions. Main routes include Turin-Milan-Venice; Milan-Bologna-Bari; Rome-Genoa-Turin; and Rome-Naples-Palermo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Italy has an extensive network of privatised motorways operated by Autostrade per l'Italia (<a href="http://www.autostrade.it">www.autostrade.it</a>). The main north-south route is the Autostrada del Sole, which extends from Milan to Naples as the A1, and from Naples to Reggio di Calabria as the A3. In the north, the main west-east route, stretching from the Slovenian border via Venice, Verona, Brescia and Milan to Turin is the A4.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Toll in Italy is charged at varying distances, scales, rates and modes. There are standardised signs at the toll gates on the motorway network indicating how payments are accepted. Toll is charged from tourists either in cash, with the prepaid Viacard, a rechargeable Telepass, or with credit or bankcards. On the motorways A36, A59 and A60 tolls are paid in the free-flow system for which prior registration at Autostrada Pedemontana Lombarda (<a href="http://apl.pedemontana.com">apl.pedemontana.com</a>) is necessary. Long-term visitors might opt to rent a Telepass transponder (<a href="http://www.telepass.com">www.telepass.com</a>) for one year, for which an Italian bank account is needed. Road signs are international. More information on the Italian motorway network and toll charges is available from Autostrade per l'Italia.</p>r<p>Italian motorways are in good condition but secondary roads are of varying quality and drivers should note that the quality of infrastructure is not the same throughout the country.</p><p>Italy has an extensive bus network, with a plethora of regional operators offering regional and interregional services. Prices are reasonable and often cheaper than their train alternatives although local routes can be slow.  Advance booking is generally not required, except on the most popular inter-city routes. You can buy tickets at the bus terminus, through agencies or in bars (<em>tabacchi</em>).</p><p>There are many available taxi companies in every major Italian city, each with varying rates per km. Official city taxis vary depending on the city so it is advisable to research beforehand. itTaxi (<a href="http://www.ittaxi.it/app">www.ittaxi.it/app</a>) is a free mobile app launched by the Italian taxi union and connects official taxis and customers throughout Italy.</p><p>All EU member states&rsquo; driving licences are recognised in Italy. In practice, many car hire agencies also accept many non-EU licences such as those from Australia, Canada, New Zealand and the USA. Drivers from other countries need an International Driving Permit. Visitors driving foreign vehicles must carry their log-book, which must be in their name as owner or have the owner's written permission to drive the vehicle. A driving licence or a motorcycle driving licence is required for motorcycles over 49cc.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in urban areas, 90kph (55mph) on ordinary roads, 110kph (68mph) on dual carriageways and 130kph (80mph) on motorways. Dipped headlights are compulsory outside built-up areas during the day. All vehicles must carry a red warning triangle.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> Fines for driving offences are on-the-spot and particularly heavy.</p><p>Automobile Club d'Italia (ACI) (tel: +39 803 116, for foreign mobile networks: 800 116 800; <a href="http://www.aci.it">www.aci.it</a>)</p><p>Car hire is available in most cities, airports and resorts. All major international car hire companies are represented and there are various Italian firms to choose from such as Locauto (<a href="http://www.locautorent.com">www.locautorent.com</a>). Drivers must be at least 18 years old.</p><p>Both city and mountain bikes are available to hire in most Italian towns. Mobike (<a href="http://mobike.com">mobike.com</a>) and Ofo (<a href="http://www.ofo.com">www.ofo.com</a>) operate dockless bike share systems in Florence and Milan. BikeMi (<a href="http://www.bikemi.com">www.bikemi.com</a>) bikes are also available in Milan. Turin is home to the TObike (<a href="http://www.tobike.it">www.tobike.it</a>) public bikeshare scheme.</p>
<p>To take bikes on board a train, you need to purchase a separate bicycle ticket.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in urban areas, 90kph (55mph) on ordinary roads, 110kph (68mph) on dual carriageways and 130kph (80mph) on motorways. Dipped headlights are compulsory outside built-up areas during the day. All vehicles must carry a red warning triangle.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> Fines for driving offences are on-the-spot and particularly heavy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers should be aware that tickets for public transport need to be validated in a ticket machine before the journey. Machines are located in entrances to platforms in railway and metro stations and on-board buses and trams. Failure to do so could lead to an on-the-spot fine.</p>
<p>All the big towns and cities (Genoa, Milan, Naples, Rome, Turin and Venice) have good public transport networks. The Rome system is run by the City Transport Authority (ATAC) and MetRo. The Milanese system is run by the Azienda Trasporti Milanesi (ATM).</p>
<p><strong>Underground:</strong>&nbsp;Rome has a three-line metro system, while Milan has a four-line network. You can buy tickets from station vending machines or tobacconists. Day passes are also available.</p>
<p><strong>Bus:</strong> Services operate in all main cities and towns. In Rome, the network is extensive and complements the underground and tram systems. In larger cities, fares are generally pre-purchased from machines or tobacconists. Bus tickets can be bought in packets of five and are fed into a stamping machine on boarding.</p>
<p><strong>Tram:</strong> There is an extensive network in Rome; Milan, Messina and Turin also have tram services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Italy</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">turin</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.35</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Italy</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">naples</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.55</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.27</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Italy</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">milan</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.05</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Italy</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">florence</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.55</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Italy</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cagliari</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.55</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier is Alitalia (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.alitalia.com/">www.alitalia.com</a>). Other airlines flying to Italy from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>). Seasonal carriers flying to Italy from the UK include Jet2.com, Monarch Airlines and Thomson Airways. American Airlines (<a href="https://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>) flies from the US to Italy.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/bologna-guglielmo-marconi-airport">Bologna Gugielmo Marconi Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/florence-airport">Florence Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/milan-linate-international-airport">Milan Linate Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/milan-malpensa-airport">Milan Malpensa Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/naples-international-airport">Naples International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/palermo-falcone-borsellino-airport">Palermo Falcone Borsellino Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/roma-ciampino-airport-giovan-battista-pastine-airport">Rome Ciampino Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/rome-leonardo-da-vinci-fiumicino-airport">Rome Leonardo da Vinci Fiumicino Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turin-caselle-airport">Turin Caselle Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/venice-marco-polo-airport">Venice Marco Polo Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/verona-villafranca-airport">Verona Villafranca Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bari-karol-wojtyla-airport">Bari Karol Wojtyla Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/cagliari-elmas-airport">Cagliari Elmas Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/ancona-falconara-airport">Marche Airport (Ancona Falconara Airport)</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/olbia-costa-smeralda-airport">Olbia Costa Ameralda Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/trieste-friuli-venezia-giulia-airport">Trieste Friuli Venezia Giulia Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/catania-fontanarossa-airport">Cantania Fontanarossa Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/genova-genoa-cristoforo-colombo-airport">Genova Cristoforo Colombo Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy/pisa-international-airport-galileo-galilei">Pisa International Airport Galileo Galilel</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/rome">Rome</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 8 hours 25 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bologna Guglielmo Marconi Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bologna-airport.it<p>Bologna Guglielmo Marconi Airport is situated 6km (3.5 miles) north of Bologna.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+39 051 647 9615</p>]]><b>Milan Malpensa Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.seamilano.eu<p>Milan Malpensa Airport is located 45km (29 miles) northwest of Milan.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+39 02 232 323.</p>]]><b>Naples International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeroportodinapoli.it<p>Naples International Airport is situated 7km (4 miles) northeast of Naples.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+39 081 789 6111.</p>]]><b>Pisa International Airport Galileo Galilei</b><![CDATA[http://www.pisa-airport.com<p>Pisa International Airport Galileo Galilei is situated 1km (0.6 miles) north of Pisa.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+39 050 849 111</p>]]><b>Rome Leonardo da Vinci Fiumicino Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.adr.it<p>Rome Leonardo da Vinci-Fiumicino Airport is located 32km (20 miles) southwest of&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/rome">Rome</a>, in the Lazio region of central Italy.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+39 06 65951</p>]]><b>Rome Ciampino Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.adr.it<p>Rome Ciampino Airport is located 12km (7.5 miles) to the southeast of the centre of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/rome">Rome</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+39 06 65951</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong>&nbsp;Ancona (<a href="http://www.porto.ancona.it">www.porto.ancona.it</a>), Brindisi (<a href="http://www.porto.br.it)">www.porto.br.it)</a>, Cagliari (<a href="http://www.porto.cagliari.it">www.porto.cagliari.it</a>), Civitavecchia&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.civitavecchiaport.org">www.civitavecchiaport.org</a>),  Genoa, Livorno (<a href="http://www.porto.livorno.it">www.porto.livorno.it</a>), Naples (<a href="http://porto.napoli.it">porto.napoli.it</a>), Palermo (<a href="http://www.portpalermo.i">www.portpalermo.i</a>t) and Venice (<a href="http://www.port.venice.it">www.port.venice.it</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trenitalia runs regular services covering national and international routes (tel: +39 06 6847 5475; <a href="http://www.trenitalia.com" target="_blank">www.trenitalia.com</a>).</p>
<p>High-speed trains run between Italy and cities in France, Germany and Switzerland. Schedules and tickets are available from ItaliaRail (<a href="http://www.italiarail.com">www.italiarail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:&nbsp;</strong>offers unlimited first or second-class travel in up to 30 European countries, including Italy, for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 15 days, or seven, 10 or 15 days in one month across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.&nbsp;The One-Country Pass does not apply to travel in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 28. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from InterRail (<a href="http://www.interrail.eu">www.interrail.eu</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:&nbsp;</strong>offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries, including Italy. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 22 days, one, two or three months, five or seven days in a month, and 10 or 15 days days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in two to four bordering countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.&nbsp;Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 28) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com">www.eurail.com</a>).<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Telephone kiosks only accept phonecards, which can be purchased at post offices, tobacconists and some newsagents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Florence, Rome, Trento, Comiso, Venice, Milan and Bologna have instituted city-wide Wi-Fi hotspots, and the majority of hotels, airports, railway stations, B&amp;Bs and even farmstays now offer free internet access. In most towns internet cafes also offer access at &euro;5 to &euro;13 per hour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Italy's newspapers are strongly regionalised, with many papers produced in Milan. The press is free but ties with politics can be strong - notably in broadcast media. Rai, the public broadcaster, has been subject to political influence and the vast Gruppo Mediaset media empire is controlled by former prime minister Silvio Berlusconi. Among the most important Italian daily newspapers&nbsp;are <em>Corriere</em> <em>della</em> <em>Sera</em> (Milan), <em>Il</em> <em>Messaggero</em> (Rome), <em>La</em> <em>Repubblica</em> (Rome), <em>La</em> <em>Stampa</em> (Turin) and <em>Il Mattino</em> (Naples).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Italian postal system can be subject to delays.  Letters between Italy and other European countries usually take 3 to 5 days and sometimes 1-2 weeks to arrive. Stamps are sold in post offices and tobacconists. In the Vatican City, stamps issued are valid only within its boundaries.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1730, Sat 0815-1345. Smaller offices may close at midday during the week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Florence Duomo (Duomo Santa Maria del Fiore)</p><![CDATA[<p>Engineered by architect and sculptor Filippo Brunelleschi (1377-1446), the soaring red-tiled dome of Florence's cathedral is one of the greatest achievements of the Italian Renaissance It was completed in 1466 after 170 years of work. Climb to the top for magnificent views over the city, then gaze on the frescoed interior, lined with monuments to the great and good such as poet Dante Alighieri.</p>]]><br/><p>Leaning Tower of Pisa</p><![CDATA[<p>Constructed in 1174, the Leaning Tower of Pisa, located in Pisa's C<em>ampo dei Miracoli</em> (Field of Miracles) is famous both for its striking beauty and awkward geometry. Today, one side is 5m (16ft) closer to the ground than the other. Galileo used the tower for experiments to prove his theory of motion whilst he was chair of mathematics at the University of Pisa in 1589.</p>]]><br/><p>Mount Etna</p><![CDATA[<p>One of Europe's most active volcanoes, Mt Etna is Sicily's most famous natural attraction, and one of the latest additions to UNESCO's list of World Heritage sites. It is also the highest mountain on the island currently measuring 3,350m (10,990ft); the height varies each time the volcano erupts. Its mythical importance dates back to the Ancient Greeks who believed Cyclops forged lightning bolts for Zeus deep within the volcano. Mount Etna is situated within the Etna Regional Park, which offers skiing opportunities in the winter and some great hiking trails in summer.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be inspired by the scenic Cinque Terre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>WB Yeats, Ezra Pound, Byron and Shelley all garnered inspiration from Italy&rsquo;s picturesque Riviera. Hardly surprising considering the dramatic curving bay and pine-covered mountains banded with vineyards and olive groves. Get a taste of the high life in the pastel-hued villas of Portofino, Rapallo, Portovenere and Lerici.</p>]]><p><b>Bring out the binoculars and go wildlife watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the National Park of Abruzzo, you might spot Marsican brown bears (unique to Italy), chamois and eagles. In the Molise region, the Matese mountain range is still a haven for wolves, while bird-watchers should head to Sardinia during the autumn migration to spot Eleonora&rsquo;s falcons and the rare cirl bunting.</p>]]><p><b>Coo at culture on the canals of Venice</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With marble palaces afloat on teal-blue waters, garden islands yielding speciality produce and golden glimpses of heaven in St Mark&rsquo;s Basilica, Venice is a work of art in itself. Drift down the world&rsquo;s most beautiful boulevard, the Grand Canal, and see where Casanova was imprisoned in the Doge&rsquo;s Palace.</p>]]><p><b>Dare to visit Europe's most active volcano</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Offering skiing in the winter and hiking in summer, Mt Etna is Sicily&rsquo;s most famous natural attraction. A UNESCO World Heritage Site and active volcano, it is also the highest mountain on the island currently measuring 3,350m (10,990ft) &ndash; the height varies with each eruption. According to Ancient Greek mythology, Cyclops forged Zeus&rsquo; lightning bolts deep within the sweltering centre of the volcano.</p>]]><p><b>Delve into Ravenna's wealth of UNESCO sites</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover early Byzantine and Christian monuments decorated with stunning mosaics in Ravenna, including the splendid Mausoleum of Galla Placidia, the golden flourishes of Basilica di San Vitale and the serene Neonian Baptistery. A trove of religious art and culture, the city boasts eight UNESCO World Heritage Sites.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the delights of Padua</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Home to Italy&rsquo;s second oldest museum and a bastion of free-thinking, Padua harbours unique treasures. Almost 200 years before Michelangelo&rsquo;s Sistine Chapel came Giotto&rsquo;s groundbreaking frescoes in the Scrovegni Chapel. Copernicus and Galileo taught at the University&rsquo;s Palazzo Bo and pilgrims still seek miracle cures at St Anthony&rsquo;s tomb in the Basilica.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the glorious Greek sites of Sicily</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hot, dry and wracked by earthquake and eruption, Sicily has been on the tourist trail since Goethe wrote home about Agrigento's Valle dei Templi in 1786. Part of Greater Greece for over 500 years, Sicily's sites outshine many in Greece. The catacombs at the Capuchin Monastery contain thousands of mummified bodies and classical Greek plays are still performed in Syracuse's Greek Theatre.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the religious riches of Vatican City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enter the Vatican City, an independent sovereign state best known for the magnificent St Peter's Basilica. Among the principal features of the Vatican Palace (the Pope's residence) are the Sistine Chapel &ndash; featuring Michelangelo's famous fresco,&nbsp;<em>The Creation of Adam,</em>&nbsp;and the Vatican Museums.</p>]]><p><b>Hike, climb and ski picture-perfect peaks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the Valle d'Aosta region, go hill walking or climbing in the Gran Paradiso National Park and Mont Avic Regional Park, home to wildlife including the chamois and ibex. On the Swiss border, the flower-cloaked slopes of the Dolomites are also ideal for hiking and mountaineering. In winter, heavy snowfall, chic hotels and Michelin-starred restaurants attract a stylish ski crowd.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about geometry at the Leaning Tower of Pisa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Constructed in 1174, the Leaning Tower of Pisa, located in Pisa's Campo dei Miracoli (Field of Miracles) is famous both for its striking beauty and awkward geometry. Today, one side is 5m (16ft) closer to the ground than the other. Galileo used the tower for experiments to prove his theory of motion when he was chair of mathematics at the town&rsquo;s university.</p>]]><p><b>Live a life of luxury among the Italian Lakes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Basking in a Mediterranean microclimate, the Italian Lakes have been a popular holiday spot since Roman times. The Borromean princes built their palaces on islands in the middle of Lake Maggiore, while modern-day movie stars and Russian billionaires now seek shelter in art deco villas amid Lake Como&rsquo;s blooming tropical gardens.</p>]]><p><b>Look for love in Verona</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Soak up the romantic sights of Verona, the setting of Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet. The Casa di Giulietta (Juliet's House) attracts thousands of visitors to its balcony each year, whilst the vast Roman Arena, built in the 1st century, is the site of an annual opera festival.</p>]]><p><b>Look under the carpet at Siena cathedral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Admire Siena's extraordinary humbug-striped cathedra (Duomo). With a grand, upper fa&ccedil;ade mosaic, peeping gargoyles and large bronze door, there is plenty to attract the eye from the outside. Inside though, the fine blue and gold interior adds to the grandeur. Go in September to see its intricate patterned floor (pavimento) which remains covered most of the year.</p>]]><p><b>Revel in the beauty of Florence</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Florence and see Brunelleschi's revolutionary design for the magnificent cathedral (Duomo).  Cross the medieval Ponte Vecchio bridge, see the art collections of the Uffizi Gallery and Michelangelo's famous statue of David at the Galleria dell'Accademia, all among the city&rsquo;s beautiful Renaissance architecture.</p>]]><p><b>Sail around spectacular Sardinia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its turquoise coastline, spectacular grottoes and coral-rich seas, Sardinia is a diver&rsquo;s paradise. Above sea level, winds blow along the northern and southern coasts, attracting wind and kite surfers to Santa Teresa di Gallura and Chiaia, while sailors cast off beneath the granite cliffs of the Golfo di Orosei.</p>]]><p><b>Take to the coast for watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From water skiing to windsurfing, head to the coast where all types of watersports are available. Popular spots include the Italian Riviera in Liguria, the Adriatic and Amalfi coasts. Less busy are the beaches in Sicily, which has large sandy stretches on the southern coast, and in Sardinia. Many of Italy's best dive sites are located in Sardinia.</p>]]><p><b>Tour the Tuscan wine cellars</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Typically, the landscape of Tuscany is one of vine-covered hills, cypress woods, fields of sunflowers and remote hilltop villages. Chianti, the best-known Italian wine, is made in the area north of Siena. With several vineyards open to the public, wine fans should drink their way around a Tuscan tasting tour.&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Tour the ancient heart of Rome</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its epic history and monumental museums, Rome is the repository of over 2,500 years of European art and architecture. Start at the beginning with the Colosseum, the Forum, the Pantheon and the Capitoline Museums. Then get intimate in the reconstructed bedrooms (<em>cubicula</em>) of Museo Nazionale Romano.</p>]]><p><b>Walk through the remains of Pompeii</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Understand how 1st-century Romans lived their daily lives when you see the remains of Pompeii and Herculaneum, engulfed in the great eruption of 79 CE. Wander the narrow streets of these well-preserved archaeological sites to see their amphitheatres, their forums and plenty of striking colourful mosaics. In Pompeii, plaster casts have been made of the doomed resident's remains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2.307 trillion (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Engineering products, textiles and clothing, production machinery, food and beverages, motor vehicles, transport equipment, and tobacco.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Engineering products, chemicals, transport equipment, energy products and minerals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, France, China,&nbsp;USA, Spain and UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Italy has a diversified economy with high gross domestic product (GDP) per capita. Traditionally agricultural, Italy industrialised rapidly after 1945, to the point where less than 4% of the population is now engaged in agriculture. The majority of these live in the south of Italy, which is substantially poorer than the rest of the country. The principal crops are sugar beet, wheat, tomatoes and fruit (especially grapes, many used for wine, of which Italy is a leading producer). <br />
<br />
As with most western European economies, the tourism industry now enjoys a major position alongside other service and manufacturing industries such as financial services, automobiles, fashion and design. Italy continues to rely heavily on the export of manufactured goods. Its particular strengths are in advanced manufacturing techniques and systems, high-quality design and precision engineering. Most industrial raw materials and more than 75% of energy requirements are imported. <br />
<br />
Since 2000 the economy has been sluggish at best, and Italy was hard hit by the effects of the 2008 economic crisis and the subsequent Eurozone crisis. Between 2007 and 2011 the economy shrank by 6.76% with public debt rising to 120% of GDP in 2012 and unemployment to 10.8%. However, the majority of Italy&rsquo;s public debt is owned by nationals and the country&rsquo;s high levels of private savings and low levels of personal debt make it one of the safest among Europe&rsquo;s struggling economies.</p>
<p>Italy's budget deficit was 1.9% in 2017. Average inflation in 2017 was 0.7%. The unemployment rate of 2017 was 11.2%. Public debt rose to 132.0% in 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prior appointments are essential. Visitors should remember that ministries and most public offices close at 1300 and it is not possible to see officials in the afternoon, except by special appointment. Business attire is smart with a suit required for men and women, and a tie for men and stylish accessories for women. The odd designer label does no harm.<br />
<br />
Greeting takes the form of a handshake (social kissing is reserved for friends and family) and business cards are exchanged. If possible, it is best to have one side printed in Italian and one in English, and all company literature should be provided in Italian. Business visitors should always refer to Italian associates as <em>lei</em> (the polite form of <em>tu</em>), unless informed to do otherwise, and colleagues should be addressed by their surname and academic/professional titles respected.<br />
<br />
Although some of the Italian business community will speak some English or French, Italian is the dominant language. Italians always appreciate a visitor who tries to speak their language, however poorly. It is often wise to take the precaution of employing an interpreter, to minimise the degree of misunderstandings.<br />
<br />
Personal relationships are extremely important and it is unlikely that decisions will be made before trust has been established between the two parties. Business lunches provide the ideal opportunity to build relationships and small talk is an essential part of any business meeting.<br />
<br />
Very often meetings will start late and run over and it&rsquo;s not considered impolite to turn up after your appointed hour, unless for an important meeting.<br />
<br />
Business tends to be more formal in the fast-paced Milan than in the more southerly cities of Florence, Rome and Naples, where business is often conducted over long lunches.</p><p>In the North, standard office hours are Monday-Friday 0900-1700, with an hour-long lunch break, while in the South there is often a two-hour lunch break during office hours of 0800-1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Unioncamere - Camere di Commercio d'Italia</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: +39 6 47041.
					Website:http://www.unioncamere.gov.it
					Address: ,Piazza Sallustio 21,Rome,00187]]><b>Agenzia per la promozione all'estero e l'internazionalizzazione delle imprese italiane (Italian Trade Agency)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: +39 6 59921.
					Website:http://www.ice.gov.it
					Address: ,Via Liszt 21,Rome,00144]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Though renowned the world over, the umbrella term, Italian cuisine, barely begins to cover the rich, regional variations that make up the Italian table. To the north, French and Austrian influences make for dishes heavy in meat, cream and butter, while further south, beyond the central region of Emilia-Romagna, the cooking turns lighter centring around ingredients such as olive oil, tomatoes and fish.</p>
<p>Locals are fiercely proud of their regional specialities, with each town or village proclaiming their local salami or cheese to be the best. Notable regional dishes include Neapolitan pizza, Milanese risotto, Sicilian sardines, Tuscan bean soup, Roman offal, Pugliese bread, Bolognese pasta, Parma ham and Piedmontese truffles.</p>
<p>The secret, of course, is in the ingredients, which are chosen with careful consideration for ripeness, texture and flavour. So eat local and eat seasonal and you&rsquo;ll be hard pressed to have a bad meal.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gnocchi alla Romana:</strong> Known in English as Roman gnocchi, these dumplings are made from rich semolina dough.<br />
<strong>Bagna c&agrave;uda:</strong> A hot dipping sauce from the Piedmont region made with anchovies, garlic, olive oil, butter and occasionally cream.<br />
<strong>Pesto:</strong> A classic Italian sauce combining basil, pine nuts and pecorino cheese.<br />
<strong>Parmigiano-reggiano:</strong> Also known as Parmesan cheese, this hard cow&rsquo;s milk cheese is often shaved over dishes. <br />
<strong>Ossobuco:</strong> A Milanese dish made with veal shanks cooked in a rich tomato and wine broth.<br />
<strong>Rag&ugrave;:</strong> A thick, slow-cooked meat sauce from Bologna served in lasagne, with tagliatelle or other types of pasta.<br />
<strong>Porchetta:</strong> A succulent pork roast infused with herbs, garlic and fennel, and encased in a crackling skin.<br />
<strong>Panettone:</strong> An Italian Christmas cake with sultanas and candied fruit.<br />
<strong>Limoncello:</strong> A lemon-flavoured liqueur from Southern Italy, drank cold as a digestive. <br />
<strong>Campari:</strong> A ruby-red coloured aperitif with a bittersweet flavour. <br />
<strong>Wines:</strong> Celebrated Roman wines include frascati, pinot bianco and pinot grigio (whites); barolo, valpolicella, cabernet and pinot bero (reds). Wine regions of note include Chianti, Montepulciano and Brunello.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Service charges and state taxes are included in all restaurant bills. It is customary to give up to 10% in addition if service has been particularly good.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>16 for beer and wine. 18 for distilled alcohol.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Italy has a rich and diverse nightlife. Youthful university cities such as Milan, Padua, Bologna, Rome, Naples and Catania enjoy a raucous late-night scene with bars kicking off around 2100 and clubs staying open until the early hours of the morning. Many clubs operate within cities during the winter months and decamp to the nearest beach resorts during summer, hence the huge summer scene in Rimini and Grado.</p>
<p>Given Italy&rsquo;s huge cultural legacy, live music in all its forms (classical, jazz, rock, indie, folk and techno) is a regular feature of the calendar with open-air concerts hosted in most major cities and tourist hotspots such as Rome, Verona, Venice, Bologna, Florence and Naples. In Rome, open-air concerts in summer are organised by the Academy of St Cecilia and the Opera House, while there is open-air theatre at the Baths of Caracalla. World-renowned opera houses are La Scala in Milan, La Fenice in Venice, Teatro San Carlo in Naples and Teatro Massimo in Palermo.</p>
<p>In summer, outdoor seating is a given at most restaurants and bars with happy hour (<em>aperitivo</em>) kicking off around 1800 and, in cities such as Milan, continuing as late as 2100. During this period you can expect your drinks to come accompanied by free snacks, some of which run to elaborate, all-you-can-eat buffets. In counterpoint, up in the mountains, there&rsquo;s a lively apr&egrave;s-ski culture.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many Italian products, especially clothes, shoes and bags, are world-famous for their style and quality. Florence, Milan and Rome are important fashion centres. Some places are known for particular products, such as Carrara in Tuscany for marble or Venice for Murano glass. Como is still famous as a centre of silk production and printing, and Cremona in Lombardy is famous for its handmade violins.</p>
<p>In contrast to other industrialised countries Italy&rsquo;s artisans have preserved their heritage crafts and skills in small family-run businesses. The Brianza district north of Milan provides designers in the fashion capital with a highly skilled technical workforce, while huge trade event venues such as Triennale in Milan and Fiera Roma give small-scale manufacturers access to a global marketplace.</p>
<p>Although big brands like Alessi lure shoppers with design classics, the real pleasure is in visiting artisan studios where you can often watch ancient techniques still in practise. In Venice seek out paper marblers and glassblowers, in Milan milliners, in Padua cobblers, in Florence goldsmiths and leatherworkers, in Sardinia knife forgers and in Sicily ceramicists. In a world of cookie-cutter designs, you can be sure that your artisanal Italian purchase won&rsquo;t be matched back home.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0830-1230 and 1530-1930, with some variations in northern Italy where the lunch break is shorter and the shops close earlier. Department stores stay open throughout the day.</p><p>In most tourist towns in Italy you&rsquo;ll see street vendors hawking designer knockoffs, anything from sunglasses to handbags. This kind of street selling is illegal all over Italy and it could land you with a hefty fine. Products made in Italy should bear the &lsquo;Made in Italy&rsquo; label; likewise specialist products like Murano glass often also bear labels of authenticity. Coral jewellery is popular in southern Italy; shop responsibly and only buy it from reputable dealers who take their stock from legal harvests.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Italy is one of the most popular tourist destinations in Europe and therefore has a wide choice of hotels that suit all tastes and budgets. Charges vary according to class, season, services available and locality. The Italian State Tourist Board publishes the official list of all Italian hotels every year. Service charges are included in the rates. VAT (IVA in Italy) operates in all hotels at 10% (22% in deluxe hotels) on room charges only. In heavily touristed cities, such as Venice and Verona, a tourist tax of &euro;3 per person, per day is also payable. Visitors are required by law to obtain an official receipt when staying at hotels.</p>
<p><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels are graded on a scale of 1 to 5 stars. The term <em>pensione</em> (pension) for a small hotel is no longer in official use in Italy. Instead these are now termed 1, 2 or 3-star hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed &amp; breakfast and home stays (where breakfast is not provided) have become increasingly popular in Italy. Visitors have the opportunity to meet local people in their own homes. Accommodation can range from simple to luxurious.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Italy is one of the most popular tourist destinations in Europe and therefore has a wide choice of hotels that suit all tastes and budgets. Charges vary according to class, season, services available and locality. The Italian State Tourist Board publishes the official list of all Italian hotels every year. Service charges are included in the rates. VAT (IVA in Italy) operates in all hotels at 10% (22% in deluxe hotels) on room charges only. In heavily touristed cities, such as Venice and Verona, a tourist tax of &euro;3 per person, per day is also payable. Visitors are required by law to obtain an official receipt when staying at hotels.</p>
<p><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels are graded on a scale of 1 to 5 stars. The term <em>pensione</em> (pension) for a small hotel is no longer in official use in Italy. Instead these are now termed 1, 2 or 3-star hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Italy is one of the most popular tourist destinations in Europe and therefore has a wide choice of hotels that suit all tastes and budgets. Charges vary according to class, season, services available and locality. The Italian State Tourist Board publishes the official list of all Italian hotels every year. Service charges are included in the rates. VAT (IVA in Italy) operates in all hotels at 10% (22% in deluxe hotels) on room charges only. In heavily touristed cities, such as Venice and Verona, a tourist tax of &euro;3 per person, per day is also payable. Visitors are required by law to obtain an official receipt when staying at hotels.</p>
<p><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels are graded on a scale of 1 to 5 stars. The term <em>pensione</em> (pension) for a small hotel is no longer in official use in Italy. Instead these are now termed 1, 2 or 3-star hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;A good standard of health care is available throughout Italy, although public hospitals tend to be better in the north than the south. Pharmacists sell over-the-counter medication and can advise on minor illnesses. They can also point you in the direction of more specialised help, if required. They keep the same hours as other shops, although some remain open at night on a rotation basis for emergency purposes. A list of those is usually on display in pharmacy windows.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For European visitors who are taken ill or have an accident, free or reduced-cost treatment is available - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). These should be obtained before leaving for Italy. The EHIC gives access to state-provided medical treatment. Travellers from other countries should find out if they are covered by other reciprocal arrangements. Australia, for example, has such an agreement as long as long as citizens carry their Medicare card. In most larger cities, English-speaking doctors or a translator service is usually available. Most dentists are private.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dial 112 for an ambulance in an emergency. For emergency treatment, go to the casualty (&lt;em&gt;pronto soccorso&lt;/em&gt;) section of the nearest public hospital, where you can also get emergency dental treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is generally safe to drink except for some rural areas. The inscription 'Acqua Non Potabile' means water is not drinkable. Milk is generally pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit, vegetables and dairy products are considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organisation (WHO) recommends vaccinations for measles, mumps, rubella, polio, pertussis, pneumococci and hepatitis B.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>In addition, local feast days are held in honour of town patron saints, generally without closure of shops and offices. These include: <br />
<strong><br />
Turin</strong>/<strong>Genoa</strong>/<strong>Florence</strong><strong>:</strong> 24 Jun (St John the Baptist).<br />
<strong>Milan</strong><strong>:</strong> 7 Dec (St Ambrose).<br />
<strong>Siena</strong><strong>:</strong> 2 Jul and 16 Aug, Palio horserace.<br />
<strong>Venice</strong><strong>:</strong> 25 Apr (St Mark).<br />
<strong>Bologna</strong><strong>:</strong> 4 Oct (St Petronius).<br />
<strong>Naples</strong><strong>:</strong> 19 Sep (St Gennaro).<br />
<strong>Bari</strong><strong>:</strong> 6 Dec (St Nichola).<br />
<strong>Palermo</strong><strong>:</strong> 15 Jul (St Rosalia).<br />
<strong>Rome</strong><strong>:</strong> 29 Jun (St Peter).<br />
<strong>Trieste</strong><strong>:</strong> 3 Nov (St Giusto).</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here:</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Liberation Day :
							25 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Republic Day :
							02 June </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>St Stephen's Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Italy is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/united-kingdom/">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragrance, skincare, cosmetics, champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% volume, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Italy by persons over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers (reduced to &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Meat and milk and any derivative products from most non-EU countries, protected animal and plant species, unlicensed firearms and weapons, and counterfeit goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cultural artefacts which are more than 50 years old must be accompanied by an export licence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol ) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of 500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of 2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign money can be changed at banks, railway stations and airports and very often at major hotels (albeit usually at a less advantageous exchange rate).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard, American Express, Cirrus, Maestro and Visa are widely accepted. Some restaurants charge an extra &lsquo;service fee&rsquo; if you pay the bill by credit or debit card &ndash; ask the establishment whether this is the case before using your card.&nbsp;</p><p>ATMs are widely available throughout Italy. Look for the &lsquo;Bancomat&rsquo; sign for machines with multilingual interfaces. Pickpocketing and petty thievery can be problematic in tourist areas, so take care to keep belongings secure and be vigilant when making cash withdrawals.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are rarely accepted even at banks. Expect high exchange rates at banks and at exchange offices. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros, Pounds Sterling or US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These vary from city to city but, in general, Mon-Fri 0830-1330 and 1500-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except British and other&nbsp;EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card.&nbsp;They must, however, still travel with a passport or ID card to prove their identity if necessary.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Certain nationals (but not those listed above) require a transit visa; check with the consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Italy is a member of the Schengen Agreement.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visas are available to short-stay travellers from non-member states (cost: &euro;60/&pound;51.60).&nbsp;Reduced fees are available for some nationalities and for children. The single-entry visa allows travellers to enter the Schengen area once and travel within it. The multiple-entry visa allows you to enter and leave the Schengen area multiple times within the allocated time permitted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: up to 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To apply for a Schengen visa to enter Italy you need to apply in person to the nearest Italian embassy or consulate. All visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you plan on residing in Italy for a longer period of time you will need permission to remain (<em>apermesso di soggiorno</em>).  This entitles you to study and work legally. To apply you will require a valid passport (stamped with your date of entry), a visa issued in your own country (for non-EU citizens) and proof of your ability to support yourself financially. To apply, visit the foreigner&rsquo;s bureau (<em>ufficio stranier</em>) of the local police station. EU citizens do not require any permits to live or work in Italy. However, after three months' continuous residency you must register at the municipal registry office (<em>anagrafe</em>) and provide proof of work or sufficient funds to support yourself.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow five to 10 days for visa processing, though some cases may take longer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you require a visa, you must be able to show sufficient funds to cover your stay in the Schengen area. On average, a budget of &pound;50 per day is recommended. You should submit an original current bank statement covering the three-month period before the date of application for the visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is generally only possible to extend a Schengen visa if proof is provided of serious personal/occupational reasons, humanitarian grounds or <em>force majeure</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A pet passport is required when travelling to Italy with a pet. Dogs, cats or ferrets require an ISO pet microchip and proof of up-to-date vaccinations (including rabies) at least 21 days prior to travel. An accredited veterinarian must then complete the bilingual EU Annex II for Italy form. Dogs also require a leash and a muzzle, and some dangerous breeds may be refused entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[42.768030]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[12.491979]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>301,340 sq km (116,348 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>59,801,004 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>201 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rome.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Italy is a boot-shaped country situated in southern&nbsp;Europe. Jutting out into the Mediterranean Sea, it shares borders with France, Switzerland, Austria and Slovenia in the mountainous north, which contains some of the highest peaks in Europe.</p>
<p>In central Italy, Tuscany has a diverse landscape composed of fertile rolling hills, lush river valleys, minor mountain ranges and a long sandy coastline. To the east is Umbria, known as the &lsquo;green heart of Italy' - hilly with broad plains, olive groves and pines, and Le Marche &ndash; a region of gentle mountains, rivers and small fertile plains.</p>
<p>Further south lies Rome, Italy's capital city. Within its precincts lies Vatican City, the world's smallest country (by landmass). The south of the country is hotter, wilder and much drier than the north, characterised by dry sierras, rocky mountain ranges and volcanic outcrops, including three of Europe&rsquo;s most active volcanoes: Vesuvius, Etna and Stromboli.</p>
<p>Puglia, the &lsquo;heel of the boot', is a mixed landscape of fertile plateaus, expansive olive groves and flat, ochre-coloured plains. The islands of Sicily and Sardinia lie offshore to the southwest and west respectively.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>80% Roman Catholic with Muslim and Protestant minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The social structure is heavily influenced by the Roman Catholic Church and, generally speaking, family ties are stronger than in most other countries in Western Europe. Normal social courtesies should be observed. Dress is casual but smart in most places, and beachwear should be confined to the beach. Conservative clothes are expected when visiting religious buildings and smaller, traditional communities. Formal wear is usually indicated on invitations. Smoking is prohibited in public buildings, transport and cinemas.</p>
<p>When visiting an Italian home for dinner, bring a small gift of sweets or chocolate, and dress well. Let your host lead when sitting and starting the meal. Take a small portion of what is offered as you will surely be cajoled into having another helping. If you do not want more wine, leave your glass full so it cannot be refilled.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs either have two round pins or three pins in a row.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Giuseppe Conte since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Sergio Mattarella since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Five centuries before the Roman Republic conquered the Italian peninsula, the Etruscans and Greeks were tussling for control of Italian ports and fertile farming land. Despite the increasing power of the Greek states in Italy, the growing might of the Roman Empire overwhelmed them by the 2nd century BCE. By 100 CE, Rome was the most powerful city in the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>While the capital prospered, poverty was rife in the provinces and by 400 CE the unwieldy Empire was divided in two, with a second capital established at Constantinople (modern-day Istanbul) in 330. When the Germans and the French Lombards overran Northern Italy, the Papacy established itself as a spiritual and secular force in Rome.</p>
<p>While the south tended towards centralised rule, supporting the Papacy, powerful port cities such as Genoa, Pisa and Venice increasingly ignored edicts from Rome, while rich power centres like Milan, Florence, Bologna and Verona resisted Roman meddling in internal affairs, developing their own forms of government between the 12th and 14th centuries.</p>
<p>These powerful city-states had both the wealth and independence to usher in a dynamic age of thinking known as the Renaissance. Despite the advances of this era, subsequent decades of war and plague were to fatally weaken the ruling dynasties. In 1797, Napoleon conquered Venice ending 700 years of independence and creating the first Kingdom of Italy in 1805.</p>
<p>Inspired by the success of the French Revolution, Italians began to agitate for a fully independent, unified nation, and finally won national independence in 1861.&nbsp;</p>
<p>At the dawn of the 20th century, Italy was embroiled in a devastating, although ultimately successful, territorial skirmish with Austria in WWI. Around 600,000 men died and the country was reduced to poverty. Frustrated by the peace settlement at Versailles, Benito Mussolini and the Fascist Party rose to power on a tide of discontent. The following alliance with the German Nazis in 1940, which brought Italy into WWII, ultimately left the country shut out of any power positions in the latter half of the 20th century.</p>
<p>Despite decades of political turbulence, Italy grew into one of the world&rsquo;s leading economies in the 1980s. High unemployment, corruption and increasing national debt, however, culminated in crisis in 2008 and three years later Silvio Berlusconi was finally toppled from office. In February 2014, 39-year-old Matteo Renzi, the youngest Italian prime minister in history, was sworn in. He was replaced by&nbsp;Paolo Gentiloni in December 2016.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Tourists fling an estimated &euro;3,000 (&pound;2,540) into the Trevi Fountain every day. This money is collected and donated to charity.<br />
&bull; Italy is home to three active volcanoes: Etna, Stromboli and Vesuvius. Etna is among the world&rsquo;s most active volcanos and has been erupting on and off for the past 3,500 years.<br />
&bull; With 51 UNESCO World Heritage Sites to its name, Italy has more than any other country in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Italian Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 612 4400. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambwashingtondc.esteri.it</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 612 4400. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1630 (visas by appointment only).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>3000 Whitehaven Street NW<br/>Washington DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Italy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+39 6 4220 0001.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-rome</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+39 6 4220 0001.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;By appointment only.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Via Venti Settembre 80A<br/>Rome<br/>00187<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Italian Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7312 2200. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.amblondra.esteri.it</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7312 2200. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;By appointment only.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Mayfair<br/>14 Three Kings Yard<br/>London<br/>W1K 4EH<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travelling around Italy remains one of those rare experiences in life &ndash; like a perfect spring day or the power of first love &ndash; that can never be overrated. In few places do history, art, fashion, food and <em>la dolce vita</em> (&ldquo;the good life&rdquo;) intermingle so effortlessly. In Italy you'll find sunny isles, glacial lakes and fiery volcanoes, rolling vineyards and urban landscapes harbouring more UNESCO World Heritage sites than any other country on Earth. Few places offer such variety and few visitors leave without a fervent desire to return.</p>
<p>The artistic and architectural treasures of Rome, Venice, Florence and Naples draw visitors to them like moths to a flame. Not content with Romans conquering most of the known world, the Venetians dispatched Marco Polo to uncharted lands off the map, while Giotto, Leonardo da Vinci, Brunelleschi and Michelangelo kick-started the Renaissance in Western art and architecture.</p>
<p>Look around at all the splendid palaces, paintings, churches and monuments and wonder at the centuries of hard graft and the unswerving devotion to traditional techniques. Like the local art, wine is also designed to elevate your spirits. From the neatly-banded stone terraces of the Cinque Terre, which snake from sea level to terrifying precipices, to the blousy hillsides of Chianti, the riverine plain of the Po valley and the volcanic slopes of Etna, Italian wines are lovingly made to complement the carefully-sourced regional cuisine on your plate.</p>
<p>Much like its food, this country is an endless feast of experiences. No matter how much you gorge yourself, you&rsquo;ll always feel as though you're still on the first course. Do you go skiing in the Dolomites, or cycling in wine country? Do you dive the sun-split waters of Sardinia, climb Aeolian volcanoes or stalk market stalls in Naples? The choice is dazzling and bewildering. So take the advice of the locals. Slow down, sit back, tuck in that napkin and get ready to begin.</p><p>Travelling around Italy remains one of those rare experiences in life &ndash; like a perfect spring day or the power of first love &ndash; that can never be overrated. In few places do history, art, fashion, food and <em>la dolce vita</em> (&ldquo;the good life&rdquo;) intermingle so effortlessly. In Italy you'll find sunny isles, glacial lakes and fiery volcanoes, rolling vineyards and urban landscapes harbouring more UNESCO World Heritage sites than any other country on Earth. Few places offer such variety and few visitors leave without a fervent desire to return.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
