<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Ivory Coast" ColCode="civ" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ci" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Ivory Coast]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dry from December to April, long rains from May to July, a short dry season from August to September, short rains in October and November. In the north the climate is more extreme - rains (May to October) and dry (November to April).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical lightweights; warmer clothing for evenings. A light raincoat in the rainy season and a hat for the sun. Casual wear is widely acceptable but beachwear should be confined to the beach or poolside. Dress tends to err on conservative - men wearing long trousers and women wearing knee-length or longer skirts, dresses and trousers. Ties need only be worn for formal occasions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire (<a href="http://www.aircotedivoire.com" target="_blank">www.aircotedivoire.com</a>) operates domestic flights in Ivory Coast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Abidjan-Ouagadougou railway is one of the most efficient in Africa and runs trains daily from Abidjan to Bouak&eacute; and Ferkess&eacute;dougou.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Road conditions are poor, but improving, especially in the capital, where new roads and bridges have been constructed. Drivers should be aware of potholes, poorly lit vehicles and bad driving. Many roads become impassable during the rainy season (May to November).&nbsp;Petrol stations are frequent except in the north.</p><p>These are available in main cities, although are often of unsound mechanical condition.</p><p>Insurance is compulsory for the driver. The driver requires a national driving licence, accompanied by attestation from the embassy of the issuing country that it is genuine.</p><p>You can hire cars in Abidjan, main towns and at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Extensive bus and boat services are operated in Abidjan by SOTRA<em>&nbsp;</em>(<a href="http://www.sotra.ci" target="_blank">www.sotra.ci</a>). Taxis are usually red and metered; rates are doubled from 0000-0600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Ivory Coast</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">san_pedro</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Ivory Coast</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">odienne</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Ivory Coast</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">man</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Ivory Coast</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bondoukou</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The quickest route from the UK to Ivory Coast is with Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) via Paris or Brussels Airlines (<a href="http://www.brusselsairlines.com" target="_blank">www.brusselsairlines.com</a>) via Brussels.&nbsp;Other airlines operating flights to Ivory Coast include Emirates (<a href="http://www.emirates.com" target="_blank">www.emirates.com</a>), Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="http://www.ethiopianairlines.com" target="_blank">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>) and Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a href="http://i/ivory-coast/abidjan-international-airport-felix-houphouet-boigny">Abidjan Félix Houphouët-Boigny</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 9 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 14 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>XOF3,000 for African destinations and XOF5,000 for all other departures (from Abidjan airport - prices differ according to airport flown from).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Abidjan Félix Houphouët-Boigny International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.abidjan-aeropart.com<p>Abidjan F&eacute;lix Houphou&euml;t-Boigny International Airport is located 16km (10 miles) southeast of Abidjan.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+225 2175 7900</p>]]><b>Yamoussoukro Airport</b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:&nbsp;</strong>Abidjan  is the main port in Ivory Coast; however, there are no regular passenger sailings. Cargo liners provide limited accommodation for passengers travelling from Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Abidjan-Niger Railway extends to Burkino Faso. There are two through-trains with sleeping and restaurant cars from Abidjan to Ouagadougou (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/burkina-faso">Burkina Faso</a>) daily (journey time - 25 to 27 hours). Those intending to travel should be aware that the Burkina Faso rail network is under constant threat of closure because of financial difficulties; check with the appropriate authorities before finalising arrangements.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International telecommunications are available in major towns and centres.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone operators.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public access is available at Internet cafes in Abidjan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government has used the media under its control, particularly the state broadcaster Radiodiffusion Télévision Ivoirienne (RTI), as a powerful tool in the country's ongoing crisis. As Ivorian forces launched attacks on rebels in the north in late 2004, state media fell into propaganda while opposition and independent newspapers based in Abidjan were raided and ceased publication. <br /><br />FM relays of foreign stations in the city such as the <em>BBC</em>, <em>Radio France Internationale</em> and <em>Africa No1</em> were disrupted. Radio is Côte d'Ivoire's most-popular medium. There are approximately 30 low-power, non-commercial community radio stations, including some run by the Catholic Church. <br /><br />There are no private terrestrial TV stations, although pay-TV services are provided by Canal Satellite Horizons. Rebels in the centre of the country use state radio and TV facilities in Bouake for their own broadcasts. In August 2004, UN peacekeepers launched their own radio station, <em>ONUCI FM</em>. The station is now available in Abidjan and rebel-held towns in the north.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes up to two weeks.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1200 and 1430-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be impressed by the capital, Yamoussoukro</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the city's lively market, the mosque and the palace of the president, not to mention the exquisite Cathédrale Notre-Dame-de-la-Paix. Fractionally smaller than St Peter's in Rome, it incorporates a greater area of stained glass than the total area of stained glass in France. Yamoussoukro was the birthplace of President Félix Houphouët-Boigny. The cathedral was paid for almost entirely out of his own pocket.</p>]]><p><b>Escape to the beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>About 100km (60 miles) east of Abidjan is the beach resort of Assouinde. Also not too far from the city is Grand Bassam, whose sandy beaches make the place a favourite weekend retreat for the inhabitants of Abidjan. Note that in Abidjan and the surrounding coastal resorts, there is a dangerous deep current and swimmers should stay near the shore.</p>]]><p><b>Go Fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There is good coastal and river fishing in Côte d'Ivoire. Red carp, barracuda, mullet and sole can all be caught from the shores of the lagoons. Sea trips can be organised through travel agencies to catch swordfish, bonito and marlin. Boats and instructors are available in Abidjan, where waterskiing and sailing are also available.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the bright lights of Abidjan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The former capital and largest city, Abidjan, comes as a pleasant surprise to many visitors. The glistening downtown is a place of bright lights and lofty skyscrapers, while the more traditional Old Town, Treichville, is home to many bars, restaurants and nightclubs, plus the colourful central market. There is a very good museum, the Ifon Museum, as well as the National Museum containing historic artefacts, statues and ivory.</p>]]><p><b>Spot African wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The largest and oldest national park in Côte d'Ivoire is Comoë National Park, in the northeast, where lions, waterbucks, hippos and other animals can be seen frolicking in their natural habitat. The Abokouamekro Game Reserve is another great spot for wildlife watching and is one of the more accessible parks, about an hour outside Yamoussoukro. Most national parks in Côte d'Ivoire are largely inaccessible for visitors without their own vehicles.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hike</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The verdant hills surrounding Man, nicknamed the 'City of 18 Mountains', are a joy for hikers. As well as harbouring some of the last remaining rainforest in Côte d'Ivoire, these lofty ranges are also home to Mount Tonkoui, whose 1,223m (4,012ft) summit offers views over Liberia and Guinea. Guides are necessary for longer walks.</p>]]><p><b>Tour the provinces</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a trip around Côte d'Ivoire. Places worth visiting include Korhogo, the main city in the north, which is notable for its woodcarving and handicrafts. The former capital of Bingerville, with its idyllic, lagoon-side setting, and the town of Bouaké, also renowned for its crafts, are also worth a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Walk to a waterfall</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From Man you can visit La Cascade, a pretty waterfall that crashes into a bamboo forest, 5km (3 miles) from town. The falls are accessed via a paved pathway, which offers a pleasant walk through the forests. Hikers can expect to receive a warm welcome if they take a detour to the villages of Biankouma and Gouessesso.</p>]]><p><b>Watch some stilt dancing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dancers in Côte d'Ivoire perform incredible acrobatics on stilts as part of time-honoured ceremonial dances. Often performed at weddings, funerals or the arrival of an important person, these rituals are performed by children as young as seven. Visits to stilt dancing performances can be arranged from Man.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$15.9 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cocoa, coffee, timber, rubber, cotton, palm oil, pineapples and bananas.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Consumer goods, food and capital goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, France, Germany, The Netherlands, Nigeria and Italy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The timber industry in Côte d'Ivoire has declined from previous levels due to excessive exploitation, although the government has now limited production in order to protect the remaining forests. A light industrial sector has grown up processing primary agricultural products and produces textiles, chemicals and sugar - again, these are aimed towards export markets.<br /><br />Newly discovered offshore oil and gas deposits will boost the country's industrial sector as well as meeting future energy needs. Côte d'Ivoire already has an established oil refining operation which, along with cigarette manufacture, forms the main components of the country's industrial economy. It will also reduce Côte d'Ivoire's reliance on imported fuel to supplement the hydroelectric installations that are its main source of power.<br /><br />A service sector is gradually developing, centred on tourism, financial services (exploiting the dominant role of the Abidjan stock exchange in the region) and telecommunications.<br /><br />Côte d'Ivoire is one of the more prosperous economies in West Africa, although its recent progress has been undermined by severe political instability and the difficulty in meeting the standards of international donors; the economy grew by just 1% in 2004.<br /> <br />The country is a member of all the main regional economic organisations, including the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) and the various bodies associated with the CFA Franc zone. <br />In Abidjan, the Palais des Congrès which is part of the Inter-Continental Hotel can host conferences for more than 3,000 persons. The political capital Yamoussoukro has a capacity for over 5,000. For details, contact the Office Ivoirien du Tourisme et de l'Hôtellerie (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>French is predominantly used in business circles, although executives in larger businesses may speak English. Translators are generally available. Punctuality is expected, although the host may be late. Business cards are essential and given to each person met. It is usual for business visitors to be entertained by local hosts in a hotel or restaurant. Lightweight suits should be worn. <br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1200 and 1430-1800, Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie de Côte d'Ivoire</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 2033 1600
					Website:http://www.ccici.org
					Address: 6 avenue Joseph Anoma,01 BP 1399,Abidjan 01,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Abidjan and other large centres have restaurants serving Caribbean, French, Italian, Lebanese and Vietnamese food. There is a growing number of African restaurants catering for foreigners. The best area for spicy African food is the Treichville district of Abidjan. The blue pages of the Abidjan telephone book have a special restaurant section. There are no restrictions on drinking.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Kedjenou:</strong> Chicken cooked with different vegetables in a stew and sometimes sealed in banana leaves.<br />
<strong>N'voufou:</strong> Mashed bananas or yam mixed with palm oil and served with aubergine sauce.<br />
<strong>Attiek&eacute;:</strong> Grated cassava similar to couscous often served as an accompaniment to barbequed meat.<br />
<strong>Alloco:</strong> Plantain fried in palm oil served with a spicy sauce of onions and chilli is often eaten as a snack with a hard-boiled egg.<br />
<strong>Foufou:</strong> Fermented and mashed cassava served as an accompaniment to soup or meat.<br />
<strong>Maafe:</strong> Meat cooked in a peanut sauce usually served with rice.<br />
<strong>Land snails:</strong> Huge snails often grilled or eaten in a sauce.<br />
<strong>Pouletbicyclette:</strong> Guinea fowl, usually served grilled.<br />
<strong>Barbequed chicken or fish:</strong> Typically served with onions and tomatoes. <br />
<strong>Bangui:</strong> Local palm wine.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels and restaurants include a service charge in the bill; if not, 15% is acceptable.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are nightclubs in most major centres. Abidjan is the most lively area with its hotels and lagoon-side tourist resorts. There are also theatres, casinos and bars. Traditional entertainment is offered in some hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the markets, hard bargaining is often necessary to get prices down to reasonable levels. Special purchases include wax prints, Ghanaian <em>kente</em> cloth, indigo fabric and woven cloth, wooden statuettes and masks, bead necklaces, pottery and basketware.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1430-1830, Sat 0800-1200 and 1500-1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels and restaurants are expensive in the larger towns. There are several hotels of international standard in Abidjan. In general, there is a choice between luxury, medium-range and cheaper accommodation in the larger towns. In all cases it is advisable to book in advance. For further information, contact the Office Ivoirien du Tourisme et de l'Hôtellerie (see <em>Accommodation Information </em>below). <br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded from <strong>1</strong> to <strong>5 stars</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels and restaurants are expensive in the larger towns. There are several hotels of international standard in Abidjan. In general, there is a choice between luxury, medium-range and cheaper accommodation in the larger towns. In all cases it is advisable to book in advance. For further information, contact the Office Ivoirien du Tourisme et de l'Hôtellerie (see <em>Accommodation Information </em>below). <br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded from <strong>1</strong> to <strong>5 stars</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels and restaurants are expensive in the larger towns. There are several hotels of international standard in Abidjan. In general, there is a choice between luxury, medium-range and cheaper accommodation in the larger towns. In all cases it is advisable to book in advance. For further information, contact the Office Ivoirien du Tourisme et de l'Hôtellerie (see <em>Accommodation Information </em>below). <br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded from <strong>1</strong> to <strong>5 stars</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health care facilities in the main towns are up to international standards but expensive; medical insurance is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Hepatitis B is hyperendemic and hepatitis E is widespread. Meningitis risk is present depending on area visited and time of year. There is a high incidence of HIV/AIDS. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are often observed the following Monday.<br /><br />Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Korité (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Korité itself. Korité and Tabaski (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							07 August </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into the Ivory Coast by travellers aged 15 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 25 cigars or 150g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of alcoholic drink.<br />
&bull; 380ml of eau de toilette. <br />
&bull; 75ml of perfume.&nbsp;<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of XOF10,000 (XOF5,000 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted items include arms and ammunition, drugs, and printed materials which have been banned by the government.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFA (<em>Communauté Financière Africaine</em>) Franc (XOF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of XOF10,000, 5,000, 2,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of XOF250, 100, 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1. Côte d'Ivoire is part of the French Monetary Area. <br /><br />Only currency issued by the <em>Banque des États de l'Afrique de l'Ouest </em>(Bank of West African States) is valid; currency issued by the <em>Banque des États de l'Afrique Centrale </em>(Bank of Central African States) is not. The CFA Franc is tied to the Euro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency can be exchanged at the airport as well as at main banks and hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express and MasterCard are widely accepted; Diners Club and Visa have more limited use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are accepted in hotels, restaurants and some shops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1300 and 1400-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay tourist visa: &euro;50 (if collecting from the embassy) or &euro;70 (if collecting at the airport); long-stay visa: &euro;130.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay tourist visa: up to three months; long-stay visa: six months to one year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). Nationals of some countries (including the UK) can apply online (<a href="http://www.snedai.com/en">www.snedai.com/en</a>) and then either collect the visa either from the embassy or at the airport in Abidjan. It's advisable to check with the embassy whether you're eligible for the airport visa pick-up.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 48 hours for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[7.598976]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-5.552997]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>322,462 sq km (124,503 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>23,254,184 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>72.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Yamoussoukro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire shares borders with Liberia, Guinea, Mali, Burkina Faso and Ghana. There are 600km (370 miles) of coast on the Gulf of Guinea (Atlantic Ocean). The southern and western parts of the country are forested, with undulating countryside rising to meet the savannah plains of the north and the mountainous western border. Three rivers, the Sassandra, the Bandama and the Como&eacute;, run directly north-south and, on their approach to the coast, flow into a series of lagoons. Birdlife is plentiful throughout the country, but particularly so near the coast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>34% Christian, 27% Muslim, 15% traditional beliefs. It is important to note, however, that these percentages are based on census results in 1998, of which some Muslim foreign workers may have been excluded - therefore, the Muslim percentage may be higher than is indicated here.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One of the most striking features of Côte d'Ivoire, distinguishing it from many other African countries, is the extreme ethnic and linguistic variety. The size of each of the 60 groups - which include the Akar, Kron, Nzima, Hone, Voltaic and Malinke peoples - varies widely and the area they occupy may cover a whole region. With very few exceptions every Ivoirian has a mother tongue which is that of the village, along with traditions, family and social relations within their ethnic group. French has become the official language of schools, cities and government and therefore has an influence on lifestyle even at a modest level. Handshaking is normal. <br /><br />Small tokens of appreciation, a souvenir from home or a business gift with the company logo are always welcome. Normal courtesies should be observed and it is considered polite to arrive punctually for social occasions. Snakes are regarded as sacred by some ethnic groups.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Amadou Gon Coulibaly since January 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Alassane Ouattara since 2010.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>During Medieval times, the region that is now C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire was at the centre of several major African trade routes, linking empires in Ghana and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mali">Mali</a>. Malinke merchants brought Islam to the region.</p>
<p>European traders had been present since the 15th century, but it was not until the 19th that the French undertook a determined penetration of the region. C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire was incorporated into French West Africa until it was granted independence in 1960.</p>
<p>At independence, F&eacute;lix Houphou&euml;t-Boigny became president, an eccentric and effective politician who dominated political life for the next 33 years through the Democratic Party of C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire (PDCI). He died in December 1993 and was replaced by Henri Konan B&eacute;di&eacute;.</p>
<p>Victory at the 1995 presidential poll, and for the PDCI at the parliamentary elections, pointed to a seamless succession. However, problems began with serious industrial unrest and the highly unpopular military intervention in the Liberian civil war.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, a military coup in December 1999, organised by General Robert Gue&iuml;, was unexpected. An ex-minister loosely allied to Ouatarra, Gue&iuml; established a new military regime. Presidential elections were held in October 2000; the principal contenders were Gue&iuml; and Laurent Gbagbo, standing for the Ivorian Popular Front, whose main constituency is among Christians in the south.</p>
<p>When Gue&iuml; tried to manipulate the result, he was driven into exile (where he died), leaving Gbagbo as the winner. The Rally of the Republicans (RDR) candidate, Ouattara, had been blocked from standing in the election, infuriating northern Muslims and sparking unrest.</p>
<p>A new government, in which Ouattara's RDR was given four ministerial posts, was set up in 2002. However, fighting broke out between pro-government forces and dissident army units, and continued until 2004 with the country divided between the rebel-held north and a government-held south. In 2007 the two sides agreed to elections, but they were not held until 2010.</p>
<p>Both Gbagbo and Ouattara claimed victory in the 2010 elections leading to violence. Gbagbo was eventually arrested and handed over to the International Criminal Court where he is being tried for triggering political unrest. Ouattara became president and has since been re-elected in a peaceful election in 2015.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Ivory Coast is the world&rsquo;s largest cocoa producer.<br />
&bull; The Basilica of Our Lady of Peace in Yamoussoukro is the largest church in the world.<br />
&bull; The official language of Ivory Coast is French, but it is estimated that 65 languages are spoken in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Côte d'Ivoire in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 797 0300.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 797 0300.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2424 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Côte d'Ivoire in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 6991.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 6991.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1230; 1500-1730 (visa application); 1400-1730 (visa collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2 Upper Belgrave St<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8BJ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ivory Coast is a country of extremes; a land of pulsating metropolises and pristine rainforests, vast churches and verdant hills, fancy restaurants and sprawling street stalls. Its reputation might be sullied by the recent civil war, but most areas are now stable and ripe for discovery.</p>
<p>Coastal Abidjan is the unofficial capital and the entry point for most travellers. The French influence is clear to see here, not least in the food, which is served in some bistros with the kind of pomp you might expect in downtown Paris. These eateries are a stark contrast to the traditional <em>maquis</em> restaurants, which sprawl out onto the city&rsquo;s bustling streets. Pull up a plastic pew, order some food and share a meal with locals.</p>
<p>Dubbed the &ldquo;Manhattan of Africa&rdquo; the gleaming skyscrapers and manicured gardens of The Plateau give downtown Abidjan a decidedly modern feel. This commercial district is also home to St Paul&rsquo;s Cathedral, which boasts impressive stained glass windows and great views across the city.</p>
<p>While most of the action takes place in Abidjan, Yamoussoukro is the official capital. It is notable for its massive mosque and even bigger Basilica of Our Lady of Peace, which is the largest church in the world. Football is also a religion here and watching The Elephants, the national football team, offers a memorable day out for sports fans.</p>
<p>Ivory Coast&rsquo;s true beauty really shines through when you get out of the cities. There are no fewer than eight national parks in the country, including Como&eacute;, the largest protected area in West Africa, which boasts the most biodiverse savannah in the world. Expect to see anything from lions and leopards to aardvarks and African elephants.&nbsp;The pygmy hippos of Tai National Park are also a big draw for naturalists, while the beautiful beaches around San Pedro,Assine and Grand Bassam attract bathers of all stripes.</p>
<p>Sure, Ivory Coast has had its problems, but a sanguine spirit is binding this country together again and putting it back on the map.</p><p>Ivory Coast is a country of extremes; a land of pulsating metropolises and pristine rainforests, vast churches and verdant hills, fancy restaurants and sprawling street stalls. Its reputation might be sullied by the recent civil war, but most areas are now stable and ripe for discovery.</p>
<p>Coastal Abidjan is the unofficial capital and the entry point for most travellers. The French influence is clear to see here, not least in the food, which is served in some bistros with the kind of pomp you might expect in downtown Paris. These eateries are a stark contrast to the traditional <em>maquis</em> restaurants, which sprawl out onto the city&rsquo;s bustling streets. Pull up a plastic pew, order some food and share a meal with locals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
