<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Jamaica" ColCode="jam" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="jm" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Jamaica]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consistently warm tropical weather ensures Jamaica is a popular destination year-round. On the coast, temperatures range from 22&deg;C (72&deg;F) and 31&deg;C (88&deg;F) with chilly mornings and evenings denoting winter. However, many people say the best time to visit is November to mid-December because of the pleasant weather and available hotel and flight deals. Peak season runs roughly from mid-December to mid-April when crowds swell and prices rise. The wettest months are May and October, but showers may occur at any time. Between June and November, Jamaica is prone to hurricanes. It also lies within the earthquake zone.  <br />
<br />
The annual rainfall averages 1980mm, but nationwide there are some considerable variations, with the east coast receiving considerably more rain than elsewhere on the island. Parts of the Blue Mountains receive an average of 7620mm a year. By contrast, the south coast sees little rain and in places is semi-barren. Jamaica is a year-round destination, though there are seasonal differences to consider. Weather-wise, temperature isn&rsquo;t an important factor: winter is usually warm by day and mild to cool by night, and summer months are simply hot.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pack lightweight cottons and casual linens. Light woollens are advised for evenings when mosquitoes can make long sleeves more appealing than skimpy beachwear. Sunhats and waterproofs are handy all year round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>AirLink Express (<a href="http://www.intlairlink.net" target="_blank">www.intlairlink.net</a>) runs domestic flights within Jamaica.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferry services run between a few selected destination points on the island. There&rsquo;s a fast catamaran between Kingston and Port Royal, and from Port Antonio a short ferry journey takes sightseers out to Navy Island. Kingston is the island's largest port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jamaica&rsquo;s road network covers the whole island and consists of some 21,000km of roads. Hiring a car or scooter is a good way of seeing the island but extra care should be taken, especially after dark, as many of the islands roads are in a poor state of repair.</p>
<p>Some important considerations before setting out are: vehicles drive on the left, the country has a poor road safety record, and pedestrians, animals and erratic drivers can all prove hazards, petrol stations accept cash only, and child safety equipment is not usually provided.</p>l<p>Although reliable services connect Kingston and Montego Bay, the rest of the island's bus schedule is patchy. The Jamaica Union of Travellers Association (JUTA) (tel: +1 876 972 4534; <a href="http://www.jutatourskingstonjm.com" target="_blank">www.jutatourskingstonjm.com</a>) is the largest operator of scheduled and unscheduled bus/minibus and vehicle charter services aimed at tourists.</p><p>Rates are per car, not per passenger, with taxis hailed on the street or booked by phone. Technically, most are supposed to have meters, but it's worth agreeing on a price for the trip ahead of departure. Fares should be displayed inside the taxi but add 25% if it's after midnight. Taxis with red plates marked PPV (Public Passenger Vehicle) charge fixed rates with a 10 to 12% tip usually added. Most hotels and resorts have assigned Jamaica Tourist Board (JTB) drivers who carry photo ID and display a prominent blue JTB sticker on the front windscreen.</p><p>Drivers can use a full UK driving licence for up to 12 months or a North American licence for up to three months.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas and 80kph (50mph) outside the main towns. Seat belts must be worn at all times and children under three years must sit in a child seat.</p><p>&nbsp;The Jamaica Automobile Association (+1 888 CALLJAA; <a href="http://www.calljaa.com">www.calljaa.com</a>) offers roadside assistance.</p><p>Car hire firms can be found in major towns, hotels and airports and most offer unlimited mileage. A general consumption tax of 16.5% is applied to all car hire transactions, and it&rsquo;s recommended to seek a rental with inclusive insurance and breakdown coverage. Drivers must be aged 25 or over, have a valid driving licence from another country and a valid credit card. The Jamaica Tourist Board offers one of the most comprehensive road maps of the island.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas and 80kph (50mph) outside the main towns. Seat belts must be worn at all times and children under three years must sit in a child seat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kingston operates an erratic bus service. Most transport in the capital and other major towns is by private &lsquo;route taxi&rsquo;, usually shared minibuses that can be flagged down as they pass. They can get exceptionally crowded, but fares charged are somewhere between local bus and private cab rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Jamaica</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">port_antonio</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Jamaica</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ocho_rios</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Jamaica</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">negril</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Jamaica</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kingston</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>British Airways (<a href="https://www.britishairways.com">www.britishairways.com</a>) flies&nbsp;between London Gatwick&nbsp;and Kingston. Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) flies direct from London Gatwick to Montego Bay. Airlines offering direct flights to Jamaica from the USA include&nbsp;Caribbean Airlines (<a href="http://www.caribbean-airlines.com" target="_blank">www.caribbean-airlines.com</a>), Fly Jamaica (<a href="http://www.fly-jamaica.com" target="_blank">www.fly-jamaica.com</a>), JetBlue (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>) and&nbsp;United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>).</p>
<p>Mid-April to early December is the cheapest period to fly to Jamaica with some fares cut by up to 60%. The rest of the year is high season, the most expensive period for flights.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jamaica/montego-bay-sangster-international-airport">Montego Bay Sangster International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jamaica/norman-manley-kingston-international-airport">Kingston Norman Manley International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours; New York - 4 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$35 and must be paid in cash &ndash; however many tickets include this tax in their price, so check first.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Kingston Norman Manley International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.nmia.aero<p>Kingston Norman Manley International Airport is situated on the Palisadoes tombolo in outer Kingston Harbour, 19km (11 miles) southeast of Kingston&rsquo;s city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(876) 9248 4526.</p>]]><b>Montego Bay Sangster International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.mbjairport.com<p>Montego Bay Sangster International Airport is located 5km (3 miles) east of Montego Bay.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 876 952 3124</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montego Bay, Falmouth and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ocho-rios">Ocho Rios</a> are ports of call for several cruise lines. Other passenger/freight lines (Geest) sail from North, South and Central American ports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes. Prepaid international phone cards make the cost of making and international call from a Jamaican land line less expensive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the population now use mobile phones as the preferred option to landlines. Several roaming agreements exist with a number of international mobile phone networks. Some companies offer handsets for short-term rental on a per-day basis. For approximately US$30.00 you can buy a cell phone here to use with phone cards, without the need for a contract.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As well as numerous cyber cafes, Kingston has several internet kiosks offering free internet connections in shopping malls throughout the city. In rural and resort areas, internet is also available in many hotels, tourist offices and libraries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jamaica enjoys a free press and its newspapers frequently criticise the establishment. The broadcast media are predominantly commercial with three terrestrial TV broadcasters and a handful of local cable channels. The main newspapers are privately owned.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jamaica has two main post offices, one in Kingston and one in Montego Bay. Airmail takes two to three weeks to reach Europe.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Dunn's River Falls</p><![CDATA[<p>Located in a dense tropical forest, Dunn's River Falls is Jamaica's most famous attraction. This Caribbean paradise consists of a number of waterfalls, which cascade over rock terraces down to the Caribbean Sea below, and beautiful natural pools that have formed in the rockface. The falls are shallow enough to enable visitors to climb the 183m (600ft) limestone tiers to reach a tropical shower, from where they can enjoy panoramic views of the surrounding area. There are beautiful beaches at the bottom of these magnificent falls that are also famous for featuring in the first James Bond film, 'Dr No'.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire Shaw Park’s floral splendours</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Jamaica is world famous for its landscaped gardening, so if you want to see some vibrant blooms check out Shaw Park Botanical Gardens, a 10-hectare (25-acre) collection of exotic Caribbean flora, which includes bougainvillea and hibiscus, the national flower. Situated on a hilltop with great views over Ocho Rios and the Caribbean Sea, the gardens' centrepiece is a waterfall, tumbling through banks of flowers.</p>]]><p><b>Dip into Milk River Spa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a rejuvenating dip in the curative waters of the Milk River, which feeds a government-owned spa nearby. Discovered in 1794, these spring-fed therapeutic waters reach temperatures of 33°C (86°F), relieving ailments such as arthritis and lumbago.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Treasure Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This isolated oasis comprises three golden sandy bays on the south of the island, where palm fronds sway, azure waters lap, and local fisherman sail their colourful boats to fish amongst the cays on the horizon. Far from the package tour circuit, this is the Jamaican paradise you saw in the brochure before you came.</p>]]><p><b>Dive into the underwater gardens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Jamaica's coast is lined with some magical underwater gardens, featuring sunken wrecks, black coral and rope sponge, hosting a multitude of multi-coloured tropical fish. One of the best is Montego Bay Marine Park, located along the west and north coasts. Montego Bay's waters are protected, and, amidst its caverns and reefs, you can spot nurse sharks, eagle rays, jellyfish, tobacco fish and snapper.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the backcountry villages</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hundreds of trails connect the villages and settlements in Jamaica's mountainous interior, including several utilitarian paths around Newcastle on the Kingston to Buff Bay Road, where trails lead to Catherine's Peak and Mount Horeb. Cockpit Country, in the northwest, has some fascinating historic routes, but be sure to go with a guided group, as paths are not well sign-posted.</p>]]><p><b>Follow in the footsteps of Columbus</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Showcasing relics of Jamaican history, Columbus Park is a commemorative park near Discovery Bay that marks the 1494 landing of Christopher Columbus. Only opened in 2014, the small gardens features historic exhibits such as an old locomotive, aqueduct and a replica of a Taino canoe.</p>]]><p><b>Get smart in Kingston</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The reputation of the Jamaican capital may include street crime and edgy shantytowns, but for a real insight into its island life nowhere else will do. Stay smart and you'll enjoy a fascinating and authentic experience encompassing grand historical sights, a beautiful harbour-front, frenetic markets and pulsating nightlife.</p>]]><p><b>Go on a Bob Marley pilgrimage</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Jamaica's most famous export is reggae and nobody on the island has done more to popularise this genre of music than Bob Marley. He lived in a modest wooden house at 56 Hope Road in Kingston, which has become something of a shrine to the dreadlocked star. Marley recorded some of his best-loved tracks at this address, which now serves as a museum and pilgrimage site for music fans.</p>]]><p><b>Hike up the Blue Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Follow one of many hiking and climbing trails up the Blue Mountains to heights above 2,100m (7,000ft). The stunning landscape ranges from gently sloping coffee plantations to dwarf cloud forest fringing the peak. Shrouded by mists that give the peaks their bluish tinge, the Blue Mountains are home to more than 200 bird species and 800 species of plants.</p>]]><p><b>Party all night in Montego Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Chill out or party hard Jamaican-style in Montego Bay, the island's most buzzing city. Whether you lounge all day on Doctor's Cave Beach or cruise through the gaudy delights of Gloucester, you'll be joining the crowds in Jamaica's biggest mass tourism destination. Once you've sampled its treats you may not make it any further.</p>]]><p><b>Peer over Lover's Leap</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A sheer 518m (1,700ft) cliff overhanging Cutlass Bay on the south coast, Lover's Leap was named after two slave lovers, Mizzy and Tunkey, who chose to jump to their deaths rather than be separated. If you get vertigo, stand well away from the edge – the view is terrifying. A statue of the ill-fated couple stands on the cliff-top.</p>]]><p><b>Raft the Rio Grande</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore one of Jamaica's largest rivers with a leisurely ride through banana and sugar cane plantations on a bamboo raft originally used to transport the crop down to Port Antonio. Set off along the Rio Grande, from the peaks of the Blue Mountains at Berrydale before winding down through the tropical vegetation to St Margaret's Bay.</p>]]><p><b>Shimmy to Soca at Carnival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take to the streets to witness Jamaica's riotous fun-filled Bacchanal Carnival, held annually in Kingston. Parading musicians, skimpily dressed dancers and floats typify this world famous street party, which starts in January, building up to the Road March and Parade after Easter. Expect outlandish behaviour to the sounds of Soca, steel bands and beating drums.</p>]]><p><b>Spelunk through limestone caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Check out a huge labyrinth of limestone caves on Jamaica's north coast, a stunning natural phenomenon characterised by stalactites, stalagmites, overhead crags, tunnels, light holes and a subterranean lake. The Green Grotto was once used as shelter by the Arawak Indians (Tainos), Jamaica's now extinct original inhabitants. You can join a guided tour from nearby Ocho Rios or Montego Bay.</p>]]><p><b>Sun and fun in Negril</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You can find Jamaica's finest beaches in <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/caribbean/jamaica/negril-beaches/">Negril</a> on the western coast. This laid-back town is renowned for its gorgeous sunsets and its beautiful Seven Mile Beach (roughly 11km/7 miles) with aqua blue water and white sand. The coral reefs and caves along the coast attract scuba divers and snorkelers, while the brave ones may indulge in extreme sports such as jumping off 12m (40ft) bluffs.</p>]]><p><b>Swim with dolphins and sharks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its backdrop of tropical rainforest, Dolphin Cove in Ocho Rios is Jamaica's largest natural lagoon, home to numerous bottlenose dolphins. Interacting and swimming with these magical creatures is sure to be one of your most unforgettable experiences in Jamaica. And if that's not enough of a thrill, you can also mingle with sharks and stingrays.</p>]]><p><b>Tour historical Spanish Town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stroll around the ancient streets of Spanish Town, Jamaica's former capital, on a historical walking tour. Under Spanish rule for over 200 years, it was once a magnificent and impressive metropolis. Some fine stately redbrick homes and grand monuments remain, including a resplendent plaza, Anglican cathedral and the magnificent Old King's House mansion.</p>]]><p><b>Uncover Port Royal, Jamaica’s old capital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you're fascinated by Jamaica's swashbuckling past, pay a visit to Port Royal, which is located at the mouth of Kingston Harbour. This fishing village was once a centre for rum-swilling privateers, who would spend their ill-gotten gains in the local inns. An earthquake in 1692 destroyed much of Port Royal, alas, but the village is still home to a number of historic buildings, which allow visitors a peek into the past.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$14.03 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Aluminum Oxide, refined petroleum, aluminum ore, hard liquor, and coffee.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Refined petroleum, cars, crude petroleum, and medical supplies.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Canada, Netherlands, Russia, UK, China, Japan, Mexico, Panama.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The discovery of bauxite in Jamaica during the 1940s spawned a thriving bauxite-alumina industry, shifting the island's economy from sugar and bananas. By the 1970s, Jamaica had emerged as a world leader in export of these minerals and today, bauxite accounts for more than half of the country's export earnings.<br />
<br />
During the mid 1990s the economy shrunk each year at a rate of 1%. In 1996, Jamaica navigated the troubled waters of an economic crisis that saw the GDP remain stagnant until 2000. In 2005/6, the economy grew by 1.8%. Economic policy has pursued a familiar course of privatisation of state-owned enterprises, deregulation, tight budgetary controls, and reform of the tax and banking systems. The process was supervised by the IMF and aimed principally at reducing Jamaica's large national debt burden. Although these measures improved Jamaica's financial position, it has offered little benefit to the population, with high inflation and unemployment rife.<br />
<br />
Today, tourism has become a major source of foreign exchange and Jamaica's economic backbone. <br />
<br />
Jamaica is a member of the Caribbean trading bloc, CARICOM, and of the Inter-American Development Bank.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jamaica's business culture is based on respect and polite formalities. A suit, jacket and tie should be worn to meetings. Punctuality is valued and appointments and business cards are expected. Meetings are friendly but formal and brevity is appreciated. Avoid high-pressure sales tactics, which are seen as confrontational. Bargaining is the norm here during negotiations and a lot of time is spent reviewing details before contacts are drawn up. Table manners during dinner engagements follow European protocol.</p><p>Mon-Thurs 0830-1700, Fri 0830-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Jamaica Conference Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 922 9160
					Website:
					Address: ,Duke Street,Kingston,]]><b>The Jamaican Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 922 0150
					Website:http://www.jamaicachamber.org/
					Address: ,39 Hope Road,Kingston 10,]]><b>The Jamaica Tourist Board</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Trade Board Ltd</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 969 0883
					Website:http://www.tradeboard.gov.jm
					Address: ,107 Constant Spring Road,Kingston 10,]]><b>The American Chamber of Commerce of Jamaica</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 929 7866
					Website:http://www.amchamjamaica.org
					Address: ,81 Knutsford Boulevard,Kingston 5,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>With its wide historical background, combining English, African, Asian and native Caribbean cultures, Jamaican cuisine is similarly rich and varied. Meat, poultry or fish play a starring role in most local dishes, which also make use of the island&rsquo;s ubiquitous fresh fruit and vegetables.</p>
<p>Although some Jamaican food can be hot and spicy, a surprising number of dishes are free of chilli peppers. Street food is a popular and affordable way to delve into local cuisine: visitors should try some street snacks, which include savoury patties and sweet coconut cakes, such as <em>gizzada</em> and <em>toto</em>.</p>
<p>Tropical fruits are plentiful and inexpensive too, including pineapple, mango, soursop, tamarind and coconut, which are delicious whether eaten fresh or blended as smoothies.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ackee</strong>: The cooked fruit of the ackee tree, served with salt fish (dried cod).<br />
<strong>Rice and peas:</strong> This ubiquitous staple dish actually consists of kidney beans mixed with white rice, coconut milk, spring onions and coconut oil.<br />
<strong>Pepperpot soup:</strong> A meaty broth with chunks of salt pork, salt beef, okra and <em>callaloo</em> (Indian kale).<br />
<strong>Jerk: </strong>Hot and spicy chicken or pork, marinated overnight in rich spices (cayenne pepper, garlic, chilli, lime juice and all spice) before being wood-smoked in strips.<br />
<strong>Curry goat:</strong> Spicy but not over-hot curry, traditionally served at festivals and special local events.<br />
<strong>Patties: </strong>Baked pastry turnovers, stuffed with meat or seafood mixed with vegetables.<br />
<strong>Bammy:</strong> Traditional flatbread made of cassava flour, eaten either as a snack or served as a side dish with meat or fish stews.<br />
<strong>Jamaican rum:</strong> Is delicious and potent, with famous labels including <em>Appleton, Myers </em>and<em> Captain Morgan.<br />
</em><strong>Coffee</strong>: Jamaica's Blue Mountains coffee is rated among the finest on the planet, though most of the best coffee beans are exported.<br />
<strong>Ting:</strong> A zesty carbonated soft drink made from Jamaican grapefruit.<br />
<strong>Red Stripe:</strong> Jamaica&rsquo;s best-known beer is sweet, nutty and smooth.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Bars can open and close when they choose. They are no licensing hours, alcohol can be bought all day and most have table or counter service.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Hotels and restaurants tend to add 10% as standard; otherwise 10 to 15% is expected. Tipping is banned in many all-inclusive resorts.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>After-dark Jamaican entertainment ranges from the sophisticated to hedonistic. As the home of Bob Marley, live reggae music can be found throughout the island. There are also regular street dances and steel bands in most towns and villages. Torch-lit limbo dancers and fire-eaters often form a part of frequent folkloric parades. Calypso, jazz, rock, soca, reggae, and many other styles of music can be found in a host of neon-lit nightclubs. The Jamaica Tourist Board's 'Meet the People' evenings offer a chance to interact with the locals throughout the island. Contact the tourist office in Kingston, Montego Bay, Ocho Rios, or Port Antonio.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local produce, handicrafts and duty-free bargains are just some of the reasons to hit the shops. Jamaica is renowned for its fine hand-loomed fabrics, embroidery, silk screening, woodcarvings, oil paintings, sandal-making and woven raffia. There is also a popular Quaker-run workshop specialising in wicker furniture, floor mats and other tropical furnishings at Highgate Village in the mountains. At the In-Craft centre, it is also possible to buy custom-made rugs and reproductions of pewter and china from the 17th-century ruins of the ancient submerged city of Port Royal.<br />
<br />
Jamaican specialities include rum and rum-related products, such as Ian Sangsters Rum Cream. The island's most famous produce market is Coronation Market, Kingston. Other markets worth visiting include Linstead Market, Kingston; Brownstown Market, St Anne; the Savanna-la-Mar Market, Savanna-la-Mar; and the Albert George Market, Falmouth. Also locally made and sold are Pepper Jellies, jams, Blue Mountain coffee, hot sauces, and spices.<br />
<br />
So-called 'in-bond' shopping allows tourists to purchase international goods free of tax or duty. Goods are sealed (hence the 'bond') until away from Jamaican waters and must be paid for in Jamaican Dollars.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700; Sat 0800-1300. Some shops close half day Wednesday in Kingston, and Thursday on the rest of the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation catering to all tastes and on wildly varying scales can be found all around the island&rsquo;s coast, as well as more and more establishments inland in areas of outstanding natural beauty such as the Blue Mountains. Montego Bay and Ochos Rios are the main &lsquo;volume tourism&rsquo; and cruise ship destinations, and they have many of the principal hotels, sights and shopping areas. At the western tip of the island, lining a spectacular seven-mile stretch of beach and some equally pretty cliffs, Negril is popular but with a very different feel, smaller-scale excusive hotels and a more laid back air. Port Antonia is also a calmer and quieter corner of the island boasting some of the most attractive countryside. Coastal areas such as Treasure Bay, Discovery Bay and Runway Bay have gained such a reputation over the years that they have become destinations in their own right, and of course a range of hotel accommodation can be found in the capital Kingston, the lively heart of Jamaica. <br />
<br />
<strong>Boutique Hotels:</strong> Jamaica realised some years ago that there were many potential holiday-makers keen to visit its shores and looking for hotel accommodation, but put off by the stranglehold of the massive chain resorts. Since then a profusion of small and intimate, luxury boutique hotels have flourished around the island, many being converted from revamped B&amp;B establishments.<br />
<br />
<strong>All-inclusive Resort:</strong> Jamaica boasts more all-inclusive resorts than any other island in the Caribbean. In fact, there are over thirty dotted around the island&rsquo;s most popular coastal locations, with something to suit every budget, and the advantage of having your holiday completely taken care of before you arrive, from meals and drinks to airport transfers. All-inclusive resorts are usually large affairs, well equipped with more than one pool and several options for restaurants and bars. By and large they fall into two categories; ones designed to cater for family holidays and those reserved for couples and honeymooners.  <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are government-controlled in four categories: A, B, C and D.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfast in a local island home can provide a fascinating insight into Jamaican family life. Learn patois from native speakers and dine on robust home-cooked Jamaican fare. Play dominoes, strum reggae classics and swap tales on the porch. Information is available from the Jamaica Tourist Board.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation catering to all tastes and on wildly varying scales can be found all around the island&rsquo;s coast, as well as more and more establishments inland in areas of outstanding natural beauty such as the Blue Mountains. Montego Bay and Ochos Rios are the main &lsquo;volume tourism&rsquo; and cruise ship destinations, and they have many of the principal hotels, sights and shopping areas. At the western tip of the island, lining a spectacular seven-mile stretch of beach and some equally pretty cliffs, Negril is popular but with a very different feel, smaller-scale excusive hotels and a more laid back air. Port Antonia is also a calmer and quieter corner of the island boasting some of the most attractive countryside. Coastal areas such as Treasure Bay, Discovery Bay and Runway Bay have gained such a reputation over the years that they have become destinations in their own right, and of course a range of hotel accommodation can be found in the capital Kingston, the lively heart of Jamaica. <br />
<br />
<strong>Boutique Hotels:</strong> Jamaica realised some years ago that there were many potential holiday-makers keen to visit its shores and looking for hotel accommodation, but put off by the stranglehold of the massive chain resorts. Since then a profusion of small and intimate, luxury boutique hotels have flourished around the island, many being converted from revamped B&amp;B establishments.<br />
<br />
<strong>All-inclusive Resort:</strong> Jamaica boasts more all-inclusive resorts than any other island in the Caribbean. In fact, there are over thirty dotted around the island&rsquo;s most popular coastal locations, with something to suit every budget, and the advantage of having your holiday completely taken care of before you arrive, from meals and drinks to airport transfers. All-inclusive resorts are usually large affairs, well equipped with more than one pool and several options for restaurants and bars. By and large they fall into two categories; ones designed to cater for family holidays and those reserved for couples and honeymooners.  <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are government-controlled in four categories: A, B, C and D.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation catering to all tastes and on wildly varying scales can be found all around the island&rsquo;s coast, as well as more and more establishments inland in areas of outstanding natural beauty such as the Blue Mountains. Montego Bay and Ochos Rios are the main &lsquo;volume tourism&rsquo; and cruise ship destinations, and they have many of the principal hotels, sights and shopping areas. At the western tip of the island, lining a spectacular seven-mile stretch of beach and some equally pretty cliffs, Negril is popular but with a very different feel, smaller-scale excusive hotels and a more laid back air. Port Antonia is also a calmer and quieter corner of the island boasting some of the most attractive countryside. Coastal areas such as Treasure Bay, Discovery Bay and Runway Bay have gained such a reputation over the years that they have become destinations in their own right, and of course a range of hotel accommodation can be found in the capital Kingston, the lively heart of Jamaica. <br />
<br />
<strong>Boutique Hotels:</strong> Jamaica realised some years ago that there were many potential holiday-makers keen to visit its shores and looking for hotel accommodation, but put off by the stranglehold of the massive chain resorts. Since then a profusion of small and intimate, luxury boutique hotels have flourished around the island, many being converted from revamped B&amp;B establishments.<br />
<br />
<strong>All-inclusive Resort:</strong> Jamaica boasts more all-inclusive resorts than any other island in the Caribbean. In fact, there are over thirty dotted around the island&rsquo;s most popular coastal locations, with something to suit every budget, and the advantage of having your holiday completely taken care of before you arrive, from meals and drinks to airport transfers. All-inclusive resorts are usually large affairs, well equipped with more than one pool and several options for restaurants and bars. By and large they fall into two categories; ones designed to cater for family holidays and those reserved for couples and honeymooners.  <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are government-controlled in four categories: A, B, C and D.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical care standards vary dramatically across the country's public and private hospitals. Away from major cities, medical centres are often poorly funded and under-resourced. Health insurance is strongly recommended since medical treatment can be expensive. Major hotels often keep a doctor and dentist on 24-hour call. Cash payment is often required, sometimes in advance.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water in key tourist areas is normally chlorinated and is considered safe to drink. However, elsewhere water quality remains poor and should be avoided. Bottled water is widely available. Make sure food is thoroughly cooked, avoid purchasing food from street vendors and check that dairy products have been pasteurized before consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;There is a high prevalence of HIV/AIDS and precautions should be undertaken to avoid exposure. Other high risk activities include tattooing and body piercing; avoiding these will also reduce the risk of other blood-borne viruses including hepatitis B and C.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Ash Wednesday :
							14 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							23 May </p><p>Emancipation Day :
							01 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							06 August </p><p>National Heroes Day :
							15 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Jamaica without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 230g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; 170ml of perfume and 340ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; US$500 of other goods (Jamaican passport holders and residents only).<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include dangerous drugs, dog racing equipment, and pornographic material. If you wish to import meat products, fruits and vegetables, pharmaceuticals, firearms, ammunition, used tyres, two way radios, or motor vehicles, you must obtain a specific import licence.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jamaican Dollar (JMD; symbol J$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of J$1,000, 500, 100 and 50. Coins are in denominations of J$20, 10, 5 and 1, and 25, 10 and 1 cents.<br />
<br />
Jamaican law requires that local currency be used when paying for all goods and services, though that law is followed very loosely and the US Dollar is accepted almost universally. To avoid confusion determine which dollar unit is being quoted in the price prior to any transaction being made.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchange bureaux are located in airports, hotels, cruise ports and commercial banks. Hold onto receipts when changing money as black market exchange is illegal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Plastic is invaluable when travelling in Jamaica. American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are all widely accepted as are other cards bearing the Cirrus or Plus logo. Most Jamaican ATMs accept international bank cards and many banks give credit card cash advances.</p><p>Most Jamaican ATMs accept international bank cards and can be found at the airports, in larger towns and in major hotels and resorts. However the island&rsquo;s ATMs still have a reputation for unreliability and shouldn&rsquo;t be relied on exclusively. Bank cards supported by Visa and Mastercard will work in most situations and the island&rsquo;s Scotia Bank cashpoints are generally considered the most reliable. As a precaution it&rsquo;s recommended that you use ATMs during business hours and avoid visiting them after dark. If a bank is open but the ATM isn&rsquo;t functioning, many banks will give cash advances on a credit card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although the concept of traveller's cheques has become antiquated in recent years, thanks to Jamaica&rsquo;s erratic ATMs, traveller&rsquo;s cheques in US Dollars are widely accepted throughout Jamaica.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0830-1700; Fri 0830-1600, with 24-hour ATMs in major cities and resort areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Jamaica, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa issued at port of entry: US$100; visa obtained in advance from embassy/high commission: &pound;25.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy or high commission). Some nationals may apply on arrival (including those mentioned above); check with the consulate for a full list.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors applying for visas in advance from the embassy/high commission should allow three days for processing. If the application has to be referred to Jamaica for approval, it may take two to three weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa applicants must be able to show proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay in Jamaica.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors may be able to extend their stay up to a maximum of six months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Only animals born in the UK or Ireland may be brought into Jamaica. You must obtain an import permit from the Veterinary Division of the Ministry of Industry, Commerce, Agriculture and Fisheries (<a href="http://www.moa.gov.jm">www.moa.gov.jm</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[18.235983]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-77.364019]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>10,992 sq km (4,244 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,881,000 (World Bank estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>266 sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kingston.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With an area of 10,992 sq km (4,244 sq miles), Jamaica is the largest island of the Commonwealth Caribbean and the third largest of the Greater Antilles, after Cuba and Hispaniola. A largely mountainous terrain reaches 2,256m (7,402ft) at the Blue Mountain Peak in the east, descending westward in a series of ridges and forested ravines. Over 1,000km (621 miles) of coastline offers fine beaches in the north and west. At its greatest extent, Jamaica is 235km (146 miles) long with a width that varies between 35 and 82km (22 and 51 miles). The island is a quarter the size of Estonia, half the size of the Scottish Highlands, roughly the same size of the American state of Connecticut.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jamaica has the most churches per capita of any country in the world. Protestant majority (Anglican, Baptist, Church of God and Methodist) with Roman Catholic, Jewish, Muslim, Hindu and Bahai communities. Rastafarianism, a religion based on belief in the divinity of the late Emperor of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ethiopia">Ethiopia</a>, Haile Selassie (Ras Tafari), is also widely practised. Jamaica also has a number of small spiritualist cults.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Away from the fast-paced capital city, Jamaica is slow and relaxed. Handshaking is the customary form of greeting. Jamaicans are hospitable and it is not uncommon to be invited into a local home where normal social conventions apply. When it comes to day attire, beachwear is only considered appropriate for the poolside or the sand and is frowned upon elsewhere. Eveningwear varies, from the formal jacket-and-tie dress codes in many top restaurants to the more relaxed casual clothing in beach bars. Marijuana, or ganja as it is known in Jamaica, is illegal to possess, use or export. Possession may lead to imprisonment and deportation.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Usually 110 volts AC, 50Hz, though some places use 220 volts AC, 60Hz. American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without a grounding pin) are mostly used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Andrew Holness since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General Patrick Linton Allen since 2009.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Before Columbus discovered it in 1494, modern-day Jamaica, then known as Xaymaca, had been peacefully inhabited by the native Arawak Indians for about 2,000 years. All of that changed in an instant as the Spanish swiftly colonised the island, driving the Arawaks out, replacing them with slaves from Africa and holding control of Jamaica until the mid-17th century.</p>
<p>The Spanish left Jamaica in 1655, in the wake of British pirates and settlers who turned Jamaica into the most important of the British Caribbean slaving colonies. The new capital Kingston soon became a vital point of the vicious trade triangle bringing many thousands more slaves to the island from Africa and exporting rum and sugar back to Europe. Even today no other island in the Caribbean feels its bonds with the African continent more keenly, and for the past centuries it has defined the island&rsquo;s very culture. It was a key event in Jamaican history therefore, when, in 1834, slavery was abolished, a date considered to be the birth of the modern nation.<br />
<br />
Jamaica remained a British crown colony, however, and it was not until the early 20th century that rising independence movements began to gain momentum. The 1920s saw the rise of black political activity as Jamaica&rsquo;s second-most-famous-son Marcus Garvey founded the &lsquo;Back to Africa&rsquo; movement, which encouraged Jamaicans to return to their homeland. The Rastafarian religion grew out of this movement after the now-deceased Haile Selassie was crowned King of Ethiopia. Believers consider Selassie to be a messiah who will return Jamaicans to Africa and bestow upon them peace and prosperity. <br />
<br />
Jamaica was finally granted independence in 1962, remaining a member of the Commonwealth. This was the decade that saw the blossoming of reggae, the musical message that put Jamaica firmly on the map with the arrival of the legendary Bob Marley. Since independence, the political arena has been dominated by the struggle between the right-wing Jamaican Labour Party (JLP) and the leftist People's National Party (PNP). The economy has been boosted by a recent rise in tourism, which accounts for some 60% of GDP.<br />
<br />
<strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;&nbsp;Ian Fleming wrote ten of his James Bond spy thrillers at his home in Jamaica.<br />
&bull;	Jamaica&rsquo;s original Arawak inhabitants named the island Xaymaca, which means &ldquo;land of wood and water&rdquo;.<br />
&bull;	Jamaican sprinters have dominated world athletics since 2005, when Asafa Powell set a new 100m Olympic record, which was subsequently beaten by Usain Bolt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Jamaican Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 452 0660.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofjamaica.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 452 0660.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1700 (embassy), 0900-1300 (consular service open for walk-ins).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1520 New Hampshire Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Jamaica High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7823 9911.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.jhcuk.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7823 9911.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1700, Fri 0900-1600 (high commission); Mon-Thurs 0930-1330, Fri 0930-1230 (consulate).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1-2 Prince Consort Road<br/>London<br/>SW7 2BZ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The famous birthplace of Bob Marley, reggae and the Rastafari movement, Jamaica&rsquo;s cultural offering to the world is far greater than its size might suggest. With varying degrees of success, beach resorts around the world have attempted to emulate the Jamaican seaside vibe, but once you&rsquo;ve felt the sand between your toes on this Caribbean island, you&rsquo;ll accept no substitutes.</p>
<p>But it&rsquo;s so much more than a beach destination. Beyond the swaying palms and white sands lie misty coffee plantations, the epic Blue Mountains, raging rivers prime for rafting and forests alive with exotic species. It&rsquo;s not all wild. Manicured parks and gardens are a Jamaican speciality, and you can spot exuberant clusters of tropical blooms on any street corner of this fertile island.</p>
<p>At the heart of it all, though, is music. From bass-heavy beats pumping out of Kingston&rsquo;s frenetic nightclubs to harmonious choirs singing in village churches, it is in the air wherever you go. If song satisfies Jamaica&rsquo;s sensual needs, food and drink tend to its soul. Culinary delights range from gourmet seafood in award-winning restaurants to street-side jerk chicken washed down with a chilled can of Red Stripe. You can taste some of the world&rsquo;s best rum and coffee here, not to mention a sumptuous range of tropical fruits.</p>
<p>Negril and Montego Bay are Jamaica&rsquo;s two main coastal resorts, with exquisite sands, lively clubs, fine restaurants and world-class golf. And then there&rsquo;s Kingston, the island&rsquo;s spirited capital and home of the island&rsquo;s music scene, where grand Georgian plazas and elegant mansions are serenaded by soca rhythms and the pulsating buzz of the city. Sleepy fishing villages offer a glimpse of Jamaica&rsquo;s quieter side, but ultimately, whether it&rsquo;s high-octane adventure or slow travel you&rsquo;re looking for, you&rsquo;ll soon be seduced by the rhythm of life on this irresistible island.</p><p>The famous birthplace of Bob Marley, reggae and the Rastafari movement, Jamaica&rsquo;s cultural offering to the world is far greater than its size might suggest. With varying degrees of success, beach resorts around the world have attempted to emulate the Jamaican seaside vibe, but once you&rsquo;ve felt the sand between your toes on this Caribbean island, you&rsquo;ll accept no substitutes. But it&rsquo;s so much more than a beach destination. Beyond the swaying palms and white sands lie misty coffee plantations, the epic Blue Mountains, raging rivers prime for rafting and forests alive with exotic species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
