<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Japan" ColCode="jpn" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="jp" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Japan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate in Japan is mostly temperate with four distinct seasons, except for the Hokkaido area and the Okinawa region.</p>
<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tokyo">Tokyo</a>, along with most areas on the main island Honshu, has a humid subtropical climate characterised by warm and wet summers and mild winters. January is usually the coldest month while August is the hottest month. July and August are the main rainy season, and umbrellas are a daily essential during this period.</p>
<p>Spring and autumn are generally mild throughout the country.</p>
<p>Typhoons, or tropical cyclones, with strong winds and torrential rains often hit Japan during August and September, but can occur through May to October. Strong typhoons often affect transport systems, causing rail and air services to be stopped, and there is a danger of landslides in rural areas.</p>
<p>The best time to visit Tokyo is usually from March to May, and October to November. Every April, tens of thousands of tourists go to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tokyo">Tokyo</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kyoto">Kyoto</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/osaka">Osaka</a> for the spectacular views of cherry blossom. Equally, many travellers visit in October for the colourful autumnal leaves.</p>
<p>Hokkaido, the northernmost island, is also Japan's coldest region. Winters are long and harsh with plenty of snowfall, making it a prime destination for snow sports. Ski resorts here often open from early December to April.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the Okinawa prefecture is about 1,000 miles (1,600km) south of Tokyo and enjoys long summers with temperatures hover around 32&deg;C (90&deg;F).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Japan, lightweight cottons and linens are required throughout summer in most areas. To avoid sunstroke and sunburn it is advisable to wear a hat. According to the region, light to medium weight clothing is best during spring and autumn; whilst medium to heavy weight clothing is recommended for winter months. A light rain coat or jacket is useful during the rainy season in June and July. Much warmer clothes will be needed in the mountains all year round. Thermal innerwear is recommended if trekking, climbing or skiing. It&rsquo;s best to purchase all necessary clothing before arriving in Japan, as it can be difficult to find larger sizes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All Nippon Airways (<a href="http://www.ana.co.jp" target="_blank">www.ana.co.jp</a>) and Japan Airlines (<a href="http://www.jal.co.jp" target="_blank">www.jal.co.jp</a>) maintain an extensive network of flights covering all of Japan and its islands. There are a few budget airlines too, such as Skymark (<a href="http://www.skymark.co.jp" target="_blank">www.skymark.co.jp</a>), Air Do (<a href="http://www.airdo.jp" target="_blank">www.airdo.jp</a>), Solaseed Air (<a href="http://www.solaseedair.jp" target="_blank">www.solaseedair.jp</a>), IBEX Airways (<a href="http://www.ibexair.co.jp" target="_blank">www.ibexair.co.jp</a>), Peach (<a href="http://www.flypeach.com" target="_blank">www.flypeach.com</a>) and Starflyer (<a href="http://www.starflyer.jp" target="_blank">www.starflyer.jp</a>). Tokyo is serviced by two airports; Haneda (HND) (<a href="http://www.tokyo-airport-bldg.co.jp" target="_blank">www.tokyo-airport-bldg.co.jp</a>) which has both domestic and international flights, and Narita (NRT) (<a href="http://www.narita-airport.jp" target="_blank">www.narita-airport.jp</a>) for international flights.</p>
<p>A monorail service runs from Hamamatsu-cho to Haneda while both JR and Keisei trains connect Narita with Tokyo (fastest train - 1 hour). Other major airports with international connections include Kansai International Airport (<a href="http://www.kansai-airport.or.jp" target="_blank">www.kansai-airport.or.jp</a>) near Osaka, Fukuoka (<a href="http://www.fuk-ab.co.jp" target="_blank">www.fuk-ab.co.jp</a>), Centrair (<a href="http://www.centrair.jp" target="_blank">www.centrair.jp</a>) near Nagoya, and New Chitose Airport (<a href="http://www.new-chitose-airport.jp" target="_blank">www.new-chitose-airport.jp</a>) near Sapporo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are domestic ferry connections between the four main islands of Japan and their major ports, as well as the thousands of smaller islands. Major sea routes from Tokyo are to Kitakyushu (Fukuoka) via Tokushima on Shikoku, and Tomakomai on Hokkaido. Other routes include Maizuru to Otaru, Aomori to Hakodate, Kobe to Takamatsu and Kagoshima to Naha. Bullet train services travel frequently to ports. Ferry companies include Shin Nihonkai Ferry (<a href="http://www.snf.jp" target="_blank">www.snf.jp</a>) and Ocean Tokyu Ferry (<a href="http://www.otf.jp" target="_blank">www.otf.jp</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Japan Railways Group (JR) runs one of the best rail networks in the world. Kyuko (Express) and Tokkyu (the faster Limited Express) trains are best for travelling within and between major urban areas, with frequent services on the main routes. Shinkansen, the 'bullet trains', are the fastest and most convenient for intercity travel, with compartments for wheelchair passengers, and refreshments for sale on board.</p>
<p>Supplements are payable on the three classes of express train and in 'Green' (first-class) cars of principal trains, for which reservations must be made. Other types of train include Kaisoku (Rapid Train) and Futsu (Local Train). For short-distance trains, tickets can be bought at vending machines outside train stations.</p>
<p>There are also two ultra-luxururious train services. Train Suite Shiki-Shirma (<a href="http://www.jreast.co.jp/shiki-shima/en">www.jreast.co.jp/shiki-shima/en</a>) offers 1-3 night itineraries around northeastern Japan, and include destinations such as Naruko Hot Springs, Nikko Toshugo Shrine and Hirosaki Castle. Twilight Express Mizukaze (www.twilightexpress-mizukaze.jp) has a choice of five itineraries in western Japan, and includes stops in Kyoto, Osaka and the Sea of Japan. The impressive interiors showcase Japanese design and craftsmanship and prices are correspondingly steep.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Japan Rail Pass (<a href="http://www.japanrailpass.net" target="_blank">www.japanrailpass.net</a>)&nbsp;is an economical pass for foreign tourists that must be purchased before arrival in Japan. It is valid for seven, 14 or 21 days and can be used on all JR trains (except the super express Nozomi services on the Shinkansen lines), and also on JR buses and JR ferries. For travellers with a JR Pass, there are various other discounts in operation including a 10% discount at any JR Group Hotel and economical car rental packages.</p>
<p>Other JR rail passes include the JR East Pass (<a href="http://www.jreast.co.jp" target="_blank">www.jreast.co.jp</a>), the Kansai Area Pass and the San'yo Area Pass from JR West (<a href="http://www.westjr.co.jp/global/en" target="_blank">www.westjr.co.jp/global/en</a>), the JR Kyushu Rail Pass (<a href="http://www.jrkyushu.co.jp/english" target="_blank">www.jrkyushu.co.jp/english</a>), and the Hokkaido Rail Pass (<a href="http://www2.jrhokkaido.co.jp/global/english/railpass/rail.html" target="_blank">www2.jrhokkaido.co.jp/global/english/railpass/rail.html</a>), which is more localised and therefore slightly cheaper than the JR Pass.</p>
<p>The seasonal Seishun 18 Ticket (<a href="http://www.jreast.co.jp/e/pass/seishun18.html" target="_blank">www.jreast.co.jp/e/pass/seishun18.html</a>) is a cheap way to travel on JR trains nationwide. It allows five individual days of unlimited travel during certain periods on local and rapid trains. The pace is leisurely but it&rsquo;s a great way to see the countryside. International visitors can buy the ticket from JR stations after arriving in Japan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Japan has a network of well-connected expressways linking major regions. However, expressway tolls are very high and there is major congestion during peak holiday seasons. Driving is convenient if you are planning to travel outside the major cities to the more remote and scenic regions. It&rsquo;s important to be aware of weather conditions &ndash; heavy rain and snow can force road closures.</p>
<p>International visitors must have an international licence in order to hire and drive a car in Japan. The minimum driving age is 18, and it is advisable to take out car insurance. Speed limits vary considerably so pay attention to signs.</p>l<p>Roads are well maintained and increasingly well signposted in both Japanese and English on major routes.</p><p>There are regular long-distance bus services running between all the major regions and cities in Japan. Both daytime and overnight buses are available. It&rsquo;s a cheap way to travel and sightseeing time during the day can be maximised by travelling at night.</p>
<p>JR Bus Kanto (tel: +81 3 3844 1950; <a href="http://www.jrbuskanto.co.jp" target="_blank">www.jrbuskanto.co.jp</a>) operates regular coach services between Osaka and Tokyo. JR Tokai (tel: +81 52 563 0489; <a href="http://www.jrtbinm.co.jp" target="_blank">www.jrtbinm.co.jp</a>) runs coach services between Osaka, Kyoto, Nagoya and several other cities. JR Chugoku (tel: +81 82 261 5489; <a href="http://www.chugoku-jrbus.co.jp" target="_blank">www.chugoku-jrbus.co.jp</a>) operates services from Hiroshima and Okayama to Osaka. Willer Express (tel: +81 50 5805 0383; <a href="http://www.willerexpress.com/e" target="_blank">www.willerexpress.com/e</a>) has direct coaches from Osaka to Sendai in northern Japan, as well as Hiroshima in the west and Nagasaki in the south.</p><p>These can be expensive, particularly in rush hour (0730-0930 and 1700-1800) when traffic can be very slow.</p>
<p>Taxi drivers are very professional, but tend not to speak  English, so it is advisable to have your destination  written out in Japanese, together with the name of some nearby landmark. A map may also help, as Japanese streets can be complicated and some taxi drivers may get confused. Hotels can provide this service.</p>
<p>A peculiarity of all Japanese taxis is that the rear doors are operated automatically by the driver - you shouldn't try to open or close the doors yourself. Tipping is not customary and could offend.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required. It&rsquo;s also advisable to have your passport on hand for additional identification. Foreign drivers can use an international licence for up to one year, but if staying longer you are required to transfer to a local Japanese licence.</p><p>Seat belts are compulsory and the speed limit on expressways is up to 100kph (62mph) although many drivers exceed this. In cities the speed limit is 40kph (25mph). The use of mobile phones is illegal when driving.</p><p>The Japan Automobile Federation (JAF) (tel: +81 570 008 139; <a href="http://www.jaf.or.jp/e" target="_blank">www.jaf.or.jp/e</a>) provides an English-language &lsquo;Rules of the Road' booklet and JAF Road Service offers 24-hour breakdown assistance for both members and non-members (tel: #8139, in Japan only). In the case of an accident, you must inform the police (tel: 110).</p><p>There are numerous car hire companies operating in Japan. One of the biggest is&nbsp;Nippon Rent-A-Car (tel: +81 3 6859 6234; <a href="http://www.nipponrentacar.co.jp" target="_blank">www.nipponrentacar.co.jp</a>). You can also get discounts with car hire and train fare package deals by booking at JR Eki Rent A Car; just look for the travel centres in every JR station (<a href="http://www.ekiren.co.jp" target="_blank">www.ekiren.co.jp</a>). All foreign visitors need an International Driving Permit in order to hire a car. The minimum age for driving in Japan is 18 years old.</p><p>Cycling is a pleasant way to enjoy exploring Japan, and often faster than using public transport. Bicycle rental is available in all major cities, especially those with major sightseeing attractions such as Tokyo, Kamakura, Kyoto, Nara and Hiroshima. Local tourist information centres can provide details.</p><p>Seat belts are compulsory and the speed limit on expressways is up to 100kph (62mph) although many drivers exceed this. In cities the speed limit is 40kph (25mph). The use of mobile phones is illegal when driving.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public transport is well developed, clean and efficient yet crowded during rush hours. The underground systems and suburban rail services, which serve all the main cities, are very convenient. Tokyo and Osaka both have loop lines, which make navigating the major areas of the city a little less confusing. Tokyo also has one working tram - the Toden-Arakawa line running 12km (7.5 miles) from Waseda via Ikebukuro to Minowa-bashi in northeast Tokyo.</p>
<p><strong>Bus:</strong> Because of a general lack of English signs, these can be confusing and are best used with someone who knows the system. Otherwise you should get exact details of your destination from your hotel. Fares systems are highly automated, and passes are usually available. In Tokyo (<a href="http://www.tokyobus.or.jp" target="_blank">www.tokyobus.or.jp</a>) you pay a flat fare on entering a bus, but elsewhere - especially if you're travelling over a distance in the countryside and suburbs - you pay on exiting the bus, depending on the distance you have travelled. This is indicated by a fare board at the front of the bus.</p>
<p><strong>Metro:</strong> All of Japan's largest cities have subway systems. Tokyo has two underground systems: the Tokyo Metro system (<a href="http://www.tokyometro.jp/en" target="_blank">www.tokyometro.jp/en</a>) and the Toei (<a href="http://www.kotsu.metro.tokyo.jp" target="_blank">www.kotsu.metro.tokyo.jp</a>). Tickets for Toei lines are not valid for the Tokyo Metro and vice versa, so you must buy a transfer ticket. A variety of tickets are available including a monthly open pass, one-day open ticket, 14 tickets for the price of 10 and a Tokyo Combination ticket. The most convenient passes are the PASMO (<a href="http://www.pasmo.co.jp" target="_blank">www.pasmo.co.jp</a>) and Suica (<a href="http://www.jreast.co.jp/e/pass/suica.html" target="_blank">www.jreast.co.jp/e/pass/suica.html</a>) stored-value cards that can be used on all subway lines as well as JR and private railway lines and buses in the Tokyo area.</p>
<p>Kyoto also has its own subway system (<a href="http://www.city.kyoto.jp/koho/eng/access/subway.html" target="_blank">www.city.kyoto.jp/koho/eng/access/subway.html</a>) as do Osaka (<a href="http://www.kotsu.city.osaka.lg.jp/foreign/english" target="_blank">www.kotsu.city.osaka.lg.jp/foreign/english</a>), Nagoya (www.kotsu.city.nagoya.jp/en/pc), Fukuoka (<a href="http://subway.city.fukuoka.lg.jp/eng" target="_blank">subway.city.fukuoka.lg.jp/eng</a>)and Sapporo (<a href="http://www.welcome.city.sapporo.jp" target="_blank">www.welcome.city.sapporo.jp</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Japan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sapporo</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.25</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">14.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Japan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">osaka</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.15</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Japan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">nagoya</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Japan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">nagasaki</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">18.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Both Japan Airlines (<a href="http://www.jal.co.jp/en" target="_blank">www.jal.co.jp/en</a>), All Nippon Airways (<a href="http://www.ana.co.jp/eng" target="_blank">www.ana.co.jp/eng</a>) and Jetstar Japan (<a href="http://www.jetstar.com/jp/en" target="_blank">www.jetstar.com/jp/en</a>) offer international flights to Japan.
<p>Peak travel times to and from Japan are during the cherry blossom season in late March/early April, the Golden Week holiday (late April/early May), the Obon holiday (mid-August) and the New Year holiday (late December/early January).</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan/tokyo-haneda-airport">Tokyo Haneda Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan/tokyo-narita-airport">Tokyo Narita International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan/osaka-kansai-international-airport">Osaka Kansai International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan/central-japan-international-airport-centrair">Central Japan International Airport (Centrair)</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan/new-chitose-airport-sapporo">New Chitose Airport (Sapporo)</a>, Fukuoka Airport and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan/sendai-airport">Sendai Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tokyo">Tokyo</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 12 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 14 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Departure tax is included in air ticket.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Osaka Kansai International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.kansai-airport.or.jp/en<p>Osaka Kansai International Airport is located 50km (31 miles) southwest of Osaka.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+81 72 455 2500.</p>]]><b>Tokyo Narita International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.narita-airport.jp<p>Tokyo Narita International Airport is located 65km (40 miles) east of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tokyo">Tokyo</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+81 4 7634 8000</p>]]><b>Chubu Centrair International Airport (Central Japan International Airport)</b><![CDATA[http://www.centrair.jp/en<p>Chubu Centrair International Airport is located on Ise Bay, a man-made island around 35km (22 miles) south of Nagoya.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+81 569 381 195</p>]]><b>Fukuoka Airport </b><![CDATA[http://www.fuk-ab.co.jp/english/<p>Fukuoka Airport is located approximately 6km (3.7 miles) from Fukuoka city centre, Japan.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+81 92 621 0303</p>]]><b>Tokyo Haneda Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.haneda-airport.jp/en<p>Tokyo Haneda Airport is located around 14km (9 miles) south of central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tokyo">Tokyo</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+81 3 5757 8111.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are international ferry services to Japan from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/taiwan">Taiwan</a> and Korea. Ticket prices are generally not cheaper than air tickets. The advantage of arriving in Japan by sea would be the chance to view some spectacular scenery.</p>
<p>Major port cities are <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/osaka">Osaka</a> (<a href="http://www.osakaport.co.jp" target="_blank">www.osakaport.co.jp</a>), Kobe (<a href="http://www.kobe-meriken.or.jp/" target="_blank">www.kobe-meriken.or.jp</a>), Yokohama (<a href="http://www.yokohamaport.org/portal" target="_blank">www.yokohamaport.org/portal</a>), Shimonoseki (<a href="http://www.shimonoseki-port.com" target="_blank">www.shimonoseki-port.com</a>), Fukuoka (<a href="http://port-of-hakata.city.fukuoka.lg.jp" target="_blank">port-of-hakata.city.fukuoka.lg.jp</a>) and Naha.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Trans-Siberian route to Japan is an interesting, if lengthy, trip. Connections can be made daily from London via Harwich or Dover through Europe to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a>. The Trans-Siberian railway departs regularly from Moscow. Among the many tour operators that organise tickets for this is The Russia Experience (<a href="http://www.trans-siberian.co.uk" target="_blank">www.trans-siberian.co.uk</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Japan Rail Pass (<a href="http://www.japanrailpass.net" target="_blank">www.japanrailpass.net</a>) is the most economical way for international visitors to travel all over Japan by rail. It can be used on all Japan Railways services including the <em>shinkansen</em> (bullet train), except for the super-express Nozomi shinkansen. The next fastest <em>shinkansen</em>, the Hikari, is just as convenient for high-speed rail travel in Japan. There are passes for seven, 14 and 21 consecutive days. Passes must be purchased in advance outside Japan and validated on the day you begin to use the pass.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Credit cards can be used directly in some phone boxes, although public phones are becoming increasingly difficult to find and are most likely to be located near train stations. They are green and grey, and accept coins and magnetic prepaid cards, available from convenience stories and vending machines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most modern phone handsets will work in Japan, but roaming charges can be steep - check with your service provider as some will offer reasonable data packages to cover your stay. If you have a smartphone, you can keep in touch using Wi-Fi only. Visitors can hire handsets at the airport from companies such as DoCoMo (<a href="http://www.nttdocomo.com" target="_blank">www.nttdocomo.com</a>), and Softbank (<a href="http://www.softbank-rental.jp" target="_blank">www.softbank-rental.jp</a>). In the UK, phones can be rented in advance of travel from Adam Phones (<a href="http://www.adamphones.com" target="_blank">www.adamphones.com</a>). Coverage is generally good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is widely available throughout Japan, and is free in many hotels and via hotspots in major cities and airports. Alternatively, there are many internet caf&eacute;s located in Tokyo and other main cities.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Japan's national public broadcaster NHK (<a href="http://www.nhk.or.jp" target="_blank">www.nhk.or.jp</a>) operates several TV and radio channels, including Radio Japan and the global English language news channel NHK World. There are four commercial broadcasting networks. The press in Japan is free to criticise the government, although freelance journalists find access to information difficult. There are two English-language daily newspapers published in Japan, the Daily Yomiuri (<a href="http://www.yomiuri.co.jp/dy" target="_blank">www.yomiuri.co.jp/dy</a>), and the Japan Times (<a href="http://www.japantimes.co.jp" target="_blank">www.japantimes.co.jp</a>). Asahi Shimbun also publishes an English version (<a href="http://www.asahi.com/ajw" target="_blank">http://www.asahi.com/ajw</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Letters in Tokyo can be taken to the International Post Office (<a href="http://www.japanpost.jp" target="_blank">www.japanpost.jp</a>), near exit A-2 Otemachi subway station, which provide English-speaking personnel. Airmail to Europe takes four to six days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700 (1900 at bigger branches). Some main post offices are open 0900-1500 on Saturdays; 0900-1230 on Sundays. Some branches have an after-hours service window.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Himeji Castle</p><![CDATA[<p>Himeji-jo is Japan&rsquo;s most impressive castle. Dating from the 17th century, it is in excellent original condition and is dominated by a towering six-storey central donjon. The castle is also known as Shirasagi-jō, or &ldquo;white egret castle&rdquo;, because of its gabled donjons and is supposed to resemble the shape of the bird in flight.  Himeji-jo survived the WW2 bombings that destroyed much of Himeji city, and in 1993 it was added to UNESCO&rsquo;s World Heritage list. It has also featured in many Japanese samurai television dramas, as well as Hollywood movies such as the 007 adventure set in Japan, <em>You Only Live Twice</em>, and the Tom Cruise film, <em>The Last Samurai</em>.</p>]]><br/><p>Hiroshima Peace Memorial Museum</p><![CDATA[<p>Hiroshima in Western Honshu is known around the world as the city which was destroyed by the world's first atomic bomb on August 6, 1945. Every year, millions of visitors come to the city to pay their respects in the Hiroshima Peace Memorial Park and the Peace Memorial Museum. The park, which was reconstructed in 1949, is home to many famous monuments and buildings, including the Children's Peace Monument and the A-Bomb Dome, which was built in 1915 and designed by the Czech architect Jan Letzel. The ruins of the dome, which are included on the UNESCO World Heritage List, have become the symbol of an international desire for peace.</p>]]><br/><p>Kyoto International Manga Museum</p><![CDATA[<p>The Kyoto International Manga Museum, housed in an old primary school, is the first museum in the world devoted to manga, or Japanese comics. The museum has a massive collection, both historical and contemporary, as well as international editions of Japanese comics and the works of international comic artists. Best of all, visitors are allowed to take the comics off the shelf and read them in one of the many reading spaces or outside on the lawn. Manga workshops are held at weekends and there are regular exhibitions of Japanese and international comics.</p>]]><br/><p>Mount Fuji</p><![CDATA[<p>From July to early September it's possible to climb Mount Fuji, Japan's highest mountain at 3,776m (12,388ft) tall. You won't be alone, as in high season there are queues along several parts of the route (<a href="http://www.city.fujiyoshida.yamanashi.jp" target="_blank">www.city.fujiyoshida.yamanashi.jp</a>). There are lodges along the route where you can stop for a rest or refreshments.</p>]]><br/><p>Sanjusangen-do Temple</p><![CDATA[<p>Completed in 1266, the <i>Sanjusangen-do Temple</i> which is officially called Rengeo-in Temple, is a faithful copy of an original that was built in 1164, but burned down in 1249. Originally built by Taira no Kiyomori for the emperor Go-Shirakawa, the temple is today a national treasure. It is best known for its wooden image of the <i>Thousand-Armed Kannon</i> (the Buddhist Goddess of Mercy), a masterpiece of the Kamakura period, which stands surrounded by 1000 smaller statues of the same goddess. The <i>hondo</i> (main building) is split into 33 <i>sanjusan</i> (bays) that exist between its many pillars to symbolise the 33 incarnations of Kannon, hence the name Sanjusangen-do Temple, which literally means '33 bay hall'.</p>]]><br/><p>Shirakawa-go Mountain Village</p><![CDATA[<p>In the mountains of central Japan, lies the remote yet picturesque area of Shirakawa-go, which is famous for its Gassho-zukuri farmhouses. These charming traditional houses have high and narrow thatched rooves – said to resemble <em>gassho</em> or hands together in prayer. This architectural style developed as a result of the heavy winter snows in the area, and also became a place to cultivate silk worms. Many of the still-inhabited farmhouses are open to the public for inspection and offer a fascinating glimpse of both traditional and modern rural life.  In winter, hoards of photographers descend upon the villages of Shirakawa-go, to capture the farmhouses covered in snow. The farmhouses are also extremely photogenic in spring and summer.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Breakfast at Tsukiji Fish Market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get up early to witness the world's largest fish market at Tsukiji in Tokyo. The action kicks off around 0400 and winds down around midday. Guided tours are available; afterwards, feast on the freshest of sushi and sashimi at the restaurants beside the market.</p>]]><p><b>Capture Shirakawa-go on camera</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the mountains of central Japan, you'll find the remote, yet utterly picturesque area of Shirakawa-go. It is famed for its Gassho-zukuri farmhouses, charming traditional houses with high and narrow thatched roofs – said to resemble <em>gassho</em> (hands together in prayer). Many are still inhabited and open to the public, offering a fascinating glimpse of both traditional and modern rural life.</p>]]><p><b>Curl up with a comic, Kyoto International Manga Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Kyoto International Manga Museum, housed in an old primary school, is the first in the world devoted to the Japanese manga comics. The museum has a massive collection, both historical and contemporary, as well as international editions of Japanese comics. Visitors can take the comics off the shelf and read them in one of the many reading spaces.</p>]]><p><b>Dine out like an Emperor in Osaka</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Japan's third largest city is renowned for its abundance of world-class restaurants, its historic castle (an excellent reproduction of the original) and the performing arts of <em>kabuki</em> (classical Japanese dance and drama) and <em>bunraku</em> (traditional puppet theatre). The city's Dotonburi area is particularly vibrant after dark and its aquarium shouldn't be missed – it is one of the largest in the world.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the floating gateway of Miyajima</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Near Hiroshima is the picturesque island of Miyajima, where a famous red Shinto torii gateway seemingly floats on the sea at high tide. Attractions here include the UNESCO-listed Itsukushima Shrine, the tame deer and the cable car up the holy Mount Misen, which offers fantastic panoramic views.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a traditional Japanese tea ceremony</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Arrange to take part in a traditional tea ceremony through the tourist information centres in Kyoto and Tokyo. The elegant ritual takes place in a <em>chashitsu</em>, a tranquil room designed and designated for tea, and is steeped in seasonal symbolism.</p>]]><p><b>Experience the opulence of Sensoji Temple</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pilgrims have flocked to Sensoji Temple, Tokyo's most revered Buddhist sanctuary, for over 1,000 years. Originally founded in AD628 to enshrine a statuette of the Kannon Bodhisattva (the Goddess of Mercy), damage from bombing raids mean that today you'll find a lavish, five-storey reconstruction. Walk under its giant lantern to reveal smoking incense, swirling crowds and teeming shops.</p>]]><p><b>Go whale and dolphin watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Several former whaling ports have caught onto the tourist value of switching to whale-watching tours, so climb aboard a boat to spot both humpback and sperm whales. For the best chance of seeing these incredible mammals, take to the seas between January and April. Dolphin watching is popular in eastern and western Japan.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the slopes with some skiing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Come winter, do as many Japanese do and hit the slopes. Mountains here are sprinkled with top-class ski resorts, especially in the central Japanese Alps and Hokkaido, where pistes are famed for their powdery snow. Many resorts also have <em>onsen</em> (hot springs) to relax in après-ski.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Himeji Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Himeji-jo is Japan's most impressive castle. Dating from the 17th century, it survived WWII bombings and is still in excellent condition. Dominated by a towering six-storey central donjon, Shirasagi-jō (or "white egret castle" as it is nicknamed) is supposed to resemble the shape of the bird in flight. In 1993 it was added to UNESCO's World Heritage list.</p>]]><p><b>Pack a picnic for the pretty cherry blossom parties</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From April through May, <em>sakura</em> (cherry blossom trees) start blooming across the country, and lively parties are held underneath the pretty blossoms. Known as a <em>Hanami</em> party, friends and family gather for a picnic with food and drinks with the most famous areas in Ueno Park in Tokyo and Maruyama Park in Kyoto.</p>]]><p><b>Pay your respects at the Hiroshima Peace Memorial Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hiroshima in Western Honshu was destroyed by the world's first atomic bomb in 1945. Visitors come to pay their respects in the Hiroshima Peace Memorial Park and the Peace Memorial Museum. The park, which was reconstructed in 1949, is home to Children's Peace Monument and the A-Bomb Dome – the ruins of which are on the UNESCO World Heritage List.</p>]]><p><b>See Japan's indigenous culture in Hokkaido</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For a long time, this northern island was Japan's Wild West, and it still retains a distinct pioneer feel. Hokkaido is home to the last of Japan's indigenous Ainu people and visitors will find the remnants of their distinct culture. If you're short on time, visit the Hokkaido Ainu Center in Sapporo or the Ainu Museum in Shiranoi.</p>]]><p><b>See anime come to life at Studio Ghibli</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Universal Studios Japan in Osaka and Tokyo's Disney Resort are both enormously popular and a great day out for families. Even better is Tokyo's delightful Ghibli Museum based on the animated movies of Studio Ghibli.</p>]]><p><b>See the world's largest bronze statue of the Buddha in Nara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One hour south of Kyoto, Nara was the first imperial capital of Japan, and marked the far eastern end of the Silk Road. See the Great Buddha of Todaiji Temple, the world's largest bronze Buddah, and the sacred deer in ancient Nara Park.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out ringside seats for Sumo wrestling</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watch the theatre of a sumo contest. Witnessing sumo wrestling is pacy, exciting and truly traditional Japanese experience. Six major tournaments are held throughout the year in Tokyo, Osaka, Nagoya and Fukuoka. Tickets can be purchased in advance or on the day.</p>]]><p><b>Set sail for culture in Naoshima</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Naoshima is an island in the Seto Inland Sea, located off the coast of Okayama Prefecture. Originally a fishing port, it is now home to an exciting array of outdoor art exhibits and contemporary art museums, including one that functions as a hotel. Old houses on the island have also been converted into exhibition spaces.</p>]]><p><b>Tour the imperial capital, Kyoto</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't miss Kyoto, the imperial capital of Japan for over 1,000 years. Founded in AD794, Kyoto's best sights include the Golden Pavilion (Kinkakuji), the Zen rock garden of Ryoanji, the dramatic verandah of Kiyomizu Temple and the medieval Nijo Castle with its musical "nightingale floor". The historic Gion geisha district makes for a wonderful late afternoon wander.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind in a hot spring</b></p><![CDATA[<p>When the Japanese want to relax, they head to a natural hot spring resort called <em>oronsen</em>. Famous soaks include Dogo in Matsuyama, Shikoku, which is one of the oldest in Japan with 3,000 years of history; and Ibusuki, on the southern tip of Kyushu, renowned for its hot-sand saunas.</p>]]><p><b>Walk the Kumano Kodo trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Kumano Kodo is an ancient pilgrimage route in the mountains of Wakayama Prefecture. It is an area of stunning natural beauty with forests, waterfalls, tea fields and soothing hot springs. It is also the spiritual heartland of Japanese mythology, and unique for its synthesis of Buddhism and Shintoism. Since 2004, it's been a UNESCO World Heritage site.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$4.92 trillion (2013).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cars, computers, electronic devices and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Raw materials, machinery, fuel, food, chemicals and textiles.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, China, Taiwan (China), Korea (Rep) and Germany.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>After suffering massive destruction during WW2, Japan was the economic phenomenon of the late 20th century. The structure of the Japanese domestic economy revolves around a group of large multi-product corporations (many of which are global household names), linked in loose alliances with banks and finance houses. Agriculture now accounts for less than 2% of the GDP.</p>
<p>The model worked superbly until the early 1990s, when competition from abroad and excessive lending by the banks began to exert pressure. The extent of the problem became apparent with the 1991 property crash and, more spectacularly, the 1997 Asian financial crisis.</p>
<p>In the following years the economy stagnated, remaining at 0% inflation for a few years. Unemployment, a comparative novelty in a country where jobs were typically guaranteed for life, reached 5.4%.</p>
<p>From 2003 to 2007, the Japanese economy enjoyed its strongest recovery since WW2. However, the global economic crisis of late 2008 hit Japan hard. Unemployment crept up towards 5%, and Japan lost its status as the second largest economy in the world to China.</p>
<p>The triple disasters which hit north-east Japan on March 11, 2011 have had a major impact on the economy. Energy issues, disruptions to manufacturing, low interest rates and the continuing strong yen are major challenges affecting economic growth and stability. The area of northeastern Japan most affected by the disasters was a major agricultural and manufacturing centre. Some companies have relocated whilst others have been forced to close. Despite this situation, Japan currently remains the third largest economy in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Manners are very important for business negotiations in Japan. While you&rsquo;ll be forgiven for not getting everything right, you&rsquo;ll be expected to wear a smart suit, exchange business cards using both hands with everyone you meet, and to be polite and punctual.</p>
<p>A large supply of business cards printed in English and Japanese is essential. Cards can be quickly printed on arrival with <em>katakana</em> Japanese translation on the reverse side. Appointments should be made in advance and, because of the formality, visits should consist of more than a few days. Business discussions are often preceded by tea and general small talk, and are usually very formal.</p>
<p>It is usual to refer to colleagues by their surnames, and hierarchies should be respected. Business negotiations may require patience as directness is mistrusted and disliked, thus straight &lsquo;yes' or &lsquo;no' answers are generally avoided. However, this depends on the region where you are doing business &ndash; in Osaka, for example, being more direct is less problematic. Impatience is frowned upon, and confrontation is out of the question, as it is considered a sign of gross weakness. Apologies and thanks are very important and should not be rushed.</p>
<p>Corporate entertaining usually takes place in restaurants and <em>izakaya</em> (drinking halls similar to pubs). Drinking (beer, whisky and sake) is very much part of the culture, as is smoking, although partners tend to be left at home. Gifts, especially those from your home country, are very important (they need not be particularly large or lavish) and are exchanged with great ceremony.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;ll often need to remove your shoes indoors: look out for lines of shoes or slippers for clues. Avoid putting your foot on the ground while changing from your shoes to any slippers provided. Make sure that you are wearing clean socks.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700. Some offices are open Sat 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Nippon Shoko Kaigi-sho (The Japan Chamber of Commerce and Industry)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (03) 3283 7824
					Website:http://www.jcci.or.jp/
					Address: Chiyoda-ku,2-2 Marunouchi 3 Chome,Tokyo,100-0005]]><b>JETRO (Japan External Trade Organisation)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (03) 3582 5511
					Website:http://www.jetro.go.jp/
					Address: Minato-Ku,Ark Mari Building,6F 12-32,Akasaka 1-Chrome,Tokyo,107-6006]]><b>JETRO in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7421 8300
					Website:http://www.jetro.go.jp/uk/
					Address: 71 High Holborn,MidCity Place,London WC1V 6AL,]]><b>Japan National Tourism Organisation (JNTO)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (03) 3201 3331
					Website:http://www.jnto.go.jp/
					Address: Chiyoda-ku,10th Floor,Tokyo Kotsu Kaikan Building,2-10-1 Yurakucho,Tokyo,100-0006]]><b>Japanese Chamber of Commerce in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7628 0069
					Website:http://www.jcci.org.uk/
					Address: 29 Finsbury Circus,Salisbury House,London EC2M 5QQ,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Japanese cuisine involves fresh, delicate flavours based on seasonal ingredients. Rice, miso (fermented soy bean) soup, tofu (soy bean curd), pickled vegetables and fresh seafood are staples of the Japanese diet. Traditionally, meat was not eaten because of Buddhist beliefs, but these days, consumption of beef, chicken and pork is widespread.</p>
<p>The wide range of ingredients, the intensive preparation methods, and the meticulous presentation found in Japanese cuisine is highly impressive. Sushi is world renowned, but it&rsquo;s not the only style of cooking and the variety of regional dishes is astounding, ranging from noodle soups and dumplings to meat skewers, octopus balls and some of the finest beef in the world. Then, of course, there is <em>kaiseki</em> &ndash; a multi-course, fine-dining-style banquet.</p>
<p>While sake (rice wine) is still regularly served, beer is by far the most popular alcoholic beverage. Whisky is also gaining popularity thanks to a number of Scotch-style distilleries.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Teriyaki:</strong> Beef, chicken or fish marinated in a soy sauce and mirin wine, and seared on a hot plate.<br />
<strong>Tempura:</strong> Seafood and vegetables deep-fried in a light batter.<br />
<strong>Sushi:</strong> Slices of raw fish and vegetables placed on cooked vinegared rice.<br />
<strong>Sashimi:</strong> Thinly sliced fresh fish served uncooked with soy sauce, pickled ginger and wasabi.<br />
<strong>Ramen:</strong> Noodles in a meat, fish, soy or miso-based broth with toppings such as sliced pork, spring onions and a boiled egg.<br />
<strong>Soba:</strong> Buckwheat noodles often served cold with a dipping sauce or in a hot broth.<br />
<strong>Kushikatsu:</strong> Crumbed fish, meat and vegetables deep-fried on skewers.<br />
<strong>Yakitori:</strong> Skewers of bite-sized grilled chicken.<br />
<strong>Okonomiyaki:</strong> A grilled savoury pancake made with shredded cabbage, seafood, pork and noodles.<br />
<strong>Champuru:</strong> Okinawan style stir-fry featuring goya bitter melon and tofu.<br />
<strong>Shojin-ryori:</strong> Known for its delicate flavourings, this traditional Buddhist cuisine is made using grains, vegetables, tofu and rice.<br />
<strong>Matcha:</strong> A bitter green tea used in tea ceremonies.<br />
<strong>Sake:</strong> Dry or sweet rice wine served hot or cold.<br />
<strong>Shochu:</strong> A strong vodka-like spirit often mixed with soft drinks.<br />
<strong>Asahi and Sapporo:</strong> Crisp, dry lagers served in most Japanese bars and restaurants.<br />
<strong>Whisky:</strong> Japanese distilleries such as Suntory and Nikka are winning plaudits around the world with their fine, Scotch-style malts.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most traditional Japanese cuisine is eaten with chopsticks. Restaurants have table service and in some places it is customary to remove footwear. There are no licensing hours, and drinking is subject to long-standing rituals of politeness. The host will pour a drink for the visitor, and will insist on the visitor's glass being full; it is bad manners for a visitor to pour one for him or herself.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tips are never expected. In some upmarket places, a 10 to 15% service charge will be added to the bill. In some bars, there may be a table or "charm" charge too, which can be quite steep; it's best to enquire in advance if you're in any doubt.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>20.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tokyo has an abundance of cinemas, theatres, bars, live music venues, coffee shops and nightclubs. A wide range of bars is available, from the upmarket and stylish to cheap street stalls where patrons stand to drink, with the key areas in Tokyo being Shibuya, Roppongi and Shinjuku. <em>Izakaya</em>, drinking halls that are similar to pubs, are patronised by everyone from university students to office workers and usually have a lively atmosphere. Karaoke &ldquo;boxes&rdquo;, venues with small private rooms where customers can be served food and drinks while they sing, are one of the most popular forms of entertainment in Japan. <br />
<br />
In summer, rooftop beer gardens are also common all over Japan. Be wary of clubs with &ldquo;hostesses&rdquo; - companions who expect to be bought drinks and snacks. There are thousands of other bars and clubs that do not charge entry and do not offer hostess service.<br />
<br />
In Tokyo, there are concerts of all styles of music almost every night. Foreign opera and ballet companies, orchestras and rock/pop stars visit Japan all year round. For those who would like to see the traditional Japanese performing arts, there is kabuki and <em>noh</em> theatre in Tokyo, Kyoto, Osaka, Nagoya and other major Japanese cities. Check the Japan Arts Council website for details of venues and performances (<a href="http://www.ntj.jac.go.jp" target="_blank">www.ntj.jac.go.jp</a>).<br />
<br />
The English-language magazines Metropolis (www.metropolisjapan.com) in Tokyo and Kansai Scene (<a href="http://www.kansaiscene.com" target="_blank">www.kansaiscene.com</a>) in Western Japan are good sources for finding out what's on. It is advisable to purchase tickets in advance because shows quickly sell out. Osaka is also renowned for its nightlife, as is Sapporo on the northern island of Hokkaido and Fukuoka on the southern island of Kyushu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shoppers will encounter a blend of quintessential Japanese goods and sophisticated sales techniques in Japan, particularly at the big department stores which are usually located near major train stations and commercial districts. Department stores, which are more like exhibitions than shops, almost always have extremely attentive and highly trained staff. Smaller specialty shops, which sell traditional goods and have often been in business for hundreds of years, also provide a unique shopping experience and offer a high level of service. Special purchases include kimonos, <em>mingei</em> (local crafts including kites and folk toys), Kyoto silks, fans, religious articles such as Shinto and Buddhist artefacts, paper lanterns, ceramics, lacquerware, cameras and other electronic equipment.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Colourful souvenir shops stocked with high-quality hand-made and region-specific goods are ubiquitous. Fans of Japanese popular culture will be able to purchase the latest fashion and character goods from their favourite manga and anime in all major Japanese cities; in particular, Akihabara in Tokyo and Den-Den Town in Osaka. Outlet stores for brand-name goods manufactured in Japan are becoming increasingly common, and are often located near international airports.</p>
<p>Bargaining is not usual, but significant discounts are available during sales in summer (June-July) and winter (December-January). &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Tax exemptions are available in authorised tax-free stores, provided that the item is taken out of Japan unopened/unused. Remember when buying electronic goods that they may not be compatible with UK or US voltage.</p><p>1000-1900 every day of the week and on public holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels are 'Japanese' or 'Western' in style, or a mix of both. Western-style accommodation is much like any modern US or European hotel, often with an excellent level of service. No-frills business hotel chains such as Toyoko Inn have become very popular; you'll find them in convenient locations in most cities and towns.</p>
<p>At ryokan (traditional Japanese-style hotels), guests receive yukata (cotton kimono) and slippers, which are perfectly acceptable to wear both within your room and around the ryokan. Rooms have Japanese tatami (straw mat flooring), fold-away futon beds, and shoji (paper) sliding doors. Prices for ryokan range from reasonable for basic inns with shared baths to expensive for the most exclusive ones where rates will invariably include lavish breakfast and dinner meals, a private garden view and extremely attentive service.</p>
<p>Most top-end hotels levy a service charge of 10 to 15% on the bill. The Tokyo Metropolitan Government also enforces a small accommodation tax of &yen;100 per night on hotels and ryokan around the city that charge over &yen;10,000 per room (&yen;200 per night if the room costs over &yen;15,000).</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> No accommodation grading system operates in Japan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Minshuku</em>, often found in vacation spots, are the Japanese equivalent of home-style lodging or pensions. Rates are moderate, and visitors receive fewer amenities than ryokan or Western-style hotels. Visitors are expected to fold up their bedding and stow it away in a closet, and towels are usually not provided. Slippers are worn in the house.  The price usually includes two meals per day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels are 'Japanese' or 'Western' in style, or a mix of both. Western-style accommodation is much like any modern US or European hotel, often with an excellent level of service. No-frills business hotel chains such as Toyoko Inn have become very popular; you'll find them in convenient locations in most cities and towns.</p>
<p>At ryokan (traditional Japanese-style hotels), guests receive yukata (cotton kimono) and slippers, which are perfectly acceptable to wear both within your room and around the ryokan. Rooms have Japanese tatami (straw mat flooring), fold-away futon beds, and shoji (paper) sliding doors. Prices for ryokan range from reasonable for basic inns with shared baths to expensive for the most exclusive ones where rates will invariably include lavish breakfast and dinner meals, a private garden view and extremely attentive service.</p>
<p>Most top-end hotels levy a service charge of 10 to 15% on the bill. The Tokyo Metropolitan Government also enforces a small accommodation tax of &yen;100 per night on hotels and ryokan around the city that charge over &yen;10,000 per room (&yen;200 per night if the room costs over &yen;15,000).</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> No accommodation grading system operates in Japan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels are 'Japanese' or 'Western' in style, or a mix of both. Western-style accommodation is much like any modern US or European hotel, often with an excellent level of service. No-frills business hotel chains such as Toyoko Inn have become very popular; you'll find them in convenient locations in most cities and towns.</p>
<p>At ryokan (traditional Japanese-style hotels), guests receive yukata (cotton kimono) and slippers, which are perfectly acceptable to wear both within your room and around the ryokan. Rooms have Japanese tatami (straw mat flooring), fold-away futon beds, and shoji (paper) sliding doors. Prices for ryokan range from reasonable for basic inns with shared baths to expensive for the most exclusive ones where rates will invariably include lavish breakfast and dinner meals, a private garden view and extremely attentive service.</p>
<p>Most top-end hotels levy a service charge of 10 to 15% on the bill. The Tokyo Metropolitan Government also enforces a small accommodation tax of &yen;100 per night on hotels and ryokan around the city that charge over &yen;10,000 per room (&yen;200 per night if the room costs over &yen;15,000).</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> No accommodation grading system operates in Japan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is strongly recommended, owing to the high cost of treatment for those outside the Japanese national healthcare system. Confirm that your health care policy fully covers travel to Japan before departure, as you will be expected to pay the full amount of any treatment you receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The International Association for Medical Assistance to Travellers (&lt;a href="http://www.iamat.org" target="_blank"&gt;www.iamat.org&lt;/a&gt;) provides a list English-speaking doctors. There are hospitals with emergency and outpatient facilities in all major cities. Throughout Japan dial 119 to call an ambulance. Because emergency operators may not speak English, assistance from a local person, if possible, would be helpful when making an emergency call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If bringing small amounts of personal medications into Japan, whether they are over the counter or prescription, make sure they are in clearly marked containers. Larger quantities or devices may require a special certificate which must be obtained before departure to Japan.  Consult the Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare website (&lt;a href="http://www.mhlw.go.jp" target="_blank"&gt;www.mhlw.go.jp&lt;/a&gt;) for more detailed information. Visitors should be aware that in Japan medications containing stimulants or codeine are illegal. You are not permitted to take commonly available nasal decongestant medication such as Sudafed and Vicks Inhalers into Japan.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;If travelling to the area near the Fukushima nuclear accident it is advisable to take supplies of food and water. Produce from the area near the Fukushima nuclear accident, which is still being sold in some supermarkets nationwide, should be avoided due to the lack of a centralized testing system in Japan for radioactive contamination in food, and discrepancies between Japanese and international standards for safe levels of radioactive substances in food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tap water in Tokyo was declared not safe for consumption after the accident, although the government has since stated otherwise. Nevertheless, if travelling with children it is advisable to take precautions. The Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare website (&lt;a href="http://www.mhlw.go.jp" target="_blank"&gt;www.mhlw.go.jp&lt;/a&gt;) has updates on contamination levels in tested food. In other parts of Japan, food and drink are generally considered safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only eat raw fish, seafood and meat from recognised establishments, and be aware that there is a risk of parasitic infection and toxins if these foods have not been prepared properly. E-coli food poisoning outbreaks tend to occur in Japan during the warmer months (June-September), and it is advisable to take precautions when consuming perishable foods at outdoor summer festivals, where refrigeration may be an issue.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;You should make sure you are  up to date with routine vaccinations. Influenza and measles epidemics have occurred in recent years and precautions should be taken. Tuberculosis and hepatitis B occur and vaccination is sometimes advised. Typhus occurs in some river valleys. Japanese encephalitis may occur. Vaccination is recommended for long-term travel (greater than one month) in rural areas. All normal precautions should also be exercised to avoid exposure to sexually-transmitted diseases such as HIV/AIDS.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If spending prolonged periods outdoors during the summer months when heat and humidity can be extreme, make sure to have plenty of fluids on hand to avoid dehydration and wear hats and other protective clothing to avoid heatstroke.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday. When there is a single day between two national holidays, it is also taken as a holiday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Coming of Age Day :
							2018<br/>08 January </p><p>National Foundation Day :
							11 February </p><p>Showa Day :
							29 April </p><p>Constitution Memorial Day :
							03 May </p><p>Greenery Day :
							04 May </p><p>Children's Day :
							05 May </p><p>Marine Day :
							16 July </p><p>Respect for the Aged Day :
							17 September </p><p>Health and Sports Day :
							08 October </p><p>Culture Day :
							03 November </p><p>Labour Thanksgiving Day :
							23 November </p><p>Emperor's Birthday :
							23 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Japan by travellers 20 years of age and older without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes or 100 cigars or 500g of tobacco or 500g of a combination of these.<br />
&bull; 3 bottles (approximately 750ml each) of alcohol.<br />
&bull; 60ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &yen;200,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include narcotics, firearms and ammunition, explosives, counterfeit money, obscene material, and articles which infringe upon intellectual copyright.</p>
<p>Restricted items include animals, plants, medicines and cosmetics, hunting guns, air guns and swords.</p>
<p>You should be aware that in Japan cold and flu medication containing stimulants are illegal. You are not permitted to take commonly available nasal decongestant medication such as Sudafed and Vicks inhalers into Japan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics and stimulants, child pornography and goods that violate design copyrights, trademarks, patents, breeding and intellectual copyrights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Japanese Yen (JPY; symbol ¥). Notes are in denominations of ¥10,000, 5,000, 2,000 and 1,000. Coins are in denominations of ¥500, 100, 50, 10, 5 and 1.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All money must be exchanged at an authorised bank or money changer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard, Visa and other major credit cards are widely accepted in major cities and towns. A pin number may be required to process the transaction. The Japan Post Bank, Seven-Eleven convenience stores and international banks accept foreign credit cards.</p><p>Japan Post Bank ATMs at main branches of the Post Office accept foreign cards Mon-Fri 0005-2355, and 0005-2100 on Sundays and holidays. ATMs at Seven-Eleven stores also accept foreign cards and are accessible 24 hours. International banks accept foreign credit or debit cards, and these are hard to find outside of major cities. Bank ATMs are generally open Mon-Fri 0700-2300, Sat-Sun 0900-1900, though some only operate during normal banking hours and on Saturday mornings. Citibank machines are the most likely to have ATMs, and also to accept foreign credit cards (and are usually open 24 hours).<strong><br />
<br />
</strong> Japan has a strong cash culture, and it is usual to see people carrying large amounts of cash with them because of the low crime rate. It is only recently that credit cards have begun to become more popular. However, travellers may still encounter difficulties with foreign credit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These can be exchanged at most major banks, larger hotels and some duty-free shops. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Japanese Yen or US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Japan, a passport valid for the duration of intended stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Documentary evidence of parental responsibility or guardianship may be required on entry if travelling as a single parent or non-relative with children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Passengers in transit and not leaving the airport do not require a visa. If you wish to leave the airport during transit and are not a visa-exempt national, you must obtain a transit visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: &pound;4; single-entry temporary visitor visa: &pound;16; multiple-entry temporary visitor visa: &pound;32. These are the fees for most visitors requiring a visa, but costs differ for certain nationalities; check with the consulate for the most up-to-date information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Temporary visitor visas are usually valid for 15, 30 or 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate (or consular section at embassy) or via a registered visa agent (in which case you don't need to visit the embassy in person).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Approximately five working days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Upon entry you will be asked to declare the amount of cash you have in your possession on an arrival card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your stay, you must apply to a regional immigration office in Japan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Animal quarantine can take several months. You can find detailed information from the Animal Quarantine Service (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.maff.go.jp/aqs/english/animal/im_index.html">www.maff.go.jp/aqs/english/animal/im_index.html</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[35.155997]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[136.060016]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>377,915 sq km (145,913 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>126,323,715 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>335.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tokyo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The archipelago of Japan is separated from the Asian mainland by 160km (100 miles) of sea and split into four main islands: Honshu, Hokkaido, Kyushu and Shikoku. About 70% of the country is covered by hills and mountains, a number of which are active or dormant volcanoes, including Mount Fuji, Japan's highest peak, reaching 3,776m (12,388ft). Japan sits on major seismic fault lines and is susceptible to frequent earthquakes. <br />
<br />
A series of mountain ranges runs from northern Hokkaido to southern Kyushu. The Japanese Alps (the most prominent range) run in a north-south direction through central Honshu. Lowlands and plains are small and scattered, mostly lying along the coast, and composed of alluvial lowlands and diluvial uplands.</p>
<p>The coastline is very long in relation to the land area, and has very varied features, for example, the deeply indented bays with good natural harbours tend to be adjacent to mountainous terrain. Many of Japan&rsquo;s major cities are located on the coastline, and have extremely high population density.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shintoism and Buddhism (most Japanese follow both religions, although religion does not play a major everyday role in most Japanese lives). Marriages are traditionally conducted at Shinto shrines and funerals at Buddhist temples. There is a Christian minority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Japanese manners and customs are vastly different from those of Western people. A strict code of behaviour and politeness is recognised and followed by almost everyone. However, Japanese people do not expect visitors to be familiar with all their customs but do expect them to behave formally and politely.<br />
<br />
A straightforward refusal traditionally does not form part of Japanese etiquette, and a vague 'yes' does not always mean 'yes'. (The visitor may be comforted to know that confusion caused by non-committal replies occurs between the Japanese themselves.)<br />
<br />
When entering a Japanese home or restaurant, shoes must be removed. Bowing is the customary greeting but handshaking is becoming more common for business meetings with Westerners. The honorific suffix <em>san </em>should be used when addressing all men and women; for instance Mr Yamada would be addressed as <em>Yamada-san</em>. <br />
<br />
Table manners are very important, although the Japanese host will be very tolerant towards a visitor. However, it is best if visitors familiarise themselves with basic table etiquette and use chopsticks. Exchange of gifts is also a common business practice and may take the form of souvenir items such as company pens, ties or high-quality spirits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>100 volts AC, 60Hz in the west (Osaka); 100 volts AC, 50Hz in eastern Japan and Tokyo. Plugs have two flat pins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Shinzō Abe since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Emperor Akihito since 1989.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Influence from the outside world followed by long periods of isolation have characterised Japan's history. In the feudal era (12th-19th century), a new ruling class of warriors emerged: the samurai.</p>
<p>One of the most famous and successful samurai, Oda Nobunaga, conquered numerous other warlords and had almost unified Japan when he was assassinated in 1582. Toyotomi Hideyoshi succeeded him and united the land in 1590 but war broke out following his death.</p>
<p>Tokugawa Ieyasu defeated all rival clans in the Battle of Sekigahara in 1600 and was appointed shogun (ruler of Japan). The Tokugawa shogunate began the isolationist sakoku (locked country) policy that spanned the two and a half centuries of tenuous political unity known as the Edo period.</p>
<p>In 1854, the US Navy forced the opening of Japan to the outside world. Ensuing economic and political crises led to the Boshin War and the establishment of a centralised state unified under the name of the Emperor (Meiji Restoration).</p>
<p>The Meiji Restoration transformed Japan into an industrialised world power that embarked on a number of military conflicts to expand the nation's sphere of influence, including two Sino-Japanese Wars (1894-1895 and 1937-1945) and the Russo-Japanese War (1904-1905).</p>
<p>On 7 December 1941, Japan attacked the US naval base in Pearl Harbor. This act brought the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> into WWII and, on 8 December, the USA, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/netherlands">Netherlands</a> declared war on Japan. After the devastating atomic bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki in 1945, Japan surrendered. The war cost Japan millions of lives and left much of the country's industry and infrastructure destroyed.</p>
<p>Japan later achieved exceptional growth to become one of the world's most powerful economies in the 1980s. In the early years of the 1990s, the Japanese economic bubble burst ushering in an era known as the &lsquo;lost decade&rsquo; &ndash; an economic crises from which the country has, as yet, not fully recovered from.</p>
<p>The 2011 earthquake, which occurred off the coast of Japan and unleashed a devastating tsunami on the Tōhoku region, still looms large in the memory of the country. It killed nearly 16,000 people and triggered equipment failures at the Fukushima Nuclear Power Plant, which resulted in the largest nuclear meltdown since the 1986 Chernobyl disaster. </p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Napping on the job may be frowned upon in the UK, but snoozing at work is acceptable in Japan. The practice is known as inemuri and is supposed to demonstrate the sleeper&rsquo;s dedication to their work. <br />
&bull;	Melons are big business in Japan, with the rare black Densuke watermelon, grown only on Hokkaido, selling for around &yen;25,000 (&pound;140).<br />
&bull;	Vending machines can be found around every corner in Japan and sell everything from batteries and lightbulbs to beer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Japan in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 238 6700 or 6800 (visa section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.us.emb-japan.go.jp/english/html</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 238 6700 or 6800 (visa section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1230 and 1400-1730 (0930-1230 and 1330-1700 for the visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2520 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Japan in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7465 6500 or 6565 (visa section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.uk.emb-japan.go.jp</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7465 6500 or 6565 (visa section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1630 (for the visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>101-104 Piccadilly<br/>London<br/>W1J 7JT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Japan]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+81 03 5211 1100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/japan</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+81 03 5211 1100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1630.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Chiyoda-ku<br/>1 Ichiban-cho<br/>Tokyo<br/>102-8381<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From kimono-clad geishas singing karaoke in Kyoto to Buddhist monks whizzing around Tokyo on motorbikes, Japan is a fascinating land of contrasts, a heady mix of tradition and modernity that often bewilders but never bores.</p>
<p>Nowhere in the world blends the old and new quite like Japan. The speed of new technological developments here is matched only by the longevity of its ancient customs and traditions. The country is a pioneer in the fields of design, technology, fashion and cuisine. You can set your watch by the trains, eat meals that look like works of contemporary art and relieve yourself in the most technologically advanced toilets on the planet (some even talk to you).</p>
<p>Paradoxically, Japan&rsquo;s embrace of the cutting edge is offset by its revered cultural traditions and celebrated historic achievements. Crumbling castles, atmospheric Buddhist temples, Shinto shrines and fascinating festivals are never far away, with historic highlights including the striking Himeji Castle and Kyoto&rsquo;s iconic Temple of the Golden Pavilion. There's also evidence of Japan&rsquo;s dramatic recent history in cities like Hiroshima and Nagasaki, where the earliest nuclear bombs were dropped with devastating consequences during WWII.</p>
<p>If you love nature, you will adore Japan. This is a country swathed in natural beauty. Ski the powdery slopes of Hokkaido, revel in the springtime beauty of the sakura cherry blossoms, frolic in the sun-drenched beaches and turquoise waters of subtropical Okinawa, or climb up the iconic Mount Fuji. Wherever you go, good food is guaranteed &ndash; from fresh sushi and sashimi to robata-fired meats and sizzling sauces, Japan is a joy for gastronomes.</p>
<p>It is also a land of wild eccentricities, where you can buy used underwear from vending machines, watch men strip at the festival of Hadaka Matsuri and get amorous in one of the country&rsquo;s many short-stay love hotels. These facets might jar somewhat with Japan&rsquo;s polished image, but they help make it one of the most singular destinations on the planet.</p><p>From kimono-clad geishas singing karaoke in Kyoto to Buddhist monks whizzing around Tokyo on motorbikes, Japan is a fascinating land of contrasts, a heady mix of tradition and modernity that often bewilders but never bores. Nowhere in the world blends the old and new quite like Japan. The speed of new technological developments here is matched only by the longevity of its ancient customs and traditions. The country is a pioneer in the fields of design, technology, fashion and cuisine. You can set your watch by the trains, eat meals that look like works of contemporary art and relieve yourself in the most technologically advanced toilets on the planet (some even talk to you).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
