<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Jordan" ColCode="jor" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="jo" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Jordan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jordan is a year-round destination. Even in high summer (June-August), <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amman">Amman</a> and most areas around the country are not excessively hot, chiefly due to the moderating influence of altitude &ndash; Amman stands around 850m (2800ft) above sea level. Similarly, Petra enjoys an elevated position &ndash; around 1,100m (3600ft) above sea level, so here, too, although days in summer can be hot, nights are often rather chilly. For Petra, as well as decent walking shoes &ndash; the only way in and out of the ruins is by a moderately testing walk over stony ground &ndash; also bring something warm for the evenings, even in summer. In winter, Petra can be very cold, with rain and even snow.</p>
<p>The Jordan Valley and the Red  Sea coast around Aqaba is warm during winter (December-February) &ndash; a pleasant relief from the chill elsewhere &ndash; but extremely hot in summer (June-August). In the Eastern Desert, the winter can be bitterly cold and dry and the summer intensely hot. Some high-altitude areas, such as Ajloun, Dana and Petra, can receive snowfall in winter. Rain falls in many areas across the country on higher ground between October and March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothes are advised between May and September. Thick winter clothes are essential for winter and a warm layer is necessary for cool summer evenings. Rainwear is advisable from November to March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Royal Jordanian (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.royalwings.com.jo/">www.rj.com</a>) operates frequent flights between Amman and Aqaba. This is the only domestic air route in the country, and is something of a luxury &ndash; the road journey between the two cities is only around 4 hours. The flight from Amman to Aqaba takes less than 45 minutes. However, fares are not excessive, and the views out over the desert are an added enticement.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no longer any scheduled passenger trains running in Jordan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s easy to move around Jordan by road. Signage is generally good (and bilingual, in Arabic and English) and road quality is mostly high. Jordan is also small - few journeys between points of interest take longer than 2 hours.&nbsp;</p>
<p>You should always carry bottled drinking water with you in your vehicle, in case you are stranded in the daytime heat. Be prepared in winter (December to February) for heavy rain, fog and/or snowfall to block roads or hinder progress, especially in high-altitude areas around Ajloun, Tafila, Petra and Ras Al Naqab, as well as in the elevated western suburbs of Amman.</p>r<p>The highways are reasonable but the local driving style can be erratic. For most visitors, in most situations, a 4-wheel drive vehicle is not needed. If you intend to drive off-road in the deserts of in Jordan&rsquo;s east and south, you are best advised to make contact with a local guide or driver in advance.</p><p>Buses are the main means of inter-city transport in Jordan &ndash; mostly small 15-seater minibuses, which ply between neighbouring towns as well as to/from Amman. These are small shoestring operations, and the best advice is to ask around locally for where buses depart from, and how to proceed. Larger coaches follow a few major inter-city routes. Companies include JETT (tel: +962 6 566 4141; <a href="http://www.jett.com.jo" target="_blank">www.jett.com.jo</a>) and Hijazi (tel: +962 2 710 1760).</p><p>In Amman all taxis operate a meter and can be hired for the day. A shared-taxi service to many towns on fixed routes is also available and can be hired for private use. Tips of around 10% are appreciated but not obligatory. Note that taxis often display the fare in fils rather than dinars and if you overpay by mistaking one for the other, no one is likely to correct you.</p><p>National driving licenses are accepted if they have been issued at least one year before travel. However, an International Driving Permit is recommended. Visitors are not allowed to drive a vehicle with normal Jordanian plates unless they have a Jordanian driving license.</p><p>Speed limits are 60kph (38mph) or less in built-up areas, 80kph (50mph) on country roads and 120kph (75mph) on motorways. Mobile radar speed-traps are common. Roadside ID checks have been withdrawn everywhere, but it&rsquo;s still a good idea to keep your passport with you at all times. The minimum driving age is 18 years. Wearing seatbelts is mandatory for all car passengers.</p><p>In case of breakdown, contact the Royal Automobile Club of Jordan (tel: +962 6 585 0626; <a href="http://www.racj.com" target="_blank">www.racj.com</a>).</p><p>Major international car hire companies and a number of local companies<em> </em>operate services in the main towns, including Amman and Aqaba. Car hire is also available from hotels and travel agents. Drivers are available for the day.</p><p>Very few Jordanians cycle, and this is reflected in the limited facilities for cyclists, and limited awareness of cycle safety among motorists. The mountainous terrain, extremes of temperature and conservative outlook among rural people all mitigate against long-distance cycling in the countryside. That said, it is not impossible - the best advice is to make contact with local cycle groups on Facebook, who can direct you to one of Amman&rsquo;s few bike shops for guidance and supplies.</p><p>Speed limits are 60kph (38mph) or less in built-up areas, 80kph (50mph) on country roads and 120kph (75mph) on motorways. Mobile radar speed-traps are common. Roadside ID checks have been withdrawn everywhere, but it&rsquo;s still a good idea to keep your passport with you at all times. The minimum driving age is 18 years. Wearing seatbelts is mandatory for all car passengers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are conventional buses and extensive fixed-route <em>servis</em> (share-taxis, most seating up to seven) in Amman and other main cities. The <em>servis</em> are licensed, with a standard fare scale, but there are no fixed pick-up or set-down points. Vehicles often fill up at central or outer terminal points and then run non-stop.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Jordan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">wadi_mousa_petra</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Jordan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">madaba</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Jordan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">dead_sea_resorts</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Jordan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">aqaba</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Royal Jordanian (<a href="http://www.rj.com" target="_blank">www.rj.com</a>), but you can find wide availability of flights on multiple carriers into the Jordanian capital <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amman">Amman</a> from major cities across Europe, Asia and North America. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) also flies direct to Jordan from the UK,&nbsp;and Amman is also served by Gulf low-cost carriers such as Air Arabia (<a href="http://www.airarabia.com" target="_blank">www.airarabia.com</a>), FlyDubai (<a href="http://www.flydubai.com" target="_blank">www.flydubai.com</a>) and Jazeera Airways (<a href="http://www.jazeeraairways.com" target="_blank">www.jazeeraairways.com</a>).</p>
<p>Direct flights come non-stop into Amman from North American hubs such as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chicago">Chicago</a>. Most flights come into Amman&rsquo;s Queen Alia International Airport (AMM). Some international flights serve Aqaba&rsquo;s King Hussein airport (AQJ).</p>
<p>The major airport is" <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amman/amman-queen-alia-international-airport">Amman Queen Alia International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amman">Amman</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 5 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 10 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>JD10 if leaving Jordan overland, otherwise it is included in the airfare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Amman Queen Alia International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.qaiairport.com<p>Amman Queen Alia International Airport is located 32km (20 miles) south of Amman.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+962 6 445 3000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Scheduled car ferries and high-speed catamarans run by AB Maritime (tel: +962 3 209 2000; <a href="http://www.abmaritime.com.jo" target="_blank">www.abmaritime.com.jo</a>) cross between Nuweiba in Egypt and Jordan&rsquo;s only port city, Aqaba. Timetables are notoriously fickle, and delays of many hours are common on this route.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no longer any scheduled passenger trains running in Jordan &ndash; the old Hejaz Railway line from Damascus has been permanently suspended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jordan has road borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/israel">Israel</a>, the Palestinian Authority, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/syrian-arab-republic">Syria</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iraq">Iraq</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/saudi-arabia">Saudi Arabia</a>, and is also linked by car  ferry to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/egypt">Egypt</a>. The JETT bus company in Amman (<a href="http://www.jett.com.jo" target="_blank">www.jett.com.jo</a>) runs scheduled buses to and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cairo">Cairo</a>, Damascus,&nbsp;Baghdad, Riyadh, Jeddah, Madina, Makkah and other cities, along with local partners in each destination.</p>
<p>To reach Amman from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jerusalem">Jerusalem</a> by public transport requires a complicated sequence of taxis and buses; you could pay extra for VIP service door-to-door through firms such as Amman2Jerusalem (tel: +962 7 9952 0066; <a href="http://www.amman2jerusalem.com" target="_blank">www.amman2jerusalem.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Phone cards are available in most big cities and major tourist sites. Cards can be purchased at numerous shops. International calls from hotels and post offices carry a three-minute minimum charge and calls made from hotels can be expensive. Internet cafes offer free or low-cost VOIP calling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with many international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafes throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Independent global rights organisation Freedom House calls Jordan &ldquo;not free&rdquo;. The press is heavily regulated and controlled, free speech is limited, and new laws censoring the internet came into force in 2013. State-run Jordan Radio and TV broadcasts in Arabic, English and French. The main English-language newspaper is the <em>Jordan Times</em>, a daily, which follows the government line. <em>The Star</em> comes out weekly. News websites offering a livelier independent view of local life include <a href="http://www.ammonnews.net" target="_blank">www.ammonnews.net</a>, <a href="http://www.7iber.com" target="_blank">www.7iber.com</a> and <a href="http://www.black-iris.com" target="_blank">www.black-iris.com</a>. Some are blocked in Jordan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes three to five days. If you send packages via Jordan Post (<a href="http://www.jordanpost.com.jo/">www.jordanpost.com.jo</a>), leave them open for customs inspection &ndash; and only send from main post offices in large cities. For a higher charge, there is a rapid service guaranteeing delivery within 24 hours to around 22 countries. A better option for sending packages may be to use a local branch of one of the global courier firms, such as DHL, Fedex or Aramex.</p><p>Sat-Thu 0800-1900 (summer) or 0700-1700 (winter), Fri 0700-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Dead Sea</p><![CDATA[<p>Lying 400m (1320ft) below sea level and spanning the border between Israel and Jordan, the Dead Sea  is a natural wonder. It contains more minerals and salt than any other stretch of water in the world, and thus it really is possible to float on top of the water. Its natural properties make it a prime centre for spa treatments and relaxation therapies. There are also several interesting sites around the Dead Sea, including Bethany, where it is believed Jesus was baptized, and Lot's Cave, where the prophet Lot lived. The Wadi Mujib Nature Reserve  on the eastern shores is a beautifully preserved area of mountains and rivers, providing a natural habitat for eagles, vultures, wolves and the endangered Nubian ibex, a large mountain goat. There are many hiking trails within the reserve. Drop in at the Dead Sea Panorama museum to put the lowest point on earth in a more elevated context; the sea is living up to its name and shrinking at an alarming rate.</p>]]><br/><p>Petra</p><![CDATA[<p>Jordan's best-known tourist attraction, Petra, is one of the great wonders of the Middle Eastern world - a city that was carved straight into solid rock. It unfolds grandly after a two kilometre (1.2 mile) walk through a very narrow chasm adding to its mystery and grandeur. Built during the 5th and 6th centuries BC, Petra is the ruined capital of the Nabatean Arabs. Its immense façades were lost for almost 1000 years until they were rediscovered by the Swiss traveller Johan Ludwig Burckhardt in 1812. Today, there are still many sites to see including the el Khazneh (The Treasury) monument, which is a giant tomb carved out of rock, the Temple of the Winged Lions, the al-Deir (Monastery) and the small Archaeological Museum, which displays artefacts found at Petra during the 19th and 20th centuries.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the amazing remains at the Amman Citadel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Towering over the bustle of downtown Amman, the capital&rsquo;s Citadel Hill boasts extensive archaeological remains, including an early-Islamic ruler&rsquo;s palace, Byzantine churches, the Hand of Hercules and the Roman Temple of Hercules. Come here for the history and the amazing views right across the city.</p>]]><p><b>Be mesmerised by multicoloured marine life at Aqaba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go diving at Aqaba and be wowed by the psychedelic underworld of the Red Sea. After admiring the beauty of the fish in their coral palaces, head back to shore to sample a few marine delicacies in one of the town's many fish restaurants.</p>]]><p><b>Carve out some time for Petra</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Petra is one of the great wonders of the Middle Eastern world &ndash; a city hewn from solid rock. Built during the 5th and 6th centuries BCE, Petra is the ruined capital of the Nabatean Arabs. There are many sites to see, including the el Khazneh (The Treasury) monument, the Temple of the Winged Lions and the al-Deir (Monastery).</p>]]><p><b>Discover Jerash's illustrious past</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Catch the spirit of ancient Rome in a trip to Jerash, a magnificently preserved Roman city north of Amman. With columns, temples, colonnaded streets, grand theatres and silent churches, the city's grand past is architecturally apparent and even today the remains endure as a feast for the eyes. </p>]]><p><b>Drive into the desert to visit Qasr Tuba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hire a guide with a 4-wheel drive vehicle and disappear into the eastern desert. Just when you think you're on the road to nowhere, you'll stumble across Qasr al Tuba, the most remote of the Umayyad desert castles, built in CE 743 for Caliph Walid II.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the waters at the Baptism Site</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In an isolated location beside the River Jordan, take time to explore the Baptism Site, a network of channels and pools where it is said John the Baptist baptised Jesus Christ. Ancient churches and hermits' caves attest to the biblical past of this astonishing place.</p>]]><p><b>Find Bedouin culture in Feynan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Far from any roads, hidden away in the harsh Wadi Araba desert, Feynan offers a living link to Jordan&rsquo;s Bedouin culture. Stay at the award-winning eco lodge here &ndash; lit only by candles &ndash; for epic stargazing, superb wilderness walks and fascinating encounters with local Bedouin families for coffee and campfire stories.</p>]]><p><b>Float in the Dead Sea</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bob like a cork in the dense salt water of the Dead Sea. Lying 400m (1320ft) below sea level, and spanning the border between Israel and Jordan, the Dead Sea is a natural wonder. After, drop in at the Dead Sea Panorama museum to learn the sea is living up to its name and shrinking at an alarming rate.</p>]]><p><b>Hark back millions of years at Jordan Museum, Amman</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Occupying a pristine new building in downtown Amman, the Jordan Museum showcases the very best of Jordan&rsquo;s archaeological finds, spanning nearly 1.5 million years of human history. Exhibitions are split between three engaging and interactive galleries: Modern Jordan, Living History and the Archaeological and Historical Gallery.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the Dana Nature Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Keep an eye open for <em>ibex</em> (wild mountain goats) on a hike in the Dana Nature Reserve. What you miss upon the rocky outcrops the enthusiastic park rangers will make up for with their lively evening chats before bedding down in the tranquil setting of an eco-lodge.</p>]]><p><b>Make time for the mosaics at Umm Ar Rasas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Even if you've seen enough mosaics to last a lifetime, spare time for one more; the magnificent mosaic floors of the excavated church of St Stephen in Um er Rasas are the largest in Jordan, and deserving of their UNESCO World Heritage Site status for their fine detailing and perfect preservation.</p>]]><p><b>Navigate the King's Highway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drive along the historic King's Highway mentioned in the Old Testament.  The route follows a line of hilltops the length of Jordan. Call in at Madaba, famed for its superb Byzantine mosaic art, including a stunning mosaic map of the Holy Land, and make the detour to Mount Nebo, from where Moses looked over the Promised Land before he died.</p>]]><p><b>Spot springtime blooms in Um Qais</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Plan a visit to Jordan in April or May when garlands of springtime flowers lace the Roman monuments at Um Qais (Biblical Gadara), perched high above the Sea of Galilee. If you're lucky, you may happen on a black iris, the national flower of Jordan.</p>]]><p><b>Spot the wildlife at the Azraq Wetlands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit one of Jordan's wildlife reserves, such as the Azraq Wetlands, or meander around the lowest nature reserve in the world at Wadi Mujib. Some residents (including hyena, wolf, gazelle, ostrich and oryx) are notoriously elusive but the infectious beauty of each location is easily caught.</p>]]><p><b>Take a tour of the Desert Castles</b></p><![CDATA[<p>East of Amman, tour a group of early-Islamic hunting lodges and trading posts known as the Desert Castles, built by the Umayyad dynasty based in Damascus. The best known include Kharanah and the frescoed Amra, but visitors shouldn&rsquo;t miss the expertly restored grandeur of Qasr Hallabat.</p>]]><p><b>Uncover the Crusader castle at Karak</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Imagine the striking of ancient hooves on cobbles at Karak Castle, a mighty Crusader fortress amid the southern hills. Aim, too, for nearby Shobak Castle, once the Crusaders' headquarters in Jordan. If you listen extra hard, you may catch the whisper of the wind penetrating the underground passageways.</p>]]><p><b>Unearth the black gem of the desert</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Catch up with more recent history at Qasr al-Azraq castle, Lawrence of Arabia's headquarters during the Great Arab Revolt of 1917. Then head north towards Mafraq and explore the deserted black basalt city of Um al Jimal, affectionately known as the "black gem of the desert".</p>]]><p><b>Wander Wadi Rum on camelback</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Step into the magnificent wind-blown desert of Wadi Rum. The wind has shaped the sandstone cliffs into a cyclorama of pillars and rock arches, explorable by jeep, on foot or astride a camel. Alternatively, soar noiselessly above in a hot-air balloon. By night, enjoy a traditional feast in a Bedouin tent then fall asleep under the stars.</p>]]><p><b>Weave your way to Mukawir</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the village of Mukawir and watch the women of the Bani Hamida workshop weave wool into colourful traditional designs. Nearby is Machaerus, the hilltop fortress of Herod Antipas, where it is said Salome danced for the head of John the Baptist.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$38.6 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Phosphates, potash, fertilisers, pharmaceuticals and clothing.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, manufactured goods, machinery and textile fabrics.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia, USA, Iraq, China (PR) and India.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jordan's agricultural sector produces tomatoes, citrus fruit, cucumbers, watermelons, aubergines and wheat, mostly grown in the fertile ground along the Jordan  Valley. Phosphate mining and potash extraction are the traditional industries; petroleum refining, chemical manufacturing and the production of metals and minerals also contribute to this sector. The service sector accounts for around two-thirds of total output and covers wholesale and retail trading, finance, transport and tourism. <br />
<br />
Jordan is a member of various pan-Arab economic bodies, notably the Council of Arab Economic Co-operation and the Arab Monetary Fund. Jordan also belongs to the World Trade Organization (WTO) and has a free trade accord with the USA and an association agreement with the EU.<br />
<br />
Employment is proving a challenge for the government and many Jordanian workers have moved abroad in search of employment - a trend the government is trying to reverse. To help improve productivity and make Jordan a more attractive country for foreign investment, the government has reduced its debt-to-GDP ratio. A major challenge now facing Jordan is reducing dependence on foreign grants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A good supply of business cards is essential. Business cards with colour, graphics or photos will impress, as will those with your details translated into Arabic. Formality in dress is important; men should wear a suit and tie for business meetings while women should avoid tight-fitting clothes, opt for high necklines and ensure that their arms are covered.</p>
<p>Arriving on time for meetings is important; even if your counterpart may be late, expect to wait. Don&rsquo;t take offence if meetings are postponed, interrupted or include other people, as this is common practice.  </p>
<p>English is widely spoken in business circles. Handshaking is the customary form of greeting. Personal relationships are central to doing business in Jordan.  Always make an effort to get to know your counterpart socially before getting down to business. You can engage in small talk, but avoid making uninformed remarks about religion and politics. Islam plays an important role in society and Friday, the Muslim holy day, is a day off.  </p>
<p>The working week is Sunday to Thursday. Most businesses also close on Saturdays, though some business people may be available. During the Muslim fasting month of Ramadan, there is no lunch break and work will end around 1400 or 1500. This, and other Muslim holidays, is not a good time to do business.</p><p>Sun-Thurs 0830-1800 with a lunch break from 1300-1500.<br />
<br />
<strong>Government office hours:</strong> Sun-Thurs 0800-1500. During the month of Ramadan, working hours are greatly reduced.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Jordan Chamber of Commerce (JCC)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (06) 566 5492
					Website:http://www.jocc.org.jo/
					Address: ,PO Box 7029,Amman 11118,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Jordanian cuisine shares many of the characteristics of Middle Eastern cooking, but the inclusion of freshly made, local yoghurt and cheese adds a twist to the menu.</p>
<p>Aubergines, chickpeas, lentils and beans turn up in many of the dishes and rice and <em>khoubs</em> (flat Arabic bread) are staples used to scoop up spreads and dips, such as hummus and labneh (a yoghurt-like cream cheese).</p>
<p>Alcohol is served in most restaurants and bars, except during the fasting month of Ramadan (non-Muslim nationals can drink alcohol only in hotels during Ramadan). Black tea is the default drink and is usually served with a spoonful of sugar, though herbal blends are also common.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mezze:</strong> A selection of starters that kick off almost every main meal; they include <em>fool</em>, a thick stew made from broad beans; hummus, mashed chickpeas with tahini or sesame paste; <em>moutabel</em>, smoked aubergine dip; and tabbouleh, finely chopped parsley salad.<br />
<strong>Mensaf:</strong> A Bedouin dish of stewed lamb in a yoghurt sauce.<br />
<strong>Maglouba:</strong> Chicken casserole with spices, including cinnamon, allspice, cardamom and nutmeg and rice.<br />
<strong>Kibbe:</strong> Deep-fried ground lamb or beef combined with <em>burghul</em> (ground, steamed wheat), onion and cinnamon.<br />
<strong>Fatet Batinjan:</strong> A casserole-style dish made with roasted eggplant, <em>labneh</em> (a kind thick yoghurt-like cheese) and minced meat.<br />
<strong>Zarb:</strong> Meat, chicken or vegetables cooked on a Bedouin barbecue pit dug into the ground.<br />
<strong>Shraak:</strong> A traditional flat bread made from whole wheat.<br />
<strong>Baklava:</strong> Assorted honey-drizzled, nut-filled filo pastries.<br />
<strong>Kunafeh:</strong> Palestinian speciality dessert of goat&rsquo;s cheese layered with pastry, served warm and drenched in syrup.<br />
<strong>Araq:</strong>&nbsp;A local aniseed liquor, similar to Greek Ouzo, usually served with water and ice.<br />
<strong>Arab coffee:</strong> A small but strong concoction made by boiling cardamom-flavoured grounds with sugar.<br />
<strong>Muhallabiyyeh:</strong> A wobbly milk pudding flavoured with almonds.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Wherever you are, diners generally use pockets of flat bread to scoop up their food; forks and spoons are rarely used, other than for serving. When eating without cutlery, use your right hand only (the left hand is traditionally reserved for toilet matters).</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Generally, a 10% service charge is added in hotels and upmarket restaurants. Extra tips are discretionary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18 years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For many Jordanians, an evening's entertainment is going out for a meal. Amman does have nightclubs in some areas, mostly attached to 5-star hotels. Many high-end hotels have popular bars. Whilst Amman does have a clubbing scene, not all places serve alcohol, and most are only open until 0100 or 0200. Some cinemas in Amman show English-language films, and there are cultural centres for concerts and exhibitions.<br />
<br />
Outside the capital, nightlife is thinner on the ground. The Dead Sea resorts offer a variety of entertainment (not usually open to non-guests), as do the 5-star hotels in the Red Sea resort city of Aqaba. In smaller places, coffee shops are often a social hub after dark; men, or couples, may feel more comfortable here than solo women. University towns such as Karak and Irbid host strips of late-night cafes and fast-food joints serving a student clientele.</p>
<p>The best source of information on entertainment listings is the website 7iber.com, while some arts events and concerts are publicised in the <em>Jordan Times</em> newspaper.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most towns have a souk selling everything from meat and live chickens to clothes and jewellery. Amman&rsquo;s downtown gold souk is a special attraction &ndash; a cluster of tiny shops with glittering window displays crammed together just off the main King Faisal Street. The gold is usually 18ct or above and there is sometimes no charge added for the craftsmanship of items like bangles, chains and earrings.  </p>
<p>Tourist-oriented towns offer many handicrafts, including carpet-weaving or mosaic pieces. Jordan&rsquo;s mosaic school in Madaba trains young people to work with the colourful, locally hewn stone.  </p>
<p>Another distinctive local craft is ostrich-egg painting. The paint is applied with needle pricks and designs can take weeks to complete.  </p>
<p>Other handcrafted items include sand jars, hand-blown glass, and embroidered clothing. Bottled holy water from the River Jordan can also be purchased, as can skin-care products made from Dead Sea mud.</p>
<p>Some of the best souvenir shopping can be done at the Nature Shops run by Jordan&rsquo;s Royal Society for the Conservation of Nature (<a href="http://www.rscn.org.jo" target="_blank">www.rscn.org.jo</a>). These are located at nature reserve headquarters around the country, and also at the Wild Jordan centre off Rainbow Street, 1st Circle in Amman. The Nature Shops stock all sorts of handmade items, from jewellery and painted ostrich eggs to leather goods, paper and novelty home decor pieces &ndash; all sourced sustainably, according to local fair trade principles.</p><p>Generally Sat-Thu 0930-1330 and 1530-1800; some shops open as early as 0800, others close as late as 2100. Some shops are closed on Friday, either all day or until around 1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A variety of accommodation is available to suit all pockets, ranging from a mattress on a rooftop to extravagant hotels. Most visitors choose Amman, Madaba, the Dead Sea, Wadi Mousa or Aqaba as their base, and visit the sites from there. Luxurious resorts along the Dead Sea offer a range of spa treatments that make the most of the healing properties of the local waters.<br />
<br />
There are no youth hostels in Jordan. Hotels in popular locations (especially Aqaba and the Dead Sea) can be fully booked during local holidays. The tourist high season traditionally avoids summer, running from March-May and September-November, but nowadays Jordan is a year-round destination. Rates are subject to approximately 20% tax and service (this varies depending on location and facilities). <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> from 1- to 5-star. Some 5- and 4-star hotels have discos and nightclubs with live music. For further information, contact the Jordan Tourism Board (<a href="http://www.visitjordan.com/" target="_blank">www.visitjordan.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>This is a new trend in Jordan, with a handful of B&amp;Bs launching in the last couple of years, almost all in Amman. Most are run by expat families living long resident in Jordan, and offer the delights of home comforts &ndash; often in private residences &ndash; alongside idiosyncratically local outlooks on where to go and what to do.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A variety of accommodation is available to suit all pockets, ranging from a mattress on a rooftop to extravagant hotels. Most visitors choose Amman, Madaba, the Dead Sea, Wadi Mousa or Aqaba as their base, and visit the sites from there. Luxurious resorts along the Dead Sea offer a range of spa treatments that make the most of the healing properties of the local waters.<br />
<br />
There are no youth hostels in Jordan. Hotels in popular locations (especially Aqaba and the Dead Sea) can be fully booked during local holidays. The tourist high season traditionally avoids summer, running from March-May and September-November, but nowadays Jordan is a year-round destination. Rates are subject to approximately 20% tax and service (this varies depending on location and facilities). <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> from 1- to 5-star. Some 5- and 4-star hotels have discos and nightclubs with live music. For further information, contact the Jordan Tourism Board (<a href="http://www.visitjordan.com/" target="_blank">www.visitjordan.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A variety of accommodation is available to suit all pockets, ranging from a mattress on a rooftop to extravagant hotels. Most visitors choose Amman, Madaba, the Dead Sea, Wadi Mousa or Aqaba as their base, and visit the sites from there. Luxurious resorts along the Dead Sea offer a range of spa treatments that make the most of the healing properties of the local waters.<br />
<br />
There are no youth hostels in Jordan. Hotels in popular locations (especially Aqaba and the Dead Sea) can be fully booked during local holidays. The tourist high season traditionally avoids summer, running from March-May and September-November, but nowadays Jordan is a year-round destination. Rates are subject to approximately 20% tax and service (this varies depending on location and facilities). <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> from 1- to 5-star. Some 5- and 4-star hotels have discos and nightclubs with live music. For further information, contact the Jordan Tourism Board (<a href="http://www.visitjordan.com/" target="_blank">www.visitjordan.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Jordan has excellent hospitals in large towns and cities, with clinics in many villages. The standard of healthcare is generally very high, with facilities in Jordanian private hospitals as good as (or, in some cases, better than) equivalent facilities in Europe or North America. Treatment is relatively cheap compared to medical care in the US. Most medical professionals will have been trained in English-speaking countries, so the language barrier is negligible. Health insurance is essential. You should not consider any sort of travel in Jordan without suitable insurance cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travellers planning to stay as a resident or long-term visitor for over 3 months should check with their nearest Jordanian embassy to find out if they need to take an HIV test as a condition of entry. HIV positive travellers can be refused entry at the border. Possessing antiretrovirals may be used as confirmation of carrier status.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Jordan&amp;rsquo;s tap water is generally safe to drink in the towns and cities &amp;ndash; it is heavily chlorinated, so may taste bad, but it will not cause harm. Nonetheless, if you can, it is advisable to stick to bottled water and pasteurised milk. Avoid dairy products made from un-boiled milk. Be careful with food and water in rural areas, ensure meat and fish are well cooked and avoid raw vegetables and ready-peeled fruit.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccination against tuberculosis and hepatitis B is sometimes recommended. There are fears Syrian refugees have brought polio to Jordan and the WHO advises vaccinations against it. Otherwise, the main health risks come from over-exposure to the sun; sunburn, sunstroke and dehydration are all real concerns. Take care to cover your skin, both to prevent skin damage and to limit dehydration.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>(a) Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.  (b) Easter holidays are observed only by Christian business establishments.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							25 May </p><p>Army Day :
							10 June </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Jordan by people 18 years of age and older without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 200g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; Gifts up to the value of JD200.</p>
<p>There are extensive duty-free shops at the airport, both in arrivals and departures, and at every border crossing by land. Within 14 days of your arrival in Jordan, you can also go to the Duty Free Shop on Tunis Street, near 4th Circle in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amman">Amman</a>, to buy your permitted allowance of cigarettes, alcohol and other luxury goods without paying duty. Bring your passport with you.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics, firearms and ammunition, and pornography.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Antiquities (classed as items dating from before AD1750).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dinar (JOD; symbol JD) = 100 piastres or qirsh, or 1000 fils. Notes are in denominations of JD50, 20, 10, 5 and 1, and 500 fils. Coins are in denominations of JD1, 1/2 and 1/4; 10, 5, 2 and 1/2 piastres; and 1 and 1/2 qirsh.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged easily in banks and bureaux de change. Most hotels also provide exchange facilities. The daily exchange rates are published in local newspapers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Visa, Diners Club and Mastercard are accepted in hotels, restaurants and larger shops.</p><p>ATMs can be found in most of the larger towns and throughout <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amman">Amman</a>. Jordan is a cash society. In most places (other than top-end hotels and restaurants) the only acceptable method of payment is cash dinars. Dollars and other foreign currencies are generally not accepted. Jordan is also very safe; crime is exceptionally low, and you do not need to worry about carrying cash with you. Scams are few. You may find yourself paying slightly over the odds for taxis or guide services, but real rip-offs are surprisingly rare.</p>
<p>One exception is in and around the tourist town of Petra &ndash; here, there is a higher-than-usual prevalence of touts and cheats trying to overcharge and under-deliver. Be more on your guard here than elsewhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Those issued by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> banks in sterling, euros or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars are accepted by licensed banks and bureaux de change. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sat-Thu 0830-1500. Hours during Ramadan are 0830-1000, although some banks open in the afternoon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Jordan, a passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit passengers continuing their journey to another country within 24 hours are exempt from visa charges. Transit visas can only be issued at Jordanian airports and not at embassies or consulates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa on arrival: JD40.</p>
<p>In advance: single-entry visa: &pound;60; double-entry visa: &pound;90; multiple-entry visa: &pound;180. An additional fee of &pound;7.50 applies to all visa types.</p>
<p>Jordan waives visa fees for those travelling in groups of five or more who stay for over two nights  and use a local tour operator or a UK company which works with a  Jordanian partner on the ground.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa on arrival: usually valid for a month.</p>
<p>Single-entry visa in advance: two months from the date of issue; double-entry visa: three months from the date of issue; multiple-entry visa: six months from the date of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nearest consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If applying in advance, visa processing usually takes four to five working days for nationals listed in the chart above, but may take longer for other nationals. Allow up to two weeks for postal applications.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas may be extended to a maximum of six months by registering with a police station in Jordan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[31.212001]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[36.384999]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>89,342 sq km (34,495 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>7,747,800 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>90.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amman.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jordan borders Israel (and the Palestinian National Authority Region), the Syrian Arab Republic, Iraq and Saudi Arabia. At 400m (1,300ft) below sea level, the Dead Sea,<strong> </strong>in the northwest of Jordan, is the lowest point on earth and one of the country's most distinctive features. The Red Sea, to which Jordan has a narrow access at Aqaba in the southwest, is teeming with life. <br />
<br />
The River Jordan flows into the Dead Sea, and there are plans to build a canal - the Two Seas Canal (or the Dead-Red Canal) -<strong> </strong>that would link the Dead Sea to the Red Sea. Capital Amman perches above the Dead Sea Depression, at a height of 800m (2,625ft), surrounded to the north by undulating hills, and by desert escarpments to the south, on which graze the sheep and goat herds of nomadic tribes. <br />
<br />
Jordan's northeastern flank is flat desert sprinkled with oases, while the spectacular southeastern desert is characterised by wind-eroded forms and brightly coloured sandstone cliffs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Over 92% Sunni Muslim, with 2% Shi'a and Druze Muslim. A significant Greek Orthodox Christian minority (6%) resides mainly in the villages around the hill city of Madaba.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the customary form of greeting. Jordanians are proud of their Arab culture and hospitality is a matter of great importance. Visitors are made to feel very welcome and Jordanians are happy to act as hosts and guides, keen to inform tourists about their traditions and culture. Islam always plays an important role in society. Arabic coffee will often be served continuously during social occasions. To signal that no more is wanted, slightly tilt the cup when handing it back, otherwise it will be refilled. If invited for dinner, a small gift is customarily given. Women are expected to dress modestly and beachwear must only be worn at private beaches or poolside.  </p>
<p><strong>Photography:</strong> It is polite to ask permission to take photographs of people and livestock; in some places photography is forbidden.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Both round European-style plugs with two round pins and British-style plugs with three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Omar al-Razzaz since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Abdullah II since 1999.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The area encompassed by the modern Kingdom of Jordan only had borders drawn around it in the 20th century. Before then, it was generally seen only as a small part of the larger Syria region.</p>
<p>Jordan was one of the locations where Stone Age hunter-gatherers settled for the first time, building villages and domesticating animals. Settlement expanded during the Bronze Age (roughly 3000-1200 BCE), when Jordan also features in the Old Testament record. The towns of Sodom and Gomorrah were probably located on Jordan&rsquo;s side of the Dead Sea.</p>
<p>During the Iron Age (1200-332 BCE), Jordan clashed with the Israelites, then the Assyrians, Babylonians and Persians, finally coming under Greek control. Around this time, an Arabian tribe known as the Nabateans settled here, naming their capital Petra. They became fabulously wealthy, controlling the lucrative trade in frankincense and spices between Arabia and Europe.</p>
<p>In 106 CE the Romans absorbed the Nabatean kingdom, building new roads across Jordan, beautifying cities and fortifying the desert frontier. By the 4th century, Roman security was beginning to crumble. Christianity was adopted and Jordan became a centre for mosaic art.</p>
<p>Islamic armies conquered the region in 636. Jordan flourished under the Umayyad dynasty (661-750 CE), which ruled from Damascus, but when power shifted east to the Baghdad-based Abbasid dynasty, Jordan fell into neglect. The invading European Christian armies of the Crusaders briefly occupied Jordan in the 12th century, but under the Ottomans Jordan became a backwater.</p>
<p>Following anti-Muslim pogroms in Russia in the 1870s, Circassian refugees settled in Jordan &ndash; then largely deserted &ndash; re-founding Amman and ushering in Jordan&rsquo;s modern history. After the Ottoman Turks were repulsed during the Great Arab Revolt of 1916-17, Jordan won independence, first as a British-controlled emirate in 1923 under Abdullah I &ndash; a monarch from the Hashemite family of Mecca &ndash; then in 1946 as a fully-fledged independent kingdom.</p>
<p>Since then, Jordan has taken in huge number of refugees from Palestine, Iraq and Syria, which has shaped the national character. However, attitudes seem to be hardening and in late 2015 the Jordanian government came under fire from human rights groups for deporting Sudanese asylum seekers.</p>
<p>As one of the West&rsquo;s key allies in the Arab world, at peace with Israel, and yet closely bound into regional politics, with strong links to Iraq and Saudi Arabia, Jordan must play one of the trickiest fence-sitting roles in world politics.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Jordan&rsquo;s national flower is the rare and endangered black iris, which flowers in Wadi Rum in spring. <br />
&bull;	Common Jordanian courtesy dictates that a host should give up any household item that a guest shows a particular interest in, so be sparing with your praise when dining in a local&rsquo;s home.<br />
&bull;	Unlike many other countries in the region, Jordan has no oil.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 966 2664.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.jordanembassyus.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 966 2664.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3504 International Drive<br/>Washington DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7937 3685.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://jordanembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7937 3685.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Kensington<br/>6 Upper Phillimore Gardens<br/>London<br/>W8 7HA<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Jordan]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+962 06 590 9200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/jordan</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+962 06 590 9200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Sun-Wed 0800-1530, Thu 0800-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Abdoun (PO Box 87)<br/>Amman<br/>11118<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s easy to see why Lawrence of Arabia was so taken with Jordan. Probably the most appealing destination in the Middle East, this ancient Arab kingdom is a hospitable land packed with epic scenery and momentous relics.</p>
<p>Many travellers visit Jordan with its history in mind, and understandably so. The country is steeped in stories from the distant past, with the ruins to prove it. There&rsquo;s the 2,000-year-old &ldquo;lost city&rdquo; of Petra, carved from rose-red sandstone cliffs by the Nabateans, and the legendary Lawrence of Arabia trail, which takes visitors from his crumbling fort at Azraq to the magnificent deserts of Wadi Rum.</p>
<p>Important biblical sites abound; visitors can trek along pilgrimage routes mentioned in the Old Testament, take in views of the Promised Land revealed to Moses and visit Bethany-by-the-Jordan where John baptised Jesus.</p>
<p>If Jordan&rsquo;s overwhelming historical sites begin to wear you out, take a restorative dip in the therapeutic waters of the Dead Sea, go scuba diving over coral reefs in the Red Sea or stay in the desert with Bedouins, who offer travellers a glimpse into their traditional way of life.</p>
<p>For all its history and natural beauty, though, Jordan looks forward. Its relatively stable economic and political position in the Middle East has fuelled modernisation, particularly in the capital Amman. With new upmarket hotels, restaurants and bars, the city is no longer just a base from which to explore the ancient sites, but a destination in its own right.</p>
<p>In Jordan, hospitality is king. Everywhere you visit you will hear heartfelt words of welcome, and will often be invited into shops or peoples&rsquo; homes for a glass of sweet tea and a conversation. In other places this might prelude a hard-sell campaign of carpet-flogging, but in Jordan, it&rsquo;s almost always borne simply of an interest to engage with a visitor. As the Jordanians say; &ldquo;Ahlan wa sahlan&rdquo; &ndash; come in and make yourself at home.</p><p>It&rsquo;s easy to see why Lawrence of Arabia was so taken with Jordan. Probably the most appealing destination in the Middle East, this ancient Arab kingdom is a hospitable land packed with epic scenery and momentous relics.&nbsp;Many travellers visit Jordan with its history in mind, and understandably so. The country is steeped in stories from the distant past, with the ruins to prove it. There&rsquo;s the 2,000-year-old &ldquo;lost city&rdquo; of Petra, carved from rose-red sandstone cliffs by the Nabateans, and the legendary Lawrence of Arabia trail, which takes visitors from his crumbling fort at Azraq to the magnificent deserts of Wadi Rum.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
