<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Kazakhstan" ColCode="kaz" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="kz" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Kazakhstan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Continental climate with cold winters and hot summers. Although Kazakhstan has some of the highest peaks in the CIS, the climate is fairly dry. The hottest month is July (August in mountain regions).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Astana (<a href="http://www.airastana.com" target="_blank">www.airastana.com</a>) operates frequent domestic flights. While Air Astana does maintain aircraft to European JAR-145 standards, travellers should note that maintenance procedures for some aircraft operating internally may not conform to internationally accepted standards.</p>
<p>Domestic airports include Astana (<a href="http://www.astanaairport.com" target="_blank">www.astanaairport.com</a>), Almaty (<a href="http://www.almatyairport.com" target="_blank">www.almatyairport.com</a>), Kyzylorda, Oral<em> </em>and Aktau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can take river trips in Semipalatinsk on the River Irtysh.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The cost of rail travel in Kazakhstan is minimal in comparison with Western Europe and there are regular connections between all the main centres. Queues at stations to buy a ticket can be long and you should bring your own food and drink for the journey. It may be advisable for foreign visitors to travel by bus between cities, owing to an increase in robberies on trains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>There is a reasonable network of roads in Kazakhstan connecting all the towns and regional centres, but roads aren't well maintained. Petrol supplies are reasonably reliable in comparison with other Central Asian republics. Road conditions can be dangerous in winter.</p><p>These are available in all Kazakh cities. Travellers should not use unlicensed taxis.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>Available in Almaty and Astana and at the airports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almaty is served by trolleybuses, buses and a modern metro system. There are plans for a light-rail network in Astana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Astana (<a href="http://www.airastana.com" target="_blank">www.airastana.com</a>) is the national airline and runs non-stop flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> to Astana. There are no direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kazakhstan/almaty-international-airport">Almaty Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Astana: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 6 hours 20 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 15 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Astana International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.astanaairport.kz]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Almaty International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.alaport.com<p>The airport is located 15km (9 miles) northeast of central Almaty.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+7 727 270 3333</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong>&nbsp;Aqtau, Atyrau, Oskemen, Pavlodar and Semey. Freight is carried on the Caspian Sea to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iran">Iran</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Services run twice a week from Almaty to Urumchi in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> and every other day to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a> (journey time - 3 days). Trains also connect Moscow and Astana every two days.&nbsp;Between Tashkent and Almaty, there are trains about twice a week.</p>
<p>Foreign visitors should exercise caution when using trains other than the Moscow trains; violent crime against Westerners is on the increase.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International calls can be made at a reduced rate from 2000-0800 local time. All major cities are equipped with card operated phones. Cards can be purchased at kiosks, and can be used to make international calls. The best card to make international calls with is an <em>i-card+</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good around the main cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet cafes in most towns and cities. Internet access is also available in major hotels, but services are usually more expensive than in cafes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Full postal facilities are available at main post offices in the cities, which are open 24 hours a day, seven days a week. The main post office in Almaty is located on Ulitsa Kurmangazy. International postal communication is undertaken by the firms <em>Blitz-Pochta</em>, <em>International Press</em> and <em>Press Limited</em>. <br />Delivery within the republic takes three to five days. Post to Western Europe and the USA takes between two to three weeks. Mail addresses should be laid out in the following order: country, postcode, city, street, house number and, lastly, the person's name. Visitors can also use post offices located within major hotels.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Almaty</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Almaty is a city of modern architecture, wide streets, cool fountains, parks and squares and spectacular mountain views. Attractions in the city include the Panfilov Park, which is dominated by one of the world's tallest wooden buildings, built at the turn of the 20th century without using a single nail, and the Zenkov Cathedral. Also find fine museums such as the State Art Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Archaeological sites</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Several archaeological and ethnographic sites have been preserved in central Kazakhstan. There are Bronze Age and Early Iron Age sites and New Stone Age and Bronze Age settlements in the Karkarala Oasis. The Bayan-Aul National Park has rock drawings, stone sculptures, clean, sparkling lakes and pines clinging to the rocks.</p>]]><p><b>Baikonur Cosmodrome</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Baikonur Cosmodrome, located 5km (3 miles) from the garrison city of Leninsk and 230km (143 miles) from Kzil-Orda, is the Central Asian answer to Cape Canaveral - tours are available, during which visitors can witness space launches. It was from here, on 12 April 1961, that Yuri Gagarin, the world's first cosmonaut, took off.</p>]]><p><b>Hiking and trekking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The country's rugged landscape and incredible mountain ranges, offer great mountain climbing and trekking. The best season for trekking is between June and September.</p>]]><p><b>Mountains and lakes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Tien Shan Mountains stretch for more than 1,500km (932 miles), with the highest peaks Pobeda Peak (7,439m/24,406ft) and Khan-Tengri Peak (7,010m/23,000ft) - a snowy, marble-like pyramid. The huge Inylchek Glacier splits the summits and the beautiful Mertzbakher Lake lies at its centre. The Kolsai Lakes - known as the 'pearls of the northern Tien-Shan' - lie within the ridges of the Kungei Alatau range. Kazakhstan also boasts one of the largest lakes in the world: the unique Lake Balkhash is half saline, half fresh water.</p>]]><p><b>Nature reserves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Kurgaldjino in the north of Kazakhstan houses the most northerly settlement of pink flamingos in the world, while Naurzum, offers a rich landscape of geographical contrasts: salt lakes ringed by forests, ancient pines strewn amongst sand dunes, pine forests growing out of salt-marsh beds, and rare animals such as hisser swans and grave eagles. Aksu-Zhabagly is a UNESCO biosphere reserve in southern Kazakhstan and home to 239 species of birds, 47 species of animals and 1,400 species of plants.</p>]]><p><b>Relax at a spa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Kazakhstan has a wide range of spas. The most internationally renowned resorts include Sari Agach (in the south), Mujaldi (in the Pavlodar region), Arasan-Kapal (in the Taldikorgan region), Jani-Kurgan (in the Kzil-Orda region), Kokshetau and Zerenda (in the Kokshetau region) and those located in Zaili Alatau.</p>]]><p><b>Watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>All the regional centres boast sport complexes, swimming pools and training halls. Rafting and canoeing can be easily arranged through local travel agents. The Ili river between Lake Qapshaghay and Lake Balhash is a good place for this.</p>]]><p><b>Winter sports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The 4,000m- (13,123ft-) high Zaili Alatau Mountains near Almaty offer great winter sporting activities. Near Almaty, the Medeu ice-skating rink is the largest speed-skating rink in the world; over 120 world records in ice skating and ice hockey have been set here. Watch Ice hockey games at the rink in Ust-Kamenogorsk. The winter sports complex of Chimbulak offers fantastic skiing<strong>,</strong> and many competitions are held here.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$132 billion (2008).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil, metals, machinery, chemicals, grain, wool and coal.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Industrial materials, oil and gas, and vehicles.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Germany, Russia, Italy, The Netherlands, China (PR), Uzbekistan, Korea (Rep) and Ukraine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kazakhstan has enormous natural deposits, including iron, nickel, zinc, manganese, coal, chromium, copper, lead, gold and silver. The coalfields of the Karaganda are some of the largest in Asia. There are substantial oil and gas deposits, many of which have only recently been located.<br /><br />Stone, such as marble and granite, is also produced in large quantities. Agriculture accounts for half of economic output; the main commodities are wheat, meat products, wool and a variety of crops: sugar beet, potatoes, cereals, cotton, fruit and vegetables. Livestock rearing is also important in this very arid region.  <br /><br />A consequence of extensive cultivation is heavy demand on water supplies, most particularly the rivers of Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan. This was the major cause of one of the greatest ecological disasters of recent times: the shrinking of the Aral Sea.<br /><br />Since independence, Kazakhstan has joined the IMF, World Bank and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, and has signed a co-operation agreement with the EU. It also belongs to the Central Asian Economic Union (ECO).<br />Many international business events are held in the Alatau Winter Resort near Almaty, by such organisations as UNESCO, ICF and others. There is an annual International Exhibition Fair called Karkara<em> </em>held at the Exhibition Complex of the Business Cooperation Centre in Almaty every September. Businesspeople from all over the world meet here to make contacts and conclude business contracts. Other large industrial towns, such as Chimkent, Karaganda and Pavlodar, have conference and convention facilities and other industrial exhibitions and fairs are held here.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Union of Chambers of Commerce and Industry of the Republic of Kazakhstan</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (3272) 777 050
					Website:
					Address: Business Centre (Nurky-Tau),Al-Farabi 5,Office 503,Almaty,50059]]><b>Ministry of Economy and Trade</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (3172) 229 032 ,241 529
					Website:
					Address: Batyr Avenue,Transport Tower,Kabanbay,Astana,473000]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Kazakhstan food is a reflection of the country's unique ethnic and religious composition. Beer, vodka, brandy and sparkling wines are available in many restaurants.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br /><em>&bull; Kazi</em> and <em>chuzhuk</em> (horsemeat sausages).<br /><em>&bull; Kaurdak</em> (mutton stew).<br /><em>&bull;</em> Sheep's head.<br /><em>&bull; Besbarmak</em> (made from horse meat or mutton and dough). <br /><em>&bull; Shashlyk</em> (skewered chunks of mutton barbecued over charcoal).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>This is not customary at restaurants and cafes, but is increasingly common in international hotels. A service charge is included in hotel and restaurant bills.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of nightclubs and casinos in Almaty and several other cities. Many restaurants play music after 2000. Kazakhstan's most reknowned concert halls and theatres are all located in Almaty.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Located north of Panfilov Park, Almaty has a bazaar, where a diverse range of items can be bought.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most towns in Kazakhstan have a limited supply of reasonable accommodation. It is advisable to make reservations in advance, either directly or through a travel agency. Most hotels deliver a basic level of comfort, although Western standards should not be expected.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> A star-grading system is in use. There are at least two 5-star hotels in Almaty, as well as numerous new hotels of a reasonable standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most towns in Kazakhstan have a limited supply of reasonable accommodation. It is advisable to make reservations in advance, either directly or through a travel agency. Most hotels deliver a basic level of comfort, although Western standards should not be expected.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> A star-grading system is in use. There are at least two 5-star hotels in Almaty, as well as numerous new hotels of a reasonable standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most towns in Kazakhstan have a limited supply of reasonable accommodation. It is advisable to make reservations in advance, either directly or through a travel agency. Most hotels deliver a basic level of comfort, although Western standards should not be expected.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> A star-grading system is in use. There are at least two 5-star hotels in Almaty, as well as numerous new hotels of a reasonable standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There is a large network of hospitals, emergency centres and pharmacies. The largest include the Central Hospital, the Maternity and Childhood Institute Clinic and the Medical Teaching Institute Clinic in Almaty, and the Spinal Centre and Hospital of Rehabilitation Treatment in Karaganda. However, standards within the public healthcare system have declined significantly since the Soviet era. It is hard to ascertain the level of expertise of the doctors, and visitors cannot rely on the availability of western medicines. Comprehensive medical insurance is strongly advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B, C and E and tuberculosis occur. Increased cases of meningitis and encephalitis have been reported in Almaty. Tick-borne encephalitis is a problem in mountains and forests, particularly during April, May and June. There is some presence of rabies. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Russian Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>People's Unity Day :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							09 May </p><p>Constitution Day :
							30 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							16 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Kazakhstan by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 200g of tobacco products.<br />
&bull; 3L of alcoholic beverages. <br />
&bull; A reasonable quantity of perfume for personal use.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of &euro;1,500 for personal use only.<br />
<br />
On entering the country, you must complete a customs declaration form, which you must retain until departure. This allows the import of articles intended for personal use, including currency and valuables, which you must register on the declaration form. You must export these at the end of the stay. Customs inspection can be long and detailed. It is advisable to keep receipts for items bought in Kazakhstan in order to avoid difficulties at customs on departure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Photographs and printed matter directed against Kazakhstan, military arms and ammunition, narcotics and live animals.</p>
<p>Food must be accompanied by a phytosanitary certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arms and ammunition, precious metals and stones, and furs.</p>
<p>Antiquities and art objects require an export permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kazakh Tenge (KZT; symbol лв). Notes are in denominations of лв 10,000, 5,000, 2,000, 1,000, 500 and 200. Coins are in denominations of лв 100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national currency, the Tenge, may only be obtained within Kazakhstan. Conversion of the Tenge back into hard currency may prove difficult. Foreign currency should only be exchanged at official bureaux and all transactions must be recorded on the currency declaration form that is issued on arrival. It is wise to retain all exchange receipts, although they are seldom inspected. Unless travelling with a licensed tourist company (in which case, accommodation, transport and meals are paid before departure), money should be brought in US Dollars cash and exchanged when necessary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major European and international credit cards, including Diners Club and Visa, are accepted in the larger hotels in Almaty and in major shops and restaurants. Facilities exist for credit card cash withdrawals in Kazakhstan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars. Traveller's cheques are accepted at larger hotels and at banks in the big cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800. Banks close for lunch 1300-1400. All banks are closed Sat-Sun.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Kazakhstan, a passport valid for six months beyond the visa expiry date is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: &pound;15 (single-entry).</p>
<p>Tourist visa: &pound;35 (single-entry).</p>
<p>Business visa: &pound;50 (single-entry); &pound;150 (multiple-entry up to one year); &pound;250 (multiple-entry up to two years).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: five days; tourist/business visas: 30 days per stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing usually takes five days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You may only extend your visa if you have documents showing a need for you to remain longer in Kazakhstan. In this case, you can extend visas at local offices affiliated to the Ministry of Interior.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[48.146028]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[67.179018]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,724,900 sq km (1,052,089 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>17,855,384 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Astana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Five times the size of France and half the size of the USA, Kazakhstan is the second largest state in the Commonwealth of Independent States, and is bordered by the Russian Federation to the north and west, the Caspian Sea, Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan to the southwest, Kyrgyzstan to the south and China to the southeast. 90% of the country is made up of steppe, the sand massives of the Kara Kum and the vast desert of Kizilkum, while in the southeast of the country the mountains of the Tian Shan and the Altai form a great natural frontier with tens of thousands of lakes and rivers. Lake Balkhash is the country's largest expanses of water, since the Aral Sea dried up.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mainly Sunni Muslim. There are Russian Orthodox and Jewish minorities. There are 10 independent denominations of Christianity. The Kazakhs do not express their religious feelings fervently - Kazakhstan is an outlying district of the Muslim world and a meeting point of Russian, Chinese and Central Asian civilisations. Islam plays a minor role in policy and there are no significant Islamic political organisations in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kazakhs are very hospitable. When greeting a guest, the host gives him/her both hands as if showing that he/she is unarmed. When addressing a guest or elder, a Kazakh may address him/her with a shortened form of the guest's or elder's name and the suffix 'ke'. For example, Abkhan may be called Abeke, Nursultan can be called Nureke. This should be regarded as indicating a high level of respect for the visitor. <br /><br />At a Kazakh home, the most honoured guest, usually the oldest, is traditionally offered a boiled sheep's head on a beautiful dish as a further sign of respect. National customs forbid young people whose parents are still alive from cutting the sheep's head. They must pass the dish to the other guests for cutting. Inside mosques, women observe their own ritual in a separate room, and must cover their heads and their arms. Formal dress is often required when visiting the theatre, or attending a dinner party. Shorts should not be worn except on the sports ground.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Karim Masimov since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Nursultan Abishuly Nazarbayev since 1991.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The south of Kazakhstan was inhabited as early as the Palaeolithic Era and tribes were breeding cattle and producing bronze-ware by the middle of the second millennium BC. Soon after, the Saks, Savromat, Kangues and Usuns occupied the area and later, the Huns. By the fourth century AD, most of the Saks and Usuns had moved west and individual states appeared, such as Westturkic Khanate, which was established by Turkish tribes trading on the Silk Road. During the eighth and ninth centuries the Kimak tribes arrived of which the largest and strongest were the Kipchaks, ancestors of the present-day Kazakhs. In the 10th century Islam was declared the state religion before the Mongols invaded in the 13th century and Genghis Khan destroyed most of the towns. However, by the 15th century, the Kazakh Khanate state was thriving as the tribes reformed into three groups – Junior, Middle and Senior Zhuzes – known as Kazakhs. In 1734 the Junior Zhuze became Russian citizens, followed by the Middle in 1742 and the Senior Zhuze in 1849. The Kazakhs had allied themselves with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a> in the mid-18th century to ward off the Mongols, but by 1860 the Russians had suppressed the last of the Kazakh rebellions and thousands of Russian and Ukrainian peasants settled in Kazakhstan. A final anti-Tsarist rebellion in 1916 was brutally supressed before the Bolshevik revolution and yet more fierce fighting in the civil war that followed. In 1920, Kazakhstan was recognised as an autonomous republic and although its mining and chemical industries, as well as agriculture, developed greatly, more than two million Kazakhs died of hunger during the 1930s before the country again experienced large-scale immigration. It was the site of most of the main testing and launch facilities for the Soviet nuclear, missile and space programmes and the first manned spaceflight by Yuri Gagarin was launched from Baikonur in central Kazakhstan. In 1986 the Brezhnevian regime was deposed in favour of a new administration under Gennadi Kolbin, a protégé of the reformist Soviet leader, Mikhail Gorbachev. Three years later Nursultan Nazarbayev, replaced him and guided Kazakhstan to independence. As the only candidate at the presidential election in December 1991 he won 98 per cent of the vote and in June 1997 realised his pet project, the inauguration of a new capital city at Astana. Kazakhstan's main assets are its huge and largely unexploited oil and gas fields.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>&bull; Kazakhstan is home to 131 ethnicities.</p><p>&bull; World IBF, WBO and IBO heavyweight boxing champion Vladimir Klitschko was born in Kazakhstan.</p><p>&bull; The unfinished Mausoleum of Khoja Ahmed Yasawi in Turkestan dates from the late 14th century is widely considered to represent the Khazakh national identity.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Kazakhstan in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 232 5488.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.kazakhembus.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 232 5488.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1830 (embassy); Mon-Friday (except Wednesday): 0900-1200 (consular).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>1401 16th Street<br/>Washington<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Kazakhstan in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b> (020) 7581 4646 (ext 207/8 for visa section)</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mfa.gov.kz/london</p><p><b>Tel:</b> (020) 7581 4646 (ext 207/8 for visa section)</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1830; Mon-Fri 0900-1200 (consular section, closed Wednesdays except for nationals of Kazakhstan and closed on Kazakhstan national holidays).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>33 Thurloe Square<br/>London<br/>SW7 2SD<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Kazakhstan]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(7172) 556200</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinkz.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(7172) 556200</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1730, Fri 0900-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>62 Kosmonavtov Street<br/>6the Floor,Renco Building<br/>Astana<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unexplored by many, Kazakhstan is a curious yet little-known land of vast plains, mountainous horizons and beautiful culture. Bordering Russia in Central Asia, it's truly massive in size – this is, after all, ranked as the world's ninth biggest country. It's also the most economically successful of those countries surrounding it, known fondly as the 'stans'. This is largely thanks to oil reserves, as well as other natural resources. The upshot? You can expect more modern, higher-quality hotels, restaurants and travel options compared to some of the country's poorer neighbours.</p><p>South Kazakhstan is a focus of Central Asian history, featuring many famous monuments. It is a scenically diverse region where the snow-capped peaks, lakes and glaciers of the Tian Shan range give way to steppe and desert. The desert is home to the Singing Barkhan - a sand dune 3.2km (2 miles) long, which, as it crumbles, produces a peculiar singing sound.</p><p>Almaty was until very recently the former capital of Kazakhstan and it enjoys a beautiful setting between mountains and plains. Still the country's biggest city, it is a hub of modern architecture, cool fountains, parks and spectacular mountain views. You can also expect irreverent nightspots, trendy cafes, and palatial malls there. The present capital of Astana is following in its predecessor's footsteps as a modern metropolis, with its space-age buildings clinging to the northern steppe.</p><p>The truth is, though, that travellers are more likely to be attracted to Kazakhstan's natural wonders. It's a beautiful country in its own haunting way, where intrepid travellers will enjoy hiking through the lofty mountains and down in the valleys of the Tian Shan. Its sparseness can seem mind-boggling, but you'll find plenty of wildlife if you look for it, especially in the lake-strewn steppe. It's also worth seeking out the underground mosques and villages that are scattered about the land. All in all, Kazakhstan is a special, unique country well worth discovering despite it being low on the radar of most tourists.</p>Unexplored by many, Kazakhstan is an intriguing and little-known land of vast plains, mountainous horizons and beautiful culture.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
