<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Kiribati" ColCode="kir" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ki" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Kiribati]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Maritime equatorial in the central islands of the group. The islands to the north and south are more tropical. The trade winds blow between March and October, making this the most pleasant time of the year, while the highest rainfall (December to May) is concentrated on the northern islands. November to February is more wet and humid than the rest of the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Kiribati (<a href="http://www.airkiribati.com.ki" target="_blank">www.airkiribati.com.ki</a>) and Coral Sun Airways (<a href="http://www.coralsunaviation.com" target="_blank">www.coralsunaviation.com</a>) operate internal flights to nearly all the outer islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Several passenger ferries run between the smaller islands. Boats are available for hire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>All-weather roads are limited to urban Tarawa and Christmas Island.</p><p>Privately owned buses<strong> </strong>are available in Tarawa and Christmas Island. Buses are fairly cheap and you can flag them down nearly anywhere.</p><p>There are no taxis in Kiribati.</p><p>International Driving Permit required.</p><p>You can rent cars, motorbikes and scooters in South Tarawa. Car hire is also available on Christmas Island. In the outer Gilbert Islands, you can rent motorbikes or small trucks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Air Kiribati (<a href="http://www.airkiribati.com.ki" target="_blank">www.airkiribati.com.ki</a>), but it only operates domestic flights. Fiji Airways (<a href="http://www.fijiairways.com" target="_blank">www.fijiairways.com</a>) flies direct from Fiji to Tarawa, while Nauru Airlines (<a href="http://www.ourairline.com.au" target="_blank">www.ourairline.com.au</a>) runs flights from Nauru to Tarawa, with connections to Brisbane, Australia. You can only reach Kanton Island by private jet or boat charters.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Tarawa: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 35 hours or more (including stopovers); Nadi, Fiji - 3 hours; Nauru - 1 hour 15 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A$20; children under two years of age, and transit passengers not leaving the airport are exempt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong>&nbsp;Banaba, Christmas Island and Tarawa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Most international calls from Kiribati have to go through the operator. Radio telephone calls can be arranged to most outer islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>GSM 900 network in use. Network provider is Telecom Services Kiribati Ltd<em> </em>(<a href="http://www.tskl.net.ki" target="_blank">www.tskl.net.ki</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no Internet cafes in Kiribati.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Freedom of speech and of the media is generally respected. The government-run radio station and newspaper offer diverse views. Both Protestant and Catholic churches publish newsletters and periodicals; these are important sources of information. The weekly papers are <em>Kiribati Newstar</em> and <em>Te Uekera</em>, published in English and Kiribati; Kiribati Business Link is published in English. There is no domestic television service; Radio Kiribati is state run.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes up to two weeks. There is a weekly postal service for overseas mail.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Embrace the bustle of South Tarawa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Most visitors to Kiribati skip the capital and head straight to the archipelago's sandy shores. It's easy to see why: bustling South Tarawa is not the prettiest town and its tourist infrastructure is somewhat limited. But if you want to get a true slice of local life – explore local markets and meet the locals – this is the place to be.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Kiribati’s underwater treasures</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Kiribati has the distinction of being the world's largest coral atoll, and is a dream destination for divers. The archipelago's beautiful white sandy beaches and crystal-clear lagoons give way to wonderful coral gardens, much of which fall into the Phoenix Island Protected Area, one of the world's largest marine reserves.</p>]]><p><b>Get a bird’s-eye view of Kiribati</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A fine way to get the whole picture of Kiribati is to take a "flight-seeing" trip on one of the many light aircraft that serve the region. Tours take in the islands of Abaiang, Abemama, Maiana and Tarawa, and other islands can be visited on request.</p>]]><p><b>Go birdwatching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Birdwatching is popular, especially on Christmas Island where millions of birds swarm everywhere. The archipelago is a major breeding ground and sanctuary for birds in the Pacific and even has its own endemic species: the Christmas Island Warbler. The best time for birdwatching is between June and December.</p>]]><p><b>Imbibe local culture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Every village in Kiribati has a <em>maneaba</em>, or community centre. Made of coconut wood and pandanus leaves, <em>maneabas</em> are the administrative headquarters of the islands villages, but they are also a place where visitors can enjoy traditional dancing, singing and storytelling.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about Kiribati’s wartime history</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Some of the bloodiest fighting between US and Japanese forces took place in Kiribati and the surrounding islands during WWII. A number of war relics can be seen on Tarawa and Butaritari Island, including defence guns, rusting tanks and concrete bunkers. Tours of battlegrounds can also be arranged.</p>]]><p><b>Make a seasonal trip to Christmas Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Actually, you don't have to wait till the festive season to visit this stunning atoll. Occupying almost half the landmass of Kiribati, Christmas Island is covered in lakes and ponds and boasts some of the largest bird colonies in the archipelago. The atoll is also a gateway to Kiribati's world-renowned coral reefs.</p>]]><p><b>Try your hand at game fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Game fishing is particularly popular on the island and in particular Christmas Island. It's of a world-class standard and has been the site of many international game fishing world records. Another big lure to Kiribati is the prevalence of the magnificent bonefish.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$64 million (2006).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Copra, pet fish and seaweed.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food and manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Japan, USA, New Zealand, Australia and China (PR).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main agricultural crop is coconut, from which copra, the principal export commodity, is derived. Bananas, breadfruit and papayas are also produced, largely for domestic consumption. The local fishing industry has declined drastically, particularly after the closure of the state fishing company, but the sale of licences to foreign fleets is an important source of government revenue. Despite its remoteness, Kiribati has managed to develop a tourism industry which now accounts for about one-fifth of GDP. The economy grew by 1.8% in 2006, while inflation hovered between 3 and 4%.<br /><br />Kiribati remains heavily dependent on foreign aid and remittances from the many islanders of working age employed overseas. Kiribati is a member of the Pacific Community, the South Pacific Forum and the Asian Development Bank. Kiribati is also involved with various regional initiatives to promote economic development. Kiribati is one of the 14 signatories to the Pacific Islands Countries Trade Agreement, agreed in 2001, which plans measures to boost regional trade.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shirt and smart trousers or skirt will suffice most of the time; ties need only be worn for formal occasions.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1230 and 1330-1615.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Restaurants are few in number and are situated mainly in the larger towns.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; In the southern islands, the boiled fruit of <em>pandanus</em> (screwpine), sliced thinly and spread with coconut cream. <br />&bull; <em>Palu sami</em> (coconut cream with sliced onion and curry powder, wrapped in taro leaves and pressure cooked in an earth-oven packed with seaweed. It can be eaten on its own or served with roast pork or chicken).<br />&bull; As in many of the islands of the South Pacific, there is a tendency amongst local people to regard imported canned products as luxuries.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Not expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are 'Island Nights' which feature traditional Polynesian music and dancing, film shows and feasts in <em>maneabas </em>(local meeting houses), which can be found throughout the islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handicrafts include baskets, table mats, fans and cups made from pandanus leaves, coconut leaves, coconut shells and sea shells. Sea-shell necklaces are popular, as are models of Gilbertese canoes and houses. A prized item is the Kiribati shark-tooth sword made of polished coconut wood with shark teeth, filed to razor sharpness, lashed to the two edges. These days, most examples are modern reproductions.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1900 (some shops open until 2030), Sun 0800-1900 (most small shops).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are few hotels in Kiribati, the major ones being on Tarawa, Christmas Island and Abemama. The small island of Kirimati also has a few hotels. <br />Accommodation is good although not luxurious, but there are plans to build a luxury 150-room hotel on Christmas Island. A 10% service charge is added to all hotel bills. Further information is available from south-pacific.travel (South Pacific Tourism Organisation) or the honorary consulate (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Inexpensive rest houses can be found on all the other islands - for example, Abemama, Captain Cook, Christmas Island, Otintai, Robert Louis Stevenson and Tarawa. However, cooking facilities are limited and visitors should take what they need with them. Prices for accommodation in rest houses vary considerably.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are few hotels in Kiribati, the major ones being on Tarawa, Christmas Island and Abemama. The small island of Kirimati also has a few hotels. <br />Accommodation is good although not luxurious, but there are plans to build a luxury 150-room hotel on Christmas Island. A 10% service charge is added to all hotel bills. Further information is available from south-pacific.travel (South Pacific Tourism Organisation) or the honorary consulate (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are few hotels in Kiribati, the major ones being on Tarawa, Christmas Island and Abemama. The small island of Kirimati also has a few hotels. <br />Accommodation is good although not luxurious, but there are plans to build a luxury 150-room hotel on Christmas Island. A 10% service charge is added to all hotel bills. Further information is available from south-pacific.travel (South Pacific Tourism Organisation) or the honorary consulate (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is strongly recommended. Tungaru Central Hospital on Tarawa provides medical service to all the islands. Government dispensaries on all islands are equipped to handle minor ailments and injuries. Visitors should bring their own supply of basic medicines with them.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B occurs. Diarrhoeal diseases are common. Dengue fever, including its haemorrhagic form, occurs in epidemics. Tuberculosis may occur.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Women's Day :
							05 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							29 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>National Health Day :
							19 April </p><p>Gospel Day :
							09 July </p><p>Senior Citizens' Day :
							10 July </p><p>Independence Day :
							12 July </p><p>Youth Day :
							05 August </p><p>National Education Day :
							08 October </p><p>Human Rights and Peace Day :
							09 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Kiribati without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 225g of tobacco or cigars.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits and 1L of wine (only if aged 21 years and older).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include counterfeit currency, indecent/obscene goods, matches containing white or yellow phosphorus, unauthorised goods bearing the national emblem of Kiribati, flick knives and imitation firearms.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include pure alcohol and soil.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Australian Dollar (AUD; symbol A$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of A$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of A$2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10 and 5 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency may be exchanged at the Bank of Kiribati Ltd or local hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard and Visa have very limited acceptance. There are ATMs at branches of the Bank of Kiribati/ANZ in Betio, Bairiki and Bikenibeu (all on Tarawa atoll).</p><p>There are ATMs at branches of the Bank of Kiribati/ANZ in Betio, Bairiki and Bikenibeu (all on Tarawa atoll).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted in hotels, some shops and at the Bank of Kiribati Ltd. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take travellers cheques in Australian Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1500. The Bikenibeu branch is open 0900-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visitors to Kiribati must possess a passport valid for the duration of their stay and an onward ticket, and must have proof of sufficient funds to support themselves while staying in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist<em> </em>and business visas: A$40 (single-entry); A$70 (multiple-entry).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visas are usually valid for up to three months and multiple-entry visas are valid for up to six months, depending on nationality; enquire at the nearest honorary consulate (or high commission in Fiji).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>High commission in Fiji or one of Kiribati's honorary consulates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three weeks for postal applications to the honorary consulate in the UK. The consul can sometimes meet applicants in London too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Extensions may be granted on application to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Immigration once in Kiribati. You can usually request one-month extensions up to a maximum of three additional months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-0.539024]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[174.227993]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>811 sq km (313 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>114,405 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>130.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tarawa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kiribati (pronounced 'Kiribass', formerly the Gilbert Islands) consists of three groups in the central Pacific: Kiribati (including Banaba, formerly Ocean Island), the Line Islands and the Phoenix Islands. The 33 islands, scattered across 5 million sq km (2 million sq miles) of the central Pacific, are low-lying coral atolls with coastal lagoons. The exception is Banaba, which is a coral formation rising to 80m (265ft). The soil is generally poor, apart from Banaba, and rainfall is variable. Coconut palms and pandanus trees comprise the main vegetation. There are no hills or streams throughout the group. Water is obtained from storage tanks or wells.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christianity (53% Roman Catholic and 39% Kiribati Protestant), the Bahai Faith and Islam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like the other Pacific islanders, the people are very friendly and hospitable and retain much of their traditional culture and lifestyle. In this casual atmosphere, European customs still prevail alongside local traditions. Although in official correspondence the Western convention of signing names with initials is adopted, it is more polite (and customary) to address people by their first name. Bikinis should not be worn except on the beach. Nudity and overly-scant swimming costumes are forbidden by local law.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. Australian-style plugs with three flat pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Taneti Mamau since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Taneti Mamau since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are indications of prehistoric migrations from South East Asia, but the present inhabitants of Kiribati descend mainly from a Samoan influx during the 13th to 15th centuries. Following European discovery, Kiribati came into contact with other Pacific islanders and the Chinese; traces of this intermixing remain in both the population and culture. Village government in Kiribati continues in the pre-colonial mode. In 1892, Kiribati became part of the British colony of the Gilbert and Ellice Islands, and was administered by the West Pacific High Commission in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/fiji">Fiji</a>. The islands were occupied by the Japanese during World War II, and were the site of some of the fiercest fighting between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a> and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>. <BR/><br /><BR/>The transition to independence began in 1963 with the formation of legislative and executive councils under the supervision of a British Governor General, who performed the functions previously exercised by the High Commissioner. The Legislative Council later evolved into the <I>Maneaba ni Maungatabu</I> (see <I>Government</I> section). In 1975, the Ellice Islands seceded from the main group to form the separate territory of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tuvalu">Tuvalu</a>. The remaining Gilbert Islands, along with a few smaller islands which the colonial authorities had tacked onto the group, became the independent republic of Kiribati in July 1979. Ieremia Tabai, a veteran of Kiribati politics, won the first three post-independence presidential elections, held in 1982, 1983 and 1987. <BR/><br /><BR/>Constitutional restraints prevented him from standing at the election held in late 1991, but he continued to exert considerable influence on the Government through his successor, former Vice President Teatao Teannaki, until the latter was turned out of office in September 1994. The victor, Teburoro Tito, was a member of the <I>Maneaba Te Mauri</I> (MTM), which had been in opposition to the dominant National Progressive Party (NPP), to which Tabai and Teannaki were both affiliated. Tito was re-elected at the election in November 1998. Simultaneous <I>Maneaba</I> elections returned the MTM as the largest bloc once again, although independents continued to hold the balance of power. <BR/><br /><BR/>The policy issues preoccupying Kiribati at present are economic and environmental. The weakness of the economy has led to what is widely seen as an over-dependence on foreign aid (see <I>Business Profile</I> section). The Government is also deeply concerned by the prospect of global warming as none of Kiribati's land lies more than 2m above sea level. A further issue, that of overpopulation, has been tackled by resettling several thousand people  along with several hundred asylum seekers rejected by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>  on the relatively remote Line Islands and Phoenix Islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Honorary Consulate of Kiribati in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(01873) 840 375.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(01873) 840 375.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Visas issued by appointment only.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Llanddewi Rhydderch<br/>The Great House<br/>Monmouthshire<br/>NP7 9UY<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>White sandy beaches and crystal-clear lagoon waters characterise the Republic of Kiribati, which is made up of over 30 coral islands scattered across the Pacific. Kiribati is remote, and the tourism industry remains very much in its infancy – all the more reason to visit sooner rather than later.</p><p>They may be relatively unknown, but the isles are peppered with swaying coconut palms, swathed in balmy breezes, and waters glistening in every direction. And so it's hard to feel anything other than intense holiday escapism. While lazing on desolate beaches is a huge draw, Kiribati does have an interesting population of both human and wildlife.</p><p>Capital Tarawa is fast becoming one of the most densely populated areas in the Pacific, while Christmas Island, stretching for almost half the land mass of Kiribati, is carpeted with lakes and ponds great for game fishing, and boasts some of the largest colonies of birds.</p><p>Other islands include Phoenix, Line and Gilbert – during British rule in the 19th and 20th centuries, Kiribati was known as the Gilbert Islands. In World War II, the islands were occupied by Japan, while in the post-war era the US and UK used Christmas island for nuclear weapons tests. The islands finally became independent in 1979.</p><p>Despite Kiribati's colonial history, many of its islands have remained much the same as they've ever been. Locals live off breadfruit, fish and coconuts to this day. The inhabitants of the main island Tarawa also continue to live in raised thatched huts like their ancestors.</p><p>You needn't fear a total separation from civilisation, however, as bars, cinemas, cars and the internet are increasingly a part of life in Kiribati. The people aren't unwelcoming, but you're more likely to be greeted by the children than adults, who tend to eye visitors cautiously. Once you break the ice, you'll find a fascinating culture, and plenty of glorious nature to explore.</p><p>The tiny nation is only 800 km sq, but if you include the many atolls, this rises to a 3.5 million km square-swathe of the Pacific. Better get the swimming costume on.</p>White sandy beaches and crystal-clear lagoon waters characterise the Republic of Kiribati: 33 coral islands scattered across the Pacific.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
