<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Kosovo" ColCode="kos" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Kosovo]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kosovo has a mild continental climate with cold, snowy winters and warm summers. May and September are the best months to visit.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In winter, mediumweight clothing and heavy overcoat; in summer, lightweight clothing and raincoat required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Trainkos (tel: +381 38 534 821; <a href="http://www.trainkos.com" target="_blank">www.trainkos.com</a>) runs Kosovo's limited rail network. There's a service between Pristina and Peja, as well as an international connection to Skopje, Macedonia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Road quality is poor, especially in rural areas and during bad weather.&nbsp;For this reason, driving at night is not advisable on minor roads in the countryside.</p>
<p>There are tollbooths along the motorways.&nbsp;Foreign-registered vehicles are charged at a higher toll than local vehicles.</p><p>Buses connect Kosovo's towns and cities and are reasonably frequent, if slow.</p><p>Main cities have metered taxis. It is possible to negotiate a fare when the meters are not in use. In this case, agree a fare before setting off. Only use officially marked taxis.</p><p>A valid national driving licence is required. The Green Card is not valid in Kosovo and vehicle registration/ownership documents and locally valid insurance policy are necessary. You can buy third-party insurance at the border.</p><p>Speed limits are 110-130kpm (68-81mph) on motorways, 80-100kph (50-62mph) on other roads and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas. Road signs may be poorly marked and new signs are likely to be in Cyrillic script in some areas of the country. Seatbelts must be worn at all times. Children under 12 are not allowed to sit in the front passenger seat.</p><p>Dial 112 to reach the emergency services.</p><p>Both major international and local firms offer car hire at airports and larger towns. Note that many Serbian car hire firms do not allow their vehicles to be driven in Kosovo.</p><p>Speed limits are 110-130kpm (68-81mph) on motorways, 80-100kph (50-62mph) on other roads and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas. Road signs may be poorly marked and new signs are likely to be in Cyrillic script in some areas of the country. Seatbelts must be worn at all times. Children under 12 are not allowed to sit in the front passenger seat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kosova Airlines&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.kosovaairlines.com/" target="_blank">www.kosovaairlines.com</a>) is the national airline. Air Prishtina (<a href="http://www.airprishtina.com" target="_blank">www.airprishtina.com</a>) and Germania (<a href="http://www.flygermania.com" target="_blank">www.flygermania.com</a>) operate direct flights to Kosovo from the UK.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 3 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 12 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Prishtina International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airportpristina.com/<p>Pristina International Airport is located 18km (11 miles) southwest of the city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(038) 595 8123</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only international service is the daily train from Skopje, Macedonia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Be prepared for delays at border crossings. Buses connect Kosovo with Albania, Macedonia. Montenegro.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong>&nbsp;Leaving Kosovo, you can only enter Serbia if you came from there, since the Serbian authorities don't recognise Kosovar border stamps.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage is patchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet use is limited, but cafes can be found in the main urban centres.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Kosovan media is split along ethnic lines, with most publications and broadcasts in Albanian. The UN established a journalistic code of conduct in Kosovo to help prevent incitement to hatred in the media.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Postal services are reasonably good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Discover Peja’s (Peć) historic charm</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This historical town is nestled close to imposing mountains, a picturesque gorge and straddling the Bistrica River. Ancestral home of the Mediaeval Serbian Orthodox Church, it was heavily damaged by recent conflicts. A bustling central bazaar and lively market still beat resolutely and retain their Old World charms.</p>]]><p><b>Eat meat on a (very) empty stomach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Kosovo, especially Serbian enclaves, is a paradise for carnivores. There is a cult of grilled meat, which is always fresh, competently cooked and served in huge portions. Ottoman heritage is evident with the likes of Tavë prizreni, a bake of lamb and aubergine, and the local markets should not be missed for those wishing to try Kosovo's traditional cheeses.</p>]]><p><b>Feel cultured in cosmopolitan Pristina</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Kosovo's capital holds the usual delights: the national museum, theatre and art gallery. There are also several historical mosques, such as Mbretit and Pirinaz, and the Serbian Church of St Nicholas with its rich iconostasis. The boldest statement though, is the modern architecture of Kosovo National Library; discuss its merits in one of the centre's many stylish cafes.</p>]]><p><b>Find a cafe near the frontline crossing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The bridge across the Vardar River in the ethnically divided town of Mitrovica is possibly the most well known symbol of the conflict. Drop in the Dolce Vita café on the Serbian side, where peacekeepers and journalists mingle with local politicians and ex-paramilitaries, but avoid the area during periods of unrest.</p>]]><p><b>Find the frescoes of Gračanica</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Serbian enclave close to Pristina is famous for its Orthodox monastery, founded in 1321. Visit the UNESCO-listed building and be sure to see its finest features – the vibrant coloured frescoes. Nearby are the ruins of the ancient Illyrian city of Ulpiana, one of the country's most fascinating archaeological sites.</p>]]><p><b>Hike to the heart of the mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At 2,656m (8,714ft), Kosovo's highest mountain Gjeravica (Äeravica) is a fairly easy climb. It is located in southwest Kosovo, alongside Montenegro and Albania, and offers jaw-dropping panoramas over the Albanian Alps. As you're near the Albanian border, look for the heart-shaped Zemra Lake.</p>]]><p><b>Make for the pink marbled monastery of Dečani</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Another Medieval monument that has helped Kosovo on to the UNESCO World Heritage Site list is the perfectly preserved Orthodox monastery, Visoki Dečani. Built in 1335, the pink and white marble church is located in a small town in the west of the country and features a three-wall iconostasis.</p>]]><p><b>Peer out of Prizren from the Kalaja Fortress</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This Ottoman city, at the foot of the Sharr Mountains, sports several beautiful mosques and 16th-century Turkish baths. The Kalaja Fortress, whose cannons face out over Prizren, sits above the city and offers superb morning views. Nearby, the Church of Our Lady of Ljeviš is on UNESCO's list of World Heritage Sites.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out the statue on Mother Teresa Boulevard</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The main pedestrian drag in Pristina is lined with cafés and restaurants, frequented by Kosovar politicians, foreign officials and peacekeepers. Walk along the tree-lined street to find the statue erected to celebrate the famous missionary, who despite being born in Macedonia, was of Kosovar Albanian ancestry.</p>]]><p><b>Strap on the skis for Brezovica</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Serb-run resort of Brezovica in Sharr (Šar) Mountains, on the border with Macedonia, attracts mostly Albanian clientele, serving as a rare example of peaceful co-existence between two communities. History aside, the resort offers exceptional skiing and is the training base for a number of the national winter sports teams.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2 billion (2007).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Energy, metals, machine parts and electric equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transport equipment, raw materials and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Balkan countries, EU, Turkey and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kosovo's economy is one of Europe's least developed. About 40% of the country's workforce is unemployed, with youth unemployment even higher. The new state is dependent on subsidies, grants and investment from the EU and USA. These countries have supported Kosovo's independence bid on the understanding that the government agree to an EU blueprint for economic reform.<br /><br />In June 2009, Kosovo became a member of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Things can go slowly on account of cumbersome bureaucracy, but most of Kosovo's entrepreneurs are very keen to forge business links with Western Europe. <br /><br />
Greetings in Kosovo society are warm and heartfelt. Meetings are always commenced and finalised with a handshake. Take the trouble to ask after your host and their family's health and be aware of their ethnicity as an appropriate greeting in either Albanian (<em>shqip </em>) or Serbian will be appreciated. Some meetings are held in offices, others in cafés or restaurants and frequently involve plenty of coffee. Typical office and business hours are Monday to Friday 0800-1700. Some organisations also open on Saturday.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0700/0800-1600/1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Kosovo Chamber of Commerce (OEK)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (38) 224 741
					Website:http://www.kosovo-eicc.org/
					Address: ,Mother Teresa 20,Pristina 10000,]]><b>Economic Initiative for Kosova (ECIKS)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01) 890 5026
					Website:http://www.eciks.org/english
					Address: A-1090 Vienna,Nussdorfer Strasse 20 / 23,Austria,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Kosovar food is hearty and home-style, borrowing elements from Serbia, Albania, Turkey and Greece among other neighbouring nations. Simple grilled meats, usually beef, chicken or lamb, are commonly served with potatoes or rice, as are freshwater fish such as carp. Pies and other pastry-based dishes are also a staple, and yogurts and cheeses are plentiful.</p>
<p>Vegetables, such as cucumbers, green tomatoes and peppers are abundant during the summer and make for delicious, fresh salads. During winter, they arrive on the plate pickled and preserved.</p>
<p>Accompanying most meals are wine; Kosovo has an excellent wine-growing tradition, though the native pours have yet to catch the attention of the wider world.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Flija:</strong> A pie made of thin pancake-like layers with a yogurt filling.<br />
<strong>Raznjici:</strong> Grilled meat cooked on a skewer.<br />
<strong>Hajvar:</strong> A red pepper relish, served mild or spicy.<br />
<strong>Burek:</strong> Fine pastry layers stuffed with meat, vegetables and rice.<br />
<strong>Cevapcici:</strong> A charcoal-grilled skinless sausage made from minced meat, garlic and spices.<br />
<strong>Sarma or japrak:</strong> Meat and rice wrapped in vine or cabbage leaves.<br />
<strong>Pljeskavica:</strong> A flavoursome, fast-food style meat patty encased in a bun.<br />
<strong>Vranac wine:</strong> Grown mainly in the Rahovec region southwest of Pristina, this indigenous Balkan grape is among the oldest grape varieties in the world.<br />
<strong>Turska kafa:</strong> Turkish coffee &ndash; thick, strong and sweet.<br />
<strong>Rakija:</strong> A strong spirit usually made from grapes.<br />
<strong>Slivovica:</strong> A potent plum brandy.<br />
<strong>Boza:</strong> A thick, sweet drink made from malted corn and flour.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pristina has the best nightlife scene with a range of lively bars, clubs and late-night cafes in the city centre around Rruga Fehmi Agani and Rruga Garibaldi, and also in the Santea neighbourhood.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prizren, Peja and Gjakova are some of the best places to find handicrafts. Metalwork includes filigree, silver, copper and brass crafts. Kosovar wood engravings and musical instruments are also popular souvenirs. Other purchases include embroidery, lace, leatherwork, knitwear and Turkish coffee sets.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1500-2000, Sat 0800-1500 (many shops are open all day Sat). Supermarkets and grocery stores keep longer hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kosovo does not have any international-standard 4- or 5-star accommodation (despite some claims to the contrary). Pristina offers a reasonable selection of hotels, but there may be little choice beyond mid-price and budget in smaller towns.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Classification is from <strong>1</strong> to <strong>5 stars</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Motels are found on most main roads, usually near the outskirts of towns. Prices are set independently according to region, tourist season and the quality of service.<br />In villages without hotels, some residents offer visitors rooms, often with meals. Discounts are available off-season. Contact tourist offices or travel agencies for details.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kosovo does not have any international-standard 4- or 5-star accommodation (despite some claims to the contrary). Pristina offers a reasonable selection of hotels, but there may be little choice beyond mid-price and budget in smaller towns.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Classification is from <strong>1</strong> to <strong>5 stars</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kosovo does not have any international-standard 4- or 5-star accommodation (despite some claims to the contrary). Pristina offers a reasonable selection of hotels, but there may be little choice beyond mid-price and budget in smaller towns.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Classification is from <strong>1</strong> to <strong>5 stars</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Doctors are well trained but medical facilities are limited. Some medicines may not be as freely available as at home. Medical treatment is free to UK residents but prescribed medicines must be paid for. Health insurance with emergency repatriation is recommended. Pharmacies are open Mon-Fri 0800-2000 and Sat 0800-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tick-borne encephalitis is present in some rural areas. Precautions such as using repellent and wearing long trousers should be taken. Pre-exposure vaccination is not always available. Any ticks found should be carefully removed and medical attention sought. Hepatitis B vaccinations are recommended for trips longer than one month.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday.  Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>Independence Day :
							17 February </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Constitution Day :
							09 April </p><p>Orthodox Easter Monday :
							09 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May <b>Date to be confirmed </b>yes
							</p><p>Europe Day :
							09 May </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following list of items may be imported into Kosovo by travellers aged 17 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of liqueurs, fortified or sparkling wine under 22% volume.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 50ml of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of &euro;175.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (€) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of €500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of €2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents. <br /><br />In Serbian enclaves, particularly in the north, the predominant currency is Serbian Dinar (RSD) = 100 paras. Notes are in denominations of RSD5,000, 1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of RSD20, 10, 5, 2 and 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As elsewhere in the ex-Yugoslav republics, the most frequently exchanged currencies are the Euro and US Dollar (Pound Sterling is rarely used). Money should be changed through official exchange offices only. ATMs are not hard to find in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pristina">Pristina</a>, but more difficult (or impossible) in smaller towns and villages.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International credit cards such as Visa and MasterCard are sometimes accepted, but this cannot be relied upon even in cities. Diners Club and American Express are not generally accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a valid national ID card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit, single-, double- or multiple-entry visa: &euro;40.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate. You should apply no more than three months before your planned visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals requiring a visa must be able to prove they have sufficient funds to support their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign nationals granted entry may extend their stay by applying to the Directorate for Foreigners at the Kosovo Police in&nbsp;Pristina.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[42.602636]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[20.902977]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>10,887 sq km (4,203 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,883,018 (CIA estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>171.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pristina.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Landlocked Kosovo shares borders with Serbia, Macedonia, Montenegro and Albania. It is ringed by mountains: the Sharr (<em>&Aring;&nbsp;ar</em> in Serbian) Mountains are located in the south and southeast, bordering Macedonia. The Kopaonik Mountains rise in the north. The southwest borders with Montenegro and Albania are also mountainous, and are home to the nation's highest mountain, Gjeravica (<em>&Auml;eravica</em> in Serbian), 2,656m (8,714ft) high. The central region is mainly hilly, but two large plains spread over Kosovo's west and east.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sunni Islamic majority, Orthodox Christian and Roman Catholic minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Avoid taking pictures of military installations and looted houses of Serbs in the Albanian-populated parts, and of Albanians in the Serbian-populated parts; it may cause bad feeling. <br /><br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Ramush Haradinaj since September 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Hashim Tha&ccedil;i since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>During medieval times, Kosovo was the centre of the Serbian Empire. That is, until the 14th-century Battle of Kosovo, when the Ottomans defeated the Serbs and their allies, paving the path for the Turks to establish a rule over the region, which would last from the mid-15th century to the early 20th century.</p>
<p>Prior to Turkish rule, the Kosovo population was predominantly Serb, but with the arrival of the Ottomans, Islam became more widespread and the number of Muslim ethnic Albanians rose.</p>
<p>In 1912, Serbia regained control over Kosovo during the First Balkan War only to lose it again during WWI, when Kosovo became part of the Kingdom of Serbs, Croats and Slovenes (later renamed Yugoslavia). During WWII, Kosovo was united with Albania under Italian control and was later liberated and granted the status of an autonomous region within Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>In 1989, Slobodan Milosevic set out his ultranationalist agenda in a speech at the rally on the Battle of Kosovo field, promising to restrict Kosovo autonomy. His policies led to three major wars and the eventual disintegration of Yugoslavia; the Kosovo conflict became the last act in the Balkan drama.</p>
<p>Brutal actions of the Serbian army and paramilitaries led to the exodus of almost the entire Albanian population and prompted NATO bombardment of Serbian cities in 1999. When the Albanians returned, it was the time for Serbian civilians to flee persecution by the Kosovo Liberation Army fighters.</p>
<p>Following years of unsuccessful talks in which neither party wanted to yield ground, Kosovo unilaterally proclaimed independence in February 2008, supported by major Western powers. It adopted a constitution, which gives broad autonomy to Serbian enclaves. However, Kosovo Serbs rejected this change and continue to see themselves as residents of the Serbian Autonomous Region of Kosovo and Metohija.</p>
<p>In 2009, Kosovo held its first democratic elections since declaring independence from Serbia. Despite periods of unrest, high unemployment and problems with corruption, Kosovo has continued to make significant progress towards stability. In 2013 and 2015, Kosovo and Serbia signed landmark agreements in an effort to normalise relations between the two countries &ndash; a process both countries hope will advance their European Union accession agenda.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Kosovo has the youngest population in Europe, with an estimated 70% of its citizens under 35.<br />
&bull; Not only is Pristina&rsquo;s main boulevard named after Bill Clinton, but the former American president is also honoured with a 3m-high (10ft) golden statue in the Kosovar capital.<br />
&bull; Kosovo is rich in lignite coal and remains one of the most polluted regions in Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Kosovo in London]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>020 7659 6140</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.kosovoembassy.org.uk/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>020 7659 6140</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>100 Pall Mall<br/>London<br/>SW1Y 5NQ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Kosovo in the United States]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b> (202) 380 3581.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ambasada-ks.net/us/</p><p><b>Tel:</b> (202) 380 3581.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>1101 30th Street, NW<br/>Presidential Plaza<br/>Washington<br/>20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Depending on your global perspective, Kosovo is either Europe&rsquo;s youngest nation or not a nation at all. Since declaring independence from Serbia in 2008 it has received only partial recognition as a sovereign state by members of the United Nations. Its fragile footing and wretched modern history might make Kosovo an unlikely travel destination, but the country can be extremely rewarding for those keen to find out what lies beyond the headlines.</p>
<p>Cultures and religions have been clashing in modern day Kosovo for centuries, but between the periods of unrest, this small, landlocked country has pioneered peaceful coexistence and mutual enrichment of cultures. While Muslim Albanians dominate the population today, followed by Orthodox Christian Serbs, there are many other groups with their own unique cultures and ways of life.</p>
<p>Granted, roadside memorials and the occasional khaki-clad NATO soldier can make its cruel past somewhat hard to forget, but historic spots such as Janjevo and the UNESCO-listed Dečani Monastery showcase a distinguished Kosovan history that has been overshadowed by the recent catalogue of horrors.</p>
<p>Europe&rsquo;s youngest capital, Pristina, is an increasingly eclectic city with a vibrant caf&eacute; culture, but pretty Prizren is the city that has most visitors smitten. Cobbled streets, ancient walls, Ottoman mosques and Orthodox churches lend a romantic air to this riverside town, while the popular Dokufest Film Festival and Hasi Jehon folklore festival give credence to its status as a cultural capital.</p>
<p>Much of the Kosovan countryside is uncharted territory for tourists, but dramatic mountain peaks, cascading waterfalls and limpid lakes are tailor made for adventure travellers. Combine all this with decidedly un-European prices and it&rsquo;s not hard to see why visitor numbers are rising.</p>
<p>Whether you&rsquo;re sipping coffee in cosmopolitan caf&eacute;s, hiking through the hinterland or visiting crumbling historic sites, in Kosovo, when you look beyond yesterday&rsquo;s headlines, you&rsquo;ll find an affable land of surprising beauty.</p><p>Depending on your global perspective, Kosovo is either Europe&rsquo;s youngest nation or not a nation at all. Since declaring independence from Serbia in 2008 it has received only partial recognition as a sovereign state by members of the United Nations. Its fragile footing and wretched modern history might make Kosovo an unlikely travel destination, but the country can be extremely rewarding for those keen to find out what lies beyond the headlines. Cultures and religions have been clashing in modern day Kosovo for centuries, but between the periods of unrest, this small, landlocked country has pioneered peaceful coexistence and mutual enrichment of cultures.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
