<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Kuwait" ColCode="kwt" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="kw" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Kuwait]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kuwait shares European weather patterns but is hotter and drier. Summers (April to October) are hot and humid with very little rain. Winters (November to March) are cool with limited rain. Springs are cool and pleasant.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can charter dhows and other small craft for trips to the offshore islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A new light rail system, using driverless trains, is expected to come into operation in 2020.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Kuwait has a good road network, but driving standards are poor and constant vigilance is essential.</p><p>Kuwait Public Transport Company (tel: +965 2232 8501; <a href="http://www.kptc.com.kw" target="_blank">www.kptc.com.kw</a>) operates long-distance buses between Kuwait City and other destinations within Kuwait and the Gulf region.</p><p>These are recognisable by red licence plates and may be hired by the day, in which case you should agree fares beforehand. Share-taxis are also available. Hailing taxis from the road is not advisable, particularly for females. It is recommended that you book taxis in advance by phone from a reputable taxi company. A standard rate is applicable in most taxis, but those at hotel ranks are more expensive. Tipping is not expected.</p><p>International Driving Permit required. You have to arrange insurance with the Gulf Insurance Company or the Kuwait Insurance Company.</p><p>Speed limits are 45kph (28mph) in residential areas, 60kph (37mph) on main roads in urban areas, 80-100kph (50-62mph) on ring roads, and 120kph (75mph) on expressways and outer roads. The minimum driving age is 18.</p><p>Road traffic police (tel: 101).</p><p>Self-drive is available. An International Driving Permit, or licence and resident permit from another Gulf country, is required.</p><p>Speed limits are 45kph (28mph) in residential areas, 60kph (37mph) on main roads in urban areas, 80-100kph (50-62mph) on ring roads, and 120kph (75mph) on expressways and outer roads. The minimum driving age is 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Kuwait Airways (<a href="http://www.kuwaitairways.com" target="_blank">www.kuwaitairways.com</a>), which offers direct flights from the UK and the USA, among other destinations. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) also flies direct to Kuwait from the UK.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kuwait/kuwait-international-airport">Kuwait International AIrport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 6 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 12 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Kuwait International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.dgca.gov.kw<p>Kuwait International Airport is located 16km (10 miles) south of Kuwait City.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+965 2431 9829</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:&nbsp;</strong>Kuwait City. Multiple shipping lines call regularly at Kuwait City. Most traffic is commercial.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers are advised against using all road links with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iraq">Iraq</a>&nbsp;due to political instability within Iraq. The border into Saudi Arabia is not open to tourists. If you have a visa for Saudi Arabia, you can use the Al-Nuwaisib crossing (for Damman) or the Al-Salmy crossing (for Riyadh).</p>
<p>There are bus services between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kuwait-city">Kuwait City</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cairo">Cairo</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/egypt">Egypt</a>), via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/aqaba">Aqaba</a> in Jordan and Nuweiba in Egypt. Buses also operate to Damman in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/saudi-arabia">Saudi Arabia</a>.&nbsp;Kuwait Public Transport Company (tel: +965 2232 8501; <a href="http://www.kptc.com.kw" target="_blank">www.kptc.com.kw</a>) is the main operator.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes throughout Kuwait provide public access to e-mail and Internet services. Many hotels have business centres with Internet access.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although remaining loyal to the ruling family, the press enjoys a fair degree of freedom.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes about five days.</p><p>Sat-Wed 0700-1400, Thurs 0700-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Failakai Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A port with many old <em>dhows</em>, Failakai Island can be reached by regular ferry services. There are also some Bronze Age and Greek archaeological sites well worth viewing, including the island's Greek temple. Traditional-style <em>boums</em> and <em>sambuks</em> (boats) are still built in Al Jahrah, although, nowadays, vessels are destined to work as pleasure boats rather than pearl fishing or trading vessels. Mina Al Ahmadi, lying 19km (12 miles) south of Kuwait City, is an oil port with immense jetties for supertanker traffic. The Oil Display Centre pays homage to the work of the Kuwait Oil Company.</p>]]><p><b>Kuwait City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Kuwait City is a bustling metropolis of high-rise office buildings, luxury hotels, wide boulevards and well-tended parks and gardens. Its most dominant landmark is Kuwait Towers, and its oldest is Seif Palace, built in 1896, the interior of which features original Islamic mosaic tilework, though these suffered badly during the Iraqi occupation. The Kuwait National Museum was also stripped of many artefacts - part of it has been renovated and is now open to the public. The Sadu House, near the museum, is made of coral and gypsum and is used as a cultural museum to protect the arts and crafts of Bedouin society. The huge Grand Mosque in the centre is also worth visiting. Liberation Tower, the symbol of Kuwaiti liberation, is one of the tallest telecommunications towers in the world. Visitors can travel 150m (492ft) up to the revolving obervation tower and restaurant.</p>]]><p><b>Sailing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sailing and scuba-diving are available. Powerboating is a Kuwaiti passion. Horse riding clubs flourish in the winter.</p>]]><p><b>Sea clubs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many of Kuwait's sea clubs ofer a wide variety of facilities and activities such as indoor and outdoor swimming pools, beaches, tennis courts, gyms, bowling and even karate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$68.4 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil and refined products and fertiliser.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, construction materials, vehicles and parts and clothing.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK, Japan, USA and Germany.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kuwait's considerable wealth is the result of the country's vast oil deposits, estimated at 100 billion barrels (9% of the world's total known reserves). With production of over 2 million barrels daily, oil now accounts for about half of total output, 90% of export income and three-quarters of government revenue.<br /><br />The economy has long since recovered from the extensive and systematic looting conducted by Iraqi troops during the occupation of 1990-1. This was estimated to have cost Kuwait US$170 billion, and the extent of the reconstruction was reflected in the fact that Kuwait was obliged to liquidate a large proportion of its overseas investment portfolio.<br /><br />These holdings, which are administered by the Kuwait Investment Office, are used partly to meet the country's running costs (free education and social services) and partly lodged in the Fund for Future Generations. During the 1990s, Kuwait, not surprisingly, invested large sums in building up a military apparatus.<br /><br />There has been some diversification of the economy, promoted and funded by the government. Heavy industrial projects have been eschewed in favour of light manufacturing industries such as paper and cement production. There is a small fishing industry and some agriculture. The government has tabled a privatisation programme both as a means to raise revenue and as an instrument of economic policy. A free-trade zone has also been established.<br /><br />Kuwait is a member of OPEC and of the Gulf Co-operation Council. The re-emergence of OPEC as a major influence appears to have triggered some disputes inside the Kuwaiti government over oil production and pricing policy. Japan, The Netherlands and Italy are the main markets for Kuwaiti oil. The principal exporters to Kuwait are Japan, the USA, Germany and the UK. <br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Smart conservative clothing is essential. This should cover the upper arm and lower leg. English is widely spoken in business circles, although a few words or phrases of Arabic are always well received. Business cards are widely used. Some of the bigger hotels have translation and bilingual secretarial services. <br /><br />
Meetings often start late; as this is an accepted part of local custom, this should not be commented on. Shaking hands is the normal greeting but visitors should note that when meeting Arab women they should not offer their hand unless the woman extends hers first. <br /><br />It is very important for visitors never to sit in such a way that their feet are pointing directly at someone else. Causing someone else to lose face, whether a client or colleague, is considered extremely offensive, and any criticism or corrections should be kept for private discussions afterwards.<br /><br />Meetings tend to start with plenty of preliminary chatting before moving onto the serious work and it is considered ill-mannered to 'get straight down to business'. <br /><br />Friday is considered a day of prayer and rest, so meetings should not be scheduled for this day. Calls to Arab people should also be avoided on this day. Similarly, local people will not answer the telephone during siestas, which are usually taken between 1400 and 1700. <br /><br />Business hours are Sunday to Thursday (or Saturday to Wednesday) 0800-1300, reopening 1700-2000. <br /><br />Visitors are strongly advised not to initiate discussions on politics, sex or religion. If drawn into any of these topics of conversation, try to avoid personalising your comments.<br /><br />Be aware that Kuwait is a dry state and the consumption of alcohol is strictly forbidden.</p><p>Sun-Thurs or Sat-Wed 0800-1300 and 1700-2000.<br /><br /><strong>Government office hours:</strong> Sat-Wed 0700-1430 (winter); 0700-1400 (summer).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Kuwait Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 805 580
					Website:http://www.kcci.org.kw
					Address: Safat 13008,PO Box 775,Kuwait City,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>There is a good choice of restaurants serving a wide choice of international and Arab cuisine. Prices are reasonable.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Hummus.<br />
&bull; Falafel.<br />
&bull; Fowl. <br />
&bull; Meat or fish <em>marag</em> (meat is first fried or boiled and then combined with other ingredients such as spices where they are steamed together in a large pot). <br />
&bull; <em>Aish</em> (Arabic flat bread).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol is totally prohibited in Kuwait.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A service charge of 15% is usually added to bills in hotels, restaurants and clubs. Otherwise 10% is acceptable.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Several cinemas in Kuwait City show recent films. There are several theatres which often put on excellent productions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Numerous large shopping complexes have recently been built. The <em>Souk Sharp Complex</em> is an extensive centre near the waterfront in Kuwait City, and contains Western chain stores as well as Kuwaiti shops. Other centres include the Al-Fanar Shopping Centre and the Leila Gallery. Boutiques and small general stores in Kuwait City sell all the basic and most luxury goods.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0900-1300 and 1630-2100, Fri 1530-2030.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels range from deluxe to first and second class. Many top hotels in Kuwait City feature sport complexes, restaurants and shopping malls. Serviced apartments, some with hotel-style room service, are also available. Prices are generally high. All rates are subject to a 15% service charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels range from deluxe to first and second class. Many top hotels in Kuwait City feature sport complexes, restaurants and shopping malls. Serviced apartments, some with hotel-style room service, are also available. Prices are generally high. All rates are subject to a 15% service charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels range from deluxe to first and second class. Many top hotels in Kuwait City feature sport complexes, restaurants and shopping malls. Serviced apartments, some with hotel-style room service, are also available. Prices are generally high. All rates are subject to a 15% service charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical insurance is essential. Both private and government health services are available.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available and is advised for the first few weeks of the stay. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Diarrhoeal diseases are common. Hepatitis B is endemic in the region.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed during the preceding or following week.  Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>National Day :
							25 February </p><p>Liberation Day :
							26 February </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kuwait/kuwait-international-airport">Kuwait</a> without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 500 cigarettes or 900g of tobacco.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol, drugs, unsealed milk products, unsealed salty fish, unsealed olives and pickles, food prepared abroad, fresh vegetables, shellfish and its products, fresh figs and mineral water.</p>
<p>Penalties for attempting to smuggle restricted items are severe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kuwait Dinar (KWD) = 1,000 fils. Notes are in denominations of KWD20, 10, 5 and 1, and 500 and 250 fils. Coins are in denominations of 100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 fils.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sun-Thurs 0800-1200/1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Kuwait, a passport valid for at least six months is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival; single- and multiple-entry visas: costs for all visas depend on the applicant's nationality.</p>
<p>30-day visas on arrival are free to British nationals. British passport holders can also obtain a 90-day visa on arrival for a fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: one month. Check with the embassy for the validity of other visas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you apply for a visa in advance, allow five working days for processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You cannot usually extend the one-month visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet to Kuwait, your animal must have a certificate of good health issued by a licensed vet and must have been vaccinated against rabies at least 30 days and not more than 12 months before travelling. You also need to obtain an import permit from the Animal Health department.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[29.427039]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[47.451994]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>17,818 sq km (6,880 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,007,146 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>156.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kuwait City.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional emirate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kuwait shares borders with Iraq and Saudi Arabia. To the southeast lies the Persian Gulf, where Kuwait has sovereignty over nine small islands (the largest is Bubiyan and the most populous is Failaka). The landscape is predominantly desert plateau with a lower, more fertile coastal belt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>95% Muslim (mostly of the Sunni sect), with Christian and Hindu minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the customary form of greeting. It is quite likely that a visitor will be invited to a Kuwaiti's home, but entertaining is also conducted in hotels and restaurants. A small gift promoting the company, or representing your own country, is always welcome. The visitor will notice that most Kuwaitis wear the national dress of long white <em>dishdashes </em>and white headcloths, and that many women wear <em>yashmaks</em>. It is important for women to dress modestly according to Islamic law. Men do not usually wear shorts in public and should not go shirtless.<br />
<br />
All other Islamic rules and customs must be respected. Convicted users of narcotics can expect to receive a sentence of up to five years' imprisonment, plus a heavy fine. Kuwait outlawed smoking indoors in public in 2012, but there is often little enforcement of this law.&nbsp;It is greatly appreciated if visitors learn at least a few words of Arabic. Homosexuality is illegal, as is any public affection between men and women. Cohabitation is also illegal. The import and use of drugs, alcohol, pork products and obscene material are forbidden and can lead to imprisonment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins and British-style plugs with three square pins are both used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Jaber al-Mubarak al-Hamad al-Sabah since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Emir Sheikh Sabah al-Ahmed al-Jaber al-Sabah since 2006.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although Mesolithic tools suggest the region of Kuwait has been inhabited since around 8000BC, its modern history dates from the founding of a town in 1613 on the site of the present Kuwait City.</p><p>For a century it was controlled by the Bani Khalid tribal confederation, but after various marital alliances and political manoeuvring by members of the rival Bani Utub clan from Basra, by the mid 18th century they had been ousted. When the Utub further splintered in 1766 only one family – the Al Sabah – remained to rule, as it does to this day.</p><p>By that time Kuwait was established as a major centre for the transport of goods from India, Arabia, Muscat and Baghdad and during the Persian siege of Basra from 1775 to 1779 Iraqi traders took refuge in Kuwait, playing a key role in the burgeoning boat building industry.</p><p>Its wealth and reputation continued to rise and by the dawn of the 20th century Kuwait was effectively a British colony whose multiculturalism and commercial pragmatism had earned it the soubriquet 'the Marseilles of the Persian Gulf'. However, the first half of the new century was not kind to Kuwait and its economy was seriously damaged by a series of trade blockades and the collapse of its pearl industry.</p><p>Its revival was entirely due to the West's thirst for oil, which had been discovered in 1937 by the Anglo-American Kuwait Oil Company. Delayed by World War 2, exportation began in 1951 and within a year Kuwait was the Gulf's largest exporter, fuelling what has become known as the Golden Era.</p><p>That ended in 1982 with the Iran-Iraq War and Kuwait suffered a series of terror attacks as well as a major economic crisis precipitated by falling oil prices. In August 1990 Iraqi forces annexed Kuwait leading to the First Gulf War when a US-led UN coalition was deployed in February 1991 to liberate Kuwait, which then became the springboard for the invasion of Iraq in 1993.</p><p>Following the death of the Emir Jabir in 2006, Sheikh Sa'ad al-Sabah ruled for just nine days before Parliament voted him out of office due to ill health. Sheikh Sabah al-Sabah succeeded him and remains on the throne to this day. Kuwait was the first Arab country in the Gulf to have an elected parliament and in 2005 granted full political rights to women.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• Kuwaiti soap operas are the most watched in the Gulf region and are shown as far away as Tunisia.</p><p>• Kuwait has a highly developed tradition of theatre-going that dates back to the 1920s.</p><p>• The name Kuwait is a contraction of an Arab word meaning 'fortress built near water'.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the State of Kuwait in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 966 0702.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.kuwaitembassy.us/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 966 0702.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2940 Tilden Street<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the State of Kuwait in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7590 3400 or 3415 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.kuwaitinfo.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7590 3400 or 3415 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Opening hours: Mon-Fri 0900-1230 and 1400-1600 (visa collection only). Open 1000-1400 during Ramadan.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2 Albert Gate<br/>London<br/>SW1X 7JU<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Kuwait you'll find an intriguing mix of Western liberalism and traditional Islamic culture. The capital, Kuwait City, is a bustling metropolis of high-rise buildings and luxury hotels, while the Gulf country is also home to spectacular mosques and palaces. Religion is an integral part of daily life here.</p><p>This juxtaposition perhaps stems from Kuwait's marrying of Islamism with oil wealth, which for decades has earned it the attention of Western powers. Upon independence from Britain in 1961, Sheikh Abdullah assumed head of state, adopting the title of emir. The large revenues from oil production allowed independent Kuwait to build up its economic infrastructure and institute educational and social welfare programmes.</p><p>In the early 1990s, the emir established a National Assembly (<em>Majlis</em>), which placed limits on the power of the ruling family. Since then, the national assembly has clashed several times with the emir and the cabinet (which is still dominated by the al-Sabah family) over misuse of state funds and poor management of the all-important oil industry. Underlying these disputes is the growing impression that the ageing al-Sabah clan is no longer capable of running the country. However, they continue to dominate Kuwaiti policies.</p><p>Surrounded by three major Middle Eastern powers, Kuwait became the target of Iraqi territorial claims, leading to Saddam Hussein's invasion of the country in 1990. The Kuwaitis later recovered their country by virtue of a US-led, UN-backed multinational military force.</p><p>After a period of euphoria, the Kuwaitis had to address a number of difficult questions; the future security of the country was dealt with by the signing of defence and security pacts with the USA, the UK and Kuwait's Gulf allies. More recently, Kuwait was one of the first countries to join Operation Iraqi Freedom following the US-led war against Iraq, and provided aid and support during Iraq's (ongoing) process of reconstruction.</p><p>Beyond the geopolitical dimension, Kuwait is a fascinating country with much elaborate architecture and a superb culinary tradition. Its inhabitants are a warm, welcoming bunch, while the fact that Kuwait is a bit less glitzy than other oil-rich Gulf countries means that it can feel like a haven of tradition Arab culture.</p><p>Kuwait consitutes a puzzling but intriguing mix of Western liberalism and strict Islam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
