<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Kyrgyzstan" ColCode="kgz" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="kg" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Kyrgyzstan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best time to visit Kyrgyzstan is between May and October as getting around outside this period can be difficult. Trekking is best between June and September, although July and August are the busiest times for foreign visitors. The south of the country, and even Bishkek, can be uncomfortably warm at this time of year, so if these are the prime destinations to be visited, spring or autumn may be a better choice.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internal connections from Bishkek to Batken, Kerben, Jalal-Abad and Osh. Air Bishkek (<a href="http://www.airbishkek.kg" target="_blank">www.airbishkek.kg</a>) and Avia Traffic (<a href="http://www.aero.kg" target="_blank">www.aero.kg</a>) operate domestic flights.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Flying between Bishkek and Osh, Jalal-Abad or Batken is much faster than travelling by road and not much more expensive (but see warning below). Access to the Central Tien-Shan region is via helicopter, which takes climbers up the Inylchek Valley.</p><p>The British Foreign and Commonwealth Office advises against using any domestic Kyrgyz airline as they are banned within the EU because they do not meet international safety standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is only one domestic railway line, an unreliable and slow, summer-only service that runs from Bishkek to Balykchy at the western end of Lake Issyk-Kul.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors should note that roads are poorly maintained and badly signposted in Cyrillic script. Many are badly potholed.</p>r<p>The main north-south route between Bishkek and Jalal-Abad is in poor condition in places and involves passing over the 3,000m (9,800ft) Too-Ashuu Pass and through a claustrophobic 3km (1.9-mile) tunnel south of Kara-Balta. The road that goes around Lake Issyk-Kul is mostly in reasonable condition. Many minor roads are really best suited to 4-wheel drives.</p>
<p>Generally, roads can be affected by landslides (especially during spring in the mountain areas), while winter may cause hazardous conditions on a number of roads (especially on mountain passes, some of which may be closed during certain periods); visitors should also note that garage services are very limited.</p><p>Regular bus services operate between Bishkek and Karakol, and between Bishkek and other towns in the Chui valley. Otherwise, the main type of long-distance travel is by minibus or shared taxi.</p><p>Taxis are generally cheap and can be found in all major towns and even some small villages. Many are unlicensed, and you should agree fares in advance. As many of the street names, particularly in the capital, have changed since independence, visitors are advised to ask for both the old and the new names when seeking directions. In the major cities, dial-up taxi services tend to be a little more expensive but safer and more reliable.</p><p>A valid national licence or an International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>Seat belts should be worn. The legal blood alcohol level for driving is zero. Speed limits are generally 60kph (37mph) in cities and 90kph (56mph) in the countryside. Foreign drivers may face harassment from traffic police. Avoid driving at night.</p><p>Car hire is available at Bishkek airport but outside Bishkek car hire is not easy to find. It's possible to hire cars with drivers for long-distance journeys and this can be good value if the other seats are filled. Foreigners may be expected to pay in US Dollars.</p><p>Travelling by bike in Kyrgyzstan is only for the adventurous: the terrain is mountainous, distances are great, roads are bad and drivers sometimes reckless. Nevertheless, it can be highly rewarding for those with determination and stamina. Freebike (<a href="http://www.freebike.kg" target="_blank">www.freebike.kg</a>) in Bishkek hires out mountain bikes.</p><p>Seat belts should be worn. The legal blood alcohol level for driving is zero. Speed limits are generally 60kph (37mph) in cities and 90kph (56mph) in the countryside. Foreign drivers may face harassment from traffic police. Avoid driving at night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are bus and trolleybus services around the capital. Minibuses cost slightly more but are still cheap and charge a flat fare. All urban transport is invariably crowded and routes are often hard to follow. Both buses and minibuses are reasonably safe although there can be problems with theft.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Kyrgyzstan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tokmak</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Kyrgyzstan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">osh</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">12.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Kyrgyzstan</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">balikchi</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier is Air Kyrgyzstan (<a href="http://www.air.kg" target="_blank">www.air.kg</a>), which has international flights to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/uzbekistan">Uzbekistan</a>. Aeroflot (<a href="http://www.aeroflot.com" target="_blank">www.aeroflot.com</a>) operates a direct flight from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a>, with connections available from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>. Pegasus Airlines (<a href="http://www.flypgs.com" target="_blank">www.flypgs.com</a>) and Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>) fly from Istanbul to Bishkek. Both also offer connecting flights from the UK.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 15 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bishkek Manas Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport.kg/eng<p>The airport is 30km (18 miles) north of Bishkek.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A twice-weekly service connects Moscow and Bishkek (journey time - 3 days). The Russian Railways website (<a href="http://pass.rzd.ru/main-pass/public/en" target="_blank">pass.rzd.ru/main-pass/public/en</a>) has details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main international road links are with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kazakhstan">Kazakhstan</a>. There are several crossings with Uzbekistan but these can close without notice from time to time. Although there are several road links with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tajikistan">Tajikistan</a>, not all are open to foreign nationals. Of the two road links with China, only the one via Irkeshtam is technically open to foreigners. The other route over the Torugart Pass requires special permission that is only granted if pre-arranged transport is organised to meet travellers on the other side of the border.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International calls should be made from a telephone office which will usually be found attached to a post office; they can also be made from some hotels by asking at reception, although these can be expensive. All international calls from Kyrgyzstan have to go through the operator. IP international calls can be made from some internet cafes, which are a much cheaper option than using Kyrgyz Telecom. Local calls (within the city) are free of charge if made from private telephones; hotels sometimes levy a small charge. Direct-dial calls within the CIS are obtained by dialling 8 and waiting for another dial tone and then dialling the city code followed by the number.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Buying a local SIM card for your phone is easy, although nationwide coverage is patchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafes available in Bishkek and major cities, with limited access elsewhere. They are inexpensive but connections outside Bishkek are sometimes very slow.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a reasonable degree of freedom of the press. <em>Slovo Kyrgyzstana</em> is a national government-owned Russian-language paper published three times a week, while the Kyrgyz-language <em>Respublika</em> and Russian language <em>Vecherniy Bishkek</em> are both privately owned dailies. The main English-language newspaper in the country is the twice-weekly Bishkek-based Times of Central Asia (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.times.kg">www.times.kg</a>). Weekly English-language newspapers include the <em>Bishkek Observer</em>, <em>Kyrgyzstan Chronicle</em> and <em>Zaman Kyrgyzstan</em>.</p>
<p>The state-run Kyrgyz National TV and Radio Broadcasting Corporation has two networks in Kyrgyz and Russian. There are also a few private channels like <em>Piramida</em>, <em>NTS</em> and <em>Osh TV</em>.</p>
<p>British newspapers like <em>The Times</em> can sometimes be found at newsstands and upmarket hotels in Bishkek but they tend to be at least two days old.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The postal service to and from Western Europe and the USA is reasonably reliable but can take anything between two weeks and two months. Stamped envelopes can be bought from post offices. Mail to recipients within Kyrgyzstan should be addressed in the following order: country, postcode, city, street, house number and, lastly, the person's name. Visitors can also use post offices located within some major hotels. Express mail may also be sent using the reliable but pricier services of DHL or Federal Express.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Absorb Arslanbob's natural beauty</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The walnut forests surrounding the ethnic Uzbek village of Arslanbob in the Jalal-Abad province are among the largest in the world and central to the local economy. The landscape here is exceptionally beautiful and perfect for summer hiking, skiing in winter or simply walking. Stop for a drink in the main square and watch the locals play chess.</p>]]><p><b>Bag a bargain at Osh market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The chaotic swell of people that duck and weave around Osh market make it one of Kyrgyzstan's main attractions. It's one of the largest in Central Asia and an excellent place to people watch or buy souvenirs, fruits, spices and everything else under the sun.</p>]]><p><b>Dare to climb Central Tien Shan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Central Tien-Shan, in the far east of the country, is for the truly intrepid as it contains the nation's two highest peaks. Access is usually by helicopter and offers challenging mountaineering and glacier walks. For experienced climbers only, a trek in Tien Shan will reward with a disappearing lake and supposed UFO landing site. Mountaineering and border permits are required.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the spectacular Ala-Archa Canyon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>South of Bishkek, and within easy reach of the capital for day trips, this rugged valley of alpine meadows, pine forest, towering mountain peaks and fast-flowing streams offers superb scenery within the confines of a national park. Whether you want to hike, rock climb or ski, do so surrounded by natural beauty.</p>]]><p><b>Get pampered at Jeti-Ögüz Sanatorium</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Issyk-Kul's last remaining spas, the Jeti-Ögüz sanatorium offers its guests Kyrgyz-style pampering. Aside from the massages, pools, and surrounding red rock formations, it's worth a visit just to wander around the eerie building that could be lifted straight from a David Lynch film.</p>]]><p><b>Hike to Tash Rabat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This isolated monument is probably Kyrgyzstan's most remarkable Silk Road site. Half-buried on a hillside some 3,500m up (11,483ft), this former caravanserai was built in the 15th century on the site of what may have been a Nestorian Christian monastery. As well as being an attraction in itself, Tash Rabat is a great starting point for hiking.</p>]]><p><b>Horse ride to Lake Song-kol</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The beautiful 3,000m-high (9,840ft) Song-Kol is the jewel in the crown of Kyrgyzstan's gorgeous mountain scenery. Visit in the summer when horse treks to the lake can be arranged from Kochkor and a stay in a yurt to complete the experience. Community Based Tourism can help arrange horse treks to Song-Kol.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the Manas Ordu Complex</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Close to the town of Talas is a large memorial complex dedicated to Manas, the legendary 10th-century Kyrgyz hero. Although it is unclear whether or not Manas is actually buried here, there is a mausoleum here that is a place of great reverence to most Kyrgyz.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out Solomon’s Mount for picturesque panoramas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The city of Osh in the south of the country has a central rocky outcrop known locally as Solomon's Throne because the legendary king was once supposed to have slept here. The top is marked with a small shrine called Babur's House, an important pilgrimage site for Uzbeks.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out the striking Burana Tower</b></p><![CDATA[<p>South of Tokmok, though close enough to Bishkek for a day excursion, this tower is actually a minaret – all that remains of the 10th-century Karakhanid city of Balasagun. As well as the tower and visitor centre the site also has an interesting array of <em>balbals</em>, Turkic stone grave markers.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll the boulevards of Bishkek</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Kyrgyzstan capital is a relaxed city with wide boulevards, leafy parks and clear views of the snow-capped Ala-Too mountain range to the south. Although specific sights are limited, the city is a pleasant place to wander, with good hotels and restaurants and interesting museums like the State Historical Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Swim in Lake Issyk-Kul</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax on Cholpon-Ata beach after a swim in Lake Issyk-Kul, the second highest alpine lake in the world.  Meaning "warm lake" in Kyrgyz (it is said never to freeze over), Lake Issyk-Kul is popular come summer and the nearby valleys make for enjoyable walking. Once you've dried off, head for a spot of karaoke on the town's main street.</p>]]><p><b>Take a camera and capture the colours of Sary-Chelek</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Sary-Chelek Biosphere Reserve has the best environmental elements of Kyrgyzstan in one place, with a series of forests, meadows and lakes. Central to this large biosphere reserve, which is home to more than 1,000 species of plants and 160 species of bird, is the beautiful cobalt-blue lake of Sary-Chelek. Visit in autumn when the leaves turn yellow.</p>]]><p><b>Trek the Altyn Arashan Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A number of treks start in Karakol, the major town near Lake Issyk-Kul. The most popular is the three-day hike around the Altyn Arashan Valley. The path is easy to follow and can be done without a guide, and although day two is hard going, the views from the highest point of the trek make the effort worthwhile. </p>]]><p><b>Uncover Uzbek petroglyphs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are petroglyphs all over Kyrgyzstan but some of the most accessible can be seen close to Cholpon-Ata, near Lake Issyk-Kul. Alternatively, visit the Saimaluu-Tash collection, where there are thousands of prehistoric rock carvings spread across two glacial marines. It was a sacred site as early as 2000BC and is still revered by people of the Tien Shan today.</p>]]><p><b>Watch eagle hunting at Bokonbaevo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hunting with eagles is an ancient Kyrgyz tradition that is in danger of dying out. The small town of Bokonbaevo on Lake Issyk-Kul's southern shore is one of the best places to see this in action and demonstrations can be arranged with the local CBT (Community Based Tourism) coordinator.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$4.6 billion (CIA 2010 estimate).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cotton, wool, tobacco, gold and uranium.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil and gas, machinery and equipment, chemicals and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Russia, China, Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan and Switzerland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kyrgyzstan is one of poorest countries of the former Soviet Union. Although its economy is largely based in agriculture, the country does have a number of natural resources. After gaining independence, Kyrgyzstan undertook a number of regulatory reforms and was the first country from the Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS) to be accepted into the World Trade Organisation. This was after a predictable drop in production following independence. Kyrgyzstan became part of the Heavily Indebted Poor Countries (HIPC) Initiative in 2006. Although the country's economy grew by 6% in 2007-08 there was a substantial drop in 2009 due to the financial crisis, and another in 2010 because of political turmoil. However, the economy had improved considerably by early 2011 thanks to improved political security and better agricultural performance. Inflation was around 19% at the end of 2010 but this was predicted to improve. Unemployment remains around 18%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kyrgyzstan is actively seeking overseas partners to modernise its industry and introduce new technology. To this end, it has enacted a number of laws to encourage and protect foreign investors; the law on property extends to all foreign investors the rights granted to Kyrgyz citizens with respect to ownership; foreigners are allowed to purchase businesses and buildings to carry out their activities, but the government reserves the exclusive right to own land, natural resources, water, agriculture and livestock. There are significant tax holidays for foreign investors.  In order to invest in Kyrgyzstan, foreigners must be registered with the Ministry of Economy and Finance. Applications to set up in Kyrgyzstan should be sent in the first instance to the State Technical Committee on Foreign Investments and Economic Assistance (Goskominvest). The government is particularly interested in encouraging investment in mining, industry (including electronics, light agricultural machinery and pharmaceuticals), petroleum, hydroelectricity and agriculture.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800, Sat 0900-1300 (Mar-Oct).<br />
Government office hours: Mon-Fri 0900-1700, Sat 0900-1300 (Nov-Feb).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>State Technical Committee of the Kyrgyz Republic on Foreign Investments and Economic Development</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 720040 ,(312) 223 292
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Ministry of Finance</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 720040 ,(312) 228 922
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Kyrgyz Chamber of Commerce and Industry, Foreign Affairs Department</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 720001 ,(312) 210 565
					Website:http://www.ihk-kg.de
					Address: ,,,]]><b>US Department of Commerce International Trade Administration</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (202) 482 4655
					Website:http://www.ita.doc.gov
					Address: 1401 Constitution Avenue,USA Trade Centre,Washington,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Kyrgyz food reflects its location and history, with its main influences drawn from the necessities of a nomadic life in a relatively harsh climate. Mutton features prominently, as do wheat products like bread and noodles. Slavic colonisation has also meant that typical Russian dishes feature prominently too, especially in the north of the country. Other important influences come from China, Korea and Uzbekistan. The choice of food in the capital, Bishkek, is much wider, with restaurants serving cuisine from all over the world from countries such as Italy, India, Turkey and Georgia.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Mutton is the staple meat, usually served with plenty of fat according to Kyrgyz taste.</p>
<br />
<p>&bull; <em>Shashlyk</em> (skewered chunks of mutton barbecued over charcoal) and lipioshka (round unleavened bread) are often sold on street corners.</p>
<br />
<p>&bull; <em>Plov</em>, rice fried with shredded turnip and scraps of mutton, served with bread, is a Central Asian staple that is popular in the southern, Uzbek-dominated areas of the country.</p>
<br />
<p>&bull; <em>Samsa</em> are baked triangular parcels of pastry filled with mutton and onions, a little like non-spicy Indian samosas.</p>
<br />
<p>&bull;<em> Beshbarmak</em> is a meal made primarily on special occasions that consists of noodles with shredded, boiled meat in bouillon. Around Lake Issyk-Kul, the noodles are sometimes served with jellied potato starch rather than meat.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>This is becoming more customary, especially in international hotels and smart Bishkek restaurants. 10% is sufficient. Elsewhere, just round up the bill slightly.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bishkek has by far the best nightlife in the country. Both Russian and European operas and ballets are performed at the State Opera and Ballet Theatre. The Russian Drama Theatre has Russian-language productions, while the State Academic Drama Theatre stages work in the Kyrgyz language. The State Philharmonic hosts classical music concerts as well as pop and folklore events. Bishkek also has many discos and nightclubs. These are best approached with caution as drunken attacks on foreigners are not unheard of. <br />
<br />
Elsewhere in the country, things are very quiet at night, although some restaurants turn into dancehalls in places like Karakol or Naryn after nightfall.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Bishkek, Osh and Alamedin bazaars are popular for food and handicrafts. There are several souvenir crafts shops and galleries along Chui and Manas Avenue and also a shop in the Art Gallery that sells paintings and traditional Kyrgyz products. One of the most authentic souvenirs to bring back from Kyrgyzstan is an embroidered shyrdak, the traditional Kyrgyz felt rug used in yurts. Also popular are embroidered Kyrgyz felt hats (kalpak), leather items, jewellery and chess sets with traditional Kyrgyz figures. Traditional handicrafts produced by Kyrgyzstan&rsquo;s Community Based Tourism initiative (<a href="http://www.cbtkyrgyzstan.kg" target="_blank">www.cbtkyrgyzstan.kg</a>) can be purchased at their Bishkek outlet at Gorky 65. TsUM, Bishkek&rsquo;s main department store, also has a decent selection of local crafts and souvenirs on its fourth floor. Antiques, or anything over 30 years old, require a special export certificate.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1800, usually closing for an hour at lunch between 1300 and 14.00. Bishkek's main bazaars are busiest at weekends, especially Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Kyrgyzstan can be hard to find outside Bishkek and major cities like Osh, Jalal-Abad, Karakol and Naryn. While the capital has a decent range of large four-star establishments and smaller boutique affairs some provincial towns often only have time-worn survivors from the Soviet period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A few people let out rooms to guests and in the more tourist-friendly parts of the country you may be approached by people offering rooms when you disembark at a bus station.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Kyrgyzstan can be hard to find outside Bishkek and major cities like Osh, Jalal-Abad, Karakol and Naryn. While the capital has a decent range of large four-star establishments and smaller boutique affairs some provincial towns often only have time-worn survivors from the Soviet period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Kyrgyzstan can be hard to find outside Bishkek and major cities like Osh, Jalal-Abad, Karakol and Naryn. While the capital has a decent range of large four-star establishments and smaller boutique affairs some provincial towns often only have time-worn survivors from the Soviet period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical services offered to foreigners, except emergency care, require immediate cash payment and are somewhat limited. There is a severe shortage of basic medical supplies and travellers are advised to bring any necessary medication or equipment. Elderly travellers and those with existing health problems may be at risk owing to inadequate medical facilities. The US Embassy maintains a list of English-speaking physicians in the area. Medical insurance is strongly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The water has been tested by the US-based Center for Diseases Control and found to be generally bacteria-free; however, it does have a high metal content and bottled or boiled water is preferable. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled. Owing to the difficulty of obtaining a balanced diet in some parts of Kyrgyzstan, visitors are advised to take vitamin supplements.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B and E occur. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay. Tuberculosis, brucellosis and meningitis are common to Kyrgyzstan. Altitude sickness is a threat above 2,500m (8,202 ft).&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Orozo Ait (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Orozo Ait itself. Orozo Ait and Kurban Ait (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Russian Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Constitution Day :
							05 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							09 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							31 August </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Kyrgyzstan by travellers aged 18 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 3L of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of &euro;1,500 weighing no more than 50kg in total.</p>
<p>On entering the country, you must complete a customs declaration form which you need to retain until departure, and then hand over on the international flight. This allows the import of articles intended for personal use, including currency and valuables which you must register on the declaration form. Customs inspection can be long and detailed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Military weapons and ammunition (subject to special permit), narcotics, fruit and vegetables, live animals (subject to special permit), and photographs and printed matter directed against Kyrgyzstan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cultural artefacts (unless certified), or precious metals and precious stones exceeding US$25,000 in value.</p>
<p>You may only export up to 5kg of fish and seafood, and up to 250g of sturgeon caviar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kyrgyz Som (KGS; symbol лв) = 100 tyin. Notes are in denominations of лв1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1, and 50, 10 and 1 tyin. Coins exist in denominations of 1,3, 5 and 10 som, and 10 and 50 tyin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged at commercial banks and at authorised bureaux de change. The US Dollar is the easiest currency to exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are accepted in some of the larger hotels and restaurants in Bishkek and can also be used at banks to withdraw cash from the counter. They are of little value outside the main cities. ATMs exist but are hardly commonplace in Bishkek or Osh and even less so elsewhere.</p><p>ATMs are easy enough to find in Bishkek, although smaller cities like Jalal-Abad and Osh have far fewer. Some ATMs issue <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars as well as Kyrgyz Som.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is limited acceptance of these, but some banks in Bishkek accept traveller's cheques, with US Dollars probably the best option; commission charges are high. Cash is recommended, with US dollars in the form of US$50 and US$100 bills being the most readily accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Usually Mon-Fri 0930-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Kyrgyzstan, a passport valid for three months beyond the date of entry, with one blank page, is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas are usually valid for five days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A variety of single-, double- and multiple-entry visas are available, including tourist visas and ordinary visas (for business travellers).</p>
<p>Information about the current visa fees can be obtained at the responsible consular department.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visas are usually valid for one month. Ordinary (business) visas are valid for up to a year and can be extended annually up to five years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow five working days for visa processing, though some applications may take longer. Three-day processing is available for double the usual fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visas can usually only be extended in an emergency by up to two months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[41.464012]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[74.555985]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>199,951 sq km (77,201 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6,033,769 (UN estimate 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>28.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bishkek.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The landlocked nation of Kyrgyzstan is bordered to the north by Kazakhstan, to the west by Uzbekistan, and to the south and east by Tajikistan and China. The majestic Tien Shan (Heavenly Mountains) range occupies the greater part of the area and 90% of the country stands above 1,500m, with 71% above 2,000m. The highest peak in Kyrgyzstan is Pik Pobedy at 7,439m (24,406ft) and the lowest point is Kara-Daryya at 132m (433ft). Kyrgyzstan is also home to several sizeable lakes, by far the largest being Lake Issyk-Kul in the northwest of the country, which stands at 1,606m (5,269 ft) above sea level and is the second largest alpine lake in the world. The climate is extreme and varied, ranging from dry continental to polar in the high Tien Shan, from subtropical in the southwest to temperate in the northern foothill zone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The major religion is Islam with 80% of Kyrgyzstan's citizens being Sunni Muslim. Christian and Russian Orthodox minorities make up a further 17%, with 3% following other religions..</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hospitality is an important component of Kyrgyz life and guests are highly honoured, especially in rural households. If invited to a Kyrgyz home or yurt a small gift is appreciated. Shoes should always be removed at the threshold. Kyrgyzstan is a fairly conservative country and handshaking should take place between men but not between men and women. At a meal, bread should be treated respectfully and never put on the floor or casually discarded. Food is eaten with the right hand only. Bride-kidnapping, although now officially illegal, is still practised in parts of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Mukhammetkaly Abulgaziyev&nbsp;since 2018.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Sooronbay Jeenbekov since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The region now known as Kyrgyzstan has seen many invasions and colonisations over the centuries. First settled during the pre-historic period, it became home to Scythian clans during the 1st millennium BC before coming under the control of various Turkic alliances from the 6th century onwards, a period in which the region prospered from its prime location on the Silk Road between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> and Europe. Islam arrived with Arab invaders in the 8th century but the Arabs did not stay long and the region came under the control of the Karakhanid dynasty based in Bokhara shortly afterwards.</p>
<p>Kyrgyz tribes started to arrive from southern Siberia sometime around the 10th century, although they soon fell victim to Genghis Khan&rsquo;s Mongol horde that was plundering and devastating vast tracts of Central Asia at this time. The Kyrgyz later became subjects of the Chinese and the Uzbek Kokand Khanate until Russian Tsarists colonised the region in the early 19th century.</p>
<p>Kirgizia, as it was formerly known, became part of the Soviet Union in 1922 and remained an autonomous republic within the USSR until independence in 1991 when it seceded along with many other former Soviet republics. The first president of the newly formed Kyrgyz Republic, Askar Akayev, managed to remain in power for 16 years before being ousted in a landslide victory in 2005 following widespread demonstrations against high levels of poverty and alleged political corruption. The victor of this so-called &lsquo;Tulip Revolution&rsquo; was Kurmanbek Bakiyev, who served as president until 2010 when widespread violent protests forced him to leave the country. These same protests also triggered ethnic violence between Kyrgyz and Uzbeks in the south of the country resulting in hundreds of deaths and thousands fleeing as refugees.</p>
<p>The new president, Almazbek Atambayev came to power in December 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Kazakhstan]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+7 7172 556 200</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://ukinkz.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+7 7172 556 200</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 08.30-17.00; Fri 08.30-15.30&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Kosmonavtov 62, Renco Building 6th floor<br/>Astana<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Kyrgyz Republic in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 449 9822</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.kgembassy.org/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 449 9822</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 09.30-12.00 (visa section)&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2360 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Kyrgyz Republic in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7935 1462</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.kyrgyz-embassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7935 1462</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1800; 0930-1230 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>119 Crawford Street<br/>Ascot House<br/>London<br/>W1U 6BJ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Often referred to as the &ldquo;Switzerland of Central Asia&rdquo;, Kyrgyzstan certainly lives up to this moniker with its soaring mountain ranges, glistening glaciers and vertiginous pine forests. If it feels like you&rsquo;re on top of the world, that&rsquo;s because you&rsquo;re not far off.</p>
<p>Despite its ubiquitous natural beauty and considerable size, few people can point to this landlocked nation on the map let alone pronounce its name (it&rsquo;s <em>Kur-gi-stan</em>, by the way). Even fewer actually visit.</p>
<p>This is due largely to Kyrgyzstan&rsquo;s geographical isolation, but also because it has been out in the cold politically &ndash; since gaining independence from the USSR, the country has remained well under the influence of neighbouring Russia.</p>
<p>Visitor numbers are increasing, but a short tourist season, an underdeveloped infrastructure and poor air links remain obstacles for all but the intrepid traveller. However, those who do make it here are guaranteed an experience they won&rsquo;t have to share with the crowds.</p>
<p>Although mountains dominate, Kyrgyzstan&rsquo;s landscapes are surprisingly varied: snow-capped peaks eventually give way to open plains and shimmering lakes. It really does look Switzerland in places, but elsewhere the countryside can conjure up images of Scotland, Kashmir and even the Middle East.&nbsp;The mountain vistas alone are reason enough to visit and no trip to Kyrgyzstan would be complete without trekking up at least one of its impressive summits.</p>
<p>For less active visitors there are a handful of beaches to speak of and, in the small window that passes as summer, holidaymakers can be found bathing on the shores of lakes such as Issyk Kul. Located in the Tian Shan mountains, this is a summer resort for the brave &ndash; the water here is bracing to say the least.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not all about the landscapes, though. In fact a big draw for tourists is the prospect of staying with the country&rsquo;s semi-nomadic shepherds, who live in yurts and eke out traditional lives in this harsh, unforgiving and unremittingly beautiful country.</p><p>Often referred to as the &ldquo;Switzerland of Central Asia&rdquo;, Kyrgyzstan certainly lives up to this moniker with its soaring mountain ranges, glistening glaciers and vertiginous pine forests. If it feels like you&rsquo;re on top of the world, that&rsquo;s because you&rsquo;re not far off.    Despite its ubiquitous natural beauty and considerable size, few people can point to this landlocked nation on the map let alone pronounce its name (it&rsquo;s Kur-gi-stan, by the way). Even fewer actually visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
