<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Laos" ColCode="lao" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="la" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Laos]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Throughout the country, the climate is hot and tropical, with the rainy season between May and October when temperatures are at their highest, up to 35&deg;C. The weather is very similar to that of northern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vietnam">Vietnam</a>. The dry season runs from November to April, which is the best time to visit as the temperature is at its most comfortable. However, the mountainous areas can be very cold at this time, down to around 5&deg;C. Across Asia the annual monsoon is becoming ever more difficult to predict, possibly as a result of global warming. This plays havoc with farming and occasionally travel plans too. As a guide, the average rainfall in the capital Vientiane is about 1,700 mm, although in the north of Laos and the highlands it is far wetter, with more than 3,000 mm each year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights and rainwear, with warmer layers from October to March and for upland areas. If you come during the monsoon summer months, bring lightweight waterproofs, an umbrella and some leech oil for trekking. Bring a swimming costume for hotel swimming pools too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lao Airlines (<a href="http://www.laos-airlines.com/" target="_blank">www.l</a><a href="http://www.laos-airlines.com/" target="_blank">aoairlines.com</a>) runs domestic air services from Vientiane to Xieng Khouang, Luang Prabang, Huay Xai and Oudomxai in the north and Pakse and Savannakhet in the south. The airline is based at Wattay airport. All domestic flight times are around an hour.&nbsp;</p><p>The domestic terminal is next door to Wattay International Airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Mekong and other rivers are still a vital part of the country's transport system, especially during the monsoon, despite the road system being gradually improved. However, the number of boats available has decreased dramatically. The choice is between irregular (and very basic) slow ferries and exciting but noisy and hazardous speedboats. A service runs from Luang Prabang to Huay Xai, but there is no longer a service between Vientiane and Luang Prabang, except for the rare cargo boat that may take passengers.</p>
<p>The journey upstream from Luang Prabang to Houay Xai takes two days, with an overnight stop in Pakbeng, and downstream it takes one day. There are regular jet-boat trips along the river, run by Lao River Exploration Services<em> </em>(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.jetboat.laopdr.com/">www.jetboat.laopdr.com</a>). Boats can also be hired privately. Many of the remaining services only run in the wet season, when the Mekong floods and becomes more navigable. Huay Xai (the border to Thailand in the northwest) to Luang Prabang and travel south of Pakse are the main routes still in use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Other than the international train between Thailand and Laos there are no other railway lines in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are on a strict timescale, it is advisable to pre-arrange travel outside Vientiane with a tour company to avoid unforeseen delays and costs.</p>r<p>Many of the roads have been paved in recent years, including the main highway from the Thai border at Savannakhet to the Vietnamese border. However, few main roads are suitable for all-weather or night driving.</p>
<p>In the north of the country, there is a road link between Vientiane and Luang Prabang, and from Vientiane to Savannakhet and Pakse in the south.</p><p>Privately run, air-conditioned VIP coaches make the journey between tourist centres whereas slower, more basic, local buses cover a far wider range of destinations. Note the toilet stops are often far and few between, and breakdowns/tyre changes are the norm rather than an exception.</p><p>The word &lsquo;tuk-tuk&rsquo; is used to describe a large variety of lightweight vehicles, generally with three wheels. While there is a tuk-tuk organization in Vientiane that is supposed to control the prices that tourists pay between destinations, the rates remain negotiable. Decide on the fare before getting in. A <em>songthaew</em> (meaning &lsquo;two rows&rsquo; in Thai) is a pick-up truck, with two benches, a roof and open sides; these operate both as  local buses and taxis.</p><p>International Driving Permit recommended.</p><p>There are very few road regulations in general within Laos.</p><p>Non-existent. It's a case of asking around the village or town to see if there is a mechanic available.</p><p>Unless you are an experienced driver, it&rsquo;s not recommended to hire cars in Laos as driving standards are not up to international levels and there are few rules. However, if you are capable, it is an excellent way to get off the beaten track and to explore. A safer option is to hire cars with a driver through hotels or tourist agencies.</p><p>Laos has plenty of quiet roads that lend themselves to cycling. It is a growing industry and there are several local operators offering guided cycling throughout the country. There are good maps available and cycling is one of the best ways to come into contact with local people.</p>
<p>Most motorcycles are either Honda Baja or scooters. Japanese-made bikes will serve you better if you&rsquo;re going off the beaten track, especially if heading to mountainous areas. Rental shops exist in Vientiane only. Don't leave your passport as a deposit/guarantee. Helmets are mandatory and the local police are keen on checking motorcycle licences, so make sure you have one or be prepared to pay a heavy fine.</p><p>There are very few road regulations in general within Laos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major towns are small and accessible on foot or by bicycle. You can hire motorbikes and bicycles for the day in Vientiane, Luang Prabang and other places frequented by tourists. There is a mixture of old and metered taxis in Vientiane that can usually be located at Wattay Airport, the Friendship Bridge and the Morning market. You can also hire taxis by the day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Laos</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">savannakhet</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.25</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Laos</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">pakse</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Laos</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">luang_prabang</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline of Laos is Lao Airlines (<a href="http://www.laoairlines.com" target="_blank">www.laoairlines.com</a>). There are no direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> or Europe; flights are mainly via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangkok">Bangkok</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vietnam">Vietnam</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cambodia">Cambodia</a>. Popular airlines flying into Laos include Bangkok Airways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.bangkokair.com/">www.bangkokair.com</a>), Thai Airways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.thaiair.com/">www.thaiair.com</a>) and Vietnam Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.vietnamairlines.com/">www.vietnamairlines.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 16 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 20 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>During festivals it can be hard to find a free seat on the national carrier, Lao Airlines, which serves both regional centres and neighbouring countries. Unlike other countries it is vital in Laos to reconfirm your flight the day before, otherwise you may be bumped off.</p>
<p>Many international flights arrive late at night. For a smooth arrival have your hotel arrange a collection from the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Usually included in the ticket price.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>During festivals it can be hard to find a free seat on the national carrier, Lao Airlines, which serves both regional centres and neighbouring countries. Unlike other countries it is vital in Laos to reconfirm your flight the day before, otherwise you may be bumped off.</p>
<p>Many international flights arrive late at night. For a smooth arrival have your hotel arrange a collection from the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Vientiane International Airport (Wattay)</b><![CDATA[https://www.vientiane-airport.com/<p>Vientiane International Airport is located 3km (1.8 miles) from Vientiane city, Laos.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+856 20 55 608 955</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to travel from the Thai border to Luang Prabang by speedboat, slow boat or by a deluxe one-day boat. The slow boat takes about two days and usually involves an overnight stay in Pak Beng. Alternatively there are &lsquo;luxury&rsquo; cruises which also take two days but have much better facilities than the ordinary slow boats. These are charged at an accordingly higher premium. The speedboat goes from Houaixay on the Laos border to Luang Prabang in around six hours.</p><p>The Navigation Office at the main landing point (Tha Heua Meh) at the end of Th Chao Phanya Kang has signs, usually not in English, that announce long-distance boat departures.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passenger services connects Bangkok and Vientiane. The train travels over across the Friendship Bridge from Nong Kai in Thailand to the international rail terminal at Thanaleng, around 15km (9 miles) from central Vientiane. It&rsquo;s easy to connect with a local tuk-tuk to get you into town.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Laos has over a dozen border-crossing possibilities. Travellers can enter by road from Cambodia, China, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/thailand">Thailand</a> and Vietnam &ndash; the exception is <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/myanmar">Myanmar</a>.</p><p>30-day visas are available at most of the land crossings, but check for up-to-date information. If you arrive at the border by road, bear in mind that you&rsquo;ll definitely have to change transport, as it&rsquo;s unlikely a driver from one of the surrounding countries will be willing or able to cross over with you. If you&rsquo;re arriving with your own car or motorbike be prepared for plenty of form-filling and fees. You can import the vehicle for the duration of your visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The General Post Office (GPO) offers public telephones for national and international calls. There are also card phone booths available. Lao Telecome Numphu Centre in Vientiane is useful for making international calls, domestic calls and sending faxes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a few international mobile phone companies. Check with your service provider. Coverage is sporadic and mainly, though not exclusively, situated around Vientiane. It's better and cheaper to arrives to Laos with your mobile phone unlocked and then to buy a pay-as-you-go SIM card. Look for Tigo and M-phone top-up cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes are located in the major towns and are becoming increasingly common in places frequented by backpackers. High-speed connection is only available in places such as Vientiane and Luang Prabang. In Vientiane the best streets to head to for fast internet connection and internet cafes with Skype and air-conditioning are Th Samsenthai and Th Setthathriat. Expect to pay around 7000K an hour for broadband. Wi-Fi is increasingly available in many Western orientated bars and cafes</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Lao media is basically a tool of the government, which owns all of the country's newspapers and broadcast media. Newspapers are not widely read. The widest read<strong> </strong>English-language newspaper is the <em>Vientiane Times</em>. <em>Le R&eacute;novateur</em>, started in 1998, is the only French-language newspaper in the Lao PDR (Laos). It is published weekly by an agency of the Ministry of Information and Culture and the French Cultural Centre of Vientiane corrects the articles written by Laotian journalists. The Lao-language daily is the <em>Vientiane Mai</em>. All newspapers are state run. You will be able to pick up copies of <em>Newsweek</em>, <em>Time</em>, <em>The Economist</em> and <em>The Bangkok Post</em> in the capital.</p>
<p>Lao National TV (TVNL) and Laos Television 3, a joint venture with a Thai company, are the main TV channels. Lao National Radio is the national radio station - it was founded in 1960, before becoming a national broadcaster in 1975.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The General Post Office (GPO) is beside the Morning Market in Vientiane. Normal postal service is inexpensive and generally reliable although it can take around two weeks to and from Western countries. A courier service is recommended for urgent or valuable mail.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700, Sat-Sun 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the sweeping lines of Wat Xieng Thong</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps the grandest of all Laos temples, Wat Xieng Thong's soaring rooftops hark back to Luang Prabang's golden era. The <em>sim </em>(chapel) was founded in 1560, and the complex is richly decorated with coloured glass and gold. It's a stunning example of traditional Laotian architecture and hosted important royal rituals when Luang Prabang was capital of the Kingdom of Laos.</p>]]><p><b>Chill out in laidback Luang Prabang</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sprawling along the banks of the mighty Mekong River, UNESCO-listed Luang Prabang is the nation's most important cultural and religious centre. Scattered around the historic centre are dozens of historic monasteries, and queues of monks wind through the city streets every morning. Travellers love Luang Prabang for its relaxed pace of life and delicious food, best sampled along the riverbank.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise the mighty Mekong</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Mekong River forms the border between Laos and Thailand, and cruising this mighty waterway is the best way to experience the slow, easy rhythms of life in this Asian backwater. One stunningly romantic trip is the three-day cruise from Pakse to the ruins of Vat Phou, aboard a gorgeous converted teak barge.</p>]]><p><b>Drift along a river</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Floating in a tyre inner tube might sound like an unlikely tourist attraction, but travellers have been lazily bobbing along the Nam Song River at Vang Vieng ever since Laos reopened to tourism in the 1990s. Today, hedonistic Vang Vieng is a victim of its own success, but travellers still flock to tube on the river and sip beers in riverside bars.</p>]]><p><b>Explore one man’s obsession in Xieng Khuan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>South of Vientiane, close to the Thai border crossing at Nong Khai, the sculpture garden at Xieng Khuan was created by the eccentric monk Luang Pu Bunleua Sulilat, who devoted a lifetime to creating a representation of Buddhist heaven and hell on Earth in the form of cement statues. Vendors nearby serve grilled river fish and pounded papaya salad.</p>]]><p><b>Learn to cook Laos’ delicious cuisine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you enjoy the rich flavours of Laotian cuisine, you can learn to make the same dishes on a cooking course in Vientiane or Luang Prabang. Most classes include a visit to the local market to purchase meat, vegetables, herbs and spices, so you'll know exactly what you need when you try to make your first Laotian meal at home.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the intricacy of Laotian silk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Laos is famous across Asia for its fine silk weaving, a tradition practiced for centuries by hill tribe villages using traditional backstrap looms. Local silk is used to make everything from shawls and sarongs to shirts and bags – the weaving village of Ban Phanom near Luang Prabang is a great place to see the weavers at work.</p>]]><p><b>Meet a monk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As dawn breaks across Laos, the streets are criss-crossed by saffron-coloured lines of monks, queuing up to receive alms from local traders. It's one of the most photogenic sights in Asia, and worth getting up for every morning. Luang Prabang is probably the most scenic spot for monk watching, but this ritual unrolls in every town each morning.</p>]]><p><b>Meet the local wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The jungles of Laos are a hotbed of biodiversity, home to hundreds of species of birds and elusive tigers, elephants, rhinos and bears. Getting close to the wildlife involves trekking into national parks, or in the case of the Bokeo Nature Reserve near Hoay Xai, travelling through the forest canopy on zip wires in search of the illusive black gibbon.</p>]]><p><b>Pause to reflect in the Pak Ou Caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The limestone mountains of Laos are worm-holed with caverns, and many have been worshipped as shrines since time immemorial. The fascinating Pak Ou Caves, a speedboat ride north from Luang Prabang, are full of hundreds of Buddha images, left there over centuries by local worshippers. It's a ritual harking back to animist traditions, and the caves are incredibly photogenic.</p>]]><p><b>Ponder the mystery of the Plain of Jars</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Laos' most enigmatic sight, the Plain of Jars, near Phonsavan, is swathed in legend and mystery. The grasslands are covered in hundreds of stone jars, some weighing up to six tonnes. Local legend says they were used to ferment rice wine in the sixth century to celebrate a victory in battle, but nobody knows for sure why they were created.</p>]]><p><b>Search for dolphins on the Mekong</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The waterways of Laos are one of the last refuges of the critically endangered Irrawaddy dolphin, which can be spotted on the Mekong River, particularly around Si Phan Don (Four Thousand Islands). This laidback archipelago is one of the favourite backpacker hangouts in Laos, and the starting point for trips to spectacular Khone Phapheng, Southeast Asia's largest waterfall by volume.</p>]]><p><b>Step back into the mists of time at Vat Phou</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ruins of lost empires lie scattered across Laos, but perhaps the most evocative site is the ruined Khmer Hindu temple complex of Vat Phou, constructed on a mountain top by the same empire builders who went on to create the mighty temples of Angkor in Cambodia. The approach by river from Pakse is almost as atmospheric as the ruins themselves.</p>]]><p><b>Tour temples and markets in colonial Vientiane</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its fading French colonial architecture and handsome Buddhist wats and stupas, Vientiane is the living image of Indochina. Home to less than 800,000 people, but dotted with golden temples, this is one of the smallest, quietest and most relaxed capital cities in the world, nestled in fertile plains on the banks of the Mekong River.</p>]]><p><b>Trek to hill tribe villages</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Like neighbouring Thailand and Myanmar, Laos is home to thousands of tribal people, who live in peaceful isolation in the jungles of the central highlands. The most popular starting point for treks to meet tribal people is the sleepy town of Muang Xing in mountainous Luang Namtha province, which is ringed by Akha and Tai Leu hill tribe villages.</p>]]><p><b>Trek to waterfalls and tribal villages on the Boloven Plateau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Boloven Plateau in Champassak province is cloaked in jungle, dotted with hill-tribe villages, and watered by some of Southeast Asia's most impressive waterfalls. Pakse, home to many ethnic minority groups, is the region's capital and the ideal base from which to explore, with organised treks to remote villages and thundering cascades.</p>]]><p><b>Watch sunset from the summit of Mount Phousi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As sunset falls over the Mekong River, the best place to catch the show is the summit of Mount Phousi in Luang Prabang, which is actually just a modest hill in the centre of the old town. A <em>naga</em> staircase climbs to the top, where a sacred stupa offers panoramic views over Luang Prabang and the surrounding rivers and hills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$7.9 billion (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Clothing, timber products, copper, electricity and coffee.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, vehicles, fuel and consumer goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Vietnam, Thailand, France and China (PR).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Laos is one of the world's poorest countries, and its predominantly agricultural economy is largely at a level of subsistence. The main crops are rice, pulses, fruits, sugar cane, tobacco and coffee. Laotian coffee is highly rated among connoisseurs and is now the country's single largest export commodity. <br />
<br />
Considerable reserves of tin, lead, zinc, iron ore, coal and timber are largely untapped. Industry is mostly concerned with textiles, basic consumer goods and processing raw materials. The tourism industry has developed since the late 1990s. It is now Laos' single largest source of income but development is hampered by chronic shortages of skilled labour and foreign exchange. <br />
<br />
Economic reforms began in the early 1990s but, compounded by the regional financial crisis, the economy was in serious difficulties by the beginning of 1999 with the Lao Kip sinking against the US Dollar, which it has continued to do. Since then, something of a recovery has taken place: in 2011 the economy was growing at around 8.3% annually while inflation had been cut to 7.8%. The economy relies heavily on foreign aid. Laos is currently working towards joining the World Trade Organisation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Punctuality is appreciated. Lightweight suits, shirt and tie should be worn. English is not spoken by all officials and knowledge of French is useful. Business cards should have a Laotian translation on the reverse. Best time to visit is during the dry season, from November to April.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300/1400-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ministry of Finance</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 412 409
					Website:
					Address: Xaysettha District,Thatluang Road,Ban Phonxay,Vientiane PO Box 46,]]><b>Lao National Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 452 579
					Website:http://www.lncci.laotel.com/
					Address: Saysettha District,BP 4596,Phonphanao Village,Vientiane,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Laotian cuisine shows the clear influence of Thai, Vietnamese and Chinese cooking, with its widespread use of chilli, fish sauce, soy and Asian herbs like lemongrass, ginger, galangal and Asian basil. There's also a subtle French influence dating back to the colonial administration, most obvious in the baguette sandwiches sold on the streets of Vientiane.</p><p>The foundation stone of any Laos meal is <em>khao niaw</em> (sticky rice), and most meals come with a side order of <em>tam mak hoong </em>(pounded green papaya salad). Perhaps the most famous dish of all is <em>laap</em>, a fiery salad of minced meat, chilli, lime juice, ground rice and mint. Green tea is usually served weak and free in most restaurants, and Beer Lao has an enthusiastic following.</p><p>Some of the most atmospheric restaurants are set on terraces overlooking the swirling waters of the Mekong River – needless to say, grilled river fish is a favourite local delicacy.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Khao niaw: </strong>Lao glutinous rice (aka sticky rice) is the national staple; simply roll it up into balls and pop in your mouth.<br />
<strong>Tam mak hoong</strong>: Laos&rsquo; favourite salad is an incendiary mix of pounded green papaya, peanuts, dried shrimp, green beans, lime juice, fish sauce and palm sugar.<br />
<strong>Laap</strong>: A lip-smacking salad made from minced meat, fish or vegetables tossed with mint, chilli, lime juice, garlic, onions and powdered rice.<br />
<strong>Pho: </strong>White rice noodle soup, usually served with beef or pork; it&rsquo;s subtly flavoured and locals spice it up with fish sauce, dried chillies and herbs.<br />
<strong>Khao jee</strong>: Baguettes are a legacy of the French colonial period, often served with tomatoes, cheese and pork in chilli sauce.<br />
<strong>Sai oua</strong>: Traditional Lao sausage, flavoured with lime leaves, onion, garlic and Lao herbs.<br />
<strong>Kai paen</strong>: Weed from the Mekong River &ndash; a Luang Prabang speciality &ndash; usually served dried into sheets with sesame.<br />
<strong>Khao poon: </strong>Spicy soup with vermicelli noodles, chilli, lime leaves and strongly-flavoured perilla leaves.<br />
<strong>Ping Kai</strong>: Lao-style grilled chicken, seasoned with pepper, coriander root, garlic and fish sauce.<br />
<strong>Or Lam</strong>: A rich jungle stew or dried buffalo meat or game, chilli, mushrooms, beans and mashed eggplants.<br />
<strong>Lao lao:</strong> The local rice whisky, traditionally prepared in village stills.<br />
<strong>Beer Lao: </strong>The nation&rsquo;s favourite brew.<br />
<strong>Cafe pakxong:</strong> Lao<em> c</em>offee, brewed using beans from plantations on the Boloven Plateau.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is illegal for a nightclub or bar to stay open later than 2330&nbsp;and therefore to expect Vientiane to be on a par with other Asian capitals in terms of nightlife would be a misstep. Generally, the Lao nightlife is quiet and laid-back, usually involving a Beer Lao, a stunning sunset firefly display and an early night. However, there are two nightclubs of note in Vientiane &ndash; Future Nightclub and Highwayman are both are fairly close to the airport and both often stay open later than they should.</p>
<p>Otherwise try the French Cultural Centre on Th Lan Xang in Vientiane which often shows movies, and has music performances. Elsewhere in the capital, there are plenty of bars along the river, most of which stay open until 2300 or so &ndash; expect plenty of classic rock, cocktails and cheap beer. In Luang Prabang it&rsquo;s the same story, although the city has the country&rsquo;s first openly gay bar &ndash; Khob Chai. Note that the streets empty out early in Laos and stumbling home drunk might not be a wise idea. Guesthouses close and bolt their doors accordingly too, so try not to get locked out.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The markets in Vientiane and Luang Prabang are worth visiting. Silk, cotton fabrics, wood carvings, pottery, silver jewellery and handmade shirts are good buys. Lao sarongs <em>(pha sin)</em> and hill tribe bags are a popular souvenir. Although the majority of shops have fixed prices, bartering is still advisable for many items.</p>
<p>In Vientiane, it&rsquo;s worth heading out to the weaving district of Ban Nong Bouathong, northeast of the city. Try the Phaeng Mai Gallery which sells beautiful Lao textiles. For something really smart, head to the American designer Carol Cassidy&rsquo;s shop, Lao Textiles, which is well-known internationally. Here, you&rsquo;ll find items that will fit in well at parties back home as well as on your travels. Lao weavers design the items and work in an attractive old French-Lao house. If buying clothes in Laos note that most fabrics are not machine washable as the dye runs. Nearby, opposite Talat Sao market, is the clumsily named Handicraft Products of Ethnic Groups- here you&rsquo;ll find handicrafts from all across the family.</p>
<p>Luang Prabang is best known for its handicrafts, art, textiles and jewelry. In an old French mansion, Pathana Boupha Antique House is certainly worth a visit. There&rsquo;s some beautiful silverwork and old photos for sale, mostly from the Lao owners&rsquo; private collection. It&rsquo;s brilliant for browsing and for choosing an inspired, unusual gift. There are also plenty of small bookshops. L&rsquo;Etranger Books &amp; Tea is a lovely place to cool off or curl up with a book in. It sells both new and second-hand books mainly about Laos and Southeast Asi but head upstairs to the tea lounge and you can see local art displayed too.</p>
<p>Another great spot to combine retail with tea is the Baan Khily Gallery, which sells Lao crafts and mulberry bark paper (<em>sǎa</em>). The friendly owner is often on-site and there&rsquo;s an upstairs terrace which lends itself to chill-out time.</p><p>Times vary but generally Mon-Sat 0800-1700 with private shops open longer hours. Some also open on Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are good hotels in Luang Prabang, Vang Vieng and Vientiane, but facilities are basic elsewhere with just a few exceptions. Local village hostels are available, but with few amenities, these are not really geared towards western tourists. One thing to bear in mind is the peak and low season periods. High season, which is from October to January means more booked-out hotels and higher prices. By contrast low-season - any date that falls outside of January to February &ndash; means more room for bargaining and less visitors. One especially impressive new opening is La Folie Lodge (<a href="http://www.lafolie-laos.com/" target="_blank">www.lafolie-laos.com</a>), a property owned by a French count, located on Don Daeng, an isolated island in the Mekong River in southern Laos. Ideal for a look at rural Laotian life and for enjoying perfect isolation in luxury.</p>
<p>Nowadays Laos has several five<strong>-</strong>star options and some fantastic boutique options. Luang Prabang has the highest concentration mainly due its UNESCO-listed setting and elegant colonial buildings. The Aman and Orient Express chains have hotels in Laos and several independent boutiques have opened, many of which are perfect for honeymooners and upscale visitors, offering world-class cuisine, cultural programmes and service of the highest standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guesthouses are common in areas frequented by tourists in Laos. There have been budget guesthouses for several years in traveller hubs, and mid-level range guesthouses are now mushrooming across the country. Lao guesthouses are often very busy during festivals – especially during the busy period of December to February and Lao New Year. The trick, as ever, is to book ahead.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are good hotels in Luang Prabang, Vang Vieng and Vientiane, but facilities are basic elsewhere with just a few exceptions. Local village hostels are available, but with few amenities, these are not really geared towards western tourists. One thing to bear in mind is the peak and low season periods. High season, which is from October to January means more booked-out hotels and higher prices. By contrast low-season - any date that falls outside of January to February &ndash; means more room for bargaining and less visitors. One especially impressive new opening is La Folie Lodge (<a href="http://www.lafolie-laos.com/" target="_blank">www.lafolie-laos.com</a>), a property owned by a French count, located on Don Daeng, an isolated island in the Mekong River in southern Laos. Ideal for a look at rural Laotian life and for enjoying perfect isolation in luxury.</p>
<p>Nowadays Laos has several five<strong>-</strong>star options and some fantastic boutique options. Luang Prabang has the highest concentration mainly due its UNESCO-listed setting and elegant colonial buildings. The Aman and Orient Express chains have hotels in Laos and several independent boutiques have opened, many of which are perfect for honeymooners and upscale visitors, offering world-class cuisine, cultural programmes and service of the highest standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are good hotels in Luang Prabang, Vang Vieng and Vientiane, but facilities are basic elsewhere with just a few exceptions. Local village hostels are available, but with few amenities, these are not really geared towards western tourists. One thing to bear in mind is the peak and low season periods. High season, which is from October to January means more booked-out hotels and higher prices. By contrast low-season - any date that falls outside of January to February &ndash; means more room for bargaining and less visitors. One especially impressive new opening is La Folie Lodge (<a href="http://www.lafolie-laos.com/" target="_blank">www.lafolie-laos.com</a>), a property owned by a French count, located on Don Daeng, an isolated island in the Mekong River in southern Laos. Ideal for a look at rural Laotian life and for enjoying perfect isolation in luxury.</p>
<p>Nowadays Laos has several five<strong>-</strong>star options and some fantastic boutique options. Luang Prabang has the highest concentration mainly due its UNESCO-listed setting and elegant colonial buildings. The Aman and Orient Express chains have hotels in Laos and several independent boutiques have opened, many of which are perfect for honeymooners and upscale visitors, offering world-class cuisine, cultural programmes and service of the highest standards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave plenty of time before travelling to contact your GP &amp;ndash; 2 months is best - to check whether you need any vaccinations or other preventive measures. If you are unfortunate enough to fall sick or are in real need of medical attention it is best to travel to Vientiane where there are several reputable medical clinics. Any treatment must generally be paid for in cash. In Laos if you need emergency medical assistance, dial 195 (ambulance Ministry of Public Health) or 030 525 7239 (ambulance centre) to request an ambulance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In urgent cases, repatriation to Thailand &amp;ndash; especially for serious injuries and illnesses &amp;ndash; is best. There you will find excellent healthcare at Bangkok  Hospital, which specifically caters to medical tourists, or Phyathai Hospitals Group which has translators for 22 languages as well as a team of English-speaking staff. The hospitals in Bangkok are some of the best in the world, usually meeting or exceeding US standards. Udon Thani and Chiang Mai are closer, depending on your location in Laos and both have clinics better than you&amp;rsquo;ll find in Laos. Bear in mind that evacuation is complicated to organise and is very expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If in doubt, a helpful concierge at one of the better hotels will probably be a good source of information as would most embassies in an emergency situation &amp;ndash; note that there is no British consular representation in Laos &amp;ndash; the closest is in Bangkok. Urgent consular assistance to British nationals is provided by the Australian Embassy in Vientiane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercise caution when buying medicines from pharmacies in Laos, unfortunately, as with many developing countries in Asia, counterfeit drugs are very common. There are few if any laws preventing such trade and Laos is somewhat of a dumping ground for phony, replica goods &amp;ndash; whether household items or medicines. Lastly, health insurance is essential and should include cover for air evacuation.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis E occurs and hepatitis B is highly endemic. Dengue fever, tuberculosis and Japanese encephalitis occur. Avoid swimming in fresh water as schistsomiasis and leptospirosis are present. Other than the capital &amp;ndash; which is malaria-free but not dengue fever-free - assume that malaria is present everywhere in Laos &amp;ndash; before leaving home check with your health clinic regarding which precautions to take as there are drug-resistant parasites around Laos. Bring DEET-laced insect repellent of at least 25% strength and sleep with a mosquito net and fan. Generally speaking - the mosquitoes that are active during daytime may be carrying dengue and those that are active at dawn and dusk, malaria.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Pathet Lao Day :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Army Day :
							2018<br/>20 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Day of the People's Party :
							22 March </p><p>Lao New Year (Pi Mai) :
							13 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Children's Day :
							01 June </p><p>National Day :
							02 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Laos by travellers aged 16 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits and 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 50ml of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of US$50.</p>
<p>You must declare any antique items purchased in other countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted goods include products affecting national security and stability or public health, narcotics, wildlife, endangered species, and historical artefacts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Any antiques of great historical value. You should check with the Ministry of Information and Culture before exporting cultural artefacts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lao Kip (LAK; symbol ₭&shy;) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of ₭50,000, 20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 2,000, 1,000, 500, 100, 50, 10, 5 and 1. Most transactions are conducted in cash; American Dollars, Thai Baht or Lao Kip (LAK).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Thai Baht, US Dollars, Euros and the British Pound are the easiest currencies to exchange. They are also widely accepted in shops, markets and hotels in Vientiane and Luang Prabang.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are accepted in the more upmarket hotels and restaurants only in Vientiane and Luang Prabang. Several banks will also offer a cash advance on credit cards for a commission.</p><p>Nowadays most ATMs are reliable. However there is a limit on how much you can withdraw during a day,  and currently the withdrawal limit per day is set at approximately 1,000,000 LAK, roughly &pound;65. Vientiane has the biggest selection of ATMs in the county, especially around Th Setthathriat. Major hotels are likely to have an ATM on-site too.</p>
<p>The domestic economy in Laos still depends on the Thai baht and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollar; pounds and euros, less so. In fact, two-thirds of the cash in the capital Vientiane, is Thai or American. Although only kip is legally negotiable in everyday transactions, it&rsquo;s worth remembering that for small purchases and transactions, prices will be quoted in kip, larger transactions, i.e for hotels or transport, it&rsquo;s likely the price will be quoted in dollars. This is relevant for whereabouts you are too - in larger cities Thai baht or US dollars are more in use, whereas in smaller towns and villages, kip is usually preferred. In spite of relative current stability, the kip is not yet a stable currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Limited acceptance and often with a hefty commission charge – available at most banks in Vientiane. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Thai Baht.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1600. Some banks remain open during lunch.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Laos, a passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.&nbsp;</p>
<p>You may not always be required to show a return ticket if you are travelling overland. However, it is wise to procure an itinerary from a travel agent to avoid problems.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adults travelling alone with children should be aware that they may be required to produce documentary evidence of parental responsibility before entering the country. Bring paperwork just in case.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A visa on arrival costs approximately US$35, depending on your nationality. If you obtain a visa in advance, it costs around US$50, but again this varies according to nationality.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are usually valid for 30 days. If you obtain a visa in advance from the embassy, it's generally valid for a 30-day stay within two months of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy), or an officially recognised tour operator. You can also obtain visas from the Laos Embassy in Bangkok or from numerous travel agents on the Khao San Road in Bangkok.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s unlikely that you will be asked to provide proof, but just in case bring your last few bank statements, tax returns or salary slips.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend your 30-day tourist visa up to an additional 60 days for a fee of US$2 per day through the Department of Immigration in Vientiane,. If you overstay you&rsquo;ll have to pay US$10 a day on exit for every day over.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Laos requires a veterinary certificate for entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[19.073986]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[103.361004]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>236,800 sq km (91,400 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6,918,367 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>29.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vientiane.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>People's Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Laos is a landlocked country encircled to the north by China, to the south by Cambodia, Vietnam to the east, to the west by Thailand along with a 235km-long (146 miles) Mekong River border with Burma.</p>
<p>Apart from the Mekong River plains, along the border to Thailand, the country is mountainous, particularly in the north, and in places is densely forested. The western border is demarcated by the Mekong River &ndash; which along with the tributaries covers about 20% of the land mass.</p>
<p>Laos is mainly mountainous, with steep terrain, tapered river valleys. The mountains stretch across the north, except for around Vientiane and the Plain of Jars in Xiangkhoang  Province. These mountains are sparsely populated by tribal minorities who traditionally have not acknowledged the border with Vietnam any more than lowland Lao have been constrained by the 1,754km (1,090 miles) Mekong River border with Thailand. Thus, ethnic minority populations are found on both the Laotian and Vietnamese sides of the frontier. Because of their relative isolation, contact between these groups and lowland Lao has been mostly confined to trading. Migration and conflict have affected the ethnic structure of the country and to the geographic distribution of its ethnic groups.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the Lao people are Buddhists. The Laos-Lum (Valley Laos) people follow the Hinayana(Theravada) form of Buddhism. The religions of the Laos-Theung (Laos of the mountain tops) range from traditional Confucianism to animism and Christianity.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Religious beliefs should be respected. Lao people should not be touched on the head and women should not touch monks. Handshaking is not that usual; Lao people greet each other with their palms together and a slight bowing of the head. Take care when discussing politics and related subjects in conversation so as not to cause offence.</p>
<p>Laos is a Buddhist country and guests should dress accordingly. Shorts or revealing clothes are never acceptable. For women, sarongs work well in the heat as do long-sleeved light cotton shirts. Shoes must be removed when entering a religious building or somebody's home. It is a legal requirement to carry an ID document or a passport, and fines for not having one for presentation on demand can be high. The Lao government prohibits sexual relationships, including sexual contact between foreign citizens and Lao nationals, except when the two parties have been married in accordance with Lao family law. Penalties for failing to register a relationship range from fines to imprisonment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with two round pins or two flat pins are most commonly used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Thongloun Sisoulith since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Bounnhang Vorachith since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In ancient history, Laos was a collection of scattered tribal communities and little written record of this early period survives. Most of what we know follows the Chinese invasion of Laos during the 4th and 5th centuries. After the Chinese, the next foreign power to gain influence over Laos was the Hindu Khmer Empire, which spread across the country before founding its capital at Angkor in neighbouring <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cambodia">Cambodia</a>.</p>
<p>During this period, the previously dominant Chinese were displaced by a massive influx of ethnic Tai peoples from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/thailand">Thailand</a> and Hinduism slowly gave way to Buddhism. The Khmer Empire eventually collapsed into warring city-states, paving the way for the independent kingdom of Lan Xang, founded in 1353 at Luang Prabang.</p>
<p>Populated by a mixture of ethnic Laos, Thais and various hill tribes, the Lan Xang Empire lasted for three centuries, fighting off successive invasion attempts from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vietnam">Vietnam</a>, Siam (Thailand) and Burma. Internal power struggles in the 18th century were exploited by its neighbours, notably Thailand, which finally conquered Vientiane in 1779, absorbing southern Laos into the Kingdom of Siam.</p>
<p>The Siamese were the dominant power until the arrival of the French in the 1870s. Joining Cambodia and Vietnam, Laos became part of French Indo-China, and colonial administration saw plantations established across the country. The Japanese occupation in WWII weakened French control and Laos finally achieved independence in 1953.</p>
<p>The restoration of the monarchy under King Sisavang Vong was initially welcomed, but resistance grew, spearheaded by the fighters of the Pathet Lao and the Laotian Patriotic Front (LPF) the Pathet Lao, who were allied to communist forces in Vietnam. The Lao Civil War mirrored the Vietnam War, and vast quantities of ordnance were secretly dropped on Laos by the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> military to weaken the communist uprising.</p>
<p>When Vietnam adopted communism in 1975, Laos followed suit, abolishing the monarchy and redrawing the economy along austere communist lines. Laos became dependent on military and economic assistance from Vietnam, and other neighbours closed relations with the Lao regime, leading to more than a decade of isolation.</p>
<p>Tensions finally began to ease in the late 1980s, and Laos slowly opened up to the outside world. Today, the country is mostly at peace and the Lao People's Revolutionary Party (LPRP) remains firmly in control, though some rebel groups are still active. Despite limited political reforms in the 1990s, Laos still languishes behind its neighbours on most economic indexes.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Although Laos was never officially at war with America, more than 2 billion tons of bombs were dropped on the country by the US.  <br />
&bull;	Vientiane&rsquo;s famous Patuxai archway was funded by an American donation that was actually intended for the construction of a new airport!<br />
&bull;	The biggest Lao export is coffee, a legacy of the coffee plantations founded in the French colonial period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Lao People's Democratic Republic in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>0207 402 3770.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>0207 402 3770.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1800.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Embassy of the Lao PDR, 49 Porchester Terrace<br/>London<br/>W2 3TS<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Lao People's Democratic Republic in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 6416.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.laoembassy.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 6416.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1630.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2222 S Street<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Laos &ndash; officially known as the Lao People's Democratic Republic &ndash; is one of the great travel frontiers; landlocked and mountainous, swamped by jungles and promising Indian Jones adventures in remote tribal villages and ancient Buddhist caves.</p>
<p>With Thailand on one side and Vietnam on the other, you might expect Laos to be commercial and crowded, but this is Asia&rsquo;s backwater, where life moves as slowly as the churning waters of the Mekong River, which forms the border with three countries &ndash; Myanmar, Thailand and Cambodia &ndash; as it snakes south towards the Gulf of Thailand.</p>
<p>A long-running civil war &ndash; during which the USA dropped millions of bombs in Laos &ndash; kept the country off the mainstream tourist circuit for many years. Unexploded ordnance and poor infrastructure continue to pose a challenge to tourism, but each year brings a new crop of upmarket accommodation to supplement the existing backpacker hostels &ndash; Laos&nbsp;is finally finding its feet. Eco-tourism looks set to be its trump card, taking visitors to remote tribal villages and pristine national parks teeming with weird and wonderful wildlife.</p>
<p>Despite this rugged outlook, the capital city, Vientiane, feels remarkably cosmopolitan, helped by a caf&eacute; culture left behind from when this was part of French Indochina. Dotted around its pleasantly faded, palm-shaded streets are ancient ruins, gleaming stupas and graceful colonial buildings.</p>
<p>The laidback atmosphere and the relative lack of modern development make Laos perhaps the most authentic and unspoiled of the Southeast Asia nations, though it competes for this title with neighbouring Myanmar. Laos is also one of the few communist countries left in the world &ndash; which should be obvious from the bureaucratic red tape and the omnipresent red stars on uniforms and state buildings.</p>
<p>Until 1988, tourists were banned from Laos, but now it is possible to travel all over the country. Nevertheless, there are few crowded tourist hotspots, with the possible exception of monastery-studded Luang Prabang and the overblown backpacker resort of Vang Vieng. Wherever you go in Laos, you&rsquo;ll encounter the delectable Lao cuisine: a little bit French, a little bit Southeast Asian, and perfect washed down with a bottle of Beer Lao.</p><p>Laos &ndash; officially known as the Lao People's Democratic Republic &ndash; is one of the great travel frontiers; landlocked and mountainous, swamped by jungles and promising Indian Jones adventures in remote tribal villages and ancient Buddhist caves.</p>
<p>With Thailand on one side and Vietnam on the other, you might expect Laos to be commercial and crowded, but this is Asia&rsquo;s backwater, where life moves as slowly as the churning waters of the Mekong River, which forms the border with three countries &ndash; Myanmar, Thailand and Cambodia &ndash; as it snakes south towards the Gulf of Thailand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
