<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Latvia" ColCode="lva" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="lv" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Latvia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To the west, the Latvian coast benefits from a maritime climate, while the hinterland in the east has a continental climate. Between June and September, days are pleasantly warm and often sunny. Winters are long and harsh, with temperatures in Riga rarely rising above freezing between December and March. Even in April they can be as low as 5&ordm;C. Rainfall is distributed throughout the year with the heaviest rainfall in August. Snowfall is common in the winter months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Light to medium weight clothes are worn during summer months. Medium to heavyweight clothes are needed during spring and autumn, and heavyweights for the bitterly cold winter. Rainwear is advisable all year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Latvia is small enough to get around without the need for domestic flights. There is one domestic route with airBaltic from Riga to Liepaja.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Boat hire and tours are possible in some areas, with the most popular being the Gauja River in the Vidzeme province. Raft, canoe and kayak rentals are commonly found near river accommodation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Latvia's rail network connects Riga to all other major towns and cities in the country, including Liepaja and Ventspils in the west, Daugavpils in the southeast, Gulbene and Rezekne in the east. The railway terminal in Riga is at Stacijas laukums.</p>
<p>For more information about the train services, including timetables, routes and bookings, contact Pasažieru vilciens (tel: +371 6723 2135; <a href="http://www.pv.lv" target="_blank">www.pv.lv</a>), or Latvijas dzelzceļ&scaron; (tel: 8000 1181, in Latvia only or +371 6723 1181; <a href="http://www.ldz.lv/" target="_blank">www.ldz.lv</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Latvia is not covered by InterRail or Eurail passes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The minimum driving age in Latvia is 18, but you must be 21 to hire a car.</p>r<p>Latvia's road network is reasonably extensive; however, road quality varies considerably from sealed roads to rough tracks strewn with potholes.</p><p>Taxis are plentiful and easy enough to flag down in Riga and other main cities. As anywhere in the world, use licensed taxis and check the meter is running.</p><p>European nationals should be in possession of an EU licence, otherwise an International Driving Permit is required. Third-party insurance is compulsory. Insurance and vehicle registration documents, as well as your licence, should be kept with you when driving.</p><p>Seat belt use is compulsory in the front and back. Headlights must be used at all times. Unless otherwise indicated, speed limits are 50kph (32mph) in towns and 90kph (56mph) on highways.</p>
<p>The use of mobile telephones while driving is forbidden. Mobile speed traps are common.</p><p>LAMB<em> </em>(tel: 1888, in Latvia only; <a href="http://www.lamb.lv/" target="_blank">www.lamb.lv</a>) offers free or discounted breakdown cover to cardholders.</p><p>Available in all major cities. The minimum age for hiring a car is 21. At the airport in Riga, there are several international car rental companies, including Budget (tel: +371 6720 7327; <a href="http://www.budget.lv" target="_blank">www.budget.lv</a>) and Europcar (tel: +371 6722 2637; <a href="https://www.europcar.lv/" target="_blank">www.europcar.lv</a>).</p><p>Riga has a bike-share system operated by Sixt (tel: +371 6767 6780; <a href="http://www.sixtbicycle.lv" target="_blank">www.sixtbicycle.lv</a>). The rental scheme offers more than 250 bikes in around two dozen conveniently accessed spots and is available 24/7.</p><p>Seat belt use is compulsory in the front and back. Headlights must be used at all times. Unless otherwise indicated, speed limits are 50kph (32mph) in towns and 90kph (56mph) on highways.</p>
<p>The use of mobile telephones while driving is forbidden. Mobile speed traps are common.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good network of bus, tram and trolleybus routes in Riga (tel: +371 8000 1919;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.rigassatiksme.lv" target="_blank">www.rigassatiksme.lv</a>), while buses and a single tramline operate in Liepaja. Tickets can be bought on board from the conductor and should be retained for inspection. Fines for fare dodging are common. E-tickets are also available for purchase through Riga&rsquo;s transportation website, making your trip more convenient (<a href="https://www.rigassatiksme.lv/en/tickets-and-e-ticket/" target="_blank">www.rigassatiksme.lv</a>).</p>
<p><em>Taksobussi </em>(share-taxis) also operate, but are slightly more expensive than ordinary buses. Regular taxis are privately run and have meters; there is a surcharge at night. There are some trams and trolleybuses running through the night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Latvia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ventspils</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Latvia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">liepaja</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.09</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Latvia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">jurmala</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Latvia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cesis</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.50</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Latvia's national carrier is airBaltic<em> </em>(<a href="http://www.airbaltic.com/" target="_blank">www.airbaltic.com</a>), which runs direct flights to the UK, among other destinations. Other airlines flying non-stop to Latvia from the UK include Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) and the Hungarian company Wizz Air  (<a href="http://www.wizzair.com" target="_blank">www.wizzair.com</a>).&nbsp;</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/latvia/riga-international-airport">Riga International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 40 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 10 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a> - 2 hours 45 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/frankfurt">Frankfurt</a> - 2 hours 5 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Liepaja International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Riga International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.riga-airport.com<p>Riga International Airport is situated 11 km (7 miles) west of central Riga.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+371 2931 1817.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Riga is a major Baltic port with a sea link to  <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/stockholm">Stockholm</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sweden">Sweden</a>. Other ports in Latvia also service water traffic from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a> and Sweden.</p><p>Those travelling with a Eurail pass are entitled to a substantial discount on the Tallink Silja ferry route between Stockholm and Riga.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Riga has rail links with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-petersburg">St Petersburg</a> in Russia, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tallinn">Tallinn</a> and Valga in Estonia, Minsk in Belarus and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vilnius">Vilnius</a> in Lithuania.</p>
<p>Latvijas Dzelzceļ&scaron; (Latvian Railways) (tel: 8000 1181, in Latvia only or + 371 6723 1181; <a href="http://www.ldz.lv" target="_blank">www.ldz.lv</a>) is the national rail operator.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Latvia is not covered by InterRail or Eurail passes (but the latter does give you a discount on some ferry routes to Latvia).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Entry by car is possible from Russia, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/estonia">Estonia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belarus">Belarus</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lithuania">Lithuania</a>. The Via Baltica highway runs through the Baltic countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Payphones are operated by phonecards which can be purchased at kiosks, post offices and in some shops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good. Purchasing a SIM card with a local plan can help avoid expensive roaming charges if you are spending extended time in Latvia. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many Internet cafes in Riga and some in other towns. Most, if not all, accommodation will provide guests with Wi-Fi access.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public radio and TV are financed by state subsidies and advertising revenue. The media operate freely, with few legal restrictions on their work. There are laws against libel and incitement of racial hatred.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post boxes are yellow. Mail delivery within Europe takes two to seven days, to America and Australia 9 to 13 days.&nbsp;<em>Riga Central Post Office</em>is located at Stacijas laukums (next to the main railway station), opening hours: Mon-Fri 0700-2100, Sat 0900-2000, Sun 1000-2000.</p><p>(General, main) Mon-Fri 0700/0800-1800/1900, Sat 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Rundāle Palace</p><![CDATA[<p>It may not be on the same scale as St Petersburg's Hermitage, but Rastrelli's Rundāle Palace is equally handsome. A visit to this opulent baroque and rococo masterpiece is a must. Located 79km (49 miles) south of Riga, Rundāle Palace and Museum nestles near the town of Bauska. Built as a summer residence for the Duke of Courland Ernst Johann Biron by the Italian architect Francesco Bartolomeo Rastrelli, the opulent palace was completed in 1768. The palace was given to the Republic of Latvia in 1920 as a part of agrarian reform. It was in a rundown state back then, but a lengthy restoration completed in 2014 has returned much of Rundāle Palace to its former grandeur. Featuring the White Hall, the Great Gallery and the Duchess&rsquo;s rooms, Rundāle displays the magnificent work of German sculptors and Italian painters.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Basilica of Aglona</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A place of pilgrimage for Catholics from all over Latvia and beyond, this immense white cathedral near Daugavpils, with its twin spires, is worth visiting even if you are not religious (tel: + 371 2918 8740; <a href="http://www.aglona.travel" target="_blank">www.aglona.travel</a>). To see the basilica at its most atmospheric, visit during the Feast of the Assumption (15 August) when around 150,000 worshippers take part in a torch lit procession celebrating the Blessed Virgin Mary.</p>]]><p><b>Birdwatching in Pape</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Latvia's coast, wetlands and traditionally cultivated farmland attract significant populations of interesting and uncommon birds. Pape, near Liepāja along the Kurzeme coast, is on the migration route for seabirds, wildfowl and other species &ndash; 200 breeds total. It is also a haven for songbirds and raptors. Cape Kolka is another good spot for birdwatching. Local operators can arrange birdwatching trips upon request. For more information, contact the Latvian Ornithological Society (tel: + 371 6722 1580; <a href="http://www.lob.lv/" target="_blank">www.lob.lv</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Cape Kolka</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The windswept beach at Cape Kolka, part of the Slītere National Park, is a breathtaking spot where the Baltic Sea and the Gulf of Riga crash together. It&rsquo;s also a good place for a brisk walk along the shore and a great spot for birdwatching. The skyline features the wooden Kolka Lighthouse, originally set aglow in June 1875 and still luring visitors to the cape today (tel: +371 2914 9105; <a href="http://www.kolkasrags.lv" target="_blank">www.kolkasrags.lv</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Cēsis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Old wooden buildings, cobbled streets, attractive churches and impressive castles transport you back through layers of history in Cēsis (<a href="http://www.turisms.cesis.lv" target="_blank">www.turisms.cesis.lv</a>). One of Latvia's oldest towns, it was first inhabited in the 13th century. Cēsu, one of Latvia&rsquo;s best-known beers, has been brewed in the well-preserved medieval city since the 16th century. The town even has an annual arts festival that celebrates traditional and contemporary Latvian culture.</p>]]><p><b>Daugavpils Mark Rothko Centre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The great 20th century abstract expressionist painter Mark Rothko was born in Daugavpils, in southeast Latvia. The Daugavpils Mark Rothko Art Centre, housed in a renovated arsenal building dated 1833, is a multi-functional institution of culture, arts and education. Featuring the main exhibition &ldquo;Mark Rothko: Life and Art,&rdquo; the centre houses original Rothko works and shows a digital exposition on the artist&rsquo;s career. 2013 marked the 110th anniversary of Rothko's birth. (<a href="http://www.rothkocenter.com" target="_blank">www.rothkocenter.com</a>)</p>]]><p><b>Ethnographic Open-Air Museum of Latvia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Just outside Riga and alongside Lake Jugla is the Ethnographic Open-Air Museum of Latvia (tel: +317 6799 4106; <a href="http://www.brivdabasmuzejs.lv" target="_blank">www.brivdabasmuzejs.lv</a>). Established in 1924, it is one of the oldest and best preserved outdoor museums in Europe. It boasts historical dwellings, workers' homesteads, a tavern and windmills, all gathered from across Latvia. Masters of 18 different crafts demonstrate their work at this artisan community.</p>]]><p><b>Fly high in Sigulda</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The cable car from Sigulda to Krimulda features a birds-eye view of the Gauja River Gorge. For adrenaline junkies, bungee jumping can be arranged from the cable car when it stops some 42m above the river itself (tel: +371 2838 3333; <a href="http://bungee.lv/en/" target="_blank">www.bungee.lv</a>). Krimulda also has a ruined castle and a sprawling landscape that can be absorbed on the seven-minute aerial ride (tel: +371 2802 0088; <a href="http://cablecar.lv/en/" target="_blank">www.cablecar.lv</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Freedom Monument</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Not only is this vaulting statue at the heart of Riga, it also commemorates the hardships that Latvian citizens have endured over the years and serves as a poignant symbol of nationhood. That it survived communist rule at all is a miracle. It stands over 42m tall and is topped by the figure of a woman holding three gold stars, symbolizing Latvia&rsquo;s three cultural regions: Kurzeme, Latgale and Vidzeme.</p>]]><p><b>Hiking in Gauja National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Latvia's national parks and protected areas boast myriads of hiking trails. Gauja is the country's biggest and oldest national park, covering an area of nearly 900 sq km (340 sq miles) around the River Gauja. It features caves, rocks and dense woods, and plenty of wildlife. One of the most popular trails is the 5km Līgatne nature trail, where visitors can see many species of wild mammals native to Latvia (tel: +371 2832 8800; <a href="http://www.visitligatne.lv/ligatnes-dabas-takas?lang=eng" target="_blank">www.visitligatne.lv</a>). Visit in spring if you want to see the mass of wild cherry trees blooming along the Gauja River valley. Latvia has four national parks &ndash; the others are Ķemeri, Slītere and Rāzna (the country&rsquo;s newest).</p>]]><p><b>Kuldiga</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This attractive town proudly promotes itself as the home of Europe's widest waterfall. While the gushing torrent is impressive when the Venta River runs high, Kuldiga (<a href="http://www.visit.kuldiga.lv/en/">www.visit.kuldiga.lv</a>) is an attractive historic settlement well worth exploring year-round. The city also hosts a &ldquo;traditional nude run&rdquo; every Summer Solstice.</p>]]><p><b>Latvian Song and Dance Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Held only once every five years and dating back to 1873, the Latvian Song and Dance Festival is one of the country&rsquo;s greatest musical and cultural events. Along with the Song and Dance festivals in neighbouring Estonia and Lithuania, this week-long celebration is inscribed on the UNESCO list of Intangible Cultural Heritage. From vibrant folk costumes to intricate choreography and harmonies, the event combines the talent of some 30,000 dancers, singers, artists and musicians.</p>]]><p><b>Liepaja</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Its old town buildings may be a little faded but Liepaja (<a href="http://www.liepaja.lv/" target="_blank">www.liepaja.lv</a>) still boasts attractive architecture, including many art nouveau buildings. It has the largest concentration of preserved wooden houses in Latvia, some dating back as far as the 17th or 18th centuries. The real highlights, though, are its seaside park and sandy EU Blue Flag beach. In Karosta, a former Russian naval base, you can take a tour of a KGB prison museum (tel: +371 2636 9470; <a href="http://karostascietums.lv/en/" target="_blank">www.karostascietums.lv</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Riga's art nouveau architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Riga boasts one of the finest collections of art nouveau buildings in the world, accounting for around a third of the properties in the city centre. Riga is also famous for its old town, which has been declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site. With its attention to detail and push toward modern design, Riga&rsquo;s art nouveau buildings are an architectural site to behold. Be sure to stroll down Alberta Street and visit Riga&rsquo;s Art Nouveau Centre (tel: +371 6718 1464; <a href="http://www.jugendstils.riga.lv/eng" target="_blank">www.jugendstils.riga.lv</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Skyline Bar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The chic, 26th-floor Skyline Bar at the Radisson Blu Hotel Latvija (tel: +371 6777 2282; <a href="https://www.radissonblu.com/en/latvijahotel-riga/bars" target="_blank">www.radissonblu.com</a>) offers epic 360-degree views over Riga. The same dramatic views can even be enjoyed from the toilets. An extensive drinks menu with over 100 cocktails complements the vistas, and weekend DJ performances feature the newest dance music.</p>]]><p><b>Spas in Jūrmala</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spa holidays are all the rage in Latvia, especially in Jūrmala (tel: +371 6714 7900; <a href="https://www.visitjurmala.lv/en/plan/spa-and-medicine/" target="_blank">www.visitjurmala.lv</a>). The ever-growing number of spa hotels in this Baltic resort are backed up by a seemingly endless sandy beach. Indulge in an aromatherapy massage or something a bit more unusual, like a salt chamber.</p>]]><p><b>Stay in the land of the Blue Lakes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s possible to rent log cabins amidst the Latgale forest, which boasts 2,000 of Latvia&rsquo;s 3,000 total lakes. Some properties are located next to lakes where the hearty can take a swim, while others have their own saunas. The peaceful retreat of &ldquo;Laimavoti&rdquo; &ndash; meaning the spring of happiness &ndash; offers an intimate look at Latvia&rsquo;s natural beauty (tel: +371 2755 9999; <a href="http://www.laimavoti.lv/en/" target="_blank">www.laimavoti.lv</a>).  Built on a peninsula and surrounded by Cārmanis lake, the resort sits along the borders of Belarus and Russia.</p>]]><p><b>Turaida Museum Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Latvia's most popular attractions throngs with tourists and Latvian school children who come to ramble around Turaida Castle, one of the country&rsquo;s most attractive citadels. There are striking views over the Gauja National Park from its ramparts, while the landscaped grounds boast several oversized esoteric sculptures. It was specially commended in the European Museum of the Year Awards in 1996 (tel: +371 6797 2376;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.turaida-muzejs.lv" target="_blank">www.turaida-muzejs.lv</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Watersports on the Gauja River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The winding Gauja River in beautiful Gauja National Park offers plenty of opportunities for watersports, from white-water kayaking to river rafting. Anyone seeking an extended watery adventure can stay at one of the national park's 23 campsites. In the Strenči district of Gauja, Latvians hold an annual Raftsmen Festival that includes two days of rafting and an immersive cultural history of the area. For more information, visit Latvia&rsquo;s tourism board on water activities (<a href="http://www.latvia.travel/en/article/water-tourism-latvia" target="_blank">www.latvia.travel</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$ 27.68 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Timber and wood products, foodstuffs, machinery and equipment, metals and textiles.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, chemicals, fuels and land vehicles.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Lithuania, Estonia, Russia and Poland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Latvia's transitional economy recovered from the 1998 Russian financial crisis, largely due to the government's strict budget and effort to move exports toward EU countries, easing Latvia's trade dependency on Russia. Most companies, banks and properties have been privatised, although the state is still involved in a few large enterprises.</p>
<p>Latvia officially joined the World Trade Organisation in 1999. EU membership, a top foreign policy goal, as well as NATO membership, came in May 2004. </p>
<p>The global financial crisis in 2008 saw unemployment in Latvia soar from 7% in 2008 to 22% in 2009. High levels of inflation (reaching 17.7% in 2008) delayed Latvia adopting the Euro, but in 2014 the country was finally accepted into the Eurozone. Since 2012, Latvia's economic growth rate has been one of the fastest among the EU member states. With a spike in international trade and an entrepreneurial attitude, Latvia ranked 20th in the 2017 global index of economic freedom.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business cards are exchanged. Appointments should be arranged in advance. In general, business is conducted in a fairly formal manner.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Dress code is relatively formal, for men and women, with suit and tie or a smart outfit expected for business meetings. However, new technology-based industries have joined the trend of dressing down in more casual gear. Handshakes are the normal way to start any meeting. Gifts are not expected, but a small gift representing your country or business are accepted.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In a nation with a high per capita rate of alcohol consumption, most evening meetings and dinners, and indeed many lunches, are peppered with alcoholic drinks. Business hours are normally Monday to Friday 0830-1730. The old Soviet era tendency to turn public holidays into an excuse for two or three days off work seems to be waning.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Association of Latvian Travel Agents</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 6721 0065.
					Website:http://www.alta.net.lv
					Address: ,Skolas iela 3-201,Riga,]]><b>Latvian Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 6722 5595
					Website:http://www.chamber.lv
					Address: ,Kr. Valdemāra iela 35,Riga,]]><b>Investment and Development Agency of Latvia (LIAA)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 6703 9400
					Website:http://www.liaa.gov.lv
					Address: ,Pērses iela 2,Riga,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Influenced by food from surrounding countries, Latvian cuisine is largely based upon meat and locally available crops. Dishes tend to be hearty and filling &ndash; which helps when the thermometer plummets. Red meat is a mainstay on menus, and it comes served as mouth-watering patties, fried in breadcrumbs or in warming stews.</p>
<p>Along the coast, fish forms a bigger part of the diet &ndash; smoked fish is a speciality. Herring is often pickled and served cold. Potatoes (particularly potato salad), sauerkraut and other vegetables are traditional accompaniments. There are a number of very tasty, distinctive soups. Many of the ingredients are seasonal &ndash; with mushrooms, berries, nettles and the like being picked at certain times of the year.</p>
<p>International restaurants abound in Riga. Every May, the city hosts a Spring Restaurant Week that offers plenty of opportunities to try Latvian cuisine. Meals are typically filling and often washed down with Latvian beer or strong liquor. There are also some wonderful fruit juices made from wild berries. One of the best places to get an appreciation of local ingredients is the massive and colourful central market in Riga, housed in several former zeppelin hangers.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Kotletes </em>(meat patties).</p>
<p><em>&bull; Zupa </em>(soup) &ndash; try beet soup or sorrel soup (<em>Skābeņu zupa</em>).</p>
<p>&bull; <em>Alexander Torte</em> (raspberry or cranberry-filled pastry strips). </p>
<p><em>&bull; Pīrāgi </em>(pastry filled with bacon and onions).</p>
<p><em>&bull; Rupjmaize </em>(dark rye bread).</p>
<p><em>&bull; Rasols </em>(potato salad with eggs, gherkins, and perhaps bacon, sausage and other ingredients).</p>
<p><em>&bull; Jāņu siers</em> (cheese with caraway seeds, traditionally served at midsummer solstice celebrations).</p>
<p><em>&bull; Karbonāde </em>(breaded pork chops).</p>
<p><em>&bull; Sauerkraut </em>(Latvian version of this well-known dish).</p>
<p><em>&bull; Kartupeļu pankūkas </em>(potato pancakes).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Drinking (or possessing an open bottle/can of alcohol) in streets, parks and other public places is forbidden in Riga and carries a hefty fine. Nightclubs allow ages 18 and older to enter, and the same age restriction applies to alcohol consumption.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Restaurant bills usually include a tip. It is customary to give a little extra for good service.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Riga's nightlife is legendary, particularly in the summer months when pubs and bars spill out onto narrow cobbled streets and terraces. Duck into a small local bar in Riga&rsquo;s old town centre, or head up to the famous Skyline Bar with its 360-degree panoramic views of the Latvian capital.</p>
<p>Nightclubs offer a varied scene, from dancing all night to blues concerts, and range in size from enormous dance floors with popular DJs to local laidback hangouts. The capital also has a few strip and lap-dancing clubs. There are also LGBT-friendly clubs in the area.</p>
<p>Throughout the year, Riga plays host to an enormous variety of events, concerts and festivals. If you need help navigating the party scene in the city, there are several agencies offering nightlife tours.</p>
<p>At the height of summer, holiday resorts such as Jūrmala are lively. Big cities like Daugavpils, Ventspils and Liepaja also have an array of drinking venues, though in general these are not so geared towards tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Long associated with the Baltics, Amber (<em>dzintars</em> in Latvian) is of high quality in Latvia and often good value. Other typical souvenirs include folk art, linen, locally made silver, colourful knitwear, wickerwork and ceramics. Latvia&rsquo;s consumable specialities include beer, Black Balsam, Jāņi cheese, honey and sweets treats such as &lsquo;edible amber&rsquo;, tinned Riga sprats and locally made chocolates.</p>
<p>Riga is one of the easiest places to find souvenirs and the main market, held inside old zeppelin hangers, is well worth a visit. Sigulda and the surrounding area is good for finding woodwork, while in Cēsis visitors should drop by the Smithy of Ancient Jewellery that sells traditional Latvian jewellery.</p>
<p>The Latgale region in the southeast of the country has a long tradition of pottery making. As well as the wonderful main market, there are several large shopping centres in Riga, including Galerija Centrs, Origo and craft fairs at the Open-Air Ethnographical Museum.</p>
<p>Passengers flying to a country outside the EU can claim a tax refund at the airport. Only shops displaying 'Tax-Free' stickers participate in the scheme. These will (if asked) give you a Global Refund cheque. A minimum spend in any one shop in a single day is required. In addition, you need to keep the original receipt and goods should be unopened.</p><p>Opening hours are typically Mon-Fri 0900/1000-1800/1900 and Sat 0900/1000-1600/1700. Some smaller shops may close for an hour or two between 1200 and 1500 for lunch. Food shops tend to open Mon-Sat 0800/0900-2000/2100. Some shops are open 24 hours.</p><p>You need a special permit to take high-value works of art, antiques and cultural objects out of Latvia. The restriction is currently defined as any object older than 50 years and with a value over &euro;42,686.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The standard of hotel accommodation in Latvia is generally high, with major international chains, boutique properties, spa hotels and family run businesses all part of the mix. Riga has the broadest range of hotel accommodation.</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The standard of hotel accommodation in Latvia is generally high, with major international chains, boutique properties, spa hotels and family run businesses all part of the mix. Riga has the broadest range of hotel accommodation.</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The standard of hotel accommodation in Latvia is generally high, with major international chains, boutique properties, spa hotels and family run businesses all part of the mix. Riga has the broadest range of hotel accommodation.</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;For European visitors who are taken ill or have an accident, free or reduced-cost treatment is available - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). The EHIC gives access to state-provided medical treatment only. Note that the EHIC replaces the Form E111, which is no longer valid.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p/><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Declaration of Independence Day :
							04 May </p><p>Ligo (Midsummer's Eve) :
							23 June </p><p>Jani (St John's Day) :
							24 June </p><p>Independence Day :
							18 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p><p>New Year's Eve :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Latvia is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragrance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% volume, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Latvia by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco (if arriving by air).<br />
&bull; 40 cigarettes or 20 cigarillos or 10 cigars or 50g of tobacco (if arriving by road, rail or water).<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;400 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers (reduced to &euro;285 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Meat and dairy products from outside the EU, narcotics, counterfeit goods, and unlicensed firearms and ammunition.</p>
<p>The import of plants and plant products from outside the EU is restricted and in some cases prohibited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must obtain a permit from the State Inspection for Heritage Protection to export art and antiques which are more than 50 years old.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In January 2014 Latvia adopted the Euro. 1 Euro (EUR; symbol &euro;) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bureaux de change are found all over main towns, including inside shops, hotels, post offices and train stations. These tend to close at 1900. The most convenient currency to exchange is the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, JCB, MasterCard and Visa are accepted by most hotels, restaurants and shops.</p><p>ATMs are available in towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most retailers in Latvia won&rsquo;t accept traveller's cheques and banks may charge to cash them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700. Some banks are open Sat 0900-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals of a few countries require a transit visa even if staying in the international transit area of the airport; check with the embassy for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Latvia is a member of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60/&pound;48. Reductions are available for some nationals and for children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate (or consular section at embassy). UK residents requiring a visa should submit applications to VFS Global's Latvia Visa Application Centre in London, Manchester or Edinburgh (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/Latvia/UK/" target="_blank">www.vfsglobal.com/Latvia/UK</a>). VFS charges an additional service fee of &pound;24.&nbsp;All visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow up to 10 working days for visa processing; certain cases may take up to 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa applicants need to show proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For stays over 90 days, EU nationals must register with the Office of Citizenship and Migration Affairs (tel: +371 6758 8675; <a href="http://www.pmlp.gov.lv/en/" target="_blank">www.pmlp.gov.lv</a>). Non-EU citizens must obtain a residence permit.</p>
<p>Holders of Schengen visas can only extend their visas in exceptional circumstances such as&nbsp;<em>force majeure&nbsp;</em>or for humanitarian reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet into Latvia, you must have an internationally recognised veterinary certificate in Latvian, English or Russian and an up-to-date vaccination record.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[56.869023]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[24.841002]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>64,589 sq km (24,938 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,937,944&nbsp;(UN estimate 2018).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>30 per sq km (77 people/sq mile).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Riga.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parliamentary Republic</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Latvia is situated on the Baltic coast and borders Estonia in the north, Lithuania in the south, the Russian Federation in the east and Belarus in the southeast. The country is divided into five broad regions: Riga in the north, Kurzeme and Zemgale in the west and Vidzeme and Latgale in the east.</p>
<p>The country is reasonably flat. A long sandy coastline is backed in places by undulating sand dunes and low sea cliffs. In Latgale, in the east, the landscape is noticeably different with rolling hills and myriad lakes. Wherever you are in Latvia you don't have to travel far to find dense forest. In addition the country boasts about 12,000 rivers. Latvia's longest river, the Daugava runs through Riga. Meanwhile, the Gauja River is at the heart of the country's best-known nature reserve, the Gauja National Park.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Majority Lutheran and Catholic, with a sizeable Russian Orthodox minority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is customary when meeting someone for the first time. Latvians can be reserved and formal, but nevertheless very hospitable. They can also be quite direct, but do not generally mean to cause offence. Latvians are proud of their culture, and visitors should respect this strong sense of national identity.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nominated Prime Minister Jānis Bordāns&nbsp;since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Raimonds Vējonis&nbsp;since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Latvia has, like neighbouring Estonia and Lithuania, been an important trading centre and strategic pawn in the Baltic region. The various Latvian tribes were self-governing until the end of the 13th century when Teutonic knights conquered the territory. Latvia was then subject to sporadic invasions by the Poles and the Swedes until the 18th century when Russia, under Peter the Great, emerged as a major European power.</p>
<p>The entire territory of modern Latvia was under Russian control from 1795 until 1918, when the Latvian National Council proclaimed it a free state. That freedom didn&rsquo;t last long though, and in 1940 the country was invaded by the Soviets. Nazi forces displaced them the following year before the Red Army invaded once again in 1944 when Latvia was incorporated into the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Protests against Soviet control and the campaign for democracy and independence began in 1986 and gathered pace with the formation of the Popular Front of Latvia in 1988. The Latvian parliament declared independence on 4 May 1990, a day still marked as a national holiday. Full independence was finally achieved following a referendum in 1991, with Latvia being admitted into the UN in September 1991.</p>
<p>Latvia joined NATO in 2004 and was admitted into the EU &ndash; along with nine other states, including Estonia and Lithuania &ndash; later the same year. The Lat, Latvia&rsquo;s currency since 1993, was then replaced by the Euro in January 2014.</p>
<p>The suppression of the Latvian language and culture during the Soviet era has left a legacy of hostility &ndash; in some areas the ethnic Russian minority are subject to discrimination and, although there has been no serious conflict between the communities, it remains a delicate issue.</p>
<p>The capital, Riga, was founded as a trading post in 1201 and has preserved many aspects of its long history, with architectural styles spanning eight centuries and a historic old town that was declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 1997. Riga was named European Capital of Culture in 2014 and remains an enticing destination for tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Latvia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 328 2840.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mfa.gov.lv</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 328 2840.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon: 1300-1600, Tues/Thurs: 1000-1300, closed Wed/Fri/Sat-Sun.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2306 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Latvia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7312 0041</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.am.gov.lvw</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7312 0041</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Opening hours: Mon-Fri 1000-1600&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Marylebone<br/>45 Nottingham Place<br/>London<br/>W1U 5LY<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Officially known as the Republic of Latvia, this small nation remained tucked behind the Iron Curtain until the early nineties. Today it is one of the most visited countries in the Baltics and lures visitors with its dramatic landscapes, rich heritage and vibrant capital, Riga.</p>
<p>Declared European Capital of Culture in 2014, the city has one of the most impressive collections of art nouveau buildings in the world, not to mention a stunning UNESCO World Heritage downtown. The latter is home to medieval churches, grand Renaissance properties and a spectacular market, which is held inside defunct zeppelin hangers from WWI. The old town is dominated by Riga Cathedral, the largest medieval church in the Baltics and one of many attractions in Riga vying for visitors&rsquo; attention.</p>
<p>The path beyond Riga is, for now, not quite so well-trodden. However, riches await those pressing further into the country; there&rsquo;s the rural paradise of Rundāle Palace, the recently renovated Turaida Stone Castle and the charming Latvian Ethnographic Open-Air Museum. The beautifully preserved historic towns of Kuldīga and Cēsis also warrant excursions.</p>
<p>Latvia is rich in natural attractions, too, like the Gulf of Riga and the windswept coastline along the Baltic Sea, which is home to seemingly infinite sandy shores. Jūrmala, a resort town just 40 minutes from Riga, boasts 26km (16 miles) of golden beaches lined with spas, thermal mud pools and seafood restaurants.</p>
<p>Inland, national parks and nature reserves abound, but Gauja National Park is the most famous. This picturesque river valley is a place of unremitting beauty: rushing rivers, ancient sandstone cliffs and, in spring, masses of white cherry blossoms. Gauja National Park is not only great for hiking, cycling and watersports, but also offers one of the best birdwatching sites in Latvia, after Pape and Cape Kolka.</p>
<p>While low cost air travel has opened Latvia to the masses, most visitors still struggle to venture beyond the capital. However, those who do find treasure in this country will, as the tourist board likes to say, discover it is &ldquo;best enjoyed slowly.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><p>Officially known as the Republic of Latvia, this small nation remained tucked behind the Iron Curtain until the early nineties. Today it is one of the most visited countries in the Baltics and lures visitors with its dramatic landscapes, rich heritage and vibrant capital, Riga.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
