<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Lebanon" ColCode="lbn" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="lb" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Lebanon]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon has a typically Mediterranean climate. There are four distinct seasons. Summer (June to September) is hot on the coast and cooler in the mountains. Spring and autumn are warm and pleasant and are the ideal times to visit for sightseeing. Winter (December to mid March) is mostly rainy, with snow in the mountains so this is the ideal time to visit to enjoy winter sports, but at lower altitudes sightseeing can be hindered by heavy rainfall.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight fabrics such as cotton and linen are best for the summer months and warm clothes for the winter period with rain protection or thermal clothing for higher altitudes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no internal flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Speed limit signs, traffic police and traffic lights are present but may not always be respected and driving, particularly in Beirut, can be quite unpredictable. As public transport is limited, roads in Beirut are severely congested. The worst times for traffic jams are 0730-0930 and 1630-1900.</p>r<p>Intercity coaches operate from each of the three bus stations in and around Beirut depending on their final destination.</p><p>Intercity taxis operate throughout Beirut and Lebanon. Travel is normally shared. Prices are negotiated in advance. Town taxis have red licence plates and an official tariff. There is a surcharge of 50% after 2200.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required. International permits must be certified by the authorities on arrival.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in urban areas and 100kph (62mph) on major highways.</p><p>Most car hire companies provide rescue services. Sodopex (SOS Auto) (tel: +961 4 400 678) offers independent rescue services, or you can contact the Ministry of Tourism for other operators.</p><p>Self-drive cars are available, but chauffeur-driven vehicles are recommended; check with the Ministry of Tourism. The major car hire companies all have offices in Beirut. Visitors planning to drive in Lebanon should exercise extreme caution as driving standards are poor, accident rates are high and traffic light signals are frequently ignored. It should also be noted that petrol is very expensive in Lebanon.</p><p>Visitors planning to cycle should be aware that roads do not have cycle lanes and cyclists are rarely given priority. Due to the traffic congestion in Beirut, cycling should only be attempted by the very experienced. Cycle tours of Beirut are available - contact the Ministry of Tourism for details. There are many cycle paths and off-road cycling trails in nature reserves around the country.</p><p>Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in urban areas and 100kph (62mph) on major highways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public bus services are available in Beirut, although service taxis remain the most widely used option.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier is Middle East Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.mea.com.lb">www.mea.com.lb</a>), which operates direct flights from the UK to Beirut, as does British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>). The peak summer months and Christmas generally tend to be the most expensive times to fly.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lebanon/beirut-rafic-hariri-international-airport">Beirut Rafic Hariri International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 4 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 12 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Beirut&rsquo;s Rafic Hariri Airport is 7km (4 miles) from the centre of the city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Beirut&rsquo;s Rafic Hariri Airport is 7km (4 miles) from the centre of the city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Beirut Rafic Hariri International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.beirutairport.gov.lb<p>Beirut Rafic Hariri International Airport is located 9km (6 miles) south of Beirut city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+961 1 628 000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Beirut  (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.portdebeyrouth.com/">www.portdebeyrouth.com</a>), Chekka, Jounieh, Tripoli, Sidon and Tyre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The British Foreign and Commonwealth Office advises against all travel to areas of Lebanon bordering Syria.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The border between Lebanon and Israel is closed. You may be refused entry to Lebanon if you have an Israeli stamp in your passport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Telephone booths are accessible for local and international calls. Payphone cards are available from post offices and kiosks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies and there is coverage througout the country. Cellular phones are widely used and are available for hire to visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafes in Beirut, Tripoli and most major towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's broadcasting scene is well developed and is generally representative of the country's diverse population. Lebanon was the first Arab country to permit private radio and television stations, but this is subject to government controls. Several stations are owned by leading politicians.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post to Europe and the USA usually takes from one to two weeks.</p><p>Opening hours vary. Check <a href="http://www.libanpost.com.lb" target="_blank">www.libanpost.com.lb</a> for individual branch opening times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Jeita caverns</p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the spectacular Jeita caverns, around 20km (13 miles) north of Beirut. On two levels, the lower gallery includes an underground waterway which can be visited by boat.</p>]]><br/><p>Tyre</p><![CDATA[<p>Often referred to in the Bible&rsquo;s New Testament, <em>Tyre</em> was founded at the start of the third millennium BC. The city experienced a golden age during the first millennium BC under Hiram, King of Tyre, but later suffered at the hands of its jealous enemies, including the King of Babylon in the sixth century BC, and Alexander the Great in 332 BC. Tyre eventually fell under Roman rule in 64 BC and during Roman Occupation, an acqueduct, triumphal arch and hippodrome were built. The impressive 480 metre (131ft) hippodrome, which once seated up to 20,000 spectators, is one of the main attractions. Tyre was declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 1979 and is one of the finest examples of architecture from the ancient world.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Al Mina</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy delicious Lebanese food in the port area of Al Mina, where many seafood restaurants and fish markets can be found.</p>]]><p><b>Al Shouf Cedar Nature Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's largest nature reserve is home to three large cedar forests, which combine to make up a quarter of the country's remaining cedar trees. As well as being home to an array of flora and fauna, the nature reserve is also criss-crossed with miles of hiking and biking trails.</p>]]><p><b>American University of Beirut</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the neo-Ottoman campus of the American University of Beirut in Hamra, which was founded in 1868 (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.aub.edu.lb/">www.aub.edu.lb</a>). It is also home to an archaeological museum housing an impressive collection of artefacts dating from the Stone Age to the Islamic periods. </p>]]><p><b>Archaeological sites</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the archaeological sites of Tyre (<a target="_blank" href="http://tyros.leb.net/tyre">http://tyros.leb.net/tyre</a>). Area one contains ruins of the large district of civic buildings, public baths and mosaic streets, whilst area two has an extensive network of Romano-Byzantine roads. Area three contains one of the largest Roman hippodromes ever found.</p>]]><p><b>Baalbeck</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set on the south western slopes of the Anti-Lebanon range in the Bekaa Valley, the spectacular ruins of Baalbeck are arguably one of the most impressive examples of surviving Phoenician and Greco-Roman architecture in the World. Its Temple of Jupiter is the largest Roman temple ever built.</p>]]><p><b>Beirut beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With 225km (140 miles) of coastline, you are never far from a stretch of beach in Lebanon. Few cities can boast sandy beaches on their doorstep but the azure waters of the Mediterranean lap much of the city&rsquo;s perimeters. There are public beaches or many sun worshippers favour the better-equipped beach clubs offering sun loungers, showers, pools and cafes and restaurants such as those offered at the Riviera Beach Lounge. (<a href="http://www.rivieirahotel.com.lb" target="_blank">www.rivieirahotel.com.lb</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Beirut's Central District</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Witness the spectacular number of modern buildings and office blocks springing up in Beirut's Central District.</p>]]><p><b>Beiteddine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set on a height in the heart of the Chouf Mountains and commanding fabulous views of the surrounding landscape is the magnificent fortress of Beiteddine. Built over a 30-year period by the Ottoman ruler Emir Bechir Chehab II, it is one of the finest examples of 19th century Lebanese palace architecture in the country. The interior features some previous mosaics as well as Turkish baths, hammams, courtyards, elegant arcades and gardens as well as an ethnological museum.</p>]]><p><b>Byblos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The charming Unesco World Heritage listed fortified seaside town of Byblos lies 40km north of Beirut (<a href="http://whc.unesco.org" target="_blank">http://whc.unesco.org</a>). Excavations have unearthed artefacts dating back to Neolithic times but Byblos&rsquo; golden period came during the reign of the Phoenicians, when it was a crucial crossroad between the east and west. Its picturesque, boat cluttered harbour and pretty honey coloured fortifications also enjoyed great popularity as a glamorous seaside retreat during the 1960s when it was visited by the likes of Brigitte Bardot.</p>]]><p><b>Downtown Beirut</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Scattered with some of Beirut's most elegant Art Deco architectural heritage much of downtown Beirut has been undergoing an expensive refurbishment since the civil war. Lined with arcades and sidewalk cafes, the spiritual heart of this pedestrianised area is the Place de L'Etoile topped by a 1930s clock tower. Nearby is the Lebanese parliament - another fine example of a Lebanese art deco style building - while the area is also home to several important churches and mosques.</p>]]><p><b>Gibran Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Gibran Museum in Besharre (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.kahlil.org/museum">www.kahlil.org/museum</a>). Best known as the birthplace of the famous Lebanese poet Khalil Gibran, author of <em>The Prophet</em>, the town is also a gateway to the Kadisha Valley, a mountainous region famous for its many cedar trees.</p>]]><p><b>Jeita caverns</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the spectacular Jeita Grotto, around 20km (13 miles) north of Beirut. On two levels, the deep, upper cavern is reached by cable car and features a dazzling display of stalactites and stalagmites, which can be viewed along a special walkway. A small tourist train collects visitors at the entrance and takes them to the lower cave, which includes an underground lake that can be admired during a short boat ride.</p>]]><p><b>Palm Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A short distance off the coast, 5.5km (3 miles) from the seaside city of Tripoli, is the Palm Islands Nature Reserve, a trio of uninhabited islands and the country's only true islands. Wildlife enthusiasts can observe the islands' colony of protected Loggerhead turtles as well as large colonies of migratory birds.</p>]]><p><b>Pigeon Rocks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Beirut's most iconic landmarks are the Pigeon Rocks, an impressive collection of arched rock formations jutting out of the Mediterranean close to the Raouche district of the city on the westerly end of the Corniche. From the pavement lined with restaurants and cafes, there is a 100m pathway that leads down to the sea and affords spectacular views.</p>]]><p><b>Scuba-diving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go scuba-diving and snorkelling in the waters near the ancient city of Tyre. Divers can explore some interesting underwater archaelogical ruins.</p>]]><p><b>Sea castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Glimpse the sea castle built of stone from Roman remains in the small port city of Sidon. See one of the best-preserved temple areas of the Roman world that is still in existence in Baalbek, near the Syrian border. The columns of the Temple of Jupiter soar behind the complex of several temples.</p>]]><p><b>Ski</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ski amidst a Mediterranean backdrop in Lebanon's many mountain resorts, such as Bakish, The Cedars, Faqra, Faraya, Laklouk and Zarour, which offer excellent accommodation and facilities (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.skileb.com/">www.skileb.com</a>). Whilst there, explore these mountains and gorges. They present excellent terrain for hiking.</p>]]><p><b>Souks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Capture the old Beirut in the city's old souks (covered markets) that are being reconstructed in an authentic way. Visit the weekly Souk El Tayab farmers market held in the downtown area of the city. Held every Saturday morning, this features an array of producers selling delicious organically produced fare from around the city and countryside including the likes of cedar honey, jams, pickles, fruit and vegetables as well as homemade olive oil (<a href="http://www.souktayeb.com" target="_blank">www.souktayeb.com</a>). The Turkish bath at Al-Nouzha provides another glimpse of antiquity, whilst the Beirut National Museum is constantly updating its interesting collection (<a href="http://www.beirutnationalmuseum.com/" target="_blank">www.beirutnationalmuseum.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Teleferique cable car</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set on the outskirts of Beirut, this cable car was first opened in 1965 and spirits visitors up 650m (2,133 ft) above sea level and offers breathtaking views of the city and beyond  (<a href="http://www.teleferiquelb.com" target="_blank">www.teleferiquelb.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Tripoli</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's second and most Arabian city. Its old medieval centre at the foot of the Crusader castle is sprinkled with many mosques that include the Al-Muallaq Burtasiyat Madrassa, Al-Qartâwiyat Madrassa, Great Mosque and Taynâl. Its bustling souks are also some of the most atmospheric in the whole of the country and an obligatory stop on any visit to the city.</p>]]><p><b>Turtles</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spot the green turtles and rare birds on the Island of Palm Trees, listed by UNESCO as a nature reserve, just off Tripoli.</p>]]><p><b>Tyre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Another of Lebanon's unmissable archaeological sites that also enjoying Unesco World Heritage status is the seaside settlement of Tyre, which is scattered with the remnants of over 5,000 years of history. Settled by the Egyptians, Ottomans, Phoenicians, Greeks, Byzantines, Arabs and Romans, it is actually three sites covering a large area, but is perhaps best known for its ancient Roman relics that include one of the largest Roman hippodromes every constructed.</p>]]><p><b>Vineyards of the Bekaa Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon has one of the oldest traditions of viticulture in the world. The Phoenicians first introduced wine to the area around 5,000 years ago and the vine-draped slopes of the Bekaa Valley form the heart of Lebanese wine production. Pay a visit to historic vineyards such as the Chateau Musar set in an 18th century castle and Chateau Ksara, two of the country's best-known producers.</p>]]><p><b>Watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try out the watersports on offer, which include waterskiing and sailing. Swimming is also popular and many beaches have freshwater pools provided to supplement the sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$39.25 billion (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Authentic jewellery, inorganic chemicals, consumer goods, fruit and tobacco.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum products, cars, medicinal products, clothing, meat and live animals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Switzerland, United Arab Emirates, Iraq, Saudi Arabia, Syria</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Beirut's position as a major financial and commercial centre for the Middle East was lost during the 16-year civil war that ended in 1990. Since then, despite more political unrest, both Lebanon and its capital have re-established themselves.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>Agriculture now accounts for about 10% of GDP. There are no significant mineral resources, but the manufacturing industry is growing rapidly. Banking and transit trade (both of which were almost wiped out during the civil war) have also recovered.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>The 2006 conflict between Hezbollah and Israel led to a collapse of the tourist industry and severely affected Lebanon's economy, which contracted by 5%. The national debt reached a record level of US$40.4 billion and a fifth of the population was unemployed. Latest economic forecasts for the country are more optimistic; due to its tightly controlled banking system, Lebanon was affected to a lesser extent that most countries by the financial crisis of 2008-2010.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>English is spoken by many local businesspeople and normal courtesies are observed. Appointments and business cards are used. In order to conduct business in Lebanon, you need to fulfil your social obligations by being hospitable and generous to your guest or host, no matter how much money is at stake. Appearance is paramount, so professional dress and meetings conducted in upmarket surroundings such as offices and restaurants are key.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1330 and 1500-1800. Government office hours:Mon-Thurs 0800-1400, Fri 0800-1100, Sat 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Euro Info Correspondence Centre (EICC)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 744 163
					Website:http://www.euroinfocentre.net
					Address: Sanayeh,PO Box 11-1801,1 Rue Justinien,Beirut,]]><b>Chamber of Commerce, Industry and Agriculture of Beirut and Mount Lebanon</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 353 390
					Website:http://www.ccib.org.lb
					Address: Sanayeh,PO Box 11-1801,1 Rue Justinien,Beirut,]]><b>Ministry of Economy and Trade</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 981 941
					Website:http://www.economy.gov.lb
					Address: Hamra,Artois Street,Beirut,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Lebanese cuisine is widely acknowledged to be the finest in the Middle East. The country's gastronomic tradition is characterised by the use of an extremely wide variety of locally produced, and therefore extremely fresh, vegetables served in all forms and shapes with an abundance of fresh herbs (mostly coriander, parsley and mint). A meal is always concluded with a wide range of fresh fruit, including melon, apples, oranges, persimmon, tangerines, cactus fruit, grapes and figs, which are all grown locally. Excellent Lebanese food is available everywhere. Beirut also offers a large choice of international restaurants which offer dishes from all over the world.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Kebbeh</em> (lamb pounded to a fine paste, often rolled into balls and fried). <br />
&bull; Meze, a range of up to 40 small dishes served as hors d'oeuvres with arak.  <br />
&bull; Tabbouleh (salad made with cracked wheat, lemon, mint and tomatoes). <br />
&bull; <em>Mutabbal</em> (dip made with baked aubergines and garlic). <br />
&bull; Baklava (the Lebanese version of these Middle Eastern pastries uses pistachio nuts and rose-water syrup).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol is widely available.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In hotels and restaurants, a tip of between 5 and 10% of the bill is expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Over the last few years Beirut has been gaining a reputation for its lively nightlife with an ever-increasing number of bars and nightclubs springing up all over the capital, especially in downtown Beirut in and around Gemayzeh Street. Entertainment ranges from solo guitarists to orchestras, floorshows discos and carbaret-style shows such as those at the popular Music Hall on Omar Daouk Street. Some British-style pubs can also be found in Beirut. There are many cinemas presenting the latest films from all over the world, while the internationally renowned Casino du Liban in Maameltain is equipped with lavish gambling halls, luxurious restaurants and a cabaret.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's traditional souks (markets) are found all over the country offering decorative and handmade items at relatively low prices. Special purchases include traditional pottery and glassware, as well as cutlery made of tempered steel or copper with ram or buffalo bone handles. Brass and copper goods include braziers, bowls, fluted jugs, ashtrays, swords and doorstops are also attractively designed and hand engraved. <br />
<br />
Cloth, silk and wool kaftans, abayas (embroidered nightwear) and table linen are popular, as is hand-worked gold and silver. Luxury and international brands crowd the streets of the newly developed Beirut Souks in the Soldiere district of downtown Beirut, which now occupies the site of the former traditional souk area. Saifi Village is another corner of the city renowned for its more eclectic range of artisans, contemporary boutiques, galleries and specialist shops catering to the upper end of the market.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1800.</p><p>The export of antiques is forbidden. It is possible to reclaim duty on purchases on departure at the airport. An official form bearing the stamp and details of the shop the goods were purchased in must accompany all purchases.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following the large-scale destruction during the civil war, Beirut's hotels have now all been rebuilt, and a number of new ones added, including the presence of international and luxury hotels such as Radisson, Sheraton and Four Seasons plus boutique properties such as Le Gray. Lebanon today offers accommodation to suit all budgets and the Ministry of Tourism publishes an annual hotel guide, which lists most of the hotels in the country. Outside Beirut, hotels are less common, particularly in the south. Visitors are advised to check reservations through a Lebanese representative at home before departing. Winter and summer rates are the same. Accommodation rates are normally subject to a 15% service charge.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are classified from 1 to 5 stars and deluxe. Prices are usually quoted in US dollars and only hotels with rooms costing more than US$50 tend to accept credit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and Breakfasts are an increasingly popular option but standards vary widely. Contact the Ministry of Tourism for details. L&rsquo;Hote Libanais is an organisation offering bed and breakfast accommodation in an array of different buildings from private homes to monasteries all over the country (see <a href="http://www.lhotelibanais.com" target="_blank">www.lhotelibanais.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following the large-scale destruction during the civil war, Beirut's hotels have now all been rebuilt, and a number of new ones added, including the presence of international and luxury hotels such as Radisson, Sheraton and Four Seasons plus boutique properties such as Le Gray. Lebanon today offers accommodation to suit all budgets and the Ministry of Tourism publishes an annual hotel guide, which lists most of the hotels in the country. Outside Beirut, hotels are less common, particularly in the south. Visitors are advised to check reservations through a Lebanese representative at home before departing. Winter and summer rates are the same. Accommodation rates are normally subject to a 15% service charge.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are classified from 1 to 5 stars and deluxe. Prices are usually quoted in US dollars and only hotels with rooms costing more than US$50 tend to accept credit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following the large-scale destruction during the civil war, Beirut's hotels have now all been rebuilt, and a number of new ones added, including the presence of international and luxury hotels such as Radisson, Sheraton and Four Seasons plus boutique properties such as Le Gray. Lebanon today offers accommodation to suit all budgets and the Ministry of Tourism publishes an annual hotel guide, which lists most of the hotels in the country. Outside Beirut, hotels are less common, particularly in the south. Visitors are advised to check reservations through a Lebanese representative at home before departing. Winter and summer rates are the same. Accommodation rates are normally subject to a 15% service charge.<br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are classified from 1 to 5 stars and deluxe. Prices are usually quoted in US dollars and only hotels with rooms costing more than US$50 tend to accept credit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is essential. Private healthcare in Lebanon is expensive. Lebanese hospitals are very modern and well equipped and many doctors are highly qualified. All doctors speak either English or French. The majority of hospitals in the region are private and require proof of the patient's ability to pay the bill before providing treatment (even in emergency cases). Visitors who are not insured and require hospitalisation should contact their embassy for advice. Standards at Lebanon's public hospitals are much lower. The two best hospitals in the country are the Hôtel Dieu in Achrafieh, Beirut, and the AUBMC (American University of Beirut Medical Centre) in Hamra, Beirut.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is recommended. Drinking water outside main towns and cities is likely to be contaminated and sterilisation is considered essential. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B is present but rare. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. There are fears Syrian refugees have brought polio to Jordan and the WHO advises vaccinations against it. Otherwise, the main health risks come from over-exposure to the sun: sunburn, sunstroke and dehydration are all real concerns. Take care to cover your skin &amp;ndash; both to prevent skin damage and to limit dehydration.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Armenian Orthodox Christmas :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>St Maroun's Day :
							09 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Orthodox Easter Sunday :
							08 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							06 May </p><p>Resistance and Liberation Day :
							25 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Independence Day :
							22 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Lebanon by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 100 cigarillos or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of spirits or fortified wines or 4L of other alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; 1L of eau de cologne and 100ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Personal belongings not exceeding L&pound;2 million or L&pound;500,000 for Lebanese, Syrian and Jordanian passengers or those arriving from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/syrian-arab-republic">Syria</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jordan">Jordan</a>.</p>
<p>Those aged under 18 years are permitted half the specified quantities for duty free except tobacco and alcoholic beverages, which are forbidden.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arms, ammunition, narcotics, and immoral publications and recordings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arms, ammunition, narcotics, archaeological artefacts and currencies.</p>
<p>Antiques require an export licence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lebanese Pound (LBP; symbol L£) = 100 piastres. Notes are in denominations of L£100,000, 50,000, 20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 1,000, 500, 250, 100, 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of L£500, 250, 100 and 50. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars and the euro are also accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a large number of banks in Beirut where international currencies can be exchanged. Numerous licensed exchange shops also operate and some hotels offer exchange services. US Dollars are best and do not need to be exchanged as they are accepted even in small shops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major credit cards are widely accepted. ATMs are widely available in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/beirut">Beirut</a> and larger cities.</p><p>ATMs are widely available in Beirut and larger cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Limited acceptance, as major banks only accept certain types of travellers cheques. Traveller's cheques also require up to two weeks to clear and are therefore generally not recommended and exchange can often be problematic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1600, Sat 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Lebanon, a passport valid for three months from the date of entry is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sole parents entering the country with children may be required to present written permission from the other parent of the child in question.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa on arrival: free.</p>
<p>In advance: single-entry tourist visa: &pound;25; multiple-entry tourist visa: &pound;50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: one month initially, renewable for three months.</p>
<p>Single-entry visa in advance: 15 days, one month or three months; multiple-entry visa in advance: three or six months. If applying for a visa in advance from the embassy, you must enter Lebanon within 90 days of the date of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Processing times for visas applied for before travelling to Lebanon vary according to the nationality of the applicant.   Please contact the embassy for information on individual cases.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Extending a stay in Lebanon without permission is a serious offence. A fee will be payable before departure is permitted. To extend your one-month visa, you must visit the nearest General Security office (<a href="http://www.general-security.gov.lb">www.general-security.gov.lb</a>).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[33.945978]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[35.809025]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>10,452 sq km (4,036 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5,988,153 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>591.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Beirut.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon lies to the east of the Mediterranean, sharing borders to the north and east with the Syrian Arab Republic, and to the south with Israel/Palestinian Territory. The country possesses four distinct zones from west to east including the coastal plain, the Mount Lebanon Range, the Bekaa Valley and the Anti Lebanon range that forms its border with Syria. Lebanon is a mountainous country with approximately half of its landscape lying at an altitude of over 900m (3,000ft). For its relatively diminutive size, Lebanon offers a surprisingly diverse landscape from the fertile Bekaa Valley to the snow capped peaks of the Anti Lebanon and cedar forests of Mount Lebanon. The famous cedar trees grow high in the mountains, while the lower slopes are cultivated with grapes, apricots, plums, peaches, figs, olives and barley, often on terraces painstakingly cut out from the mountainsides. On the coastal plain, citrus fruit, bananas and vegetables are also grown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are 18 registered sects in Lebanon with Islam and Christianity the main religions. Islam (predominantly Shi'ite) accounts for approximately 59.7% of the population's beliefs, while Christian denominations, mainly Greek Orthodox, Maronite, Armenian and Protestant, account for a further 39%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lebanese people are known for their hospitality. A handshake is the normal form of greeting. It is acceptable to give a small gift, particularly if invited home for a meal. As far as dress is concerned, casual dress is suitable for daytime wear, except in main towns where dress tends to be rather formal. Smarter hotels and restaurants often require guests to dress for dinner. Since Lebanon is almost evenly divided between those adhering to the Muslim faith, and those adhering to the Christian faith, visitors should dress according to the custom of the majority in the individual places being visited. In 2012 smoking was prohibited in enclosed public places such as cafes, restaurants and hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with two or three round pins or three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Saad Hariri since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Michel Aoun since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's advantageous geographical location on the edge of the Mediterranean and at the crossroads between Europe and the Middle East has shaped its historical, cultural and political identity. The earliest evidence of civilisation in Lebanon dates back more than 7000 years and the area was a stronghold of the powerful seafaring Phoenicians who founded important coastal trading ports like Tyre, Tripoli and Byblos.</p><p>The Turks took control of the area in the 16th century during the major expansion of the Ottoman Empire and remained there until the end of World War 1. Lebanon was created in its present boundaries in 1920 under the French Mandate, which administered the country until Lebanon gained independence and became a republic in 1943.</p><p>For several decades Lebanon's diverse religious groups existed in relative harmony and the country developed a thriving economy, while Beirut became one of the most visited cities in the Mediterranean.</p><p>However, in the early 1970s large numbers of PLO (Palestine Liberation Organization) fighters expelled from Jordan sought refuge in Lebanon, which in 1975 led to civil war with Beirut split across the Green Line, dividing the Christian-dominated east and the Muslim west.</p><p>In 1982 the presence of the PLO led to an Israeli invasion of Lebanon and although they retreated to a self-declared security zone in the south there followed an intense guerrilla war with Hezbollah that continued despite the peacekeeping efforts of the international community.</p><p>Peace returned to most of Lebanon in 1990, although fighting continued between Israel and Shia militia in the south until Israeli occupation ended a decade later. With a more stable political environment, the lengthy process of rebuilding Beirut began in earnest and the country seemed poised to make a comeback until the assassination on 14 February 2005 of former Prime Minister Rafic Hariri in a bomb attack in Beirut.</p><p>Since 2006 Lebanon has been embroiled political crisis. A major conflict erupted between Lebanon and Israel, which resulted in heavy fighting and large-scale loss of life on both sides of the border. A ceasefire finally came into place, following intervention from the UN Security Council.</p><p>In 2009 Rafiq Hariri's son, Saad Hariri was elected prime minister and formed a national unity government, but the relative stability that ensued did not last and in January 2011 the government collapsed. A new government led by Najib Mikati was formed in June. </p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• In the 1960s Lebanon was known as the 'Switzerland of the East'.</p><p>• Next to Israel, Lebanon is the largest recipient of US military aid per head of population.</p><p>• Several Lebanese writers have achieved international success, most notably Khalil Gibran whose 1923 book <em>The Prophet</em> is a modern classic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Lebanon in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 939 6300</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.lebanonembassyus.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 939 6300</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2560 28th Street<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Lebanon in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7229 7265</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.lebaneseembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7229 7265</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1530&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>21 Palace Gardens Mews<br/>London<br/>W8 4RB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fringed by golden beaches, peppered with World Heritage Sites and home to the Middle East's premier party city, Lebanon has all the hallmarks of a classic traveller's destination. <br /><br />Yet the reality, alas, is not quite so rosy. Still recovering from a brutal civil war (1975-1990), the conflict in neighbouring Syria is spilling across the border and the Bekaa Valley remains a stronghold for the militant group Hezbollah. Suffice to say, cautious tourists have stayed away.  <br /><br />Nevertheless, for now, a fragile peace prevails in Lebanon, which extends a warm welcome to foreign visitors. Nowhere is this clearer than in the capital, Beirut, a friendly party town sandwiched between the Mediterranean Sea and the foothills of Mount Lebanon. <br /><br />Characterised by its affable inhabitants, dramatic coastline and delicious cuisine, bustling Beirut sits at the crossroads between Europe and Arabia. Influences from east and west abound – it is not uncommon to hear the call to prayer competing with DJs in some of the livelier parts of town.  <br /><br />Although buildings still bear the scars of past conflicts, the city is a forward-thinking capital where the biggest danger nowadays seems to be the traffic – crossing the road can feel like an extreme sport. <br /><br />Though small in size, Lebanon boasts five UNESCO World Heritage Sites including the city of Byblos, one of the oldest Phoenician ports, and the haunting remains of Baalbeck in the Hezbollah-run Bekaa Valley, one of the finest examples of Greco-Roman architecture in existence.  <br /><br />Other highlights including the magnificent cedar forests and Christian monasteries of the Holy Valley, as well as the ancient cities of Tyr and Tripoli, home to one of the oldest seaports in the world. <br /><br />And if that's not enough, there's always skiing in Mount Lebanon. Granted, it might not be an obvious place to hit the slopes, but there are few places in this world that can offer sun, sand and skiing in one day. But then Lebanon is not your average destination.</p>Fringed by golden beaches, peppered with World Heritage Sites and home to the Middle East's premier party city, Lebanon has all the hallmarks of a classic traveller's destination. 

Yet the reality, alas, is not quite so rosy. Still recovering from a brutal civil war (1975-1990), the conflict in neighbouring Syria is spilling across the border and the Bekaa Valley remains a stronghold for the militant group Hezbollah. Suffice to say, cautious tourists have stayed away.  ]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
