<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Liberia" ColCode="lbr" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="lr" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Liberia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot, tropical climate with little variation in temperature. The wet season runs from May to October. The dry harmattan wind blows from December to March, making the coastal belt particularly arid.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are worn throughout the year, with waterproofing advised during the wet season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are only two commercial airports open in Liberia and no domestic airline to fly between them. There are other airports scattered around the country, but these cater only for UN staff and passengers taking chartered flights.</p><p>Liberty Aviation (<a href="http://www.libertyaviationgroup.com" target="_blank">www.libertyaviationgroup.com</a>) operates chartered flights around Liberia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no regular passenger service between ports in Liberia. The seas along the coast are   not safe for passenger travel in basic canoes. You can hire small craft, but you must check safety measures, such as radios and life jackets, before going on board. Equally along the rivers care must be taken, especially near or in the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only rail road operating in Liberia is used for transporting iron ore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Road is the main mode of transport within Liberia.</p>r<p>In and around Monrovia, roads are tarred and relatively smooth as far as Bo Waterside in the northwest, Gbarnga in the north and Buchanan in the south. Outside of these they revert mainly to clay-top roads. As a general rule, the further from Monrovia, the worse the road. In dry season the clay roads are dusty and bumpy but driveable. During the wet season some towns become isolated by roads turning into thick clogging mud.</p><p>The National Transit Authority (<a href="http://www.nta.com.lr" target="_blank">www.nta.com.lr</a>) is a government-run bus service, which is currently expanding its network across the country. Details on the website are sketchy (there are no timetables or fare prices online) but there is a contact form which can be used for queries.</p><p>Liberia is a nation of taxis. Shared taxis operate in every part of the country and literally drive the economy. Prices and seat allocation are strictly controlled by the Transport Union, which protects both passengers and drivers. Double seats for extra comfort are a recommended option. If travelling alone they are a brilliant source of information on everything from language to accommodation.</p><p>It is best to over document in Liberia. It is best to travel with full documentation, including both driver&rsquo;s and passenger&rsquo;s visas, passports, driving licence and vehicle ownership documents.</p>
<p>Getting a valid driving licence is surprisingly easy. Simply call into the Ministry of Transport, Broad Street, Monrovia, with a valid passport and visa. The process is a little different for each person but in most cases a simple 30-minute process is all that is needed.</p><p>Internal police checkpoints operate on every road across Liberia.</p><p>There is no national breakdown service, but there are car servicing mechanics scattered around the country. If hiring a car be sure to check the breakdown service clauses.</p><p>You can hire self-drive or chauffeured cars in Monrovia from Ucar Rental (+231 88 080 0800).</p><p>Given the nature of the roads, cycling in Liberia is ill advised.</p><p>Internal police checkpoints operate on every road across Liberia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While there is now a bus service, most locals travel by shared taxis. These are usually crowded, driven at speed and out of date. They are also cheap, easy to access and, unlike the roads they travel on, reliable. If a passenger is not delivered they do not pay, which is far more than car hire companies promise.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brussels Airlines (<a href="http://www.brusselsairlines.com" target="_blank">www.brusselsairlines.com</a>) operates direct flights to Liberia from Brussels, with connections from other cities in Europe, including London. Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>) flies from Casablanca and offers connecting flights to the USA and Europe, including London. Arik (<a href="http://www.arikair.com" target="_blank">www.arikair.com</a>) flies to Liberia from Lagos and also has connections to the UK and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London - 9 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); New York - 17 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are two airports, James Spriggs Payne Airport operating out of Congo Town, in Monrovia and the larger Robertsport Airport based in Harbel, an hours drive outside Monrovia. Other listed airports are reserved for UN staff and partners. A vaccination card for yellow fever is necessary if you're arriving from a country at risk of yellow-fever transmission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are two airports, James Spriggs Payne Airport operating out of Congo Town, in Monrovia and the larger Robertsport Airport based in Harbel, an hours drive outside Monrovia. Other listed airports are reserved for UN staff and partners. A vaccination card for yellow fever is necessary if you're arriving from a country at risk of yellow-fever transmission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Spriggs Payne Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Monrovia Roberts International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.robertsinternationalairport.com<p>The airport  is 60km (36 miles) southeast of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no routine operating passenger boats arriving in Liberia.</p><p>Most sea travel must be approached with caution given the rough nature of the waves and rip tides around Liberia. Make sure all boats hired are up to date, have safety features and are run by experienced personnel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no passenger rail networks into or within Liberia. Those that are open carry iron ore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several border crossings into Liberia open strictly from 0900-1800, every day. From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sierra-leone">Sierra Leone</a> the main crossing is at Bo Waterside, and a second, smaller crossing is at Mendakomah near Foya. From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guinea">Guinea</a> there is a small crossing at Solumbah near Foya, and two more at Ganta and Yekepa. From the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ivory-coast">Ivory Coast</a> there is a crossing is at Loqatou near Kahnplay and Pedebo near Harper.</p><p>Crossing into Liberia by road is likely to be a muddy or dusty affair, depending on the season. Roads are, generally, of a poor quality.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The internal network in Monrovia is gradually being extended over the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage is mostly limited to Monrovia and surrounding areas. There is some coverage along the north and northeastern borders with Guinea and Côte d'Ivoire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a few Internet cafés in Monrovia and some hotels offer Internet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following years of civil war, Liberia's broadcasters and publishers are still struggling to find resources to pay their staff. LBS, the state-run broadcaster has no television service and operates a single radio service, which does not have national coverage. Private television stations include <em>Clar TV</em>, <em>Power TV</em> and <em>Real TV</em>. Many radio stations are run with the support of international agencies, such as <em>UNMIL Radio</em>, which is operated by the United Nations mission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes up to one month or can be as little as five days with an express mail service provider.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask on Monrovia's Beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The most famous beaches are the surfing ones near Robertsport. However there are a series of beaches surrounding Monrovia. Most have dangerous currents, but ELWA, Silver, and Cece Beach are all open to swimmers. Both Silver and Cece have bars and restaurants, with Cece stretching miles beyond the crowds for those in need of solitude.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Mountain Woligizi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mount Wologizi in northern Liberia is the country's highest point. Flanked by dense jungle, the mountain is accessible by road at the village of Lisco. The mountain trail leads past waterfalls and a series of sloping hills to the summit, from which three countries can be seen (Liberia, Sierra Leone and Guinea), not to mention the largely unmapped tropical forests that cover swathes of the region.</p>]]><p><b>Cross a monkey bridge</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fast running rivers cascade through the Lofa rainforest to the mangroves surrounding Monrovia. Crossing these torrents are monkey bridges, which are made from rainforest materials (vines and the like) and are rewoven by locals every year. The reweaving of these monkey bridges is part of a ceremony organised by local secret societies, which are responsible for organising most social activity in Lofa.</p>]]><p><b>Experience the bustle of Monrovia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The capital of Liberia, this is where most urban attractions sit mixed together: ruined buildings from a dozen different eras mix with sushi bars, a national museum, Waterside cloth market, the Freemasons Temple and packed new supermarkets. The population is equally diverse with UN and NGO expatiates from around the world exchanging detailed stories of life in Liberia and world politics with people from every part of Liberia.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Sapo National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Corruption and war has seen many of Liberia's forests destroyed for timber, but Sapo lives on. This is largely down to the Sapo people, who gave up their land to create this national park and now dedicate their time protecting it. The journey there takes over 11 hours from Monrovia, but it's worth it: according to Conservation International it has the highest concentration of mammals on Earth.</p>]]><p><b>Go deep-sea fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Just 12km (7.5 miles) off the shore of Monrovia, a deep sea trench hides a wealth of fish giants, including scores of blue marlin, sailfish, and yellow fin tuna. The best season is November through May when boats, complete with experienced captains, can be charted. Despite the wealth of fish, there are relatively few boats to compete with.</p>]]><p><b>Monkey around in Marshall</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This verdant coastal resort often comes as a surprise to tourists. Not only because it contains a luxury resort, which offers something of a contrast to accommodation standards in the rest of the country, but because it is also home to an island populated exclusively by rescued chimpanzees. There's also a swimmable lagoon and gorgeous golden beaches.</p>]]><p><b>Search for pygmy hippos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the extreme north of Liberia lies the East Nimba Nature Reserve, a verdant jungle that harbours birds, butterflies, monkeys and the elusive pygmy hippo. Trails crisscross the reserve and well-informed guides and guesthouses are available for visitors. Nimba is easier to reach than Sapo with a tar road for most of the route from Monrovia to Gabrnga.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in time at Harper</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located in southern Liberia, Harper was once the home of President Tubman, who lavished attention on his town with vanity construction projects. However, the gorgeous art deco houses, once the jewel in Harper's crown, have long since been abandoned and reoccupied by those in need of shelter. As well as providing an extraordinary contrast between then and now, wealth and poverty, Harper offers stunning beaches and bountiful marine life including whales and dolphins.</p>]]><p><b>Surf at Robertsport</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The most famous beaches are the surfing ones near Robertsport in Grand Cape Mount County. Some surfers prefer to ride the waves during the quieter weekdays, while others like showboating to the crowds at the weekend, but all are united in their appreciation for the reliable breaks that roll in most days. Local surfers offer lessons for the less experienced.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$1.951 billion (2013)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Rubber, iron ore, timber.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, food, machinery and transport equipment, manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, South Korea, USA, EU and ECOWAS area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Liberia's economy depends on viewpoint. For example, up to three quarters of its populations income comes from small agriculture holdings and small boat fishing, even while two thirds of its food is imported. On the other hand most of the profitable sectors: timber, iron ore and commercial farming, are export driven. Corruption and land rights are two constants in the economy and there is a vast difference between the lives of those within the wealthy loop and those without.</p>
<p>The UN &amp; NGO community play a powerful role both in terms of wage distortion and national decision making. Gender inequality impedes progress, especially within the agricultural area where, despite their majority role in producing and processing food, women are rarely found in discussions on major decisions regarding land use or selling.</p>
<p>The surprise is the shipping industry. Over 3,000 vessels sail under the Liberian flag, used as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flag_of_convenience" target="_blank">a flag of convenience</a>, making it one of the world's largest shipping registries. This is despite Liberia having few operating ports. Other difficulties such as the high cost of fuel, electricity and internet are balanced against a view of what has been achieved in recent years such as the cancelling of the national debt, the simplifying of the procedure to set up a business to a remarkable two days and the setting up of the first legal process dedicated to contract disputes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Liberian business dress is a relatively formal affair. Even for minor meetings and gatherings appearance is important and seen as an indicator of both character and a show of respect towards others attending. Liberians devote time and effort in appearing smart, clean and groomed. No excuses of travel or climate will be given or taken.</p>
<p>In making contact, the person who is lower in status, calls and approaches those higher. Businesses cards are essential, as is English. Outside of these parameters many things are allowed to be fluid. Time keeping in particular is not seen as important and no offence is meant or will be taken if business people turn up an hour or more late. It is best to ring well in advance, and often, to make sure people are on their way.</p><p>Typically Mon-Fri 0800-1700. Banks close at 15:00.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Liberia Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 231 223 738
					Website:
					Address: ,PO Box 92,Monrovia,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Liberian food ranges from fiery stews to honey covered peanut cookies. Meals are usually served with a mountain of rice topped with a spicy sauce made from red palm oil, leaves, meat and fish. A dozen different types of breads are also made while bushmeat is prized, even if the meat in question is illegal.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><em>&bull; Torborgee (a spicy stew made from the Torborgee bean, palm oil and meat or fish)</em><br />
<em>&bull; Beef and cassava leaf soup </em><br />
<em>&bull; Goat meat soup </em><br />
<em>&bull; Kanyah (ground peanuts mixed with toasted rice flour and sugar)</em><br />
<em>&bull; Liberian rice bread</em><br />
<em>&bull; Monrovian coconut pie (coconut and egg pie in a pastry case)</em><br />
<em>&bull; Palm butter soup (crab claws, chicken and prawns cooked with palm butter and chilli)   </em></p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>A host is responsible for guests at their party and must provide all drinks, food and entertainment, even when the party is based in a bar. When a guest, be aware that the host feels in charge and be sure to inform them when leaving.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% at hotels, restaurants and bars is expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Drinking age is 18, but most Liberia's start working hard well before that age and most rules are interpreted to reflect their status as breadwinners.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A sunset beer is a daily event in Monrovia with the beach bars along Newton Street in Mamba full most evenings. Tides Bar, Mamba Point (+231 7700 05003) and Lila Brown, Mamba Point (+231 8867 77007) are two of the more popular Mamba hangouts, and offers great views from their terraces. Meanwhile, over in Sajj, most people leave the beach and head to haunts such as Fuzion d'Afrique, 14th Street and Tubman Boulevard (+231 8869 69969).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopping for souvenirs is best done in the shops and markets of Monrovia. Mango Rags, Camp Johnson Road, sells find local clothing and fabrics, while Waterside Market, Water Street has everything from local food and jewellery to vibrant fabrics and wooden carvings.</p><p>Those with a few weeks to prepare can take advantage of numerous skilled tailors and leather workers who can create inexpensive, clothes, personalised wallets, sandals and bags that are made to measure.</p><p>Typically, Mon-Sat 0800-1900. On Sundays most shops and markets are closed.</p><p>Bargaining is a fact of every transaction in Liberia, and Monrovia is legendary for its expensive day-to-day costs. Express shock at every figure and fight hard, but remember costs are high for locals too. Costs can be cut by buying, eating and travelling in the most popular local ways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel accommodation can be quite expensive, but is not extortionate by international standards. It is advisable to book well in advance, whatever the category of accommodation. There are a few air-conditioned hotels of international standard and a range of inexpensive hotels and motels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a selection of bed and breakfast hotels in Monrovia. There are several mission guest houses with both cooking and laundry facilities about 4km (2 miles) from the city centre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel accommodation can be quite expensive, but is not extortionate by international standards. It is advisable to book well in advance, whatever the category of accommodation. There are a few air-conditioned hotels of international standard and a range of inexpensive hotels and motels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel accommodation can be quite expensive, but is not extortionate by international standards. It is advisable to book well in advance, whatever the category of accommodation. There are a few air-conditioned hotels of international standard and a range of inexpensive hotels and motels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;International travellers are strongly advised against travelling to Liberia due to the Ebola outbreak. Click here for &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/foreign-travel-advice/liberia" target="_blank"&gt;the British Government's latest advice&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Meningococcal meningitis is a risk, depending on the area visited and time of year. Hepatitis B is hyperendemic, and hepatitis E is widespread. Malaria and yellow fever are high risks in some locations. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Armed Forces Day :
							11 February </p><p>National Decoration Day :
							14 March </p><p>J J Roberts' Birthday :
							15 March </p><p>National Redemption Day :
							12 April </p><p>National Fast and Prayer Day :
							13 April </p><p>National Unification Day :
							14 May </p><p>Africa Day :
							25 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							26 July </p><p>Flag Day :
							24 August </p><p>Thanksgiving Day :
							01 November </p><p>President Tubman's Birthday :
							29 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Liberia without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 25 cigars or 250g tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits and 1L of wine.<br />
&bull; 100ml of perfume and 1L of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of US$125.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Restricted imports include flowers and plants, which must be accompanied by a phytosanitary certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Liberian Dollar (LRD; symbol L$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of L$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins in circulation are L$1 and 50, 25, 10 and 5 cents. US Dollar notes are in circulation in the following denominations: US$100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1.<br /><br />The Liberian Dollar is tied to the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money can be exchanged at the Liberia Bank for Development and Investment (LBDI), on the corner of Randall and Ashmun Streets in Monrovia. LBDI also incorporates a Western Union office, which can receive urgent money transfers from abroad (though the procedure is lengthy and will take approximately one day).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not generally accepted.</p><p>There are few ATMs in Liberia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are generally not accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0900-1200, Fri 0800-1400. Some banks may open on Saturday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Liberia, a passport valid for a minimum of six months from the date of entry is required by the nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>
<p>All travellers require a yellow fever vaccination certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications for visas for children must include a notarised letter from the parent/guardian.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US nationals: single-entry visa: US$131; one-year multiple-entry visa: US$200; two-year multiple-entry visa: US$300; three-year multiple-entry visa: US$400.</p>
<p>All other nationals: single-entry visa: US$70; one-year multiple-entry visa: US$150; two-year multiple-entry visa: US$250; three-year multiple-entry visa: US$350.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visas: up to three months; multiple-entry visas: one to three years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas for Liberia typically take around 10 working days to process.   For a same-day or next-day service, an additional fee applies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must be able to show evidence of sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[6.411981]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-9.323022]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>111,369 sq km (43,000 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,615,222 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>37.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Monrovia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Liberia borders Sierra Leone, Guinea Republic and C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire. The Atlantic coastline to the west is 560km (348 miles) long, of which over half is sandy beach. Lying parallel to the shore are three distinct belts. The low coastal belt is well watered by shallow lagoons, tidal creeks and mangrove swamps, behind which rises a gently undulating plateau, 500 to 800m (1,640 to 2,625ft) high, partly covered with dense forests. Inland and to the north is the mountain region which includes Mount Nimba at 1,752m (5,748ft) and Waulo Mountain at 1,400m (4,593ft). About half of the country's population are rural dwellers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Officially a Christian state, with more than 30 denominations represented; Islam is practised in the north and traditional animist beliefs exist throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Muslim areas, the visitor should respect the conventions of dress and the food laws, since failure to do so will be taken as an insult. Dress is casual and must be practical, but smarter dress will be expected in hotel dining rooms and for important social functions. The visitor should be aware that the cost of living is high. Sending flowers or chocolates to hosts is inappropriate; a letter of thanks is all that is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>120 volts AC, 60Hz. American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without round grounding pin) are most common.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President George Weah since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President George Weah since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Little is known for sure about this slice of West Africa prior to the 14th century. However, historians believe the indigenous population of Liberia are likely to have descended from migrants fleeing the <a href="h/i/mali">Mali</a> and Songhey Empires between the 13th and 16th century.</p>
<p>During this period, European traders established contact with coastal communities whose inhabitants became fluent in many languages. The slave trade both expanded this connection to the rest of the world and caused deep changes in legal and social structures within Liberia, draining the country of skilled, youthful people.</p>
<p>As resistance to the slave trade grew, a movement began in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> called the American Colonisation Society (ACS), which sought to return African slaves back to their motherland. Critics say the ACS was borne out of fear that freed slaves would pose a threat to American society, but, nevertheless, the group established the colony of Liberia in 1822 and sent thousands of emancipated slaves there to start new lives.</p>
<p>Indigenous Liberians allowed the new arrivals to share their land, but were surprised when the settlers didn&rsquo;t abide by the laws of the local chiefs. Scuffles ensued. So in 1847 the settlers, aided by the United States, formed a republic to reinforce their right to rule themselves and to defend themselves against a series of indigenous attacks.</p>
<p>Using US military support, the republic not only survived but thrived and it wasn&rsquo;t until 1904 that the indigenous tribes were enfranchised in this new society. However, long-term inequality and deepening poverty resulted in the Rice Riots of 1979 and a coup d&rsquo;&eacute;tat in 1980. However, the new regime of Sergeant Samuel Doe failed to quell unrest, which simmered over in 1989 with the outbreak of the First Liberian Civil War.</p>
<p>Peace negotiations and elections ended the war in 1997 and saw Charles Taylor appointed president. But the peace was short-lived and in 1999 the Second Liberian Civil War broke out, drawing in neighbouring <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sierra-leone">Sierra Leone</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guinea">Guinea</a>. By 2003 when the fighting finally ceased, <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-13729504" target="_blank">Liberia&rsquo;s brutal wars had claimed an estimated 300,000 lives</a>.</p>
<p>President Taylor went into exile in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nigeria">Nigeria</a>, but in 2006 he was arrested for war crimes and extradited to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hague">The Hague</a> where he was found guilty and sentenced to 50 years imprisonment.</p>
<p>As Taylor started his sentence, the new Liberian president, Ellen Johnson Sirleaf, was awarded a Nobel Peace Prize. As Africa&rsquo;s first elected female president, she leads a nation described in the 2013 Ibrahim Index of African Governance as the continent&rsquo;s most improved country.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; Liberia was founded by the United States in 1822 and became Africa&rsquo;s first republic in 1847.<br />
&bull; The Liberian flag is based largely on that of the USA&rsquo;s &ndash; the star symbolises the freedom ex-slaves were given and the stripes represent the signatories of the Liberian Declaration of Independence.<br />
&bull; Much of the Liberia&rsquo;s revenue comes from the controversial practice of providing a &ldquo;flag of convenience,&rdquo; which means allowing foreign ships to register as Liberian. This enables vessel owners to bypass stringent regulations set by their home countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Liberia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 723 0437.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofliberia.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 723 0437.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>5201 16th Street<br/>Washington<br/>20011<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Liberia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7388 5489.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofliberia.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7388 5489.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 1030-1500; Mon-Thurs 1100-1530 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>23 Fitzroy Square<br/>London<br/>W1 6EW<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>They say all publicity is good publicity, but Liberia might argue otherwise. Africa&rsquo;s oldest republic has barely been out of the headlines in recent decades, but for all the wrong reasons; reports from the country have been dominated by two civil wars and an outbreak of Ebola. Suffice to say tourists have stayed away.</p>
<p>But Liberia has come a long way since the dark days of its civil war. The 2013 Ibrahim Index of African Governance proclaimed this small West African nation to be the most improved country on the continent &ndash; and many are hoping Liberia will continue in this vein.</p>
<p>Assuming it does, adventurous travellers will likely be tempted back to this small, coastal nation; a country characterised by its windswept golden beaches, luscious rainforests and verdant savannahs, where twittering birds, screeching monkeys and stomping elephants provide a wild soundtrack.</p>
<p>But there&rsquo;s more to this country than natural wonders. Founded by freed American and Caribbean slaves, Africa&rsquo;s oldest republic is home to a staggering diversity of cultures; its four million odd inhabitants are comprised of more than 16 established peoples, and there&rsquo;s a burgeoning Asian and Middle Eastern population, too.</p>
<p>Art has long played an important role in Liberian culture, and the country&rsquo;s various ethnic groups are renowned for their ornate wooden sculptures, particularly wooden masks, which are said to connect the living with ancestral spirits and ancient deities. Like art, religion is also woven into the fabric of Liberian life; casual ceremonies with sacred catfish hold force even while churches and mosques are full.</p>
<p>Liberia&rsquo;s tropical climate, with a long dry season from September to June and rains peaking in August, still decide everything from transport to working schedules. During the monsoon roads become rivers and, at times, the country feels very much at the mercy of nature.</p>
<p>Yet Liberia is very much the master of its own destiny and its emergence as a credible tourist destination will depend largely on whether peace prevails and whether there is significant investment in the country&rsquo;s creaking infrastructure.</p>Liberia, Africa's oldest republic, is one of the continents most history-rich yet cash-poor nations.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
