<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Libya" ColCode="lby" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ly" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Libya]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Summers are very hot and dry; winters are mild with cooler evenings. The desert has hot days and cold nights. Spring and autumn are ideal times to visit, when the warm air comes up from the Sahara and meets a cooling breeze from the Mediterranean. </p><p>Libya is a huge country and weather patterns vary by region. The Mediterranean coastline is the focus of most travellers' trips to Libya. There, summers are hot and dry and winters are mild, although the evenings can be worthy of scarves and hats.You'll find similar, though slightly warmer conditions to those on the other side of the ocean, such as southern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece">Greece</a>. Libya's coastline can be very windy, so be sure to pack a headscarf (women should of course bring one anyway as this is a deeply conservative Muslim country) to protect your ears from being blasted by the breeze.</p><p>Rainfall is sporadic and rarely heavy, but drizzly days in autumn and winter are fairly common. Temperatures in <a href="http:/i/tripoli">Tripoli</a> in January range from 7 to 17&deg;C; in July, you can expect bright sunshine, blue skies and a mercury reading of between 20 and 25&deg;C. In the winter of 2011/12, Libya's coastline had its first snowfall in decades. The desert has hot days and cold nights; the closer to the equator you travel, the hotter the days will be. With the exception of the far southern desert close to Libya's borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chad">Chad</a>, southern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/egypt">Egypt</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sudan">Sudan</a>, humidity is generally low. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Loose, long clothes in natural fabrics are recommended. A cover-up for the cooler months is advisable. Warm clothing for nights in the desert. Modest dress is advised, especially for women - upper legs and arms, shoulders and cleavage should be covered. A headscarf can be useful as extra coverage, and is essential for visiting mosques, cemeteries or other sites that bear religious significance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Libyan Airlines (<a href="http://libyanairlines.aero" target="_blank">libyanairlines.aero</a>) and Afriqiyah Airways (<a href="http://www.afriqiyah.aero" target="_blank">www.afriqiyah.aero</a>) are Libya's main carriers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Note that the British Foreign and Commonwealth Office advises against all travel to Libya.</p>
<p>From Tripoli to Benghazi is a 10 to 12-hour drive, depending on traffic and the speed at which you are comfortable travelling. There are some coaches that ply this route, although most Libyans prefer to fly rather than spend all day on the road. If you do travel by coach, expect plenty of cigarette and coffee stops, checkpoints and passport checks.</p>r<p>The main through-road hugs the coastline, linking Tripoli and Benghazi. Road conditions are generally excellent in major towns and along the coast; unfortunately, this means that many drivers like to show off on the roads and travel much faster than is acceptable by UK standards. Signposts are mostly in Arabic script, with some English signs in Tripoli, Benghazi and near ancient sites.</p>
<p>Off-road driving is best done with a 4-wheel drive vehicle and in organised tour groups. In the desert regions, particularly in the Eastern Desert and Great Sand Sea south of Al Jaghbub, you can rent a 4-wheel drive vehicle and a driver for desert trips, including trips as far south as the Sudanese border.</p>
<p>Drivers should watch out for wind-blown sand deposits and wild animals, which can cause hazards on the roads. By far the greatest hazard is dangerous driving. Drivers should be well-prepared with fuel, water and food if travelling into remote areas.</p><p>There are a few bus services, mainly luxury, air-conditioned coaches between Tripoli and Benghazi and other major urban areas. A minibus service operates from Benghazi to Tobruk.</p><p>Taxis, the easiest way to get around, are plentiful and reasonably priced. Long-distance taxi fares can be quite expensive and should be agreed in advance.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is valid for three months. After this time, you must obtain a Libyan licence.</p><p>Police enforcement of traffic signs and laws is rare.</p><p>There is no reliable nationwide breakdown service for non-Libyans.</p><p>Car hire is available from local firms based in Tripoli airport and city, in Benghazi and other towns. The best bet is to check with your hotel, who can help organise transport. You can hire a car as an individual or - a safer idea, especially if you are not used to Libyan roads - one that comes with a driver.</p><p>Most Libyans do not cycle outside of small towns. Ask at your hotel for bike hire, but do not expect to find a big cycling culture.</p><p>Police enforcement of traffic signs and laws is rare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a few public buses in Libyan towns. An overcrowded microbus system operates in Tripoli and Benghazi along certain routes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no direct flights to Tripoli from the UK or the USA. You can fly to Istanbul, from where Afriqiyah Airways (<a href="http://www.afriqiyah.aero" target="_blank">www.afriqiyah.aero</a>) flies to Tripoli or fly to Tunis and catch a connecting flight with Libyan Airlines (<a href="http://libyanairlines.aero" target="_blank">libyanairlines.aero</a>). Tripoli International Airport is located about 26km (16 miles) from the city centre.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 7 to 11 hours (including stopovers); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 15 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is currently no departure tax.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Benina International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 19km (12 miles) east of Benghazi city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Tripoli International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is situated 35km (22 miles) south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tripoli">Tripoli</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(022) 605 026</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports are Benghazi, Darna, Brega, Misrata and Tripoli.</p><p>There were once passenger boats from Benghazi to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malta">Malta</a>. General passenger services along the coast or to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/egypt">Egypt</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tunisia">Tunisia</a> have been suspended for years. During Libya's conflict, you could also travel by fishing boat along the coast, and from Benghazi to Malta, but now doing so is harder without flouting rules. Still, if this is something that interests you, it's worth asking around at the main port in Benghazi. It's wise to pay attention to the state of the vessel and the safety situation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no international rail links.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Due to the dangerous security situation and ongoing fighting in Libya, the British Foreign and Commonwealth Office advises against all travel to Libya. The following information was accurate at the time of writing, but may no longer reflect the situation on the ground.</p>
<p>You can cross into Libya by road from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cairo">Cairo</a> (12-hour drive to Benghazi) and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tunis">Tunis</a> (11-hour drive to Tripoli) although visa formalities mean that travelling by air is simpler. Neither border post is particularly likely to be closed to foreign travellers, but if you have been granted a visa, it's wise to check if the means of travel is stipulated, before embarking on a journey by land (if your visa says you are travelling by air, you must.) Libya's land borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/algeria">Algeria</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/niger">Niger</a>, <a href="http://i/sudan">Sudan</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chad">Chad</a> are closed to non-Africans.</p>
<p>From Cairo, you need to drive west, crossing the border into Libya near Al Burdi. This was the entry point for the majority of international journalists covering the conflict in the eastern part of Libya. The border post still houses some of the people displaced by the Libyan conflict, and can be chaotic. Expect to spend about three hours crossing the border. You need to get your passport stamped on the Egyptian side and again on the Libyan side, and you may need to show a yellow fever certificate if you have recently travelled to an affected area. There is a short distance to walk between the two border posts; if you have lots of luggage you might wish to pay a porter to help carry your things. Once on the Libyan side, it's about a further six-hour drive to reach Benghazi.</p>
<p>From Tunis, you can take minibuses all the way to the Ras Ajdir border crossing, which lies about 11 hours' east of Tunis. If you're travelling with your own car, the border guards may charge you a fee. Reports from travellers who have crossed the border since the end of the conflict suggest that it is still possible, but that transiting through Ras Ajdir can be slow due to increased formalities. You can also enter via the Dehiba/Waziin border crossing, further south.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International calls can be made from internet cafes and telephone offices, readily available in main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Libyana SIM cards for mobile phones are available in most towns, although you may need to bring your passport and register the card to your name. Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is patchy in desert regions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafes in Tripoli, Benghazi and other main towns. Wi-Fi is available in many hotels and some restaurants across the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many independent newspapers have emerged since the end of the revolution; until then, the state controlled a large proportion of the country's output, with working non-state journalists often afraid to report independently for fear of upsetting the regime. Pro-NTC student or youth publications surged during the conflict, notably in Benghazi.</p>
<p>Libyan and international channels are available in many hotels. Expect films that include adult content to be censored. In terms of radio, The Voice of Free Libya is made up of journalists who broke free from state-run radio. With newspapers, look out for <em>Libya Freedom</em> - dubbed 'the voice of the revolution' - <em>Burniq</em> or <em>Libya Today</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Postal services are available in all main towns. Mail to Europe takes approximately one week, and to North America or Australia, one-two weeks. The main post office in Tripoli is on Maidan al-Jezayir.</p><p>Post office (main) hours: Sat-Thurs 0800-2230; smaller offices' hours are usually Sat-Thurs 0800-1300 and 1700-2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Akakus Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The mountain scenery on the border with Algeria is spectacular but, as if that wasn't enough, these rock cliffs hide some of the Sahara's finest prehistoric rock art, particularly at Wadi Metkandoush and Wadi Tashwinat.</p>]]><p><b>Ancient cities</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Libya's coastline is dotted with some of the most spectacular ancient ruins in all of the Mediterranean. In most cases, the sites are well-preserved and best of all, you'll encounter very few tourists - that was the case even before the revolution. Leptis Magna, a short drive from Tripoli, is the most magnificent of all; its cobbled streets, Severan Arch (erected in honour of Emperor Septimus Severus), marble- and granite-lined Hadrianic Baths, detailed basilica and large amphitheatre are easily worth a day of your time. Cyrene, three hours from Benghazi, spills across the hilltop; check out its ancient fertility temples, beautiful Temple of Zeus and Roman stadium. Sabratha, between Tripoli and the Tunisia border, is also stunning. All three sites - and four more along the coast near Benghazi - closed their doors during the revolution, but you may be able to talk tour guides hanging around nearby into allowing you a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Assai al-Hamra (Red Castle)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tripoli's spectacular fortress houses a maze of courtyards and buildings, situated on a promontory above the city. The Jamahiriya Museum, which houses ancient artefacts, closed during the revolution, but there are plans for it to re-open.</p>]]><p><b>Beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There isn't much of a beach culture in Libya; many local people prefer to go out for picnics in the countryside instead. This means you'll sometimes have the coastline's gorgeous golden sands to yourselves. With 2,000km (1,243 miles) of Mediterranean coastline, there is plenty of choice when it comes to splendid beaches, including Neqezzah (112km east of Tripoli), Ras al-Hammamah, Sabratha and the splendid beaches from Zuara to Ras al-Jadir.</p>]]><p><b>Berber architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Berber villages are scattered throughout the more remote mountain area of the Jebel Nafousa, but the unusual mud-brick architecture of the Berber grain storage houses in Nalut, Kabaou and Kasr Elhaj is particularly interesting.</p>]]><p><b>Camel riding</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Several tour operators organise camel treks through the Akakus mountains or other parts of the Sahara. This is the true way to discover the quiet solitude, slowness and unique beauty of the desert.</p>]]><p><b>Desert driving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There's nothing quite like riding in a 4WD across miles and miles of seemingly endless desert, climbing the ridges of enormous sand dunes and tumbling down them bare-footed. The best place for this kind of adventure is the amazing Great Sand Sea, about four hours drive from Benghazi. You can sleep overnight in a desert villa in the dusty town of Al Jaghbub, then visit nearby desert lakes before swanning off into the desert. The Great Sand Sea was once an ocean; you can still see the evidence of that, in the fossilised starfish, seashells and rock formations shaped by the waves and sand. Also worth looking out for are the ancient tombs (complete with bones), sun-dried palm groves and a collection of WWII-era British cars, left to rust between the dunes.</p>]]><p><b>Dune-surfing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The dunes near the Ubari lakes are seriously high and a few snowboards are available nearby to surf down them. Beware it can be dangerous.</p>]]><p><b>Freedom Square (Green Square)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once a symbol of Gaddafi's regime, Tripoli's main square became famous during the 2011 revolution. It was here that Gaddafi vowed to fight against the uprising; it was here, too, that thousands gathered to usher in a new era after Tripoli finally fell. These days, most of the square is used as a car park for the nearby souk, but it's worth wandering around and absorbing the square's remarkable history.</p>]]><p><b>Ghadames</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Most travellers to Libya come back with rave reviews of Ghadames, saying it's like nowhere else on earth. The unique desert oasis town, known as the 'Pearl of the Desert', is in the western region, 800km (500 miles) southwest of Tripoli. The UNESCO-protected old town's unique architecture consists of whitewashed mud-brick walls, covered labyrinthine walkways and elaborate orchard gardens with date palms, pomegranate and orange trees and vegetables. Under the Gaddafi regime, people living in the ancient houses were offered new homes nearby, but the old buildings remain and are often frequented by the people of the town.</p>]]><p><b>Leptis Magna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The incredible well-preserved ancient remains of a Roman settlement, highlights of which are the Severan Arch (erected in honour of Emperor Septimus Severus), the marble- and granite-lined Hadrianic Baths, the detailed basilica and the large amphitheatre.</p>]]><p><b>Qasr Libya</b></p><![CDATA[<p>About two and a half hours from Benghazi, Qasr Libya (Castle Libya) is often overlooked by travellers. But this dusty site houses an incredible collection of Byzantine mosaics that date back centuries. Colourful and well-kept, some are humorous, others poignant; together they illustrate the rich Byzantine culture.</p>]]><p><b>Roman Libya</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Roman cities are well-preserved in Libya but nowhere can you imagine just how good the Romans had it as in Villa Sileen. Come to the house late afternoon, after visiting Leptis Magna, and feel the sea breeze on the wonderful terrace.</p>]]><p><b>Snorkelling</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On the bay beneath Cyrene, the sun-dappled ruins of the port city of Apollonia are worth visiting in their own right. Crumbling roman theatres tumble down to the water and there's even the remnants of an ancient library and olive press. You can snorkel in the turquoise ocean, but you'll have to bring your own equipment and you may have to talk the guards of the nearby museum into turning a blind eye. There are shipwrecks off the coast that you may be able to explore as long as you are careful and respectful. Women may want to cover up in a t-shirt or wetsuit.</p>]]><p><b>Souk shopping</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The old souks and winding lanes of the capital, Tripoli, with its traditional mosques and <em>khans</em> (inns/warehouses), have particular streets given to spices, gold, bridal fabrics made from a desert plant and animal skins.</p>]]><p><b>The Pentapolis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Of the five ancient and powerful Greek city states in Libya Cyrene, Sussa (Apollonia) and Tolmitha (Ptolemaeis) have the most atmospheric remains. The setting of Cyrenaica is particularly impressive in the Jebel al Akhdar overlooking the sea, and its museum is spectacular.</p>]]><p><b>Trekking and caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The pretty hills, rock formations and cooler climate of the Jebel al-Akhdar (Green Mountains) or the Jebel Nafusa in the west are ideal for trekking but you will have to work out your own routes as few tour companies organise walking trips. There are caves, ancient churches, olive groves and even some prehistoric caves to explore. Haua Fteah cave is a large shallow site a few kilometres from the town of Marsa Sousa, in the Jebel al-Akhdar. Archaeologists estimate that it dates back to about 100,000 years.</p>]]><p><b>Ubari sand dunes &amp; lakes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Ubari, majestic sand dunes run down to picturesque salt lakes that are surrounded by palm trees. Locals, not that there are many around here, come to these lakes for salt-lake bathing, where a microscopic shrimp is believed to clean the skin, and rejuvenating mighty hot sand baths in an exotic setting.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$NA (2011 est.)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, petroleum products, natural gas and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, semi-finished goods, food, transport equipment and consumer products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Italy, Tunisia, Egypt, Turkey and Gulf states.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Libya's biggest challenge in the aftermath of the revolution is to unite the country and reconstruct the fragile economy. The National Transitional Council inherited an economy that is still bruised from the corruption of the Gaddafi regime, but foreign companies are beginning to return to Libyan shores and oil production is once again underway.</p>
<p>National GDP dropped by 60% during 2011, but it is predicted to rise by 70% in 2012. Inflation hit 14% in 2011, but is expected to hover at around two percent in 2012. Revenues from the oil industry still account for the bulk of Libya's post-conflict economy; in March 2011, the new government said the state's production of oil was reaching targets of 1.3 million barrels per day.</p>
<p>Unemployment is now estimated to be around 37%, higher than the rate of 30% in 2004. The deflated economy means that even some medical and education graduates cannot find steady work. Major construction projects have been on hold since the revolution, and may remain so until the new administration is able to disarm militias and restore international confidence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shirts and smart trousers, or smart-casual office dress is acceptable business wear. Suits and ties are worn for more formal occasions. Women should take care to cover shoulders and knees, but many Libyan women dress fashionably in spite of this restriction. English, and often Italian, is widely understood. It is, however, government policy for official documents to be in Arabic (or translated into Arabic) and for official business to be conducted in Arabic. Business visitors need to be fully prepared for this. Appointments are necessary and business cards are useful, though not widely used. Hours for businesses and government offices fluctuate, but the working day starts early.</p><p>Sat-Wed 0700-1400 (summer) and 0800-1600 (winter). Many businesses close on Fridays. Private businesses and shops operate differently and are usually open into the evening for shopping. During Ramadan, working hours are different and businesses are usually opened after sunset.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Benghazi Chamber of Commerce, Trade and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (61) 909 5142
					Website:
					Address: Sharia Gamal Abdul-Nasser,PO Box 208,Benghazi,]]><b>Tripoli Chamber of Commerce, Industry and Agriculture</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 333 3755
					Website:
					Address: ,PO Box 2321,Tripoli,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Libyan cuisine is a mixture of Arabic and Mediterranean, with a strong Italian influence. There is an abundance of dates, oranges, apricots, figs, lemons and olives. Hotel restaurants offer international cuisine. Seafood in Tripoli is particularly good. Most restaurants have table service, and although food is traditionally eaten with the right hand only, knives and forks will generally be available in major towns.</p>
<p>Most restaurant meals consist of soup, salad, a selection of meat or fish dishes, vegetables and tea or coffee, followed by a piece of fruit. Some travellers find Libyan cuisine disappointing. Indeed, in the major towns and tourist areas it is often formulaic, with little of the panache seen across the borders in Egypt and Tunisia. But if you are invited into the homes of Libyans, you'll suddenly start to see a difference. Away from the expectation of tourists, Libyan cuisine thrives. You can expect such delicacies as traditional Libyan salad, made with cucumbers, tomatoes and spice, or stuffed sheep's intestines - a wonderful mix of herbs, rice and spices poured into grilled intestines, resulting in a type of homemade gourmet sausage. There are very few restaurants outside of the main towns.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>
<there dates.="" and="" milk="" food:="" libyan="" traditional="" of="" ingredients="" key="" four="" are="">&bull; <em>Shorba Libiya </em>(a spicy lamb and tomato soup).<br />
&bull; Couscous. <br />
<em>&bull; Ruuz</em> (a rice dish with a variety of spices, meat and vegetables). <br />
<em>&bull; Rishda</em> (traditional pasta dish with chickpeas, tomato and onion).<br />
<em>&bull; Bazin</em> (hard paste, made from barley, salt and water).<br />
&bull; <em>Zumita</em> (a doughy mix of water and flour, similar to <em>bazin</em>.)<br />
&bull; Desert bread (a traditional circular flatbread that is baked in makeshift ovens beneath the sand in desert areas. The hot sand becomes an effective oven, and you need only shake the bread afterwards to remove the dry sand from it.) </there>
</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol is banned in Libya.  Nevertheless, some Libyans make their own beer or wine at home. Moonshine, which can often be incredibly strong, is sometimes sold illegally. If you're in the market for this, make sure you are buying it from a reputable brewer who can be vouched for; there have been cases of severe alcohol poisoning after travellers ingested strong moonshine. Lunch is usually served late in Libya, between 1330 and 1500 in the afternoon, even in hotels. Dinner is generally served from 1900 onwards in most establishments.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A tip of 10-20% is usually included in hotel and restaurant bills.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nightlife in Libya is almost nonexistent, even after the fall of the regime. Indeed, many young people from the northeastern part of the country head to Egypt for nightlife fixes. Under Gaddafi, nightclubs, bars and concert venues were banned. Underground venues occasionally pop up in Tripoli or Benghazi but are frowned upon, and you'll have to ask around to find them. Drinking alcohol remains illegal in Libya, although some travellers might be are able to find locally-brewed beer and wine.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>After dark, coffee shops and shisha bars are generally the preserve of men; groups of women entering can expect to be met with raised eyebrows and requests for phone numbers. There are cinemas in major towns, some showing foreign films. Many towns and cities put on a festival with traditional dancing and music. The ancient city of Cyrene, near Benghazi, used to put on theatre productions in its Roman amphitheatre during tourist seasons - there are plans to reinstate these when tourism picks up again. In the summer, small theme parks become popular with Libyan families.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The old souks and winding lanes of the capital, Tripoli, with its traditional mosques and <em>khans</em> (inns/warehouses), have particular streets given to spices, gold, silverware and animal skins. There are beautiful jewellery and perfume shops, filled with racks of blended oils and fragrances and old warehouses devoted to copper creations. <br />
<br />
Keep an eye out for the bridal shops, selling everything the modern Libyan woman needs to tie the knot. There, you can even buy hen night hampers containing hairdryers, henna and underwear. Other local craft specialities include the famous embroidered Ghadames slippers, pottery from Gharian, trays and baskets made from palm leaves, and leather bags and belts. Be prepared to bargain a little, although not too hard.<br />
<br />
Between the shops and market stalls are traditional hammams (each one has separate opening times for men and women) and places to grab a fruit smoothie, a bite to eat or a cup of sweet mint tea. It's worth noting that most Libyan women go to the souks in the morning; female travellers visiting alone might prefer to go then, rather than brace themselves for crowds of curious men. Souk shopping hours are generally Sat-Thurs 0800-1700, Fri 0800-1300.</p>
<p>Tripoli and Benghazi each have central shopping streets, where you can find clothing, groceries, books, magazines and souvenirs. Many shops are stocked with Italian imports; fine Italian shirts can be a good buy, as can shoes. Bookstores are largely limited to Arabic-language products, although you might get lucky and find a few books in English or Italian (try the children's and students' sections.) Nowhere does late night shopping better than the Arabic-speaking world, and Tripoli and Benghazi are no exception. Shops are usually open until 10 or 11pm most nights. Friday night shopping is a favourite family activity for many Libyans. Outside of the main cities, shopping is generally limited to the necessities. </p><p>Sat-Thurs 0800-1330 and 1600-2000, Fri 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels can be found in the main towns and cities. Hotels range from budget with basic facilities, to more luxurious establishments which have ensuite rooms equipped with air conditioning and TV, commonly frequented by tour groups before the revolution. The price usually includes breakfast. A few small privately run boutique hotels are springing up, particularly in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tripoli">Tripoli</a>, offering more charm and a friendlier service than the government hotels - which, under Gaddafi, often featured enormous portraits of the late leader in their lobbies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Ghadames, villas offer bed & breakfast-style accommodation in homes. All offer kitchen facilities and some have bedrooms with private bathrooms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels can be found in the main towns and cities. Hotels range from budget with basic facilities, to more luxurious establishments which have ensuite rooms equipped with air conditioning and TV, commonly frequented by tour groups before the revolution. The price usually includes breakfast. A few small privately run boutique hotels are springing up, particularly in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tripoli">Tripoli</a>, offering more charm and a friendlier service than the government hotels - which, under Gaddafi, often featured enormous portraits of the late leader in their lobbies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels can be found in the main towns and cities. Hotels range from budget with basic facilities, to more luxurious establishments which have ensuite rooms equipped with air conditioning and TV, commonly frequented by tour groups before the revolution. The price usually includes breakfast. A few small privately run boutique hotels are springing up, particularly in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tripoli">Tripoli</a>, offering more charm and a friendlier service than the government hotels - which, under Gaddafi, often featured enormous portraits of the late leader in their lobbies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;If you get sick in Libya, you should be well-taken care of in the main cities, but for serious illnesses it would be wise to seek treatment outside of the country, such as in Egypt or Tunisia, where healthcare resources are better. There are pharmacies throughout Libya, although these will of course be better-stocked in Tripoli and Benghazi than in smaller towns. You may want to carry anti-diarrhoea medicine, antibiotics and a basic first aid kit with you when you travel, especially if you plan to visit remote areas where healthcare will be limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always wear a seatbelt when you travel by road: not only is this the law, but road accidents are the most common cause of death among visitors to Libya. Check if your travel insurance will cover a visit to Libya; many companies will not insure you if you are travelling to a country that is not deemed safe by the British Foreign Office, or other national equivalent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under Gaddafi, healthcare in Libya was free, with some provision for private facilities for those who chose to pay. This was one benefit of the Gaddafi regime - another was education; even studies at college and at university comes without cost in Libya as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the government invested a great deal of money in constructing large, fancy hospitals that it was never able to complete. You can still see the evidence of Gaddafi's overambitious healthcare policy if you visit Tripoli and Benghazi. In Benghazi, the largest hospital only operates on the lower floors; the higher floors, which have space for hundreds of beds, were never completed, meaning that the lower wards are crammed with beds instead. Many doctors in Libya complain about the dire healthcare situation. Medical training in the country is generally good, but there is still a lack of supplies and a lack of staff. Hundreds of Filipina and other foreign nurses left Libya during the revolution, and many have yet to return. Young doctors compete for graduate jobs.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The water in Libya is relatively safe to drink but visitors are recommended to stick to widely available bottled water or to sterilise other water. Milk can be unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit should be peeled before eating.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Diarrhoeal diseases are common. Hepatitis A and B occur throughout the country, but are extremely rare. There is a rare chance of catching bilharzia (schistosomiasis) from paddling in stagnant fresh water, but the desert lakes are mostly salty. Very few cases of meningococcal meningitis have been reported in the Sebha region. Malaria is not common in the areas that travellers are most likely to visit, although there have been cases in the southern part of the country and close to the borders with Chad, Sudan and Niger.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Revolution Day :
							17 February </p><p>Jamahiriya Day :
							02 March </p><p>British Evacuation Day :
							28 March </p><p>American Evacuation Day :
							11 June </p><p>Italian Evacuation Day :
							07 October </p><p>Liberation Day :
							23 October </p><p>Independence Day :
							24 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Duty-free information unavailable at the time of writing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All alcohol is prohibited, as are arms, erotic literature and pork products. All goods made in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/israel">Israel</a> or manufactured by companies that do business with Israel are prohibited, for instance Coca Cola and certain makes of CDs. Bags are X-rayed upon arrival. For a full list of prohibited items, contact the nearest Libyan diplomatic representative.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms, and historic artefacts, including items of ancient Roman, Greek and Byzantine origin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Libyan Dinar (LYD; symbol LD) = 1,000 dirhams. Notes are in denominations of LD20, 10, 5, 1, 1/2 and 1/4 dinars. Coins are in denominations of 100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 dirhams and 1/2 and 1/4 dinars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Libya is a cash society. Credit cards are not widely used, although some are accepted in major hotels and banks.  You can walk into some of the major banks and ask if it is possible to withdraw cash against your credit card. Recent reports from travellers suggest that this is possible in Benghazi and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tripoli">Tripoli</a>, although it may depend on individual cases and the information is liable to change.</p><p>There are working ATMs in Tripoli, Benghazi and some other towns. In the capital, head to Martyrs' Square, where you'll find branches of the major Libyan banks. Visa and Mastercard are accepted; American Express may also be in some cases. Some ATMs in Libya have built-in MP3 players that blare tracks while you wait for your money. There are also mobile ATMs, attached to the back of small vans, that move around Tripoli, parking in various places; again, try the area around Martyrs' Square if you're looking for one of these.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are generally not accepted anywhere in Libya. Western Union operates in Tripoli, Benghazi and some other towns. Check the company's website for listings of providers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sat-Thurs 0700-1400 and 1600-1800. Most banks are closed on Fridays, Sundays and on Saturday afternoons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Libya, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visit visa: &pound;65; single-entry business visa: &pound;100; multiple-entry visa: &pound;150.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Residency paperwork will be organised by your company if you are employed in Libya.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow two days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[27.236043]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[18.044037]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,759,500 sq km (679,347 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6,330,159 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tripoli.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>General National Congress (transitional government) since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>About 95% of Libya, Africa's fourth largest country, consists of desert (the Sahara). In the west the Sahara desert extends into Tunisia and Algeria, in the east into Egypt, and across the southern frontiers into Niger, Chad and Sudan. Only 20% of the desert features sand dunes - most of it consists of <em>hamada</em> (rock plateau) and, in the south, dramatic basalt mountains, the highest point of which is Bikubiti (2285m), near the Chad border. There are a few oases scattered throughout the country, mainly in the south.</p>
<p>There are almost 1,770 km (1,100 miles) of Mediterranean coast, with a low plain extending from the Tunisian border to the Jebel Akhdar (Green Mountain) area in the east. Inland the terrain becomes more hilly. Agriculture has developed mainly on the coast between Zuwarah and Misratah in the west and from Marsa Susa to Benghazi in the east. In the uplands of the old province of Cyrenaica and on Jebel Akhdar the vegetation is more lush.</p>
<p>Desertification is a huge problem, but the Great Manmade River Project, the largest water development scheme in the world, was built to bring water from large aquifers under the Sahara to the coastal cities. Gaddafi left the Great Manmade River Project unfinished, but there are plans to bring in new developers sometime in the future.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sunni Muslim 97%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although Libya is a deeply conservative country, people are friendly and generally like to enjoy life. This is all the more true since the revolution, when many people seemed to break free from the shackles imposed by the Gaddafi regime. Young men drive fast cars through the streets of Benghazi, showing off the tinted windows that were banned under the late leader's administration. And while there are no nightclubs or bars in the country yet, young people like to enjoy music and hang out in shisha cafes and shwarma joints. It's important to dress modestly wherever you go, particularly if you are female. Alcohol is forbidden and most people get married at a young age, often through arranged agreements. Weddings tend to be a three-day affair with lots of singing and emphasis on beautiful outfits.</p>
<br />
<p><strong><br />
Photography:</strong> In this sparsely-populated country, expect most of your shots to be of the landscapes. As in other places, it's wise to ask before photographing someone, and to keep your camera away from military sites or groups of militia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>127/230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs used are European-style with two circular metal pins and South African/Indian-style with two circular metal pins above a large circular grounding pin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Fayez al-Sarraj since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Aqilah Salah Issa, President of the House of Representatives, since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From the eighth century BC onwards when the Phoenicians settled Libya has been conquered several times over  its archaeological heritage includes both Greek and Roman remains.</p><p>Under UN direction, the country was granted full independence in 1951 and King Idris became head of state, pursuing a pro-Western foreign policy while keeping up cordial relations with other Arab states. During the 1950s and 1960s, major discoveries of oil greatly improved the economic prospects of the country.</p><p>Idris was overthrown by a military coup lead by Colonel Muammar Gaddafi in 1969 and in the 1980s and 1990s Libya was ostracised from the international community because of Gaddafi's support for various revolutionary and terrorist groups, most notably the 1988 bombing of the Pan Am flight over the Scottish town of Lockerbie that killed all 270 passengers on board. UN sanctions were imposed from 1992, a measure that cost Libya billions of dollars in revenue, but when Gaddafi announced in 2003 that he would give up his nuclear weapons, sanctions were lifted and in 2006 Libya was rehabilitated and taken off the US list of states sponsoring terrorism.</p><p>In 2011, as part of the Arab Spring that took place across many of the Middle East and northern African countries, there was a widespread uprising against Colonel Gaddafi's rule, resulting in civil war. Libyan forces loyal to the transitional council, supported by NATO forces, were eventually successful in their aims, resulting in the unseating Colonel Gaddafi in October 2011 and his death at the hands of his own people. Under Gaddafi a multi-party state was forbidden, but dozens of new parties have sprung up in the wake of the revolution, including the Muslim Brotherhood and the Salafis.</p><p>A Libyan General National Congress was elected in 2012, then dissolved after the June 2014 elections, but reconvened by a minority of its members. The country's Council of Deputies also claimed to be the legitimate government and some areas of the country fell beyond either group's control. Following UN-sponsored peace talks between the factions the Government of National Accord was formed and entered Tobruk in April 2016. Elections are due to be held within two years.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p> There is little or no pop music in Libya, although various kinds of Arab music are popular and the Tuareg people have their own folk music.</p><p> There has been a Jewish community in Libya since the third century BC  Simon of Cyrene, a Libyan Jew, is believed to have helped Jesus carry the cross.</p><p> In the 16th century the Knights of St John occupied Tripoli until it was besieged by the Ottomans in 1551.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Libyan Embassy in US]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>202 944 9601/2 </p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>202 944 9601/2 </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900 - 1630&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2600 Virginia Avenue, NW Suite 705<br/>Washington DC<br/>20037<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Libya]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>213 351 084/5/6</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-tripoli</p><p><b>Tel:</b>213 351 084/5/6</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Sun-Thurs: 0800-1515&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>24th Floor, Tripoli Towers (formerly Bourj al Fateh)<br/>Tripoli<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Libyan Embassy in the UK (Consular section)]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>020 3006 9890</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://libya.embassyhomepage.com/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>020 3006 9890</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Wed 1000-1030 (visa application); Tues-Thurs 1400-1500 (visa collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>61-62 Ennismore Gardens<br/>London<br/>SW7 1NH<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travel to Libya is ill-advised at the moment due to the ongoing civil war. And that&rsquo;s a shame, because this beautiful land has much to offer the intrepid traveller.</p>
<p>One of the largest countries in African, Libya boasts a stunning Mediterranean coastline, gorgeous desert landscapes and no fewer than seven UNESCO World Heritage Sites. These ancient sites are a reminder that Libya&rsquo;s history has always been tumultuous: before Gaddafi&rsquo;s regime and the ensuing civil war, the country endured Greek, Roman and Italian rule.</p>
<p>But Libya has more to offer than war stories. From the mystical desert town of Ghadames to the stunning Sahara Desert, this is a land of empty beaches, ancient mountain trails and shimmering oases. It is a land where sand dunes stretch to the heavens, palm trees reflect in desert lakes and prehistoric rock carvings decorate the dramatic Akakus Mountains.</p>
<p>Rural Libya is characterised by neatly cultivated olive groves, fat lemons dangling from trees and remote Berber settlements. In the cities, merchants sell wares in rose-scented souks, flogging silver, spices, henna, hijabs and Tuareg scarves. The smell of spicy lentil soup and Benghazi seafood hangs deliciously in the air.</p>
<p>The population of Libya is mostly of Arab and Berber descent. Berbers make up about 10% of inhabitants and live in more remote areas. The rest of the population lives largely in coastal cities like <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tripoli">Tripoli</a> and Benghazi, although recent fighting has forced many to flee.</p>
<p>Libyan hospitality is legendary and its people love showing travellers around. But tourism faltered after the Arab Spring and has been paralyzed by the ensuing Civil War. At the time of writing, tourist visas were not being issued and most tour companies have closed their doors &ndash; many guides now work as fixers for war reporters instead.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s impossible to say how current events will pan out, but, like many travellers, we hope the doors to Libya will swing open again soon.</p><p>Travel to Libya is ill-advised at the moment due to the ongoing civil war. And that&rsquo;s a shame, because this beautiful land has much to offer the intrepid traveller.</p>
<p>One of the largest countries in African, Libya boasts a stunning Mediterranean coastline, gorgeous desert landscapes and no fewer than seven UNESCO World Heritage Sites. These ancient sites are a reminder that Libya&rsquo;s history has always been tumultuous: before Gaddafi&rsquo;s regime and the ensuing civil war, the country endured Greek, Roman and Italian rule.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
