<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Liechtenstein" ColCode="lie" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="li" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Liechtenstein]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Liechtenstein has a temperate, alpine climate, with warm, wet summers and mild winters.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mediumweights with some lightweight clothing is advised for summer.<br />Warmer heavyweights are worn in winter. Waterproofs are needed<br />throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are limited rail routes within the country &ndash; buses are the easiest way to get around.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving is an easy way to get around Liechtenstein.</p>r<p>Liechtenstein has good roads, though roadworks are a persistent disruption throughout the week and weekend, and the lack of alternative routes can mean long, backlogged detours.</p><p>Due to the size of the country, there are no coach routes, only scheduled bus routes.</p><p>Registered taxis are available for hire throughout Liechtenstein, and all are fitted with meters. However, fares are very high, with a premium on journeys that cross borders.</p><p>A full national driving licence is required.</p><p>The speed limit is a torturously slow 50kph (31mph) throughout Liechtenstein &ndash; up to 80kph (50mph) for some very short stretches &ndash; and this is enforced with heavy fines and even imprisonment. During winter, all cars require winter tyres, and if you plan to leave the main road, you need snow chains too. Drivers and passengers are required to wear seat belts.</p><p>Both the AA (<a href="http://www.theaa.com" target="_blank">www.theaa.com</a>) and RAC (<a href="http://www.rac.co.uk" target="_blank">www.rac.co.uk</a>) cover Liechtenstein as part of their European travel packages.</p><p>Major international car hire companies, such as Sixt (<a href="http://www.sixt.com" target="_blank">www.sixt.com</a>)&nbsp;and Avis (<a href="http://www.avis.ch" target="_blank">www.avis.ch</a>) are represented, along with a number of local car hire companies.</p><p>As Liechtenstein is a small and green country, bicycles are an excellent way to get between the towns. As well as cycling on the road, there are more than 100km (62 miles) of cycle paths &ndash; though if you wish to venture off these, you need a good mountain bike. It's possible to hire bikes at the Liechtenstein Centre in Vaduz.</p><p>The speed limit is a torturously slow 50kph (31mph) throughout Liechtenstein &ndash; up to 80kph (50mph) for some very short stretches &ndash; and this is enforced with heavy fines and even imprisonment. During winter, all cars require winter tyres, and if you plan to leave the main road, you need snow chains too. Drivers and passengers are required to wear seat belts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For buses in Liechtenstein, you can get a single ticket, a one-day ticket (equivalent in price to two single tickets) and a weekly ticket. The fee varies according to how many zones you travel through.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Liechtenstein</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">zurich</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Liechtenstein</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">paris</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Liechtenstein</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">munich</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Liechtenstein</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">milan</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Liechtenstein</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">geneva</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The nearest international airport to Liechtenstein is Zurich Airport in neighbouring <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland">Switzerland</a>. Flights are served by the national airline, Swiss (<a href="http://www.swiss.com" target="_blank">www.swiss.com</a>). From the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you can also book direct flights to Zurich through British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>). There is also a good selection of flights to Switzerland from other countries, including direct flights from North America.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/z%C3%BCrich">Zurich</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 1 hour 40 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours 40 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The departure tax is included in all flight tickets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best rail access to Liechtenstein is via the Swiss border stations at Buchs or Sargans, or via the Austrian station at Feldkirch. All are well served by express trains and connected with Vaduz by bus. From Buchs, it takes just 15 minutes by bus or 10 minutes by taxi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although Liechtenstein does not have a motorway within its borders, it is easily accessible in all directions (Switzerland to the west, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a> to the north, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/austria">Austria</a> to the east and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a> to the south) by major road arteries. From the UK, you can travel through the Channel Tunnel with Eurotunnel (tel: +44 8443 353 535; <a href="http://www.eurotunnel.com" target="_blank">www.eurotunnel.com</a>) to Calais, then drive on highways through <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> and Switzerland for nine hours to reach Liechtenstein.</p><p>Although you do not need a vignette (road tax sticker) for Liechtenstein, you do need one for both neighbouring countries, Austria and Switzerland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Swisscom payphones are widely available, where payment can be made by card and sometimes cash.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handsets can be hired at the Telecom shops in Vaduz and Eschen. Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone operators. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet access is available in phone booths operated by Swisscom. Charges are payable by phonecard or credit card. Public access is also available at the Telecom shops in Vaduz and Eschen.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Liechtenstein's media scene is diminutive. The newspaper circulation figures barely hit 10,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post to European destinations takes four to seven days, although can be delivered in one to two days if posted with the urgent service.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1200 and 1345-1830, Sat 0800-1100, (Mon-Fri 0745-1800, Sat 0800-1100 in Vaduz).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the architecture in Balzers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located in the far south-western corner of the country, Balzers is most renowned for its Burg Gutenberg, a 12th century castle teetering on a rocky hill over the centre of town. But it's also well-known for its two ornate chapels – the Chapel of St. Peter and the Chapel of Mariahilf.</p>]]><p><b>Count the chapels</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are also beautiful chapels to be found elsewhere in Liechtenstein. Perhaps the best of the bunch are the beautiful 9th century St Mamerten chapel in the old part of the village in Triesen (renowned for its 14th century tower steeple) and the Chapel of St Joseph in Planken.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Ski and Winter Sports Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A must-see for ski lovers, this museum (<a href="http://www.skimuseum.li" target="_blank">www.skimuseum.li</a>) explores the sport's long history. Former ski racer Noldi Beck has gathered more than 1,000 exhibits taking in a century of ski history, from 1920s ski-bending appliances to trophies from contemporary ski competitions.</p>]]><p><b>Go skiing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Liechtenstein is a skier's haven. Ski at Malbun (1,600m/5,250 ft) and Steg (1,300m/4,250 ft). At Malbun, there are several ski lifts and a natural ice rink. Steg has a sledge run as well as its famous cross-country skiing loop with three distances (4 km/2.5 miles, 12 km/7 miles and 12.5 km/7.8 miles).</p>]]><p><b>Hike around the castle ruins of Schellenberg</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Actually two sets of castle ruins, most visitors climb up to the Obere Burg (Upper Castle) for a glimpse of history and a spectacular panorama. Originally built in 1250, then extended over a century, today the castle ruins are popular spots for local medieval festivals and recreations.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the Museum of Fine Arts</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Founded in 2000, the Kunstmuseum (<a href="http://www.kunstmuseum.li" target="_blank">www.kunstmuseum.li</a>) is the national art gallery, and focuses on international contemporary art. Housed in an eye-catching modernist black cube in central Vaduz, the collection takes in art from the 19th century right up to the modern day. Artists featured include Rembrandt, Rubens and Van Dyck.</p>]]><p><b>Pop in to the Postage Stamp Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Founded in 1930, this exhibition – one part of the Liechtenstein National Museum – tells the story of Liechtenstein's postal service throughout the country's history. The main focus is the series of postage stamps issued by the Principality since 1912, including original designs, test prints and needle plates, though the historical postal service equipment are also highlights.</p>]]><p><b>Saddle up</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As well as means of transport, cycling is a popular recreational sport in Liechtenstein, so why not cycle in the valleys and lower-lying areas of the country? There are 96 km (56 miles) of cycling trails on both sides of the River Rhine. Mountain bikers may also use the hiking trails.</p>]]><p><b>Spend a day or two in Schaan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Schaan is Liechtenstein's largest municipality and boasts several tourist attractions. Local highlights include the St Maria zum Trost Chapel, DoMus cultural centre and a series of Roman excavations. Schaan also boasts some of the best restaurants and bars in the country.</p>]]><p><b>Take a bird’s eye view of Lichtenstein</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Those who want to see the country from a new perspective can also paraglide through the mountains of Liechtenstein – and beyond. For experienced paragliders, there are several launchpads across the country, while beginners can try a taster course with an experienced instructor, including a tandem flight.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hike</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of hiking opportunities in Liechtenstein, and you will find hiking maps at the tourist office in Vaduz. One of the most famous hikes is from Gaflei, at 1,500m (4,920ft). This is the starting point for the <em>Fürstensteig –</em> a winding path along the high ridge that divides the Rhine and Samina valleys.</p>]]><p><b>Take a tour of the Prince's Wine Cellars</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the country's long viticultural history on a tour of the Prince's Wine Cellars in Vaduz (<a href="http://www.hofkellerei.li" target="_blank">www.hofkellerei.li</a>). Visitors can take a tour, which includes a walk through the vineyards, which are perfect for growing Pinot Noir and Chardonnay, a stroll through the atmospheric basement and the chance to try a range of princely wines.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Vaduz Castle (Schloss Vaduz)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wonder at the Liechtenstein royal family home and the capital's most renowned landmark, Vaduz Castle. The original keep was built in the 12th century, but it was extended in the 16th and 17th centuries to become the impressive structure that today looms high above Vaduz.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around the Liechtenstein National Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In a building that dates back to 1438, which has previously been a royal tavern, a customs house and a government building, is this fascinating national museum. There are hundreds of artefacts on display in the permanent exhibition here, including royal crowns, natural history specimens and nationalist paintings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$4.8 billion (2009).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Specialist machinery, dental products, electronics, vehicle parts and hardware</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Agricultural products, raw materials, energy products, machinery, and metal goods</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>EU and the USA</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The population of Liechtenstein is amongst the world's most prosperous. Financial services are the main component of the economy. Dairy and arable farming account for the bulk of agriculture. The manufacturing industry processes and recycles metals, producing machine tools and precision instruments.<br />
<br />
The country has vital economic links with Switzerland, based upon a customs union, and uses the Swiss Franc as currency. Liechtenstein joined the European Free Trade Association (EFTA) in 1991 and the European Economic Area (EEA) in 1995. The unemployment rate was a mere 1.5% in 2008.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Liechtenstein has a traditional and formal business culture. Business visitors should schedule appointments in advance, be punctual, stand when introduced to someone, greet with a firm handshake, exchange business cards upon meeting, and address contacts with their personal title and surname.</p>
<p>For business meetings, expect a strict agenda, attention to detail, and for everything to be recorded in writing. You should avoid asking your hosts personal questions. Formal business attire is expected and visitors should expect a strict hierarchy with decisions made only at a senior level. Any agreements made are expected to be followed by the letter.</p>
<p>Times to avoid business visits include the Easter holiday, the second half of July and August, and the week after Christmas.</p>
<p>Although there is no conference association in Liechtenstein, a number of hotels have conference facilities and can organise conventions: L&ouml;wen in Vaduz, Schaanerhof in Schaan, Meierhof in Triesen, Kulm in Triesenberg, Gorfion and Malbuner-Hof in Malbun/Triesenberg.</p><p>Typically Mon-Fri 0800-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Liechtensteinische Industrie und Handelskammer (Chamber of Industry and Commerce)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 237 5511
					Website:http://www.lihk.li
					Address: ,Josef Rheinberger-Strasse 11,FL- Vaduz,9490]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Liechtensteiner cuisine is greatly influenced by neighbouring Austria and Switzerland, as well as by countries further afield, like France and Germany. Yet it also has a distinct gastronomic culture of its own. For example, the twin culinary pillars of cheese and soup feature far more often in Liechtenstein than elsewhere – at least one will make an appearance at every meal.</p><p>Foodie visitors to Liechtenstein have diverse options. They can experience traditional hearty dishes served in a rustic mountain hut, or formal fine dining in a luxury gourmet restaurant.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><em>&bull; K&auml;skn&ouml;pfle mit Apfelmus</em> (a doughy pasta-like cheese dish with apple sauce)<br />
<em>&bull;Rheintaler Ribelmais</em> (similar to polenta, but only served in the Rhine Valley)<br />
<em>&bull; Schwartenmagen</em> (pickled meat in jelly)<br />
<em>&bull; </em>M&uuml;esli (uncooked rolled oats, fruit and nuts soaked in water or juice)<br />
<em>&bull; Schnitzel</em> (a breaded cutlet of wafer-thin pork meat, served with French fries)<br />
<em>&bull;R&ouml;sti</em> (coarsely grated potato, flattened into a pancake and fried)</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 15% service charge is included in most bills.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>16 for wine, beer and cider, 18 for spirits and spirit-based beverages</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For a small country, Liechtenstein has surprisingly rich and varied after-dark entertainment.</p><p>When it comes to cinemas and live entertainment, there are several options. The best cinema is TaKino in Schaan (<a href="http://www.filmclub.li" target="_blank">www.filmclub.li</a>), which offers 99 soft, velour seats for ultimate movie-watching comfort and shows everything from Hollywood films to art house flicks; while TaK, or Theater am Kirchplatz (<a href="http://www.tak.li" target="_blank">www.tak.li</a>), is the top venue for theatre, dance and classical music.</p><p>For a quiet (or not so quiet) drink, make a beeline for Städtle, a pedestrianised area of Vaduz with a wide variety of bars serving decent beer and local Liechtensteiner wine. Schaan also has a number of trendy bars, while you'll find many others in Balzers, Malbun and Nendeln.</p><p>Nightclubs are considerably rarer. Most young people head to Coco Loco Nightclub in Balzers, where a mix of DJs and live bands entertain the crowds into the early hours of the morning. However, there are several live concerts taking place during weekends throughout the year.</p><p>It's also worth remembering that it's easy to cross the border from Liechtenstein to Feldkirch in Austria, or Buchs in Switzerland, for further drinking, dancing and entertainment options.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can shop for all sorts of things in Liechtenstein. The capital, Vaduz, is the place to go for all your general retail needs, from supermarkets to department stores, and also has a range of souvenir shops for finding items that are unique to the region.</p><p>Many of the souvenirs sold in Vaduz are similar to those found in Switzerland. You will find fine embroidery and linen, expert woodcarving, delicious Swiss chocolate, handmade luxury clocks and watches, wonderfully-pungent cheeses and stylish Swiss army knives.</p><p>However, there are also a few items which are unique to Liechtenstein.</p><p>Liechtenstein is famous for its handmade ceramics and pottery, as well as items made from local Balzner marble. There are also Liechtensteiner wines available, many of which will have been recently picked from the vineyards above the souvenir shops.</p><p>But perhaps the most unique souvenirs a tourist can take from Liechtenstein are the postage stamps. All of the souvenir shops in the capital sell current and historical postage stamps, which offer colourful and graphical illustrations of the country's monarchy and major events of the last 100 years.</p><p>Be prepared that prices for souvenirs in Liechtenstein are similar to those in Switzerland – that means very expensive for the majority of foreign visitors. It is possible to find some similar souvenirs just across the Austrian border in Feldkirch for potentially half the price.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1330-1830, Sat 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide choice of hotels throughout Liechtenstein, both in cities and in the countryside.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Private pensions or guest houses offer a more personable and cheaper option than hotels, sometimes serving breakfast. There are several available in towns and rural areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide choice of hotels throughout Liechtenstein, both in cities and in the countryside.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide choice of hotels throughout Liechtenstein, both in cities and in the countryside.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The standard of health care in Liechtenstein is very high, but also very expensive. The National Hospital in Vaduz is run with private practitioners. Emergency services are available. Pharmacies are widely available.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If suddenly taken ill or involved in an accident during a visit to Liechtenstein, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available for European travellers - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). Comprehensive insurance is advised for all other nationals.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The tap water in Liechenstein is safe to drink and of high quality.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccination against tick-borne encephalitis is sometimes advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Candlemas :
							02 February </p><p>Feast of St Joseph :
							19 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Nativity of Our Lady :
							08 September </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>St Stephen's Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The customs regulations for travellers visiting Liechtenstein are the same as for <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland">Switzerland</a>. For further details, see the Switzerland section.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Swiss Franc (CHF; symbol SFr) = 100 centimes. For further information on currency, see the <em><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland">Switzerland</a></em> section.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0815-1200 and 1330-1600/1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For passport and visa regulations for Liechtenstein, please see the Switzerland passport &amp; visa section.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Liechtenstein does not issue its own visas. There are no border controls between Liechtenstein and Switzerland and, without exception, the same visa requirements apply to travellers to Liechtenstein as to travellers to Switzerland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[47.145028]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[9.553960]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>160 sq km (62 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>37,776 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>235.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vaduz.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Imperial principality with a hereditary constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Liechtenstein shares borders with Austria and Switzerland and lies between the upper reaches of the Rhine Valley and the Austrian Alps. The principality is noted for its fine vineyards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christian, predominantly Roman Catholic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Similar to northwest <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/europe">Europe</a>. The government is proposing a law on the protection of non-smokers with a smoking ban in publicly-accessible premises and in public administration buildings, this entails a smoking ban in restaurants in principle.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Adrian Hasler since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prince Hans Adam II since 1989.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although this area of Europe is believed to have been inhabited for more than 7,500 years, the history of Liechtenstein as we know it today only really began in 1719 AD. That's when Holy Roman Emperor Charles VI granted the new territory to Anton Florian of Liechtenstein, recognising it as a principality, and as a sovereign member state of the Holy Roman Empire.</p>
<p>The Napoleonic Wars during the early 19th century, which led to the fall of the Holy Roman Empire, effectively granted Liechtenstein further sovereignty, and during this century the fledgling state gradually grew its industry, financial institutions and military, though the latter was quickly disbanded (and it still doesn't have its own military).</p>
<p>Until the end of World War I, Liechtenstein was closely allied with the Austrian Empire, and later Austria-Hungary, but after the war it signed a customs and monetary union with its other neighbour, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland">Switzerland</a>.</p>
<p>Following Switzerland's lead, it remained neutral during the Second World War; though there were sympathies with the Nazi cause and it became a repository for Nazi gold and valuables.</p>
<p>Since the 1970s, Liechtenstein has utilised its low corporate tax rates to attract international companies to the country, and has become a tax haven for countless high-profile individuals and organisations. This has allowed this small country to become one of the wealthiest in the world, and its population enjoys one of the highest standards of living anywhere on Earth.</p>
<p>Hans-Adam II, the current Prince is Liechtenstein, is the world's sixth wealthiest monarch, worth an estimated US$5 billion. And this is in a country with a population of just 35,000.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; Liechtenstein is one of only two doubly-landlocked countries in the world (which means it is only surrounded by other landlocked countries). The other is <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/uzbekistan">Uzbekistan</a>.<br />
&bull; The total area of the country is just 46 sq m (120 sq km).<br />
&bull; Grauspitz is the country's highest point, at 2,599m (8,527ft). The lowest is Ruggeller Riet at 430m (1,410m). It's still higher than anywhere in Holland.<br />
&bull; Liechtenstein is the only German-speaking country not to border <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a>.<br />
&bull; The Prince is able to veto any legislation, except a referendum to become a republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Diplomatic representation]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A pocket-sized principality in the heart of Europe, Liechtenstein rarely tops anybody's bucket list of continental must-sees. Yet this tiny, landlocked nation offers more than you'd imagine: from long-standing history to sky-high mountains; cliff-hanging castles to odd cultural quirks.</p><p>Many of Liechtenstein's historical highlights are located in the capital, Vaduz. While this tiny town may only have around 5,000 inhabitants, it also boasts an array of fascinating museums and galleries – including the Liechtenstein National Museum, the Museum of Fine Arts and the FIS Ski and Winter Sports Museum – as well as the atmospheric Prince's Wine Cellars and the neo-Gothic Vaduz Cathedral. All these attractions are watched over by the pretty Vaduz Castle, which remains the official residence of the Prince of Liechtenstein.</p><p>Vaduz isn't Liechtenstein's only town of historical note. The second town, Schaan, is actually larger than Vaduz, and comes with its very own impressive church and Roman remains, while Balzers in the south west boasts what is perhaps Liechtenstein's most arresting fortification. There are also beautiful chapels to be found in lesser-visited villages like Triesen and Planken.</p><p>And yet the true star of Liechtenstein is the remarkable nature. This country has arguably the most impressive landscape in Europe. Most of the peaks in Liechtenstein soar more than 2,000m (6,562ft) into the sky, making Liechtenstein a premier destination for skiing, hiking and mountain biking. Its shimmering lakes are also a big draw for swimmers.</p><p>As well as its permanent attractions, Liechtenstein also excels when it comes to unusual events. Some of the fun annual highlights include the Monster Concert (where troupes of musicians and dancers dress in outlandish costumes and bang drums), the Cattle Drive (where cows and sheep are festooned in colourful garments and adorned with bells) and the LGT Alpine Marathon (where competitors from around the globe run for 26 miles through the mountains).</p><p>Factor in Liechtenstein's dynamic dining, drinking and live music offerings, and you have a pocket sized nation that punches well above its weight.</p><p>Liechtenstein seems to be the forgotten corner of Europe; tucked in between Switzerland and Austria, this beautiful country is often overlooked, despite being more than a fair match for its neighbours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
