<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Lithuania" ColCode="ltu" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="lt" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Lithuania]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Temperate climate, but with considerable temperature variations. Summer is warm with relatively mild weather in spring and autumn. Winter, which lasts from November to mid-March, can be very cold. Rainfall is distributed throughout the year with the heaviest rainfall in August. Heavy snowfalls are common in the winter months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no scheduled internal flights. Lithuania's compact size means it makes more sense to get around by car, bus or train.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local ferries connect Klaipeda and the Curonian Spit. Klaipeda is also home to yacht clubs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lietuvos Gelezinkeliai (tel: +370 7005 5111; <a href="http://www.litrail.lt" target="_blank">www.litrail.lt</a>) provides good connections from Vilnius to Kaunas, Klaipeda and Siauliai. Twice-daily passenger trains (including a sleeper train) connect Vilnius with the Baltic coast. Though the train does not stop in Palanga, the major resort on the Baltic coast, passengers to Palanga usually get off at Kretinga station or in Klaipeda and then reach Palanga by bus.</p>
<p>Passengers to Neringa (Nida, Juodkrante) can go to Klaipeda by train and then take a bus. Suburban trains going to Ignalina connect Vilnius with the popular lake district of the National Park. You can reach the ancient Trakai Castle by taking the suburban train going to Trakai.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>There is a good network of roads within the country.&nbsp;Modern four-lane motorways connect Vilnius with Klaipeda, Kaunas and Panevezys.</p><p>A good coach network connects Vilnius with major towns and cities around Lithuania and beyond. You can buy tickets online at <a href="http://www.autobusubilietai.lt" target="_blank">www.autobusubilietai.lt</a>.</p><p>Most European nationals should be in possession of EU pink format driving licences. Otherwise, a national driving licence is sufficient, if supported by photo-bearing ID.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in towns, 70-90kph (43-56mph) on country roads and 100-130kph (62-81mph) on motorways.  Winter conditions can be severe in Lithuania so winter tyres are a legal requirement from November to March. Dipped headlights are also compulsory all year round.</p><p>Available from local and international firms.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in towns, 70-90kph (43-56mph) on country roads and 100-130kph (62-81mph) on motorways.  Winter conditions can be severe in Lithuania so winter tyres are a legal requirement from November to March. Dipped headlights are also compulsory all year round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public transport in urban districts includes buses and trolleybuses, which usually run from 0500 to 2300, but times do vary between routes. You can buy tickets either at news kiosks before boarding or from the driver. Minibuses are less crowded but more expensive. Taxis<strong> </strong>display illuminated <em>Taksi</em> signs and can be hailed in the street, found at taxi ranks or ordered by phone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating direct flights to Lithuania from the UK include Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) and Wizz (<a href="http://www.wizzair.com" target="_blank">www.wizzair.com</a>). You can find cheap fares year-round, with prices rising over busy periods such as Christmas, Easter and school summer holidays. If travelling from the USA, the quickest routes are via Amsterdam, Frankfurt or Helsinki.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lithuania/vilnius-airport">Vilnius Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 40 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 11 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lt60.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Kaunas International Airport </b><b>Tel: </b><b>Palanga International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.palanga-airport.lt]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Vilnius Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.vilnius-airport.lt<p>The airport is located roughly 6km (4 miles) south of Vilnius city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+370 6124 44442</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong>&nbsp;Klaipeda is connected by trade routes with foreign ports. It also has a cruise-ship terminal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lietuvos Gelezinkeliai (tel: +370 7005 5111; <a href="http://www.litrail.lt" target="_blank">www.litrail.lt</a>) runs Lithunia's well-developed rail network. International services connect Vilnius with Minsk, Belarus, with onward connections to Moscow, St Petersburg and Warsaw.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lithuania has direct road connections to Latvia, Belarus, Poland and the Russian exclave Kaliningrad.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet is available; public access is at the Lithuanian National Library and increasingly at Internet centres and cafes in main cities and towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lithuania's TV market is dominated by commercial channels. The radio market is similarly competitive, with more than 30 stations competing for listeners and advertisers. Lithuania's media are free and operate independently of the state, and there are no Government-owned newspapers. However, politicians do occasionally attempt to influence editorial policy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post to Western Europe takes up to six days. There is a variety of private companies offering express mail services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Action sports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Partake in some action sports - Nida, a village on the spit surrounded by endless stretches of white sand, makes a true paradise for sailing, windsurfing, paragliding and kiting.</p>]]><p><b>Amber Museum-Gallery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See Palanga's Amber Museum-Gallery (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ambergallery.lt/">www.ambergallery.lt</a>) and botanical park. To the south, lies the city of Klaipeda, an important seaport as well as the main centre for ferry connections.</p>]]><p><b>Days of the Capital festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit during the Days of the Capital festival in September and be spoilt with carnivals, fairs, concerts and fireworks, taking place in all streets and squares of the capital (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.vilniusfestivals.lt/">www.vilniusfestivals.lt</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Extreme sports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try out more extreme sports, such as hot-air ballooning and gliding. There is also the opportunity to leap off Vilnius' TV Tower, the tallest bungee jump of its kind in Europe.</p>]]><p><b>Forests</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Witness the forests that cover a quarter of Lithuania, a predominantly flat country. There are five national parks and numerous other conservation areas.</p>]]><p><b>Gediminas Tower</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy a view over Vilnius after climbing the Gediminas Tower, high on a hill in the centre of the city.</p>]]><p><b>Hike</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike in the Curonian Spit National Park (another UNESCO World Heritage site) (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.nerija.lt/">www.nerija.lt</a>), on the peninsula separating the Curonian Lagoon from the Baltic Sea, where visitors can explore a range of large sand dunes and several pine forests. Rare flora and fauna are to be found here.</p>]]><p><b>International Folklore Festival (Skamba Skamba Kankliai)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit craft fairs, taste traditional dishes, join song and glee parties and listen to psalms during the International Folklore Festival (Skamba Skamba Kankliai), held in Vilnius' Old Town in May.</p>]]><p><b>Kaunas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Look around Kaunas, Lithuania's 'city of museums', which boasts the Devil Museum, a memorial to those who suffered during the Nazi occupation and a museum dedicated to the works of the Lithuanian painter, Ciurlionis. There are also three theatres, some 11th-century castle ruins and the old City Hall.</p>]]><p><b>Kernave</b></p><![CDATA[<p>View the five strange grassy mounds marking Lithuania's ancient capital at Kernave (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.kernave.org/">www.kernave.org</a>), one of Lithuania's UNESCO World Heritage sites.</p>]]><p><b>Lakes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the many lakes in the Trakai National Park and the hills, lakes and uplands in the Aukstaitija and Zemaitija National Parks.</p>]]><p><b>Mardi Gras</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the Mardi Gras festivities held in various Lithuanian cities and small towns. The procession in Vilnius Old Town at the beginning of February remains the most renowned.</p>]]><p><b>Nida lighthouse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Behold the lighthouse in Nida that was built in 1874. The Thomas Mann Cultural Centre (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.mann.lt/">www.mann.lt</a>), situated in the house where the German writer spent his holidays between 1930 and 1932, is also close by. There is also the award-winning Park of Soviet Sculptures at Gruto Parkas, which reflects some of Lithuania's grim past.</p>]]><p><b>Palanga</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Have some old-fashioned fun in popular seaside resorts. Palanga and Kursiu Nerija (with the settlements of Nida and Juodkrante) are famous for their clean white-sand beaches, natural sand dunes and pine forests.</p>]]><p><b>St Ann's Church</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the many interesting churches in Vilnius, including the gothic St Ann's Church and St Peter and St Paul's Church, which houses the body of St Casimieras, one of Lithuania's most revered dukes.</p>]]><p><b>Trakai</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit <strong>Trakai</strong>, an ancient capital of Lithuania. Situated on the shore of the picturesque <strong>Lake Galve</strong>, the city has a castle dating from the 14th century.</p>]]><p><b>University of Vilnius</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't miss the historic <strong>University of Vilnius</strong> (website: <a href="http://www.vu.lt/" target="_blank">www.vu.lt</a>), which was granted its charter in 1579.</p>]]><p><b>Vilnius</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the historic capital city of <strong>Vilnius</strong>, founded in 1323. Its <strong>Old Town</strong> is the biggest in Europe and is also a UNESCO World Heritage site. The capital's heart is the beautiful and spacious <strong>Gediminas Square</strong>, which is dominated by the classical <strong>Cathedral</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$28.6 billion (2007).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Mineral products, textiles and clothing, machinery and equipment, chemicals, wood and wood products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Mineral products, machinery and equipment, transport equipment, chemicals, textiles and clothing.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Russian Federation, Germany, Poland, Latvia and Estonia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lithuania has historically been the least developed of the Baltic republics, with a smaller industrial base and greater dependence on agriculture, prior to rapid industrialisation during the Soviet era. Sugar beet, cereals, potatoes and vegetables are the main crops. Electrical, electronic and optical goods and light machinery are the main industrial products.<br /><br />The government plans to reduce the percentage but faces major problems regarding waste disposal and alternative energy sources. Further privatisations of state assets, principally in the banking and transport sectors, were completed in 2002.<br /><br />Following a 90% endorsement in a national referendum held in May 2003, Lithuania joined the EU on 1 May 2004.<br /><br />Lithuania's trade patterns have gradually shifted during the 1990s towards the West, and the European Union now accounts for just under half of all Lithuanian trade. Lithuania has recovered from the serious knock-on effects of the 1998 Russian financial crisis, and growth was 8% in 2007.<br /><br />Inflation was 5.4% last year and unemployment at 5.7%.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business is conducted in a fairly formal manner and a smart appearance is important, with suit and tie expected for business meetings, although new technology-based industries have got behind the trend of dressing down in more casual gear. Appointments should be made in advance. Handshakes are the normal way to start any meeting and gifts are appreciated, especially luxury items. English is used for international commerce but knowledge of German, Russian or Polish may also be useful. Business hours are normally Monday to Friday 0900-1800.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1400-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>European Committee of the Government of the Republic of Lithuania</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (5) 266 3827
					Website:http://www.euro.lt
					Address: ,Gedimino ave 11,LT- Vilnius,1103]]><b>LITEXPO (Information on Conferences/Conventions)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (5) 245 1800
					Website:http://www.litexpo.lt
					Address: ,Laisves pr 5,LT- Vilnius,4215]]><b>Association of Lithuanian Chambers of Commerce, Industry and Crafts</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (5) 261 2102
					Website:http://www.chambers.lt
					Address: ,J Tumo-Vaizganto 9/1-63A,LT- Vilnius,1108]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Waiter service is usual in restaurants and cafes, but self-service restaurants, bistros and snack bars are also popular.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
<em>&bull; Skilandis</em> (smoked meat).<br />
<em>&bull; Salti barsciai</em> (cold soup).<br />
<em>&bull; Vedarai</em> (potato sausage) and <em>bulviniai blynai</em> (potato pancakes). <br />
&bull; Smoked eel is a famous Baltic delicacy. <br />
&bull; Mild white curd cheese, best served with honey.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Restaurant bills include a tip. Otherwise, tips are discretionary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cinemas can be found in all towns. Lithuanian theatres, most of which are concentrated in the capital, are also renowned. The Jaunimo <em>teatras </em>(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.jaunimoteatras.lt">www.jaunimoteatras.lt</a>) in Vilnius are famous throughout the country. Opera and ballet are staged in the city at the Vilnius Opera Theatre and Kaunas has a Musical Theatre. Puppet shows are staged for children in Vilnius and Kaunas. There are restaurants with live music as well as numerous discos and nightclubs with variety shows in the larger towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Baltic amber can be purchased in various forms, especially jewellery. Linen goods, clay pots and local crafts are also good buys. National artists sell their works in specialised art galleries in major towns.</p><p>Grocery shops open Mon-Fri 0800-2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Western-style hotels and motels have been built in Lithuania in co-operation with foreign firms. Modernisation and renovation programmes are generally concentrated in Vilnius. All major hotels in Kaunas are concentrated in the centre of the town. Meanwhile, Vilnius and the other major centres in the country enjoy an adequate range of good accommodation including large hotels and smaller pensions.</p>
<p><br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Western-style hotels and motels have been built in Lithuania in co-operation with foreign firms. Modernisation and renovation programmes are generally concentrated in Vilnius. All major hotels in Kaunas are concentrated in the centre of the town. Meanwhile, Vilnius and the other major centres in the country enjoy an adequate range of good accommodation including large hotels and smaller pensions.</p>
<p><br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Western-style hotels and motels have been built in Lithuania in co-operation with foreign firms. Modernisation and renovation programmes are generally concentrated in Vilnius. All major hotels in Kaunas are concentrated in the centre of the town. Meanwhile, Vilnius and the other major centres in the country enjoy an adequate range of good accommodation including large hotels and smaller pensions.</p>
<p><br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;If suddenly taken ill or involved in an accident during a visit to Lithuania, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available for European travellers - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). Comprehensive insurance is advised for all other nationals.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water supplies are generally reliable in cities, though it has a high mineral content and can be cloudy. Bottled or filtered water is preferable for these reasons. If travelling in rural areas, drink only bottled water. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are generally safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat. Exercise food and drink hygiene precautions, especially in rural areas.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B is present. Tuberculosis may be a threat. Tick-borne encephalitis occurs in forested areas, and vaccination is strongly advisable. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend, including those that are always celebrated on Sunday, are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Independence Day :
							16 February </p><p>Restoration of the Lithuanian State :
							11 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Mother's Day :
							06 May </p><p>Fathers' Day :
							03 June </p><p>Jonines (St John's Day) :
							24 June </p><p>Anniversary of the Coronation of King Mindaugas :
							06 July </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lithuania is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% volume, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Lithuania by persons over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco (if arriving by air).<br />
&bull; 40 cigarettes or 20 cigarillos or 10 cigars or 50g of tobacco (if arriving by other means).<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers (reduced to &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Meat and dairy products from outside the EU, narcotics, and unlicensed firearms and ammunition.</p>
<p>There are restrictions on the import of plants and plant products.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drugs, and unlicensed firearms and ammunition.</p>
<p>You need to obtain a permit to export cultural artefacts and antiques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol €) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of €500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of €2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency can be exchanged at banks and bureaux de change. There are 24-hour exchange bureaux at Gelezinkelio 6, near the main railway station and at Lietuvos Taupomasis Bankas, Savanoriu 15A in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vilnius">Vilnius</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are accepted in the main hotels, restaurants, shops and in some petrol stations. ATMs are available in most cities.</p><p>ATMs are available in most cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are not accepted by retailers and can only be exchanged at a few outlets. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700. Some banks also open Sat 0900-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lithuania is part of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60. Reductions are available for some nationals and for children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate (or consular section at embassy). Visa applicants aged 12 or over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 15 days for visa processing. Some cases may take 30 to 60 days however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals who require a Schengen visa must provide proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EU nationals staying longer than 90 days need to apply for a certificate entitling them to residence. Non-EU nationals require residence permits if staying beyond 90 days. See the Migration Department website (<a href="http://www.migracija.lt">www.migracija.lt</a>) for further details.</p>
<p>Schengen visa holders can only extend their visas in exceptional circumstances such as <em>force majeure</em> or for humanitarian reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet from within the EU, you must ensure your animal has a pet passport, microchip and valid rabies vaccination certificate. Animals from outside the EU must have a rabies vaccination and recognised veterinary certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[55.338022]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[23.874028]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>65,300 sq km (25,212 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,850,030 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>44.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vilnius.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lithuania is situated on the eastern Baltic coast and borders Latvia in the north, the Kaliningrad region of the Russian Federation and Poland in the southwest, and Belarus in the southwest and east. The geometrical centre of Europe lies in eastern Lithuania near the village of Bernotai, 25km (16 miles) north of Vilnius. The landscape alternates between lowland plains and hilly uplands and has a dense, intricate network of rivers, including the Nemunas and the Neris. Around 1.5% of the country's territory is made up of lakes, of which there are over 2,800. The majority of these lie in the east of the country and include Lake Druksiai and Lake Tauragnas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly (79%) Roman Catholic with Russian Orthodox and Protestant, including Evangelical Lutheran and Evangelical Reformist.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is customary. Normal courtesies should be observed. The Lithuanians are proud of their culture and their national heritage and visitors should take care to respect this sense of national identity.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Algirdas Butkevičius since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Dalia Grybauskaitė since 2009.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Present-day Lithuanians, along with Latvians and ancient Prussians, are descendants of the Balts, an Indo-European ethnic group that settled on the Baltic coast 4000 years ago.</p><p>The formation of Lithuania dates back to around 1009 and the region has endured a series of invasions and conquests by neighbouring countries. In the 13th century the Kingdom of Lithuania was formed and was one of the largest areas in Europe to adopt Christianity. In 1795 Lithuania was taken over by the Russian Empire, and remain under its control until 1918 when it re-established itself as a democratic state.</p><p>Its relatively brief life between the wars was dominated by border disputes with Poland and Germany as the former seized the Vilnius region in 1920 and Klaipėda, gained from the latter in 1923, was ceded following a Nazi ultimatum delivered in 1939.</p><p>In World War 2 Lithuania was occupied first by Soviet Russia and then by the Nazis until 1944 when the Red Army re-occupied the territory. It's thougth some 780,000 Lithuanians lost their lives during the war, but although partisans fought a guerrilla action against the Red Army until as late as 1952 Lithuania remained a Soviet republic until the early 1990s when it became the first former Soviet republic to restore its independence and began to develop into an economically strong country. The last Soviet troops left Lithuania in August 1993.</p><p>Lithuania is now a full member of the EU, as well as the Council of Europe, and adopted the euro as its currency in 2015. It signed up to the Schengen Agreement, effectively abolishing border controls between members. It also belongs to NATO and in 2013 became the first Baltic state to be elected to the United Nations Security Council.</p><p>Since independence Lithuania has upheld its democracy and the current president, Dalia Grybauskaitė – its first female head of state – was elected for a second term in 2014. Lithuanians enjoy one of the lowest rates of income tax in Europe – just 15 per cent.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• Internet speed in Lithuania is among the fastest in the world ranking in the top five for both uploads and downloads according to speedtest.net.</p><p>• Lithuanian-born film maker Jonas Mekas is regarded as the godfather of American avant-garde cinema.</p><p>• Vilnius is the only city wit three choirs laureates – the Brevis, Jauna Muzika and Chamber Choir of the Conservatoire – reflecting the importance of choral music in Lithuanian culture.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Lithuania]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>5246 2900.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-vilnius</p><p><b>Tel:</b>5246 2900.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0830-1645; Fri 0830-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Antakalnio str. 2<br/>Vilnius<br/>LT-10308<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Lithuania in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(0)20 7592 2840. </p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(0)20 7592 2840. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300 (consular section); Tues-Thurs 1500-1600 (visa section; appointments necessary).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>84 Gloucester Place<br/>London<br/>W1U 6AU<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Lithuania in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234-5860.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.usa.mfa.lt</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234-5860.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1200 (consular and visa sections).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2622 16th Street<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lithuania is a spellbinding land of castles, lakes and forests. Though relatively few knew of its charms until recently, Lithuania's capital, Vilnius, is one of Europe's most enchanting cities, owing especially to its Baroque old town. Then there is the Baltic shore, which may not have the sun-soaked appeal of other coasts, but is idyllic and largely unspoilt. The southernmost country in the Baltics, Lithuania is also home to vast plains parted by hills and sand dunes.</p><p>Lithuanian independence came soon after the collapse of the Soviet Union in 1991. By 1995, the transition to a full market economy had been completed. The long-running border dispute with Poland was settled with the signing of a friendship and co-operation treaty in January 1992 and negotiations with Russia led to the withdrawal of the remaining Russian troops in Lithuania in August 1993. The Russian connection remains, however, with Russians being the second largest ethnic minority in the country. The largest of the three Baltic states, Lithuania gaining EU membership in 2004, since which time the country has been thrust on to the global stage, encouraging more visitors than ever.</p><p>Most of the attraction for Lithuania lies with its natural treasures. Much of the country is verdant, with several national parks that are perfect for hikers and explorers. All around the country there are countless sprawling forests ripe for wandering, as well as numerous lakes sprinkled across the landscape.</p><p>Perhaps the country's trump card is the Baltic coastline, where beguiling wetlands brim with wildlife, most notably the thousands of bird species. There's also the Curonian Spit, a stunning 100km strip of land that separates the Curonian Lagoon from the Baltic Sea, which is covered in white sands.</p><p>Lithuania is a land of castles, lakes and forests.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
