<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Luxembourg" ColCode="lux" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="lu" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Luxembourg]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Warm weather can generally be expected from May to September. Snow is not uncommon during the winter months, especially in the higher Ardennes regions in the northern half of the country, but this is less reliable than it once was, and has led to the virtual eradication of the former (albeit small) cross-country skiing industry.</p>
<p>The north (the Ardennes region) tends to be slightly wetter and slightly colder than the south at all times of year. As has been seen in other regions, weather patterns have become far less predictable in recent years than they used to be, and visitors should be braced for anything whenever they travel.</p>
<p>Restaurants, hotels and most visitor attractions in Luxembourg City remain open all year round, and there is no specific high or low season, although certain peak times such as the National Day in June, Easter and Christmas can become booked out well in advance. Many other parts of the country however experience a very distinct low season in January and February, and tourist grinds to a halt in much of the Ardennes. Many smaller hotels and some restaurants shut completely during the winter months, and establishments that remain open often have limited opening hours.</p>
<p>Autumn can be a good time to visit the north as the annual turning of the leaves is a wonderful and free natural spectacle, many country hotels have open fires going, and the restaurants offer seasonal menus featuring local game.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Waterproofs are advisable at all times of the year. There is no discernible wet or dry season in Luxembourg, and it is best to come prepared for all eventualities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With only one airport, there are no domestic flights within Luxembourg.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only commercially navigable waterway in Luxembourg is the Moselle River. The MS Princesse Marie-Astrid offers daily pleasure cruises from Easter to September, but one-way travel is also permitted. See <a href="http://www.marie-astrid.lu" target="_blank">www.marie-astrid.lu</a>&nbsp;for fares and timetables.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national railway company, Chemins de Fer Luxembourgeois (CFL) (tel: +352 2489 2489; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.cfl.lu">www.cfl.lu</a>), runs an efficient rail service which is fully integrated with the bus network. CFL has a so-called <em>horaire cadenc&eacute;</em> schedule, meaning there is at least one train every hour to every station at the same time in every hour. Reductions are offered for weekend and holiday return tickets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Luxembourg Card:</strong> gives unlimited travel on public transport for a period of one to three days, with free entrance to up to 40 attractions.</p>
<p><strong>Day Ticket (<em>Billet Longue Dur&eacute;e</em>):</strong> a single-day ticket for unlimited travel until 0400 the next day, on all forms of public transport (not valid on sightseeing buses), with concessions for senior citizens. For further information, contact CFL.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no toll roads in Luxembourg.</p>r<p>As in the rest of Western Europe, there is an excellent network of roads and motorways in Luxembourg.</p><p>Taxis are metered, but expensive. There is a minimum charge and a 10% surcharge is applied from 2200-0600. There is also an extra 25% surcharge all day on Sundays. Taxis are plentiful in Luxembourg City (rarer elsewhere) but cannot be hailed in the street. A 10% tip is usual.</p><p>Third-party insurance is necessary. A Green Card is not obligatory but is strongly recommended. Without it, you only have the minimum legal cover in Luxembourg (if your have motor insurance at home). The Green Card tops this up to the level of cover provided by your domestic policy. For most nationalities a valid national driving licence is sufficient.</p><p>The minimum age for driving is 18. The wearing of seat belts is compulsory in the front seat and in the back, where seatbelts are fitted. Children under 12 years of age must travel in the back seats, unless they are 1.5m (5ft) or taller, or if the front seat is fitted with an appropriate ECE-approved child seat. Motorcyclists must use a dipped beam even by day. Cars must be fitted with winter tyres during conditions of sleet or snow. You must carry reflective clothing in your car in case of a breakdown.</p>
<p>The speed limit is 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (56mph) outside built-up areas, and 130kph (74mph) on motorways, except where otherwise stated.</p><p>Automobile Club du Grand-Duch&eacute; de Luxembourg (tel: 26000, emergency number in Luxembourg only or +352 450 0451; <a href="http://www.acl.lu" target="_blank">www.acl.lu</a>).</p><p>All the main agencies operate in Luxembourg. Most of the rental offices are located inside the Findel airport terminal.</p><p>You can hire bikes in most towns. Ask in the local tourist offices for more information. You can borrow bikes for a short duration for a small fee (free up to 30 minutes) from vel&rsquo;oh! stations dotted across the centre of Luxembourg City, but you must first register for this service via the website (<a href="http://www.veloh.lu" target="_blank">www.veloh.lu</a>) and pay a deposit.</p>
<p>In the Moselle Valley, RentaBike Miselerland (<a href="http://www.rentabike-miselerland.lu" target="_blank">www.rentabike-miselerland.lu</a>) has around a dozen rental outlets, and you can return bikes to any site.</p><p>The minimum age for driving is 18. The wearing of seat belts is compulsory in the front seat and in the back, where seatbelts are fitted. Children under 12 years of age must travel in the back seats, unless they are 1.5m (5ft) or taller, or if the front seat is fitted with an appropriate ECE-approved child seat. Motorcyclists must use a dipped beam even by day. Cars must be fitted with winter tyres during conditions of sleet or snow. You must carry reflective clothing in your car in case of a breakdown.</p>
<p>The speed limit is 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (56mph) outside built-up areas, and 130kph (74mph) on motorways, except where otherwise stated.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luxembourg City has municipal bus services, for which you can buy single-journey flat-fare tickets or all-day tickets. The former 'short-duration' ticket is valid for two hours from purchase on the whole of Luxembourg's public transport network, and also allows transits between city and country buses and trains. Ten-journey tickets are also available, but you must buy these advance. A comprehensive network of public buses connects most towns and villages. Tickets are also valid on domestic trains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Luxembourg</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">paris</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Luxembourg</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">london</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">*8.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">**6.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Luxembourg</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">brussels</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Luxembourg</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">amsterdam</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.30</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Luxair (<a href="http://www.luxair.lu" target="_blank">www.luxair.lu</a>), which operates direct flights from numerous destinations within Europe, including London. Other airlines flying direct to Luxembourg from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: Luxembourg Airport.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 1 hour 10 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 10 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in ticket prices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Luxembourg Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.lux-airport.lu<p>Luxembourg Airport is located 8km (5 miles) east of Luxembourg City centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+352 24640</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luxembourg is land-locked and has no seaports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The quickest route by train from the UK is through the Channel Tunnel with connections from Paris Gare de l'Est (journey time - 3 to 4 hours) or Brussels to Luxembourg. Eurostar (tel: +44 1233 617 575, in the UK; <a href="http://www.eurostar.com" target="_blank">www.eurostar.com</a>)&nbsp;operates direct high-speed trains from London St Pancras to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a>&nbsp;Gare du Nord and to Brussels Midi/Zuid. It takes 2 hours 15 minutes from London to Paris and 2 hours to Brussels.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>InterRail Benelux Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Belgium, Luxembourg and the Netherlands. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Also available from Voyages-sncf.com</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The quickest way to cross the channel is by driving the car onto Eurotunnel trains.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel (tel: +44 8443 353 535, in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>; <a href="http://www.eurotunnel.com" target="_blank">www.eurotunnel.com</a>) runs shuttle trains for all types of vehicles between Folkestone in Kent, and Calais, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>. The journey takes about 35 minutes from platform to platform and around one hour from motorway to motorway.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Alternatively, car ferries operate frequently between Dover and Calais, and Dover and Dunkirk. From both French ports, the quickest route is to take the motorway to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brussels">Brussels</a> via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lille">Lille</a> (A25, then head south through Namur along the E411 to Luxembourg). In total, the journey from London (including the ferry crossing) takes approximately seven hours.</p><p>From the Channel ports or the Calais Eurotunnel terminal, driving takes around 4 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public telephone boxes are becoming fewer in number as the growth in mobile phone use reduces the need for them. Using one requires either a phone card (available from newsagents and post offices) or a credit card. Coin-operated phones have been phased out.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is excellent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are few internet cafes in Luxembourg, but most hotels offer Wi-Fi services either free or for a small fee. The internet terminals in Luxembourg City&rsquo;s municipal library (off Place d&rsquo;Armes) are free to use. Many caf&eacute;s are also free Wi-Fi hotspots. Hot City (<a href="http://www.hotcity.lu/www_laptop_en" target="_blank">www.hotcity.lu/www_laptop_en</a>) is a pay-to-use wireless network accessible throughout Luxembourg City.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luxembourg has a long tradition of operating radio and TV services for pan-European audiences, including those in France, Germany and the UK thanks to the Luxembourg-based media group RTL. Today, RTL's television and radio stations (RTL Tele Letzebuerg and RTL Radio Letzebuerg) remain key players in media markets across Europe. The country is also home to Europe's largest satellite operator, Societ&eacute; Europ&eacute;enne des Satellites (SES), which operates the Astra satellite fleet. Nordliicht TV broadcasts in northern Luxembourg. Other radio networks include Den Neien Radio, a commercial network, Radio ARA, which has music and some English-language programmes, EldoRadio which broadcasts pop music and Honnert,7 (100.7), a public, cultural station.<br />
<br />
There are several daily newspapers including the <em>Luxemburger Wort</em> and <em>Tageblatt</em>. The website of the former (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.wort.lu">www.wort.lu</a>) has an English-language version 352 (www.352luxmag.lu) is a regular publication in English, but it no longer printed in paper format. Instead, magazines can be downloaded via the website.<br />
<br />
Freedom of speech is guaranteed by the constitution.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Post to other European destinations takes two to four days; to the USA allow for three to seven working days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1330-1700. Smaller offices may open for only a few hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Ardennes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the scenic beauty and quiet of the Ardennes region, referred to locally as <em>Eisl&eacute;ck</em>. The area consists of forested plateaux, wooded hills and lush valleys. Head for the small town of Esch-sur-S&ucirc;re, a well-known resort surrounded by the River S&ucirc;re (<em>Sauer</em>).</p>]]><p><b>Breweries</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit breweries and sample more of the region's alcoholic produce in the towns of Bascharage and Wiltz, or arrange an overnight stay in the Béierhaascht brewery hotel, also in Bascharage.</p>]]><p><b>Clervaux</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the medieval market town of Clervaux, visit the 12th-century castle - now home to government offices, the tourist office, a small war museum on the 1944-1945 Ardennes offensive (the famous 'Battle of the Bulge'), and a renowned collection of documentary art photography, the <em>Family of Man</em>, by Edward Steichen (note: the latter is closed until 2013 for essential renovation work).</p>]]><p><b>Echternach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Further east, in the town of Echternach, see a colourful religious dancing procession, which takes place annually on Whit Tuesday, attracting pilgrims from the world over. The town's seventh century Benedictine Abbey (now housing a museum) and St Willibrord's Basilica are well worth visiting, as is the distinctive 15th-century town hall.</p>]]><p><b>Galleries and museums</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get cultural in the capital's numerous galleries and museums. Highlights include the National Museum of Natural History, the National Museum of History and Art and the Museum of the City of Luxembourg.</p>]]><p><b>Luxembourg City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wine and dine al fresco in Luxembourg City's charming main square, the Place d'Armes. The area known as the Grund, near the River Alzette, also has many lively cafes and restaurants; it can be reached via a lift down through the ancient rock.</p>]]><p><b>Luxembourg City old town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the delightful old centre of the capital, Luxembourg City. See the grand squares and winding, cobblestone streets. Visit the underground tunnels, known as casemates, and hop on the special open-air tourist train through the Pétrusse Valley. See the changing of the guard at the Palais Grand Ducal, the Grand Duke's official residence, which can also be toured in July and August. Other attractions in the city include the Place Guillaume II (also called Knuedler), its twice-weekly market (Wednesday and Saturday); and the 17th-century Notre Dame Cathedral.</p>]]><p><b>Müllerthal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tramp around the M&uuml;llerthal region (<a href="http://www.mullerthal.lu/en" target="_blank">www.mullerthal.lu/en</a>), Luxembourg's 'Little Switzerland'. Dense forests, crystal-clear brooks and spectacular rock formations combine to make this one of the country's most popular areas for walking and hiking. The main resorts are Berdorf, Beaufort and Larochette. The latter two both have medieval castles.</p>]]><p><b>Plateau du Kirchberg</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head for the modern district on the Plateau du Kirchberg (reached via the Pont Grand Duchesse Charlotte - the capital's most impressive bridge); it's home to a thriving international finance centre, many European institutions and Luxembourg's biggest cinema complex and shopping mall.</p>]]><p><b>Rock climbing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Harness up and go rock climbing; there are some good ascents and facilities available near Berdorf in the Müllerthal region.</p>]]><p><b>Schengen</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the small village of Schengen, where the Moselle marks the meeting of three countries (Luxembourg, France and Germany), which has become internationally known after the 'Schengen Agreement' was signed here in 1995.</p>]]><p><b>Thermal health treatments</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pamper yourself with thermal health treatments, and enjoy the sports and leisure facilities in the spa town of Mondorf-les-Bains.</p>]]><p><b>Upper Sûre National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Splash out on some water sports: located within the Upper Sûre National Park (an area of outstanding beauty) is the country's drinking water reservoir, where a barrage dam (the Staudamm) has created a beautiful lake.</p>]]><p><b>Vianden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Vianden, be impressed by a magnificent castle, built between the 11th and 14th centuries and restored in the 20th century. The castle overlooks the town from a rocky perch. For a bird's-eye view, ride the chairlift to the viewing platform on the hillside, 450m (1,476ft) above both castle and town. Another equally impressive castle can be visited at Bourscheid, around 10km (7 miles) from Vianden.</p>]]><p><b>Wine-tasting tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Indulge yourself in a wine-tasting tour in the southeast. The River Moselle flows through Luxembourg's main wine-producing region (referred to as 'the Moselle' or d'Musel), and a number of the larger wineries offer tours of their cellars (<em>caves</em>), usually for a small fee, with tasting included. Smaller wineries welcome visitors, but require advance appointments for practical purposes. Boat-cruises on the river are also available (<a href="http://www.visitmoselle.lu" target="_blank">www.visitmoselle.lu</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$62.9 billion (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, steel products, chemicals, rubber products and glass.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Minerals, metals, food and quality consumer goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Belgium, France, China and UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luxembourg is one of the most prosperous countries in Western Europe. Two very different industries (banking and steel) have historically been the mainstays of the economy. The steel industry has ceased to be so dominant as other industries, notably chemicals, rubber, plastics, metal products and light manufacturing have prospered.</p>
<p>The banking and finance sector is also in a healthy condition: companies originally attracted to Luxembourg by favourable banking secrecy laws and low taxation have prospered despite the gradual harmonisation of taxes and tariffs across the EU. There is also a small but healthy agricultural sector mainly producing crops.</p>
<p>In 2010, growth was 3.4%, with inflation at 2.1% and unemployment was 5.5%. The Luxembourg economy has long been linked with that of Belgium, initially through the 1921 economic union, supplemented by a further treaty in 1958 and latterly, by mutual membership of the EU. Luxembourg was an inaugural adopter of the Euro at the beginning of 1999.</p>
<p>The location of the Grand Duchy of Luxembourg at the heart of the EU ensures its status as one of the most popular destinations for conferences and conventions in Western Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople are expected to wear suits. It is advisable to make prior appointments and business cards are often exchanged. Avoid business visits during Christmas and New Year, Easter week and July and August.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0830-1200 and 1400-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Luxembourg Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 423 9391
					Website:http://www.cc.lu
					Address: ,7 rue Alcide de Gasperi,,2981]]><b>Luxembourg-Congrès, Hémicycle Européen</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 4302 57751
					Website:http://www.luxcongress.lu
					Address: L- Luxembourg-Ville,1 rue de Fort Thüngen,,1499]]><b>Belgium/Luxembourg Chamber of Commerce in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 0870 246 1610
					Website:http://www.blcc.co.uk
					Address: Hessle,105 Ferriby Road,HU13 0HX,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Traditional Luxembourg cooking combines vast portion sizes that reflect German heartiness and large appetites, with flair and flamboyance that show more Franco-Belgian finesse. The preparation of local freshwater fish, trout, pike&nbsp; and crayfish&nbsp; is almost universally excellent, as are the pastries and cakes. Delicious desserts are prepared with local liqueurs, and a dash of <em>quetsch</em>, mirabelle or kirsch is added to babas or fruit cups.</p>
<p>Most aspects of restaurants and bars are similar to the rest of northern Europe. Despite their geographical proximity to the German Mosel region, Luxembourg's white Moselle wines most closely resemble those of the French Alsace region. Like the Alsace they usually feature single grape varieties, including Riesling, Pinot Blanc, Pinot Gris and Gew&uuml;rztraminer. The quality is often excellent and is gaining an increasing international reputation. The white sparkling wines, mostly classified as <em>cr&eacute;mants</em>, are also of a very high standard, and frequently enjoyed as a pre-dinner aperitif. The red wines, mainly Pinot Noir, are a rarer find, but increasing in quality each year.</p>
<p>Many small wineries that lack their own bottling facilities sell their produce via a large-scale cooperative, Domaines de Vinsmoselle, and this is the most commonly seen label in the country. Beer is another speciality and a traditional industry, but brewing traditions are not as great as in neighbouring Germany and Belgium.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Judd mat gaardebounen</em> (smoked neck of pork served with a stew of broad beans and potatoes saut&eacute;ed with bacon).<br />
&bull; <em>Bouch&eacute;e &agrave; la reine</em>, or <em>pascht&eacute;itchen</em> (chicken and mushrooms in a b&eacute;chamel sauce served in a puff pastry case. Similar to a large vol-au-vent).<br />
&bull; <em>Weinzossis</em> (a light sausage usually served with mashed potatoes and a mustard cream sauce)<br />
&bull; <em>Cochon de lait en gel&eacute;e</em> (jellied suckling pig).<br />
&bull; <em>Jambon d'Ardennes</em> (famous smoked Ardennes ham, traditionally eaten cold and served with a light salad and French Fries). <br />
&bull; <em>T</em><em>arte aux quetsches</em> (quetsch plum tart). <br />
&bull; <em>Friture de la Moselle</em> (small river fish, deep fried and eaten whole &ndash; similar to whitebait).<br />
&bull; <em>Gibier</em> (general term for game, usually appearing on menus in autumn, particularly in the northern Ardennes region, from where the animals originate. Wild boar (<em>sanglier</em>) and venison (<em>chevreuil</em>, or <em>biche</em>) are both popular).<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Traditional Luxembourg dishes such as <em>judd mat gaardebounen</em> tend to be served in gargantuan portion sizes and are not for the faint-hearted. More modern restaurants however are far more French influenced, and the serving sizes are reduced accordingly to more normal levels. Many tourist restaurants in the Ardennes usually have menus based around veal (as schnitzels or with cream sauces), but this reflects the wishes of the predominantly Dutch and German guests rather than any Luxembourg traditions.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Bills generally include service, but a rounded up tip is often given.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>17.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors to Luxembourg City can enjoy a variety of evening entertainment from theatre performances, classical music concerts, opera and ballet, to nightclubs, cinemas and discos. There is also a wide range of top restaurants to suit all tastes. The largest cinema complex in the country is the Utopolis (<a href="http://www.utopolis.lu" target="_blank">www.utopolis.lu</a>), an 11-screen multiplex, located beside Auchan Mall on Plateau du Kirchberg. Among younger and more affluent adults, Rives de Clausen has become the focal point of the capital&rsquo;s nightlife in recent years, since it opened in 2008 on the site of a former brewery in the lower town district of Clausen. There are more than a dozen bars and clubs here that play music into the early hours. There are also several theatres in the city, but few dramatic performances are in English.</p>
<p>For more information on all events happening in the city, contact the Luxembourg City Tourist Office. Due to the small size of most other Luxembourg towns and villages, there are fewer theatres, cinemas and nightclubs elsewhere in the country. Esch-sur-Alzette, the second city, has the most options, including the Cin&eacute; Belval multiplex cinema, and the Rockhal (<a href="http://www.rockhal.lu" target="_blank">www.rockhal.lu</a>), the country&rsquo;s largest and most important rock music venue. The latter attracts top global acts. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases include beautiful porcelain and crystal. Villeroy &amp; Boch's porcelain factory in Luxembourg City closed in 2010 as manufacturing moved to Asia, but the site is still open as an outlet store for &lsquo;seconds&rsquo; and end of line items. There is also a regular Villeroy &amp; Boch store in the city centre. Another regional speciality is earthenware pottery from Nospelt, where in August there is a fortnight-long exhibition of local work. The most popular items produced in Nospelt potteries &ndash; especially among younger children &ndash; are the warbling <em>p&eacute;ckvillchen</em>: glazed and hand-painted terracotta bird-shaped whistles. They are also sold at the Emaischen pottery market, held on Easter Monday in Luxembourg City.</p>
<p>For upmarket fashion goods and accessories, Grand Rue in central Luxembourg City has a number of internationally renowned designer label stores. The largest shopping mall in the city is the Auchan Mall on Plateau du Kirchberg, with more than 60 shops selling the full range of goods. Belval Plaza in Esch-sur-Alzette, Luxembourg&rsquo;s second-largest city, is another very large shopping mall.</p>
<p>For advice on where to find what in the capital, Luxembourg City has a dedicated shopping information office, Cityshopping Info Point (<a href="http://www.cityshopping.lu" target="_blank">www.cityshopping.lu</a>), located just off the central Place d&rsquo;Armes, open Tue-Sat 1000-1800. Cityshopping also produces a free booklet containing a directory of shops in the city. It is available from the information office or can be downloaded from the website.</p><p>Mon 1200-1800, Tues-Sat 0800-1800 (hours vary from shop to shop). Some shops in Luxembourg City and in the larger malls open longer hours. Those in smaller towns and villages may close for an hour or two at lunchtimes.</p><p>Shops in Luxembourg City are only open on a few selected Sundays each year, usually those leading up to Christmas. Some other shops do not open on Mondays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a large range of hotels in Luxembourg. Most of the larger international chain hotels are located in and around Luxembourg City, where most of the business guests tend to accumulate. Elsewhere the bulk of hotels are smaller and more country-style hotels, some of which have been run by the same families for several generations. They can be more personal and friendly and less formal than the chains, but the quality of facilities can also vary dramatically. Some are little more than large bed and breakfasts; others have fitness rooms, swimming pools and top-class restaurants.</p>
<p>Almost all hotel rooms have private bathrooms; not all establishments have air conditioning. For most independently run hotels, breakfast is included in the room price. In the larger chain hotels, which are primarily aimed at a business clientele, breakfast often costs extra.</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are very few bed & breakfast establishments in Luxembourg, in the common understanding of the term, but there are large numbers of small family-run hotels offering similar services and a family-style personalised welcome.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a large range of hotels in Luxembourg. Most of the larger international chain hotels are located in and around Luxembourg City, where most of the business guests tend to accumulate. Elsewhere the bulk of hotels are smaller and more country-style hotels, some of which have been run by the same families for several generations. They can be more personal and friendly and less formal than the chains, but the quality of facilities can also vary dramatically. Some are little more than large bed and breakfasts; others have fitness rooms, swimming pools and top-class restaurants.</p>
<p>Almost all hotel rooms have private bathrooms; not all establishments have air conditioning. For most independently run hotels, breakfast is included in the room price. In the larger chain hotels, which are primarily aimed at a business clientele, breakfast often costs extra.</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a large range of hotels in Luxembourg. Most of the larger international chain hotels are located in and around Luxembourg City, where most of the business guests tend to accumulate. Elsewhere the bulk of hotels are smaller and more country-style hotels, some of which have been run by the same families for several generations. They can be more personal and friendly and less formal than the chains, but the quality of facilities can also vary dramatically. Some are little more than large bed and breakfasts; others have fitness rooms, swimming pools and top-class restaurants.</p>
<p>Almost all hotel rooms have private bathrooms; not all establishments have air conditioning. For most independently run hotels, breakfast is included in the room price. In the larger chain hotels, which are primarily aimed at a business clientele, breakfast often costs extra.</p>
<p><strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are no major health risks in Luxembourg, no compulsory vaccinations, no endemic diseases to be concerned about, and along with the rest of Northern Europe, the standards of hygiene are generally very high. If you do require treatment for any reason, the standards of medical care you will receive will be excellent. Tap water is safe to drink anywhere in the country. As with any country, keeping regular booster vaccinations against Tetanus and Polio up to date is highly recommended. Elderly or vulnerable visitors travelling during the winter months may with to consider vaccination against Influenza, as outbreaks do occur.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you are suddenly taken ill or unlucky enough to be involved in an accident during a visit to Luxembourg, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available for European travellers - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). Comprehensive insurance is advised for all other nationals. Even EU travellers may wish to consider taking out additional insurance that covers the costs of repatriation to your home country in the event of an accident. Standards of healthcare in Luxembourg are as high as anywhere else in the world. In a medical emergency, the number to dial to call an ambulance is 112.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Luxembourg City&amp;rsquo;s two biggest medical facilities are Centre Hospitalier de Luxembourg (4 Rue Nicolas Ernest Barbl&amp;eacute;, Luxembourg City; tel: 441 111; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.chl.lu"&gt;www.chl.lu&lt;/a&gt;), and Kirchberg Hospital (9 Rue Edward Steichen, Luxembourg City; tel: 24681; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.chk.lu"&gt;www.chk.lu&lt;/a&gt;). Both offer world-class treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is safe to drink everywhere in Luxembourg. Most Luxembourgers drink bottled mineral water, but this is a taste preference, and not based on any perceived medical risk. Food served in restaurants is generally prepared to exacting hygiene standards and poses no specific risks. As anywhere, travellers' diarrhoea can strike those without strong constitutions, but this can be caused by a change of water supply and is not necessarily a sign of infection. As with anywhere, shellfish can be a problem, so exercise reasonable caution, although incidences of infection are rare and isolated.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;There is a slight risk of Lime Disease (carried by deer ticks) in rural areas, but cases are exceedingly rare and normal precautions (wearing long trousers when walking through thickly forested areas) are sufficient. Avoid drinking water directly from streams. Insect bites, particularly from horseflies, can also be a factor in rural areas, but these are more of a nuisance than a serious issue, resulting in swelling and itching rather than major health problem. Consider carrying some form of anti-histamine cream as relief if you are planning on doing any hiking.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday may be deferred to the following Monday, for a maximum of two holidays.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>National Day :
							23 June </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Luxembourg City Kermesse :
							03 September </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>St Stephen's Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luxembourg is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the UK, you are entitled to bring in fragrances, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, beer, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% volume, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>Nationals arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Luxembourg by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods (this includes perfume, tea or coffee) up to the value of &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can't import living animals or products of wild flora and fauna which originate from outside the EEA or Switzerland. International restrictions on narcotics, firearms, eggs, and endangered species apply.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International restrictions on the movement of narcotics, firearms and endangered species apply. There are also restrictions on the export of cultural goods such as antiques or works of art.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (&euro;) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents. In practice, higher domination notes (above &euro;100) are rarely seen in circulation; 1 and 2 cent coins are regarded as a nuisance and rarely used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies, traveller's cheques and cheques can be exchanged at banks, bureaux de change, the airport and some major hotels (generally at a less advantageous rate). Check commission charges carefully before deciding where to change money, as these can vary greatly from one outlet to the next.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard, Visa and other major credit cards are all widely accepted. Many retailers require a minimum (eg &euro;10-25) before accepting credit/debit cards. If paying with a credit card you will need to know your 4- or 6-digit PIN code in order to authorise payments.</p><p>ATMs are very common, and located in all but the smallest villages. Most are linked up to all international networks (CIRRUS etc) and will accept most international cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers&rsquo; cheques are becoming less widely accepted than they once were. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros. Using cash obtained from an ATM with a credit/bank card can work out as a cheaper alternative.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0900-1630, with some opening on Saturday. Hours vary from one bank to the next.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>According to international practice, all children travelling internationally must now have their own passport, and can no longer be added to a parent&rsquo;s passport. For children under the age of six who require a Schengen visa, these are issued free of charge. Although there are no restrictions on unaccompanied children entering Luxembourg, some airline carriers impose age restrictions on unaccompanied minors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas via the Schengen area are only required by nationals of a few countries; check with the embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luxembourg is part of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa:&nbsp;&euro;60. Reductions are available for some nationalities and for children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate (or consular section at embassy); you must book an appointment in advance. All visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment. For those countries without a Luxembourg Embassy, affairs are handled via the Belgian Embassy. If your main destination within the Schengen area is not Luxembourg, you must apply for the visa via the embassy or consulate of the relevant country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EU, Swiss and EEA nationals can reside in Luxembourg for periods longer than three months provided they are (self-)employed, or can show sufficient funds, and they register with the local municipality within three months of arrival. All other nationals intending to stay for longer than three months must apply for a temporary residence permit through an embassy or consulate before arrival in Luxembourg.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It generally takes two to 10 working days to process a visa for Luxembourg.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa applicants must provide proof of sufficient funds to support their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Entry permit extensions for non-EU nationals beyond 90 days are difficult and time-consuming. Those planning to stay longer are advised to apply for a temporary residence permit in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cats and dogs over three months old may enter Luxembourg from within the EU provided they are in possession of a valid EU pet passport, available from any vet, identifying the animal and showing proof of vaccination against rabies. They must also have an identifying microchip or tattoo. Rabbits and other rodents do not require a pet passport, but must be declared at the border. Animals can be moved to Luxembourg from outside the EU, but must have a recognised veterinary certificate, a microchip or tattoo, and proof of vaccination against rabies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[49.777973]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[6.095026]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,586 sq km (998 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>576,243 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luxembourg (City).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Grand Duchy of Luxembourg shares borders to the north and west with Belgium, to the south with France and to the east with Germany. Although similar in size to a typical English county, there are a number of distinct geographical regions. Most of the northern half of the country is made up of the high plateau of the Ardennes, carved and scarred by a network of steep-sided thickly forested river valleys. Most of this region is around 500m (1,640ft) above sea level.</p>
<p>The southern half &ndash; known locally the Gutland or Good Land - is gently rolling lowland, covered with woods and farmland, mostly sitting around 250m (820ft) above sea level. There are no towns of any significant size in the north; the south is more urbanised. In the southeast is the rich wine-growing valley of the Moselle river, which enjoys a unique microclimate well-suited to the cultivation of grapes. The area around Echternach, Larochette and Beaufort is a spectacular region of narrow sandstone micro-gorges and thick forest, which was christened &lsquo;Little Switzerland&rsquo; by early tourists. The capital meanwhile, Luxembourg City, is built on a rocky outcrop overlooking the two adjoining gorges of the Alzette and P&eacute;trusse valleys.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Around 87% of the population are Roman Catholic, but there are also significant Protestant, Anglican, Jewish and Muslim minority groups. Religious tolerance is widespread and there are few tensions between the different groups.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the normal greeting for men and women on a first meeting. Once you are familiar with a person, three kisses on alternate cheeks is the normal greeting between men and women, and between women. The code of practice for visiting someone's home is similar to that of other Western European countries: it is common practice to give a small gift or flowers if you are invited for a meal. Smart-casual or casual dress is widely acceptable, but some dining rooms, clubs and social functions will demand more formal attire. <br /><br />Smoking is prohibited in most public areas, and since January 2014, the law has changed to explicitly prohibit smoking in cafés, bars and clubs. Some venues will still be able to offer separate smoking rooms. Following the trend across the rest of Western Europe and North America, the habit is also becoming less socially acceptable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Xavier Bettel since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Grand Duke Henri since 2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Luxembourg owes its continued existence to a mixture of good fortune and good diplomacy, which have prevented it from being permanently absorbed into the territories of its larger neighbours despite the small nation's strategic location at the heart of Europe.<br/><br/>By the time that Luxembourg's independence was finally confirmed in 1867, the Grand Duchy was left with such a tiny territory that its people had to look across its borders for economic survival. Still, Luxembourg has historically experienced commercial prosperity and the country has a cosmopolitan attitude, exemplified not only by the fact that the country has the highest percentage of foreigners of any EU country, but also by the trilingual ability of its people.</p><p>During World War 2 Luxembourg sent a small group of volunteers who took part in the Normandy landings leading to the Duchy's eventual liberation from Nazi occupation in September 1944.</p><p>A constitutional monarchy, Luxembourg's head of state is the Grand Duke – currently Henri – and since 2011 a system of absolute primogeniture has been in place permitting legitimate female descendants to be included in the line of succession.</p><p>Luxembourg was a founder member of the European Community (having previously formed close economic ties with the Netherlands and Belgium) and was host to the European Parliament until its move to Brussels and Strasbourg. It remains the home of the Secretariat of the European Parliament. Luxembourg is in the mainstream on the current EU issues of monetary union, EU expansion, social policy and immigration and adopted the Euro upon its inception.</p><p>Domestic politics are typical of Western European nations, with Christian Democrat and Socialist parties and a centrist Parti Démocratique (PD) represented in the National Assembly. More recently, the Greens and the right-wing Action Committee for Democracy and Pensions Justice (ADR) have also been represented and the current government is a coalition of the Parti Démocratique, the Greens and the Luxembourg Socialist Workers' Party.</p><p>Luxembourg enjoys the world's highest GDP per capita and in 2016 its citizens have either visa-free or visa-on-arrival access to 172 countries.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• As a result of Grand Duke Henri's refusal to ratify a law to legalise euthanasia in 2008, the constitution was changed so that laws pass into statute without the Grand Duke's assent.</p><p>• Prime Minister Xavier Bettel is openly gay, the first Luxembourg Prime Minister to be so.</p><p>• Luxembourg won an Oscar in 2014 for the animated short film <em>Mr Hublot</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Grand Duchy of Luxembourg in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 6961.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://londres.mae.lu</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 6961.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1145 (visa section)&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>27 Wilton Crescent<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8SD<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Grand Duchy of Luxembourg in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 4171. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://washington.mae.lu</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 4171. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830–1230 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2200 Massachusetts Ave NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As the wealthiest nation in Europe and one of the founding fathers of the EU, it&rsquo;s safe to say little Luxembourg is punching well above its weight.</p>
<p>But as well as the highest per capita income on the continent, this diminutive country also has more than its fair share of natural beauty with rolling hills, verdant valleys and meandering rivers painting picture of rural idyll.</p>
<p>Proud of its role as a founding member of the EU, Luxembourg plays a prominent position in European affairs and is home to a number of European Union institutions.</p>
<p>Most of the action takes place in the capital, Luxembourg City, which has something of a split personality: while it&rsquo;s all antiquated charm in the Old Town, with its elegant squares, imposing churches, independent shops and cobblestone streets, the Kirchberg district has a modern, flashier feel thanks to its ubiquitous offices, shopping malls and entertainment complexes.</p>
<p>The most popular destination outside the capital is medieval Vianden in the northeast, with its cobbled streets and hilltop castle, which is the envy of many European cities. Vianden also hosts a range of festivals and events throughout the year, many of which celebrate its historical past.</p>
<p>Echternach, founded in the 7th century, is the oldest city in the country, with a picturesque centre dominated by an abbey. It is also a convenient base for exploring &lsquo;Little Switzerland&rsquo;, a tiny region of rocky outcrops, cliffs, cascades, and forests, crisscrossed by walking trails that are a haven for hikers and mountain-bikers.</p>
<p>On the southeastern border with Germany, the Moselle Valley enjoys a unique microclimate that has given rise to one of Europe&rsquo;s smallest wine-growing districts, producing award-winning whites and sparkling wines. Meanwhile, northern Luxembourg is dominated by the Ardennes, an area of high plateau where wooded valleys, shimmering rivers and lofty peaks make for stunning trekking. </p>
<p>All in all, not bad for a country the size of Dorset.</p><p>As the wealthiest nation in Europe and one of the founding fathers of the EU, it&rsquo;s safe to say little Luxembourg is punching well above its weight. <br />
But as well as the highest per capita income on the continent, this diminutive country also has more than its fair share of natural beauty with rolling hills, verdant valleys and meandering rivers painting picture of rural idyll.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
