<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Macedonia" ColCode="mkd" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mk" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Macedonia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As a landlocked country, Macedonia  has a pronounced continental climate, with very cold winters and hot summers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mediumweight clothing and very warm overcoats in winter; lightweight clothing and raincoats required for the summer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no regularly scheduled domestic flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Makedonski Zeleznici (tel: +389 2 511 7782; <a href="http://mztransportad.com.mk" target="_blank">http://mztransportad.com.mk</a>) operates rail links from Skopje to Kumanovo in the north, to Stip in the east, to Veles and Gevgelija in the south, and to Prilep and Bitola in the southwest.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>InterRail One-Country Pass: offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within FYR Macedonia. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Road conditions are variable and driving standards aren't always great. Some motorways have tolls, which you can pay in cash (Macedonian denars or Euros) or by credit card.</p>r<p>Buses connect Skopje with other towns and cities in FYR Macedonia.</p><p>Taxis are a cheap way of getting around cities and a good-value way of travelling between cities if you're in a group.</p><p>A valid national driving licence or International Driving Permit is required. If bringing you own car, you must carry the car registration/ownership documents and an insurance policy valid in FYR Macedonia.</p><p>Seatbelts are compulsory. You must drive with dipped headlights at all times, including during the day. Speed limits are 130kph (81mph) on motorways, 110kph (68mph) on major highways, 90kph (56mph) on other non-urban roads and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas. You must use winter tyres between 15 November and 15 March.</p><p>Available from international and local firms.</p><p>Cycling can be a great way of exploring the countryside, but watch out for careless drivers.</p><p>Seatbelts are compulsory. You must drive with dipped headlights at all times, including during the day. Speed limits are 130kph (81mph) on motorways, 110kph (68mph) on major highways, 90kph (56mph) on other non-urban roads and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas. You must use winter tyres between 15 November and 15 March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wizz (<a href="http://wizzair.com" target="_blank">http://wizzair.com</a>) operates direct flights to FYR Macedonia from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>. The quickest route from the USA is via Vienna.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 3 hours 10 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 12 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ohrid St. Paul the Apostle Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airports.com.mk]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Skopje Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport  is 17km (10.2 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Intercity trains operate between Skopje and and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belgrade">Belgrade</a> (Serbia). Trains also run between Skopje and Thessaloniki (Greece). A daily train connects Skopje with Pristina (Kosovo).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The international highway E-75 runs north to south from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/serbia">Serbia</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece">Greece</a>. There are also good road links to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bulgaria">Bulgaria</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/albania">Albania</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>All telecommunications services are generally working normally.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is mostly good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a few Internet cafes in the main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The constitution guarantees freedom of speech and access to information.<strong><br /></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Services work normally.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be sure not to miss Bitola's Byzantine ruins</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Surrounded by the hills and forest of Pelister National Park, pretty Bitola is the second-largest town in the FYR Macedonia. Located 18km (11 miles) from the Greek border, it was an important centre of Ottoman rule. Nearby, the ruins of the ancient it of Heraclea Lyncestis are well-preserved. Walk the remains of its Byzantine basilica with excellent mosaics.</p>]]><p><b>Catch the cable car to one of the world's biggest crosses</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Standing proudly atop Vodno Mountain, the Millennium Cross was erected to celebrate 2,000 years of Christianity in Macedonia. At 66m-high (217ft), the cross is one of the largest in the world and can be seen from Skopje city centre. Visitors can hike or take the Ropewalk cable car to the monument.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the delights of Ohrid, the former capital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its lakeside location, Ohrid is possibly the most attractive town in the FYR Macedonia. The site of the first Slav university, it was the Macedonian capital under leader Tsar Samuil. From his reign between 977 and 997 AD, the fortress walls survive and now provide a venue for summer concerts. Worthy of attention too are the number of ancient churches, particularly the cathedral of St Sophia.</p>]]><p><b>Explore FYR Macedonia's mosques and monasteries</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The FYR Macedonia boasts many mosques dating from the Ottoman period, but among the best is the 15th-century Mustafa Pasha Mosque in Skopje&rsquo;s Old Bazaar. Just outside the capital, the Nerezi Monastery and its 12th-century Church of St Panteleimon will also delight with its neat domes and magnificent Byzantine frescoes.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the new and old in Skopje</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Much of Macedonia's capital, Skopje, is new following an earthquake in 1963. This includes several new statues and the Memorial House of Mother Teresa, which were erected in 2014 as a government drive to make the city more classical. There is plenty of (actual) history in the Old Bazaar area and the attractive quarter is full of charming Ottoman touches.</p>]]><p><b>Make for the Museum of Contemporary Art</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Founded following the earthquake in 1963, the Museum of Contemporary Art houses one of the finest collections of art in the country. Perched above the city, the building is an excellent example of late modernism architecture. Works by Pablo Picasso, Hans Hartung and Robert Jacobsen give the light-drenched exhibition space an international feel.</p>]]><p><b>See Skopje's stone landmarks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Skopje's Stone Bridge is a city landmark and even features on its coat of arms. Crossing the Vardar River, the bridge was originally built by the Romans and connects Macedonia Square with the Old Town. Kale Fortress is an imposing 6th-century castle overlooking the river. Stroll up to its ramparts for exceptional views and see various archaeological finds inside.</p>]]><p><b>See the sunken church of Mavrovo Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Southwest of Skopje is Mavrovo National Park. A vast 780 sq km (300 sq miles) region of deep canyons, snowy peaks and dense forest, it is ideal for hiking. Walk to Mavrovo Lake, it freezes during winter but during summer offers great boating and swimming opportunities. In its centre sits a half-submerged church.</p>]]><p><b>Take in Skopje’s Old Town sights</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Church of the Holy Saviour in Skopje's Old Town. Unassuming from the outside, its interior contains an intricately carved iconostasis. Nearby, two former <em>caravanserais</em> (roadside inns), the 15th century Suli An and 16-century Kursumli An, retain their wonderful archways, whilst the distinctive domed Daut Pasha Baths now houses an art gallery.</p>]]><p><b>Unearth history at the National Archaeological Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The National Archaeological Museum (as the vast exterior columns attest) was borne out of the government's drive to make Skopje appear more classical. With artefacts dating back to the Neolithic period, the vast museum is worthy of an afternoon's exploration. The exhibitions are overwhelming in places, so a guided tour is recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$5.6 billion (2006).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Steel, iron, textile products, tobacco, food and beverages.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, automobiles, chemicals, fuels and food products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Serbia and Montenegro, Bulgaria, Greece, Germany, Italy and Russia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The FYR Macedonia's economy has improved over the years. Its low tax rates and free economic zones also help to attract foreign investment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits and ties are correct attire for men, with skirt, blouse and tights the accepted attire for women. English, French and German are spoken in most business circles.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Economic Chamber of FYR Macedonia</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 324 4000
					Website:http://info.mchamber.org.mk
					Address: 1000 Skopje,St Dimitrie Cupovski 13,Macedonia,]]><b>National Bank of the Republic of Macedonia</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 310 8108
					Website:http://www.nbrm.gov.mk
					Address: PO Box 401,Kompleks Banki bb,1000 Skopje,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Macedonian cuisine is a hybrid style, blending Balkan and Mediterranean flavours and traditions with delicious results. Turkish influences inherited from centuries of Ottoman rule are also evident.</p>
<p>During summer, markets are well-stocked with fresh tomatoes, carrots, lettuce and onions as well as watermelons, apricots and peaches. To make the summer bounty last through the harsher continental winter, veg is often pickled (tur&scaron;ija) or jarred into tasty spreads.</p>
<p>Meze, a selection of small, creamy vegetable spreads, is usually served with bread to start and is often followed by a main dish of grilled chicken or pork, freshwater fish, stuffed pastry or stew. When it comes to drink, sugared Turkish coffee is the order of the day, though milky, Italian-style coffees, such as cappuccino and lattes are becoming increasingly popular. </p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pindžur:</strong> A spicy roast pepper and aubergine relish.<br />
<strong>Kifli:</strong> A half-moon-shaped bread roll filled with feta cheese and topped with sesame seeds.<br />
<strong>Gravce tavce:</strong> A chunky bean stew cooked in a skillet and flavoured with spices including paprika.<br />
<strong>Shopska salata:</strong> A mixed salad made by combining tomato, peppers, cucumbers, onions and crumbled feta cheese.<br />
<strong>Kebapči:</strong> Minced meat sausages typically served with flatbread, kajmak (a type of clotted cream) and onions.<br />
<strong>Ajvar:</strong> A ubiquitous relish made from roasted red bell peppers, paprika and garlic. <br />
<strong>Burek:</strong> A flaky pie filled with combinations of ham, cheese, spinach and ground beef.<br />
<strong>Selsko meso:</strong> A thick stew of meat, potatoes, onions, tomatoes and carrots cooked in a clay pot.<br />
<strong>Kačamak:</strong> A porridge-esque cornmeal mixture often sprinkled with feta cheese.<br />
<strong>Tulumbi:</strong> Fried dough rolls covered in honey and nuts. <br />
<strong>Rakija:</strong> A potent fruit brandy made from grapes.<br />
<strong>Mastika:</strong> An Ouzo-style aperitif seasoned with mastic and served over ice.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-2000 and Sat 0800-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macedonia (Former Yugoslav Republic) has two 5-star hotels in Skopje, as well as other 3-star and 4-star hotels in the capital and in the Lake Ohrid tourist area on the border with Albania and Greece.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macedonia (Former Yugoslav Republic) has two 5-star hotels in Skopje, as well as other 3-star and 4-star hotels in the capital and in the Lake Ohrid tourist area on the border with Albania and Greece.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macedonia (Former Yugoslav Republic) has two 5-star hotels in Skopje, as well as other 3-star and 4-star hotels in the capital and in the Lake Ohrid tourist area on the border with Albania and Greece.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Prescribed medicines must be paid for. There is a reciprocal health agreement with the UK. Health insurance with emergency repatriation is strongly recommended for all nationals (including UK nationals).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available and is advised for the first few weeks of the stay. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccination against hepatitis B and tuberculosis is sometimes advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are usually observed on a different day.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Orthodox Easter Monday :
							09 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ilinden (Republic Day) :
							02 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							08 September </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into FYR Macedonia by travellers over 18 years old without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic drinks under 22% volume.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 50ml of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of &euro;350.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unauthorised firearms and ammunition, unlicensed drugs, and counterfeit or pirated goods.&nbsp;</p>
<p>You must obtain a permit to import animals, plants or their products.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unauthorised firearms and ammunition, unlicensed drugs, and counterfeit or pirated goods.&nbsp;</p>
<p>You must obtain a permit to export objects of historical or cultural value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Macedonian Denar (MKD; symbol ден) = 100 deni. Notes are in denominations of ден5,000, 1,000, 500, 100, 50 and 10. Coins are in denominations of ден5, 2 and 1, and 50 deni.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major currencies may be exchanged, but Euros are easiest to exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Limited acceptance outside the bigger cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take cheques in US Dollars or Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0700-1900; Sat 0700-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above, except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a valid national ID card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Five-day transit visas are also available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay visa; long-day visa: check with the embassy for the latest fees.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay visa: 90 days; long-stay visa: visits over 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three to five days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If taking a pet to FYR Macedonia, your animal must have a pet passport and an up-to-date certificate of good health from an authorised vet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[41.608635]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[21.745275]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>25,713 sq km (9,927.8 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,081,012 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>81.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Skopje.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roughly rectangular in shape, and on the strategic Vardar Valley north-south communications route, the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia (FYROM or FYR Macedonia in short) is landlocked, bordering Serbia to the north, Albania to the west, Greece to the south and Bulgaria to the east.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>67% of the population are Eastern Orthodox Macedonians and around 23% are Muslim Albanians. There are also Muslim Turks and Serbian Orthodox minorities. As elsewhere in the former Yugoslav federation, local politics are now strongly divided along national religious lines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the common practice on introduction. Local business protocol is fairly informal, but things go very slowly or not at all owing to the local bureaucracy and the more recent general socio-economic collapse in the Republic.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Zoran Zaev since June 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Gjorge Ivanov since 2009.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An ancient, strategically important and much-contested territory, the historical region known as Macedonia was variously controlled by the Greeks, Romans, Bulgarians, Byzantines, Serbs and the marauding Ottoman Turks, who conquered the area in 1371, and kept it until the beginning of the 20th century. Then, as Turkish power declined, Macedonia once again became a bone of contention between its various neighbours and their respective superpower allies.</p>
<p>In 1912 and 1913, the Balkan Wars drove the Turks out of the area, and the territory was carved up between Serbia and Greece, with Bulgaria retaining a small part. Vardar Macedonia became part of the new 'Kingdom of Serbs, Croats and Slovenes' in 1918, becoming Yugoslavia from 1929.</p>
<p>However, this caused much anti-Serbian resentment locally. In 1945, the area became a constituent republic of the new communist Yugoslav federation, which the Serbs opposed. Thereafter a new 'Macedonian' nation was created, but this was never accepted as legitimate by any of the republic's neighbours.</p>
<p>In 1990, following the collapse of communism in Yugoslavia (now Serbia and Montenegro), Macedonia held its first multi-party elections. The Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia's quest for international recognition ran up against objections from Greece, which felt that Skopje's use of the title 'Macedonia' implies a territorial claim against Aegean Macedonia in Greece, given that it corresponds with the northern Greek province of the same name.</p>
<p>The Greeks agreed to a compromise name, 'The Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia', under which it joined the United Nations in 1993. In 1997, simmering ethnic tensions between the majority Slavic population and the country's Albanian minority &ndash; who make up roughly 20% of the population &ndash; turned violent. The conflict was closely related to that in the Yugoslav province of Kosovo to the north.</p>
<p>The situation deteriorated until, in 1998, the flight of thousands of refugees from Kosovo persuaded the Macedonian government to close the border. The crisis passed but erupted again in 2001 after a series of clashes between Macedonian security forces and ethnic Albanian guerrillas. Urgent international diplomacy brought about the Ohrid Agreement that same year guaranteeing political and cultural rights for the Albanian population.</p>
<p>While the Greek government still call its northern neighbour by its interim name, 'The Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia', some 140 countries, including the US and China, refer to it as 'The Republic of Macedonia'. Negotiations with Greece to resolve the name issue continue.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Mother Teresa was born in Macedonia&rsquo;s capital, Skopje.<br />
&bull;	Macedonia was the first country in the world to provide wireless broadband coverage to virtually all of its population. <br />
&bull;	The French mixed fruit salad, mac&eacute;doine, was so-named because of Macedonia&rsquo;s ethnic diversity.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in FYR Macedonia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(2) 3299 299.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-skopje</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(2) 3299 299.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1630; Fri 0800-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Todor Aleksandrov No.165<br/>Skopje<br/>Skopje 1000<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Macedonia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7976 0535.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.macedonianembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7976 0535.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; Mon, Wed and Fri 1000-1300 (for personal callers).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Buckingham Gate 75/83<br/>Suite 2.1 &amp; 2.2, Buckingham Court<br/>London<br/>SW1E 6PE<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Macedonia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 667 0501.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.macedonianembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 667 0501.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2129 Wyoming Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia (sometimes abbreviated as FYROM and FYR Macedonia), is underrated and underexplored. A mountainous nation at the heart of the Balkans, it&rsquo;s sprinkled with picturesque valleys and shimmering lakes, offering outdoor appeal in spades. Yet that isn't its sole selling point &ndash; FYR Macedonia also has a bustling capital, a rich Hellenic heritage and an up-and-coming wine industry that appears on the cusp of international recognition.</p>
<p>For most visitors, the adventure begins in the capital Skopje. The cityscape is an incongruous jumble of buildings and gigantic neoclassical statuary. Monolithic socialist apartment blocks sit beside grandiloquent monuments, controversially added during an ambitious government scheme dubbed Skopje 2014. Old Ottoman and Byzantine edifices hark back to the nation's pre-communist history, while buzzing bars and clubs project its forward-looking aspirations.</p>
<p>Rural FYR Macedonia is far easier of the eye. Blessed with an extraordinary diversity of landscapes, the countryside is also home to serene lakeside towns such as Ohrid, which offers glorious relief from the sizzling Balkan summer. Visitors can while away lazy days on the dreamy lake&rsquo;s edge, visit the region&rsquo;s handsome, time-warp churches and enjoy languid evenings quaffing wine produced in the surrounding hills.</p>
<p>From Ohrid push on into the endless green pastures of the &Scaron;ar Planina mountain range, where the tranquil glacier lakes mirror the surrounding peaks, or try trekking the mountainous Pelister National Park, a dead ringer for the Swiss Alps. Outdoor enthusiasts heading to the remote hinterlands are more likely to see wild goats than deluxe resorts, but the country&rsquo;s rustic inns are welcoming and affordable. During winter, there are many opportunities for skiing and snowboarding, particularly in the Mavrovo region.</p>
<p>Like most countries in the region, FYR Macedonia has had its fair share of political and economic problems over the years. But shrug aside the stigma of the past and you&rsquo;ll find a different Europe &ndash; one that&rsquo;s fresh, crowd-free and, for the time being, incredibly affordable.</p><p>The former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia (sometimes abbreviated as FYROM and FYR Macedonia), is underrated and underexplored. A mountainous nation at the heart of the Balkans, it&rsquo;s sprinkled with picturesque valleys and shimmering lakes, offering outdoor appeal in spades. Yet that isn't its sole selling point &ndash; FYR Macedonia also has a bustling capital, a rich Hellenic heritage and an up-and-coming wine industry that appears on the cusp of international recognition.&nbsp;For most visitors, the adventure begins in the capital, Skopje. The cityscape is an incongruous jumble of buildings and gigantic neoclassical statuary. Monolithic socialist apartment blocks sit beside grandiloquent monuments, controversially added during an ambitious government scheme dubbed Skopje 2014. Old Ottoman and Byzantine edifices hark back to the nation's pre-communist history, while buzzing bars and clubs project its forward-looking aspirations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
