<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Madagascar" ColCode="mdg" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mg" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Madagascar]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Madagascar&rsquo;s highly diverse subtropical climate means it pays to do some research before you plan a trip. Rainy season runs from December to March. This is when the rainforested eastern and northern parts of the country are battered by tropical storms brought on by cyclone season, and temperatures tend to hover around 30&ordm;C (86&ordm;F). Despite being rainy season up north, during this period, the central parts will be a lot drier and cooler, with temperatures around 25&ordm;C (77&ordm;F). The southern and western coasts are the driest parts of the country.</p>
<p>Dry season runs from April to October but tourist numbers don't start to swell until early May. Peak months are July and August, due to the timing of school holidays in Europe and the <a href="http://i/united-states-america">USA</a>. If visiting for wildlife, September to December is also a good time to visit, as many of the snakes and lizards populating the island come out of hibernation during this time. The mountains, including Antananarivo, are dry, cool and windy during this time of year, shifting to warm and thundery from November to April. Due to the extreme storms and occasional cyclones, travelling to Madagascar between January and March is ill-advised.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To cope with the Madagascan climate, lightweights should be worn during the summer on high central plateaux and throughout the year in the north and south. Cotton and natural fibres work better in this sweaty weather. Warmer clothes are advised for during the evenings and winter in mountainous areas. Rainwear is advisable as a precaution.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Madagascar (<a href="http://www.airmadagascar.com" target="_blank">www.airmadagascar.com</a>) operates flights from the capital city to Diego Suarez, Majunga, Nosy Be, Ile Sainte Marie, Tamatave, Tulear and Fort Dauphin most days. Less regular Air Madagascar services connect a further half dozen towns across the country.</p>
<p>No other airlines provide scheduled domestic flights, but five or six charter companies have light aircraft and helicopters for passenger transfers to more than 80 airstrips nationwide.</p>
<p>Nosy Be and Ile Sainte Marie are islands and are most readily accessed by air. On the mainland, some towns are not easily accessible overland. As such, most people prefer to fly to Fort Dauphin, Maroantsetra, Sambava and Antalaha.</p>
<p>Advance booking is necessary on popular routes during peak season (typically July to September and around Christmas and New Year).</p><p>It takes a little under 90 minutes to fly from Antananarivo to the far north or south of Madagascar.</p>
<p>Air Madagascar offers up to 50% off domestic flights for those who also use them as their international carrier.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Madagascar has a strong maritime tradition and there are many coastal transport services. Rapids render many of the rivers unnavigable.</p>
<p>Tour operators can organise small-boat descents of some of the western rivers, including Tsiribihina, Manambolo, Mangoky, Mahavavy, Betsiboka and Onilahy, with overnight camping stops.</p>
<p>The Pangalanes Canal runs for more than 650km (400 miles) along the east coast, south of Tamatave. Some sections are too clogged with vegetation to be navigable nowadays, but the northernmost third is popular with tourists.</p>
<p>Many operators offer multi-day live-aboard yacht charters (including some specialising in fishing or diving) from Nosy Be, either going northeast to the Mitsio archipelago or southwest to the Radama archipelago.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Madagascar&rsquo;s rail network is limited to just two relatively short lines. The first connects Fianarantsoa in the highlands with Manakara on the east coast, and takes about eight hours each way. A single train operates the route, going down one day and back up the next.</p>
<p>The second rail line connects Moramanga with Tamatave (ten hours), and has a side branch to Ambatondrazaka. This railway also has just one passenger train in operation.</p>
<p>Rail lines also run from the capital city east to Moramanga and south Antsirabe, but neither route runs a regular passenger service. There is a Micheline (1930s rubber-wheeled train) that occasionally does weekend tourist outings to Andasibe and Antsirabe along these two lines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tickets for the Fianarantsoa-Manakara line can be purchased from the terminus stations. The other lines are administered by Madarail (<a href="http://www.madarail.mg" target="_blank">www.madarail.mg</a>), which has an office in Soarano station in Antananarivo. There are no special passes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Madagascar has less than 6,000km (3,728 miles) of paved roads. To appreciate just how limited this road network is, consider that it is just over just over 1% of the size of the UK&rsquo;s, despite Madagascar being a considerably larger country!</p>r<p>Malagasy road surfacing is done cheaply with poor materials, and many of the roads are subjected to severe weather conditions each rainy season. Consequently potholes develop rapidly, and a 'fast' road can become a slow one in a matter of a couple of years.</p>
<p>Presently, the roads connecting the capital city with Tul&eacute;ar (RN7), Tamatave (RN2), Majunga (RN4), Diego Suarez (RN6), Morondava (RN34/35) and Manakara (RN25) are largely in good condition.</p>
<p>Most roads are little more than dirt tracks, many of which become impassable during the rainy season (November/December to March/April).</p>
<p>Owing to security issues, travelling by road during hours of darkness is inadvisable (including by bus). Daytime driving is safe in almost all areas.</p><p>Between towns, public transport is in the form of <em>taxi-brousses</em>. These are typically minibuses with around 15 seats.</p>
<p>For relatively short journeys (up to an hour or so) as many as 30 passengers may be crammed in, but on longer journeys (sometimes in excess of 24 hours for the most far-flung destinations on bad roads) each paying passenger gets a seat to himself.</p>
<p>Luggage is usually strapped to the roof (and covered with a tarpaulin if rain is likely).</p>
<p>These taxi-brousses are run by numerous cooperatives. Each town has at least one taxi-brousse station, where each cooperative has a ticket kiosk listing the destinations they serve.</p><p>Taxis can be found in most cities and large towns and are an affordable way of getting around. Drivers are generally reliable and friendly. In the capital city taxis are plentiful. They are normally coloured cream and marked with a rooftop taxi sign.</p>
<p>Taxis do not have meters. In some towns there are pre-determined rates (usually a flat fare for any trip within the town) but elsewhere, including in Antananarivo, you should agree a price before setting off.</p><p>A national driving licence is sufficient but an International Driving Permit is advised for minimal hassle at police checkpoints.</p>
<p>You must also carry your passport, insurance documents, vehicle hire agreement and any other vehicle paperwork at all times when driving.</p><p>You must carry all relevant documents when driving, including your passport. There are regular police checkpoints where these may be requested.</p>
<p>Drivers and passengers must wear seatbelts and there are strict rules about driving under the influence of drink or drugs.</p>
<p>The highway code explicitly states that you must give way not only to ambulance, police and fire vehicles but also to security trucks transporting money and to the presidential convoy.</p><p>There are no breakdown services &ndash; another reason why hiring a vehicle with a driver is a good idea. Your driver will have the necessary equipment and knowledge to repair the vehicle or, if necessary, be able to communicate with locals to enlist their help if you break down.</p><p>You can easily find car-hire agencies in all the main towns. Hire cars are typically 4-wheel drives as you need a good vehicle to cope with the rough access roads to national parks and other rural sites.</p>
<p>Note that car hire in Madagascar almost always includes a driver. Few companies hire out self-drive vehicles, and in any case there is no real difference in cost between hiring with or without a driver.</p>
<p>The minimum driving age is 18, however most driving agencies including Hertz and Sixt require their drivers to be at least 23 to hire a car.&nbsp;</p><p>Many adventurous tourists consider motorbike or mountain bike to be the best means of transport if you want to get off the beaten track and keep en element of independence. You can hire both forms of transport from several companies, especially in the capital.</p><p>You must carry all relevant documents when driving, including your passport. There are regular police checkpoints where these may be requested.</p>
<p>Drivers and passengers must wear seatbelts and there are strict rules about driving under the influence of drink or drugs.</p>
<p>The highway code explicitly states that you must give way not only to ambulance, police and fire vehicles but also to security trucks transporting money and to the presidential convoy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rickshaws called <em>pousse-pousses</em> are popular in some of the flatter towns, most notably Antsirabe. In recent years they are increasingly being replaced by the quicker <em>cyclo-pousses</em> (cycle rickshaws). Prices are not fixed and are agreed before getting in, depending on the distance to be travelled; a higher amount may be demanded in rain or after dark.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Madagascar's national airline is Air Madagascar (<a href="http://www.airmadagascar.com" target="_blank">www.airmadagascar.com</a>). Although they are no longer banned from the list of carriers allowed into the EU due to safety concerns, the airline is still not recommended as cancellations and delays are common. Other major airlines serving the country include Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>), Kenya Airways (<a href="http://www.kenya-airways.com" target="_blank">www.kenya-airways.com</a>) and Airlink (<a href="http://www.flyairlink.com" target="_blank">www.flyairlink.com</a>), the last of which partners with South African Airways to connect Madagascar with countless countries via <a href="http://i/johannesburg">Johannesburg</a>.</p>
<p>For flights to Madagascar within the Indian Ocean region, Air Austral (<a href="http://www.air-austral.com" target="_blank">www.air-austral.com</a>) and Air Mauritius (<a href="http://www.airmauritius.com" target="_blank">www.airmauritius.com</a>) are the main operators.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 16 hours (including stopover); from <a href="new-york-city">New York</a> - 19 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International flights mainly go to Ivato airport (Antananarivo), with a few landing at Fascene airport (Nosy Be).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International flights mainly go to Ivato airport (Antananarivo), with a few landing at Fascene airport (Nosy Be).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Toamasina Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Antananarivo Ivato International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 17km (11 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The country&rsquo;s main port is at Tamatave. There are also ports at Diego Suarez, Majunga, Morondava, Fort Dauphin and Tul&eacute;ar. It is occasionally possible to book a passenger cabin on a cargo ship that is scheduled to call at a Malagasy port.</p><p>The waters north of Madagascar have become known for piracy in recent years, but there have been few incidents as far south as Madagascar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>For cheap calls buy a telephone card – you can buy cards almost everywhere, including post offices and hotels – and use a public telephone booth. These are found more commonly in the main cities but their usage has been eclipsed by growing mobile phone ownership.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies. Coverage reaches major cities and main roads but is scarce in rural areas. If you have an unlocked phone, consider picking up a Malagasy sim card and using this for your stay; it is far cheaper to make calls this way.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public Internet access exists in large cities; there are a few internet cafés in Antananarivo but connections tend to be horribly slow. Many post office also offer internet facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Madagascar's constitution does allow for a free press, but whilst freedom of speech is generally respected, in reality the dominant voice is that of the government, since much of the country's media is state-sponsored. Ousted President Ravalomanana owns the Malagasy Broadcasting System, which operates MBS TV and Radio MBS, and many private radio stations in the capital are owned by pro-Ravalomanana politicians. Although nationwide radio and TV broadcasting remain the monopoly of the state, there are hundreds of private local radio and TV stations.</p><p>A boom in privately-owned FM radio stations and more critical political reporting by the print media followed a 1990s law on press freedom. However, during the island's recent political turmoil many Malagasy journalists have faced censorship, threats, and arrest for reporting contentious issues or voicing critical opinion. There are no English-language newspapers on the island, with the main newspapers, such as <em>La Gazette de la Grande Ile</em>, <em>Madagascar Tribune </em>and <em>Midi Madagasikara</em> being published in French or Malagasy. Privately owned radio stations include Radio Don Bosco (Roman Catholic FM station), Radio Tsioka Vao and Radio Korail. Malagasy National Radio (RNM) is state-owned.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes at least seven days and surface mail three to four months.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0700-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire majestic architecture at the Queen's Palace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The <em>rova</em> (palace) surveys the capital city from its highest point, recently partly rebuilt following a terrible fire in 1995. The original wooden palace was built by Frenchman Jean Laborde in 1839 – its exterior was later clad in stone by Scottish missionary, James Cameron. Take a tour of the compound to learn about Madagascar's dramatic royal history.</p>]]><p><b>Call in at Andasibe-Mantadia National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Close to the capital, this is Madagascar's most accessible rainforest reserve, and also one of the most rewarding. Frogs, reptiles and birds abound, but top of the bill is the indri, the largest of all living lemurs. These creatures sing a haunting song (reminiscent of whale song), which carries for miles across the forest.</p>]]><p><b>Cameras at the ready for Baobab Alley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This natural avenue of imposing Grandidier&rsquo;s baobabs is one of Madagascar&rsquo;s must-see sights. Located some 35 minutes from Morondava, on the dusty track to Kirindy Reserve, Baobab Alley is best visited around sunrise or sunset because the softer lighting brings out the red tones of the tree trunks and makes for a splendid photo opportunity.</p>]]><p><b>Capture the craftsmanship of Antsirabe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the wonderful arts and crafts in Antsirabe: taking a <em>pousse-pousse</em> tour of artisanal workshops is the thing to do in this bustling highland town. Marvel at the skill of local craftsmen creating toys from recycled tin cans, wooden sculptures, zebu-horn jewellery, polished gems and minerals, embroidered tablecloths, silk scarves, raffia handicrafts and more.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a tea break at the Sahambavy Estate</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For almost half a century, this estate has been producing green tea (and black tea since 2004). The 335ha (828-acre) plantation yields more than 550 tonnes of tea every year, most of which is destined for Kenya. Guided factory tours take around one hour and end with a tasting.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the afterlife at Ambalavao</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dabble in the macabre at Ambalavao (the so-called "home of the departed") where the revered bones of exhumed ancestors lie. The spectacular crags of Ambondrome and Ifandana were the site of a mass suicide in 1811, though the region is also known for its Ataimoro paper and silk weaving today.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the otherworldly Spiny Forest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Unique to Madagascar, the dry and inhospitable spiny forest of the far south is a most curious and startling ecosystem. All of its botanical wonders are perfectly adapted to this tough environment, often preserving precious water in their swollen succulent forms protected by vicious prickles. The strange waving fingers of octopus trees add to the habitat's otherworldly feel.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the palaces of former capital, Ambohimanga</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps the most sacred site in all Madagascar, Ambohimanga (Blue Hill) was the original capital when the great king Andrianampoinimerina began his reign in 1787. The compound is a UNESCO World Heritage Site and comprises more than a dozen impressive stone gates, the king's house and various elegant royal summerhouses.</p>]]><p><b>Find out about flora at Arboretum d'Antsokay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Near to Tuléar, this botanical garden showcases some 900 plant species endemic to Madagascar's arid south. You'll learn about the plants and how they are used in construction, food and medicine. Birders will also find this place rewarding and there are some bungalows for those wishing to linger.</p>]]><p><b>Follow the scent to Nosy Be</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Follow the exotic perfumed lure of Nosy Be and the surrounding islets of Nosy Komba (famous for its black lemurs), Nosy Sakatia and Nosy Tanikely (a marine reserve with exceptional snorkelling). On Nosy Be itself, sweet-smelling plants such as ylang-ylang, vanilla, lemongrass and patchouli fill the air with a delectable fragrance.</p>]]><p><b>Look at the lemurs of Montagne d'Arbre National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover waterfalls, orchids and lemurs at Amber Mountain. This 18,500ha (45,715-acre) national park is the country's oldest, protecting some splendid montane rainforest. Ranging in altitude between 850m (2,790ft) and 1,475m (4,840ft), the mountain has its own microclimate. Sanford's lemurs and crowned lemurs are easily seen, as well as countless reptiles and birds.</p>]]><p><b>Meander the Tsiribihina River mangroves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spend three to five days floating down the tranquil Tsiribihina River to the east coast, ending up near to Tsingy de Bemaraha National Park. If you want to get off the beaten track, then other less touristy rivers include the Manambolo, Mangoky, Mahavavy, Betsiboka and Onilahy.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the breaks at Libanona Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Grab your surfboard and hit the waves that break on offshore coral reefs to experience the island's little-known surf thrills. The surf at Libanona Beach in Fort Dauphin is suitable for beginners. Other top riding spots include Lavanono and Anakao, while the far northeast of Madagascar is the place for kitesurfing.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out spectacular sea life, Mitsio Archipelago</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Mitsio islands have fantastic beaches, glorious turquoise waters, and some truly world-class dive sites. Revel in the deep-water discovery of boxfish, barracuda, rays, sea urchins, starfish, eels, and a thousand other creatures of the reef. The area is best explored by chartering a catamaran from Nosy Be.</p>]]><p><b>Swim in seclusion at Anakao</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax on the idyllic beaches in this isolated southwestern Vezo fishing village. On offer are <em>pirogue</em> (dugout canoe) trips to nearby mangroves and islands, including one that's home to the world's southernmost breeding colony of red-tailed tropicbirds. A day trip to the salt lake at Tsimanampetsotsa National Park is a must.</p>]]><p><b>Walk the history-rich hills of Antananarivo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Revel in the distinctively French flavour and ambience of Madagascar's history-rich capital. The quaint winding streets and vast markets are best explored on foot, but you can't go far without a steep climb – this city is built on seven hills. For the best views across all of Antananarivo, head to the area around the Queen's Palace.</p>]]><p><b>Wander the rugged beauty of Tsingy de Bemaraha National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Delve into one of the most striking national parks on the planet. At Tsingy de Bemaraha, there are undisturbed forests, lakes and canyons  – but top of the bill is the incredible limestone karst known as <em>tsingy</em>. These vast forests of limestone pinnacles make for a landscape unlike any other.</p>]]><p><b>Witness the watery wonders of Lake Itasy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the lush, volcanic region of Ampefy, renowned for its spectacular geysers and waterfalls on the banks of beautiful Itasy Lake. Amidst rolling hills, the thunderous torrents of Chute de la Lily's cascades are an unforgettable highlight – but be prepared for a reverberating roar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$10 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Coffee, vanilla, shellfish, sugar and cotton.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Capital goods, petroleum, consumer goods and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, China, USA, Germany and India.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Agriculture accounts for more than 25% of GDP and employs 82% of the population. Coffee is produced for foreign exchange, rice and cassava for domestic consumption. Deforestation and erosion, aggravated by the use of firewood as the primary source of fuel, are serious concerns. The country suffers from frequent cyclones which can make crop yields wildly unpredictable.<br />
<br />
Madagascar has appreciable mineral deposits which are being exploited, whilst the manufacturing industry, mainly textiles and food processing, accounts for around half of all exports.<br />
<br />
The economy grew strongly between 2002 and 2009, but a coup left the country without an official government for over four years. During that period, the economic progress of the 2000s was undone.<br />
<br />
<br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p>France has been the main trading partner of Madagascar since independence in 1960, but its influence is now reducing. Exports to the USA< rocketed in the early 2000s, eventually exceeding a third of Madagascar's total sales, as a result of an arrangement called AGOA that permitted duty-free sales to the US. The 2009 coup saw Madagascar suspended from AGOA, however, and US sales have since plummeted to just 10% of all exports.</p>
<p>Trade with China is increasing fast and exports there now exceed those to the US.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Meetings tend to be formal with handshakes and titles observed. Loosely gripping your right forearm with your left hand whilst shaking hands is a sign of respect, as is passing or receiving something with both hands (you will notice that the Malagasy may pass you money or documents, for example, two-handed).</p>
<p>Lightweight suits are advised and business cards exchanged. Interpreters can sometimes be supplied by your embassy if pre-arranged well in advance.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700 with a two-hour lunch break at noon. Banks operate the same hours but most towns have one bank that opens Saturday morning.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Fédération des Chambres de Commerce d'Industrie et d'Agriculture de Madagascar</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (20) 222 0211
					Website:http://www.cci-tana.org
					Address: Antaninarenina,20 Rue Henri Razanatseheno,Antananarivo 101,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>At first glance, the cuisine of Madagascar can appear quite dull. Traditionally the Malagasy eat a large mound of rice, dwarfing the surprisingly small accompanying portion of meat, vegetables and sauce.</p><p>Tourist establishments tend to serve meals with the rice-to-accompaniment ratio turned on its head. These dishes tend to have a French influence and fries are often offered in place of rice.</p><p><em>Zebu</em> (beef) steaks are usually excellent and most commonly served with a delicious creamy green peppercorn sauce. On the coast, seafood naturally predominates, including all manner of fish, as well as lobster and shellfish. Pizza is popular everywhere. Most towns have cheap Chinese eateries, which are usually reliable and popular with independent travellers.</p><p>Note that more isolated hotels tend to offer a set menu or a very limited choice to their guests. Even restaurants with an apparently extensive menu may have a rather restricted number of dishes available outside peak tourist season.</p><p>Vegetarians can usually be accommodated without too much fuss, even if there are no vegetarian dishes explicitly listed on the menu. Travellers with more unusual dietary requirements, such as a peanut allergy, would be well advised to find out the Malagasy and French words for what they cannot eat and write them down on a card, so that their needs can be communicated unequivocally to waiters and chefs.</p><p>Street snacks include slices of coconut and peanuts in a sweet coconut or toffee coating. If you spot a man carrying a glass case on his head, he is probably selling <em>koba</em> (banana, peanuts and rice, ground to a paste, wrapped in a banana leaf and served in slices), <em>sambos</em> (samosas) or <em>nems</em> (spring rolls).</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><em>Romazava</em> (a type of beef stew).</p><p><em>Ravitoto</em> (pork served with shredded cassava leaves).</p><p><em>Varanga</em> (fried slivers of beef).</p><p><em>Sesika</em> (a sort of poultry blood sausage).</p><p><em>Vorivorin-kena</em> (beef tripe).</p><p><em>Smalona</em> (stuffed eels).</p><p><em>Lasary</em> (a colourful chutney usually made from lemon, mango or papaya – or sometimes tomato, peanuts or vegetables).</p><p><em>Khimo</em> (curried ground beef popular in Majunga).</p><p><em>Kabaro</em> (lima beans with curry or coconut, a speciality in Morondava).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Malagasy cuisine is not usually particularly hot and spicy, but a chilli relish called <em>sakay</em> (in both red and green forms) is always available to liven up any dish. This ranges from merely quite hot to cataclysmically spicy, so test with caution before dolloping it on.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tipping is not really customary amongst the Malagasy, but it is increasingly normal in tourist places. At restaurants, about 5% would be plenty.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Live bands, discos and solo musicians are the key attraction. Nightclubs are a feature of even the smallest rural villages, especially in the south. Bigger discos often hold themed nights, which they advertise ahead of time on their Facebook pages. In more major tourist centres, most especially on Nosy Be, foreigners may be hassled by large numbers of local prostitutes. Many bars and restaurants also host live music, typically one night per week.</p><p>Casinos can be found in Antananarivo, Tamatave and on Nosy Be, but more often than not in the rest of the country the word casino refers to a room with a few simple arcade machines – rather than roulette, craps and other croupier-managed games.</p><p>Most main towns have a cinema and sometimes a theatre, and local touring theatre groups perform Madagascar-wide. Traditional dance troupes can also be seen. It's worth consulting the local Alliance Française (most towns have a branch) for information of forthcoming events.</p><p>In Antananarivo, the Centre Culturel Albert Camus on the main avenue in Analakely hosts all kinds of arts events, including dance performances, film screenings, art exhibitions and plays.</p><p>To find out what's on in the capital, pick up the latest edition of <em>No Comment</em>, <em>Tana Planète</em> or <em>Sortir à Tana</em> – all regular free booklets that can be found in hotels and restaurants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handicrafts include textiles such as <em>lamba</em> (traditional sarong-like cloths in various designs worn by women in a number of different ways, including as a sling for carrying their babies) and silk scarves, usually made from the rough silk of an endemic silkworm rather than the smooth silk more typically found abroad.</p><p>Crocheted and embroidered table cloths are also a popular product of the northern and central areas, especially Nosy Be and Tamatave. Good quality cotton T-shirts printed with Malagasy designs and slogans are found everywhere.</p><p>Wooden items are popular, either carved or with marquetry, including chessboards and boxes. The main centre for woodwork is Ambositra on the RN7 south of the capital. Wooden musical instruments include djembe drums and the <em>valiha</em> (Malagasy tube zither).</p><p>Most wooden handicrafts are made from palisander, rosewood or ebony, all precious slow-growing hardwoods being logged from the forests at an alarming rate, so there is an ethical issue with buying carved souvenirs.</p><p>Jewellery includes silver bracelets and items made from zebu horn and precious stones. Polished specimens of semi-precious minerals come in endless variety, betraying the country's fascinating and diverse geology.</p><p>Toy cars and <em>taxi-brousses</em> handmade from recycled tins make for a particularly novel and colourful gift. They can be found on markets in the capital.</p><p>Other souvenirs include items woven from reeds, raffia, sisal and straw (including hats, bags and ornamental animals). Antaimoro paper, decorated with embedded dried flowers, is sold as sheets, notebooks, bookmarks, and even made into picture frames, purses and lampshades.</p><p>For those who prefer edible souvenirs, you will be offered vanilla pods, peppercorns, cinnamon sticks, cloves and other spices; there is locally produced chocolate too (look for the Robert brand). Malagasy wine is available although the quality is mostly rather mediocre.</p><p>Note that products incorporating flora or fauna, as well as gems and minerals, often require export permits. Consult the relevant ministry kiosk at the airport.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1730 with closure of around two hours for lunch.</p><p>Haggling is expected on markets, but less so in shops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s plenty of choice when it comes to Madagascar&rsquo;s hotel options, particularly in the capital Antananarivo and towns of Nossi B&eacute;, Toamasina, Majunga, Ifaty and Tamatave. Ongoing tourism initiatives are continuing to add an increasing number of international-standard at moderate prices in major centres. However, it&rsquo;s certainly possible to stay in budget hotels (around US$10 a night) in the cities. Outside the larger towns, the hotels are much more basic with rustic, shoestring accommodation the norm. Lodging for groups and young people is also available.</p>
<p><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels are classified from 1 to 5 stars (5-star being equivalent to an international standard of about 3 stars); a secondary system of <em>ravinala</em> (travellers' palms) is used for simple, budget accommodation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Those on smaller budgets might want to consider staying in a guesthouse or B&amp;B. Again, the majority will be found in Antananarivo and other larger towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s plenty of choice when it comes to Madagascar&rsquo;s hotel options, particularly in the capital Antananarivo and towns of Nossi B&eacute;, Toamasina, Majunga, Ifaty and Tamatave. Ongoing tourism initiatives are continuing to add an increasing number of international-standard at moderate prices in major centres. However, it&rsquo;s certainly possible to stay in budget hotels (around US$10 a night) in the cities. Outside the larger towns, the hotels are much more basic with rustic, shoestring accommodation the norm. Lodging for groups and young people is also available.</p>
<p><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels are classified from 1 to 5 stars (5-star being equivalent to an international standard of about 3 stars); a secondary system of <em>ravinala</em> (travellers' palms) is used for simple, budget accommodation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s plenty of choice when it comes to Madagascar&rsquo;s hotel options, particularly in the capital Antananarivo and towns of Nossi B&eacute;, Toamasina, Majunga, Ifaty and Tamatave. Ongoing tourism initiatives are continuing to add an increasing number of international-standard at moderate prices in major centres. However, it&rsquo;s certainly possible to stay in budget hotels (around US$10 a night) in the cities. Outside the larger towns, the hotels are much more basic with rustic, shoestring accommodation the norm. Lodging for groups and young people is also available.</p>
<p><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels are classified from 1 to 5 stars (5-star being equivalent to an international standard of about 3 stars); a secondary system of <em>ravinala</em> (travellers' palms) is used for simple, budget accommodation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Much of the healthcare in Madagascar is robust, with several hospitals and health care centres spread throughout the country. However, services are sometimes lacking, and whilst basic healthcare is free, hospitals are often woefully under staffed. Health insurance is strongly recommended; it should include cover for emergency repatriation. Private healthcare is also available. Pharmacies are thin on the ground so visitors should stock up and pack plenty of medication for stomach upsets as effective remedies in the country will be limited. There is no emergency ambulance service on the island, although a private air ambulance service is available. The emergency number for police is 17.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Visitors should not drink the tap water in Madagascar. Water quality country-wide is likely to be contaminated so water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should be sterilised or boiled first. Milk is unpasteurised and so the widely-available powdered or tinned milk is advised. Dairy products are also best avoided. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled. Check all food is well-cooked, especially meat and fish.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Bilharzia is common but travellers can avoid it by avoiding swimming and paddling in fresh water and saving their swims for only clean, well-chlorinated swimming pools. Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes advised. There have been outbreaks of human plague in Northwest Madagascar as well as in other regions; travellers should avoid handling sick or dead animals and take insect protection measures such as wearing repellent. Malaria is a risk in Madagascar, so do take steps to protect yourself by taking a course of anti-malarials.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							29 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							26 June </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods can be imported into Madagascar without incurring customs duty by persons 18 years of age and over:</p>
<p>&bull; 2 cartons or 20 packs of cigarettes.<br />
&bull; 2L of alcoholic drinks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unauthorised firearms and ammunition, and endangered species (unless accompanied by a CITES permit).&nbsp;</p>
<p>Plants, fruit and vegetables require a phytosanitary certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Endangered species (unless accompanied by a CITES certificate).</p>
<p>You must obtain a certificate/permit to export animals and plants and their products, precious wood and precious stones.</p>
<p>Tourists should be aware that many items on sale may have been manufactured illegally and may not be taken out of the country, with or without a permit.</p>
<p>For certain goods, there are limits to the quantities you can export from Madagascar. For example, you can export up to 2kg of vanilla or 1kg of precious stones (250g for residents).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ariary (MGA; symbol Ar) = 5 iraimbilanja. Notes are in denominations of Ar20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 2,000, 1,000, 500, 200 and 100. Coins are in denominations of Ar50, 20, 10, 5, 2, 1, and 2, 1 iraimbilanja.</p>
<p><strong>Note: </strong>Malagasy Francs are no longer accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency can be bought only at banks and official bureaux de change in hotels and at the airport in Antananarivo. Exchange rates in hotels are less-favourable than other outlets. The Ariary is a non-convertible currency and cannot be exchanged back into tradable currency. Changing small amounts, as required, is therefore advisable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, Mastercard and Visa are accepted at top-end hotels in Tana and the provincial capitals. However, outside of the main cities cash is king.</p><p>ATMs can be found in and around the capital and in some of the larger towns. However, many of these only take visa; the daily withdrawal limit is 400,000Ar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These can be exchanged in banks and major hotels. Traveller's cheques in Euros or US Dollars are advisable to avoid additional exchange rate charges. Cashing traveller's cheques can be very time-consuming.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1100 and 1400-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Madagascar, a passport valid for six months after the date of entry is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay tourism visa: &euro;27/ $28.70 (up to 30 days); &euro;33 / $35.88 (31 to 60 days); &euro;46 / $50.23 (61 to 90 days).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay tourism visa: 30, 60 or 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). UK residents should apply to the embassy in Paris.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow two to five working days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-19.272009]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[46.698011]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>587,041 sq km (226,658 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>24,890,000 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>40.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Antananarivo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Located 500km (300 miles) off the coast of Mozambique in the Indian Ocean, Madagascar is world&rsquo;s fourth-largest island. Accompanied by several much smaller sibling isles, it is characterised by a central chain of high mountains, the Hauts Plateaux. This spiny ridge dominates the main island&rsquo;s terrain and is a dividing line that marks Madagascar&rsquo;s east-and-west differences in ethnicity, climate, and scenery.</p>
<p>On the east coast, a skinny strip of lowlands, settled from the sixth century by Polynesian seafarers, is largely covered by dense rainforests. The broader west-coast landscape, once clad in dry deciduous forests, is now mostly grasslands. On both coasts, the climate is wetter towards the north although the east coast receives the monsoon. Semi-desert and forests of cactus-like scrub characterises the island&rsquo;s southern tip with much of Madagascar&rsquo;s flora and fauna is wholly unique. Busy capital city, Antananarivo, is situated high up in the Hauts Plateaux and almost denotes the island&rsquo;s geographical centre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Around 52% follow animist beliefs whilst about 41% are Christian. The remainder are Muslim.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malagasy people are extremely hospitable and welcoming with a refreshingly open communicative style that can sometimes border on direct. A handshake is the usual form of of greeting between strangers meeting for the first time. If meeting a friend then three kisses on the cheek is fine.</p><p>Arrangements and meetings can suffer as a result of a relaxed attitude to clock-watching. Dress is casual, except for posh hotels and restaurants where lightweight suits are advised. Note that military-style clothing should always be avoided, as wearing it can lead to arrest. Restaurants and bars are used for entertaining, with invitations to a family home requiring a good degree of personal acquaintance. An invitation to attend a special celebration is a great honour. Acts of kindness should be rewarded with a gift, but never money. Respect should be afforded to the many local taboos (<em>fady</em>) of the Malagasy – these are  various behaviours that you shouldn't do. Although these can change from tribe to tribe and person to person (try to be informed about what they will be before travelling to a new area on the island), some fady are imposed nationwide. Examples include not pointing at tombs, and not killing a propithecus lemur.</p><p><strong>Photography: </strong>Military, airport or police establishments should not be photographed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220-240 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins (sometimes with a grounding pin) are most commonly used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Christian Ntsay since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Interim President Rivo Rakotovao since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Until the French invasion of 1895, for most of the 19th century Madagascar had been a kingdom, although historically it had been ruled by a variety of alliances. It remained a French colony until achieving full independence in 1960, following a bloody uprising 13 years previously.</p><p>For most of the next 40 years, former military man Didier Ratsiraka held power imposing his own brand of Christian-Marxism until his policies caused spectacular economic collapse.</p><p>In the early 2000s, a businessman and former mayor of Antananarivo – Marc Ravalomanana – took over the presidency after achieving a narrow electoral victory, which Ratsiraka initially refused to accept.</p><p>There followed seven years of impressive economic growth for Madagascar under Ravalomanana's leadership, accompanied by extensive development such as road building. The international community was impressed by the president's resolve to triple the protected areas of the country to around 10 per cent.</p><p>Sadly, during his second term in office, he began to abuse his position for personal gain and public opinion turned against him. A young former DJ named Andry Rajoelina seized this opportunity to topple Ravalomanana in a coup d'état. Rajoelina successfully forced Ravalomanana into exile and appointed himself leader.</p><p>Between 2009 and 2014, Madagascar had no internationally recognised government. Most international aid was stopped, living standards across the country dropped, the economy backpedalled and the security situation worsened.</p><p>Rajoelina's stated aim was to organise democratic elections, but it soon became clear that he had no intention of giving up power. During those five years he dragged his feet and deliberately derailed plans each time election dates were set, while hurrying through constitutional changes that would favour him as a presidential candidate.</p><p>Eventually he realised that the international community would never accept him as rightful president, even if he were to win free and fair democratic elections. He decided to change tack and put forward a proxy candidate called Hery Rajaonarimampianina.</p><p>Elections went ahead in late 2013 and Rajaonarimampianina won, having spent eye-watering sums – thought to have come from the sale of vast quantities of illegally logged rosewood timber to China – on campaigning. He assumed the presidency in January 2014, with Rajoelina subsequently declaring his intention to run for president in the future.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• In many regions, savika – cattle wrestling – is a popular recreation.</p><p>• The lamba, Madagascar's national dress, is a rectangular length of cloth wrapped around the upper body. Ceremonial lamba can be made of silk or cow hide, but everyday ones are more likely to be cotton, bast or raffia pig skin.</p><p>• Libertatia, a possibly fictitious anarchist colony formed by pirates, may have been based on Nosy Boroha, a small island off the northeastern coast of Madagascar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Madagascar in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 5525.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.madagascar-consulate.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 265 5525.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Madagascar in France]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>01 4504 6211.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambassade-madagascar.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>01 4504 6211.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1400-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>4 Avenue Raphael<br/>Paris<br/>75016<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Madagascar]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+261 2022 33053.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-antananarivo</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+261 2022 33053.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Mon-Fri 0830-1230 and 1400-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Ravoninahitriniarivo Street<br/>Ninth Floor Tour Zital<br/>Ankorondrano<br/>Antananarivo 101<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Undoubtedly one of the world&rsquo;s most fascinating destinations, Madagascar floats off the coast of Mozambique, in the turquoise waters of the Indian Ocean, and is home to some of the weirdest, most wonderful wildlife in existence. A clich&eacute; it may be, but there really is nowhere quite like it.</p>
<p>Up to 90% of the flora and fauna found in Madagascar is unique to the island, which was cut adrift from the African mainland millions of years ago and has evolved in sweet isolation since. Mother Nature had a chance to experiment in Madagascar, and experiment she did.</p>
<p>Nowadays the island is home to around a quarter of our planet&rsquo;s primates and they exist in glorious variety: big and small, social and solitary, adorably cute and downright freaky. The primates&rsquo; story is played out across the animal groups: there are several hundred types of frog, dozens of bats, over a hundred snakes (mostly small, all harmless) and almost half of the world&rsquo;s chameleons. It&rsquo;s a similar story where flora is concerned, too.</p>
<p>But Madagascar is not just a nirvana for naturalists: the island offers splendid beaches, scuba diving and surfing; gnarly rock climbing and caving; lazy river trips; spectacular scenery; and warm, welcoming people with interesting beliefs and cultural practices.</p>
<p>The island is divided along its middle by a high plateau. Lush rainforest runs in a band down the eastern side, while drier deciduous forests lie to the west. In the far south is the unique arid spiny forest, home to the island&rsquo;s wackiest plant life. Giant baobab trees populate the western regions.</p>
<p>A mix of influences provides telltale evidence of the Polynesian settlers, Arabic presence, Bantu tribes-folk and European arrivals of the past, all of which have culminated in a fascinating cultural melting pot. For sheer diversity, Madagascar hard to beat.</p><p>Undoubtedly one of the world&rsquo;s most fascinating destinations, Madagascar floats off the coast of Mozambique, in the turquoise waters of the Indian Ocean, and is home to some of the weirdest, most wonderful wildlife in existence. A clich&eacute; it may be, but there really is nowhere quite like it.</p>
<p>Up to 90% of the flora and fauna found in Madagascar is unique to the island, which was cut adrift from the African mainland millions of years ago and has evolved in sweet isolation since. Mother Nature had a chance to experiment in Madagascar, and experiment she did.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
