<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Malawi" ColCode="mwi" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mw" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Malawi]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Varies from cool in the highlands to warm around Lake Malawi. Winter (May to July) is dry and nights can be chilly, particularly in the highlands. The rainy season runs from November to March. Around Lake Malawi, in winter, the climate is particularly dry with pleasant cooling breezes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights are worn all year in the Lake Malawi area, with warmer<br />clothes advised in the mountains, particularly during winter and on<br />chilly evenings elsewhere. Visitors to Nyika and Zomba should note that<br />the nights can be cold. Dark or 'natural' coloured clothing should be<br />worn for game viewing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ulendo Airlink (<a href="http://www.flyulendo.com/" target="_blank">www.flyulendo.com</a>) operates domestic flights in Malawi, serving destinations including Lilongwe, Liwonde and Likoma Island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Ilala ferry connects communities along Lake Malawi and has single and double cabins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Central East African Railways (tel: +265 1 840 841) operates the lines in the country. The main route connects Mchinji, Lilongwe, Salima, Chipoka, Blantyre, Limbe and Nsanje. Trains tend to be slow and crowded and are little used by tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>All major roads are tarmac and most secondary roads are all-weather.</p><p>AXA Coach Service (tel: +265 1 876 000) operates coaches between Malawi's main towns and cities.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>Available from local and international firms, particularly in Lilongwe and Blantyre, with a number of companies offering a wide choice of vehicles. Standards do vary (even with the internationally franchised chains) so it's worth seeking a recommendation. Nonetheless, you should reserve cars well in advance as they are very much in demand. Chauffeur-driven cars are also available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bus:</strong> There are services in all major cities.</p>
<p><strong>Taxi:</strong> You can find taxis in cities, but they're less easy to pick up in rural areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Malawi</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">zomba</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Malawi</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">mzuzu</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Malawi</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">mangochi</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Malawi</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">karonga</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Malawi</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">blantyre</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Proflight <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/zambia">Zambia</a> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.proflight-zambia.com">www.proflight-zambia.com</a>) connects Zambia with flights to Malawi's capital Lilongwe. From the UK, you can fly to Malawi with Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="http://www.ethiopianairlines.com" target="_blank">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>) via Addis Ababa or Kenya Airways (<a href="http://www.kenya-airways.com" target="_blank">www.kenya-airways.com</a>) via Nairobi. Alternatively, British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), South African Airways (<a href="http://www.flysaa.com" target="_blank">www.flysaa.com</a>) and Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) fly direct from London to Johannesburg, from where you can take a connecting flight with Ethiopian Airlines or South African Airways.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 14 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 19 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chileka International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport (Chileka) is 13km (8 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Lilongwe International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport (Lilongwe International) is 26km (16 miles) from the city (journey time - 25 to 30 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Central East African Railways (CEAR) (tel: +265 1 840 841; <a href="http://www.cear.mw" target="_blank">www.cear.mw</a>) has a network which extends from the Zambian border in the west to connections with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mozambique">Mozambique</a>'s Nacala corridor in the east and Beira corridor in the south.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements currently exist with many international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good in urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Services are available in business centres in hotels, and there are a few Internet cafes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Radio is the chief source of information and state-run MBC is the main national broadcaster. Television was introduced in 1999. Privately owned publications present a range of opinions, although the government has used libel and other laws to put pressure on newspaper journalists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Letters take about seven to 10 days to reach Europe by airmail.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0730-1200 and 1300-1700. Post offices in some of the larger towns may be open Sun 0900-1000, but only to sell stamps or to accept telegrams.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Lake Malawi</p><![CDATA[<p>See the 24,000 sq km (15,000 sq miles) lake that lies in the deep, trough-like rift valley, running the length of the country. Lake Malawi contains more fish than any other lake in the world and some of the rarest tropical fish are unique to it. Lake Malawi National Park was created in 1980 as the world's first freshwater national park. It can be found on the southern shore of Lake Malawi. The park encompasses a wide variety of scenery, ranging from the wooded rocky mountains sloping down to the shores of the lake, to sandy coves and beaches. The lush vegetation is home to a range of wildlife including many species of bird and fish. The clear blue waters of the lake are popular for snorkelling and scuba diving, as well as sailing, kayaking and swimming. Within the park, visitors can stay at lodges to enjoy traditional Malawian hospitality and fresh fish from the lake.</p>]]><br/><p>Liwonde National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Due to its unspoilt environment and prolific game, <em>Liwonde National Park</em> is generally regarded as the best game reserve in Malawi. It covers 550 sq kilometres (212 sq miles) of mopane and savanna woodland on the floodplains of the <em>River Shire</em> and <em>Lake Malombe </em>in the south of the country. Wildlife includes large herds of elephant, hippos, crocodiles, antelope, zebra, warthogs, bushback and sable. In addition, visitors can also see lions and leopards. The river plains are home to many species of bird. Plants and trees found in Liwonde National Park include the baobab, a large native African tree bearing a gourd-like fruit with a delicious pulp. Despite the incredible sigths, the park is still relatively peaceful and uncommercialised.w</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Climb the Mulanje Massif</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rising out of the surrounding plains and tea-growing Mulanje region, the massif is popular with hikers and climbers, and has several huts. The highest point of this huge block of mountains, which cover more than 640 sq km (250 sq miles), is Sapitwa Peak. At just over 3,000m (10,000ft), it is the country's loftiest summit.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Lower Shire Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Malawi's far south, the Lower Shire Valley has a very different look and feel. Low lying with higher temperatures, it is dominated by the River Shire. The only river to drain from Lake Malawi, it goes on to join the mighty Zambezi. A fertile region, there are vast sugar plantations to be seen at Sucoma.</p>]]><p><b>Follow in the footsteps of Livingstone</b></p><![CDATA[<p>View the many markets on the shore of Lake Malawi, including Nkhotakota, one of Africa's oldest market towns and a major centre of the Arab-Swahili slave trade until David Livingstone convinced Chief Jumbe to end the practice. Further north, Nkhata Bay is a busy port and market and a favourite with visitors for its lush tropical atmosphere.</p>]]><p><b>Get active on the Nyika Plateau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike, mountain bike or ride a horse on the grassland of Nyika Plateau, where safaris on horseback are a popular activity. Fully encompassing Nyika National Park, the plateau is known for its wildlife, particularly Burchell's zebra and endemic butterfly, bird and orchid populations. Accommodation and equipment hire is at Chelinda.</p>]]><p><b>Go on safari in Liwonde National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Due to its unspoiled environment and prolific game, Liwonde National Park is generally considered the best reserve in Malawi. Covering 550 sq km (212 sq miles) of thin woodland in the country's south, wildlife includes large herds of elephant, hippos, lion, and a vast array of birds and antelope. Alternatively, look out for elephant and buffalo in Kasungu National Park.</p>]]><p><b>Grab a rod and reel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fishing, possible all year round on the southern lakeshore north of Mangochi and at Senga Bay, offers the opportunity to reel in <em>ngumbo</em> (yellow fish), <em>mpasa</em> (lake salmon) and <em>ncheni</em> (lake tiger) among other species. Trout fishing is easily arranged in the rivers and streams of the Nyika and Zomba Plateaus.</p>]]><p><b>Head north to Mzuzu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Capital of the northern region, Mzuzu reflects the culture of the Tumbuka, while remaining largely agricultural with tea, coffee and rubber plantations. Africa's largest manmade forest lies to the south, and Nyika National Park and Vwasa Marsh Wildlife Reserve are nearby. The famous Livingstonia Mission, with its red brick homes and small museum, is approximately three hours away.</p>]]><p><b>Immerse yourself in Lake Malawi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A range of watersports are available along the 580km (360 mile) length of Lake Malawi. Snorkelling and scuba-diving are increasingly popular because of the attraction of seeing the brilliantly coloured fish, the <em>mbuna</em> (African cichlids). Swimming, waterskiing, sailing and kayaking are all possible at various locations on the lakeshore.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in the capital, Lilongwe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Malawi's capital since 1975, Lilongwe was officially founded in 1906 as a colonial trading post. Alongside the traditional Old Town, with its interesting walled markets, is the modern New Town and seat of government with its imaginative architecture and beautiful garden setting. A short journey away is the famous pottery workshop at Dedza.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about Blantyre’s history</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Malawi's commercial capital and largest town was established at the end of the 19th century. Sights include the National Museum on Chichiri Hill, St Michael and All Angels Church and its associated clock tower with its links to David Livingstone, and Mandala House. The oldest European building in Malawi, it dates back to 1882.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the view from Zomba Plateau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>North of Blantyre, the 2,100m (6,890ft) Zomba Plateau offers spectacular views and fantastic walking, rock climbing and mountain biking. Its vast forests and waterfalls tower above Zomba, a university town and the former capital. Known for its colonial architecture and botanic gardens, the town is also home to a school of dressage.</p>]]><p><b>Take the steamer to Likoma Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located near Malawi's marine border with Mozambique, Likoma and its sister island Chizumulu offer a glimpse of largely unspoiled East African ocean and excellent swimming. The town of Mbamba is the site of the Saint Peter's Anglican Cathedral. One of the largest churches in Africa, it was built by missionaries over a century ago.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the world’s first freshwater national park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lake Malawi National Park lies towards the southern extremity of the lake near Monkey Bay. Snorkelling or scuba-diving reveals tropical fish, while inland antelope and vervet monkeys can be seen. An 800-year-old baobab tree in the park is reported to have been one of explorer David Livingstone's favourite spots.</p>]]><p><b>Witness a traditional dance</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Traditional dances play a part in most ceremonies in Malawi. The <em>Gule Wamkulu</em> is an important dance performed by members of the Chewa tribe's Nyau brotherhood, who cover themselves in carved masks, feathers and skin paint. It takes place following the July harvest, and also at weddings and funerals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2.2 billion (2006).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Tobacco, tea and coffee, sugar, peanuts and wood products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, petroleum products, semi-manufactured goods, consumer goods and transportation equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>South Africa, Germany, USA and Zimbabwe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The economy is almost entirely agricultural but the manufacturing industry now accounts for about 15% of economic output. Manufacturing is concentrated in light industrial import substitution projects such as textiles, chemicals, agricultural implements and processed foodstuffs. Tourism is intended to become a major source of foreign exchange but this will depend on improvements in basic infrastructure and political stability in the region.<br /><br />In 2006, the economy grew by 6.4%, while inflation was 14%. Recent economic policy has followed an orthodox course of privatisation, deregulation and government spending cuts. The latter have had a severe impact on the country's already limited basic services, especially healthcare. Between one-third and one-half of the working population are thought to be infected with HIV/AIDS, with the inevitable economic consequences.<br /><br />Malawi is normally self-sufficient in food, especially maize, the main staple. But it also has a vast balance of payments deficit and is heavily dependent on foreign aid, both bilateral and from the World Bank.<br />Malawi's only dedicated conference centre is the Kwacha International Conference Centre in Blantyre, with seating for up to 500 people. Details of this and hotels with conference facilities can be obtained from the Malawi Tourism (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits or a jacket and tie are suitable for business meetings in cities. Similar to the European system, appointments should generally be made and business cards are used. Offices tend to open early in Malawi. Best months for business visits are May to July and September to November.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Malawi Confederation of Chambers of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 01 871 988
					Website:http://www.mccci.org
					Address: PO Box 258,Masauko Chipembere Highway,Chichiri Trade Fair Ground,Blantyre,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Relatively free from outside influences, the food of Malawi remains rustic and traditional. Outside of the big cities, it's likely the food you eat will have been grown locally by those serving you.</p><p>Dishes are centred on starchy carbohydrates, which are still often served at all three daily meals, with side dishes of vegetables and meat, particularly chicken and goat.</p><p>Fresh fish from Lake Malawi is the country's speciality, and is both tastily cooked and easy to come by. Dairy products are plentiful thanks to cattle farming, and tropical fruits such as bananas, mangoes and pineapples are abundant in season.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Nsima</strong>: Traditional thick carbohydrate staple made from maize flour.<br />
<strong>Ndivo</strong>: Sauce or stew made with either vegetable leaves or meat that is added to nsima for flavour.<br />
<strong>Utipa</strong>: A small fish like whitebait or sardines.<br />
<strong>Chambo</strong>: Often curried with carrots, onion and lemon juice, this fish is also known as tilapia.<br />
<strong>Nkhwaniwotendera</strong>: Pumpkin leaves in peanut powder stew.<br />
<strong>Dziwala</strong>: Fried grasshopper sprinkled with onion, salt and tomatoes.<br />
<strong>Nthochi</strong>: Bread made from mashed banana.<br />
<strong>Waliwasamaki</strong>: Salmon served with vermicelli, onions, carrots, rice and seasoning.<br />
<strong>Mbatata</strong>: Biscuits made with sweet potato and cinnamon.<br />
<strong>Mandasi</strong>: Type of plain local deep-fried doughnut.<br />
<strong>Mawehu</strong>: Refreshing unsweetened non-alcoholic drink made from maize meal.<br />
<strong>Chibuku:</strong> Served in a milk carton this beer is made from fermented maize and has the consistency of porridge.<br />
<strong>Kuche Kuche:</strong> A light local beer.<br />
<strong>Malawi Gin:</strong> Serve with tonic and a slice of lemon.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Generally not expected, but some employees who are very poorly paid might appreciate a small tip for good service.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is little nightlife in the European or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> sense. Some restaurants have entertainment as do some of the hotels but outside Blantyre and Lilongwe this will usually take the form of a display of dancing during or after dinner at the lakeshore hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malawi produces a variety of colourful arts and crafts. Items are invariably handmade and there is no factory production of curios. Purchases include woodcarvings, wood and cane furniture, soapstone carvings, decorated wooden articles, colourful textiles, pottery, beadwork, cane and raffia items. The standard of woodcarving is one of the highest in Africa. The <em>Mua Mission</em>, south of Salima, where carvers are trained, has an excellent shop. Traditional musical instruments are also sold throughout Malawi.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1700. Markets and roadside stalls trade every day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are good hotels in all the main centres, along the shore of Lake Malawi and at some attractions, including a luxury hotel at the Zomba Plateau. Along the lakeshore, there is a concentration in the south between Monkey Bay, Mangochi and Senga Bay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are good hotels in all the main centres, along the shore of Lake Malawi and at some attractions, including a luxury hotel at the Zomba Plateau. Along the lakeshore, there is a concentration in the south between Monkey Bay, Mangochi and Senga Bay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are good hotels in all the main centres, along the shore of Lake Malawi and at some attractions, including a luxury hotel at the Zomba Plateau. Along the lakeshore, there is a concentration in the south between Monkey Bay, Mangochi and Senga Bay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is essential. It is advisable to take personal medical supplies, including needles.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against meningococcal meningitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Avoid swimming and paddling in slow-moving or stagnant fresh water; swimming pools which are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. The risk of contracting bilharzia when engaging in watersports in Lake Malawi is minimised if sensible precautions are taken. Bathers should swim only at the resort areas known to be free of bilharzia, avoiding parts of the lake where there is still water or close human habitation. Many areas of the lake are free of this disease.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the preceding Friday or following Monday.<br /><br />Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Chilembwe Day :
							2018<br/>15 January </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							03 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Freedom Day :
							14 June </p><p>Republic Day :
							06 July </p><p>Mother's Day :
							08 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Malawi by passengers over 16 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 250g of tobacco in any form.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits.<br />
&bull; 1L of wine or beer.<br />
&bull; 250ml of eau de toilette and 50ml of perfume.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited or restricted imports include arms and ammunition, flick knives, game traps, pharmaceutical products, gold, sugar, wild animals and their products, and some foods (eg bananas, potatoes and uncooked meat).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kwacha (MWK; symbol Mk) = 100 tambala. Notes are in denominations of Mk500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of Mk1 and 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 tambala.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollars, Pounds Sterling, Euros or South African Rand are readily exchanged but lesser-known currencies may prove difficult to exchange.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Acceptance of credit and debit cards is very limited, although in Lilongwe and Blantyre and in main hotels, American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa can be used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques can be exchanged in banks, hotels and other institutions. In remote areas, the Treasury Office of Local District Commissioner's offices will cash traveller's cheques. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars, Euros, Pounds Sterling or South African Rand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Malawi, a passport valid for at least six months beyond the date of intended departure is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>
<p>All nationals referred to in the chart above are required to have a return ticket except in special circumstances such as long-term study visits or working contracts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: Transit visa: US$50; single-entry visa: US$75; six-month multiple-entry visa: US$150; one-year multiple-entry visa: US$250.</p>
<p>Visa from the embassy/high commission:&nbsp;Transit visa: &pound;50; single-entry visa: &pound;65; six-month multiple-entry visa: &pound;145; one-year multiple entry visa: &pound;200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: seven days; single-entry visa: 90 days; multiple-entry visas: six months or one year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy or high commission) or on arrival at the airport (for certain countries only).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa applications are processed in three days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals who require a visa must show bank statements from the past three months when applying.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-13.350005]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[33.754036]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>118,484 sq km (45,747 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>17,749,826 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>151.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lilongwe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malawi shares borders to the north and northeast with Tanzania, to the south, east and southwest with Mozambique and to the west with Zambia. Lake Malawi, the third largest lake in Africa, is the dominant feature of the country, forming the eastern boundary with Tanzania and Mozambique. The scenery varies in the country's three regions. The Northern Region is mountainous, with the highest peaks reaching over 2,500m (8,200ft), and features the rolling Nyika Plateau, rugged escarpments, valleys and the thickly forested slopes of the Viphya Plateau. The Central Region is mainly a plateau, over 1,000m (3,300ft) high, with fine upland scenery. This is the country's main agricultural area. The Southern Region is mostly low-lying except for the 2,100m-high (6,890ft) Zomba Plateau south of Lake Malawi and the huge, isolated Mulanje Massif (3,000m/10,000ft) in the southeast. The variety of landscape and the wildlife it supports make this relatively unspoilt country particularly attractive to visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>80% are Christian, 13% Muslim. A recorded 4.3% of the remaining 7% have no religion (1998 census).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite the large number of tribal backgrounds in the Malawi population, integration is well established and visitors need not be aware of any social differences. The white population is very small in number. There are some religious differences, most noticeable among the Muslim population and especially as far as alcohol consumption is concerned. </p>
<p>Malawians place emphasis on the importance of shaking hands on meeting and departing. The special handshake, which includes grasping the thumb and putting the other hand on the forearm, is best avoided unless practised. Children and some women may curtsey as a greeting or if being made a presentation. Offering a soft drink to a visitor is common at meetings. </p>
<p>Malawians tend to be conventional rather than casual in their dress, especially in formal gatherings. Modest dress should be worn unless at the beach or playing sport.</p><br />]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Peter Mutharika since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Peter Mutharika since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The shores of Lake Malawi have been inhabited for thousands of years and recent archaeological excavations have revealed evidence of settlements dating back to the late Stone and Iron Ages. The majority of the present population descend from Bantu tribes, who arrived in the region some time before the first Arab slave traders and Portuguese explorers. British colonial settlers and missionaries, including David Livingstone, moved into the area in the late 1850s.</p>
<p>Colonial domination became inevitable and, in 1891, the British declared the country the British Protectorate of Nyasaland. In 1953, the British federated Nyasaland with Northern and Southern Rhodesia (now Zambia and Zimbabwe), but Nyasaland seceded in 1963 following elections which gave Dr Hastings Banda a majority.</p>
<p>In 1964, Nyasaland became independent as Malawi and, two years later, was declared a republic and a one-party state. In 1971, Dr Banda became President for Life, and during his subsequent reign retained a firm grip of the country, jailing or exiling opponents and attracting criticism for his support of South Africa&rsquo;s apartheid regime.</p>
<p>By 1993, the ailing Banda was forced to concede political pluralism in Malawi. After the adoption of a new constitution, simultaneous parliamentary and presidential elections were held in 1994. Banda and his chief henchman, the much-hated and feared John Tembo, were put on trial for their alleged role in the 1983 murders of four opposition politicians. They were acquitted in 1995, although investigations into various financial misdemeanours continued. The prosecution of Banda ended with his death in 1997, but Tembo was eventually convicted in 2003.</p>
<p>Abroad, Malawi has aligned itself with the post-liberation government in South Africa, the main political and economic force in the region. Domestically, the HIV/AIDS pandemic has been the dominant issue: Malawi is one of the worst affected countries with an estimated one million people (just under 10% of the total population) living with the infection.</p>
<p>Traditionally a very conservative society strongly influenced by Scottish missionaries during the colonial era, Malawi has found it hard to come to terms with its plight.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Blantyre, the second city, hosts an annual nsima eating contest. Winners can expect to pack away up to 3kg of the starch.<br />
&bull;	Lake Malawi contains more fish species than any other lake.<br />
&bull;	The lake is locally known as Lake Nyasa, which translates as &lsquo;Lake Lake&rsquo;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Malawi]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>177 2400.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-high-commission-lilongwe</p><p><b>Tel:</b>177 2400.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0730-1200 and 1330-1630; Fri 0730-1230.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Off Convention Drive<br/>Lilongwe 3<br/>P.O. box 30042<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Malawi in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 721 0270.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.malawiembassy-dc.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 721 0270.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2408 Massachusetts Avenue NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission of the Republic of Malawi in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7421 6010.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7421 6010.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Opening hours: Mon-Fri 0930-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Holborn<br/>36 John Street<br/>London<br/>WC1N 2AT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Little Malawi is dwarfed by its much bigger southern African neighbours and this has undoubtedly affected both its tourism and its economy over the years.</p>
<p>But thanks to a number of successful conservation and wildlife reintroduction programs, Malawi is fast developing a reputation as an up-and-coming safari destination, and tourists are slowly cottoning on to the wealth of other offerings to be found in the so-called warm heart of Africa.</p>
<p>Malawi currently has nine national parks and wildlife reserves, six of which are especially recommended for visitors. There are also many attractive and accessible forest reserves. All the parks and reserves are uncrowded and give visitors an excellent experience of unspoiled wilderness. In 2012, lions were reintroduced into Majete Wildlife Reserve after a 30-year absence, which means Malawi is once again home to the Big 5 (lion, leopard, elephant, buffalo and rhino).</p>
<p>As well as iconic African wildlife, Malawi also boasts diverse scenery, including deep valleys, evergreen forests and waterfalls, all presided over by the dramatic peaks of Mount Mulanje and the rugged and regal Zomba Plateau in the south.</p>
<p>Outdoor activities are central to any visit to Malawi. You can trek, mountain bike or horse ride in entirely natural surroundings or climb peaks and plateaus.&nbsp;But the vast Lake Malawi remains the shimmering jewel in Malawi&rsquo;s crown. Cut into the Great Rift Valley and stretching from the northern tip of the country to Mangochi in the south, Lake Malawi is Africa&rsquo;s third largest lake.&nbsp;Some of the world&rsquo;s rarest tropical fish are found here, not to mention myriad bird species. It&rsquo;s a dream destination for twitching, scuba diving and kayaking, or simply relaxing by the beach.</p>
<p>Though Malawi remains one of the poorest countries in Africa, unlike some its neighbours it is an inherently peaceful place. And what it lacks in economic capital, it more than makes up for with its natural riches and ubiquitous kindness.</p><p>Little Malawi is dwarfed by its much bigger southern African neighbours and this has undoubtedly affected both its tourism and its economy over the years. But thanks to a number of successful conservation and wildlife reintroduction programs, Malawi is fast developing a reputation as an up-and-coming safari destination, and tourists are slowly cottoning on to the wealth of other offerings to be found in the so-called warm heart of Africa.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
