<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Malaysia" ColCode="mys" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="my" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[The best time for beach holidays or scuba-diving will depend on which part of Malaysia you intend to visit. The country is affected by the south-west monsoon from May to September and the north-east monsoon from November to March, and different parts of the country have their dry and wet seasons at different times of year.</p>
<p>On the west coast, the wettest months are May to October, while on the east coast, the wettest months are September to December. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kuala-lumpur">Kuala Lumpur</a> is wettest from March to April and September to November, while Malaysian Borneo sees its heaviest rainfall between November and February. The best time to visit for dry weather is June and July on the east coast, January and February on the west coast, April in Sabah and June to July in Sarawak.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight, loose-fitting clothes are sensible at any time of year. To avoid offending local sensibilities, female travellers should wear clothes that cover the legs and upper arms. Note that shorts are rarely worn by adults, except at the beach. Full-length trousers will create a better impression. Because of the rainfall patterns and the vagaries of Malaysia weather, always carry an umbrella.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main hubs for domestic flights are Kuala Lumpur, and Kota Kinabalu in Sabah, East Malaysia. Malaysia Airlines (<a href="http://www.malaysiaairlines.com" target="_blank">www.malaysiaairlines.com</a>) serves airports across the peninsula and Borneo, and MASwings (www.maswings.com.my) also offers domestic flights to Borneo.&nbsp;Low-cost options include Air Asia (<a href="http://www.airasia.com" target="_blank">www.airasia.com</a>), Malaysia Airlines subsidiary Firefly (<a href="http://www.fireflyz.com.my" target="_blank">www.fireflyz.com.my</a>) and Malindo Air (<a href="http://www.malindoair.com" target="_blank">www.malindoair.com</a>).</p>
<p>Unless you travel through Indonesia, the only way to get from peninsular Malaysia to East Malaysia is by air &ndash; the flight from Kuala Lumpur to Kota Kinabalu takes 2 hours 30 minutes. Advance bookings are recommended, particularly during school and religious holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coastal ferries<strong> </strong>sail frequently between Penang and Butterworth (<a href="http://www.penangport.com.my" target="_blank">www.penangport.com.my</a>) and there is a scheduled passenger service linking Port Klang with Kuantan, Sarawak and Sabah. Ferries also run between Kuala Perlis, Kuala Kedah, Penang, Satun and Langkawi; one of the companies serving the route between Kuala Perlis and Langkawi is  Langkawi-Ro-Ro-ferries (<a href="http://www.langkawiroro.com" target="_blank">www.langkawiroro.com</a>). Regular boat services connect Lumut to Pangkor Island and Tunjung Gemak or Mersing to Tioman Island.</p>
<p>In Sabah, long boats connect Labuan to Menumbak. Small rivercraft often provide the most practical means of getting about in East Malaysia, even in the towns, and they are the only way to reach the more isolated settlements (unless one has access to a helicopter). In rural Sarawak the major means of transport are air-conditioned express boats. Boats may easily be chartered and river buses and taxis are plentiful.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Keretapi Tanah Melayu Berhad (KTMB) (tel: +60 3 2267 1200; <a href="http://www.ktmb.com.my" target="_blank">www.ktmb.com.my</a>) operates train services in peninsular Malaysia. The main line runs north from Singapore to Kuala Lumpur and on to Butterworth and Pedang Basar on the Thai border. A second line separates at Gemas and runs northeast to Tumpat in Kelantan.</p>
<p>East Malaysia has one railway line, the North Borneo Railway, which connects Kota Kinabalu (Sabah) to the town of Papar. The only services on this line are the luxury steam trains run by the Sutera Harbour Resort (tel: +60 6088 318 88; <a href="http://www.suteraharbour.com" target="_blank">www.suteraharbour.com</a>) in Kota Kinabalu. There are no rail services in Sarawak.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>KTM Rail Pass:</strong> available to foreign tourists (except Singaporeans) and valid for five, 10 or 15 days. Passes permit unlimited travel on Intercity train services on the KTM network and into Singapore. Supplements apply for sleeping berths and on night trains. You can buy passes through travel agencies and at major railway stations, including the stations in Kuala Lumpur, Butterworth, Johor Bahru and Singapore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The road network is extensive and major roads are well maintained. However, standards deteriorate once you leave the big cities, and road rules are followed erratically in rural areas, particularly in Malaysian Borneo. For this reason, it's best not to drive at night. Note that unsurfaced roads in the highlands are often impassable during the rainy season.</p>
<p>The north-south expressway spans 890km (553 miles) from Bukit Kayu Hitam (on the Kedah-Thailand border) to Johor Bahru is the main highway.</p>l<p>Most roads in the peninsular states are paved and signs leading to the various destinations are well placed and clear.</p><p>There are dozens of private bus companies running services across Peninsular Malaysia and Borneo. Aeroline (tel: +60 3 6258 8800; <a href="http://www.aeroline.com.my" target="_blank">www.aeroline.com.my</a>) runs deluxe express buses from Kuala Lumpur to Penang. Transnasional (tel: +60 3 4045 8878; <a href="http://www.transnasional.com.my" target="_blank">www.transnasional.com.my</a>) is another reliable operator.</p><p>Malaysian taxis are metered, but drivers often ask for a fixed fare, particularly during the morning and afternoon rush hour, so you may need to bargain. If things are particularly busy, drivers may refuse to travel to certain destinations at all, in which case you may have to rely on local buses and commuter trains. You can flag taxis down in the street, but a queuing system operates at many train stations and shopping centres.</p>
<p>In Kuala Lumpur, shared taxis run from Puduraya Bus Station to cities around the country. In rural areas, taxis supplement the bus service, picking up passengers on route; you may need to pay extra to charter the whole taxi. Taxi drivers are usually not tipped.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is recommended. For UK citizens, a national driving licence is valid for three months.</p><p>Speed limits are 110kph (68mph) on expressways, 80-90kph (50-56mph) on main roads and 60kph (37mph) in urban areas unless otherwise posted. Seatbelts must be worn at all times. The use of handheld mobile phones is prohibited when driving. Penalties for drinking and driving are severe.</p><p>The Automobile Association of Malaysia (tel: 1 300 226 226, in Malaysia only or +60 3 5511 1932; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.aam.org.my/">www.aam.org.my</a>) provides a 24-hour emergency breakdown service.</p><p>This is available through international and domestic agencies.</p><p>Speed limits are 110kph (68mph) on expressways, 80-90kph (50-56mph) on main roads and 60kph (37mph) in urban areas unless otherwise posted. Seatbelts must be worn at all times. The use of handheld mobile phones is prohibited when driving. Penalties for drinking and driving are severe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rapid KL (tel +60 3 7885 2585; www.myrapid.com.my) runs Kuala Lumpur's buses, light rail and monorail. Trains serving the northern, southern and western suburbs are run by KTM (tel: +60 3 2267 1200; <a href="http://www.ktmb.com.my" target="_blank">www.ktmb.com.my</a>), part of the national train company KTMB. KLIA Ekspres and KLIA Transit trains (tel: +60 3 2267 8000; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.kliaekspres.com">www.kliaekspres.com</a>) serve destinations en route to Kuala Lumpur International Airport. It's also possible to get around by <em>Bas Mini</em> (fixed-route minibuses), taxis and pedi-cabs (trishaws).</p>
<p>Larger cities, including Melaka, Penang, Kuching and Kota Kinabalu, have their own public transport systems, mainly using buses, taxis and trishaws. Many smaller towns have local ferry services along and across rivers and inlets and between islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Malaysia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">singapore</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Malaysia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">penang</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Malaysia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">johor_bahru</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Malaysia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">alor_setar</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.30</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kuala-lumpur">Kuala Lumpur</a> is a major hub for flights between Europe, Asia and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>. Malaysia Airlines (<a href="http://www.malaysiaairlines.com" target="_blank">www.malaysiaairlines.com</a>) offers an extensive network of domestic and international flights, including direct routes between Europe and Malaysian Borneo.&nbsp;</p>
<p>For cheap fares to Singapore and cities around South-East Asia, try budget carriers Air Asia (<a href="http://www.airasia.com" target="_blank">www.airasia.com</a>), Jetstar (<a href="http://www.jetstar.com" target="_blank">www.jetstar.com</a>) and Firefly (www.fireflyz.com.my). Malindo Air (www.malindoair.com) offers flights within Malaysia as well as in Asia and Australia.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Because of the varied climatic conditions around the country, there is no nationwide high season, but flights can be expensive over Christmas and New Year, and during the Malaysian school holidays in May, June and August.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malaysia/kuala-lumpur-international-airport">Kuala Lumpur International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malaysia/penang-bayan-lepas-international-airport">Pengang International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 12 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 21 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Kuala Lumpur International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.klia.com.my<p>Kuala Lumpur International Airport is situated 55km (34 miles) south of Kuala Lumpur.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+603 8776 2000</p>]]><b>Penang International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.penangairport.com<p>Penang International Airport is located 16km (10 miles) south of Penang's capital city Georgetown and 6km (4 miles) north of Bayan Baru.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(04) 643 4411.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong>&nbsp;George Town (Penang)  (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.penangport.com.my/">www.penangport.com.my</a>), Port Klang (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.pka.gov.my/">www.pka.gov.my</a>), Northport (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.northport.com.my/">www.northport.com.my</a>) and Westport (for Kuala Lumpur) (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.westports.com.my/">www.westports.com.my</a>). In East Malaysia (for Sabah and Sarawak), they are Bintulu (www.bintuluport.com.my), Kota Kinabalu (www.spsb.com.my), Kuching (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.kpa.gov.my/">www.kpa.gov.my</a>), Lahad Datu (www.spsb.com.my), Rajang (www.rajangport.gov.my), Sandakan (www.spsb.com.my) and Tawau (www.spsb.com.my).</p>
<p>Limbongan Maju (tel: +60 7 827 8001;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.tanjungbelungkor.com" target="_blank">www.tanjungbelungkor.com</a>) operates a ferry between Tanjung Belungkor and Changi Point in Singapore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Keretapi Tanah Melayu Berhad (KTM Berhad) (tel: +60 3 2267 1200; <a href="http://www.ktmb.com.my" target="_blank">www.ktmb.com.my</a>) runs Malaysia's train services. From Kuala Lumpur, there are direct services south to Singapore and north to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangkok">Bangkok</a> in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/thailand">Thailand</a>, via Butterworth (the main train station for Penang).</p>
<p>To traverse the peninsula in style, ride the luxurious Eastern and Oriental Express (<a href="http://www.belmond.com/eastern-and-oriental-express" target="_blank">www.belmond.com/eastern-and-oriental-express</a>). The train completes the journey between Singapore, Kuala Lumpur and Bangkok in three or four days, with detours and tours along the way.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>KTM Rail Pass:</strong> Available to foreign tourists (except Singaporeans) and valid for five, 10 or 15 days. Passes permit unlimited travel on Intercity train services on the KTM network and into Singapore. Supplements apply for sleeping berths and on night trains. You can buy passes online (www.ktmb.com.my), through travel agencies and at major railway stations, including the stations in Kuala Lumpur, Butterworth, Johor Bahru and Singapore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malaysia is one of the few places in South-East Asia where visitors are happy to drive. Roads are well maintained, routes are clearly signposted, and for the most part, local drivers follow traffic rules. Road tolls are levied on all highways but smaller roads are toll-free.</p>
<p>Note that unsurfaced roads are common on Borneo and in the highlands of peninsular Malaysia. These require a 4-wheel drive, and can be impassable to any vehicle during the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International calls can be made from public telephones or at any office of Malaysia Telekom Berhad, the national phone company (<a href="http://www.tm.com.my" target="_blank">www.tm.com.my</a>). Public phones can be found in many areas, such as supermarkets, shopping centres and post offices, and most use coins or pre-paid cards, which can be purchased at petrol stations and convenience stores</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with many international mobile phone companies and network coverage is good in most areas of Peninsular Malaysia, and in larger cities in East Malaysia. Signals are less reliable in the highlands and vanish entirely in rural areas of Borneo. Malaysia has GSM 900/1800 and 3G mobile networks, and pre-paid SIM cards can be purchased locally for unlocked mobile phones. If your phone is locked to a network, cheap handsets are widely available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet caf&eacute;s are found everywhere and most chain coffee shops and shopping centres offer Wi-Fi connections. Larger hotels offer in-room internet access and Wi-Fi  access in the lobby.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government strives hard to shield the Malaysian population from foreign influences that are deemed harmful, and to maintain the perception of national unity. There are strict laws on censorship, and most newspapers self-censor to avoid falling foul of the authorities. Private radio stations broadcast in Malay, Tamil, Chinese and English, but all are circumspect in their political coverage. The censorship laws extend to music and films, and many recordings from outside Malaysia are banned.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are post offices in the commercial centre of all towns.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Batu Caves</p><![CDATA[<p>Just 13km north of Kuala Lumpur, the remarkable Batu Caves are a series of dramatic limestone caverns, dripping with stalactites, revered as a Hindu shrine. Every year in January or February, millions of devotees parade through the chambers and perform ritual acts of self-mortification for the spectacular Thaipusam festival.</p>]]><br/><p>Petronas Twin Towers</p><![CDATA[<p>Looming over downtown Kuala Lumpur like twin rocket ships, the iconic Petronas Towers were the world's tallest buildings from 1998 to 2004. Soaring to 436m (1,453ft), the towers are linked by a glass walkway with a viewing deck on the 41st floor. At the base of the towers is the Kuala Lumpur Convention Centre and the swish Suria KLCC mall.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Chill out on the Perhentian Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The twin islands of Perhentian Besar and Perhentian Kecil, together known as Pulau Perhentian, are among the country's most beautiful islands. Despite spectacular diving on teeming coral reefs, pristine white beaches, crystal clear waters, the islands are still relatively unexploited, with a laid-back, backpacker vibe.</p>]]><p><b>Climb the Petronas Towers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Looming over downtown Kuala Lumpur like twin rocket ships, the iconic Petronas Towers were the world's tallest buildings from 1998 to 2004. Soaring to 436m (1,453ft), the towers are linked by a glass walkway with a viewing deck on the 41st floor. At the base of the towers is the Kuala Lumpur Convention Centre and the swish Suria KLCC mall.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Penang's temples and beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The third great colonial city of Malaysia after Kuala Lumpur and Malacca, Penang is famous for its fantastic food, terrific temples and sun-kissed beaches. Historic George Town, the island's capital, is dotted with atmospheric Chinese temples, but perhaps the grandest temple is Kek Lok Si, whose Buddhist pagoda rises above the rooftops.</p>]]><p><b>Dive Malaysia’s coral reefs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Malaysia is a world famous destination for scuba diving, with reefs and sunken islands that attract plenty of megafauna, including schooling hammerheads and rare whale sharks. There are dive sites all over the country, but the finest lie around the islands of Sipadan and Layang Layang, offshore from Sabah in East Malaysia.</p>]]><p><b>Ease into the rainforest in Taman Negara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Malaysia is covered in pristine jungles, but Taman Negara National Park offers the chance to get deep into the rainforest without having to cut a path through the lianas. Marked trails and boardwalks snake between the trees, offering the chance to spot monkeys, snakes, deer and tapir. Expert guides can be hired from the Wildlife Department at Kuala Tahan.</p>]]><p><b>Eat the streets in Kuala Lumpur</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The melting pot of Malaysia comes to life on the streets of Kuala Lumpur, where whole districts are given over to Chinese, Indian and Malay food. The street food here is simply spectacular, and a reason to travel to Malaysia all by itself. At the other end of the spectrum, the city's restaurants are some of the best in Asia.</p>]]><p><b>Escape to the cool Cameron Highlands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>To escape the heat of the lowlands, the British colonials retreated to the hills north of Kuala Lumpur founding tea plantation and hill resorts in the cool Cameron Highlands. Today, this is Malaysia's best-known hill station, with trekking and tea tasting as the main attractions.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Malay culture and customs in Kota Bharu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bordering Thailand on the east coast of Malaysia, Kota Bharu is alive with the culture and customs of the Malay Peninsula. The town is famous for its traditional kites and shadow puppets and eating at the Kota Bharu night market, one of Malaysia's great feasts. Festivals abound, including the Kite Festival in June and Puja Umur (the Sultan's birthday) in March/April.</p>]]><p><b>Feel a different pace of life in Kuching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The capital of Sarawak is a bustling metropolis by the standards of the tribal villages inland, but a sleepy backwater compared to the cities of Peninsular Malaysia. Highlights include temples and mosques, quirky museums, amazing crafts and cultural traditions, colonial relics and animated markets.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the sense of history in Malacca</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The best place to re-live Malaysia's colonial past is its oldest city, Malacca, the one-time capital of Malay sultans and Portuguese, Dutch and British seafarers. A couple of hours south of Kuala Lumpur on the west coast, the city is famous for its Portuguese and Dutch colonial architecture, and its fascinating hybrid cuisine, which fuses Indian, Chinese and Malay influences.</p>]]><p><b>Join pilgrims in the Batu Caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Just 13km (8 miles) north of Kuala Lumpur, the remarkable Batu Caves are a series of dramatic limestone caverns, dripping with stalactites, revered as a Hindu shrine. Every year in January or February, millions of devotees parade through the chambers and perform ritual acts of self-mortification for the spectacular Thaipusam festival.</p>]]><p><b>Paddle up the Batang Rejang</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The mighty Batang Rejang river is the gateway to Borneo's tribal heartland. Visitors who come here in May and early June can visit the longhouse homes of the Iban tribe, which shelter generations of the same family, recalling traditions that date back thousands of years. The best places to arrange a local guide are the jungle outposts of Kapit and Belaga.</p>]]><p><b>Roam the rainforest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Despite expanding deforestation, large areas of Malaysia are still covered in stunning rainforests. You don't have to go far in Malaysia to find a patch of jungle; Templar Park, just 22km (14 miles) north of Kuala Lumpur, is a well-preserved tract of primary rainforest, criss-crossed by jungle paths and dotted with swimming lagoons and waterfalls.</p>]]><p><b>Say hello to an orang-utan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Offering the rare chance to see wild orang-utans in their natural habitat, the Sepilok Orangutan Rehabilitation Centre in Sandakan, Borneo, exists to rehabilitate orang-utans rescued from hunters and loggers. In fact, it has the world's largest population of these 'wild men of Borneo', numbering some 80 individuals.</p>]]><p><b>See Malaysia’s magnificent mosques</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Malaysia is studded with magnificent mosques, from the historic Jamek Masjid in Kuala Lumpur, to the grand blue expanse of the Masjid Negara. Malaysia's mosques come in all shapes and sizes; there are mosques covered in glass (Kuala Terengganu), mosques made from pink granite (Putrajaya), mosques made from timber (Malacca) and mosques floating on water (all over the country).</p>]]><p><b>Stay in a Malaysian longhouse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A stay in a longhouse, the traditional tribal communal houses of Malaysian Borneo, is one of the definitive Malaysian experiences. These expansive wooden homes are really entire villages housed under one single roof, and visits and even overnight stays are possible in the company of a local guide. Longhouses are found along many of the rivers of Sarawak and Sabah.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll the sands on Langkawi Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Malaysia's premier resort island, Langkawi boasts white sand beaches, fringing coral reefs, swaying palms and superior shopping, thanks to the island's duty free status. In fact, there are 99 islands in the archipelago, ringed by spectacular beaches. Ferries and flights come here daily from the mainland and you can continue by boat to Satun in southern Thailand.</p>]]><p><b>Summit Mount Kinabulu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Climbing Southeast Asia's highest peak is one of the highlights of a trip to East Malaysia. Located in Kinabalu National Park, the soaring granite dome of Mount Kinabulu reaches 4,094m (13,432ft), and the summit offers epic views over the island. Most people start the trek before dawn to catch sunrise at the summit, but you'll need a guide and permit.</p>]]><p><b>Uncover centuries of history in Kuala Lumpur</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A fascinating colonial history and rich cultural diversity make Kuala Lumpur one of Asia's most invigorating capitals. The old centre is dotted with grand colonial architecture and relics of the British colonial administration, and around the city are fascinating enclaves of Indian, Chinese and Malay culture, interspersed with space-age skyscrapers and shopping malls.</p>]]><p><b>Walk in the canopy at the Forest Research Institute of Malaysia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Just a short train ride from central Kuala Lumpur, this scientific research centre offers peaceful walking trails, jungle swimming holes and a 200m-long (656ft) rainforest boardwalk, suspended high in the canopy. It's a fine retreat from the hubbub of the city, and the Zoo Negara and Batu Caves are close by.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$296.3 billion (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Electrical equipment, petroleum, liquefied natural gas, chemicals and palm oil.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Electronics, machinery, petroleum products, plastics and vehicles.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Japan, Singapore, China and Hong Kong.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A fully-fledged 'tiger' economy, from the 1970s onwards Malaysia's GDP grew rapidly at around 10% annually. However, in 1997 the Asian financial crisis brought this process to a shuddering halt. Malaysia has recovered reasonably well since then, although the headlong pre-1997 expansion has been replaced by a more measured pace of growth of around 4 to 5.5% each year, reaching 6.3% in 2007. Inflation was around 3% in 2007.<br />
<br />
Healthy foreign exchange reserves, low inflation and a small external debt are all strengths that make it unlikely that a financial crisis similar to 1997 will re-occur. The Ringgit/US Dollar peg was abolished in July 2005. This has not resulted in any major change to the exchange rate. <br />
<br />
Malaysia is a member of the Pacific Rim organisation APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Forum), which is assuming an increasingly important role in the regional economy.<br />
<br />
Malaysia has rocketed up the international conventions league table; Tthe primary venue is the Kuala Lumpur Convention Centre, a large and very modern facility in the heart of the KLCC district (website: <a href="http://www.klccconventioncentre.com/" target="_blank">www.klccconventioncentre.com</a>). Many hotels around the country also offer event facilities. Further information can be obtained from Tourism Malaysia, Convention Promotion Division (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best time to conduct business is the dry season, but the dry months vary as you move around the country &ndash; see the climate section for details. During the monsoon months, flooding can cause delays even in central Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>Suits are the preferred attire for business meetings, but a shirt and trousers is acceptable for less formal occasions. Female businesspeople should dress modestly, in long sleeves and a skirt that finishes below the knees. Business visitors should remember that the Malay population is predominantly Muslim and religious customs should be respected. Avoid criticising Malaysia in conversation &ndash; national identity is also taken very seriously.</p>
<p>Appointments should be made for meetings &ndash; punctuality is expected so call ahead if you are likely to be delayed. Personal relationships are important and it may take several meetings to secure a deal. Handshakes are a common greeting, and women may shake hands with other women but men should never shake hands with women. It is customary to exchange business cards, but always present your business card with both hands. If possible, have your cards printed in English and Chinese characters.</p>
<p>Gifts are rarely exchanged in a business situation, but you may bring a gift if you are invited to a family home. Avoid alcohol, pork or beef products and images of dogs or pigs for religious reasons. Confectionary or flowers are usually best, as Hindus, Muslims and Chinese Buddhists each have their own taboos. Never wrap gifts in white paper, as this is associated with death. It is not appropriate for a man to give a gift to a woman he does not know. Always give gifts with the right hand.  When eating, always pass things with the right hand and do not let the serving spoon touch your plate.</p>
<p>When paying in a restaurant, hand over the money with your right hand. Never leave your chopsticks sticking upright in a bowl of rice as this is similar to the offerings made for the dead.</p><p>Most private sector offices are open Monday to Friday 0900-1700 and Saturday 0900-1300, but many public sector offices operate a five-day week.</p>
<p>Government office hours: Mon-Fri, 0830-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Malaysian International Chamber of Commerce and Industry (MICCI)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (03) 6201 7708
					Website:http://www.micci.com/
					Address: ,PO Box 12921,Kuala Lumpur,50792]]><b>National Chamber of Commerce and Industry of Malaysia</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (03) 2141 9600
					Website:http://www.nccim.org.my/
					Address: 6th Floor,6A,Kuala Lumpur.,55100]]><b>Malaysian External Trade Development Corporation (MATRADE) in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7499 5255
					Website:http://www.matrade.gov.my/
					Address: London W1J 5HR,17 Curzon Street,UK,]]><b>Malaysian Industrial Development Authority (MIDA</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (03) 2267 3633
					Website:http://www.mida.gov.my/
					Address: Jalan Stesen Sentral 5,Block 4,Plaza Sentral,Kuala Lumpur,50470]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Malaysia is not just a melting pot it is a cooking pot, blending culinary influences from as far away as Europe, China and India. The national cuisine shares obvious similarities with Thai and Indonesian food, but Malaysian cooking has its own unique specialities, based on exotic spices, chilli, ginger, lemongrass, lime leaves, coconut milk and peanuts. Many dishes are extremely spicy, but rice is served with almost everything, and a cup of sweet <em>tehtarik</em> will help cool things down.</p><p>The Indian and Chinese communities have their own traditions, with lots of meaty curries and noodle soups. Be sure to sample <em>mamak</em> cuisine, imported to Malaysia by Tamil Muslims. Traditionally served at street stalls, mamak dishes can be sampled at <em>nasi kendar</em> (rice and curry) canteens across the country. Although Malaysia is predominantly Islamic, bars and restaurants in larger cities serve beer, wine and spirits.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Nasi lemak</strong>: Rice steamed with coconut milk, served with dried anchovies, sambal, peanuts and eggs, the national dish.<br />
<strong>Char KwayTeow</strong>: Thick rice noodles stir fried with soy sauce and meat or fish.<br />
<strong>Nasi goreng</strong>: Malay-style fried rice, a favourite at street stalls and night markets; it&rsquo;s a popular takeaway for long bus journeys.<br />
<strong>Roti canai</strong>: Fried flat bread with curry sauce, a delicious and cheap snack served everywhere.<br />
<strong>Tehtarik:</strong> &lsquo;Pulled&rsquo; tea, made with sweet condensed milk and poured between two jugs to aerate the mix.<br />
<strong>Rendang daging</strong>: Slow-cooked beef with lemongrass and coconut; often served at festivals.<br />
<strong>Rojak: </strong>A spicy fruit or vegetable salad, plus other ingredients such as fried tofu and <em>youtiao</em> (Chinese cruellers).<br />
<strong>Laksa: </strong>A hot and sour seafood soup with coconut milk.<br />
<strong>Nasi kandar: </strong>Mamak-style steamed rice with curries and vegetable side dishes.<br />
<strong>Aiskacang: </strong>A Malay desert of shaved ice, fruits, beans, sweetcorn, grass jelly, condensed or evaporated milk and fruit syrups.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Chopsticks are customary in Chinese restaurants. Indian and Malay food is traditionally eaten with the fingers, but western cutlery is generally provided.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% service charge and 5% government tax are usually included in bills, and added to the menu prices.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>The minimum drinking age will be raised from 18 to 21 on 1 December 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Muslims in Malaysia are prohibited from drinking alcohol, but Chinese and Indian residents and foreign visitors are free to imbibe. Kuala Lumpur has the most dynamic nightlife in the country, with plenty of bars and nightclubs, particularly around Jalan Bukit Bintang, Asian Heritage Row, CapSquare, Starhill Gallery, Bangsar, Sri Hartamas and the Curve mall, in Mutiara Damansara. Nightclubs generally stay open until 0500 or 0600 from Wednesday to Sunday and most request a cover charge which includes the price of the first drink. Look out for two-for-one deals before 2000.</p>
<p>Away from the big cities, nightlife tends to be focused around night markets, where locals gather to eat, drink and talk to the early hours. Most night markets set up around 1600 each evening. Most large towns have cinemas showing Malay, Chinese and Indian films, often with English subtitles. You&rsquo;ll also find plenty of imported American blockbusters. The only permitted options for gambling are the national lottery and Malaysia's only casino at Genting Highlands (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.rwgenting.com">www.rwgenting.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malaysia is a world-class shopping destination, with futuristic malls, unique cultural stores and bustling street markets. Bargaining is expected in the markets, but shops and department stores charge fixed prices, and offer bargain prices during the annual sales from July to September and November to January.</p>
<p>Kuala Lumpur is the most popular shopping destination, rivalling Singapore and Hong Kong for fashions and electronic goods. At the base of the Petronas Towers, Suria KLCC, houses a great selection of leading international brands. Sleek Starhill Gallery and Lot 10 have more glamorous brands, while Berjaya Times Square has its own amusement park, with rollercoasters looping past the stores. The Jalan Petaling street market in Chinatown is good for inexpensive souvenirs, and quality handicrafts can be found in the eye-catching Central Market.</p>
<p>Electronic goods, cosmetics and perfumes are available duty-free throughout Malaysia, and distinctive Malaysian souvenirs include Royal Selangor pewter, batiks, wood-carvings, jewellery, handmade kris knives and songket brocade cloth. The islands of Labuan and Langkawi are duty-free zones. Enquire at the Royal Malaysian Customs Department (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.customs.gov.my">www.customs.gov.my</a>) about claiming cashback on duty-free goods.</p><p>Hours vary, but larger shops, malls and department stores open 1000-2200 daily.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Malaysia range from inexpensive roadhouses to five-star hotels with cutting edge amenities. Facilities vary from the very basic (just a box room with a bed) to the truly luxurious: flat-screen TVs, in-room business facilities, and even private spa pools. Malaysia also has a number of atmospheric heritage hotels in historic mansions and colonial villas.</p>
<p>There is a tourism tax on hotel stays of 10 RM per night. Guests need to pay the tourism tax themselves at the hotels.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Kuala Lumpur has no shortage of hotel beds, but in smaller towns and at popular resorts, it is wise to book in advance, particularly during school and public holidays. Note that prices at the coastal resorts peak during the dry season &ndash; for bargain rates, travel during the monsoon months. A new official grading system was introduced in 2007, in which hotels are awarded 1-5 stars or an orchid rating for more modest establishments.</p>
<p><strong>Resorts:</strong> Malaysia boasts some of the finest beach resorts in Asia, with on-site spas and pools and restaurants spilling right onto the sand. Most offer activities, including scuba-diving and other watersports. There are also plenty of moderately-priced resorts catering to local and international tourists, as well as budget resorts in the main backpacker hangouts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Malaysia range from inexpensive roadhouses to five-star hotels with cutting edge amenities. Facilities vary from the very basic (just a box room with a bed) to the truly luxurious: flat-screen TVs, in-room business facilities, and even private spa pools. Malaysia also has a number of atmospheric heritage hotels in historic mansions and colonial villas.</p>
<p>There is a tourism tax on hotel stays of 10 RM per night. Guests need to pay the tourism tax themselves at the hotels.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Kuala Lumpur has no shortage of hotel beds, but in smaller towns and at popular resorts, it is wise to book in advance, particularly during school and public holidays. Note that prices at the coastal resorts peak during the dry season &ndash; for bargain rates, travel during the monsoon months. A new official grading system was introduced in 2007, in which hotels are awarded 1-5 stars or an orchid rating for more modest establishments.</p>
<p><strong>Resorts:</strong> Malaysia boasts some of the finest beach resorts in Asia, with on-site spas and pools and restaurants spilling right onto the sand. Most offer activities, including scuba-diving and other watersports. There are also plenty of moderately-priced resorts catering to local and international tourists, as well as budget resorts in the main backpacker hangouts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Malaysia range from inexpensive roadhouses to five-star hotels with cutting edge amenities. Facilities vary from the very basic (just a box room with a bed) to the truly luxurious: flat-screen TVs, in-room business facilities, and even private spa pools. Malaysia also has a number of atmospheric heritage hotels in historic mansions and colonial villas.</p>
<p>There is a tourism tax on hotel stays of 10 RM per night. Guests need to pay the tourism tax themselves at the hotels.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Kuala Lumpur has no shortage of hotel beds, but in smaller towns and at popular resorts, it is wise to book in advance, particularly during school and public holidays. Note that prices at the coastal resorts peak during the dry season &ndash; for bargain rates, travel during the monsoon months. A new official grading system was introduced in 2007, in which hotels are awarded 1-5 stars or an orchid rating for more modest establishments.</p>
<p><strong>Resorts:</strong> Malaysia boasts some of the finest beach resorts in Asia, with on-site spas and pools and restaurants spilling right onto the sand. Most offer activities, including scuba-diving and other watersports. There are also plenty of moderately-priced resorts catering to local and international tourists, as well as budget resorts in the main backpacker hangouts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes***]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes **]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is recommended. Government and private hospitals are found in all the main cities and can deal with major medical needs, but all charge for treatments. Standards are generally higher at private hospitals &amp;ndash; the Association of Private Hospitals of Malaysia (&lt;a href="http://www.hospitals-malaysia.org" target="_blank"&gt;www.hospitals-malaysia.org&lt;/a&gt;) has a list of member hospitals. In an emergency, dial 999.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food is one of the highlights of any trip to Malaysia, but a little caution is required as standards of hygiene can vary. Restaurants are usually fine, and you should also be safe at street stalls and night markets where the food is prepared freshly on the premises. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish and avoid places where food has been left lying around in the open air. Avoid ice cream and other unpasteurised dairy products as they may have been defrosted and refrozen.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Tap water in larger cities is usually safe, but most people prefer to drink bottled water. Elsewhere, all water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated – stick to water that has been boiled or sterilised. Be wary of ice as it may have been prepared using contaminated water. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled – milk used in tea has normally been boiled or treated.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Malaria and Hepatitis A and C are present in Malaysia and Hepatitis B is also widespread, though the risk to travellers is low. Outbreaks of dengue fever, Japanese encephalitis and meningococcal meningitis occur in both urban and rural areas, but are rare in Kuala Lumpur, Penang and coastal resorts. Rabies is present; if bitten by monkeys or dogs, seek immediate medical attention. There have been several outbreaks of avian influenza since 2004 but no human fatalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zika virus in endemic in Malaysia. The mosquito-borne illness can be spread from a pregnant woman to her unborn baby as well as through sexual contact. Travellers to Malaysia should protect themselves from mosquito bites and wear clothes (preferably light-coloured) that cover as much of the body as possible, sleeping under mosquito nets and using repellents that contain DEET (diethyltoluamide), IR 3535 ((3- [N-butyl-N-acetyl], aminopropionic acid ethyl-ester) or KBR3023 (also called Icaridin or Picaridin). Pregnant women are advised to postpone non-essential travel until after pregnancy and pregnant women whose sexual partners live in or travel to areas with Zika virus transmission should follow safe sexual practices or abstain from sex for the duration of their pregnancy.&amp;nbsp;Women who are pregnant, at risk of getting pregnant, or planning pregnancy should seek further advice from their doctor before travelling to Malaysia.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following day.<br /><br />(a) Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Hari Raya Puasa (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Hari Raya Puasa itself. Hari Raya Puasa and Hari Raya Qurban (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.<br /><br />(b) Buddhist festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Federal Territory Day :
							01 February </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>King's Birthday :
							02 June </p><p>Merdeka Day (National Day) :
							31 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>New Year's Day :
							2019<br/>01 January </p><p>Federal Territory Day :
							01 February </p><p>Chinese New Year :
							05 February </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Malaysia without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 225g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; Food up to the value of RM75.<br />
&bull; 3 pieces of new clothing and 1 new pair of shoes.<br />
&bull; 1 portable electronic item for personal care.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of RM400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Illicit drugs, counterfeit currency, indecent publications (books, films, paintings etc), anything considered prejudicial to the interest of Malaysia, piranha fish, turtle eggs, cocoa pods, daggers or flick knives, articles resembling syringes (eg pens or pencils), and poisonous chemicals.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Also prohibited unless accompanied by an import licence are animals, fish, meat, plants, eggs in their shells, explosives and fireworks, arms and ammunition, imitation arms, soil, rice, coral and pharmaceutical products.</p>
<p>The penalty for drug trafficking is death by hanging.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Illicit drugs, turtle eggs and rattan from the Malaysian peninsula.</p>
<p>Also prohibited unless accompanied by an export licence are animals, birds, poultry, meat, cockles, plants, over 3kg of vegetables, palm kernels and seeds, military clothing and equipment, arms and ammunition, antiquities, sugar, rice, coral, live prawns/shrimp/fish, and collections of cultural value (eg of zoological or archaeological interest).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ringgit (MYR; symbol RM) = 100 sen. Notes are in denominations of RM100, 50, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 sen. The Ringgit is often referred to as the Malaysian Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best currency for exchange is the Pound Sterling, but US Dollars are also widely accepted. All commercial banks are authorised foreign exchange dealers; major hotels are only licensed to buy or accept foreign currency in the form of notes and traveller's cheques. It may be difficult to exchange foreign currencies outside the main tourist centres.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mastercard, Visa and American Express are widely accepted. Diners Club is accepted at larger department stores and shopping centres and some upmarket restaurants and hotels. Credit cards are less widely accepted in rural areas &ndash; carry cash or travellers cheques as a back up.</p><p>ATMs are found in all cities and most accept international cards from Visa, Mastercard and other major card issuers. Because of the high incidence of credit card fraud, banks may put an automatic block on your card unless you notify them first that you are travelling to Malaysia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted by all banks, hotels and large department stores. Most major brands of travellers cheques are accepted, but travellers are advised to carry cheques in Pounds Sterling, US Dollars or Australian Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0915-1630 (some branches close at 1600 on Friday and some open on Saturdays). Banks in Kelantan and Terengganu open Sun-Thurs 0915-1630 (till 1600 on Thursday).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Passports should be valid for at least six months after the date of arrival in Malaysia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign nationals continuing to the next destination on the same flight within 24 hours without leaving the airport do not require a visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: &pound;10; multiple-entry visa: &pound;20.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visas:&nbsp;three months from the date of issue; multiple-entry visas: three months to one year from the date of issue with a maximum stay of 30 days per visit. Multiple-entry visas are usually issued to business visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy or high commission).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are usually issued on the day you submit the application.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors requiring a visa need to show bank statements from the previous three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are usually only allowed to extend their stay in exceptional circumstances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[3.191992]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[114.215023]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>329,847 sq km (127,355 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>30,751,602 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>92.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kuala Lumpur.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malaysia is situated in central South-East Asia, bordering Thailand in the north, with Singapore to the south and Indonesia to the south and west. It is composed of Peninsular Malaysia and the states of Sabah and Sarawak on the north coast of the island of Borneo, 650 to 950km (404 to 600 miles) across the South China Sea. Peninsular Malaysia is an area of forested mountain ranges running north-south, on either side of which are low-lying coastal plains. The coastline extends some 1,900km (1,200 miles).</p>
<p>The west coast consists of mangrove swamps and mudflats which separate into bays and inlets. In the west, the plains have been cleared and cultivated, while the unsheltered east coast consists of tranquil beaches backed by dense jungle. The major islands are Langkawi (a group of 99 islands), Penang and Pangkor off the west coast; and Tioman, Redang, Kapas, Perhentian and Rawa off the east coast. In Malaysian Borneo, Sarawak has alluvial and, in places, swampy coastal plains with rivers penetrating the jungle-covered hills and mountains of the interior. Sabah has a narrow coastal plain which gives way to mountains and jungle. Mt Kinabalu, at 4,094m (13,432ft), is the highest peak in Malaysia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malaysia's official religion is Islam and 60% of the population are Muslim, but the country also has Hindu and Buddhist populations. Chinese Malaysians also follow Taoist and Confucianist traditions and tribal people in Borneo and other remote areas following traditional animist beliefs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Social conventions in Malaysia are dictated by religion and culture, with different norms amongst Muslim Malays, Indian Hindus and followers of Chinese religions. The catch-all greeting in Bahasa Melayu is <em>selamat</em>, but Malays are more likely to use the Arabic phrase <em>assalamualaikum</em>, meaning 'peace be with you'. The standard title for Malay men is <em>Encik</em> (pronounced Enchik), which can be used with or without the person&rsquo;s name; single Malay women should be called <em>Cik</em> (pronounced Che) and married women <em>Puan</em>.</p>
<p>Touching the hand to the chest is a sign of respect and a relaxed wrist and gentle touch should be adopted when shaking hands. Chinese and Indians usually use Western forms of address. Hospitality is always warm, lavish and informal. When eating food by hand, only the right hand should be used. Visitors should respect religious beliefs and follow the Malaysian example, particular when it comes to appropriate attire. Footwear should be taken off at the door when entering a house or temple. Outside the workplace, dress should be informal, but not overly casual.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Tun Mahathir bin Mohamad since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Muhammad V ibni Sultan Ismail Petra since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The tribal history of Malaysia dates back 40,000 years, but Hindu and Buddhist kingdoms spread out across the peninsula from the 3rd century BC onwards. Islam arrived with Indian and Arab traders in the 13th century and Malacca was established as the seat of the first Malay sultanate. Over the following centuries, Islamic dynasties spread their faith across the peninsula and surrounding islands.</p>
<p>The Dutch and Portuguese were the first colonial powers to establish trading posts in Malaysia, but the British took an increasingly dominant role from the 18th century onwards. In 1857, the port cities of Georgetown (Penang) and Malacca were joined by a new city, Kuala Lumpur, which sprouted out of the jungle-cloaked interior. Founded by Chinese tin miners, KL grew to become first a provincial capital, and later the capital of the nation.</p>
<p>Established in 1895, the Federated Malay States remained under British control until the Japanese invasion in WWII and occupied the region for three years. Having been re-conquered by the Allies, popular support for independence grew and the 11 states were reinvented under autonomous rulers as a British protectorate and rebranded as the Federation of Malaya. From 1948 to 1960, the country faced a violent communist uprising, known as the Emergency, which drove a wedge between the Malay and Chinese populations.</p>
<p>After a series of complicated negotiations, the federation merged with Singapore and the former British colonies of Sarawak and Sabah (formerly North Borneo), to form a new federal Malaysia, which came into existence on 16 September 1963. But with power concentrated amongst Muslim Malays, Chinese-dominated Singapore seceded to become an independent state in 1965, leaving Malaysia in its present form.</p>
<p>Since independence, Malaysia has grown into one of the powerhouse economies of Southeast Asia, despite a number of national crises, most significantly the Asian financial crisis of 1997. The political situation is still volatile, with internal power struggles between the main political parties, and unresolved tensions between Malay, Indian and Chinese citizens, but its economy is ranked third largest in the region.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Malaysia has never recognised Israel and will have no diplomatic ties with it until a peace agreement with the State of Palestine is signed.<br />
&bull;	Traditional Malay music is based around percussion instruments the most important of which is the gendang drum.<br />
&bull;	The state of Sabah is home to the rafflesia plant, which produces the largest flower in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Malaysia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+60 3 2170 2200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/malaysia</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+60 3 2170 2200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0800-1230 and 1315-1630. Fri 0800-1230.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>2 Jalan Binjai<br/>Level 27 Menara Binjai<br/>Kuala Lumpur<br/>50450<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Malaysia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 572 9700.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 572 9700.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>3516 International Court NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission of Malaysia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7235 8033.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.jimlondon.net</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7235 8033.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1200 (visa submissions) and 1500-1600 (visa collections).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>45-46 Belgrave Square<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8QT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With reefs and rainforests, mountains and minarets, skyscrapers and sampans, Malaysia certainly lives up to its slogan: &ldquo;truly Asia.&rdquo;&nbsp;One of the world&rsquo;s great cultural melting pots, Malaysia is a nation where Chinese joss houses, Hindu temples and gold-domed mosques jostle for space with towering skyscrapers. The British once presided over this fascinating sampling platter of Asian culture, leaving behind a legacy of hill stations, polo fields and high tea.</p>
<p>In fact, Malaysia offers two countries for the price of one; Peninsular Malaysia, bordering Thailand at the southern end of the Malay Peninsula; and East Malaysia, the northern half of the island of Borneo, nuzzling up against Indonesia and Brunei. This opens up some spectacular opportunities for nation-hopping across Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>Malaysia&rsquo;s supercharged capital, Kuala Lumpur, resembles a crystal garden that has grown miraculously in the jungle. Indeed, pockets of virgin rainforest still survive amongst the towering skyscrapers, multi-storey shopping malls and monorail tracks. If you do nothing else, devote a day to sampling KL&rsquo;s street food; from Chinese noodles and Indian dosas (rice pancakes) to aromatic and spicy Malay curries and seafood.</p>
<p>Away from the cities, untamed nature awaits, in the form of jungles dripping with rare and exotic species and coral reefs thronged by turtles, sharks and tropical fish. Malaysia&rsquo;s national parks and wildlife reserves are well-organised and well looked after, and you might be lucky enough to meet Malaysia&rsquo;s most charismatic resident, the orang-utan (literally, &ldquo;forest man&rdquo;).</p>
<p>Then there are the islands; tropical resorts such as Langkawi, Tioman and the Perhentian Islands have become almost legendary for fans of swaying palms, sparkling sand and scuba diving on pristine reefs. Malaysia&rsquo;s dive sites &ndash; particularly those reached on live-aboard safaris &ndash; rank amongst the best in the world.</p>
<p>Peninsular Malaysia is where people go for bustling cities and colonial history, but the states of Sabah and Sarawak on Borneo are the gateway to another world. Lush rainforests are inhabited by isolated indigenous tribes, whose traditional way of life is vanishing fast as the modern world encroaches; catch it now before they put up a parking lot.</p><p>&nbsp;With reefs and rainforests, mountains and minarets, skyscrapers and sampans, Malaysia certainly lives up to its slogan: &ldquo;truly Asia.&rdquo; One of the world&rsquo;s great cultural melting pots, Malaysia is a nation where Chinese joss houses, Hindu temples and gold-domed mosques jostle for space with towering skyscrapers. The British once presided over this fascinating sampling platter of Asian culture, leaving behind a legacy of hill stations, polo fields and high tea.</p>
<p>In fact, Malaysia offers two countries for the price of one; Peninsular Malaysia, bordering Thailand at the southern end of the Malay Peninsula; and East Malaysia, the northern half of the island of Borneo, nuzzling up against Indonesia and Brunei.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
