<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Maldives" ColCode="mdv" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mv" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Maldives]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Maldives has a year-round hot tropical climate. There are two monsoons, the southwest from May to October and the northeast from November to April. Generally the southwest brings more wind and rain in June and July. The temperature rarely falls below 25°C (77°F).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens throughout the year. Light waterproofs are advised during the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internal&nbsp;flights in the Maldives&nbsp;are operated by Maldivian (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.maldivian.aero">www.maldivian.aero</a>), linking Mal&eacute; with provincial centres Hanimaadhoo, Kaadedhdhoo, Kadhdhoo and Gan.</p>
<p>Trans Maldivian Airways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.transmaldivian.com">www.transmaldivian.com</a>) and Maldivian Air Taxi (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.maldivianairtaxi.com">www.maldivianairtaxi.com</a>) operate seaplane transfers from Mal&eacute; airport to individual resorts. These services are also available for charter trips around the islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors generally remain on their resort island for the duration of their stay, although island-hopping trips by dhoni charters are widely available. High-speed boats usually meet arrivals at the airport, supplied by the resort they are booked with, and boats are available for hire at the ferry counter near the jetty area. The speedboats connect the airport with North and South Mal&eacute; Atolls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are only roads in Mal&eacute; and a couple of other islands where there are small tarmaced strips. Overland transport on resort islands is by golf buggy.</p><p>In Mal&eacute;, it is possible to take taxis.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Maldivian (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.maldivian.aero">www.maldivian.aero</a>) is the national carrier. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) operates direct flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>.&nbsp;Flights year-round are fairly expensive, but they are especially high during Christmas and the winter months.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/maldives/male-international-airport">Malé Ibrahim Nasir International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 18 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Malé Ibrahim Nasir International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.macl.aero<p>Mal&eacute; Ibrahim Nasir International Airport is located on Hulhul&eacute; Island, about 2.5km (1.5 miles) northeast of Mal&eacute; in the Maldives.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>332 2211.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The easiest way to call home is via a computer or a mobile phone. To avoid roaming charges, people at home can call your room in your resort.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is decent throughout the islands, though as the country is so spead out, there are still some blindspots. It's possible to buy a local SIM card in Malé to make cheap local calls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Internet can be accessed from most areas of the Maldives. Mal&eacute;, the capital, has a lack of Internet caf&eacute;s, but Wi-Fi is available in many other caf&eacute;s. Almost all resorts have Internet connections via terminals for guest use or wireless, though these are rarely free.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since the democratic change in the Maldives in 2008, the press has become a far freer society with a more developed civil society and media. Open debate and discussion of the governments performance is now the norm after decades of compliant and uncritical media coverage. Most media is in Divehi only, though there are several online English-language newspapers. European and American newspapers are sometimes available in international editions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes about one week.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0730-1330 and 1600-1750.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Drop beneath the waves in a submarine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Divers and non-divers alike will love this alternative way to get underwater and see life under the waves. Docked a short distance from Malé, the comfortable windowed 'whale' submarine gives a unique perspective on the local coral reefs. It's particularly popular with children, though adults get just as excited.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Addu Atoll</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Beautiful Addu Atoll, the most southerly of the Maldives island groups, is definitely worth visiting for divers. Here, the coral is the best in the country, while a modern road linking Gan's Equator Village resort to the Maldives' second city of Hithadhoo is a great place for a bike ride.</p>]]><p><b>Go shopping for local produce</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many resorts offer day trips to islands where you can usually visit local artisans in their workshops and buy some of the beautiful local arts and crafts. Malé also has several markets of fresh and wholesome food produce for those wanting to sample local fare.</p>]]><p><b>Grab rod and reel for big game fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A fishing trip on a modern speedboat equipped for big game fishing is a great experience for any wannabe Hemingway. Head out during the day for tuna and sail fish, or go at night to catch grouper, snapper, squirrelfish or barracuda. Round off the trip by barbecuing the day's catch.</p>]]><p><b>Learn how to windsurf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For a taste of some of the Maldives' more challenging activities, try your hand at windsurfing at Lhohifushi and Dhonveli in the North Malé Atoll. These two relatively reasonably-priced island resorts are where the country's most famous breaks can be found. The season for surf lasts from March-October.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Malé’s fish market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The whole of Malé is a hive of economic activity – everybody seems to be buying or selling something, but this is nowhere more the case than at the busy fish market on the waterfront, where produce fresh from the sea is gutted and sold right before your eyes.</p>]]><p><b>Mix with the locals in Malé</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The tiny, crowded capital of the Maldives is a fantastic place for a visit as it gives you the chance to see real life away from the resorts and meet Maldivians on an equal footing. Don't miss the beautiful 17th-century coral stone <em>Hukuru </em>(Friday Mosque) or the interesting exhibits, including the Sultan's thrones and palanquins, in Malé's National Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Spend the night on an uninhabited island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A day and a night spent alone on an uninhabited island is quite the experience, and you can usually do so as part of an island-hopping tour. Another option is to combine a visit to a fishing village with a trip to an uninhabited island, where the day is often rounded off with a beach barbecue as the sun sets.</p>]]><p><b>Take the ferry to Hulhumalé</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ferry trip from Malé to the nearby manmade island of Hulhumalé, is a look to the future. A utopian town, Hulhumalé is set to become the new hub of the Maldives in decades to come as sea levels rise. At 2m above sea level, it is mountainous by local standards.</p>]]><p><b>Treat yourself to a spa treatment</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For an enormous range of treatments, including massages, relaxation therapies and other pamperings, make an appointment at your resort's spa – now a feature at almost every resort on the islands. For an extra special treat book a double massage for you and your partner.</p>]]><p><b>Volunteer as a conservationist</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many of the better resorts now have a dedicated team of scientists taking care of the local marine life. They will usually have volunteer programs allowing guests to get involved even for a short amount of time. Typical activities include seeding coral reefs, and looking after juvenile sharks, turtles and rare fish in captivity.</p>]]><p><b>Watch the sun sink on a boat cruise</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A sunset boat cruise aboard a <em>dhoni</em>, the wooden boat that is the Maldives' standard mode of transport, is a blissful way to end the day. You'll cruise around uninhabited islands, where you'll be served drinks and snacks while local musicians play their traditional <em>bodu beru</em> drums to attract dolphins.</p>]]><p><b>While away the day in Vilingili</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If Malé's crowded streets leave you searching for relaxation and the quieter side of the Maldives, make the short ferry journey to the tranquil neighbouring island of Vilingili. Join locals at the beach, watch cricket matches in the park, and picnic under the multitude of gently-waving palm trees.</p>]]><p><b>Witness life under the waves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>To appreciate the abundant underwater life, go diving or snorkelling. Some of the world's best sites are found in the Maldives and all resorts have professional, fully-equipped dive schools. A dive that shouldn't be missed is at Mushimasmingili Thila, where you'll see grey reef sharks, giant snappers and tropical reef fish in a pristine section of Ari Atoll.</p>]]><p><b>Wrek dive the Maldives Victory</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An unforgettable underwater experience for divers is the wreck of the merchant ship <em>Maldives Victory</em>, which lies 35m (115 ft) below the waves near Hulhule. Sinking in 1981, the ship has become an artificial reef, with coral, sponges and fish all making it their home.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$1.37 billion (2009).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fish.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum products, ships, food, clothing, intermediate and capital goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>India, China, Japan, Malaysia and Singapore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourism, the Maldives' largest industry, accounts for 28% of GDP, and over 90% of government tax revenue comes from import duties and tourism-related taxes. Fishing is the second leading sector. Agriculture and manufacturing play almost no role in the economy, constrained by limited cultivable land and the shortage of domestic labour. Most staple foods must be imported. Industry, which consists mainly of garment production, boat building and handicrafts, accounts for about 7% of GDP.<br /><br />The December 2004 tsunami left more than 100 dead, 12,000 displaced, and property damage exceeding US$300 million, though recovery has been steady and didn't affect the tourism industry particularly adversely by the standards of other tsunami-afflicted countries.<br /><br />Diversifying beyond tourism and fishing is the major challenge facing the government. The new government is seeking to diversify the tourism market by introducing hotels on inhabited islands and creating a national transport network - both two things that in the past have kept independent travellers away. There is also a plan to make Maldives the world's first carbon-neutral country by 2012.<br /><strong>State Trading Organisation</strong><br />Boduthakurufaanu Magu, Maafannu, Malé, 20345, Republic of Maldives<br />Tel: 334 4333.<br />Website: <a href="http://www.stomaldives.com/" target="_blank">www.stomaldives.com</a><br /><br /><strong>Universal Resorts</strong> (Information on Conferences/Conventions)<br />Universal Enterprises Ltd, 39 Orchid Magu, Malé, Republic of Maldives <br />Tel: 332 3080 <em>or</em> 333 2262/70/71.<br />Website: <a href="http://www.universalresorts.com/" target="_blank">www.universalresorts.com</a></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since the islands import almost everything, business potential is high, but only in Malé. Most business takes place during the morning. An informal attitude prevails. Appointments should be made well in advance. For business meetings, men normally wear a short-sleeved shirt and tie with formal but lightweight trousers. Women wear a lightweight suit or equivalent. Handshaking is the customary form of greeting. Business cards are expected.</p><p>Sun-Thurs 0730-1430. Friday and Saturday are official rest days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Maldivian food can at first appear a fairly limited affair. The country's small size and tropical oceanic location ensures fish and fruit, normally the coconut, are central ingredients to many dishes. Most meals will consist of fish, usually combined in some way with rice and coconut.</p><p>The islands are heavily influenced in palate by the Indian subcontinent, specifically Kerala in southern India and Sri Lanka, but with its own distinct richness of flavour. The use of peppers, chillies and curry leaves to make curries therefore abounds, and flavours are generally very hot and spicy.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Banbukeylu harisa:</strong> Curry of steamed breadfruit, chilli, onion and coconut.<br />
<strong>Bis keemiyaa: </strong>Pastry filled with tuna and hardboiled egg.<br />
<strong>Hedhikaa:</strong> Traditional snacks, or &lsquo;short eats&rsquo;, such as samosas, sold by small caf&eacute;s.<br />
<strong>Garudiya:</strong> Fish broth prepared using chillies, onion and lemon juice.<br />
<strong>Rihaakuru:</strong> Brown paste made from concentrating down fish stock.<br />
<strong>Mashuni:</strong> Mashed tuna mixed with coconut, chilli and onion and served for breakfast with roshi.<br />
<strong>Roshi:</strong> Flatbread.<br />
<strong>Thelui mas:</strong> Spicy fried fish such as grouper, swordfish, jobfish or octopus.<br />
<strong>Kavaabu:</strong> Deep-fried snacks made from rice, tuna, coconut, lentils and spices.<br />
<strong>Dhon riha:</strong> Tuna curry with coconut, mango, cinnamon and ginger.<br />
<strong>Dhonkeyo kajuru:</strong> Fried banana cake flavoured with rose water or vanilla.<br />
<strong>Sai:</strong> Tea; a Maldivian favourite.<br />
<strong>Raa:</strong> Toddy tapped from palm trees, sometimes left to ferment and thus slightly alcoholic - the closest any Maldivian gets to alcohol.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Locals do not drink alcohol, which is generally only sold in tourist resorts.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In international style restaurants in Malé 10-15% is standard. In local cafés it is not expected. In resorts, a service charge of 10-15% is usually automatically included in meals and for drinks.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Officially none since alcohol is prohibited outside resorts. In the resorts a discretionary drinking age of 18 is generally applied.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is little or no nightlife in the Maldives, and this is definitely not a destination for party animals. That said, most resorts have bars, the occassional live music act and a few larger ones even have small nightclubs. Beach parties and barbecues are also popular. Some resorts have occasional film showings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lacquered wooden boxes are the most distinctive Maldivian handicrafts, and are most famously produced in Thulhaadhoo in Baa Atoll. The craft involves the process of shaping and hollowing out pieces of wood from endemic trees to form intricately crafted boxes, containers and ornamental objects. Beautiful reed mats are woven throughout the country, the most famous of which are those that are woven by the women of Gadhdhoo in Gaafu Dhaalu Atoll. Ranging from placemats to full-size single mattress mats, they are hand-decorated with intricate abstract designs.<br />
<br />
In Mal&eacute;, most souvenir shops line the northern end of Chaandanee Magu, earlier known as the Singapore Bazaar for its many imports from Singapore. The local market offers stalls with a variety of local produce, mainly from the atolls, such as different kinds of local vegetables, fruits and yams, packets of sweetmeat, nuts and breadfruit chips, bottles of homemade sweets and pickles, and bunches of bananas hanging on coir ropes from ceiling beams.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0830-2000, Fri 1330-2000. Shops officially shut for 15 minutes five times a day in deference to Muslim prayer times; however, this rule is not always strictly adhered to in the tourist areas away from the capital.</p><p>There are strict prohibitions against the export of coral and turtle- or tortoiseshell.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[There are numerous resorts in the Maldives, which vary from extravagantly luxurious to fairly simple. Accommodation in the Maldives almost invariably consists of thatch-roofed coral cabanas with en suite facilities. Most of the resorts have air-conditioned rooms with mini-bar, although some of the resorts still have fan-cooled rooms. Many resort groups have recently installed desalination plants to provide clean tap water.<br /><br />The resorts are fully integral communities with sport and leisure facilities including scuba-diving and snorkelling, restaurants and bars and, in some cases, a shop and/or disco. There is a shop on every resort island. Different islands tend to attract different nationalities.

Resorts specifically geared towards divers are very common in the Maldives, as it's one of the country's biggest attractions. The best diving resorts are a long way from other resorts, meaning that it's rare to encounter dive groups from other islands. Dive resorts always cater to non-divers too, and each one has a good beach as well as other activities such as water sports or a spa. <br /><p>Hotels in the Maldives are world class, with an unmatched range of top end luxury resorts, as well as plenty of mid-range accommodations and a smattering of cheaper (yet still not budget) diving resorts.</p>
<p>Mal&eacute; is the only place you&rsquo;ll find hotels rather than resorts. All are midrange and fairly mediocre. Business travellers used to world class hotels usually stay in one of the several resort islands near to Mal&eacute;.</p>
<p>There are no guest houses or hotels on any of the inhabited islands, although the government have announced plans to build a network of guesthouses on inhabited islands to attract independent travellers.</p><br />Contrary to popular belief, there is a cheap end to the Maldives' accommodation market, though it's still relatively pricey compared to those in most Asian countries. Budget resorts in the Maldives tend to be favoured by divers and families, and many are much larger in size than the average, although there are plenty of laid back, quiet resorts in this category too.]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[There are numerous resorts in the Maldives, which vary from extravagantly luxurious to fairly simple. Accommodation in the Maldives almost invariably consists of thatch-roofed coral cabanas with en suite facilities. Most of the resorts have air-conditioned rooms with mini-bar, although some of the resorts still have fan-cooled rooms. Many resort groups have recently installed desalination plants to provide clean tap water.<br /><br />The resorts are fully integral communities with sport and leisure facilities including scuba-diving and snorkelling, restaurants and bars and, in some cases, a shop and/or disco. There is a shop on every resort island. Different islands tend to attract different nationalities.

Resorts specifically geared towards divers are very common in the Maldives, as it's one of the country's biggest attractions. The best diving resorts are a long way from other resorts, meaning that it's rare to encounter dive groups from other islands. Dive resorts always cater to non-divers too, and each one has a good beach as well as other activities such as water sports or a spa. <br /><p>Hotels in the Maldives are world class, with an unmatched range of top end luxury resorts, as well as plenty of mid-range accommodations and a smattering of cheaper (yet still not budget) diving resorts.</p>
<p>Mal&eacute; is the only place you&rsquo;ll find hotels rather than resorts. All are midrange and fairly mediocre. Business travellers used to world class hotels usually stay in one of the several resort islands near to Mal&eacute;.</p>
<p>There are no guest houses or hotels on any of the inhabited islands, although the government have announced plans to build a network of guesthouses on inhabited islands to attract independent travellers.</p><br />Contrary to popular belief, there is a cheap end to the Maldives' accommodation market, though it's still relatively pricey compared to those in most Asian countries. Budget resorts in the Maldives tend to be favoured by divers and families, and many are much larger in size than the average, although there are plenty of laid back, quiet resorts in this category too.]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[There are numerous resorts in the Maldives, which vary from extravagantly luxurious to fairly simple. Accommodation in the Maldives almost invariably consists of thatch-roofed coral cabanas with en suite facilities. Most of the resorts have air-conditioned rooms with mini-bar, although some of the resorts still have fan-cooled rooms. Many resort groups have recently installed desalination plants to provide clean tap water.<br /><br />The resorts are fully integral communities with sport and leisure facilities including scuba-diving and snorkelling, restaurants and bars and, in some cases, a shop and/or disco. There is a shop on every resort island. Different islands tend to attract different nationalities.

Resorts specifically geared towards divers are very common in the Maldives, as it's one of the country's biggest attractions. The best diving resorts are a long way from other resorts, meaning that it's rare to encounter dive groups from other islands. Dive resorts always cater to non-divers too, and each one has a good beach as well as other activities such as water sports or a spa. <br /><p>Hotels in the Maldives are world class, with an unmatched range of top end luxury resorts, as well as plenty of mid-range accommodations and a smattering of cheaper (yet still not budget) diving resorts.</p>
<p>Mal&eacute; is the only place you&rsquo;ll find hotels rather than resorts. All are midrange and fairly mediocre. Business travellers used to world class hotels usually stay in one of the several resort islands near to Mal&eacute;.</p>
<p>There are no guest houses or hotels on any of the inhabited islands, although the government have announced plans to build a network of guesthouses on inhabited islands to attract independent travellers.</p><br />Contrary to popular belief, there is a cheap end to the Maldives' accommodation market, though it's still relatively pricey compared to those in most Asian countries. Budget resorts in the Maldives tend to be favoured by divers and families, and many are much larger in size than the average, although there are plenty of laid back, quiet resorts in this category too.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are two hospitals on Malé, the Indhira Gandhi Memorial Hospital and the ADK private hospital. First-aid facilities are available on all resort islands. A decompression chamber is accessible in Malé in case of diving emergencies. Medical treatment in the Maldives can be very expensive and comprehensive health insurance is recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;The water provided in the resort areas is generally safe to drink. In other areas, water of uncertain origin used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Food in hotels and resorts is usually risk free, although visitors should be cautious elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last anything up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Independence Day :
							26 July </p><p>Victory Day :
							03 November </p><p>Republic Day :
							11 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into the Maldives over 16 years old without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 25 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of MRf6,000.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s important to note that while you can drink alcohol in all resorts, it&rsquo;s illegal to import any alcoholic drinks. A doctor's prescription is required for all medication.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include religious materials offensive to Islam, idols for worship, pornography, narcotics, live pigs, dogs and dangerous animals.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include alcohol, arms and ammunition, chemicals, pork, live animals and plants, and communications equipment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Numerous fish and marine products are banned from export, including coral, black coral necklaces, turtle shell, mother of pearl, conch shell and lobster meat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Maldivian Rufiya (MVR; symbol MRf) = 100 laari. Notes are in denominations of MRf500, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of MRf2 and 1, and 50, 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1 laari.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major currencies can be exchanged at banks, tourist resort islands, hotels and leading shops. Payments in hotels can be made in most hard currencies (particularly US Dollars) in cash, traveller's cheques or credit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major island resorts, local and souvenir shops will accept American Express, Diners Club, Mastercard and Visa. Arrangements vary from island to island. There are ATMs widely available in Mal&eacute;.</p><p>There are ATMs widely available in Malé.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are generally accepted. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sun-Thurs 0730-1430.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter the Maldives, a passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: free.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are issued on arrival at the immigration desk at Mal&eacute; International Airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa extensions are available for a fee of MRf700 for 60 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is illegal to bring dogs into the Maldives. Other pets must have a valid veterinary certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-0.670151]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[73.116760]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>298 sq km (115 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>369,812 (UN estimate 2016)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,319.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mal&eacute;.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Republic of Maldives consists of about 1,190 low-lying coral islands, of which only 200 are inhabited. Most of the inhabited islands are covered by lush tropical vegetation and palm trees, while the numerous uninhabited islands, some of which are mere sand spits or coral tips, are covered in shrubs.</p>
<p>Each island is surrounded by a reef enclosing a shallow lagoon. Hundreds of these islands together with other coral growth form an atoll, surrounding a lagoon. All the islands are low-lying, none more than 2m (7ft) above sea level.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The indigenous population is entirely Sunni Muslim, and the group practice of other religions is illegal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the indigenous population does not mix with the tourist visitors, with the exception of those involved with tourism in the resorts and Malé. Dress is informal, but locals who are Muslim will be offended by nudity or scanty clothing in public places, and the government rigidly enforces these standards. Bikinis and other scanty beachwear are not acceptable in Malé or on any other inhabited island; they should be restricted to resort islands only. When entering a mosque, the legs and the body, but not the neck and the face, should be covered. Handshaking is the most common form of greeting. The indigenous population not involved in the tourist trade lives in isolated island communities maintaining almost total privacy. A large number of locals smoke, but smoking and eating during Ramadan is discouraged.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plug types vary; it's best to check with your hotel before you travel, but European-style plugs with two round pins and British-style plugs with three square pins are both commonly used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Ibrahim Mohamed Solih since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Ibrahim Mohamed Solih since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Maldives are thought to have been originally settled by Buddhists and Hindus from the coast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sri-lanka">Sri Lanka</a> sometime between 300 BC and AD 300. After the arrival of Arab traders, the islands eventually converted to Islam in the 12th century, and became a centre of the coir industry. The tough fibre from the husk of dried coconuts was turned into rope and used on shipping as far afield as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/yemen">Yemen</a>.</p>
<p>The islands remained Islamic, resisting all attempts to convert it to Christianity, even during the period of Portuguese control, which lasted on and off into the 17th century. In 1887 the Sultan of the Maldives signed over his territory to British protection, giving up the islands&rsquo; control over policy but maintaining self-government. British rule continued until independence in 1965, despite earlier abortive attempts by various factions to claim a republic and overthrow the sultan.</p>
<p>A popular referendum was held in 1968 to decide if the newly independent nation should continue its constitutional monarchy &ndash; the sultan, Muhammad Fareed Didi, had declared himself king three years earlier &ndash; or become a presidential republic. More than 93% of the population voted in favour of establishing a republic, ending the 853-year monarchy.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s modern history is largely shaped by Maumoon Gayoom, who was president between 1978 and 2008. Gayoom, who ruled the country virtually unchallenged, finally made concessions to allow for free and democratic elections in 2008. After a run-off, long-time political dissident and opposition leader Mohamed Nasheed was declared president.</p>
<p>Despite having been imprisoned on multiple occasions by Gayoom's police, Nasheed signalled that his government would not prosecute any member of the previous administration. The new government has since focussed on much needed reforms such as improving education, health care, social security and environmental protection. In 2009 the government announced plans to make the Maldives the world's first carbon-neutral country in response to climate change predictions showing the low-lying islands disappearing beneath rising sea levels.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	President Nasheed held the world&rsquo;s first underwater cabinet meeting in October 2009.<br />
&bull;	The Maldives&rsquo; highest point is found on Villingili Island, rising to just 2.3m (7.5ft) above sea level.<br />
&bull;	In September 2013 a coconut was detained by police for acting suspiciously outside a polling station.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Sri Lanka]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+94 (11) 5390 639.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-high-commission-maldives</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+94 (11) 5390 639.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0800-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>389 Bauddhaloka Mw<br/>Colombo<br/>Colombo 7<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Permanent Mission of the Republic of Maldives to the United Nations in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 599 6194 or (212) 599 6195.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.maldivesmission.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 599 6194 or (212) 599 6195.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Suite 400E<br/>800 Second Avenue<br/>New York<br/>10017<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission of the Republic of Maldives in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7224 2135.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.maldiveshighcommission.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7224 2135.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1230 and 1330-1730.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>22 Nottingham Place<br/>London<br/>W1U 5NJ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Maldives is a by-word for luxury, romance and tropical bliss. A beautiful string of low-lying coral islands in the Indian Ocean, they're also a paradise for diving enthusiasts and sun seekers alike.</p><p>The country's 26 natural atolls and over 1000 islands boast uniformly perfect coasts lapped by turquoise lagoons the temperature of bath water. White powdery sand fringes most of the islands, which partly explains why more than a million people come here a year.</p><p>Tourism only began in the 1970s. Now the Maldives' most important industry, it concentrates on the luxury market, meaning that the country is home to some of the world's best hotels. Pretty much every resort here has its own private island. With the finest hotels offering personal butlers and in-room massages, the Maldives are a firm favourite with honeymooners. There are also islands offering slightly less opulent options, and some are aimed at families and divers.</p><p>Sadly, even in paradise, trouble can bubble beneath the surface. It is precisely because the Maldives is so low-lying (80% of the territory is less than 1m/3.3ft above sea level) that their very existence is threatened by global warming. As such, since the 2008 election of young reformer Mohamed Nasheed, the Maldives have worked hard to become one of the most environmentally friendly countries on earth, and continue to do so under new president Mohammed Waheed Hassan.</p><p>Beyond all the luxury and tourism, these coral islands are not the most hospitable, with inhabitants having long struggled in previous times to eke out a living here. There is little in the way of local resources, and while the immaculate ocean may make visitors wonder, it also serves as a constant threat.</p><p>Recently, it has become more feasible on the Maldives for independent travellers and backpackers to avoid the luxury hotels and stay among the local people. The growing number of private guesthouses may well give the Maldives a new lease of life away from big-money tourism. What luxury means, after all, is in the eye of the beholder.</p>The Maldives is a by-word for luxury, romance and tropical bliss; a beautiful string of low-lying coral islands in the Indian Ocean, and a paradise for diving enthusiasts and sun seekers alike.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
