<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Mali" ColCode="mli" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ml" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Mali]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Three main seasons which vary according to latitude. Rainy season runs between June and October, diminishing further north. The cooler season (October to February) is followed by extremely hot, dry weather until June.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are worn throughout most of the year,<br />though warmer clothing is needed between November and February.<br />Waterproofing is advised during the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no scheduled domestic flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Between July and December, there are services between Bamako and Gao via Timbuktu along the River Niger. However, because of drought in the Sahel desert, services are sometimes suspended. The journey is approximately 1,300km (800 miles) and takes five or six days. Between December and March, travel is only possible between Mopti and Gao. Food is available on the boats and first-class cabins can be booked in advance.</p>
<p>Motorised and non-motorised <em>pirogues</em> and <em>pinasses</em> (types of river boat) are available for hire between Timbuktu and Mopti.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A train travels between Kayes and Bamako three times a week using second-hand Indian carriages. The service to Dakar (Senegal) isn't running at present.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main road runs from Sikasso in the south to Bamako, and to Mopti and Gao. Road and driving conditions are poor. Keep to the main roads, otherwise travel in convoy. Avoid travelling at night and be sure to consult official travel advice. Take particular care if driving in Bamako.</p>
<p>Stops at customs and police checkpoints are frequent on major roads.</p>r<p>Roads in Mali range from moderate to very bad.</p>
<p>Between Mopti and Gao, travel can be difficult during the rainy season (mid-June to mid-September) when the Niger, at its confluence with the Bani, splits into a network of channels, and floods its banks to form the marshlands of the Macina.</p><p>International Driving Permit recommended. Insurance and a <em>carnet de passage</em> are also needed. Ensure you carry your vehicle documents and passport at all times when driving.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Collective taxis in cities are cheap. Taxis charge a standard fare regardless of the distance travelled. Tipping is not expected.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating flights to Mali include Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) from Paris and Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>) from Casablanca. Both offer connections from the UK and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 8 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 16 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bamako-Senou International Airport </b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 15km (9 miles) from the city (journey time - 20 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Bamako-Dakar (Senegal) service is not currently running.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Outgoing international calls must be made via the international operator. These are expensive and collect calls cannot be made from Mali.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with several international mobile phone companies. Coverage is limited to main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is an Internet cafe in Bamako. Some hotels offer access.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mali's broadcast and print media are among the most free in Africa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International post is limited to main towns and the central post office. Airmail to Europe takes approximately two weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Djenne Mosque</p><![CDATA[<p>Situated 354 km (220 miles) southwest of <em>Timbuktu</em> on the floodplains of the <em>Bani</em> and <em>Niger</em> rivers, <em>Old Djenne</em> is thought to be the oldest known city in <em>Sub-Saharan Africa</em>. Situated along the ancient trans-Sahara trading routes, by the 16th century Djenne had developed into an important settlement in the region and a centre for Islamic learning. Completed in 1907 to replace an earlier mosque, the famous <em>Djenne Mosque</em> (also known at the <em>Grand Mosque</em>) dominates the old town. Built in the Sudanic style and constructed from sun-baked mud-bricks, each year after the rainy season the entire town turn out to repair the structure at the Spring Festival. Wooden posts that adorn the structure enable workers to scale the walls during the restoration process. A traditional African market is located around the mosque&rsquo;s perimeter. In 1988, Old Djenne and the Grand Mosque were added to the UNESCO list of World Heritage sites.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the traditional architecture of Djenné</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Often considered the 'Jewel of the Niger', Djenné is home to the world's largest mud-brick building, the Grande Mosquée. Almost every building in town follows the same traditional adobe architecture. About 5km (3 miles) to the south is the archaeological site of Djenné-Djeno (Old Djenné), founded around 250BC and one of the oldest towns in sub-Saharan Africa.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Gao’s traditional architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An important town on the trans-Saharan trade routes, Gao had its heyday in the 15th century when it was capital of the Songhai Empire. The mosque of Musa I (considered the richest man who has ever lived) and the tomb of Askia, both traditional Sahelian mud-brick structures, can be found here.</p>]]><p><b>Go on safari at Boucle de Baoulé National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With a number of permanent water sources Boucle de Baoulé National Park permits an array of southern Sahelian species to thrive even during the dry season. Giraffe, leopard, lion, elephant, buffalo and hippo are all present in the park. Mostly comprising a savannah landscape, this natural wonder is also known for its prehistoric tombs and rock art.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Mount Hombori</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located close to Mopti, flat-topped Mount Hombori is not only Mali's tallest mountain at just over 1,150m (3,800 feet), but also an important ecological and archaeological site. Its steep sides have protected its flora and fauna from degradation and its caves have been inhabited for more than 2000 years.</p>]]><p><b>Reach the fabled city of Timbuktu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The city of Timbuktu, straddling ancient trans-Saharan caravan routes, remains the centre of a lucrative trade in salt and gold that dates back centuries, as well as being an important centre of Islamic learning. The Tuareg presence gives the city an Arabic feel that contrasts Mali's other cities, and many historic mosques and tombs remain.</p>]]><p><b>Sit by the Niger at Mopti</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located at the confluence of the Bani and the Niger rivers, Mopti is built on three islands joined by raised causeways. The mud-brick Grand Mosque is a good example of Sahelian architecture. The town's central market, Marché des Souvenirs, and the area surrounding the port are also worth visiting.</p>]]><p><b>Swing by Ségou</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located on the banks of the River Niger, Ségou is known for its pottery and the production of bogolan cloth, dyed using fermented mud. The nearby village of Ségou-Koro (Old Ségou), lying 10km (6 miles) upstream, became the capital of the Bambara Empire in the 17th century, and was visited by explorer Mungo Park in 1796.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the capital’s culture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mali's capital, Bamako, is a modern-looking city on the River Niger and the educational and cultural centre of the country. Not to be missed are its markets, the botanical gardens, the Musée National and the craft centre at the Maison des Artisans. The nearby Point G Hill houses prehistoric cave paintings and offers great views of Bamako below.</p>]]><p><b>Trek Dogon country</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A trek between the traditional villages of the Bandiagara escarpment, which are cut into pink sandstone cliffs, offers exquisite views. Inhabited by the Dogon, whose ancient beliefs have remained largely untouched by Islam, the unique architectural style of these villages has helped them become listed by UNESCO as a World Heritage Site.</p>]]><p><b>Watch sunset over La Dune Rose</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A short distance from Gao, La Dune Rose lies on the right bank of the Niger. Come sunset, Koïma – as it is known locally – turns a wondrous pink. To take maximum advantage of the atmosphere, head upstream to Quema and Hondo, where the sunset ignites similar colours on more dunes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$5.8 billion (2006).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cotton, gold and livestock.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, machinery and equipment, petroleum products, chemicals and pharmaceuticals, and textiles.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, Thailand, France, Senegal and Côte d'Ivoire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mali is one of the poorest countries in the world with an average per capita annual income of about US$470 (2006), an unemployment rate of 14.6% and 64% below the poverty line (2001) . The economy is almost entirely agricultural even though less than 2% of the land is cultivable. Livestock and subsistence crops such as millet, sorghum, maize and rice are raised for domestic consumption.<br /><br />The main cash crop is cotton, of which Mali is one of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/africa">Africa</a>'s largest producers and exporters. The Malian cotton industry, upon which one-third of the population depend for their livelihood, is in serious difficulty because of exceptionally low world prices.<br /><br />Mali is one of the largest gold producers in Africa. Marble, salt and phosphates are also being exploited; there are also known reserves of iron ore and uranium.<br /><br />Much of the economy has been privatised and deregulated since 1997 under the supervision of the IMF with which Mali presently enjoys good relations. Mali has also been one of the main beneficiaries of the debt cancellation for the poorest countries, and it continues to rely on foreign aid and remittances from émigrés. Mali is a member of ECOWAS and various other West African multinational economic organisations.<br />Information can be obtained from the embassy (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The forms of address are those of France, eg Monsieur le Directeur. Lightweight suit and tie are advised for only the smartest meetings. Otherwise, a light, open-neck shirt is worn. It is essential to be able to speak French for business purposes.</p><p>Mon-Thurs 0730-1230 and 1300-1600, Fri 0730-1230 and 1430-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie du Mali</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 222 5036
					Website:http://www.lamaisondelafrique.com/
					Address: BP 46,Place de la Liberté,Bamako,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Though dishes vary from region to region along roughly tribal lines, Mali's staple ingredients – all carbohydrate – include rice, millet and sorghum prepared in a variety of ways. Meals generally take the form of one of these carbohydrates served with a meat or fish sauce. Chicken and lamb are the most popular and readily-available meats.</p><p>Since the majority of Mali's population is Muslim, most people tend to drink fruit juice rather than alcohol, and as a result there is a good range of fresh fruit juices as well as the fruits, including mango and banana, themselves.</p><p>Desserts are few and far between. In order to satisfy a sweet tooth you'll need to turn to Malian tea, or one of the patisseries in the capital.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Capitaine sangha</strong>:&nbsp;Nile perch served with hot chilli sauce, whole fried bananas and rice.<br />
<strong>Djablani</strong>: Juice made from hibiscus, ginger, or the fruit of the baobab tree.<br />
<strong>Gumbo</strong>: Thick green musty-flavoured sauce made from okra pods.<br />
<strong>Tigad&eacute;gu&eacute;na</strong>: Meat served in a peanut sauce.<br />
<strong>Pouletyassa</strong>: Fried chicken in a chilli sauce.<br />
<strong>Alabadja</strong>: Traditional Tuareg recipe that mixes white rice and minced meat in a butter sauce.<br />
<strong>Chouo</strong> <strong>and</strong> <strong>Touru</strong>: Stewed beans, and fried onions, respectively. Though separate dishes they are almost always served together, frequently with spaghetti.<br />
<strong>Saga saga</strong>: Leaf vegetable sauce flavoured with onion and spicy stock.<br />
<strong>Fakoye</strong>: Lamb with herbs, a speciality of the Songhay region.<br />
<strong>T&ocirc;</strong>: Solid starch made from pounded millet used as a vessel for a number of sauces.<br />
<strong>Juices:</strong> Tamarind and guava are particularly delicious.<br />
<strong>Tea:</strong> Drunk in three stages; the first is very strong ('as bitter as death'); the second is slightly sweetened ('just like life'); the third is well sugared ('as sweet as love'). A fourth means you&rsquo;ve overstayed your welcome.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 10% tip is customary in restaurants and bars.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Mali has no known minimum drinking age.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bamako has a good selection of nightclubs with music and dancing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional crafts range from the striking masks of the Bambara, Dogon and Malinko peoples, to woodcarvings, original designs in ebony and bronze, woven cloth, and mats, gold and silver jewellery and copperware. Excellent pottery is made in the S&eacute;gou region, while Timbuktu is a good centre for iron and copper articles, including swords, daggers and traditional household utensils.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1800; some open Sun 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels range from international, 5-star standard to budget. Advance booking is recommended. Further information can be obtained from the tourist office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels range from international, 5-star standard to budget. Advance booking is recommended. Further information can be obtained from the tourist office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels range from international, 5-star standard to budget. Advance booking is recommended. Further information can be obtained from the tourist office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are very limited, although Bamako's hospitals are recognised as being of good standard and emergency services in the city are available 24 hours. Health insurance (including adequate medical evacuation) is therefore essential. Doctors and hospitals may expect immediate cash payment for health care services.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water is sometimes unsafe - it is advised to drink bottled water and to avoid ice cubes. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against meningococcal meningitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water; swimming pools which are well chlorinated and maintained are safe.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Korité (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Korité itself. Korité and Tabaski (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Armed Forces Day :
							2018<br/>20 January </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							26 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Africa Day :
							25 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							22 September </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Mali without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 1,000 cigarettes or 250 cigars or 2kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of XOF250,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include narcotics, beef, food or medicine past the best-before date, and alcohol in plastic sachets.</p>
<p>Restricted items include medicine, meat, plants, explosives, and firearms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Restricted exports requiring authorisation include meat, hunting trophies, plants and artworks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFA (<em>Communauté Financière Africaine</em>) Franc (XOF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of XOF10,000, 5,000, 2,000 and 1,000. Coins are in denominations of XOF500, 200, 250, 100, 50, 25, 10 and 5.<br /><br />Mali is part of the French Monetary Area. Only currency issued by the <em>Banque des Etats de l'Afrique de l'Ouest</em> (Bank of West African States) is valid; currency issued by the <em>Banque des Etats de l'Afrique Centrale</em> (Bank of Central African States) is not. The CFA Franc is tied to the Euro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to exchange Euros and US Dollars in Bamako.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are very little used in Mali's cash economy - and are only accepted at major banks, airports, hotels and restaurants. Visa is the main card accepted; MasterCard and American Express can sometimes be used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Can be exchanged In Bamako. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1630, Sat 0800-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>
<p>All travellers require a yellow fever vaccination certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: &pound;190; multiple-entry visa: &pound;220 (three months) or &pound;260 (six months).</p>
<p>The fee for US&nbsp;nationals is US$131, regardless of the length of stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: one month; multiple-entry visa: three or six months. US nationals are also eligible for multiple-entry visas valid for up to five years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). UK residents can apply to the honorary consulate in London.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 10 days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[17.358015]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-3.526013]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,240,192 sq km (478,841 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>18,134,835 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>13.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bamako.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mali is a landlocked republic, sharing borders with Mauritania, Algeria, Burkina Faso, C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire, Guinea, Niger and Senegal. It is a vast land of flat plains fed by two major rivers, the Senegal on its western edge and the great River Niger. On its journey north the Niger converges with the River Bani, and forms a rich inland delta, the marshlands of the Macina, stretching for some 450km (280 miles) along the river's length, in some places 200km (124 miles) wide. The central part of the country is arid grazing land, called the Sahel, which has suffered great drought.<br />
<br />
At Timbuktu, the Niger reaches the desert and here it turns first to the east, then to the southeast at Bourem, where it heads for the ocean. In the desert, near the Algerian and Niger borders in the northeast, the Adrar des Iforas massif rises 800m (2,625ft). The north of the country is true desert except for the few oases along the ancient trans-Saharan camel routes. Tuaregs still live around these oases and camel routes. Further south live the Peulh cattle-raising nomads. The majority of the population lives in the savannah region in the south. The peoples of this region comprise Songhai, Malinke, Senoufou, Dogon and the Bambara (the largest ethnic group).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Majority Muslim, with indigenous and Christian minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malians are hospitable people and will welcome visitors gracefully into their homes. Visitors must remember that this is a Muslim country and the religious customs and beliefs of the people should be respected. Modesty in dress, particularly for women, is essential.<br /><br /><strong>Photography:</strong> This is no longer restricted, except for military subjects. However, interpretation of what is considered off limits tends to vary. Other subjects may be considered sensitive from a cultural or religious point of view and it is advisable to obtain permission before taking photographs in Mali.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Larger towns in Mali have their own locally generated supply. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Soumeylou Boub&egrave;ye Ma&iuml;ga since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Ibrahim Boubacar Ke&iuml;ta since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Once one of the great centres of Islamic culture and wealth, Mali owes much of its reputation to its situation as a major trading centre and to the tax that is levied on its trans-Saharan route. The Ghana Empire was the first to rise in the region, expanding throughout West Africa between the 8th and 11th centuries.</p>
<p>The second, the Mali Empire, reached its zenith in the early 14th century. After its decline, the territory became part of the Songhai Empire, which was brought to an end by a Moroccan invasion in 1591. With the decline of the trans-Saharan trading routes in salt, gold and slaves, the area enjoyed little strategic importance and was divided into small kingdoms for the next two centuries until the arrival of French colonists. Mali was absorbed into French West Africa in 1895. In 1960, together with what is now&nbsp;Senegal, it achieved independence as the Federation of Mali, although Senegal seceded after a few weeks.</p>
<p>The first president was Modibo Keita, who severed ties with&nbsp;France&nbsp;and developed strong links with the USSR. In 1968, a military coup overthrew Keita and the coup leader promised a return to civilian rule. This failed to materialise until in 1991, army officer, Lieutenant-Colonel Amadou Toumani Tour&eacute;, assumed power.</p>
<p>In presidential elections later that year, the leader of the Alliance pour la D&eacute;mocratie au Mali (ADEMA), Alpha Oumar Konar&eacute;, won and dominated Malian politics for the next 10 years. Konar&eacute; secured re-election in 1997 but the political environment was far from peaceful during the period of ADEMA rule. The country was beset by strikes, student protests, as well as a revolving door of prime ministers, few of whom lasted more than a year.</p>
<p>In 2002, after a decade in the political wilderness, Tour&eacute; returned to office. French approval quickly became evident when the bulk of Mali's debt to France was cancelled within months of the election. Tour&eacute; won elections again in 2007, and democratic institutions continue to strengthen despite a Tuareg rebellion and French military intervention in 2012.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The 14th century emperor Mansa Musa gave away so much gold he caused the price to collapse.<br />
&bull;	Gordon Laing is considered the first European to reach fabled Timbuktu. He was killed by Tuaregs before being able to claim the 10,000 francs in prize money from the French Soci&eacute;t&eacute; de G&eacute;ographie.<br />
&bull;	The prime meridian runs through the city of Gao.<br />
&bull;	333 Muslim saints are buried in Timbuktu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Mali in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 2249.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.maliembassy.us</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 2249.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2130 R Street NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Mali in Belgium]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(02) 345 7432.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.amba-mali.be/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(02) 345 7432.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Avenue Molière 487<br/>Brussels<br/>1050<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With a history blighted by political instability, it's hardly surprising that Mali is missing from most people&rsquo;s bucket lists. But as peace slowly returns to this dusty land, travellers are trickling back to unearth the country&rsquo;s cultural treasures &ndash; of which there are many.</p>
<p>Though it&rsquo;s hard to see how one of the most remote nations in the world, located deep within the Sahara Desert, ever became a centre of world learning, Timbuktu is not only a byword for long distances, but also an internationally recognised centre of knowledge: its libraries contain seminal notes on astronomy, mathematics and philosophy dating back to the 16th century.</p>
<p>Closely linked to Timbuktu by the Saharan trade in gold, salt and slaves, Djenn&eacute; is known the world over for its adobe architecture, in particular the Grand Mosque, a UNESCO World Heritage Site and the largest mud-brick building in the world.</p>
<p>Bamako, Mali&rsquo;s capital, may not have the cultural attractions of Timbuktu or Djenn&eacute;, but it has a fascinating collection of architectural styles and an elegant location on the banks of the River Niger. What&rsquo;s more, it is the centre of the country&rsquo;s traditional music scene and Malians of all ethnicities throng to the nightclubs of Bamako to dance the night away to the sound of the kora, a lute-like instrument.</p>
<p>The most distinct of Mali&rsquo;s people are the Dogon, whose secluded, cliff-side villages cling to sheer rock faces. Deliberately isolating themselves from the influences of neighbouring tribes they have developed a culture with no similarity in the region.</p>
<p>A land of faraway cities, intriguing civilisations and architecture like nowhere else on Earth, Mali&rsquo;s position as a cultural juggernaut is well founded and its tentative steps towards stability have opened up an avenue of discovery for intrepid travellers.</p><p>With a history blighted by political instability, it's hardly surprising that Mali is missing from most people&rsquo;s bucket lists. But as peace slowly returns to this dusty land, travellers are trickling back to unearth the country&rsquo;s cultural treasures &ndash; of which there are many.</p>
<p>Though it&rsquo;s hard to see how one of the most remote nations in the world, located deep within the Sahara Desert, ever became a centre of world learning, Timbuktu is not only a byword for long distances, but also an internationally recognised centre of knowledge: its libraries contain seminal notes on astronomy, mathematics and philosophy dating back to the 16th century.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
