<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Malta" ColCode="mlt" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mt" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Malta]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Summer is May-October and the hottest months are July to September when temperatures can reach 30+ degrees. In winter, the days are mild but the evenings can be quite chilly due to slightly stronger winds. <br /><br /><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malta">Malta</a>'s beaches welcome scores of sun worshippers throughout the summer, while windsurfers prefer the stronger winds of the winter months. The island can get pretty packed during the summer so if sightseeing is your main aim, visit outside of peak season when it is sunny but cooler.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are worn between March and September, although warmer clothes may occasionally be necessary in spring and autumn and on cooler evenings. A light raincoat is advisable for winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gozo Channel (tel: +356 2210 9000; <a href="http://www.gozochannel.com" target="_blank">www.gozochannel.com</a>) operates a passenger car ferry several times daily between Cirkewwa in Malta and Mgarr in Gozo (journey time - about 25 minutes).</p>
<p>Comino Ferries (tel: +356 9940 6529;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.cominoferries.com" target="_blank">www.cominoferries.com</a>) operates services from Marfa and Cirkewwa, Malta, to the Blue Lagoon, Comino. The Comino Hotel (<a href="http://www.cominohotel.com" target="_blank">www.cominohotel.com</a>) runs a ferry service to the island from March to November. Paradise Diving (<a href="http://www.paradisediving.com" target="_blank">www.paradisediving.com</a>), in Cirkewwa, offers a daily service to the Blue Lagoon from May to October.</p>
<p>A &amp; S Water Taxis operates in the Grand Harbour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>The main roads are all good quality. Some of the smaller roads in the country may require care when driving.</p><p>Taxis here are identifiable by their all-white livery. Although taxi fares are government controlled, it's still best to agree prices before departure. Taxis from the airport have fixed prices. Battery-powered CT cabs operate in Valletta.</p><p>Valid international or EU driving licence required.</p><p>The speed limit is 80kph (50mph) on highways and 50kph (30mph) in residential areas, unless otherwise directed. Speed cameras are in operation. Driving is on the left and seatbelts are compulsory. Children up to three years must use an appropriate restraint when travelling in the front. Use of headlights in tunnels is compulsory.</p><p>Many of the car hire firms offer breakdown as an option when hiring a car or a moped.</p><p>A number of car hire firms offer self-drive cars. International firms are represented at the airport. Rates on Malta are among the cheapest in Europe.</p><p>Bicycles and mopeds are available to hire on the island.</p><p>The speed limit is 80kph (50mph) on highways and 50kph (30mph) in residential areas, unless otherwise directed. Speed cameras are in operation. Driving is on the left and seatbelts are compulsory. Children up to three years must use an appropriate restraint when travelling in the front. Use of headlights in tunnels is compulsory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public transport is efficient and reasonably priced.  The main bus terminus in Malta is in Valletta, just outside the City Gate.  An express bus service links the principal resorts with Sliema, Marsaxlokk, Mdina, the Three Cities and the main sandy beaches. In Gozo, the bus terminus is in Main Gate Street, Victoria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier is Air Malta (<a href="http://www.airmalta.com" target="_blank">www.airmalta.com</a>). Other airlines operating direct flights from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malta/malta-international-airport">Malta International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 3 hours 10 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 12 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Malta International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.maltairport.com<p>Malta International Airport is located 5km (3 miles) southeast of&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/valletta">Valletta</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+356 2124 9600</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports: </strong>Valletta, Marsaxlokk and Mgarr/Gozo.</p>
<p>For information on the ports in Malta, contact Transport Malta (tel: +356 2122 2203; www.transport.gov.mt).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes. Public telephone booths are available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafes in the main towns and resorts. Most hotels offer wireless connection.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Daily and weekly publications appear in both English and Maltese. <em>In-Nazzjon Taghna</em> and <em>L'Orizzont</em> are the Maltese dailies, with <em>The Malta Independent</em>, <em>The Times of Malta, Malta Star</em> and <em>Malta Today</em> being the English equivalent. Imported papers are available. </p>
<p>Television is a broad mix of English, Italian and Maltese with TVM being the national station, Super One TV being owned by the Labour Party, and Net TV by the Nationalist Party. There are commercial radio stations such as Bay Radio. Radio 101 is owned by the Nationalist Party and Super One Radio is owned by the Malta Labour Party.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good postal services exist within the island. Mail within the EU usually takes around five working days to arrive. Opening Hours: Mon-Sat 0730-1245.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Blue Grotto</p><![CDATA[<p>The Blue Grotto is the most famous cave in Malta, with its deep waters displaying magnificent dazzling colours, ranging from turquoise to deep blue. Situated near the village of Zurrieq in southwestern Malta, which is famous for its rocky coastline, the waters around the limestone caves and archways are said to be at their most impressive in the early morning when the sun's rays glimmer through the opening to the grotto. The cave, which is known as Il-Hnejja, meaning 'The Arch', in Maltese, was given its English name by British soldiers who thought that its blue waters resembled the Grotta Azzurra  (Blue Grotto) in Capri. To get to the grotto, visitors travel by boat, passing under a massive arch, deep into the 43-metre (140-ft) high cave which is hollowed out of the cliff rockface.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bathe in the Blue Lagoon of Comino</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The blockbuster film, <em>Troy</em>, was filmed by the shimmering turquoise waters of this lagoon. A popular day trip for swimmers and sun worshippers who come to lounge on the small rocky and sandy beaches, it gets horribly overcrowded in summer, so visit early in the day or out of peak season.</p>]]><p><b>Be dazzled by the Blue Grotto</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Blue Grotto is the most famous cave in Malta, with its deep waters displaying magnificent dazzling colours, ranging from turquoise to deep blue. Situated near the village of Zurrieq in southwestern Malta, the waters around the limestone caves and archways are said to be at their most impressive in the early morning when the sun's rays glimmer through the opening to the grotto.</p>]]><p><b>Breathe the sea air at Grand Harbour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the deepest natural harbours in the world, it has been in use since Phoenician times. It provided a base to the Knights of St John and was used by the British for over 170 years. Its sheer size has to be seen to be believed, but today it's a far more serene affair, with restaurants, bars and the tranquil Barrakka Gardens.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Gozo Citadel and Santa Maria Cathedral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The 7,000-year-old fortress looms above the Gozo city of Victoria with its imposing façade, Baroque architecture and sweeping views. There is an interesting audio tour of the cathedral, with its 3D-effect painted dome and marble floor tombstones. The cathedral has one of the world's largest unsupported domes.</p>]]><p><b>Go medieval at Mdina</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its imposing walls, cobbled streets and fascinating architecture, the Mdina citadel is one site you cannot afford to miss. Follow in the footsteps of medieval knights and visit the cathedral, dungeons and 13th century Palazzo Falson with its extraordinary collection of art and antiques. From Bastion Square, see breath-taking views of the surrounding area and St Paul's Bay.</p>]]><p><b>Head underground at Hal Saflieni Hypogeum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This underground complex of halls, chambers, passages and carvings near Paola was built around 3600 BC and only discovered by accident in 1902. It's a treasure trove of pottery, ornaments, animal carvings and entombed corpses. Booking is essential as visitor numbers are restricted.</p>]]><p><b>Lounge the day away at Golden Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Malta is home to a collection of beautiful and unspoiled sandy beaches, of which Golden Bay is perhaps the most spectacular in Malta. This long stretch of gleaming sand attracts families and sun worshippers by day, as well as horse riders at twilight; one-hour rides and sunset treks are available at Golden Bay stables.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the stunning capital of Valletta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This UNESCO-listed fortress was built of sandstone by the Knights of St John in 1566. In 2018 Valletta bears the title of &quot;European Capital of Culture&quot;. Today it is filled with ornate churches, palaces and museums befitting a city with such an illustrious history. It's all packed with outdoor cafes serving traditional <em>pastizzi</em> (puff pastry filled with ricotta or mushy peas), and many restaurants cooking up authentic Maltese cuisine.</p>]]><p><b>Wander St Agatha's Catacombs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>According to local tradition, during the persecution of Christians, St. Agatha fled from Sicily and took refuge in Malta. A natural cave built underneath Malta's oldest parish church was turned into a crypt, typical of the underground Christian cemeteries of the time. The extensive subterranean catacombs hold numerous galleries and graves.</p>]]><p><b>Worship the megalithic temples</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Erected between the 4th and 3rd millenniums BC, the UNESCO-listed temples of Malta are thought to be amongst the oldest surviving buildings in the world. The tiny island of Gozo, which is part of the Maltese archipelago, features the so-called Ggantija temples; the name means "belonging to the giants", as locals probably thought giants alone were capable of bringing the large stones to the fertile plan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$ 8.8 billion (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Potatoes, machinery, manufactured goods, fish, pharmaceutical products</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, transportation equipment, manufactured goods, foodstuffs, and mineral fuels and oils</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Italy, France, UK, USA and Germany.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malta's agricultural sector is small, with potatoes being the only major export commodity. With few natural resources, governments have sought to develop the economy through tourism and manufacturing. The industrial sector includes textiles, footwear and clothing, plastics, printing, electronic components and electrical equipment. The old naval dockyard used by the British now operates as a commercial shipyard.<br/> Malta's membership to the EU was endorsed in March 2003 by popular referendum. Negotiations progressed fairly smoothly and Malta joined the EU in May 2004. The country joined the eurozone on 1 January 2008.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>English is widely spoken in business circles and, on the whole, Maltese businesspeople have a conservative approach to business protocol. Punctuality is expected and appreciated and dress must be smart. The best months for business visits are October to May.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1730, Sat 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Malta Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 2123 3873
					Website:http://www.chamber.org.mt
					Address: Republic Street,Exchange Buildings,Valletta VLT 05,]]><b>Ministry of Foreign Affairs</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 2124 2191
					Website:http://www.foreign.gov.mt
					Address: Merchants' Street,Palazzo Parisio,Valletta,]]><b>Conference and Incentive Travel Division of the Malta Tourism Authority</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 2291 5000
					Website:http://www.maltaconferences.com
					Address: Merchants Street,Auberge d'Italie,Valletta,VLT 1170]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Malta is the hidden gem of the Mediterranean with a fine reputation for its varied cuisine, borrowing heavily from neighbouring Sicily and North Africa. Although food from every part of the globe is to be found on the island, local restaurants providing rustic home-cooked family recipes are definitely worth seeking out.</p><p>Particularly noteworthy are the places serving traditional rabbit recipes. The family get-together also plays an important part in the Maltese dining experience, so expect to see large multi-generational gatherings especially on Sundays enjoying their food and drink during a distinctly Mediterranean feast that will last for hours.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Timpana</strong>: Pasta with a Bolognese-style sauce baked in pastry.<br />
<strong>Bragioli</strong>: Thin slices of steak rolled around a ground veal filling and covered in a tomato-based sauce.<br />
<strong>Fenek</strong>: Rabbit cooked in wine.<br />
<strong>Pastizzi</strong>: Ricotta or pea-filled savoury pastries.<br />
<strong>Lampuki pie</strong>: A baked pastry derived from the popular <em>lampuki</em> fish.<br />
<strong>Qara bali mimli</strong>: Round pale green zucchini or courgettes stuffed with minced beef, cheese and parsley or with ricotta and grated sharp cheese.<br />
<strong>Mazzit</strong>: Maltese blood sausage.<br />
<strong>Kinnie: S</strong>parkling soft drink with a distinctive bitter orange flavour.<br />
<strong>Cisk lager</strong>: Malta's national beer.<br />
<strong>Bajtra</strong>: One of Malta's traditional liqueurs, distilled from prickly pears.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Expect to pay 10 to 15% in hotels and restaurants when service is not included in the bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>17.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malta's nightlife is centred around St Julian's, particularly Paceville, and St Paul's Bay. There you will find many discos, bars and nightclubs to suit every age. Roulette, baccarat and blackjack are played at Malta's three casinos - The Dragonara in Paceville, Cottonera and St Paul's Bay. Three multiplex cinemas showing the latest releases are located in St Julian's, Valletta and St Paul's Bay and there is a small arts cinema in the St James Cavalier Arts complex in Valetta. The Manoel Theatre in Valletta is a delightful architectural gem and is reputed to be one of the oldest theatres in Europe. Performances are generally held until June and include concerts, opera and drama.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malta offers many handmade goods that make wonderful souvenirs. Mdina Glass has a long established history as a leading glass-blower and it is worthwhile paying a visit to the factory. Maltese gold and silver jewellery are of high quality as is the local filigree work. Pottery, handmade lace and embroidery are also worth looking out for. Leading fashion stores and boutiques are located in Sliema.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1900 (shops may sometimes close later in tourist resorts).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a huge selection of hotels in Malta catering for every budget. The majority are clustered around St Julian's, Sliema, St Paul's Bay, St George&rsquo;s Bay and Bugibba. There are several in Valletta. For further information, contact the Malta Tourist Office.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guest houses (<a href="http://www.visitmalta.com/guesthouses_malta" target="_blank">www.visitmalta.com/guesthouses_malta</a>) are divided into standard class and comfort class.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a huge selection of hotels in Malta catering for every budget. The majority are clustered around St Julian's, Sliema, St Paul's Bay, St George&rsquo;s Bay and Bugibba. There are several in Valletta. For further information, contact the Malta Tourist Office.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a huge selection of hotels in Malta catering for every budget. The majority are clustered around St Julian's, Sliema, St Paul's Bay, St George&rsquo;s Bay and Bugibba. There are several in Valletta. For further information, contact the Malta Tourist Office.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;If suddenly taken ill or involved in an accident during a visit to Malta, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available for European travellers - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). Travellers from other countries should find out if they are covered by other reciprocal arrangements. Australia, for example, has such an agreement as long as long as citizens carry their Medicare card. Comprehensive insurance is advised for all other nationals.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The principal hospital is Mater Dei at B&amp;rsquo;Kara, in Malta. Ambulance travel is free in an emergency (telephone 112), as long as you can prove that you are entitled to treatment.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Malta has a reciprocal health agreement with Australia; residents from Australia visiting are entitled to free medical hospital care during their first six months in Malta.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available and is advised for the first few weeks of the stay. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Feast of St Paul's Shipwreck :
							10 February </p><p>Feast of St Joseph :
							19 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Freedom Day :
							31 March </p><p>Workers' Day :
							01 May </p><p>Sette Giugno :
							07 June </p><p>Feast of Saints Peter and Paul :
							29 June </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Feast of Our Lady of Victories :
							08 September </p><p>Independence Day :
							21 September </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Republic Day :
							13 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import into <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malta/malta-international-airport">Malta</a>, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22%, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Malta by persons over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms and ammunition, counterfeit goods, unlicensed drugs, obscene literature and other media, animals and birds (dead or alive), plants, and dairy and meat products from outside the EU.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol €) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of €500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of €2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money can be changed at banks, bureaux de change, some hotels, and larger shops and restaurants. Automated foreign exchange machines are available at various locations on the islands. Exchange bureaux are often open 24 hours a day. Some hotels, larger shops and restaurants accept foreign currency. The best rates of exchange will always be found at the banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted. ATMs are available.</p><p>ATMs are available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchanged in the normal authorised institutions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1730, Sat 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>Malta is part of the Schengen system. Therefore, if travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen system, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some nationals require an airport transit visa; check with the embassy or high commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malta is part of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate (or consular section of embassy or high commission). UK residents requiring a visa can submit applications to the high commission in London or to a VFS Global&nbsp;Visa Application Centre in Edinburgh or Manchester (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/Malta/UK" target="_blank">www.vfsglobal.com/Malta/UK</a>). VFS charges an additional service fee of &pound;25.09.&nbsp;Visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa applicants are advised to apply at least a month before travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors who require a Schengen visa must show proof of sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa holders can only extend their stay in exceptional circumstances such as <em>force majeure</em> or for humanitarian reasons.</p>
<p>All nationals planning to stay for longer than 90 days must apply for residence. Different rules apply to EU and non-EU nationals; visit the Ministry for Home Affairs and National Security website for details (<a href="http://homeaffairs.gov.mt">http://homeaffairs.gov.mt</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you bring a pet from another EU country, your animal must have a microchip, pet passport and valid rabies vaccination certificate. Animals from outside the EU must have a microchip, rabies vaccination and official veterinary certificate.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Dogs travelling to Malta from most countries must first undergo tapeworm treatment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[35.933005]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[14.380983]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>316 sq km (122 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>419,615 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,310 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Valletta.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Maltese archipelago is situated in the centre of the Mediterranean, with the largest inhabited island, Malta, lying 93km (58 miles) south of Sicily and 290km (180 miles) from North Africa. Gozo and Comino are the only other inhabited islands. The landscape of all three is characterised by low hills with terraced fields.</p>
<p>Malta the largest island and the cultural and commercial centre, has a rolling terrain and a largely rugged coastline, indented with harbours, bays, creeks, sandy beaches and rocky coves.  It has no mountains or rivers.  Gozo is connected to Malta by ferry and is more verdant, with many flat-topped hills and craggy cliffs. Comino, the smallest island, is connected to Malta and Gozo by ferry and is very sparsely populated.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>95% Roman Catholic, with the remaining 5% divided between Anglican, Church of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland">Scotland</a>, Greek Orthodox, Jewish, Methodists and Muslim.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The usual European courtesies are expected, but the visitor should also bear in mind the tremendous importance of Roman Catholicism; if visiting a church, for instance, modest dress covering the shoulders and legs will be expected. Smoking is prohibited on public transport and in all public buildings, including cinemas, restaurants and bars.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Joseph Muscat since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Marie-Louise Coleiro Preca since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Malta's position in the central Mediterranean has made it an important strategic base for many different powers, and meant that it has been subject to many invasions throughout the ages. A multitude of civilisations have occupied the island, notably the Phoenicians, Carthaginians, Romans, Turks, Arabs and British.</p>
<p>Malta's human history stretches far beyond all of these invaders, though, with a number of megalithic temples dating back to the early Bronze Age on the island, remnants from one of the oldest civilisations in the Mediterranean. It remained a sleepy place for many centuries until the 12th century when there was great expansion of trade and a flowering of the arts and sciences in the region; during this time, the island changed hands between the Aragonese, Venetians, Genoese, Papacy, kings of France, and Arabs.</p>
<p>Political stability did not return until the 16th century, when Malta, together with Sicily, became part of the vast empire of Charles V, who in 1530, recognised the strategic value of the islands for Christendom and granted them to the Knights of St John.</p>
<p>For the next 250 years, Malta was a bulwark against Turkish ambitions in Europe. Napoleon briefly held Malta but a British-backed rebellion forced him to retreat and the British ruled for the next 181 years. The most famous episode in Malta's recent history was the heroic defence of the island during WWII, which saw the island held under siege by the Axis between 1940 and 1942. The nation was awarded the George Cross for its role in the war.</p>
<p>Since achieving independence from Britain in 1964, Malta has been stable with domestic issues dominating its internal politics. Malta became a republic in 1974 and a member of the European Union in 2004. It adopted the euro in 2008, and has flourished since, both politically and commercially, with vast sums of money being invested in infrastructure and roads. Malta rejoined NATO&rsquo;s Partnership for Peace in 2009 and remains committed to its neutral status.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Some 3,000 bombing raids were made on Malta by Italian and German air forces during WWII.<br />
&bull;	Malta's Calypso Cave is believed to be the same cave Homer mentioned in The Odyssey.<br />
&bull;	Malta has two co-official languages &ndash; English and Maltese. The latter tongue is closely related to the medieval Sicilian dialect of Arabic, although it has gradually been Latinised over the centuries, and there are many English loan words.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Malta]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(356) 2323 0000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-high-commission-malta</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(356) 2323 0000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1200 and 1230-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Ta' Xbiex<br/>Whitehall Mansions, Ta' Xbiex Seafront<br/>Valletta<br/>XBX 1026<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Malta High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7292 4800.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.foreign.gov.mt</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7292 4800.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1230 and 1430-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>36-38 Piccadilly<br/>Malta House<br/>London<br/>W1J OLE<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Malta in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 462 3611.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.foreign.gov.mt</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 462 3611.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2017 Connecticut Avenue NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From the MTV music festival in Valletta to abseiling and climbing in Gozo, Malta rocks. Small in size but big in character, the Mediterranean island offers cool cafes, buzzing nightclubs, exhilarating activities and amazing archaeological wonders, whatever the time of year.</p>
<p>Situated in the centre of the Mediterranean Sea, the Maltese archipelago includes Gozo, Comino, Cominotto and Filfla. It has bags of character at every turn, with secluded bays, medieval walled citadels and splendid baroque churches.</p>
<p>Most tourists come for the weather (there are more than 300 days of sunshine annually) and crystalline waters, which make it one of the best places to go snorkelling and diving in the Mediterranean. The water is in fact amongst the cleanest in the region.</p>
<p>But Malta&rsquo;s distinctive appeal lies in its extraordinary 7,000 years of history. This small island has a greater concentration of historic sights than any country. Visitors can explore some of the oldest stone structures in the world here, as well as prehistoric temples, Roman catacombs and medieval villages.</p>
<p>The island is also famous for the Knights of St John, otherwise known as the Knights of Malta, who ruled it for 250 years and left behind plenty of remarkable architecture. Several museums explore Malta&rsquo;s multi-faceted past, which saw it ruled by Greeks, Phoenicians, Romans, Arabs, Normans and more.</p>
<p>Later came British rule, leaving behind a legacy of English as joint-official language with Maltese, as well as red letterboxes and phone booths. Despite this era, the island remains thoroughly Maltese. Summertime is greeted with lots of local festivals, and many restaurants now serve traditional Mediterranean food, which have pushed Anglo-influenced dishes off the menu.</p>
<p>Spring and autumn are probably the best times to visit this unique island, as temperatures are a little cooler while still suitable for sunbathing and swimming. It&rsquo;s also when the tourist numbers ease from their summer peak.</p><p>From the MTV music festival in Valletta to abseiling and climbing in Gozo, Malta rocks. Small in size but big in character, the Mediterranean island offers cool cafes, buzzing nightclubs, exhilarating activities and amazing archaeological wonders, whatever the time of year. Situated in the centre of the Mediterranean Sea, the Maltese archipelago includes Gozo, Comino, Cominotto and Filfla. It has bags of character at every turn, with secluded bays, medieval walled citadels and splendid baroque churches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
