<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Martinique" ColCode="mtq" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mq" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Martinique]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Warm weather throughout the year, with the main rainy season occurring in the autumn. Showers can occur at other times of the year, but they are usually brief. Cooler in the upland areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight, with waterproof wear advised for the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Antilles (<a href="http://www.flyairantilles.com" target="_blank">www.flyairantilles.com</a>) operates flights from Martinique to neighbouring islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Scheduled ferries ply between Fort-de-France and the main resorts of Trois &Icirc;lets and Sainte-Anne via Anse Mitan, Pointe du Bout, Anse &agrave; l'&Acirc;ne and Anses d'Arlet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>The road system is well developed and surfaced.</p><p>Plentiful and reasonably cheap if shared. The majority of taxis are Mercedes-Benz. Main taxi stands are at major hotels, resorts and the airport.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is recommended, but a national driving licence is sufficient, provided you have at least one year's experience. The minimum driving age is 21.</p><p>The island has excellent car hire facilities. You can also hire bikes and mopeds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public buses serve Fort-de-France and beyond. Share taxis are called 'taxicos' and can be a great way to meet locals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) operates direct flights to Martinique from Paris, with connections from the UK. Norwegian (www.norwegian.com) flies direct to Martinique from New York. American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>) flies non-stop from Miami.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London - 12 hours (including stopover); New York - 5 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Martinique Aimé Césaire International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.martinique.aeroport.fr<p>The airport is 11km (7 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main port:&nbsp;</strong>Fort-de-France. The Pointe Simon cruise dock, nearer the city centre, accommodates larger cruise ships.</p>
<p>L'Express des Iles (tel: 0825 359 000, in the French Antilles only; <a href="http://www.express-des-iles.com" target="_blank">www.express-des-iles.com</a>) runs regular high-speed catamaran services run to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guadeloupe">Guadeloupe</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-lucia">St Lucia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dominica">Dominica</a>.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are both payphones and card phones on the island. <em>Télécartes</em> (phonecards) are sold at post offices, newsagents and kiosks. There are only card phones at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies. Coverage extends throughout the French Antilles and in French Guiana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a few Internet cafes in Martinique, predominantly in the cities such as Fort de France and main tourist areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>TV and radio services are provided by the French public overseas broadcaster, <em>RFO</em>, and by private operators.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Letters take about a week to reach Europe.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0700-1800 and Saturday mornings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the Arawak artefacts at Musée Départemental</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pay a visit to the Musée Départemental, which tells the story of the island through a series of artefacts. Housed in a colonial building and focussing predominantly on Arawak and Carib Indian prehistory, the museum offers an interesting insight into island life before Christopher Columbus landed in the early 16th century.</p>]]><p><b>Bathe in the beaches of Pointe du Bout</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the south of the island is Pointe du Bout, Martinique's major resort area. Sainte-Anne, Le Diamant and Les Anses d'Arlets have some of the island's best bathing beaches. HMS Diamond Rock, 4km (2.5 miles) off Diamant, is a rock which was designated a man-of-war by the British during the Napoleonic wars and rates a 12-gun salute from passing British warships.</p>]]><p><b>Call in at the Cathedral of St-Louis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by Paris' Eiffel Tower, the Cathedral of St-Louis is a late 17th-century cathedral with a Roman-style bell tower. Peaking above the Fort-de-France skyline, the Gothic revival structure is a stand out sight in the capital and its bright, atmospheric interior is also the final resting place of many of the island's former governors.</p>]]><p><b>Dive down and see shipwrecks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the wrecks of the ships which were in the harbour on the day Montagne Pelée erupted – all but one of them went down in the disaster. Special submarines with glass windows take tourists to view the wrecks and the colourful fish that swim around them. It is also possible to dive down to get that little bit closer.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Pearl of the Caribbean destroyed by Montagne Pelée</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Montagne Pelée, the 1,430m (4,700ft) volcanic mountain in the north, last erupted in 1902 destroying the city of St Pierre. Known as the "Pearl of the Caribbean", the remains are now a tourist attraction. Old stone stairways and the ruined theatre still exist, while its notable historic buildings like the old customs house are being rebuilt and restored.</p>]]><p><b>Make a splash by snorkelling, skiing and sailing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Water based activities are abundant in Martinique. Whether you want to water-ski, explore the bays in a sailboat, scuba-dive, snorkel, or try your hand at spearfishing, many coastal resorts offer all. Take part in the Aqua Festival, a sailing event held each year around the Bay of Robert, or watch the yachting regatta held every June in Le Marin.</p>]]><p><b>Pay a visit to a plantation at Le Carbet</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Le Carbet is where Columbus landed on his fourth voyage in 1502. The Centre d'Art Paul Gauguin can be found in the town and contains exhibits relating to the painter's stay in the area, including the work he did whilst here. Nearby, the restored plantation of Leyritz welcomes visitors to stay in restored stone cottages.</p>]]><p><b>Saddle up and explore the countryside</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Horse riding is a very enjoyable way to see Martinique's lovely countryside, so saddle up for a coastline canter. For those that wish to see the island under their own steam will find easy hiking trails, whilst mountain biking and climbing are both catered for. There is also horseracing to be enjoyed at Hippodrome de Carrère, Lamentin. </p>]]><p><b>Sample the island's rum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sampling Martinique's island rum is a must. Distilleries abound throughout the island and all of them welcome visitors for a sampling of their product. The St James Distillery at Sainte-Marie in the north operates the Musée du Rhum and Rhum Clement Domaine Acajou, in Le François on the east coast, also has a fine contemporary museum.</p>]]><p><b>Wander the winding streets of Fort-de-France</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Winding streets and colourful markets make the island's capital, Fort-de-France, a delightful spot. Seek out the park of La Savanne and the statue which commemorates Napoleon's Empress Josephine, a native of Martinique. Her home, La Pagerie, is one of the main tourist attractions and her birthplace, La Pagerie, has a museum chock full of her mementos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$37 million.</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum products, bananas, sugar, cut flowers, rum and pineapples.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum products, crude oil, foodstuffs, construction materials, vehicles, clothing and other consumer goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guadeloupe">Guadeloupe</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/venezuela">Venezuela</a> and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the agricultural sector, sugar cane and bananas are the main cash crops; a range of fruit is also grown for domestic consumption and export. Cut flowers have also become an important export earner. The processing of agricultural goods and refining of imported oil (which is also the main source of energy) are the island's main industries. <br /><br />The most important part of the economy is tourism, both as a major employer and a vital source of foreign exchange - worth some US$400 million a year to the economy. Martinique also enjoys substantial material benefits from being an integral part of the French nation, receiving financial support both from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a> and the EU. France accounts for more than 75% of Martinique's foreign trade, with the remainder of the import market captured by the major EU economies and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.<br />Facilities for business conferences are available at the Palais des Congrès Convention Centre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits are recommended. The best time to visit is January to March and June to September. A command of French is essential, as most of the island's business is connected with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1400-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Palais des Congrès (Convention Centre)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 721 515
					Website:
					Address: Madiana,Schoelcher Commune,Martinique,]]><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie de la Martinique</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 552 800
					Website:http://www.martinique.cci.fr
					Address: 50 rue Ernest Deproge,BP 478,97241 Fort-de-France,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The island's cuisine is characterised by French and Caribbean influences. Creole cuisine is also widely available and is an original combination of French, Indian and African traditions seasoned with exotic spices.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Lobster, red snapper, conch and sea urchin. <br />
&bull; Stuffed crab.<br />
&bull; Stewed conch. <br />
&bull; <em>Colombo</em> (dish of goat, chicken, pork or lamb in a thick curry sauce).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are no licensing restrictions. Meals are ended with tropical fruit.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is acceptable.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of restaurants, bars and discos and some displays of local dancing and music. The<em> Ballet Martiniquais</em> is one of the world's most prestigious traditional ballet companies. Limbo dancers and steel bands often perform at hotels in the evenings. The local music, <em>zouk</em>, lively, two-beat music similar to merengue but unique to the French West Indies, can be heard everywhere and Martinicans are very proud of it.<br />
<br />
There are two casinos, the Casino de la Bateli&egrave;re Plazza, in Schoelcher, and there is one in the M&eacute;ridien Hotel. The Fort-de-France City Hall is now a municipal theatre. The local guide, <em>Choubouloute</em>, contains information on local entertainment and is sold at newsagents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>French imports are worthwhile purchases, especially wines, liqueurs and crystal. Local items include rum, straw goods, bamboo hats, creole dolls, creole jewellery, baskets and objects of aromatic vetiver roots. A discount of 20% is given if payment is made by traveller's cheques in some tourist shops.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good selection of hotels on Martinique; 10% service is charged, sometimes with other government taxes added. The Relais de la Martinique is an association of small hotels, often called <em>Relais Créoles</em>, and guest houses offering special reservation and tour facilities. Hotels range from deluxe, to medium- and low-priced. For further information, contact the tourist office, <em>or</em> Maison de la <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good selection of hotels on Martinique; 10% service is charged, sometimes with other government taxes added. The Relais de la Martinique is an association of small hotels, often called <em>Relais Créoles</em>, and guest houses offering special reservation and tour facilities. Hotels range from deluxe, to medium- and low-priced. For further information, contact the tourist office, <em>or</em> Maison de la <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good selection of hotels on Martinique; 10% service is charged, sometimes with other government taxes added. The Relais de la Martinique is an association of small hotels, often called <em>Relais Créoles</em>, and guest houses offering special reservation and tour facilities. Hotels range from deluxe, to medium- and low-priced. For further information, contact the tourist office, <em>or</em> Maison de la <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;A reciprocal health agreement exists between &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france"&gt;France&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom"&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt;. However, the benefits which go with this agreement may not be fully available in Martinique. Check with your doctor before departure. Martinique has 18 hospitals and several specialists and clinics.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available. Drinking water outside main cities and towns may be contaminated and sterilisation is advisable. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water; swimming pools which are well chlorinated and maintained are safe.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Slavery Abolition Day :
							22 May </p><p>Schoelcher Day :
							21 July </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Martinique by travellers over the age of 17:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of spirits up to 22% volume.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine.<br />
&bull; 16L of beer.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of &euro;1,000 if arriving from mainland <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> or another EU country.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of &euro;430 if arriving from a non-EU country (or &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unauthorised firearms, counterfeit goods, plants and flowers, and endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unauthorised firearms and endangered species.</p>
<p>You must obtain an authorisation certificate to export goods of cultural value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Euro is the official currency for the French Overseas Departments (<em>D&eacute;partements d'outre-mer</em>), French Guiana, Guadeloupe, Martinique and R&eacute;union. For further details, see <em><a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/france/money-duty-free/" target="www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/france/money-duty-free/">France</a></em> section. US Dollars are also accepted in some places.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major currencies can be exchanged at banks and bureaux de change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club and Visa are accepted in the major tourist areas. Mastercard has limited acceptance. Cards can also be used in ATMs.</p><p>Cards can also be used in ATMs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted in most places, and may qualify for discounts on luxury items. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros or US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1430-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for the duration of stay in Martinique is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above, except&nbsp;nationals of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a> and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> whose passport must be valid for three months following departure.</p>
<p><strong>1. </strong>EU nationals may also&nbsp;enter with a national ID card, but check with your airline first, as you may need a passport to board the flight.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay/Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period; long-stay visa: valid for stays of over three months.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>French consulate (or consular section at embassy).&nbsp;In the UK, the consulate has outsourced the visa application process to <a href="https://fr.tlscontact.com/gb/splash.php" target="fr.tlscontact.com/gb/splash.php">TLScontact</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 15 days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EU nationals staying longer than three months are exempted from long-term entry visas and must register at the pr&eacute;fecture to apply for a <em>carte de s&eacute;jour</em>. Other nationals require a long-stay visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[14.643027]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-60.977960]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,100 sq km (425 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>396,364 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>343.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fort-de-France.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Martinique is an Overseas Department of France and as such is an integral part of the French Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The French Overseas Department of Martinique, a volcanic and picturesque island, is the northernmost of the Windward Caribbean group. The island is noticeably more rocky than those of the Leeward group, with beaches (of fine black or white or peppered sand) surrounded by sugar, palm, banana and pineapple plantations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the population is Roman Catholic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The atmosphere is generally relaxed and informal. Casual dress is acceptable everywhere, but formal attire is needed for dining out and nightclubs.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs are mainly European-style with two round pins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President of the Executive Council Alfred Marie-Jeanne since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Emmanuel Macron since 2017, represented by the prefect Franck Robine since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prior to the discovery of Martinique by Columbus in 1493, the area was inhabited by Arawak and Carib Indians. There was no real European interest in the island until French colonies were established in 1635. Though the British made brief attempts to occupy the island during the 18th and 19th centuries, it has remained under French control ever since (along with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guadeloupe">Guadeloupe</a>). Slavery was abolished in 1848 and, in the late 19th century, tens of thousands of immigrant workers arrived from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a> to replace the slave workforce on the plantations. Both Martinique and Guadeloupe were administered as parts of French Antilles. In 1946, rather than following a path to independence, the two islands were incorporated into the French nation with the status of Overseas Departments. <br />
<br />
There was little political evolution until 1974 when Martinique, along with Guadeloupe and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/french-guiana">French Guiana</a>, was granted some local political and economic autonomy. This was increased in 1982 and 1983 following a package of decentralisation policies introduced by French President Mitterand. Most affairs, with the major exceptions of defence and security, are now generally under local control. The thrust of French government policy in the region is now to bolster links between its remaining possessions, Martinique and Guadeloupe, and other French Caribbean nations. <br />
<br />
Four parties dominate the political scene in Martinique: the Gaullist RPR-UDF<i> </i>(allied to the French party of the same name), the Parti Communiste Martiniquais<i> </i>and two island-based nationalist parties, the Parti Progressiste Martiniquais<i> </i>(PPM) and the Mouvement Ind&eacute;pendantiste Martiniquais<i> </i>(MIM, which now operates under the moniker <i>P</i>atriotes Martiniquais). Martinique's political centre of gravity is generally, but not always, to the left of the French mainstream. The PPM controls the Conseil G&eacute;n&eacute;rale (elected into office in 2000), while the RPR is the majority party in the Conseil Regional (1998).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[French Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7073 1000. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambafrance-uk.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7073 1000. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>58 Knightsbridge<br/>London<br/>SW1X 7JT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[French Embassy in the USA ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 944 6000. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambafrance-us.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 944 6000. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Visa appointments are available Mon-Fri 0845-1200. Appointments can be booked online.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>4101 Reservoir Road NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When he discovered Martinique in 1493, Christopher Columbus gushed that it was &ldquo;the most beautiful country in the world&rdquo;. Since then this island has lost little of the magic that so captivated the great explorer: it remains one of the most beautiful destinations you are likely to visit.</p>
<p>Originally inhabited by Arawak and Carib Indians, who were swiftly eradicated by the French, the island has been hotly fought over. The British made numerous attempts to occupy Martinique during the 18th and 19th centuries, but it has remained defiantly French since 1635 (along with nearby Guadeloupe).&nbsp;</p>
<p>Tourism represents a major part of the local economy and each year hundreds of thousands of visitors come to enjoy Martinique's picturesque volcanic landscape, luscious rainforests and fine beaches, which are lined with sugar, palm, banana and pineapple plantations.</p>
<p>An accommodating people, most Martinicans are of mixed ancestry, being the descendants of 17th century French settlers and slaves brought from Africa to work on the island's plantations. This French and Creole heritage is infused in local customs, food and languages, which is a joy for travellers.</p>
<p>Do make sure you pack your dancing shoes. It&rsquo;s impossible to escape <em>zouk</em>, the lively, two-beat local music that is similar to <em>merengue </em>in the Dominican Republic,&nbsp;but is unique to the French West Indies. Martinicans are very proud of their <em>zouk</em>, which will provide the soundtrack to your trip.</p>
<p>If you need a bit of Dutch courage to get on the dance floor, you&rsquo;re in luck, because Martinique produces fine rum. So exceptional is the liquor, in fact, that it was awarded the prestigious French label <em>appellation d'origine controlee</em>, which was previously only reserved for mainland produce.</p><p>When he discovered Martinique in 1493, Christopher Columbus gushed that it was &ldquo;the most beautiful country in the world&rdquo;. Since then this island has lost little of the magic that so captivated the great explorer: it remains one of the most beautiful destinations you are likely to visit.</p>
<p>Originally inhabited by Arawak and Carib Indians, who were swiftly eradicated by the French, the island has been hotly fought over. The British made numerous attempts to occupy Martinique during the 18th and 19th centuries, but it has remained defiantly French since 1635.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
