<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Mauritius" ColCode="mus" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mu" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Mauritius]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritius has a tropical maritime climate, with relatively little seasonal variation in temperatures, and generally pleasant and sunny on the coast year round. Winter, from May to October is warm and dry. Summer from November to April is hot, humid and rainy. Cyclones occur between January and March. Sea breezes blow all year, especially on the east coast, and the inland central plateau around Curepipe is cooler and rainy year round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical lightweights, with warmer wear for evenings and winter months. Rainwear advisable all year round. In the summer months, sun-care products and a hat are advisable and long sleeves and trousers to help prevent insect bites.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Mauritius (<a href="http://www.airmauritius.com" target="_blank">www.airmauritius.com</a>) operates daily flights from Mauritius to Rodrigues, a small island to the east of the mainland (flight time - 1 hour 30 minutes). Air Mauritius also offers helicopter transfers and sightseeing tours (<a href="http://www.airmauritius.com/helicopter.htm" target="_blank">www.airmauritius.com/helicopter.htm</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritius Shipping Corporation runs sailings between Rodrigues Island and Port Louis (tel: +230 217 2284; <a href="http://www.mauritiusshipping.net" target="_blank">www.mauritiusshipping.net</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One major highway runs north to south, otherwise a good network of paved, if sometimes narrow, roads cover the island.</p><p>These are regulated and metered and linked to provinces or hotels, printed on a yellow panel on the drivers' door. Tips are not customary for taxi drivers, but appreciated.</p><p>A foreign licence is accepted.</p><p>Drivers are required to be over 23 years old. Speed limits are 110kph (68mph) on motorways, 80kph (50mph) on other non-urban roads and 40kph (25mph) in built-up areas. Seatbelts must be worn.</p><p>Numerous car hire companies include major international and independent firms.</p><p>Drivers are required to be over 23 years old. Speed limits are 110kph (68mph) on motorways, 80kph (50mph) on other non-urban roads and 40kph (25mph) in built-up areas. Seatbelts must be worn.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bus and taxi services are best used in urban areas. Bicycles and motorbikes are also available for hire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Mauritius</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">mahebourg_southeast</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Mauritius</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">grand_baie_north</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Mauritius</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">curepipe</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier is Air Mauritius (<a href="http://www.airmauritius.com">www.airmauritius.com</a>), which has daily flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London Heathrow</a>. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com">www.ba.com</a>) also flies directly from London Heathrow.&nbsp;There is no cheap time to fly to Mauritius, so in general terms book early to get the best fares and avoid Christmas.</p>
<p>Major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mauitius">Mauritius Sir Seewoosagur Ramgoolam International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 12 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 20 hours 15 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Mauritius Sir Seewoosagur Ramgoolam International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://mauritius-airport.atol.aero<p>Sir Seewoosagur Ramgoolam International Airport is located 6km (4 miles) from Mah&eacute;bourg and 40km (25 miles) southeast of the capital, Port Louis.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+230 603 6000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:&nbsp;</strong>Port Louis  is primarily commercial, but there is a limited passenger service to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/madagascar">Madagascar</a>, R&eacute;union and Rodrigues Island; contact Mauritius Shipping Corporation (tel: +230 217 2284; <a href="http://www.mauritiusshipping.net" target="_blank">www.mauritiusshipping.net</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes. There are a limited number of public telephone booths, mainly at the airport and in major hotels. Mauritius Telecom (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.mauritiustelecom.com/">www.mauritiustelecom.com</a>) offers a good, reliable service and payphones are found in their customer service centres in towns around the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements with international mobile phone companies are available and coverage extends over the entire island. Local mobile calls are the same as the price of landline calls, so it&rsquo;s worth buying a local SIM card for your handset if you plan to make more than a few phone calls on the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet caf&eacute;s in both main towns and tourist centres such as Grand Baie and Port Louis. Most hotels offer wireless Internet access.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritius has a free press, which means the media is full of colourful debate. The main language is French, but all the languages are represented in a variety of media, from Chinese newspapers to Bollywood movies. Some UK newspapers are available in their international editions at larger resorts and at big price mark ups.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe usually takes seven days; by sea, mail takes four to six weeks.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0815-1115 and 1200-1600, Sat 0815-1145.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask on beautiful beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It's no exaggeration to say beaches are everywhere on Mauritius. Some of our favourite spots are on the northern beaches such as Trou aux Biches, shaded by tall casuarinas trees. Mont Choisy, a 2km (1.2 mile) stretch of white sand curves north from here, while between Grand Baie and Cap Malheureux lies the small cove of Péreybère.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the marvellous Moka Range</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the Moka Range by quad bike, horse or a 4-wheel drive. For spectacular 360-degree views of Port Louis make the easy two-hour climb of Le Pouce, Mauritius' third highest mountain, which reaches a height of 812m (2,664ft). The village of La Laura is the best place to start the hike.</p>]]><p><b>Follow the pilgrimage route to Grand Bassin</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Grand Bassin's pilgrimage route leads pilgrims to a natural crater lake and sacred Hindu site on the Plaine Champagne. A towering statue of Shiva 33m (108ft) high heralds the entrance to the colourfully-decorated temples, busy with people and heavy with the scent of burning incense come festival time.</p>]]><p><b>Get your adrenaline fix on Grand Baie</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A seaside village with a beautiful beach and emerald waters, Grand Baie has become the centre of the island's watersports industry, with parasailing, underwater walks, submarine excursions and semi-submersible scooters all available. At La Cuvette, a long silky beach with clear water between Grand Baie and Cap Malheureux, sailors, windsurfers and waterskiers are welcomed<strong>.</strong></p>]]><p><b>Hike in Black River Gorges National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Black River Gorges National Park, a 6,800-hectare (17,000 acre) forest, provides a habitat for indigenous plants, birds and wildlife. It's also home to Little Black River Peak, Mauritius' highest mountain, which reaches for the sky at 830m (2,700ft). Hike to the summit or take the Maccabee Trail, which slopes down to the leafy banks of the Black River.</p>]]><p><b>Learn to dive in pristine waters</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Diving centres exist all along Mauritius' coast, to the west around Flic-en-Flac, in the north at Trou aux Biches, and on the Northern Islands to name just a handful of locations. The good underwater visibility, warm seas, and bountiful sea life make this one of the world's top diving destinations.</p>]]><p><b>Let your imagination run riot at Le Souffleur</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Unusually for reef-protected Mauritius, the full force of the ocean strikes its southern coast, leading to otherworldly rock formations. A cave in cliffs around Souillac at Le Souffleur helps funnel waves into a geyser 20m (65ft) high. A natural rock bridge exists at Pont Naturel, and at the clifftops of Gris Gris sits a rock shaped like a witch.</p>]]><p><b>Peer through you binoculars on Ile aux Aigrettes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This Ile aux Aigrettes nature reserve lies off the coast of Mauritius and is home to several species that you will struggle to find anywhere else in the world, including the pink pigeon, giant Aldabra tortoises and Telfair's skink. 90 minute visits to the island leave daily from near Mahébourg.</p>]]><p><b>Photograph the coloured earth of Chamarel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An extraordinary natural phenomenon, the famous coloured earths of Chamarel are believed to have been formed by various rock strata cooling at different speeds following volcanic activity here millions of years ago. They're certainly a beautiful sight, and the picture-perfect waterfall nearby is another reason to make the trip.</p>]]><p><b>Relax on Rodrigues Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tiny, rugged, volcanic Rodrigues Island lies 560km (350 miles) east of Mauritius and is known as the 'anti-stress' island. Its capital, Port Mathurin, is only seven streets wide, with a friendly Creole population. Rodrigues offers walking, diving, kitesurfing, deep sea fishing and fabulously empty white sand beaches.</p>]]><p><b>Set sail for the Northern Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a speedboat from Trou d'eau Douce to the popular island playground of Ile aux Cerfs for clean solitary beaches, golf and watersports. For a quieter day, take a catamaran through the crystal clear lagoons to the Northern Islands – Gabriel and Flat Island and Gunner's Quoin.</p>]]><p><b>Spend the day at The Crocodile Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The family friendly, La Vanille Réserve des Mascareignes nature park is commonly referred to as The Crocodile Park, for its thousands of Nile crocodiles. It is the only place worldwide to breed Radiata and Aldabra giant tortoises and also has deer, monkeys, boar, an insectarium, aquarium and small museum.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll around Pamplemousses Garden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pamplemousses Botanical Garden is the third oldest botanical gardens in the world and oldest in the southern hemisphere, having been created in 1770. Its international collection of plants includes a long pond of giant Amazon lilies and the talipot palm, which flowers once every 60 years, then dies.</p>]]><p><b>Take a walking tour of Port Louis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A walk around the capital, Port Louis, offers the chance of encountering interesting attractions inside and out. It's worth exploring the fine colonial architecture of buildings such as Government House, which sits atop the palm-lined Place d'Armes, before popping into the Blue Penny Museum to gaze at one of the world's rarest stamps, or gawk at dodo skeletons in the Natural History Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Take to the water at Blue Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Swim, snorkel or take a glass-bottomed boat out to see the fish and more than 50 species of coral in Blue Bay, Mauritius' only marine park. Better still, take a luxury excursion to the private island, Iles des Deux Cocos, just off the coast to explore the park from there.</p>]]><p><b>Tour Mahébourg’s colonial past</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The most characterful town on the island, Mahébourg, has a lively market, slowly mouldering colonial buildings and stalls on the new waterfront offering spicy <em>gajaks </em>(snacks) and a view across the bay of Grand Port, the site of the 1810 naval skirmish between the British and victorious French, and Lion Mountain.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Mauritius Aquarium</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mauritius Aquarium, in the island's northwest in the village of Pointe Aux Piments, provides artificial habitats for 200 species of fish, invertebrates, coral and sponges originating from the waters around the island in five main buildings surrounded by tropical gardens. It also has a touch pool for children.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around the National History Museum in Mahébourg</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The colonial mansion now containing the National History Museum in Mahébourg contains a number of important island artefacts including the bell from the San Géran shipwreck that inspired Mauritius' most famous romantic legend, <em>Paul et Virginie</em>. There are also rooms dedicated to the Dutch, French and British periods of colonial rule.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$12.2 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Clothing and textiles, sugar, cut flowers, canned tuna and molasses.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Manufactured goods, capital equipment, foodstuff, petroleum products and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, UK and other EU countries such as Germany and Finland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Historically, sugar has dominated Mauritius' agricultural economy and today accounts for 25% of export earnings. Since independence in 1968, the government has deliberately sought to diversify by developing the industrial and service components of the economy.<br />
<br />
The island's industrial capacity is centred on a number of Export Processing Zones and its service economy is based on tourism and financial services, as well as a growing telecommunications provision which has attracted more than 9,000 offshore entities. Tourism is well established and now worth over US$500 million annually. Investment in banking is more than US$1 billion. The overall economy grew at 3.6% in 2016, with inflation at 1.3% and unemployment 7.6%.<br />
<br />
The government's economic policy aims to counter the threat to the two largest sectors of the economy (sugar and textiles) from new regulations introduced by the World Trade Organization. The centrepiece of its strategy is the creation of a custom-built 'cyber-city', based on similar development in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>, using high-speed communications links to offer e-commerce and financial transactions.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Mauritius is a member of the Indian Ocean Commission, which promotes regional economic cooperation, and of the Southern African Development Community.<br />
With its fabulous hotels and great beaches, sunshine and high quality food, ecotourism offerings and more, Mauritius is courting the conference and incentive market. An International Conference and Exhibition Centre opened in 2004, which with a capacity of 2,500 is the largest in the Indian Ocean.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits are usually worn in business circles. As a multicultural island, business etiquette varies between communities. But in all business transactions, hospitality and personal relationships are central here.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1600, Sat 0900-1200 (some offices only).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Mauritius Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 208 3301
					Website:http://www.mcci.org/
					Address: ,3 Royal Street,Port Louis,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Standards of cuisine, richly infused with French, Creole, Indian, Chinese and even English influences, are generally very high, but fruit, meat, vegetables and even ever-popular fresh seafood are often imported.</p>
<p>The range of influences gives Mauritian dishes a range from curries to coq au vin, via noodles and English bacon, while the basic ingredients of Creole dishes are tomatoes, onion, ginger and a mild spice palate.</p>
<p>Full of unique flavours as a result of centuries as a melting point, Mauritian cuisine helps define and unify an otherwise diverse population and its history.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Achard</strong>: Relish of pickled vegetables with mustard.<br />
<strong>Camarons: </strong>Freshwater prawns in a hot sauce.<br />
<strong>Fish vindaye</strong>: Curried fish with mustard, garlic, ginger and onion. It is served with rice and pickled vegetables.<br />
<strong>Dholl puri</strong>: Wheat pancake stuffed with ground peas and served with curry.<br />
<strong>Rougaille</strong>: Popular Creole tomato stew with meat or fish, garlic, onion and thyme.<br />
<strong>Mine frites</strong>: Soy sauce fried noodles with spring onions and chilli.<br />
<strong>Manioc goujons</strong>: Deep-fried cassava chips served as a street snack.<br />
<strong>Mazavaroo</strong>: Hot finely chopped chillies or chilli paste served with almost every meal.<br />
<strong>Gateaux piments</strong>: Lentil and chilli fritters.<br />
<strong>Daube de poulet</strong>: Fried chicken stewed with tomato, onion and spices.<br />
<strong>Bol renverse</strong>: Layer of rice followed by pork, chicken or fish, then vegetables all topped with a fried egg or omelette.<br />
<strong>Phoenix: </strong>A local lager.<br />
<strong>Rum</strong>: Commonly supped brands include Green Island and Pink Pigeon.<br />
<strong>Alouda</strong>: Almond-flavoured milk drink.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is usual in most hotels and restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritius isn&rsquo;t really a destination for great nightlife, though the best of what there is can be found in and around Grand Baie, where you&rsquo;ll find lively bars, live music, restaurants and nightclubs. Port Louis has mainly restaurants and bars, but is neither very busy nor particularly safe after dark beyond the Caudan Waterfront. Rivi&egrave;re Noire is a Creole fishermen's district where<em> sega</em> dancing is especially lively on Saturday nights. <em>Sega</em> troupes give performances at most hotels. Gamblers are lavishly catered for; casinos are among the island's attractions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritius has abolished taxes on most shopping items, meaning that it&rsquo;s a great place to come to buy luxury goods, such as designer clothing, jewellery, perfume and electrical goods. Tourist shopping centres are located around the island, with a good selection of designer shops at the Caudan Waterfront complex in Port Louis, as well as in the smart resort town of Grand Baie.  For real bargain hunters, join the locals at the textile markets and clothing factory outlet stores of Curepipe, Quatre-Bornes and Rose-Hill. In terms of traditional handicrafts, Mauritius offers little of huge interest, with the possible exception of locally produced baskets, tea, spices and fabrics. Another popular souvenir are model ships, for which Mauritius is famous.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0930-1700. Some shops are open until 1200 on Sundays and public holidays. Markets usually close around 1600. Shops in Rose-Hill, Curepipe and Quatre-Bornes close on Thursday afternoons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The line between hotels and resorts in Mauritius can be fairly blurred, but there are many large, self-contained beach resorts offering every service and amenity from babysitting to windsurfing. Most resorts are scattered along the country&rsquo;s best beaches &ndash; particularly along the south coast and the east coasts.</p>
<p>There is an abundance of hotels throughout the island, most of them hugging the coast. Mauritius standards and service are known to be the best in the Indian Ocean.<br />
<br />
From June to September, and during the Christmas and Easter holidays, reservations should be made in advance. A 10% tax is added to all hotel bills.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Although there is no official grading system away from the international chains, many of whom have hotels on the island, Mauritius has a higher density of 5-star hotels than anywhere else in the world. Most of Mauritius' hotel inventory is 4 and 5 star; even 3-star hotels provide a 5-star welcome.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are also plenty of budget options, increasing with the trend for visitors to book over the Internet. These include family-run chambre d'h&ocirc;tes, self-catering <em>campements</em> or weekend houses, beach bungalows and villas and lodges or even rental of colonial outhouses in the interior. They can be found throughout the island, although mainly in tourist centres - in the north around Grand Baie and in the west around Flic-en-Flac.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>So called <em>chambre d&rsquo;h&ocirc;te</em> accommodation (the French equivalent of bed and breakfast) is an extremely popular and excellent value option. These rooms tend to be of higher quality and in more charming surroundings than the term &lsquo;bed and breakfast&rsquo; suggests in English &ndash; the very best are downright luxurious. Many also offer <em>table d&rsquo;h&ocirc;te</em>, or a lavish home cooked meal hosted by the owners &ndash; a great way to meet fellow travellers and locals in a relaxed and friendly setting.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The line between hotels and resorts in Mauritius can be fairly blurred, but there are many large, self-contained beach resorts offering every service and amenity from babysitting to windsurfing. Most resorts are scattered along the country&rsquo;s best beaches &ndash; particularly along the south coast and the east coasts.</p>
<p>There is an abundance of hotels throughout the island, most of them hugging the coast. Mauritius standards and service are known to be the best in the Indian Ocean.<br />
<br />
From June to September, and during the Christmas and Easter holidays, reservations should be made in advance. A 10% tax is added to all hotel bills.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Although there is no official grading system away from the international chains, many of whom have hotels on the island, Mauritius has a higher density of 5-star hotels than anywhere else in the world. Most of Mauritius' hotel inventory is 4 and 5 star; even 3-star hotels provide a 5-star welcome.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are also plenty of budget options, increasing with the trend for visitors to book over the Internet. These include family-run chambre d'h&ocirc;tes, self-catering <em>campements</em> or weekend houses, beach bungalows and villas and lodges or even rental of colonial outhouses in the interior. They can be found throughout the island, although mainly in tourist centres - in the north around Grand Baie and in the west around Flic-en-Flac.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The line between hotels and resorts in Mauritius can be fairly blurred, but there are many large, self-contained beach resorts offering every service and amenity from babysitting to windsurfing. Most resorts are scattered along the country&rsquo;s best beaches &ndash; particularly along the south coast and the east coasts.</p>
<p>There is an abundance of hotels throughout the island, most of them hugging the coast. Mauritius standards and service are known to be the best in the Indian Ocean.<br />
<br />
From June to September, and during the Christmas and Easter holidays, reservations should be made in advance. A 10% tax is added to all hotel bills.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Although there is no official grading system away from the international chains, many of whom have hotels on the island, Mauritius has a higher density of 5-star hotels than anywhere else in the world. Most of Mauritius' hotel inventory is 4 and 5 star; even 3-star hotels provide a 5-star welcome.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are also plenty of budget options, increasing with the trend for visitors to book over the Internet. These include family-run chambre d'h&ocirc;tes, self-catering <em>campements</em> or weekend houses, beach bungalows and villas and lodges or even rental of colonial outhouses in the interior. They can be found throughout the island, although mainly in tourist centres - in the north around Grand Baie and in the west around Flic-en-Flac.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Public medical facilities are numerous and of a high standard and there are several inexpensive private clinics, mostly staffed by doctors educated in the west. There is no reciprocal health agreement with the UK; foreign visitors have to pay at state-run clinics and hospitals. Emergency evacuation health insurance is advised for those at serious risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; For travellers applying for a working visa or permanent residence, a HIV test will be required.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water for drinking should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Bottled water is readily available. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Dysentery, typhoid and hepatitis B occur, and meningococcal meningitis&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is a risk from December to June. More common is dengue fever and around 5,000 cases of chikungunya virus have been reported - precautionary measures should be taken, especially in summer (Oct to May). Stonefish stings are uncommon but can be fatal.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>(a) Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.<br /><br />(b) Hindu festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Abolition of Slavery Day :
							01 February </p><p>National Day :
							12 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Anniversary of the Arrival of Indentured Labourers :
							02 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Mauritius by travellers aged 18 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 250g of tobacco products.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits and 2L of wine, ale or beer, or 2L of spirits if no wine, ale or beer.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine, ale or beer if no sprits.</p>
<p>&bull; Other goods to the value of Rs 15,000 (Mauritians under 12 years old or foreigners) or Rs 30,000 (Mauritians over 12 years old).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include plant and plant products, underwater fishing guns, ivory and tortoise shell, second-hand motor vehicle spare parts, toy pistols and guns with projectiles, toy known as &ldquo;Water Ball Yo-Yo&rdquo;, illegal drugs, obscene literature and pornographic materials.</p>
<p>Restricted items requiring a permit include arms and ammunition, and endangered species.</p>
<p>You must declare all fruits and vegetables, plants and seeds, handicrafts made from animal parts (e.g. bone or feathers), wooden items, and outdoor equipment which may contain traces of soil such as camping gear, golf clubs, bikes and sports shoes.</p>
<p>If carrying prescription medicines, you must bring a copy of the prescription and ensure the medicines are in the original, labelled container.</p>
<p>You can find more prohibited imports information at <a href="http://www.mra.mu/index.php/import-export-others/import/prohibited-goods" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.mra.mu</a>. <br />
You can find more restricted imports information at <a href="http://www.mra.mu/index.php/import-export-others/travellers/91-import-restrictions" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.mra.mu</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Scrap metal is a prohibited export.</p>
<p>Restricted exports include live animals (including birds), fresh and dried vegetables, what or muslin flour, sugar, sand, animal organs and rough diamonds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritian Rupee (MUR; symbol Rp) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of Rp2,000, 1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50 and 25. Coins are in denominations of Rp10, 5 and 1.</p>
<p>Please note that payments in cash as well as cash deposits are prohibited for sums exceeding the equivalent of Rp500,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in banks and at bureaux de change. A better rate of exchange can be obtained on traveller's cheques than on cash. Mauritius Commercial Bank is reputed to have the quickest service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mastercard and Visa are the most widely accepted by most banks, hotels, restaurants and tourist shops followed by American Express and Diners Club. ATMs are widespread.</p><p>ATMs are widespread.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>May be exchanged at banks, hotels and authorised dealers, but generally difficult to do.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thu 0900-1500, Fri 0900-1700. Banks are also open to coincide with the arrival and departure of international flights at the Sir Seewoosagur Ramgoolam Airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Mauritius, a passport valid for the duration of stay with at least one blank page is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For those nationals who do require a visa, some nationals are granted a two-week or 60-day visa on arrival, while others need to obtain a visa in advance; check with the embassy/high commission. Visas and extensions are issued free of charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy/high commission).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applicants who require a visa should allow an average of five working days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors who do require a visa must be able to show proof of having at least US$100 per day to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To extend your stay, you should contact the Passport and Immigration Office (<a href="http://passport.govmu.org">http://passport.govmu.org</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-20.219992]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[57.588975]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,030 sq km (783 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,265,946 (2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>623 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Port Louis.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritius, a volcanic and mountainous island in the Indian Ocean, lies 2,000km (1,240 miles) off the south-eastern coast of Africa, due east of Madagascar. The island state stands on what was once a land bridge between Asia and Africa called the Mascarene Archipelago. From the coast, the land rises to form a broad fertile plain on which sugar cane flourishes and beyond, crater edges form a mountainous backbone. Some 500km (310 miles) east is Rodrigues Island, while northeast are the Cargados Carajos Shoals and 900km (560 miles) to the north is Agalega.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>52% Hindu, 31% Christian (mainly Roman Catholic), 15% Muslim and 2% other.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the customary form of greeting. Visitors should respect the traditions of their hosts, particularly when visiting a private house. The type of hospitality the visitor receives is determined by the religion and social customs of the host, which are closely related. It is appropriate to give a gift as a small token of appreciation if invited for a meal. Dress is normally informal although men will need to wear a suit for particularly formal occasions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are commonly used in hotels; you can often find European-style sockets (two round pins) as well.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Pravind Jugnauth since January 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Acting President Barlen Vyapoory since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Due to its sheer remoteness Mauritius was completely uninhabited until the 16th century, though it had been visited by Arab trading vessels during the Middle Ages.</p>
<p>Sailors from Portugal were the first modern Europeans to set foot on the island, setting up a trading centre around 1510. It was finally colonised by a small Dutch force sailing into Grand Port in 1638. They named the island after Prince Maurice of Nassau, a member of the Dutch royal family, and sought to take advantage of what natural resources were available, including ebony and sugar cane.</p>
<p>With the Dutch failing to make the colony a success, Mauritius was left uninhabited again in 1710, only to be re-colonised five years later by the French, who imported African slaves to work on the sugar plantations. Mauritius was captured by the British during the Napoleonic Wars (1803-1815), after Britain became tired of its commercial ships being attacked by vessels based there. It became part of the British Empire in 1814 while retaining many of its French influences including the language and law.</p>
<p>After the abolition of slavery in the 1830s, Indian labourers were brought to the island, and their descendants now comprise more than two-thirds of the population, further contributing to today&rsquo;s impressive ethnic diversity.</p>
<p>Mauritius remained a British colony until 1957, when it was granted internal self-government with an electoral system based on the Westminster model. Queen Elizabeth II remained head of state. The first election based on the principles of adult universal suffrage was held in 1959, and won by the Labour Party. Despite being British for almost 150 years, French influence from the early 19th century continued to dominate the island&rsquo;s culture.</p>
<p>Full independence was granted in 1968, when the independence movement, led by Sir Seewoosagur Ramgoolam, finally triumphed, though Queen Elizabeth II remained head of state until 1992 when a presidential republic was declared. Post-independence Mauritian politics have been dominated by the Ramgoolam family (Navin Ramgoolam, the prime minister since 1995 is the son of Sir Seewoosagur) and by the two principal figures of the Mauritian Left, Paul B&eacute;renger and Sir Anerood Jugnauth.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Boxer Bruno Julie gave the island its first Olympic medal at the Beijing Games in 2008.<br />
&bull;	Because of its small size, Mauritius is the most densely populated country in Africa.<br />
&bull;	Despite being extinct for 350 years, the Dodo is the island&rsquo;s national bird.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Mauritius in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 244 1491.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 244 1491.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1709 N St NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mauritius High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7581 0294.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7581 0294.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1300 and 1400-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Kensington<br/>32/33 Elvaston Pl <br/>London<br/>SW7 5NW<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Mauritius]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>202 9400.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-high-commission-port-louis</p><p><b>Tel:</b>202 9400.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0745-1545; Fri 0745-1345.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Edith Cavell Street<br/>7th floor, Cascades Building<br/>Port Louis<br/>P.O. box 1063<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A hypnotic blend of Indian, African and European influences, Mauritius might be synonymous with luxury beach breaks, but this destination will dazzle even the most discerning traveller, with its superb hiking, excellent mountain climbing and world-class diving.</p>
<p>The beaches are, indeed, noteworthy of praise. Encircling the island, they are exactly what the holiday brochures promise. But beyond its celebrated sands, native forests grow over the cooler central plateau, providing a home to rare plants and animals such as the Mauritius flying fox, which can be found nowhere else on Earth.</p>
<p>Back on the coast, a massive coral reef surrounds almost the entire island and has become a Mecca for divers thanks to its bountiful marine life. Hop out of the water and into local culture along the east coast, which is home to fine beaches and sleepy fishing communities. Village such as Petite Julie and Queen Victoria demonstrate the mixed Anglo-French heritage of the country, and it is in these sleepy outposts that you can hear <em>sega</em> music played in its most traditional form.</p>
<p>The northern regions offer the best combination of beaches, cuisine and nightlife. Further west, the capital, Port Louis, is famed for its Caudan Waterfront complex of restaurants, shops and casinos, as well as the colonial-era central market and Places D&rsquo;Armes.</p>
<p>Dolphin safaris, rum distilleries and sand dunes add to the west&rsquo;s appeal, though for many visitors the star attraction here is Le Morne mountain, which was used as a hideout by runaway slaves. A UNESCO World Heritage Site, this rugged outcrop has become synonymous with the struggle for freedom.</p>
<p>Friendly, welcoming and unremittingly beautiful, Mauritius offers not only fantastic weather and exquisite beaches, but also a distinct cultural identity that is well worth exploring.</p><p>A hypnotic blend of Indian, African and European influences, Mauritius might be synonymous with luxury beach breaks, but this destination will dazzle even the most discerning traveller, with its superb hiking, excellent mountain climbing and world-class diving.</p>
<p>The beaches are, indeed, noteworthy of praise. Encircling the island, they are exactly what the holiday brochures promise. But beyond its celebrated sands, native forests grow over the cooler central plateau, providing a home to rare plants and animals such as the Mauritius flying fox, which can be found nowhere else on Earth.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
