<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Mauritania" ColCode="mrt" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mr" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Mauritania]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the country is hot and dry with practically no rain. In the south, however, rainfall is higher with a rainy season which runs from July to September. The coast is tempered by trade winds and is mild with the exception of the hot Nouakchott region (where the rainy season begins a month later). Deserts are cooler and windy in March and April.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens, with a warm wrap for cool evenings. Waterproofs are necessary for the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritania Airlines International (<a href="http://www.mauritaniaairlines.mr" target="_blank">www.mauritaniaairlines.mr</a>) is the only airline in the country which does domestic flights. It's possible to charter light aircraft.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a line between Nou&acirc;dhibou and Zou&eacute;rat provided by the national mining company, SNIM, to serve the ore mines. Passenger cars are sometimes attached to trains and some passengers ride in empty freight cars; journeys are long and arduous. You need to buy a ticket in advance for the passenger car.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers should never attempt any desert journey without a full set of spare parts and essential safety equipment. Travelling in convoy is recommended, and make sure you have plenty of water and fuel.</p>
<p>Driving standards are poor.</p>r<p>There are adequate roads linking Nouakchott with Rosso in the south of the country, N&eacute;ma in the southeast and Akjoujt in the north.&nbsp;La Route de l'Espoir, a paved highway, runs east from Nouakchott to Mali.&nbsp;All other routes are sand tracks requiring 4-wheel drive vehicles.</p>
<p>In some regions during and after the rainy season roads may become impassable.&nbsp;Similarly, in the dry season tracks can be obscured by drifting sand; a guide is highly recommended, if not essential.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is recommended.</p><p>Available in Nouakchott, Nou&acirc;dhibou and At&acirc;r. 4-wheel drive vehicles with a driver can be hired and are recommended, but they are expensive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taxis are plentiful but expensive in towns (Nouakchott and Nouadhibou). Fares are set, not metered, and a small tip is expected.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritania's national carrier is Mauritania Airlines International (<a href="http://www.mauritaniaairlines.mr" target="_blank">www.mauritaniaairlines.mr</a>). Other airlines serving Mauritania include Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) from Paris and Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>) from Casablanca, which both offer connections from the UK and the USA. Travellers from the USA can also fly with Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) to Dakar, Senegal and catch a connecting flight to Nouakchott with Mauritania Airlines.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 8 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 15 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Nouadhibou Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 4km (2.5 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Nouakchott International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 5km (3 miles) east of the city (journey time - 20 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The principal port is Nouadhibou and there is a small port at Nouakchott, while St Louis in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/senegal">Senegal</a> also serves Mauritania.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Outgoing international calls must go through the operator.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone operators. Coverage is limited to urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several Internet cafes in Nouakchott.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritania's TV and radio stations are state-owned. As such, coverage favours the government and opposition access to is limited. Newspapers are in French and Arabic. Under press law, newspapers can be banned for publishing material that is perceived to threaten national security or undermine Islam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International postal facilities are limited to main cities. Airmail to Europe takes approximately two weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Cool off in a desert oasis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Atâr, capital of the Adrar Region, an oasis lying on the route of salt caravans. It is the market centre for the nomads of northern Mauritania and has an old quarter, the Ksar, with flat-roofed houses and a fine palm grove.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mauritania's coast is essentially one long sandy beach that's almost devoid of vegetation, but supports an astonishingly varied population of birds. Inland, the landscape is empty desert. If you have a 4x4 vehicle it is possible to drive along the beach, tide depending.</p>]]><p><b>Go birdwatching in the Parc National du Banc d'Arguin</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mauritania's best attraction is the spectacular Parc National du Banc d'Arguin. A vast area of islands and coastline located on the Atlantic coast, it is one of the world's largest bird sanctuaries and a UNESCO World Heritage Site. There are also several archaeological sites on the islands.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Nouâdhibou</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover the port town of Nouâdhibou, the centre of Mauritania's fishing industry, which is situated on a peninsula at the northern end of the Bay of Levrier. Attractions include bustling markets, the resident monk seals and a ship graveyard.</p>]]><p><b>Make the most of the Atlantic</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mauritania has a long Atlantic coastline and visitors should make the most of the water. There are good spots for fishing, swimming and surfing along the coast in the west. Remote and deserted beaches can be found near Nouâdhibou, but there is a risk of landmines in the area so take local advice.</p>]]><p><b>Spot a rare monk seal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The monk seal is an endangered species and one of the last and largest remaining colonies is on the Cap Blanc peninsular in Mauritania. They are relatively large seals with adults weighing 300kg or more. If you are lucky you can see seals from the cliffs.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll around Nouakchott</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The capital city, Nouakchott, was created in 1960, but maintains the traditional Berber style of architecture. It lies near the sea in a desert landscape of low dunes and adjoins the Ksar, an old Moorish settlement. Don't miss the Plage du Wharf, the Ksar and its market, the African market and the camel market, the crafts centre, the Maison de la Culture and the carpet factory.</p>]]><p><b>Take in some archaeological sites</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the Affolé and Assaba regions, south and southeast of the Tagant, via Kiffa, Tamchakett and Ayoun el Atrous, to the wild plateaux of El Agher. Interesting archaeological sites include Koumbi Saleh, once capital of the Ghana Empire, 70km (45 miles) from Timbedra.</p>]]><p><b>Visit a fortified medieval town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the UNESCO World Heritage Site at Oualata, once among the greatest caravan markets of the Sahara. A fortified medieval town built in terraces up a rocky peak, it has for centuries been a place of refuge for scholars. There is a manuscript museum with examples of calligraphy on ancient scrolls. Tirzet and its Muslim cemetery are nearby.</p>]]><p><b>Visit a holy city</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take an excursion over the breath-taking mountain pass of Homogjar to Chinguetti, a holy city of Islam founded in the 13th century and now listed as a UNESCO World Heritage Site. The city has a medieval mosque and a library housing ancient manuscripts. It used to be a stopover for pilgrims on their way to Mecca but today much of the city is buried under sand dunes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$1.6 billion (2006).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Iron ore, fish and fish products and gold.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, petroleum products, capital goods, food and consumer goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, France, Italy, USA and Belgium.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>More than half the population is engaged in subsistence agriculture, mostly in the Senegal River valley. The quantities produced are insufficient to meet domestic needs and Mauritania relies on imports of basic foodstuffs. <br /><br />Mining is Mauritania's principal industry. There are plans to exploit the country's copper reserves, which were long thought uneconomic, as well as newly located diamond deposits. Offshore drilling for oil and gas fields has begun. <br /><br />Nonetheless, Mauritania's financial position remains precarious and it will remain an exceptionally poor country for the foreseeable future and a major aid recipient, with other Arab countries as the main donors. The economy grew by 5.4% in 2005; inflation was 17.1% in the same year.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Use forms of address as for France, eg 'Monsieur le Directeur'. It is essential that businesspeople have a sound knowledge of French, as very few executives speak English.<br /></p><p>Sun-Thurs 0800-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce, d'Agriculture, d'Elevage, d'Industrie et des Mines de Mauritanie</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 252 214
					Website:
					Address: BP 215,Avenue de la Republique,Nouakchott,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Moroccan, Lebanese, Chinese, Italian and French restaurants can be found in the capital and in Nouadhibou. Local cuisine, based on lamb, goat and rice can be sampled throughout the country. Food is often served in one big dish which all diners help themselves with their hands. Meals have improved with better distribution of food throughout the country.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Thieboudienne:</strong> Considered the national dish. It is fish and rice in a sauce usually made from tomatoes.<br />
<strong>Yassa chicken:</strong> Common in other parts of West Africa too, this is chicken cooked in a sauce made with onions and tomatoes.<br />
<strong>Mahfe or Maffe:</strong> Usually goat or camel meat in a peanut, okra and tomato sauce served with rice.<br />
<strong>Mechoui:</strong> Whole roasted lamb.<br />
<strong>Couscous:</strong> Made from millet, wheat or barley flour and usually served with meat.<br />
<strong>Harira:</strong> A soup, also served in Morocco, made from tomatoes, chickpeas, lentils, onions, rice and eggs. It can include meat.<br />
<strong>Hakko:</strong> A sauce of ground bean leaves, which tastes like spinach, is served over couscous.<br />
<strong>Dates:</strong> Delicious and popular in Mauritania.<br />
<strong>Zrig: </strong>Camel milk.<br />
<strong>Jus de Bouye:</strong> A drink made from the fruits of baobab trees.<br />
<strong>Tea:</strong> Sweet green tea with mint is a big thing in Mauritania severed after most meals. It is usually poured from a height to create froth.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Consumption of alcohol is prohibited by the Islamic faith, but alcoholic beverages may be found in hotel bars.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>12 to 15% is normal.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol is official prohibited</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handicrafts such as dyed leather cushions and some engraved silver items, rugs and woodcarvings can be bought on the open market. A fine selection of silver jewellery, daggers, wood and silver chests, carpets and decorated nomad tents can be bought in the crafts centre in Nouakchott. <br />
<br />
Unique to the Tagant region are neolithic arrowheads, awls and pottery, while at Boutilimit in the south is a Marabout centre (Institute of High Islamic Studies) where fine carpets of goat and camel hair are made.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0800-1200 and 1400-1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel accommodation is very limited in Mauritania and visitors are advised to book well in advance. The larger hotels in Nouakchott are comfortable and have air conditioning but, even in the capital, accommodation is limited and expensive. Bills normally include service and local tax.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are numerous government rest houses throughout the country, bookable through the Ministère du Commerce de l'Artisanat et du Tourisme (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel accommodation is very limited in Mauritania and visitors are advised to book well in advance. The larger hotels in Nouakchott are comfortable and have air conditioning but, even in the capital, accommodation is limited and expensive. Bills normally include service and local tax.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel accommodation is very limited in Mauritania and visitors are advised to book well in advance. The larger hotels in Nouakchott are comfortable and have air conditioning but, even in the capital, accommodation is limited and expensive. Bills normally include service and local tax.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are very limited. Nouakchott boasts the country's best medical facilities with many doctors, most in private practices or clinics, and plenty of chemists stocking most existing French medicines. Health insurance, to include cover for emergency repatriation, is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Avoid swimming or paddling in fresh water due to the risk of Bilharzia; swimming pools that are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. Cholera is a serious risk and precautions are essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Korité (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Korité itself. Korité and Tabaski (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>African Liberation Day (Anniversary of the OAU's Foundation) :
							25 May </p><p>Armed Forces Day :
							10 July </p><p>Independence Day :
							28 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items can be imported into Mauritania by travellers of 18 years of age and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 25 cigars or 450g of tobacco. <br />
&bull; 50ml of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol, pork and pork products.</p>
<p>Sporting guns require an import and gun licence from the Home Ministry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A single Mauritanian Ouguiya (MRU) = 5 khoums. Notes are in denominations of MRU1,000, 500, 200, 100 and 50. Coins are in denominations of MRU20, 10, 5, 1 and 0.2 Ouguiya.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency declaration forms are issued on arrival and should be kept. US dollars and euros can be exchanged at the airport, at the main banks in Nouakchott, in some hotels or at official bureaux de change. It is illegal to exchange money on the black market.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards can be used in a few hotels in Nouakchott and Nouadhibou. There are some hotels that only accept Visa cards.</p><p>There are very few ATMs, but some do accept foreign credit or debit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers&rsquo; cheques are of limited use and shouldn&rsquo;t be relied on. Travellers are advised to take travellers&rsquo; cheques in US Dollars if the use of one is absolutely necessary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sun-Thu 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above to enter Mauritania. Nationals holding passports from Algeria, Ivory Coast, the Gambia, Libya, Mali, Niger, Senegal, Syria and Tunisia do not require a visa to enter Mauritania.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa cost for 30 days for Arab &amp; African countries: &euro;40 / US$45; for the rest of the world: &euro;55 / US$60.<br />
Visa cost for 90 days for Arab &amp; African countries: &euro;70 / US$75; for the rest of the world: &euro;95 / US$100.<br />
Visa cost for 3 months - 1 year for Arab &amp; African countries: &euro;135 / US$145; for the rest of the world: &euro;190 / US$200.<br />
Visa cost for 1 year - 2 years for Arab &amp; African countries: &euro;190 / US$200; for the rest of the world: &euro;270 / US$285.<br />
Visa cost for 2 years - 3 years for Arab &amp; African countries: &euro;270 / US$285; for the rest of the world: &euro;405 / US$425.<br />
Visa cost for 3 years and more for Arab &amp; African countries: &euro;540 / US$565; for the rest of the world: &euro;810 / US$845.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas can be valid for 30 days, 90 days, 3 months - 1 year, 1 year - 2 years, 2 years - 3 years or 3 years and more.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On arrival at the airport or land border.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[20.259005]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-10.363960]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,030,700 sq km (397,955 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,166,463 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nouakchott.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Islamic Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritania is bordered by Algeria, Mali, Western Sahara (Sahrawi Arab Democratic Republic) and Senegal. To the west lies the Atlantic Ocean. Mauritania consists mainly of the vast Saharan plain of sand and scrub. Most of this area is a sea of sand dunes, but in places the land rises to rocky plateaux with deep ravines leaving isolated peaks. The Adrar plateau in the central region rises to 500m (1,640ft), and the Tagant further south to 600m (1,970ft). The area is scattered with towns, small villages and oases. The northern bank of the Senegal River, which forms the country's southern border, is the only area in the country with any degree of permanent vegetation and it supports a wide variety of wildlife.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Islam is the official religion. Despite ethnic and cultural differences among Mauritanians, they are all bound by a common Muslim attachment to the Malekite sect.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Islam has been the major influence in this country since the seventh and eighth centuries and visitors should respect the religious laws and customs. Dress for women should be uncompromisingly modest. Nearly all the population have traditionally been nomadic herdsmen. The bulk of the population is divided into two main Moorish groups, the Bidan (55%) and the Harattin (20%), with the non-Moorish population concentrated in the Senegal River area. Different classes and tribes tend to be contiguous.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Mohamed Salem Ould B&eacute;chir since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Mohamed Ould Abdel Aziz since 2009.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritania lies across one of the great trans-Saharan trade routes. For over 500 years, to 1674 when the Arabs defeated them, the Almoravid Dynasty controlled the trade in gold, slaves and salt.</p>
<p>French domination of the area was established in the late 19th century and until 1960 when Mauritania achieved independence. Since the 1970s, the country has been locked in dispute with its two northern neighbours, Algeria and Morocco, concerning the future of Western Sahara, a disputed territory ceded to Morocco and Mauritania by Spain in 1975.</p>
<p>Mauritania's first post-independence ruler, Mukhtar Ould Daddah, was able to keep control of his poor, sparsely populated desert country only by playing his two powerful neighbours, Morocco and Algeria, off against one another. This didn't wash for long and&nbsp;he was duly deposed in a military coup in 1978.</p>
<p>The dominant political figure in Mauritania for the last two decades has been Maaouiya Ould Sid'Ahmed Taya, a former army officer who first seized power in a military coup in 1984.</p>
<p>In the early 1990s, Mauritania came under pressure to introduce representative civilian government. Elections for a presidency and a bicameral parliament were held the following year. Taya reinvented himself as a civilian politician and comfortably won the presidential race. He was elected for a third term in the hotly disputed presidential poll in November 2003.</p>
<p>What followed was growing discontent over the government's often heavy-handed approach to political opposition, which mainly comes from the organised labour movement and Islamist organisations. Both are subject to periodic crackdowns. There are also tensions between black Mauritanians and those of Arab origin.</p>
<p>In 2005, there was a largely bloodless coup in which a transitional government was appointed. A new constitution was passed in 2006 and elections held in 2007. These proved inconclusive and there was another coup in 2008. Mohamed Ould Abdel Aziz, leader of the 2005 coup, was elected president in 2009.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Mauritania&rsquo;s coast is home to the so-called Dolphin Tribe, a fishing community that uses wild dolphins to help them haul in the day&rsquo;s catch.<br />
&bull; Mauritania boasts one of the longest trains in the world. Stretching up to 3km long (1.8miles), the train carries iron ore from Adrar to the coast.<br />
&bull; In this country plagued by food shortages, to be fat is to be beautiful, wealthy and prestigious. Some girls under go a process of &lsquo;fattening up&rsquo; to ensure they can make a good marriage.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Islamic Republic of Mauritania in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 232 5700.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 232 5700.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2129 Leroy Place NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Consulate of the Islamic Republic of Mauritania in the UK ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7233 6158.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mauritanianembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7233 6158.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 1000-1600, Fri 1000-1400.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>235-237 Vauxhall Bridge Road<br/>Carlyle House<br/>London<br/>SW1V 1EJ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mauritania&rsquo;s is a lonely beauty. A land of endless deserts, empty coastlines and spectacular birdlife, it is lays claim to some of the most spectacular scenery in Africa and a fascinating population comprised of Arab-Berbers and black Africans.</p>
<p>Arguably the jewel in Mauritania&rsquo;s crown is the Banc d&rsquo;Arguin, where the Sahara Desert slips silently into the Atlantic Ocean. This is nirvana for twitchers, particularly during the European winter, when more than two million migratory birds descend on the national park. The Banc d&rsquo;Arguin is also home to the Imraguen fishermen, who catch their quarry with a little help from local dolphins.</p>
<p>The Mauritanian coastline is a bleak and beautiful place, an empty shore littered with the occasional shipwreck or whale skeleton. Miraculously, one of the last remaining Mediterranean monk seal colonies can be found living around Cap Blanc, where there is a small nature reserve dedicated to protecting this endangered species.</p>
<p>Inland lies the oasis settlement of Ouad&acirc;ne. Concealed by coloured sand dunes, this ghost town was once a centre for intellectual thinking and its private libraries contain thousands of ancient scholarly manuscripts. It&rsquo;s also home to the crumbling remains of a 14th century mosque, which dominates this UNESCO-listed town. Nearby Chinguetti, the seventh holiest city of Islam, is also worth a visit.</p>
<p>Nouakchott, the capital, is hot and dusty and doesn&rsquo;t have very much to recommend it besides a few French restaurants and bustling markets. The best thing to do in town is to watch local fishermen land their catch at Port de Peche, where every evening a colourful mass of people haul nets, carry fish and drag brightly painted boats out of the waves, singing songs as they go. It&rsquo;s one of Mauritania&rsquo;s many simple pleasures.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp;Mauritania&rsquo;s is a lonely beauty. A land of endless deserts, empty coastlines and spectacular birdlife, it is lays claim to some of the most spectacular scenery in Africa and a fascinating population comprised of Arab-Berbers and black Africans.</p>
<p>Arguably the jewel in Mauritania&rsquo;s crown is the Banc d&rsquo;Arguin, where the Sahara Desert slips silently into the Atlantic Ocean. This is nirvana for twitchers, particularly during the European winter, when more than two million migratory birds descend on the national park. The Banc d&rsquo;Arguin is also home to the Imraguen fishermen, who catch their quarry with a little help from local dolphins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
