<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Mexico" ColCode="mex" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mx" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Mexico]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mexico is a great destination to visit throughout the year. Altitude is a determining factor with regards to the weather, with cooler temperatures at higher elevations (Mexico City, Puebla, San Crist&oacute;bal de las Casas) and warmer, tropical weather as you descend to sea level (Guadalajara, Cuernavaca, Cancun).</p>
<p>Along the Pacific and Caribbean coasts, the winter months (November-February) are warm and sunny. Many Europeans visit during this time to escape winter in their homelands. The summer months (June-August), meanwhile, are very hot and humid with heavy rain showers and the occasional hurricane.</p>
<p>October and November are perhaps the best months to visit the interior, after the rains have ended and everything is still green.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>This varies from area to area. Natural fibres are best in the heat, but have a sweater on hand as the nights are generally cooler. A sun hat will help to avoid dehydration. In the mountains, heavier clothing will be required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is an excellent network of daily scheduled&nbsp;flights in Mexico&nbsp;between principal commercial centres operated by longstanding airline Aerom&eacute;xico (<a href="http://www.aeromexico.com" target="_blank">www.aeromexico.com</a>). Many of the smaller airports also have capacity for large planes and some international flights.</p>
<p>A plethora of small domestic carriers offer low-cost flights to a range of destinations. These include VivaAerobus (<a href="http://www.vivaaerobus.com" target="_blank">www.vivaaerobus.com</a>), Volaris (<a href="http://www.volaris.com" target="_blank">www.volaris.com</a>) and Interjet (<a href="http://www.interjet.com.mx" target="_blank">www.interjet.com.mx</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Baja Ferries (tel: 01 800 377 7437, in Mexico only; <a href="http://www.bajaferries.com" target="_blank">www.bajaferries.com</a>) operates regular sailings between Mazatl&aacute;n and La Paz (Baja California) and between Topolobampo and La Paz.</p>
<p>Ferry Santa Rosalia (tel: 01 800 505 5018, in Mexico only; <a href="http://www.ferrysantarosalia.com" target="_blank">www.ferrysantarosalia.com</a>) runs a ferry across the Gulf of California from Guaymas to Santa Rosal&iacute;a.</p>
<p>Some west coast cruises include Pacific ports such as Mazatl&aacute;n, Puerto Vallarta and Acapulco. There are also regular ferries from the mainland to the Caribbean Islands of Isla Mujeres and Cozumel. Ferry operators, their names, websites and schedules are in a constant state of flux. Advance bookings are rarely needed or available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only long-distance passenger route is the Chihuahua-Pacific Railway, commonly known as El Chepe (tel: 01 800 122 4373, in Mexico only or +52 1 614 439 7211; <a href="http://www.chepe.com.mx">www.chepe.com.mx</a>). The tourist-oriented line from the city of Chihuahua to Los Mochis traverses the Sierra Tarahumara range and includes a stop in the Copper Canyon region.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is advisable to keep car doors and windows closed and locked, especially at traffic lights.</p><p>Coaches and buses link almost all towns and cities. Central bus terminals in major cities provide service and information on fares and schedules.</p>
<p>Major operators include ETN (tel: 01 800 800 0386, in Mexico only; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.etn.com.mx">www.etn.com.mx</a>), covering the Pacific coast, western and northern Mexico; ADO (tel: 01 800 369 4652, in Mexico only; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.ado.com.mx">www.ado.com.mx</a>), serving the Gulf coast and Mexican southeast; Primera Plus (tel: 01 800 375 7587, in Mexico only; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.primeraplus.com.mx">www.primeraplus.com.mx</a>), serving central and northern Mexico; and Estrella Blanca (tel: 01 800 507 5500, in Mexico only; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.estrellablanca.com.mx">www.estrellablanca.com.mx</a>), with service throughout the country.</p><p>An International Driving Permit or a valid driving licence from your country of residence is required. The minimum driving age is for car hire is usually 21. Mexican vehicle insurance is compulsory; check insurance is included in hire agreements.</p><p>Speed limits are 30-50kph (19-31mph) in towns and 100-110kph (62-68mph) on motorways. All passengers are required to wear seatbelts. Car use in Mexico City is restricted so as to reduce pollution. The last digit of the car number plate determines when that car cannot be driven.</p><p>Rest areas at toll-booths provide ambulance and breakdown services. The Angeles Verdes (Green Angels) (tel: 078, in Mexico only), run by the tourist ministry, provide breakdown assistance to tourists between the hours of 0800 and 1800 daily, with free labour and parts at cost. If you do need to call them out, it should go without saying that you should tip generously.</p><p>Self-drive cars are available at airports, city centres and resorts. All the established international agencies operate in Mexico. Reputable internet-only agencies are worth a look for cheap deals. Beware of hidden extras, and poor breakdown services, particularly with local firms.</p><p>Speed limits are 30-50kph (19-31mph) in towns and 100-110kph (62-68mph) on motorways. All passengers are required to wear seatbelts. Car use in Mexico City is restricted so as to reduce pollution. The last digit of the car number plate determines when that car cannot be driven.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mexican cities and towns generally have good public transportation networks, with frequent bus and taxi service around town and to/from inter-city bus stations. Buses are cheap, with signs affixed to their windshields announcing their destinations. Taxis are easy to find; usually they charge by distance (it's best to agree on the fare beforehand) but in larger cities are metered.</p>
<p>The country's three largest cities, Mexico City, Monterrey and Guadalajara, all feature metro systems. Mexico City's is the most extensive, with frequent, efficient service and a flat fare payable by single tickets or preloadable smartcard. Another component of the capital's transit network is its expanding Metrobus system, with double-length buses stopping at enclosed stations that are accessible by smartcard.</p>
<p>Various kinds of taxis ply the streets of Mexico City: cruising street taxis are metered and cheap, while radio taxis operating from sitios (taxi stands) charge more but are considered a more secure option. In the city centre, bicycle taxis offer a non-polluting alternative.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Mexico</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">puerto_vallarta</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.55</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">14.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Mexico</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">chihuahua</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">34.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Mexico</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cancuacuten</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">30.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Mexico</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">acapulco</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mexico's national carrier is Aerom&eacute;xico (<a href="http://www.aeromexico.com" target="_blank">www.aeromexico.com</a>). Some of Mexico's domestic airlines serve <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> destinations, including VivaAerobus (<a href="http://www.vivaerobus.com" target="_blank">www.vivaerobus.com</a>) and Volaris (<a href="http://www.volaris.mx" target="_blank">www.volaris.mx</a>). Aerom&eacute;xico and British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) both operate direct flights to Mexico City from the UK. British Airways and Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) offer non-stop flights from London to Canc&uacute;n.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico/cancun-international-airport">Cancun International Airport </a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico/guadalajara-miguel-hidalgo-y-costilla-international-airport">Guadalajara Miguel Hidalgo y Costilla International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico/mexico-city-benito-juarez-international-airport">Mexico City Benito Juarez International Airport </a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico/monterrey-general-mariano-escobedo-international-airport">Monterrey General Mariano</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico-city">Mexico City</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 11 hours 20 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 5 hours 15 minutes.</p>
<p>To Canc&uacute;n: from London - 11 hours; New York - 4 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Around US$48 depending on the exchange rate. Usually included in the air fare, otherwise payable at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Guadalajara Miguel Hidalgo y Costilla International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeropuertosgap.com.mx<p>Guadalajara International Airport is situated 17km (12 miles) southeast of Guadalajara.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+52 33 3688 5248</p>]]><b>Mexico City Benito Juárez International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aicm.com.mx<p>Mexico City Benito Juárez International Airport is located 13km (8 miles) east of Mexico City.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+52 55 2482 2400</p>]]><b>Monterrey General Mariano Escobedo International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.oma.aero<p>The airport is situated 24km (15 miles) northeast of Monterrey.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+52 81 8288 7700</p>]]><b>Cancún International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.cancunairport.com<p>Canc&uacute;n International Airport is located 17.6km (11 miles) southwest of Canc&uacute;n.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+52 99 8848 7200</p>]]><b>Acapulco International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Acapulco (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.apiacapulcoport.com">www.apiacapulcoport.com</a>), Cabo San Lucas, Cozumel (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.apiqroo.com.mx">www.apiqroo.com.mx</a>), Manzanillo (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.puertomanzanillo.com.mx">www.puertomanzanillo.com.mx</a>), Mazatl&aacute;n (<a href="http://www.puertomazatlan.com.mx" target="_blank">www.puertomazatlan.com.mx</a>), Puerto Vallarta (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.puertodevallarta.com.mx">www.puertodevallarta.com.mx</a>), Tampico (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.puertodetampico.com.mx">www.puertodetampico.com.mx</a>) and Zihuatanejo/Ixtap.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amtrak provides railway connections to various points along the Mexican border from cities in the USA or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a> (tel: +1 800 872 7245, in the USA; <a href="http://www.amtrak.com/" target="_blank">www.amtrak.com</a>).</p>
<p>To get into Mexico by train, the only option is on luxurious private services like the Sierra Madre Express operating between Tuscon, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/arizona">Arizona</a> and Mexico's Copper Canyon. Tickets are available through specialist agents. Mexlist (<a href="http://www.mexlist.com/" target="_blank">www.mexlist.com</a>) maintains a list of similar luxury services, most of which have pullman sleepers, restaurant cars, lounge observation and club cars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drivers crossing the border into Mexico in private cars or US hire cars must present originals and photocopies of the current car registration and a current driving licence to obtain an automobile permit, valid for the length of stay specified on their tourist card (maximum of 180 days). The cost of this should be charged to a credit card to avoid leaving a large cash deposit.</p>
<p>Mexican car insurance is also compulsory - extensions to US policies are not valid. You can buy insurance through agencies on the US side of the border but better deals are available through online brokers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Long-distance calls are very expensive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile phones can be purchased inexpensively, and credit can be added by prepaid card. Of the major providers, Telcel has the most thorough coverage. Roaming agreements exist with a few international mobile phone companies but is pricey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet is available in all regions. Most hotels in the mid-range and above categories provide Wi-Fi or access to connected computer terminals. There are also many inexpensive cyber-caf&eacute;s in cities and towns throughout Mexico.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The major daily newspapers published in Spanish are <em>El Universal, Exc&eacute;lsior, El Financiero, La Jornada</em> and <em>Reforma</em>, all of which maintain web versions. Local English-language papers include <em>The News</em>, a daily running mostly reports from international wire services, and <em>Inside Mexico</em>, a monthly publication with useful information for tourists and expats. In the 2010 &lsquo;Press Freedom Index', issued by Reporters without Borders, Mexico was close to the bottom of the league in the Americas; only Colombia and Cuba received a lower rank. Mexican reporters who get too close to drug-cartel or political corruption stories have a habit of ending up dead or disappearing, particularly in the north of the country where drug violence is rife.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes about six days. Surface mail is slow, taking weeks if not months. Within the capital, there is an immediate delivery (<em>entrega inmediata</em>) service, which usually takes two or three days.</p><p>Typically Mon-Fri 0900-1700. Some larger branches open on Saturday morning for a reduced range of services. In Mexico City, the Correo Mayor (main post office) is behind the Palacio de Bellas Artes and opens Mon-Sat 0800-2100 and Sun 0800-1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Copper Canyon (Barrancas del Cobre)</p><![CDATA[<p>One of the largest canyon systems in the world, Copper Canyon is a land of mountains, rivers, waterfalls, desert and forest. Four of the canyons are deeper than Arizona's famous Grand Canyon, although none of them are as wide. Perhaps the most famous attraction for visitors is the Chihuahua al Pacífico Railway, a scenic journey that crosses 36 major bridges, travels through 87 tunnels and climbs to a height of 2438m (8000ft) before descending back down to sea level. The Sierra Tarahumara mountains are inhabited by Tarahumara Indians, who live in isolated communities along the railway line.</p>]]><br/><p>Palenque</p><![CDATA[<p>Located in <em>Palenque National Park</em> in the northern Chiapas highlands, <em>Palenque </em>is one of the grandest of all classical Mayan sites. Situated on a ledge picturesquely overlooking swampy plains to the north, and set against a backdrop of lush, green mountains, Palenque was in its prime between AD 500-700. Visitors can wander from one structure to another amongst waterfalls and jungle, taking in the marvels of this ancient settlement, which is all the more remarkable for having been constructed without the aid of metal tools, the wheel or pack animals. The most notable structures are the <em>Palace </em>and the <em>Temple of Inscriptions </em>pyramid crypt.</p>]]><br/><p>Parroquia (San Miguel de Allende Parish Church)</p><![CDATA[<p><i>La Parroquia</i>, a pink, Gothic parish church, is one of San Miguel de Allende's most famous landmarks as well as one of the finest examples of colonial architecture in Mexico. Standing in the city's main square <i>(El Jardin</i>), the church was originally built in 1683 but was given a facelift in 1880. The crypt underneath the main altar contains the remains of Felipe Gonzalez and General Anastasio Bustamante, both of whom were heroes of the Mexican War of Independence (1810-1821) against Spain. There is also a sculpture of Ignacio Allende, who is the city's namesake, displayed on the main altar; he was born in San Miguel in 1779 and became a leader and martyr during the Mexican independence movement, prior to his execution in 1811.</p>]]><br/><p>White Mountain</p><![CDATA[<p>Monte Alban was at one time home to 50,000 Zapotec people. The builders of Monte Alban artificially levelled the top of the mountain, which overshadows the three surrounding valleys of Oaxaca. The site emerged as a political centre in around 400 BC, and later developed as an important cultural centre between 500 BC to AD 700. The site was abandoned by the Zapotecs when they began to lose political power, which resulted in conflict between them and the Mixtecs, who moved into the Valley and used it as a burial ground. It was later invaded by the Aztecs and then by the Spanish who gave the site the name Monte Alban, meaning White Mountain, due to the white flowering trees that grow in the area.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>All aboard the Tequila Express</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Home to Mexico's most popular export, the town of Guadalajara in Jalisco state sits amidst fields of blue agave, the plant that is the basis of tequila. You can sample José Cuervo and Sauza's finest liquor at the distilleries, which can be reached via the Tequila Express, a lively tourist train that wends through agave fields whilst plying passengers with tequila.</p>]]><p><b>Climb the mighty pyramids of Teotihuacán</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lying to the northeast of Mexico City, Teotihuacán grew to be the largest of Mexico's pre-Hispanic cities, constructing vast pyramids that surpass those of the ancient Egyptians. Its greatest building is the Pyramid of the Sun, standing at a height of 63m (207ft). It is joined on the Avenue of the Dead to the Pyramid of the Moon, which was originally part of a 'Moon Plaza'.</p>]]><p><b>Commemorate the dead on Isla Janitzio</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Janitzio, off Lake Pátzcuaro, is considered the most magical place to witness Mexico's Day of the Dead festival, with candlelit boats conveying Purépecha villagers to the tiny island where they decorate the tombs of their loved ones in an all-night vigil. Similar ceremonies are held from midnight on 1 November to 2 November (All Souls' Day) in cemeteries throughout Mexico; respectful visitors are welcomed.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise the canals of Xochimilco</b></p><![CDATA[<p>They may be a world away from Venice, but the beautiful, tree-lined canals and floating gardens of Xochimilco also draw romantic couples floating on brightly painted trajineras (a type of gondola, usually accompanied by mariachi singers).  The canals are the surviving remnants of the Aztecs' original lake and waterways built over by modern Mexico City.</p>]]><p><b>Dip into an ancient cenote</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The limestone terrain of the Yucatán peninsula is peppered with deep, naturally formed sinkhole pools known as cenotes, ideal for swimming or diving. Some, such as Xlacah near the archaeological site of Dzibilchaltún, have ritual significance for the local Maya. Others, like Dos Ojos near Akumal in the Yucatán Peninsula, connect to extensive underground cave networks.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Mexico’s living Maya culture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An enclave of traditional Maya culture in the Chiapas highlands, San Cristobal is known for its magnificent weaving: the intricately designed <em>huipiles</em> (loose-fitting blouse) woven and worn by local women open a window on Maya cosmology. San Cristóbal is surrounded by fascinating indigenous villages like San Juan Chamula and Zinacantán.</p>]]><p><b>Dive off Cozumel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From Baja California's deep Pacific waters to the warm Caribbean Sea, Mexico offers some fine dive sites. The reefs surrounding Cozumel island are prized diving spots known for their tropical marine life and unusual coral formations. Other fine spots for diving or snorkelling include Banco Chinchorro coral atoll off Yucatán's Costa Maya, and southern Baja California and Zihuatanejo on the Pacific coast.</p>]]><p><b>Experience the equinox at Chichén-Itzá</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ceremonial city of Chichén-Itzá was built over 1,000 years ago, but the Maya mystique still draws crowds. The best time to visit is during the spring or autumn equinox when shadows show Kukulcan, a Mayan snake deity, working his way up the steps. Other amazing but less-visited Maya sites include Calakmul in southern Campeche and Bonampak, with its polychromatic murals, in Chiapas.</p>]]><p><b>Find your own personal beach paradise</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mexico boasts fantastic beaches along both coasts. On the Baja California Peninsula, many head for Los Cabos, to San Lucas and San José. On the Caribbean side, make for Isla de Mujeres, a slender island off the Yucatán coast fringed by crushed coral sands. Surfers wil be right at home on the Pacific coast, notably along the Costa Azul of southern Baja, as well as to Sayulita and Puerto Escondido.</p>]]><p><b>Greet the dawn at Tulum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Seeing the sunrise over the Maya-Toltec ruins of Tulum, near Playa del Carmen, is well worth an early start. The intentionally top-heavy temples were dedicated to the setting sun, but if you want to avoid the evening crowds, explore in peace then take a pre-breakfast dip in the turquoise sea – the ruins virtually sit on the beach.</p>]]><p><b>Party all night in Cancun</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hedonists should book a ticket to one of Cancún's 15,000-capacity beach parties, which go on all night and most of the day.  Spring Break is the ultimate party period, when many American students come to town to let their hair down. For a more distinctively Mexican blowout, try the Pacific port of Mazatlán for Carnival (preceding Ash Wednesday).</p>]]><p><b>Plunge into the mayhem of Mexico City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the world's biggest cities, Mexico's capital brims with historic and cultural attractions. Its gigantic main square is overlooked by the imposing Catedral Metropolitana and flanked by the remains of the ceremonial centre of the original Aztec city of Tenochtitlán. Of the city's myriad museums, the one must-see is the vast National Museum of Anthropology, covering Mexico's astounding archaeological legacy by region.</p>]]><p><b>Saddle up on a Mexican ranch</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Luxury guest ranches let you play at being a charro – Mexico's more dressy version of the US western cowboy – with action-packed days in the saddle and relaxing evenings of fine local cuisine and indulgent tequila tastings. Horseback adventures are available all over the country, from a few hours riding for beginners, to weeklong stays in a traditional hacienda, trekking deep into the countryside.</p>]]><p><b>Scale the peaks of Popocatépetl and Iztaccíhuatl</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The two snow-capped volcanoes east of Mexico City make for memorable hiking and climbing. Popo, though still active, is ringed by a series of indigenous villages and 16th-century monasteries, which are inscribed on UNESCO's World Heritage list. Popo is a relatively easy hike, but dormant Izta should only be scaled by experienced climbers with proper gear.</p>]]><p><b>See sunset at sacred Monte Albán</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Monte Albán, a sacred ceremonial site and centre of the 2,000 year-old Zapotec culture, stands on a hilltop overlooking the surrounding valley. Relive the majestic past glory of this UNESCO World Heritage Site by watching sunset from the top of one of its prominent pyramids. The Central Plaza, the Ball Court, and some of the tombs are also open to the public.</p>]]><p><b>Shop for silver in Taxco</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ornate silver jewellery produced in Taxco is a joy to behold. Fortunes were made from the silver mines here in this stunning colonial town that is a delight to explore on foot. The first booty was sent back to Spain, but much wealth was also poured back into the Church of Santa Prisca and San Sebastián, jewels of Churrigueresque architecture.</p>]]><p><b>Sink into a bubbling hot spa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Central America's ancient civilisations knew what was good for them and they made full use of Mexico's countless hot springs. Follow in the footsteps of the Aztecs with a relaxing spa break. Many luxury resorts boast a pampering spa, but natural hot springs offer a more authentic experience, with many in volcanically active central states including Puebla and near the colonial town of San Miguel de Allende in Guanajuato,</p>]]><p><b>Tour the colourful talavera tiles of Puebla</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For chic colonial-style, look no further than Puebla, one of the oldest and best-preserved cities in Mexico, nestled in the foothills of the central Sierra Madre. Many church domes and house walls are covered in <em>talavera</em>, colourful glazed tiles that are still produced by the town's artisans. In particular, don't miss the gorgeously decorated Patio de los Azulejos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$1.463 trillion (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil, manufactured goods, silver, fruit, vegetables and coffee.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Agricultural machinery, electrical equipment, car parts, parts for motor vehicles, aircraft and aircraft parts.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Canada, China, South Korea, Japan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The agricultural sector, in decline for decades, now accounts for only 4% of the country's GDP yet employs nearly 20% of the workforce. However, US moves towards ethanol power have pushed up the world price of corn (from which ethanol is produced). Mexico, the birthplace of corn and the world's fourth largest producer, is well placed to benefit.<br /><br />In the service sector, tourism continues to be Mexico's biggest industry, despite some concerns about national violence, and the effects of the global recession.<br /><br />Oil and manufacturing are big contributors to the country's economic health, but are at the mercy of price fluctuations, and the state of the US car industry.<br /><br />Inflation is rising after a 30-year low in 2005 and in 2009 was hovering around 6%. A 30% drop in the peso since August 2008, couple with a collapse in exports to the US and an increase in unemployment due to the economic crisis has left many Mexicans feeling nervous. In 2008, growth was at 2% and unemployment at 4.1%.<br />Mexico, with its sophisticated conventions infrastructure, is one of the most popular destinations in the world for incentive and business travel. Some of the larger and more modern convention centers include the World Trade Center and Banamex Center, both in Mexico City, the Acapulco Convention Center, and the Cancún Convention Center, with Taxco, Morelia, Puerto Vallarta, Ixtapa, Guadalajara and Mazatlán all boasting good facilities amd convention centres.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mexicans attach much importance to courtesy and the use of titles. English is widely spoken in business circles although it is naturally appreciated when visitors use a few words of Spanish, at least when introducing themselves. A handshake is customary upon first acquaintance, with men or women. Business wear is relatively formal. Mexicans generally avoid confrontation: if they disagree with a proposal, they rarely express that opinion outright and find it rude when others do so. Sometimes the absence of explicit approval may be interpreted as a refusal.</p><p>These vary considerably, but are usually Mon-Fri 0900-1900/2000; lunch breaks usually last an hour but some business lunches can go on for longer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>ProMéxico</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (52) 5447 7000
					Website:http://www.buyinmexico.com.mx
					Address: ,Camino a Santa Teresa 1679,Mexico,1900]]><b>Confederación de Cámaras Nacionales de Comercio Servicios y Turismo (CONCANACO)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (55) 5722 9300
					Website:http://www.concanaco.com.mx
					Address: ,Balderas 144,Colonia Centro,6079]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Mexican cuisine is a gloriously rich mix, reflecting the many cultural influences the country has absorbed throughout its history. Nevertheless, the main ingredient in Mexican meals is the humble but versatile corn, prepared in every conceivable way.</p><p>A basket of hot tortillas – savoury cornmeal pancakes – is always on the table. Tacos, available everywhere, consist of crispy tortillas topped with beef, pork or fish. And there's a huge range of corn-based <em>antojitos</em> (snacks), including those listed below, which are staples at street stalls across the country.</p><p>Fresh fish and shellfish are the main attraction along both coasts. For vegetarians, <em>nopales</em>, the succulent leaves of the prickly pear cactus are a good option, as are squash blossoms and all kinds of wild mushrooms. Also look out for exotic fruits like <em>zapote</em> (sapodilla) and <em>tuna </em>(cactus fruit).</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mole</strong>: A range of complex sauces based around chillies and a number of other herbs and spices.<br />
<strong>Guacamole: </strong>Avocado mashed with red peppers, onions and tomatoes.<br />
<strong>Exotic fruits</strong>: Local markets offer a dazzling variety, including <em>zapote</em> (brown fruit resembling an avocado), and <em>tuna </em>(juicy prickly pear, fruit of the cactus).<br />
<strong>Cabritoasado:</strong> Roasted kid goat, a northern specialty. Served on a bed of sizzling onions with cowboy beans and plenty of tortillas.<br />
<strong>Cochinitapibil:</strong> Yucat&aacute;n's signature dish: suckling pig marinated in citrus juice and the reddish dye of annatto seeds, wrapped in banana leaves, then slow-roasted in an underground pit.<br />
<strong>Tamales:</strong> Banana leaf or corn-husk packages of cornmeal stuffed with meat, cheese or vegetables, and laced with various spicy sauces.<br />
<strong>Quesadillas:</strong> Fried tortillas filled with cheese and/or vegetables.<br />
<strong>Flautas: </strong>Chicken-filled tortillas rolled like cigars and deep fried.<br />
<strong>Huevos rancheros:</strong> Fried eggs on top of tortillas and covered in spicy tomato sauce; one of many egg dishes popular for breakfast.<br />
<strong>Salsas:</strong> Zesty sauces, often spicy, based on chilli and tomatoes, a standard fixture on most restaurant tables.<br />
<strong>Tequilla:</strong> A double or triple-distilled spirit made from the blue variety of the agave plant. Young <em>blanco</em> tequilas can have a rough 'cowboy' edge to them. Older <em>a&ntilde;ejo</em> varieties are woody and smooth.<br />
<strong>Mezcal:</strong> A similar spirit to tequila but is distilled only once and can be made from different varieties of agave. It is not generally used in cocktails like tequila, but consumed in shots.<br />
<strong>Kahl&uacute;a:</strong> Mexico's world-famous liqueur, made with coffee and rum.<br />
<strong>Lager: </strong>Sol, Corona and Modelo, all of which are light lagers, are the most popular beers.<br />
<strong>NegraModelo:</strong> One of Mexico&rsquo;s few dark beers.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Service charges are rarely added to hotel, restaurant or bar bills and many of the staff depend on tips for their livelihood. 15% is expected and 20% if the service has been very good.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Every larger city has its nightlife zones. In Mexico City it's the <em>Zona Rosa </em>(Pink Zone) near the business centre, and Condesa and Polanco on either side of Chapultepec Park; in Monterrey, it's the Barrio Antiguo; in Puebla, the Plazuela de los Sapos; in Acapulco, 'La Costera,' the coastal strip. These areas generally feature some combination of <em>antros</em> - rowdy drinking halls for a younger set, often with live music - and dance clubs. The latter don't usually get going until late, opening around midnight and closing at dawn.</p>
<p>In the hinterlands, you're more likely to catch accordion-driven <em>norte&ntilde;o</em> combos pumping out polkas and cumbias in crowded dancehalls or at street festivals. <em>Mariachis</em> - brass and string ensembles in charro outfits - perform beautiful renditions of traditional ballads wherever they can find employment, whether at weddings, restaurants, bars, or designated zones such as Mexico City's Plaza Garabaldi. Mexico City, Guadalajara and Monterrey all attract international rock and pop acts and Latin music stars, as well as some fine ballet and orchestra companies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no shortage of shopping opportunities in Mexico, from fashionable clothing boutiques to bustling market places selling traditional indigenous crafts. Taxco is renowned for fine jewellery and silverware; Oaxaca for mezcal, <em>alebrijes </em>(fanciful animal figurines) and distinctive black pottery; Saltillo for beautiful <em>sarapes</em> (colour-banded shawls); Le&oacute;n for leatherwork and cowboy boots; M&eacute;rida, Yucat&aacute;n for hammocks; and Guerrero state for masks, all of which make great gifts. The best woodworkers are in Guadalajara, but furniture from the region is on sale in Mexico City, as are crafts from all other parts of the country.</p>
<p>Market buildings are fun to explore throughout the country, as much to observe the activity as to pick up souvenirs. La Merced in Mexico City and Mercado La Libertad in Guadalajara are among the biggest, most frenetic markets in the country. However, many Mexicans do their shopping in glitzy, modern malls with all the usual department stores, boutiques and franchises.</p><p>Mon-Sat 1000-2000 in big towns and cities; shops in smaller towns may close midday for lunch, usually from 1400 to 1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[All-inclusive packages are very popular in large resorts such as Cancún, where pay-as-you-go tariffs are often referred to as 'European Plan'. The all-inclusive plans will typically include all meals, snacks, non-alcoholic and (domestic) alcoholic beverages - imported wines and spirits will cost extra. In terms of activities, non-motorised watersports are free, and planned entertainment is often provided in the evening. Spa treatments are usually extra. Some resorts are specifically family-oriented and others are adults-only.<br /><p>Hotels in Mexico are plentiful, from humble guesthouses to large international chains. In between, there are numerous mid-priced establishments. Hotels in that category are usually clean and comfortable and may vary in style from strictly functional business blocks to lovingly restored historic edifices. Every hotel in Mexico is required to display officially approved rates for low and high season. Outside of the Christmas and Easter seasons, it is rarely necessary to book ahead, and many hotels, particularly in resort areas, offer substantial discounts. If you do make reservations, obtain confirmation of rates in writing or by e-mail.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfasts in Mexico are&nbsp;becoming increasingly available in both cities and colonial towns and can be an attractive alternative for their personalised treatment and authentic atmosphere. They're often in historic homes and lavishly decorated with local fabrics, ceramics and art. They may be humble family-run establishments or posh inns with swimming pools. Breakfast is usually included in the room rate. For extensive listings, check <a href="http://www.bedandbreakfast.com/mexico.html">www.bedandbreakfast.com/mexico.html</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[All-inclusive packages are very popular in large resorts such as Cancún, where pay-as-you-go tariffs are often referred to as 'European Plan'. The all-inclusive plans will typically include all meals, snacks, non-alcoholic and (domestic) alcoholic beverages - imported wines and spirits will cost extra. In terms of activities, non-motorised watersports are free, and planned entertainment is often provided in the evening. Spa treatments are usually extra. Some resorts are specifically family-oriented and others are adults-only.<br /><p>Hotels in Mexico are plentiful, from humble guesthouses to large international chains. In between, there are numerous mid-priced establishments. Hotels in that category are usually clean and comfortable and may vary in style from strictly functional business blocks to lovingly restored historic edifices. Every hotel in Mexico is required to display officially approved rates for low and high season. Outside of the Christmas and Easter seasons, it is rarely necessary to book ahead, and many hotels, particularly in resort areas, offer substantial discounts. If you do make reservations, obtain confirmation of rates in writing or by e-mail.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[All-inclusive packages are very popular in large resorts such as Cancún, where pay-as-you-go tariffs are often referred to as 'European Plan'. The all-inclusive plans will typically include all meals, snacks, non-alcoholic and (domestic) alcoholic beverages - imported wines and spirits will cost extra. In terms of activities, non-motorised watersports are free, and planned entertainment is often provided in the evening. Spa treatments are usually extra. Some resorts are specifically family-oriented and others are adults-only.<br /><p>Hotels in Mexico are plentiful, from humble guesthouses to large international chains. In between, there are numerous mid-priced establishments. Hotels in that category are usually clean and comfortable and may vary in style from strictly functional business blocks to lovingly restored historic edifices. Every hotel in Mexico is required to display officially approved rates for low and high season. Outside of the Christmas and Easter seasons, it is rarely necessary to book ahead, and many hotels, particularly in resort areas, offer substantial discounts. If you do make reservations, obtain confirmation of rates in writing or by e-mail.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Comprehensive health insurance is recommended. Medical facilities are both private and state-organised and generally good. Medicines are often available without prescriptions, and pharmacists can diagnose and treat minor ailments.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water in bottles or marked 'drinking/sterilised water' can be drunk without precautions. All other water should be boiled or sterilised before consuming. Milk in major cities, hotels and resorts is pasteurised, otherwise it will probably be unpasteurised. Travellers concerned about drinking unpasteurised milk will find powdered or tinned milk readily available. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, cooked vegetables and peeled fruit.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Diarrhoea and sunburn affect some travellers. Outbreaks of dengue fever have occurred, chiefly in the southeast states of Chiapas and Veracruz and the northern border states of Chihuahua and Tamaulipas. Rabies is present. If bitten, seek medical advice without delay. Owing to the high altitude and level of smog in Mexico City, visitors may take some time to acclimatise.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Below are listed Public Holidays for the January 2014-December 2015 period.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Constitution Day :
							05 February </p><p>Birthday of Benito Ju :
							19 March </p><p>Maundy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Anniversary of the Battle of Puebla :
							05 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							16 September </p><p>D :
							12 October </p><p>D :
							02 November </p><p>Revolution Day :
							19 November </p><p>Day of Our Lady of Guadalupe :
							12 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be brought into Mexico by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 10 packs of cigarettes or 25 cigars or 200g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 3L of spirits and 6L of wine.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of US$500 (if arriving by air) or US$300 (if arriving by land). Mexican nationals may bring goods to the value of US$500 if arriving by land during holiday periods such as Easter week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited or restricted items include narcotics, images depicting childhood in a degrading manner, live species of predatory fish, firearms and ammunition, and used clothing that is not part of your personal luggage.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Archaeological artefacts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mexican Peso (MXN; symbol M$) = 100 centavos. Notes are in denominations of M$1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50 and 20. Coins are in denominations of M$10, 5, 2 and 1, and 50 and 20 centavos.</p>
<p><strong>Note: </strong>The M$1,000 and M$500 notes can be difficult to change and are sometimes not accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollar is widely accepted; indeed in some instances it can be difficult to pay in pesos. Currency exchange houses give a preferable rate of exchange to hotels and a much quicker service than banks. Not all banks in Mexico exchange money.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mastercard, Visa and American Express cards are generally accepted by businesses catering to tourists, such as car rental agencies, airlines, some bus lines and higher-end hotels, shops and restaurants. (Credit companies add a surcharge of around 5% for foreign transactions.) At humbler establishments you'll need pesos to make purchases.</p><p>ATMs on the Cirrus and Plus networks are easily found in cities and towns throughout Mexico, dispensing pesos for holders of both debit and credit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>ATMs and credit cards mean traveller's cheques are less necessary as a means of carrying money than they used to be and not necessarily recommended. However, traveller's cheques issued by well-known brands can be cashed in exchange houses. Traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling and Euros are now as readily accepted as those in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1600; some banks are open longer hours and others are open on Saturday mornings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for the duration of stay is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Mexican authorities have suspended the need for children travelling alone to carry a notarised permit from their parents to leave the country; this now only applies to Mexican nationals or foreigners residing permanently or temporarily in Mexico.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa: &pound;27.85.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa: up to six months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing usually takes two working days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors who do require a visa need to provide payslips or bank statements from the six months preceding their application.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to bring your pet into Mexico, you must present a veterinary certificate to the Office of Agriculture and Health Inspection at your port of entry. This must certify that your animal has been inspected, is in good health and has been vaccinated against rabies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[23.909004]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-102.633998]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,964,375 sq km (758,449 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>128,632,004 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>62 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mexico City.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mexico is at the southern extremity of North America and is bordered to the north by the USA, northwest by the Gulf of California, west by the Pacific, south by Guatemala and Belize, and east by the Gulf of Mexico and the Caribbean.</p>
<p>Mexico's geographical features range from swamp to desert, and from tropical lowland jungle to high alpine vegetation. Over half the country is at an altitude greater than 1,000m (3,300ft). The central land mass is a plateau flanked by ranges of mountains to the east and west that lie roughly parallel to the coast. The northern area of this plateau is arid and thinly populated, and occupies 40% of the total area of Mexico.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>89% Roman Catholic, 5% Protestant and 6% other denominations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the most common form of greeting. Casual wear is acceptable during the day throughout Mexico. At beach resorts, clothing is very informal for men and women. In <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico-city">Mexico City</a>, however, appearance tends to be smart in elegant restaurants and hotel dining rooms. Smoking is banned in all enclosed public places, punishable by stiff fines and even a jail sentence - although smoking in bars and restaurants is permitted if they have separate rooms or outdoor areas.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style two-pin (flat) plugs are usual, but most sockets cannot accept a North American-style three-pin plug.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Andr&eacute;s Manuel L&oacute;pez Obrador since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Andr&eacute;s Manuel L&oacute;pez Obrador since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mexico's early civilizations remain a source of pride to modern Mexicans. The pyramids of Teotihuac&aacute;n, north of Mexico City, attest to the extraordinary achievement of a society that flourished around the same time as the Roman Empire then mysteriously disappeared. The legacy of the great Maya civilisation continues to reverberate amongst its descendants on the Yucat&aacute;n Peninsula and in southeast Mexico. These and other great civilizations had developed before the Aztecs established their empire at Tenochtitl&aacute;n, the predecessor of modern Mexico City. The Maya, above all, asserted their hegemony over central Mexico and beyond, through present-day Central America.</p>
<p>When the Spanish arrived on Mexico's Gulf Coast in 1517, the Aztec Empire was in disarray and widely reviled by its far-flung subjects. This situation greatly facilitated the Spanish conquest of Mexico and within two years the European invaders had taken over the Aztec domains. Catholic missionaries arrived in the new Spanish colony to evangelize the masses of Indians. Thus were planted the seeds of the &ldquo;mestizaje&rdquo;, the blending of European and indigenous peoples and cultures that still characterizes the complex racial mix of today's Mexico.</p>
<p>The three centuries of Spanish rule that followed were primarily devoted to exploiting the colony's vast silver reserves and enslaving the populace to that end. The ensuing decades of political instability culminated in the regime of Porfirio D&iacute;az (1876-1910), which modernised Mexico's industry and infrastructure while trampling on the civil and economic rights of most Mexicans. This state of affairs sparked the Mexican Revolution (1910-20), a devastating conflict that ushered in a version of democratic government with a single political party, the PRI, at the helm for the next seven decades.</p>
<p>Electoral reforms implemented by President Ernesto Zedillo (1994-2000) facilitated the election of an opposition-party candidate, Vicente Fox, for the first time in the country's modern history. Fox&rsquo;s party, PAN (Partido Accion Nacional), represented a broad platform of centrist, Catholic principles, which challenged PRI&rsquo;s historic dominance</p>
<p>Mexico celebrated the bicentennial of its independence from Spain in 2010 but remained preoccupied by a vicious conflict against and between bands of drug cartels. The tough stance advocated by President Felipe Calder&oacute;n, and continued by his successor, Enrique Pe&ntilde;a Nieto, has taken an unprecedented human toll and sadly tarnished the country's international image.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Contrary to popular belief, agave, the main ingredient of tequila, is not a cactus, but is a plant related to the lily.<br />
&bull;	Mezcal, Mexico&rsquo;s other agave-based spirit, usually includes an agave worm, which is eaten as a delicacy.<br />
&bull;	Chapo Guzman, leader of the Sinaloa Cartel, was once smuggled out of prison in a laundry cart. He was re-captured in 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mexican Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 728 1600.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://embamex.sre.gob.mx/eua</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 728 1600.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1800.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1911 Pennsylvania Avenue NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20006<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mexican Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7499 8586.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://embamex.sre.gob.mx/reinounido</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7499 8586.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>16 St George Street<br/>London<br/>W1S 1LX<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Mexico]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(55) 1670 3200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-mexico-city</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(55) 1670 3200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1630; Fri 0800-1400.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Col. Cuauhtémoc<br/>Río Lerma 71<br/>Mexico City<br/>CP. 06500<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As spicy as <em>salsa</em>, intoxicating as tequila and surreal as a Frida Kahlo canvas, Mexico fills the senses, energizes the intellect and nourishes the soul. This huge country encompasses epic landscapes; from northern deserts and snowy peaks of the central sierra, to the jungle highlands of southern Chiapas and the beaches of the Yucat&aacute;n Peninsula.</p>
<p>Pre-Colombian civilisations made their mark with the vast pyramids of Teotihuac&aacute;n, stunning temples of Chich&eacute;n Itz&aacute; and countless other archaeological wonders. The Spanish heritage has also been well preserved, with charming towns built around shady plazas and whitewashed churches; San Miguel de Allende, Guanajuato and Dolores Hidalgo are treasures of the central Colonial Heartland.</p>
<p>Mexico today is a booming modern economy, led by its gargantuan capital, Mexico City. Once you adjust to the relentless pace of life in this metropolis, you can indulge in world-class museums, dine in exquisite restaurants, cut shapes in clubs and barter at sprawling markets. Beyond the modern cities, lie sleepy villages where age-old customs and ancient beliefs endure. San Cristobal de las Casas is a major hub, ringed by indigenous villages, with churches combining pagan beliefs with Roman Catholicism. Across the country, lively festivals reflect this blending of faiths, most famously at the Day of the Dead ceremony.</p>
<p>For visitors seeking outdoor adventure, Mexico delivers. Nature lovers can go whale watching in Baja California, reef diving off the Yucat&aacute;n Peninsula and trekking through the jungle to glowing blue lagoons bordering Guatemala. Adrenaline activities are in amply supply too, from canyoning in Veracruz and hang-gliding in Hidalgo to volcano climbing, caving and river rafting.</p>
<p>One of the great joys of a visit to Mexico is its cuisine. Emulated around the world, its crispy tacos, mole sauces and burritos are amongst the mouth-watering specialities on offer. They are best washed down with one of Mexico&rsquo;s many beers or a shot of mescal if you&rsquo;re in the party mood, which everyone else here seems to be.</p><p>As spicy as <em>salsa</em>, intoxicating as tequila and surreal as a Frida Kahlo canvas, Mexico fills the senses, energizes the intellect and nourishes the soul. This huge country encompasses epic landscapes; from northern deserts and snowy peaks of the central sierra, to the jungle highlands of southern Chiapas and the beaches of the Yucat&aacute;n Peninsula.&nbsp;Pre-Colombian civilisations made their mark with the vast pyramids of Teotihuac&aacute;n, stunning temples of Chich&eacute;n Itz&aacute; and countless other archaeological wonders. The Spanish heritage has also been well preserved, with charming towns built around shady plazas and whitewashed churches; San Miguel de Allende, Guanajuato and Dolores Hidalgo are treasures of the central Colonial Heartland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
