<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Moldova" ColCode="mda" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="md" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Moldova]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Very mild and pleasant. Temperate with warm summers 20 to 23°C (68 to 73°F), crisp, sunny autumns and cold, sometimes snowy, winters.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mediumweights, thick coat and waterproof shoes for winter; lightweights for summer. A light raincoat is useful.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The railway in Moldova is run by Calea Ferata din Moldova (CFM)<em> </em>(tel: +373 22 252 737/5; <a href="http://www.railway.md/" target="_blank">www.railway.md/</a>). There are connections to most parts of the country and beyond.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Roads outside of Chisinau are generally in a bad condition. Driving standards are poor.</p><p>These can be found everywhere. You should negotiate fares in advance, though drivers prefer to charge per hour.</p><p>A valid national driving licence, plus a Green Card and your vehicle registration documents if bringing your own car.</p><p>You must keep your headlights switched on at all times from 1 November until 31 March.</p><p>There are a few car hire companies in Chisinau.</p><p>You must keep your headlights switched on at all times from 1 November until 31 March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buses, trolleybuses and minibuses are cheap but notoriously crowded and unreliable. You can buy tickets for buses and trolleybuses from kiosks or on board the vehicle. Minibus tickets are available from the driver.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier is&nbsp;Air Moldova&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.airmoldova.md" target="_blank">www.airmoldova.md</a>), which operates direct flights from the UK, among other destinations.&nbsp;Wizz (<a href="http://www.wizzair.com" target="_blank">www.wizzair.com</a>) also has non-stop flights to Chisinau from London.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chisinau-international-airport">Chisinau International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 50 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 11 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chisinau International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport.md<p>The airport is located 11km (7 miles) southeast of central Chişinău.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+373 22 525 111</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London and Berlin it's possible to travel by rail to Chisinau via Bucharest. Tickets are inexpensive between Hungary and Moldova, and there are the options of second-class four-berth sleeper carriages or first-class with two berths. There's a bar car selling snacks and drinks, but no restaurant, so take your own food.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Local payphones are cheap and plentiful. They work by phonecards available at kiosks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone operators. Coverage is generally good all over the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet cafes in main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Moldovan constitution guarantees freedom of the press, but laws prohibit defamation and insulting the state. Political parties publish their own newspapers, which often criticise the government. Moldovan editions of Russian titles are among the most-popular Russian-language publications.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All mail to and from Moldova may be subject to long delays. There are express mail services in Chisinau.</p><p>Daily 0900-2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Emil Racovita</p><![CDATA[<p>Named after the eminent 19th century Romanian biologist Emil Racovita, the cave complex in the village of Criva in Moldova is one of the biggest in the world. A network of underground galleries stretches over 89,000m (291,991 ft) and is split across several levels. Discovered in 1959, the cave is the third largest gypsum cave in the world and parts of the complex are only accessible via large wells. The huge caves have been given names such as Cinderella's Hall and Dacia's Hall reflecting their size and grandeur and there are also several underground lakes including the Blue Lake and the Dinosaur Lake. There are no trail markers but visitors are able to explore the caves in small groups with an experienced guide.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Chekhov Drama Theatre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watch a performance at the former Chisinau Choral Synagogue that today houses the Chekhov Drama Theatre.</p>]]><p><b>Chisinau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the Moldovan capital of Chisinau (formerly Kishinev), which stands on the banks of the small River Byk. Visit the Pushkin House - the place where the great Russian poet spent his days in exile and where he began working on his epic poem <em>Eugene Onegin</em>.</p>]]><p><b>Chisinau Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Swim at the man-made Chisinau Lake with picturesque bathing beaches, and boats for hire.</p>]]><p><b>Chisinau cemeteries</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pay respects at the two old cemeteries in Chisinau, the Armenian Cemetery and the Jewish Cemetery. The latter is famous as the burial place for the victims of the Chisinau Pogrom in 1903.</p>]]><p><b>Emil Racovita</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Named after the eminent 19th century Romanian biologist Emil Racovita, the cave complex in the village of Criva in Moldova is one of the biggest in the world. A network of underground galleries stretches over 89,000m (291,991 ft) and is split across several levels. Discovered in 1959, the cave is the third largest gypsum cave in the world and parts of the complex are only accessible via large wells. The huge caves have been given names such as Cinderella's Hall and Dacia's Hall reflecting their size and grandeur and there are also several underground lakes including the Blue Lake and the Dinosaur Lake. There are no trail markers but visitors are able to explore the caves in small groups with an experienced guide.</p>]]><p><b>Explore forests</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spot indigenous flora and fauna in the country's forests, such as the Stanca-Jeloboc forest.</p>]]><p><b>History and Regional Lore Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Find out about Moldova's history in the History and Regional Lore Museum, in Chisinau, presented in a beautiful Turkish-style complex, while the Fine Arts Museum houses good examples of Russian, West European and Moldovan paintings, sculpture and applied arts.</p>]]><p><b>Monument of Stefan cel Mare</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the Monument of Stefan cel Mare (Stefan the Great) which was the focal point of meetings and violent clashes between Moldova's Nationalists and pro-Soviet supporters in 1990-91.</p>]]><p><b>Thermal spas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax and unwind in Cahul - a town famous for its thermal spas and mud treatments and also a good local theatre. Hirjauca is a renowned spa in the area.</p>]]><p><b>Vineyard visit</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sup the national wines - the vineyards and wine cellars of Mileshti and Krikova-Veki are renowned throughout the region.</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at Benderi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wonder at Benderi (Tighina) - one of the oldest towns in Moldova. Its beautiful 17th-century fortress, as well as the town itself, were seriously damaged during the fighting in 1992.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$2.6 billion (2006).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, textiles and machinery.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Mineral products and fuel, machinery and equipment, chemicals, and textiles.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Russia, Romania, Ukraine, Germany and Italy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Moldova remains one of the poorest countries in Europe. It has a temperate climate and good farmland but has no major mineral deposits and must import almost all of its energy supplies. As a result, the economy depends heavily on agriculture, particularly fruits, vegetables, wine and tobacco.<br /><br />GDP grew by 6% or more every year between 2000-05, though this was based largely on consumption fed by money received from Moldovans working outside of the country - about 25% of working-age Moldovans are employed abroad. The country had an unemployment rate of 7.3% in 2005.<br /><br />The illegal separatist regime in the Transistria region also continues to drag on the Moldovan economy.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Formal business etiquette applies to Moldovan business meetings, and smart attire is required.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chamber of Commerce and Industry of the Republic of Moldova</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (22) 221 552
					Website:http://www.chamber.md
					Address: ,151 Stefan cel Mare Str,Chisinau,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of small restaurants and coffee shops. The service tends to be slow, but the cuisine is delicious, with a range of traditional national dishes and European food.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; <em>Mititeyi</em> (small grilled sausages with onion and pepper).<br />
&bull; <em>Mamaliga</em> (thick, sticky maize pie) which is served with <em>brinza</em> (feta cheese).<br />
&bull; <em>Tocana</em> (pork stew) should be tried with sweet-and-sour watermelons and apples.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>5 to 10% will be gladly accepted.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Chisinau, there is a good selection of theatres and concert halls, and an opera house. The Eminescu Music and Drama Theatre specialises in Romanian productions, as does the Youth Theatre Luceafarul (Poetic Star). All performances in the Chekhov Drama Theatre are exclusively in Russian (the building used to be the Chisinau Choral Synagogue). The Philharmonia Concert Hall houses Moldova's Symphony Orchestra. It is also the base for the folklore Doina Choir, the internationally-renowned Zhok National Dance Ensemble and the Fluerash Orchestra of National Music. Russian and Romanian productions can be seen in the puppet theatre Licurici (Glow-worm). The country is famous for its tradition of folk arts and there are many lively musical groups (<em>Tarafs</em>), which play a variety of rare folk instruments including the <em>tsambal</em> (not unlike a dulcimer), <em>cimpoi</em> (bagpipe), <em>fluier</em> and <em>nai</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Good buys are the vividly-coloured costumes, handmade carpets and locally-produced wines and brandies. The main open-air market (<em>tolchok</em>) is on Calea Mosilor, about 10 minutes' drive away from central Chisinau. Although crowded, it sells everything and is a good place for bargains. There are several craft centres where trades include woodcarving, enamel painting, embroidery, weaving, and the making of musical instruments.</p><p>Larger shops open Mon-Fri 0800-2000; all others open 0900-1700. Grocery stores are generally open seven days a week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a small selection of hotels in the capital Chisinau, most of which are located close to the railway station and in the city centre. There are some lower-grade hotels in other towns. <br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> From <strong>1-star</strong> (basic facilities) to <strong>5-stars</strong> (larger capacity and greater facilities of a higher standard).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a small selection of hotels in the capital Chisinau, most of which are located close to the railway station and in the city centre. There are some lower-grade hotels in other towns. <br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> From <strong>1-star</strong> (basic facilities) to <strong>5-stars</strong> (larger capacity and greater facilities of a higher standard).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a small selection of hotels in the capital Chisinau, most of which are located close to the railway station and in the city centre. There are some lower-grade hotels in other towns. <br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> From <strong>1-star</strong> (basic facilities) to <strong>5-stars</strong> (larger capacity and greater facilities of a higher standard).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The standard of medical care in Moldova is below that available in some other European countries. Non Russian/Romanian speakers may encounter difficulties in a medical emergency. The embassy (see &lt;em&gt;Contact Addresses&lt;/em&gt;) has details of English-speaking doctors.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A number of large medical institutions operate in Chisinau, including the Republican Clinical Hospital. Elderly travellers and those with existing health problems may be at risk owing to inadequate medical facilities.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
All services and prescriptions are charged for and doctors and hospitals often expect immediate cash payment; medical insurance is strongly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated but bottled water is available and advised. Local meat, poultry, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccination is sometimes recommended for tick-borne encephalitis. Travellers staying longer than three months may be required to produce proof of HIV-negative status.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Orthodox Easter Monday :
							09 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Victory and Commemoration Day :
							09 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							27 August </p><p>Limba Noastra (National Language Day) :
							31 August </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Moldova by travellers aged 18 years or older without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or cigarillos.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine and 5L of beer.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of &euro;300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Check with the Ministry of Culture and Tourism before exporting items of cultural value; the export of certain artefacts is prohibited and other goods may require a permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Leu (MDL; symbol (plural) Lei) = 100 bani. Notes are in denominations of Lei500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and Leu1. Coins are in denominations of 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 bani.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged in hotels or bureaux de change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards are only accepted by a few banks. Moldova is essentially a cash-only economy. There are ATMs in Chisinau and other main towns.</p><p>There are ATMs in Chisinau and other main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are not generally accepted, though a few banks may exchange them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800. Some banks and bureaux de change are open Saturdays and Sundays also.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Moldova, a passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airport transit visa: &pound;23; transit visa: &pound;40; short-term visa: &pound;56; long-term visa: &pound;72. There is no fee for children under 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: up to five days per entry within a period of up to a year; short-term visa: 90 days within a six-month period; long-term visa: valid for up to a year, with entries of no more than 90 days in each six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing takes five days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You cannot usually extend tourist visas.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[47.203031]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[28.473037]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>33,800 sq km (13,050 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,062,862 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>104.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chisinau (Kishinev).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Moldova is a small landlocked state in southeastern Europe - one of the most highly populated republics of the former USSR. To the north, east and south, Moldova is bound by Ukraine; to the west by Romania. The River Prut constitutes the border with Romania. The country has rich pastures and wooded slopes, ideal for wine-growing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mostly Eastern Orthodox Christian and other Christian denominations. A small amount of the population are Jewish.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dress should be casual but conservative. For official engagements, men should wear a jacket and tie.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two circular pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Pavel Filip since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Igor Dodon since 2016, has again been temporarily suspended in September 2018.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Having declared its independence from the Soviet Union in August 1991 &ndash; and gained formal recognition by the United Nations a year later &ndash; Moldova is now well established as a European nation.</p>
<p>The region has been inhabited since Palaeolithic times, more than a million years ago, and during the Stone Age its population farmed, hunted and made distinctive pottery. The first millennium saw the area occupied by various outside forces including Goths, Huns, Avars, Magyars, Cumans, Mongols and Tatars before the Principality of Moldova was established in 1359.</p>
<p>For most of the 19th century Moldova was split between the Ottoman Empire, Romania and Russia, then in the wake of the Russian Revolution the region voted to become part of Romania. The new Soviet Union objected and by 1924 had brought it within Moscow&rsquo;s orbit.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the Molotov-Ribbentrop Pact in 1940 Moldova was occupied by Soviet troops before the Nazi invasion of the USSR put it first under German control then Romanian. The Red Army overran it in 1944 and the Moscow government began its policy of detaching Moldova from its Romanian roots. Change gathered pace with the instigation of Gorbachev&rsquo;s reform programme and by the late 1980s Moldova started to move towards independence.</p>
<p>Since the early-1990s, Moldovan politics have been dominated by the sometimes-violent friction between the Transnistria region &ndash; a sliver of land to the east of the Dniester River mainly populated by ethnic Russians &ndash; and the rest of the country. Attached to Moldova by Stalinist social engineering, Transnistria remains essential to Moldova for economic reasons but is run by its own parliament even though the United Nations considers it to be part of Moldova.</p>
<p>In 2014, following the example of the controversial annexation of Crimea by Russian forces, the breakaway Transnistrian government asked to join the Russian Federation and in July 2015 mobilised men aged 18-27 amid fears it could become an East-West flashpoint.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull;	Moldova has competed in the Eurovision Song Contest since 2005, with the pelvic-thrusting antics of Sergy Stepanov, sax player with the band SunStroke Project, achieving viral status in 2010.<br />
&bull;	The national sport is <em>tranta</em>, a form of upright wrestling.<br />
&bull;	It is estimated that up to one million Moldovans are working abroad.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Moldova in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 8996 0546.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.britania.mfa.gov.md</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 8996 0546.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Edensor Road<br/>5 Dolphin Square<br/>London<br/>W4 2ST<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Moldova in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 667 1130.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.sua.mfa.md</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 667 1130.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2101 S Street NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Moldova]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(22) 225 902.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-chisinau/office/british-embassy</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(22) 225 902.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1730; Fri 0900-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>18/1 Nicolae Iorga Str.<br/>Chisinau<br/>MD-2012<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Moldova is a largely overlooked destination, as yet untouched by the budget airline brigade. But it shouldn't be. In this land-locked Eastern European country, you can wander round vast monasteries, trek through ancient forests, or sample the local wines. Rich with history and fertile soils that produce abundant vineyards, Moldova is a special country despite its lack of fame, and one well worth getting to know.</p><p>Despite remaining one of the poorest countries in Europe, the people are friendly and welcoming, and the main hubs, such as the capital Chişinău, have everything a visitor could need. Although few outsiders have heard about it as a viable city break destination, Chişinău has plenty going on. There's a buzzing cafe-bar and restaurant scene, while its cathedrals, monuments and museums have survived despite the city taking a serious pounding from aerial bombardments during World War II. One such survivor not to miss is the house where the writer Pushkin spent his days in exile penning some of his most famous works.</p><p>The most obvious selling point of Moldova is probably that it's almost the least known spot in Europe. With only a few thousand visiting the country in every year – even neighbouring Romania and Ukraine see far higher foreign footfall – it's mainly favoured by intrepid backpacking completists. But there's much more to the country than this.</p><p>A largely unspoilt, natural hinterland with plenty in the way of traditional culture and village life still going, Moldova can feel like a fragment of old Europe, at least if you get beyond the cities. Cross the Dniestr River, and you'll find yourself in the beguiling separatist Russian-speaking province of Transdniestr, all Soviet architecture and Lenin busts.</p><p>Then there's the wine. The Moldovan grape's slowly fermenting fame means that the wine tourism industry is just beginning to emerge. The upshot? You can try one of Europe's best, most unique wines in a hidden land that will surely have more than its fair of tourists in the years to come.</p><p>Rich with history and fertile soils that produce abundant vineyards, Moldova is an unjustifiably forgotten tourist destination, as yet untouched by the budget airline brigade.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
