<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Monaco" ColCode="mco" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mc" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Monaco]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Monaco has a mild climate throughout the year, the hottest months being July and August, and the coolest being January and February. Rain mostly falls during the cooler winter months and there is an average of only 60 days' rain per year.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights are worn, with a warm wrap for cooler summer evenings. Light- to mediumweights are advised for winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no airport in Monaco. The nearest airport is <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nice">Nice</a> (NCE) (Nice-Cote d'Azur) (<a href="http://www.nice.aeroport.fr" target="_blank">www.nice.aeroport.fr</a>), 22km (14 miles) from Monaco. There is a direct bus service from Nice Airport to Monaco (journey time - 45 minutes). A helicopter service run by H&eacute;li-Air Monaco (YO) (<a href="http://www.heliairmonaco.com" target="_blank">www.heliairmonaco.com</a>) links Monaco with the airport (journey time - 7 minutes).</p>
<p>Airlines operating direct flights to Nice from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Norwegian (<a href="http://www.norwegian.com" target="_blank">www.norwegian.com</a>). Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) offers direct flights from the  USA.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Nice: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 8 hours 10 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main harbours are at Condamine (Hercule port) and Fontvieille, which are equipped to handle yachts of all tonnages.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An extensive train service, including daily and overnight through-trains, runs through the principality to all neighbouring towns. The TGV M&eacute;diterran&eacute;e line runs between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a> and Monaco (journey time - 6 hours). High-speed trains on this route run through the beautiful Burgundy and Provencal countryside. Direct trains also run to Genoa&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/milan">Milan</a>&nbsp;in Italy.</p>
<p>French rail operator SNCF (tel: 3635, in France only or +33 892 353 535, in France; <a href="http://www.sncf.com" target="_blank">www.sncf.com</a>) runs most trains to Monaco.  Trenitalia (tel: +39 6 6847 5475, in Italy; <a href="http://www.trenitalia.com" target="_blank">www.trenitalia.com</a>) runs trains from Italy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Azur Express Tourist Train</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Monaco-Ville (the Old Town), hop on the Azur Express Tourist Train, which offers commentaries in French, Italian, German and English.</p>]]><p><b>Bask on Lavartto Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This free public access beach is a perfect escape for some sun and sea. Clean and safe, all you need to take is a towel, sun block and binoculars for yacht spotting. There are also handy caf&eacute;s and kiosks nearby for refreshments and light lunches. If you're curious to see what 'real' people living in Monaco do for fun, this is it - the millionaires have their private beaches.</p>]]><p><b>Fontvieille</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover more than 180 varieties of rose at the Princess Grace Rose Garden. The Museum of Stamps and Coins features rare philatelic items from the postal history of the Principality. The permanent exhibition of Prince Rainier III's Private Collection of Classic Cars, with over 100 classic cars, is nearby. The Naval Museum and the Zoological Terraces are also located here.</p>]]><p><b>Gamble</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gamble in style at the Grand Casino in Monte Carlo. The casino is located in Monaco's most exclusive <em>quartier</em>, where all the most luxurious and fashionable hotels, restaurants and boutiques can also be found (including the famous Hôtel de Paris). The building's style is distinctively grand and luxurious and the casino is linked to the Salle Garnier Opera House by an impressive atrium lined with 28 Ionic Golden Circle columns made of onyx. The minimum age for entering any of Monte Carlo's casinos is 21. You will need your passport at the door as well as an entry fee of â¬10.</p>]]><p><b>Gardens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Chill out at the serene and sea-facing Saint-Martin Gardens (also in the Old Town), which inspired the poet Guillaume Apollinaire between 1887 and 1889. Alternatively, visit the Japanese Gardens, right next to the sea.</p>]]><p><b>Monaco Cathedral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Consecrated in 1875, Saint Nicholas Cathedral is a special place for Monegasques. It was where Princess Grace married Prince Rainier as well as where they have both been buried. The Grimaldi family have buried their family here for centuries and the tombs are beautiful. <strong></strong><strong>Museums</strong>The Oceanographic Museum and Aquarium, whose grandiose facade rises spectacularly out of the sea, houses a world-renowned collection of marine fauna and interactive exhibits. Other museums include the Museum of Napoleonic Souvenirs and Collection of the Palace's Historic Archives, which exhibits thousands of objects relating to the First Empire (Napoleon I); the Wax Museum of the Princes of Monaco; and the Monte Carlo Story, a multivision show about Monaco's history.</p>]]><p><b>Place du Palais</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At Monte Carlo's spiritual heart is Monaco-Ville (old town) where the Place du Palais houses the Prince's Palace and State Apartments. Built around 1215, the palace's focal points are the Throne Room and the Main Courtyard with its horse-shaped marble staircase, adorned with millions of geometric patterns. Attend the Changing of the Palace Guard (admission free), which takes place daily, just before noon (1155).</p>]]><p><b>Port Hercule</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spend a morning having a look at the multi million dollar yachts moored at this first class harbour. There are several places where you can sit and have a drink while admiring the vast amount wealth floating before you.</p>]]><p><b>Relax at a spa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax at Monaco's health spas and beauty centres, the most famous one being the Thermes Marins de Monte Carlo (<a href="http://www.montecarlospa.com/" target="_blank">www.montecarlospa.com/</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Take a helicopter ride</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a panoramic flight over the principality and the surrounding area with Heli-Air Monaco (tel: 0826 105 050; <a href="http://www.heliairmonaco.com/" target="_blank">www.heliairmonaco.com</a>). Trips last from 10 to 40 minutes.</p>]]><p><b>Watch Formula One</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Attend the world-famous Monaco Grand Prix Formula One race, which takes place every year in the principality's narrow winding streets, attracting thousands of spectators. Another favourite is the Historic Grand Prix, which is held every other year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>Monaco does not publish its GDP.</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Pharmaceuticals, perfumes and clothing.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Electricity.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France and Italy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Service industries, especially property and financial services, account for the bulk of Monaco's economy. Tourism is also a major source of revenue, contributing about 25% of government revenue, as well as being the mainstay of local retail businesses. There is also a highly successful, custom-built business conference venue. The dearth of land precludes any agriculture, but there is some light industry, the main products of which are pharmaceuticals, plastics, electronics, paper and textiles. <br /><br />Monaco attracts many extremely wealthy individuals as residents, by virtue of its pleasant climate, reputation and environment as well as the absence of income or inheritance tax and lack of financial reporting requirements. Migrant, non-resident labour supplies the menial workforce.<br /><br />Almost all the principality's external trade is conducted with France - and France, along with Italy, supplies the bulk of Monaco's visitors (both as tourists and foreign labour). <br />Monaco is a year-round leisure and business destination and there are extensive conference facilities. The Forum Grimaldi Cultural and Exhibition Centre, one of Europe's largest venues for conference events, provides three terraced auditoria, the largest with 1,900 seats and two massive exhibitions halls. Large parts of the new complex are built under water.<br /><br />Other conference venues include the 1,100-capacity Convention Centre and Auditorium (built on land reclaimed from the sea), including technical support and exhibition areas; the International Conference Centre (with a capacity for 450 persons); and the Meridien Beach Plaza Club, which can seat up to 1,624 people. For further information, contact the Direction du Tourisme (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A suit should be worn and prior appointments are necessary. Business meetings are formal. It is considered impolite to begin a conversation in French and then revert to English.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1200 and 1400-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Grimaldi Forum Monaco</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 9999 2000
					Website:http://www.grimaldiforum.com
					Address: ,(Information on Conferences/Conventions),,]]><b>Conseil Economique et Social</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 9330 2082.
					Website:
					Address: ,rue Louis Notari,Monaco,MC 98000 ]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Restaurants in Monaco offer a wide choice of food. Service and standards are excellent. Cuisine is similar to France.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull; <em>Barbagiuan</em> (a type of pastry filled with rice and pumpkin). <br /><em>&bull; Fougasse</em> (fragrant orange flower water pastries decorated with nuts, almonds and aniseed). <br /><em>&bull; Socca</em> (chick-pea flour pancakes).<br /><em>&bull; Stocafi</em> (dried cod cooked in a tomato sauce).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Hotel and restaurant bills generally include a 15% service charge; however, where this is not added it is customary to leave a 15% tip.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Monaco is not a particularly vibrant place for night owls. Restaurants shut quite early in comparison to European capitals and there are only a few night clubs, all housed in the city's James Bond-esque casinos. Jimmy Z's, located in the Sporting Club is a Monte Carlo establishment, where rich young things flock to the dance floor in designer heels. The world-famous Monte Carlo Casino is another grand complex worth visiting, if not for a drink and dance, then just to look at. Casinos put on nightly shows, cabarets and the like - all thoroughly entertaining, if a tad OTT.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Monégasque products include perfume, chocolates, ceramics, clothing, hosiery, shoes, books, jewellery and embroidery. Handcrafted items are sold at Boutique du Rocher, a charity of the late Princess Grâce de Monaco. Monégasque stamps are highly prized by collectors.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1230 and 1500-1830.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some of the most luxurious hotels and conference facilities are centred in Monte Carlo, and all are equipped with extensive modern amenities. <br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Monaco are graded <strong>1- </strong>to <strong>4-star deluxe</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some of the most luxurious hotels and conference facilities are centred in Monte Carlo, and all are equipped with extensive modern amenities. <br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Monaco are graded <strong>1- </strong>to <strong>4-star deluxe</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some of the most luxurious hotels and conference facilities are centred in Monte Carlo, and all are equipped with extensive modern amenities. <br /><br /><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Monaco are graded <strong>1- </strong>to <strong>4-star deluxe</strong>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Sainte-D̩vote Day :
							2018<br/>27 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>National Day :
							19 November </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>See France section for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[43.739809]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[7.427046]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2 sq km (0.8 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>37,863 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>18,865.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Monaco.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Monaco is second only to the Vatican as the smallest independent state in Europe. Set on the Mediterranean coast of France just a few miles from the Italian border, the country is a narrow ribbon of coastline backed by the Alpes-Maritimes foothills, creating a natural amphitheatre overlooking the sea.</p>
<p>Monaco-Ville is set on a rocky promontory dominating the coast. The Palace is the home of the Grimaldi family, the oldest ruling house in Europe. Monaco-Ville also boasts a fine Romanesque cathedral among its other attractions. La Condamine is the area around the Port, while Monte-Carlo is the main centre for business and entertainment. Fontvieille has been set aside as an area for new light industrial and residential development.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>95% Roman Catholic (Monaco has a Catholic Bishop), with Anglican minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Casual wear is acceptable for daytime and dress is the same as for the rest of the French Riviera. Smart restaurants, dining rooms, clubs and the casino's private rooms require more formal attire. Handshaking and, more familiarly, kissing both cheeks, are accepted forms of greeting.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Minister of State Serge Telle since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prince Albert II since 2005.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The history of Monaco is inseparable from that of the House of Grimaldi, who descended from Genoa and rose to prominence during the 12th century. In the late-13th century, with the Holy Roman Empire rife with internal strife, the Grimaldis took refuge in Provence where Fran&ccedil;ois Grimaldi led a group of partisans into the fortress of Monaco in 1297. The family has ruled the region ever since, preserving its independence through a mixture of good luck and cunning diplomacy.</p>
<p>At various times, they were allied to almost every power in the region, particularly during the Italian Wars in the late-15th and early-16th centuries. Monaco is ideally placed geographically to either help or hinder the repeated attempts by French kings to conquer Italy. The principality&rsquo;s Machiavellian diplomacy was richly rewarded in 1612 when Honor&eacute; II was granted the title of prince by the French Crown. He signed a treaty of friendship with France and Monaco has been independent ever since, with a brief interruption during the French Revolution.</p>
<p>The Grimaldi motto &ndash; <em>'DeoJuvante</em>' (&lsquo;With God's Help&rsquo;) &ndash; provides another possible explanation for the survival of this tiny country, which became an independent state under French protection in 1861. Paris has long since maintained a firm grip on the principality through its ambassador and key appointees in the executive and judiciary.</p>
<p>In 1993, Monaco joined the United Nations, becoming its smallest member and in 2004 joined the Council of Europe. It is not a formal member of the EU but does follow various EU policies, notably in customs and border control. Its principal attraction to the outside world lies in the provision of tax concessions and discreet banking facilities and this has periodically led to spats with France and the international community.</p>
<p>Monaco is a constitutional monarchy and following the death of Prince Rainier in 2005, his son Prince Albert II was enthroned as head of state. In 2010 he appointed a Frenchman, Michel Roger, as Minister of State, the head of government.</p>
<p><strong>Do you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Angered by its tax haven status, President Charles de Gaulle ordered the blockade of Monaco in 1963.<br />
&bull;	Monaco is the world&rsquo;s second smallest country by area.<br />
&bull;	The principality has no navy or air force, but with 515 officers for 36,000 inhabitants, it does have one of the largest per capita police forces in the world. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Marseille]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(04) 9115 7210.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(04) 9115 7210.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>24 avenue du Prado<br/>Marseille<br/>13006<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Monaco in the United States]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234 1530.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.monaco-usa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234 1530.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Suite 2K - 100<br/>3400 International Drive NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008-3006<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Consulate General of the Principality of Monaco in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7318 1083.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.monaco-consulate-uk.gouv.mc</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7318 1083.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1200 and 1400-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>7 Upper Grosvenor Street<br/>London<br/>W1K 2LX<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From the multi-million pound yachts glinting in Monte Carlo harbour, to the endless flow of golden champagne, Monaco oozes privilege. Celebrities flock to this Mediterranean members-only club, with its opulent lifestyle, discreet banking facilities and heavily policed streets.</p><p>There's more to this 200-hectare principality than meets the eye, though, with some terrific restaurants and an interesting history that continues to beguile to this day. In this, the second smallest country after the Vatican, natives still speak the Monégasque dialect, which sits somewhere between French and Italian. Meanwhile, Monaco's citizens famously don't have to pay taxes, which has partly made it an attractive place to live for some of the world's richest people.</p><p>For visitors wishing to bask in some Monaco glitz, there are big annual events such as the Tennis Masters Series in April and the Formula 1 Grand Prix in May. Other festivals include the Monaco International Non Violent Film Festival, the Monte Carlo Opera and the annual Spring Arts Festival.</p><p>In Monaco, you can expect plenty of luxury hotel towers, glamorous nightclubs and grand casinos. The latter attraction is tied up with the modern fate of Monaco. The tiny country's history of gambling dates back to the 1850s when the head of state commissioned the building of a casino to provide him with income, without having to increase taxes on his citizens. At first, the casino remained bizarrely empty, until a railroad connected Monaco with the rest of the world. It was soon doing so well that the principality was able to do away with taxes altogether. Overnight, Monaco became popular for Europe's most hedonistic elites, who came for the ever-flowing champagne and renowned opera productions.</p><p>Away from the glamour, Monaco's balmy climate and seaside location make it a naturally beautiful place to visit. You can enjoy scenic walking routes along pretty costal bays, and stop for a drink at many al fresco cafés. For those with a couple of days to spare, Provence, the French Riviera and Italy are all within easy reach.</p>From the multi million pound yachts glinting in Monte Carlo harbour, to the endless flow of golden champagne, Monaco oozes privilege.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
