<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Mongolia" ColCode="mng" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mn" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Mongolia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A dry climate with short, mild summers and long, severe winters (November to February). In the depths of the winter (December and January), temperatures can remain below zero degrees for several weeks. Cold snaps can bring the temperature to minus 30&deg;C (86&deg;F). Spring (March-May) brings unsettled weather, strong winds and wild fluctuations in temperature. Summers (June-August) are warm across the country, particularly in the Gobi Desert where temperatures can reach 40&deg;C (104&deg;F). Thunderstorms are common in late summer. September and October are cool in the north but quite pleasant in Gobi areas. July and August are generally the best months for travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mediumweights are worn during summer, with very warm heavyweights advised for winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internal flights are operated by AeroMongolia (<a href="http://www.aeromongolia.mn">www.aeromongolia.mn</a>). MIAT&nbsp;Mongolian Airlines (<a href="http://www.miat.com">www.miat.com</a>) operates international flights only. Flying domestically can vastly decrease travel times; for example a trip from Ulaanbaatar to Bayan Olgii is either 60 hours by road or four hours by air.</p>
<p>Flights are available to most provincial capitals but any flight between provincial capitals will be routed through Ulaanbaatar. Book well in advance for July and August flights as these are often full. Flights to Bayan Olgii are full ahead of the annual Eagle Festival in October.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main rail line in Mongolia runs from north to south: Sukhbaatar-Darkhan-Ulaanbaatar-Sainshand. A branch line serves the city of Erdenet. The domestic railway ticket office is located in the building next to the main railway station.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alternative transport in Mongolia includes Jeeps, camels or horses, which are available for trekkers and special-interest travellers. Cycle touring is also popular but you should bring all your own equipment.</p>
<p>Driving standards are poor. In Ulaanbaatar, roads are congested. Ideally, hire a professional driver rather than attempting to drive yourself.</p><p>The national highway system is rudimentary and most of the roads in the countryside are little more than dust tracks.</p><p>Taxis in Ulaanbaatar can be either official or non-official. When possible, use offical taxis as they are more reliable. The main company is Noyon Zuuch Taxi (tel: +976 1950). Fares are per kilometre; for the latest rates ask your hotel or guesthouse.</p><p>Car hire in Mongolia is available through tourism companies. Nearly all come with a driver due to the poor driving conditions. Self-drive cars are available through Drive Mongolia (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.drivemongolia.com">www.drivemongolia.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are bus and trolleybus services in Ulaanbaatar. However, buses tend to be crowded and pickpockets are a danger. Routes are also difficult to understand and maps are only marked in Mongolian. Most foreigners use taxis to get around the city. Other cities have limited (or no) local transportation options.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Mongolia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">khovd</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4/5 days</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Mongolia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">erdenet</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Mongolia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">darkhan</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Mongolia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">dalanzadgad</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">12.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mongolia's national carrier is MIAT&nbsp;Mongolian Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.miat.com">www.miat.com</a>). From the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you can fly to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/beijing">Beijing</a> with Air China (<a href="http://www.airchina.com" target="_blank">www.airchina.com</a>) or British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and take a connecting flight with MIAT. Alternatively, Aeroflot (<a href="http://www.aeroflot.com" target="_blank">www.aeroflot.com</a>) offers connecting flights via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a>. Flights to Mongolia increase in price in July, to coincide with the peak summer travel season. Discounts are available in winter.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - at least 12 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 20 hours (including stopovers).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the price of the ticket.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ulaanbaatar Chinggis Khaan International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport.mn<p>The airport is 20km (12 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ulaanbaatar is linked to Russia&nbsp;and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> by the Trans-Mongolian Railway. An express train runs between Moscow, Ulaanbaatar and Beijing. Trains on international routes have sleeping and restaurant cars. There are also other trains from Ulaanbaatar to Beijing and Ulaanbaatar to Moscow. Local trains also operate to the border towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Area codes: Darkhan: 01 372, Erdenet: 01 352, Khovd: 01 432. Ulaanbaatar has several area codes, the most common area code is 11. However, if a phone number begins with a 23, 24 or 25 then the code is 21. If the phone number begins with a 26 the code is 51. International calls can be made from telephone exchanges in Ulaanbaatar and provincial capitals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone operators. Coverage includes large cities, provincial capitals, many county centres and main roads. Mongolia has four mobile phone service providers, two run on the GSM network and two run on the CDMA network. SIM cards are available at low cost from local phone shops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Access is available in Ulaanbaatar at business centres (often located in hotels), Internet caf&eacute;s and at the telephone exchange on Suhkbaatar Square. Many caf&eacute;s, restaurants and hotels in Ulaanbaatar offer free Wi-Fi access. Free Wi-Fi is also available in Sukhbaatar Square. Every provincial capital has a reliable Internet caf&eacute; at the central telecom office. Wi-Fi access outside Ulaanbaatar is rare. The Internet is open and unrestricted. High-speed access is available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In general the media are free, and sometimes outspoken in their criticism of the authorities. However, journalists risk imprisonment for defamation and violating 'state secrets'. The privately-run English language <em>UB Post</em> is published twice weekly. The government-owned Mongol Messenger is published once weekly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail abroad can be very slow. There is an express mail service available for a limited number of countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Amarbayasgalant Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the few monasteries to survive the Stalinist purges, Amarbayasgalant is considered one of the finest examples of pre-20th century architecture in Mongolia. The monastery is situated in a peaceful location in Selenge aimag. Ger (tent) camp accommodation is available. Other monasteries worth visiting include Erdene Zuu (Kharkhorin) and Gandan Monastery (Ulaanbaatar).</p>]]><p><b>Birdwatching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mongolia is home to 429 recorded bird species. With a strong pair of binoculars twitchers can spot falcons, eagles, vultures, swans, cranes and more. The best places to look are around the lakes in western Mongolia, such as Uvs Nuur or Khar Us Nuur.</p>]]><p><b>Camping</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In this land without fences you can pitch your tent any place that pleases you. Some of the best spots are in Khovsgol National Park, Terelj and Tavan Bogd National Park. Car camping is an option or you can hike between camping spots.</p>]]><p><b>Cross-country skiing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The vast steppes of Mongolia get plenty of snow in winter, making the country a great place for cross-country skiers. A good place to start is Terelj National Park, which has ger camps still operating in the winter months. It's best to bring your own equipment as the local stuff isn't very reliable.</p>]]><p><b>Fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The fishing in Mongolia is world-renowned. The big catch is taiman, the world's largest salmonoid. These beasts can live more than 50 years and grow up to 45kg. Catch and release is standard practice. Getting a fishing permit on your own can be difficult so travellers are encouraged to work with a licensed tour operator. See <a href="http://www.taiman.mn">www.taiman.mn</a>&nbsp;for further information.</p>]]><p><b>Ghengis Khan's birthplace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel to northern part of Khentii aimag, and you'll experience the boyhood home of Ghengis Khan. This landscape of beautiful lakes, rolling mountains and clear streams has changed little since the great warlord last pitched his tent here, some 800 years ago.</p>]]><p><b>Gobi Desert</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The mysterious Gobi Desert is not as barren as one may think. The vast area contains mountains, lakes, sand dunes and even an oasis or two. Visitors can hunt for dinosaur fossils, go on a camel trek or hike along the ice-filled gorge of Yolyn Am.</p>]]><p><b>Homestay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For a truly authentic experience, try to arrange a night in a ger (yurt). Staying with a nomad family is a fascinating experience and full of surprises. You'll get to taste local food, ride horse and help herd the sheep. Remember to bring some thoughtful gifts in exchange for hospitality.</p>]]><p><b>Horse Riding</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mongolians are avid horse riders and this is still the main form of transportation in rural areas. Visitors can sign up for a horse trek with a tour company or even organise their own horse expedition. Steppe Riders (<a href="http://www.stepperiders.mn/" target="_blank">www.stepperiders.mn</a>) provides introductory horse riding lessons.</p>]]><p><b>Lake Khovsgol</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Known as the 'pearl of Mongolia', this lake is ideal for fishing, camping, horse riding and hiking. The gateway to the area is the village of Khatgal, where lodge accommodation is available. In winter tour companies offer skating and dog sledding trips over the frozen lake.</p>]]><p><b>Monasteries</b></p><![CDATA[<p>After years of communist persecution, Mongolia is seeing a revival in Buddhism and you can visit a number of active monasteries. Don't miss the beautiful and well-maintained monasteries Erdene Zuu (near Kharkhorin), Amarbayasgalant (between Darkhan and Erdenet) and Gandan (Ulaanbaatar).</p>]]><p><b>Naadams</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This nomad sports extravaganza features horse racing, wrestling and archery. It's a great time to see Mongolians decked out in their festive gear and taking part in traditional sporting events. The biggest <em>naadam</em> is in Ulaanbaatar but more intimate <em>naadams</em> are held all around the country.</p>]]><p><b>National Museum of Mongolia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The National Museum in Ulaanbaatar shows off Mongolia's most prized archaeological finds and historical treasures. Ulaanbaatar has a number of other excellent museums, including the Zanabazar Museum of Buddhist Art and the Natural History Museum. All the regional capitals have their own modest museums.</p>]]><p><b>Tavan Bogd National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the best places in Mongolia for back country walking, this park is a high alpine zone with numerous lakes, forests and glaciated peaks. There are no set trails so a good map and a GPS or compass are essential. Khoton Lake is one of the best places for trekking within the park and in summer Kazakh families pasture their sheep on the shores of the lake. Other suggested hiking areas include Bogd Khan Uul and Otgontenger Uul.</p>]]><p><b>Wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bring a pair of binoculars and keep an eye out for gazelle bounding over the steppes, marmots scurrying over rocks and argali sheep perched on the mountaintops. Wolves, snow leopards and bears are harder to spot but keep your camera ready, just in case.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$11.16 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Copper, livestock, animal products, cashmere, wool, hide and coal.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, fuels, cars, food products, industrial consumer goods and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China (PR), Korea (Rep), Russian Federation, Japan and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mongolia's economy has traditionally been based on herding and agriculture. Mongolia has extensive mineral deposits; copper, coal, tin, tungsten and gold account for a large part of industrial production.<br />
<br />
Mongolia's economy continues to be heavily influenced by its neighbours. For example, Mongolia purchases over 90% of its petroleum products and a substantial amount of electric power from Russia, leaving it vulnerable to price increases. China is Mongolia's chief export partner.<br />
<br />
Remittances from Mongolians working abroad both legally and illegally are sizable, and money laundering is a growing concern. Registered unemployment was at 2.7% in 2007 but the real figure is 30% or more because so few register. Unemployment figures increased in early 2009 as the global economic downturn slowed the flow of money in the country.<br />
<br />
Mongolia, which joined the World Trade Organization in 1997, seeks to expand its participation and integration into Asian regional economic and trade regimes.<br />
For further information, contact the Mongolian Chamber of Commerce and Industry (see below).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits are recommended. Translator services should be arranged prior to departure for Mongolia, although an increasing number of executives speak English, and Russian is widely spoken. Government officials may not be available for meetings on weekends. Exchanging business cards is customary.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Mongolian Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (11) 327 176 ,312 501 ,323 974
					Website:http://www.mongolchamber.mn/
					Address: ,J Sambuu Street-11,Ulaanbaatar 211238,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Meat is the basis of the diet, primarily mutton, with goat, horse, camel and yak meat dishes also on offer. Rice, flour, potatoes and onions are other main ingredients while green vegetables are rarely encountered outside the capital. The local cooking is quite distinctive.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Traditional meals generally consist of boiled mutton with lots of fat and flour with either rice, pasta, noodles or dairy products.<br />
<em>&bull; Boodog</em> is the whole carcass of a goat or marmot roasted from the inside - the entrails and bones are taken out through the throat, the carcass is filled with burning hot stones and the neck tied tightly, and thus the goat is cooked from the inside to the outside.<br />
&bull; <em>Khorkhog </em>is popular in the Mongolian countryside.&nbsp;This meal consists of chopped up goat, potatoes and onions slowly steamed inside a metal container. Scalding hot rocks are placed inside the container to create the steam and once extracted it is customary to pass the stones from hand to hand.<br />
&bull; <em>Buuz </em>is the national food; a steamed dumpling filled with mutton. These are eaten in great quantities during the Tsaagan Sar (New Year) festival. You can find <em>buuz</em> in restaurants throughout Ulaanbaatar.&nbsp;<br />
<em>&bull; Khuushuur</em>&nbsp;is another popular food item. This deep fried mutton pancake is particularly popular during the summer Naadam festivities.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Many restaurants will add a sales tax.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Not customary, but this is changing and 10% is the norm if leaving a tip.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nightlife in Mongolia is varied, with evening performances at the State Opera and Ballet Theatre, State Drama Theatre and Puppet Theatre. The Moonstone Song &amp; Dance Ensemble perform at Tsuki House. The most popular cultural show is staged by the Tumen Ekh Song &amp; Dance Ensemble at the State Youth &amp; Children&rsquo;s Theatre (in Nairamdal Park). Provincial capitals also have theatres although performances are generally only staged during holidays. The Tengis Cinema and Urgoo Cinema in Ulaanbaatar both feature Hollywood and Korean films, as well as Mongolian movies when they appear.</p>
<p>Ulaanbaatar is teeming with bars, discos and restaurants. The best places to hear live music are River Sounds (Choidog Street) and Grand Khaan Irish Pub (Seoul Street). A popular live music genre in Mongolia&nbsp;is a four- or five-piece band that plays Western style rock music with traditional Mongolian instruments. Night entertainment in provincial capitals is limited but some bars and nightclubs are generally available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ulaanbaatar is well-endowed with antique stores and souvenir shops. Best buys include landscape paintings, cashmere garments, camel-wool blankets, national costumes, boots, jewellery, carpets, books and handicrafts. The State Department Store (Ikh Delguur) has the largest selection of souvenirs and gifts in the country. Juulchin (Tourist) Street has several antique shops. When buying antiques be sure to get a certificate of sale that will allow you to take them out of the country.<br />
<br />
The notorious Naran Market on the outskirts of Ulaanbaatar is a large, crowded flea market which sells a huge variety of items. Suitable for the adventurous traveller, it is patronised mainly by local people. Pickpockets here are skilful, so leave valuables in your hotel.</p><p>Daily 1000-1800 as a general guide although times and days vary considerably.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Mongolia are mostly found in Ulaanbaatar, where&nbsp;there are several large offerings to choose from. Most are locally owned and operated, although as Mongolia increases in popularity international chains such as Shangri-La and Hilton can be found in Ulaanbaatar. There are also many smaller hotels of varying standards. Outside the capital, hotels are basic and few in number.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Mongolia are mostly found in Ulaanbaatar, where&nbsp;there are several large offerings to choose from. Most are locally owned and operated, although as Mongolia increases in popularity international chains such as Shangri-La and Hilton can be found in Ulaanbaatar. There are also many smaller hotels of varying standards. Outside the capital, hotels are basic and few in number.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Mongolia are mostly found in Ulaanbaatar, where&nbsp;there are several large offerings to choose from. Most are locally owned and operated, although as Mongolia increases in popularity international chains such as Shangri-La and Hilton can be found in Ulaanbaatar. There are also many smaller hotels of varying standards. Outside the capital, hotels are basic and few in number.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health care facilities are improving in Ulaanbaatar and provincial capitals but still short of Western standards. Serious medical emergencies may require evacuation to Beijing or Seoul. Doctors and hospitals may expect immediate cash payment for health services. Visitors are urged to have health insurance, including cover for evacuation, and to take any regular medication with them. For emergency care contact SOS Medica (tel: 11 464 325 or 9666 0670, after hours 9911 0335). In Ulaanbaatar the direct phone number for an ambulance is 103.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Bottled water is available in Ulaanbaatar and some provincial centers. Some milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered, long-life or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are recommended. Take care around dogs as rabies is prevalent. Any bite from a dog should be immediately treated at a hospital. Hypothermia is a risk in winter; visitors should dress warmly and in layers. Injuries caused by a fall from a horse are common among foreign tourists in summer, inexperienced riders should insist on riding a nomhon moir (&lt;em&gt;calm horse&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Mother's and Children's Day :
							01 June </p><p>Naadam :
							11 July </p><p>Independence Day :
							26 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Mongolia by travellers over the age of 18 without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes and 50 cigars and 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits and 2L of wine and 3L of beer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted imports include narcotics, hazardous chemicals, explosives, and firearms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you plan to export items of historical or cultural value (eg antiques or fossils), you must ensure you have official permission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tugrik (MNT; symbol ₮). Notes are in denominations of ₮20,000, 10,000, 5,000, 1,000, 500, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of ₮500, 200, 100, 50 and 20, but are not widely used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Official organisations authorised to exchange foreign currency include commercial banks in Ulaanbaatar and bureaux de change found along the streets and in hotels. Rates vary slightly and are likely to be lower in hotels. The easiest currency to exchange is the US Dollar, followed by the Euro and the Russian Rouble.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted by main commercial banks, large hotels and a few shops and restaurants in Ulaanbaatar. ATMs are available in Ulaanbaatar and most Mongolian province (aimag) capitals. Both Visa and Mastercard are widely accepted.</p><p>ATMs are available in Ulaanbaatar and most Mongolian province (aimag) capitals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are accepted although credit and debit cards remain faster and more convenient. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars. Traveller's cheques can be difficult to exchange outside the capital.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1400-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adults accompanying children other than their own should bring a notarised letter from the child's parent/legal guardian authorising them to travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals transiting via train can apply for a single- or double-entry transit visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry transit visa: GBP&pound;40; double-entry transit visa: GBP&pound;55. Expedited service will cost more.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>30 days within three months of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing takes two to five days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[46.836001]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[103.067003]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,564,116 sq km (603,909 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3,068,243 (UN estimate 2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ulaanbaatar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mongolia has a 3,485km (2,165-mile) border with the Russian Federation in the north and a 4,670km (2,902-mile) border with China in the south. From north to south, it can be divided into four areas: mountain-forest steppe, mountain steppe and, in the extreme south, semi-desert and desert (the latter being about 3% of the entire territory). The majority of the country has a high elevation, with the principal mountains concentrated in the west. The highest point is the peak of Tavan Bogd, in the Altai Mountains, at 4,374m (14,350ft) high. The lowest point, Khukh Nuur lake, in the east, lies at 560m (1,820ft). There are several hundred lakes in the country and numerous rivers, of which the Orkhon is the longest at 1,124km (698 miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buddhist Lamaism is the main religion, although there is no state religion. The Kazakhs in western Mongolia loosely adhere to Sunni Islam. About 5% of Mongolians are Christian. The traditional animist religion is still popular in northern Mongolia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Religious customs should be respected. Mongolia has a large number of customs and traditions although Mongolians are generally not offended when foreigners break custom.<br />
<br />
<strong>Photography:</strong> Permission should be granted before entering temples and monasteries. A fee is payable for photography in protected areas, although this regulation is often not enforced. Caution should be exercised when photographing government buildings, military establishments and border crossings.</p><br />]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Ukhnaagiin Kh&uuml;rels&uuml;kh since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Khaltmaagiin Battulga&nbsp;since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Hunnu (Xiongnu) Empire was the first great confederation of tribes to occupy the land of present day Mongolia and its raiding parties caused the Chinese to build the Great Wall of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>. Under the leadership of Genghis&nbsp;Khan, the Mongols emerged in the 13th century and quickly amassed an empire that stretched from Korea to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hungary">Hungary</a>. Even today, Mongolians view this period as their golden age and Khan still enjoys God-like reverence.</p>
<p>Mongolian independence was achieved in 1911 after the fall of the Qing Dynasty. China attempted to reassert its rule following the Russian Revolution of 1917 but was beaten back in 1921, with Soviet help. The Soviet intervention led to virtual occupation by the USSR for the next 70 years.</p>
<p>China finally recognised Mongolian independence in 1944 and in 1990 pro-democracy demonstrations erupted in Ulaanbaatar eventually leading to the demise of communism and the creation of a new constitution based on democratic principles.</p>
<p>A number of political parties participate in free elections and Mongolia has been ruled by several coalitions under a directly elected President who then appoints a Prime Minister.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Mongolia is undergoing dramatic change with the demise of a traditional nomadic lifestyle that, a generation ago, was lived by a third of the population. Mongolia&rsquo;s cities are growing rapidly as people leave the land. Another important change has been the resurgence of Buddhism, which the Communists largely suppressed. Mongolians are adherents of the Dalai Lama, although this is handled with great caution by the country&rsquo;s leadership for fear of upsetting the Chinese.</p>
<p>Mongolia&rsquo;s foreign relations are necessarily dominated by its giant neighbours, China and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a>, and based on bilateral friendship treaties. However, the Mongolians have also quietly developed increasingly closer links with the West and in 2003, a small but symbolically significant contingent of Mongolian troops was despatched to support the US-led military operation in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iraq">Iraq</a>.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; Mongolia&rsquo;s first rock band, Soyol Erdene, formed in 1971 and were heavily criticised by the government for their Merseybeat sound. They are still active today.</p>
<p>&bull; The country&rsquo;s main festival, Naadam, has existed for centuries and is held throughout the country in midsummer when participants compete in horse racing, archery and traditional Mongolian wrestling.</p>
<p>&bull; On 21 November 2005 George W Bush became the first sitting US President to visit Mongolia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Mongolia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>976 1145 8133</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-ulaanbaatar</p><p><b>Tel:</b>976 1145 8133</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0830-1300 and 1400-1700. Fri 0830-1330.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Bayanzurkh District<br/>Peace Avenue 30<br/>Ulaanbaatar<br/>13381<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Mongolia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 (202) 333 7117.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mongolianembassy.us</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 (202) 333 7117.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1400-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2833 M Street NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Mongolia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 (020) 7937 0150.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofmongolia.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 (020) 7937 0150.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon, Wed and Fri 1000-1200 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>7-8 Kensington Court<br/>London<br/>W8 5DL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mongolia is far-flung and hardly well-trodden, but don't let that put you off. There is so much to see and do in this sizeable Central Asian country, from the stunning scenery and wildlife of mountains and deserts to the emerging luxury hotels and restaurants of capital Ulaanbaatar.</p>
<p>In the ancient land of Mongolia, history buffs and culture vultures will find plenty to keep them entertained. Outside the main cities many Mongolians continue to hold on to the traditional life of the <em>malchin</em>, or herdsmen. Transporting their goods by camel and residing in portable felt and canvas tents, the nomadic lifestyle of modern-day Mongolia would still be recognisable to Ghengis Khan, the most famous Mongol of them all.</p>
<p>Mongolia's vast areas of wilderness, from the sprawling Gobi Desert to the snow-peaked mountains of the Bayan-&Ouml;lgi, offer plenty of scope for adventurous outdoor enthusiasts. Fishing, jeep tours, horse and camel riding, mountain biking and birdwatching are but a few of the activities on offer. The most intrepid visitors will find numerous temples and ruins to explore.</p>
<p>While infrastructure remains underdeveloped in vast swathes of rural Mongolia, elsewhere the country is racing headlong into the 21st century. The capital Ulaanbaatar is transforming at a pace that any returning visitors will find dizzying. In a relatively short space of time, the city has turned into an ultra-modern metropolis with international restaurants, five-star hotels, shopping malls and glass tower blocks &ndash; a sure sign of Mongolia's status as an up-and-coming Asian travel hotspot.</p>
<p>While there's plenty of nightlife and excitement in Ulaanbaatar, don't visit Mongolia without exploring the wild, largely unspoilt landscapes and traditional lifestyle of its inhabitants. Leaving the capital doesn't mean being stranded from civilisation. Internet is now available even in small villages and it's not uncommon to see nomads toting mobile phones. It's perhaps this contrast that makes Mongolia such a fascinating destination to visit today. Get planning your trip now before the tourist hordes inevitably catch on.</p><p>Mongolia is far-flung and little visited yet has much to offer, from the stunning scenery and wildlife of mountains and deserts to the emerging luxury hotels and restaurants of capital Ulaanbaatar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
