<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Montenegro" ColCode="mnt" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="me" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Montenegro]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montenegro has a Mediterranean climate on the coast, with alpine conditions in the mountains. The average summer coastal temperature is 27&deg;C (81&deg;F), and this is peak season (Jul-Aug), when the majority of visitors come here. Those who can&rsquo;t bear the summer heat would do well to head inland for the mountains, where summer night time temperatures drop as low as 12&deg;C (54&deg;F).</p>
<p>In shoulder season (May-Jun and Sep-Oct) you can expect sunny days on the shores of the Adriatic &ndash; the sea is warm enough to swim, but without the crowds, and average daytime temperatures are 20&deg;C (69&deg;F). This is the ideal time for outdoor activities such as hiking and cycling, though bear in mind that there will be sporadic rain in the mountains.</p>
<p>In low season (Nov-Apr), many hotels and restaurants along the coast shut completely. The weather remains mild, with the average daytime winter temperature being 7&deg;C (44&deg;F). Inland, however, there is substantial snowfall in the mountains, with the average daytime winter temperature in Kola&scaron;in hovering around 0&deg;C (32&deg;F). In fact, Dec-Mar is peak season for inland towns such as Kola&scaron;in and Žabljak, which are popular ski resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In winter, medium weight clothing and heavy overcoat and boots if travelling in the mountains; in summer, lightweight clothing, swimwear and sun cream required on the coast, plus a jumper or jacket for colder nights in the mountains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montenegro is a small country and there are no internal flights between its two airports, Podgorica and Tivat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national rail network is being upgraded. Due to the country&rsquo;s mountainous terrain, railways are difficult to build and require tunnels and bridges. Some routes are exceptionally scenic, most notably the stretch from Kola&scaron;in to Podgorica.</p>
<p>Bar, Podgorica, Kola&scaron;in, Mojkovac and Bijelo Polje are on the main railway line running to Serbia. A local line runs from Podgorica to Nik&scaron;ić, passing through Danilovgrad en route. Timetables are available from Railway Transport of Montenegro (<a href="http://www.zcg-prevoz.me" target="_blank">www.zcg-prevoz.me</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All main towns are connected by decent roads, but caution should be taken on poor roads in rural areas.</p>r<p>There are no motorways in Montenegro, but main roads connecting the larger towns, such as the Bar-Podgorica route, are well maintained. The 4km (3-mile) Sozina Tunnel (toll payable) means that it's possible to drive from Podgorica to Bar in just 30 minutes. The so-called Adriatic highway, running the length of the coast from Igalo (on the border with Croatia) to Ulcinj (on the border with Albania) is a beautiful but rather tiring drive, and it does get busy in summer.</p>
<p>Inland, roads in rural areas are often narrow, twisty and poorly maintained. The two-lane Morača Canyon, between Podgorica and Kola&scaron;in, is a notoriously bad road and should be avoided when possible. In winter, be prepared for snow in the mountains - by law you should carry snow chains between 15 November and 30 March. Local drivers have a reputation for recklessness.</p><p>All main towns, as well as many villages, are connected by an extensive network of long-distance buses, which are reasonably priced but do get crowded, especially along the coast in summer. Major routes include Kotor-Budva-Bar and Bar-Podgorica.</p><p>Main cities have metered taxis, which are reasonably priced, though foreigners are sometimes charged higher rates. It is possible to negotiate a fare when the meters are not in use. Only use officially marked taxis.</p><p>An International Driving Licence is required. No customs documents are required but car log books, a Green Card, vehicle registration/ownership documents and a locally valid insurance policy are necessary.</p><p>Speed limits are 100kph (62mph) on main roads , 80kph (49mph) on regional roads and 50kph (31mph) in towns. Road signs may be poorly marked. Seatbelts must be worn at all times. The minimum driving age is 18. Car headlights must be switched on at all times.</p><p>The emergency breakdown service is called Auto-moto Savez Crne Gore (Automobile Association of Montenegro), AMSCG (tel: 19807; <a href="http://www.amscg.org/index.php?lang=en" target="_blank">www.amscg.org/index.php?lang=en</a>).</p><p>Both international and domestic car hire firms are represented in airports and main towns. Most car hire companies stipulate a minimum age of 21, though some companies say 18.</p><p>Motorcyclists must wear crash helmets and drive with dipped headlights switched on at all times. Montenegro&rsquo;s varied landscapes, unspoilt nature and pleasant climate making it an increasingly popular destination for cyclists. The quiet roads of the stunning interior are a haven for mountain biking, though you need to be prepared to tackle some steep slopes.</p><p>Speed limits are 100kph (62mph) on main roads , 80kph (49mph) on regional roads and 50kph (31mph) in towns. Road signs may be poorly marked. Seatbelts must be worn at all times. The minimum driving age is 18. Car headlights must be switched on at all times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Podgorica has a local bus system, but taxis can be a more reliable way to get around. The medieval-walled old towns of Kotor and Budva are pedestrian only, and are a joy to explore on foot. Towns along the coast are connected to one another by public buses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Montenegro Airlines (<a href="http://montenegroairlines.com" target="_blank">http://montenegroairlines.com</a>). Flights to Montenegro depart from various European capitals (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belgrade">Belgrade</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/rome">Rome</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/vienna">Vienna</a>) year-round for Podgorica Airport and Tivat Airport. In summer there are additional flights, including a direct service from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> Gatwick to Tivat.</p>
<p>Alternatively, you can fly from London to Vienna with Austrian Airlines (<a href="http://www.austrian.com" target="_blank">www.austrian.com</a>) and catch a connecting flight to Podgorica.&nbsp;Prices vary dramatically depending on demand and availability.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Tivat: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 40 minutes.</p>
<p>To Podgorica: from London - 4 hours 15 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 10 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dubrovnik, in neighbouring <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia">Croatia</a>, is better served by flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, so many visitors choose to fly to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dubrovnik">Dubrovnik</a>, then drive 16km (10 miles) south, over the border into Montenegro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&euro;15.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dubrovnik, in neighbouring <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia">Croatia</a>, is better served by flights from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, so many visitors choose to fly to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dubrovnik">Dubrovnik</a>, then drive 16km (10 miles) south, over the border into Montenegro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Podgorica Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.montenegroairports.com<p>The airport  is 12km (7.5 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Tivat</b><![CDATA[http://www.montenegroairports.com<p>The airport is 4km (2.5 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports are in Bar (<a href="http://www.lukabar.me" target="_blank">www.lukabar.me</a>) and Kotor (<a href="http://www.portofkotor.co.me" target="_blank">www.portofkotor.co.me</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montenegro has direct rail links with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/serbia">Serbia</a> (freight and passenger) and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/albania">Albania</a> (freight only), but not with Croatia. Trains run from Belgrade, Serbia to Bar (two trains daily; journey time - 11 hours; couchettes available on the night train) via Podgorica. Timetables are available from Railway Transport of Montenegro (<a href="http://www.zcg-prevoz.me" target="_blank">www.zcg-prevoz.me</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Adriatic Highway is being incorporated into the long-awaited Adriatic-Ionian motorway, which will run all the way from Croatia down into <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece">Greece</a>. However, the building of the Belgrade - Bar motorway, passing through Podgorica and incorporating dozens of bridges and tunnels, is currently a priority for Montenegro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The cheapest way to call home is from a call centre or internet café. Card-operated public telephones are becoming increasingly scarce.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is mostly good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes can be found in the main towns and cities. Internet is fast and efficient. Many hotels and even some private accommodation offer free Wi-Fi to guests.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The media in Montenegro is recognised as &ldquo;partly free&rdquo;. The main problems are editorial bias (manipulated by business leaders and the government) and the physical intimidation of journalists (there are several cases of journalists being attacked, especially when investigating organised crime). English-language newspapers are available in all the main holiday resorts during the summer.&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are three Montenegrin daily newspapers: <em>Dan, Vijesti and Pobjeda</em>. The state-run Radio Television of Montenegro (RTCG) operates three TV channels (2 terrestrial, 1 international via satellite) plus one radio station. There are also several private channels, including NTV Montena, RTV Atlas and TV Vijesti. Foreign channels, such as CNN, are available via satellite in most hotels. Regarding radio, Radio Crne Gore is state-run, and Atlas Radio, Montena Radio and Radio Antena Mare privately operated.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Postal services, run by the state company, Po&scaron;ta Crna Gora (<a href="http://www.postacg.me/" target="_blank">www.postacg.me</a>), are reasonably good. It takes approximately seven days for a letter to arrive in the UK and 10 days to the US. However, parcels occasionally go astray, so if sending valuable items, a courier is recommended.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-2000 (note that some post offices in small resorts only work during the summer season).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the lively port of Kotor</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the bustling port of Kotor, sitting at the end of the Kotor Bay. There's plenty to recommend this UNESCO-listed fortified old town, including its Venetian architecture, 17th-century clock tower, 12th-century Romanesque cathedral, naval museum, chic boutique hotels and seafood eateries.</p>]]><p><b>Charter a yacht</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It's possible to charter a private yacht for the day and sail around the Bay of Kotor. Ringed by dramatic soaring mountains, this meandering bay is often described as Europe's southernmost "fjord", though it is in fact a submerged river canyon. Its shores are dotted with waterside villages made up of centuries-old stone houses and fishing harbours filled with coloured wooden boats.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the tiny floating islands of Perast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On the Bay of Kotor, Perast is made up of old stone villas, overlooking two tiny islets, Sveti Đorđe (St. George) and Gospa od Škrpjela (Our Lady of the Rocks), each capped by a church. The islets can be visited by boat from Perast's waterfront.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy the luxurious Sveti Sfetan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Southeast of Budva, this medieval stone village, perched on a fortified islet, connected to the mainland by a causeway, is a luxury resort. First converted into a hotel during the Yugoslav years, when guests included Elizabeth Taylor and Richard Burton, it reopened as the 5-star Aman Sveti Stefan in 2009.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the 700-year-oldHerceg Novi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A 700-year-old town with much to recommend, Herceg Novi is a must-see. Visit the fascinating baroque Savina Monastery and the beaches on Luštica peninsula, which overlook the entrance to the Bay of Kotor and are accessible by boat.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the old town of Budva</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Protected by medieval walls, Budva's car-free old town is made up of quaint cobbled alleys, lined by Venetian-era buildings, many now hosting restaurants, cafes and souvenir shops. East of town, Slovenska plaža is a long narrow beach overlooked by a string of big modern hotels.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the rugged Durmitor National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike, bike, kayak, raft or paraglide in stunning Durmitor National Park, which has been awarded UNESCO World Natural Heritage status for its glacial landscapes, high peaks, dense pine forests and some of the deepest gorges in Europe. The highlight is the Crno Jezero (Black Lake), a 3km (2-mile) walk from the national park office in Žabljak.</p>]]><p><b>Go birdwatching on Lake Skadar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The biggest lake in the Balkans, Lake Skadar, on the border between Montenegro and Albania, is on the Ramsar List of Wetlands and is a haven for birdwatching, hosting some 270 species, many endangered or rare. The National Park office is in Virpazar – from here you can take a boat trip across the lake, and eat fresh carp at waterside restaurants.</p>]]><p><b>Go climbing in Lovćen National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a trip up the rocky mountain massif of Lovćen, towering above Kotor. Its peak, at 1,657m (5,440ft), is home to the Njegoš Mausoleum, dedicated to the Prince-Bishop and poet, Petar II Petrović-Njegoš. From here, you'll enjoy spectacular views, both inland and down onto the Bay of Kotor. The national park office is in Cetinje, which used to be home to the Montenegrin royal family and capital of Montenegro.</p>]]><p><b>Go primordial at Biogradska Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the Biogradska Gora National Park, home one of the last three jungles in Europe. The primal forest spans 5,400 hectares (13,343 acres) between the Lim and Tara Rivers. You can also find eagles inhabiting the soaring Bjelasica Mountains. The national park office is in Kolašin.</p>]]><p><b>Hit Jaz, the best beach in Montenegro</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Widely considered the best beach in Montenegro, Jaz, just west of Budva, is a 1.2km (0.7-mile) stretch of fine pebble beach, lined with sun beds and umbrellas, overlooking a turquoise bay. Open-air concerts are sometimes staged here – The Rolling Stones played in 2007, followed by Madonna in 2008.</p>]]><p><b>Meet Tara, the deepest canyon in Europe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The highlight of inland Montenegro, at 82km (51 miles) in length and a depth of 1,300m (4,300ft), is the dramatic Tara Canyon. The deepest canyon in Europe boasts endless rapids, adventure sports such as rafting and canyoning. There's also bungee jumping and zip-lining off the Tara Bridge, a five-arch concrete road bridge with amazing views down into the canyon. The nearest towns are Kolašin and Žabljak.</p>]]><p><b>Scale the cliff that bears Ostrog Monastery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You'll be amazed by the 17th-century Ostrog Monastery, which is built into a vertical cliff on the road between Danilovgrad and Nikšić. Inside, in a tiny cave church, lie the remains of the founder of the monastery, St Basil of Ostrog.</p>]]><p><b>Take a tipple or two at Plantaže Winery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Montenegro's largest wine producer, Plantaže is best known for its potent red Vranac wine. <em>Vranac</em> means "black horse", which in the past was considered the symbol of strength and beauty, as is this wine. Visit Plantaže's Šipčanik wine cellar, between Podgorica and Lake Skadar, to taste their wines and purchase bottles to bring home.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around timeworn Ulcinj</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk around Ulcinj, one of the oldest towns on the Adriatic coast. Its top attractions include the Balsica Tower and Renaissance Church Mosque, which is also home to the City Museum. The 12km long (7-mile) Velika Plaža is a fine sandy beach, which remains largely underdeveloped and is backed by a flat hinterland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$4.28 billion (2012 estimate).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Non-ferrous metals, iron and steel, beverages, cork and wood.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Energy and petroleum products, electricity, transport equipment, pharmaceuticals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Serbia, Croatia, Greece, Slovenia and China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montenegro was the smallest of the six constituent republics of the former Yugoslavia. Civil war and economic sanctions in the 1990s halved its economic output, and destroyed much of its infrastructure and industrial capacity. However, since 2000 the economic outlook has brightened. In 2005, economic growth was 4.1%, inflation 1.8% and unemployment 18.4%. In 2006 Montenegro gained independence, splitting from Serbia, so statistics are hard to compare, but by 2012 economic growth had slipped to 0%, inflation was 4% and unemployment 19.1%. However, these figures also reflect the general global economic downturn.<br />
<br />
Agriculture is now mainly geared to domestic consumption. The country has a resilient mining industry that produces coal, copper ores, bauxite and more. The country has been under pressure to privatise state-owned industries, but many of these schemes, such as the privatisation of the Podgorica Aluminium Plant (in 2005), have ended in law suits, lay offs, and bankruptcy, due mainly to corruption and mismanagement. However, service industries, which accounted for 87.9% of GDP in 2011, are the mainstay of Montenegro's economy. Tourism in particular is expected to grow and in 2013 Montenegro was forecast to have the fastest growing tourism industry in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits should be worn. Business attire is relatively formal, and although more casual wear is acceptable in summer, Montenegrin businesspeople tend to dress smartly. It is usual to shake hands to greet a business contact. Communication is not a major problem, as English is popular as a second language. Montenegrins are proud of their country and their hospitality, and visiting businesspeople are normally taken to lunch. Montenegrins will appreciate it if foreigners show enthusiasm for local wines and spirits. Almost everyone smokes. Drinking coffee is also something of a social ritual.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chamber of Economy of Montenegro</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (81) 210 110 ,230 545
					Website:http://www.pkcg.org
					Address: Novaka Miloseva 29,Foreign Economic Relations Sector,Podgorica,81000]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Montenegrins take great pleasure in wining and dining. As a visitor, you can eat at a <em>restoran </em>(a formal type of restaurant) or <em>konoba </em>(a tavern, which is more informal, normally with a rustic stone and wood interior).</p><p>Cuisine varies greatly from one region to another. Along the coast, fresh fish and seafood from the Adriatic predominate, while meat and cheese are more popular inland. Many meals begin with a platter of thinly sliced <em>pršut </em>(smoked ham, similar to Italian prosciutto) and flavoursome <em>ovčji sir </em>(sheep's cheese) or <em>kožji sir</em> (goat's cheese).</p><p>Lake Skadar is known for its excellent fresh <em>šaran </em>(carp) and the River Tara is home to delicious <em>pastrmka </em>(trout). For a quick meal, try a pizzeria – some are surprisingly good, comparable to the best in Italy.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Salata od hobotnice</strong>: Octopus salad.<br />
<strong>Riblja čorba</strong>: Fish soup.<br />
<strong>Crni rižot</strong>: Black risotto prepared with cuttlefish ink.<br />
<strong>Lignje</strong>: Squid rings, typically battered.<br />
<strong>Riba na žaru</strong>: Barbecued fish, either <em>orada</em> (gilthead bream), <em>brancin</em> (sea bass) or <em>andcipol</em> (mullet).<br />
<strong>&Scaron;opskasalata</strong>: Salad of tomatoes, peppers, cucumber, onion, olives and feta cheese, originating from Macedonia and similar to Greek salad.<br />
<strong>Jagnjece</strong>: Roast lamb, usually eaten on special occasions.<br />
<strong>Pljeskavice</strong>: Homemade beef burger.<br />
<strong>Ražnjići</strong>: Various kebabs &ndash; a much-loved fast food dish.<br />
<strong>Rakija</strong>: A potent spirit made from distilled grapes, occasionally flavoured with herbs or fruit, and often served before a meal as an appetiser.<br />
<strong>Montenegro wine</strong>: Look out for Vranac, a delicious red, and Krstac, the white equivalent.<br />
<strong>Nik&scaron;ićkopivo</strong>: Lager brewed in Nik&scaron;ić, found in most bars and cafes.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It is normal to leave a 10% tip in change for your waiter or waitress if you were satisfied with the service.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For most visitors, nightlife in Montenegro is all about open-air dining, drinking and dancing by the sea. If you&rsquo;re travelling as a couple, there are some stunningly romantic venues. <br />
<br />
Budva has the glitziest nightlife scene, catering for wealthy young holidaying Serbs and Russians, who can be found at the string of open-air bars and clubs that line the coastal path east of town, past the marina. Here they serve cocktails, play loud turbo-folk (Serbian pop music with Turkish influence, prevalent throughout the Balkans) and have girls in bikinis dancing on podiums until 0500 in peak season. <br />
<br />
The country&rsquo;s most extravagant venue has to be Top Hill (<a href="http://www.tophill.me" target="_blank">www.tophill.me</a>)&nbsp; Located on a hillside, 600m (1970 ft) above sea level, it&rsquo;s a 25-min drive from Budva. Able to host 5000 revellers, making it one of largest open-air clubs in Europe, it attracts world-class DJs, playing mainly electronic music, plus a glamorous slickly-dressed see-and-be-seen clientele. It works through July to August only. <br />
<br />
Up the coast in Kotor, there&rsquo;s a similar buzz, with late night bars playing loud techno into the early-hours in the car-free old town. The biggest venue here is Maximus, with several dance floors spread over three levels, and a capacity of over 4000. Like Top Hill, it regularly hosts big name DJs, and also stages the annual three day Refresh Festival of electronic music.<br />
If you&rsquo;re looking for something more sedate, you&rsquo;ll find various cultural events in several other medieval towns along the coast, with concerts and theatre performances below the stars during the summer months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montenegro is hardly a great shopping destination, but there are a few local products that make good gifts to bring home. Top of the list has to be wine &ndash; a bottle of velvety red <em>Vranac</em> being the obvious choice. For something a little stronger, pick up a bottle of potent <em>rakija</em> &ndash; there are numerous kinds, ranging from <em>loza</em> (made from distilled grapes) to <em>&scaron;ljivovica</em> (made from plums) and <em>kru&scaron;kovac </em>(made from pears). Other unusual presents include <em>pr&scaron;ut </em>(smoked ham) which you might buy vacuum-packed to make it easier to pack, and strings of dried figs, threaded onto a piece of cotton and interspersed with bay leafs. Montenegrins swear by the health benefits of their locally-produced <em>med</em> (honey), which is especially tasty when bought direct from producers in the mountainous interior &ndash; some beekeepers also sell other products such as honey with propolis, beeswax candles and honey-based cosmetics. Dried herbal teas are regarded as medicinal in Montenegro, so you might buy <em>kadulja</em> (sage) for sore throats and coughs, <em>metvica</em> (mint) to sooth indigestion and nausea, or <em>kamilica </em>(chamomile) to calm the nervous system for a sound night&rsquo;s sleep.</p>
<p>Clothes and shoes are generally imported, so you won&rsquo;t find anything particularly unusual. But, for quirky one-off items of clothing and accessories, try the small luxurious (and very expensive) boutiques at Porto Montenegro in Tivat, several of which stock the works of young up-and-coming Montenegrin and Serbian designers.</p>
<p>Town markets sell locally-produced fresh seasonal fruit and vegetables, cheese, meat and fish, as well as cheap clothing and household goods. Herceg Novi's old town is renowned for its jewellery shops and artists' galleries. Podgorica has a wide range of clothes shops and shopping centres.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-2100, Sat 0800-1500 (many shops are open all day Sat). Grocery stores open at 0600. Shops in tourist resorts often stay open until midnight in high season. Some family-run shops close for siesta 1400-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You&rsquo;ll find the best hotels in Montenegro in Kotor and Budva, on the coast. While Kotor offers a fine choice of boutique hotels, occupying restored medieval stone buildings in the old town and offering personalised service, Budva is known for its big modern hotels with good sports facilities, which date from the Yugoslav-era, and are gradually being renovated to include minimalist interiors and luxury wellness centres. The country&rsquo;s most prestigious hotel in is the 5-star Aman Sveti Stefan, occupying a totally restructured medieval fortified village on a tiny island, close to Budva. In both Kotor and Budva, the best hotels are heavily booked in peak season (when prices rise accordingly), so advance booking is essential.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong>Like in most other European countries, hotels in Montenegro are classified using a star rating from 1 to 5.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A bed and breakfast in Montenegro is known as a pansion, and is generally a low-grade hotel. Many visitors prefer to rent a room in a private house, or a self-catering apartment, both of which tend to offer higher standards and better value for money.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You&rsquo;ll find the best hotels in Montenegro in Kotor and Budva, on the coast. While Kotor offers a fine choice of boutique hotels, occupying restored medieval stone buildings in the old town and offering personalised service, Budva is known for its big modern hotels with good sports facilities, which date from the Yugoslav-era, and are gradually being renovated to include minimalist interiors and luxury wellness centres. The country&rsquo;s most prestigious hotel in is the 5-star Aman Sveti Stefan, occupying a totally restructured medieval fortified village on a tiny island, close to Budva. In both Kotor and Budva, the best hotels are heavily booked in peak season (when prices rise accordingly), so advance booking is essential.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong>Like in most other European countries, hotels in Montenegro are classified using a star rating from 1 to 5.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You&rsquo;ll find the best hotels in Montenegro in Kotor and Budva, on the coast. While Kotor offers a fine choice of boutique hotels, occupying restored medieval stone buildings in the old town and offering personalised service, Budva is known for its big modern hotels with good sports facilities, which date from the Yugoslav-era, and are gradually being renovated to include minimalist interiors and luxury wellness centres. The country&rsquo;s most prestigious hotel in is the 5-star Aman Sveti Stefan, occupying a totally restructured medieval fortified village on a tiny island, close to Budva. In both Kotor and Budva, the best hotels are heavily booked in peak season (when prices rise accordingly), so advance booking is essential.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong>Like in most other European countries, hotels in Montenegro are classified using a star rating from 1 to 5.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Doctors are well trained and generally speak basic English, but medical facilities are generally not to Western European standards. There are seven state-run general hospitals in the country, as well as three specialist hospitals, plus an increasing number of private hospitals. Many medicines and basic medical supplies are often unavailable at state-run pharmacies, so make sure you take an adequate supply of any prescription drugs. There is a gradually increasing number of privately-owned pharmacies, and these tend to be better stocked with essential drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK and other EU countries have reciprocal healthcare agreements with Montenegro, so that emergency hospital treatment is free (upon the presentation of your passport and a document such as a European Health Insurance Card, EHIC), though in non-urgent cases you will be expected to pay, normally in hard currency. Note that doctors often expect a small cash bribe from patients in return for priority treatment. Prescribed medicines must also be paid for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health insurance with emergency repatriation is strongly recommended for visitors from outside the EU. Visitors may be asked to pay first and seek reimbursement later. If you planning to take part in &amp;lsquo;extreme&amp;rsquo; sports, such as bungee jumping or scuba diving while here, you would be advised to take out extra insurance for that. Respective consulates and Podgorica-based embassies can help visitors find hospitals and doctors in Montenegro, should the need arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pharmacists in Montenegro are highly qualified and can offer advice and medication for mild conditions, so for minor problems, a visit to a pharmacy may suffice. In summer, drink plenty of water to avoid dehydration, and wear sun-cream (SPF 15 or greater) to avoid sunburn. In you go hiking in the mountains, you might also take insect repellent. For emergencies, ring 124 (ambulance). Pharmacies (&lt;em&gt;apoteke&lt;/em&gt;) are generally open Mon-Fri 0800-2000 and Sat 0800-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tick-borne encephalitis (especially if going to the mountains), tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>Orthodox Christmas Eve :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>Orthodox Good Friday :
							06 April </p><p>Orthodox Easter Monday :
							09 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							09 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							21 May </p><p>Statehood Day :
							13 July </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Montenegro by travellers aged 17 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 100 cigarillos or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of alcoholic drinks up to 22% volume or 1L of spirits over 22% volume.<br />
&bull; 4L of non-sparkling wine.<br />
&bull; 16L of beer.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of &euro;430 if arriving by air or sea or &euro;300 if arriving by land (reduced to &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>
<p>Note that Port Montenegro, the luxury marina-resort in Tivat, offers duty-free and tax-free fuel, at the cost of 45% of retail diesel prices, to both private and commercial yachts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include narcotics and endangered species of flora and fauna (unless authorised). You can only import arms and ammunition if you're bringing them in for sporting or hunting purposes, in which case you must declare them to the police on arrival.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlicensed cultural artefacts, protected fauna and flora.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (&euro;) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>
<p>Note: Montenegro does not have its own currency and although it is not a member of the EU, it adopted the Euro as currency in 2002 (having previously used the German Deutsche Mark). The European Central Bank and the European Commission were not altogether happy about this, and when Montenegro was officially recognised as a candidate for EU membership in 2010, the situation became even more complicated. By EU law, member countries have to meet a stringent set of economic criteria before they can adopt the Euro. However, it looks unlikely that Montenegro will be forced to drop the Euro. As Montenegro is not an official member of the Eurozone, it has no issuing rights and cannot mint its own national version of the Euro coins (cents).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money should be exchanged through official exchange offices and banks only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International credit and debit cards such as Visa, Mastercard, Diners Club, American Express and Maestro are accepted, but cash may be necessary for some payments, especially in small restaurants and shops in remotes areas. ATMs accept all the main international debit cards.</p><p>ATMs are widely available in all main towns and resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although acceptable in theory, in practice these can be very hard to exchange. It is advisable to take cash and credit or debit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-2000 and Sat 0800-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Montenegro, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above, except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a valid ID card who can stay up to 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airport transit visa; transit visa; short-stay visa; long-stay visa. Check with the embassy for the latest fees.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airport transit visa: valid for one or several airport transits within three months; transit visa: valid for one, two or exceptionally several overland transits for five days per journey within six months.</p>
<p>Short-stay visa: 90 days within six months; long-stay visa: over 90 days, but no more than six months in one year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). In countries where Montenegro has no diplomatic representation, visitors requiring a visa should apply to the Serbian Embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For stays of more than 90 days, you must apply for a temporary residence permit one week before the 90 days expire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[43.855025]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[20.590035]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>13,812 sq km (5,333 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>626,101 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>47.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Podgorica.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montenegro is bordered by Croatia to the north, Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina to the northeast, Serbia to the east and Albania to the south. To the east lie the deep blue waters of the Adriatic Sea, and it is the 293km (183-mile) Montenegrin coastal strip that attracts the majority of visitors, with top destinations being the centuries-old seaside towns of Kotor and Budva. Here one of the most notably features is the stunning Bay of Kotor, a submerged river canyon resembling a fjord.</p>
<p>Inland, the landscape is dominated by dramatic soaring alpine mountains rising over 2,000m (6,562ft), with the highest peak, Bobotov Kuk, reaching 2,523m (8,278ft). Here you&rsquo;ll find dramatic glacial features, such as lakes and canyons, the most impressive being the River Tara Canyon, and dense forests. In the centre of the country, around Podgorica and Nik&scaron;ić, lie fertile plains planted with crops and vineyards, while to the south, on the border with Albania, lies Lake Skadar, a vast wetland. Approximately 38% of land is given over to agriculture, but of this only 10% is cultivated, due to difficult terrain and poor soils.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Majority Eastern Orthodox (72%, according to the 2011 census), with a Muslim minority (19%) and a Roman Catholic minority (3.5%). The remainder are either Atheist or "other".</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As in any other foreign country, you should respect local laws and social customs when visiting Montenegro. This is an Eastern Orthodox country, so you should dress respectably for visiting churches and monasteries &ndash; legs and shoulders covered, for both men and women.</p>
<p>Be cautious when talking about the war and the break-up of Yugoslavia - many people come from mixed families (which might include Eastern Orthodox Serbs, Roman Catholic Croats and Muslim Bosniaks), and &ldquo;who was right&rdquo; and &ldquo;who was wrong&rdquo; cannot be clearly defined. Also be aware that there is an Albanian minority (predominantly Muslim) in Montenegro, concentrated around Ulcinj. What various individuals think about the current situation in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kosovo">Kosovo</a> will vary from person to person, so avoid entering into heated debate on this topic. </p>
<p>Montenegrins are traditional and patriarchal, and the society has a deeply ingrained aversion to homosexuality. Gay visitors are advised to limit public displays of affection. In October 2013, 60 people were injured at the Gay Pride march in Podgorica, when anti-gay protestors threw stones at the demonstrators, and the police responded with tear-gas. </p>
<p>Montenegrins enjoy drinking immensely but being able to hold one&rsquo;s alcohol is a matter of pride, and public displays of drunken behaviour are considered degrading.</p>
<p>Nudism is allowed on designated beaches and topless bathing for women is generally accepted on all beaches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Milo Đjukanović since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Milo Djukanovic since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montenegro is often considered a new country, having only gained independence from Serbia in 2006. However, its history goes back millennia, and it is closely intertwined with that of its Balkan neighbours.</p>
<p>Montenegro's first known inhabitants were the Illyrians, a warlike Bronze Age people present along much of the East Adriatic coast. The Ancient Greeks arrived in the 4th century BC, founding the coastal town of Budva, though by the 1st century AD the entire area was absorbed into Roman Empire. It is around this point that the Illyrians proper were extinct.</p>
<p>The Slavs arrived in the 7th century, mixed with descendants of the Romanised Illyrians, and adopted Christianity. A proud warrior people, they lived in clans, established their own royal family and secured independence from the Byzantines in the 11th century.</p>
<p>The Slavs inhabited much of present-day Montenegro, then known as Duklja, which became the front line in various wars between the Byzantine Empire and Serbian Kingdom. In 1186, Duklja, which had been weakened by infighting, was incorporated into the Serbian Kingdom.</p>
<p>The Serbian Empire, which evolved from the Serbian Kingdom, fell apart in the 14th century allowing the region to fall under the spell of the Ottoman Empire. WWI brought the Ottoman Empire to a dramatic end, with modern-day Montenegro forming part of a new country, Yugoslavia, in 1918.</p>
<p>After WWII, Yugoslavia was governed by Josip Tito, a &ldquo;benevolent dictator&rdquo; whose authoritarian regime kept a lid on the ethnic tensions that existed within Yugoslavia. Tito was a socialist revolutionary and under his rule most businesses were run as workers&rsquo; co-operatives. Being a non-aligned country, Yugoslavia kept good relations with both West and East, and allowed its people more freedoms than their socialist counterparts in the USSR.</p>
<p>When Yugoslavia began to break up during the 1990s, Montenegro remained loyal to Belgrade. Although there was no actual fighting on Montenegrin territory, the people suffered much economic hardship during that time. Eventually, in May 2006, Montenegro held a referendum and the people voted for independence from Serbia.</p>
<p>In 2008, Montenegro applied for EU membership, and in 2012, having proved that it was serious about tackling corruption and organised crime, it opened accession negotiations with the EU.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Having no currency of its own, Montenegro has unilaterally adopted the Euro, the first non-EU fully recognised country to do so (Kosovo has also adopted the Euro unilaterally).<br />
&bull;	Tito&rsquo;s brand of socialism, often referred to as Titoism, pulled off the enviable feat of appealing to both communists and non-communists. <br />
&bull;	Brad Pitt's first lead role was back in 1988, in <em>Dark Side of the Sun</em>, which was filmed by former Yugoslav director, Bozidar Nikolic, in Kotor, Montenegro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Montenegro in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234 6108.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 234 6108.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1610 New Hampshire Ave NW  <br/>Washington<br/>DC 20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Montenegro in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7727 6007.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7727 6007.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>18 Callcott Street<br/>London<br/>W8 7SU<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Montenegro]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>020 618 010.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>020 618 010.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0930-1700; Fri 0900-1330.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Ulcinjska 8, Gorica C<br/>Podgorica<br/>81000<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Consulate General of Montenegro in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 661 5400.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 661 5400.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>801 Second Avenue, 7 th Floor<br/>New York<br/>NY 10017<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montenegro remains one of Europe&rsquo;s hidden gems&hellip; but for how much longer? Independent since 2006, the country has been quietly developing its fledgling tourism industry and is now being vaunted as one of the continent&rsquo;s hottest new destinations.</p>
<p>So what does this nascent nation have to offer? Well, inland it&rsquo;s all pine-scented mountains, rolling prairies and traditional, stone villages, which are a joy for hikers, bikers and nature lovers. The star attraction, though, is the blissful, 293km (183mile) coastline, which gives onto the calm blue waters of the Adriatic Sea.</p>
<p>The most popular coastal destinations are the enchanting Venetian-era port towns of Kotor and Budva, with their medieval stone buildings, family-run seafood restaurants and burgeoning hotel scene. Other less developed seaside towns include Herceg Novi, Petrovac, Bar and Ulcinj, where travellers can get a taste of local life.</p>
<p>The coastline harbours a pleasing combination of long sandy beaches to the south, near Ulcinj, curving pebble bays along the so-called Budva Riviera, and little coves around the perimeter of the meandering Bay of Kotor to the north.</p>
<p>As investment arrives, luxury marina-resorts have begun to spring up, offering mooring facilities for sailing boats as well as accommodation, restaurants, cafes, spas and shops. Porto Montenegro in Tivat is designed to accommodate some of the world&rsquo;s biggest mega yachts and is indicative of the kind of travellers Montenegro seems to be targeting.</p>
<p>Of course, it&rsquo;s not all about wealthy oligarchs. Particularly inland, where travellers can grab a slice of traditional Balkan life and lose themselves in rugged mountains, many of which rise above 2,000m (6,560ft).</p>
<p>The hinterland is also home to five national parks. Go in search of bears, wolves and lynx atop the peaks of Durmitor National Park; raft down the River Tara in Europe's deepest canyon; explore Europe's last virgin forest within Biogradska Gora National Park; or go bird watching in the wetlands of Lake Skadar National Park. But go now, before everyone else gets the same idea.</p><p>Montenegro remains one of Europe&rsquo;s hidden gems&hellip; but for how much longer? Independent since 2006, the country has been quietly developing its fledgling tourism industry and is now being vaunted as one of the continent&rsquo;s hottest new destinations.</p>
<p>So what does this nascent nation have to offer? Well, inland it&rsquo;s all pine-scented mountains, rolling prairies and traditional, stone villages, which are a joy for hikers, bikers and nature lovers. The star attraction, though, is the blissful, 293km (183mile) coastline, which gives onto the calm blue waters of the Adriatic Sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
