<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Montserrat" ColCode="msr" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ms" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Montserrat]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is subtropical, tempered by trade winds. There is little climatic variation throughout the year making Montserrat a great year round destination. The heaviest rainfall occurs between July and November; however, the heavy cloudbursts serve to refresh the atmosphere and once they are over the sun reappears.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical lightweights are worn, with light woollens for cooler evenings. A light raincoat or an umbrella is useful.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Charter yachts are available. The main harbour is at Little Bay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[l<p>There is a good road network connecting all places of interest.&nbsp;Montserrat has well-paved roads, but driving can be difficult for those not used to winding mountain roads.</p><p>Montserrat's buses are minivans. There are no timetables or bus stops - just stick your arm out when you see one pass and it will stop for you.</p><p>You can pick up a taxi at the airport and ferry terminal. Drivers can act as guides and a number of different tours can be arranged. Official taxi drivers wear uniforms and display ID.</p><p>If you bring your valid national driving licence, you can obtain a driving permit from any police station.</p><p>Speed limits are restricted to 32kph (20mph).</p><p>A number of local car hire companies operate on the island. Quad-bike hire is also available.</p><p>Speed limits are restricted to 32kph (20mph).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The nearest international gateway is Antigua. Fly Montserrat (<a href="http://www.flymontserrat.com" target="_blank">www.flymontserrat.com</a>)&nbsp;and ABM Air (<a href="http://www.montserrat-flights.com" target="_blank">www.montserrat-flights.com</a>)&nbsp;operate daily flights from Antigua to Montserrat.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/montserrat">Montserrat</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/antigua-and-barbuda">Antigua</a> - 20 minutes.</p>
<p>To Antigua: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 9 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 4 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EC$35 (US$13) for CARICOM nationals and EC$55 (US$21) for other nationals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Gerald R Ford International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.grr.org/index.php]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Phone booths are operated by coins and phonecards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>No roaming agreements have been declared. Coverage is limited. Mobile phones can be hired and local SIM cards are available to buy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet access is available at Andy's Internet Café and Grant Enterprises & Trading.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main post office in Brades is open Mon-Fri 0815-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Do a jig and celebrate St Patrick's Week</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This exotic destination is known as the Emerald Isle of the Caribbean and is the only country outside of Ireland to make St Patrick's Day a public holiday. Join in the festivities during St Patrick's Week, which commemorates Montserrat's slave uprising on 17 March 1768, as well as celebrating the island's Irish heritage.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the uunderwater world</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Duck underwater with a snorkel and mask or plunge deeper with full scuba gear. Montserrat's reefs are teeming with colourful coral and fish that include reef sharks, sea turtles, parrotfish and plenty of colourful coral. There are several major dive centres located on the island.</p>]]><p><b>Lace up your hiking boots</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of hiking trails that criss-cross Montserrat and make it perfect to explore on foot. Popular routes are the Cot trail (which runs through an oki banana plantation to a historic family house), Runaway Ghaut, the Blackwood Allen trail, and the Silver Hills trail (which passes through one of the island's oldest volcanic centres).</p>]]><p><b>Make a date at Rendezvous Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel by boat to Rendezvous Bay and enjoy the only white sandy beach in Montserrat; sand in the other bays is of volcanic origin and may be grey or black. You could also hire a fishing boat and try your luck at catching marlin, wahoo or tuna.</p>]]><p><b>Picnic at the Oriole Complex</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Trace Montserrat's history at the Oriole Complex, and take a guided tour of the gardens. The accompanying pastry barn is also the perfect place to stock up with some treats before heading to the gardens for a lazy picnic.</p>]]><p><b>See the active Soufrière Hills Volcano</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take the opportunity to see an active volcano, and the devastation caused by the 1997 eruption, from the viewing platform on Jack Boy Hill. After centuries of dormancy, the Soufriere Hills volcano became active in 1995 and continues to sporadically erupt. The volcano takes its name from the French word soufriere, meaning sulphur outlet.</p>]]><p><b>Spend the day birdwatching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Make your way to Pelican Point on the east coast, home to the island's only breeding colony of the spectacular frigate birds. Look out for the <em>icterus oberi</em> (a species of oriole), Montserrat's national bird, at Centre and Silver Hill in the north of the island.</p>]]><p><b>Take a boat tour of the island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the best ways to get the measure of Montserrat is to take a boat tour around the island. A view from the sea allows you to observe the Soufrière Hills Volcano, the Tar River Delta and the remnants of the old W H Bramble Airport.</p>]]><p><b>Tour the Montserrat Volcano Observatory</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Meet the scientists monitoring volcanic activity at the Montserrat Volcano Observatory. Twice a week (Tuesdays and Thursdays), they take visitors on a tour of the facility. The activities at the observatory also include research, education and advising on the active Soufriere Hills volcano.</p>]]><p><b>Watch a local football match</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Time your trip to coincide with a friendly football match between the Montserrat national side and a visiting European team. Football is the second most popular sport in Montserrat after cricket. Nicknamed "The Emerald Boys", the team play at the Blakes Estate Stadium near the village of Look Out.</p>]]><p><b>Witness the vanishing town of Plymouth</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From Richmond Hill, cast your eye over the deserted capital, Plymouth. The town now lies buried in ash, vanishing a little more each year as mudflows and volcanic debris mount up. The town was swamped by volcanic eruptions in 1995 and 1997 and promptly abandoned.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>EC$94.7 million (2004).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Electronic components, plastic bags, clothing, hot peppers, limes, live plants and cattle.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transportation equipment, food, manufactured goods, fuels, lubricants and related materials.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, UK, Japan, Trinidad & Tobago and Puerto Rico.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The island was recovering from the volcanic explosion of January 1997, which destroyed much of the island's productive capacity, when it was hit by a new series of eruptions in July 2003.<br /><br />Previously, Montserrat had a diverse if fragile economy. The agricultural sector produced vegetables, cotton and livestock. The industrial sector, which employed one-third of the workforce and earned the bulk of Montserrat's export income, was concentrated in food processing and the assembly of electronic components. In the service sector, e-commerce and financial services were two important growth areas. <br /><br />After the 1997 eruption, the island became largely dependent on foreign aid - in particular, a US$125 million aid package from the UK.<br />Contact the Montserrat Tourist Board for further details (see <em>Contact Addresses).</em></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A short- or long-sleeved shirt without a jacket is suitable for most business visits.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Economic Development Unit</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 491 2066
					Website:http://www.devunit.gov.ms
					Address: ,PO Box 292,Brades,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Dining options in Montserrat are varied, with a choice of international or local specialities. Most bars serve imported beers, spirits and wines. Waiter service is normal.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Salt fish.<br />
&bull; Mountain chicken - not actually chicken, but the leg from a local species of large frog (Dominica is the only other island where these frogs can be found). <br />
&bull; Pumpkin soup.<br />
&bull; Goat water (comparable to Irish stew).<br />
&bull; Aubergine patties.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 10% service charge is added to most restaurant bills.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Don't expect wild partying in Montserrat. Nightlife here usually involves sipping on drinks and chilling out (or 'liming') at a roadside bar or maybe catching a live band on Friday or Saturday night. Come during festival time (December) or over St Patrick's Day (March) and things get a little crazier however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Locally made items include leather goods, handwoven items made from locally grown cotton, volcanic soap, and preserves such as guava jelly and hot pepper sauce. Local arts and crafts shops are dotted throughout the island. Small shopping complexes include the BBC complex and the Ryan buildings.</p><p>Mon, Tues, Thurs and Fri 0800-1700, Wed and Sat 0800-1200. Grocery shops usually stay open later and also open for a few hours on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are two hotels - the 18-room Tropical Mansion Suites and the Vue Pointe Hotel. The Vue Pointe is temporarily closed owing to increased volcanic activity. A 10% accommodation tax is charged for hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montserrat has several guest houses. Visit the Montserrat Tourist Board's website for a full list (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>). A 7% accommodation tax is charged for guest houses and bed and breakfasts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are two hotels - the 18-room Tropical Mansion Suites and the Vue Pointe Hotel. The Vue Pointe is temporarily closed owing to increased volcanic activity. A 10% accommodation tax is charged for hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are two hotels - the 18-room Tropical Mansion Suites and the Vue Pointe Hotel. The Vue Pointe is temporarily closed owing to increased volcanic activity. A 10% accommodation tax is charged for hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There is a well-equipped hospital, providing 24-hour casualty service. Montserrat is a UK Dependency and a limited reciprocal health agreement exists with the UK. On presentation of proof of UK residence, free treatment is available at the general hospital and at state-run clinics to those aged over 65 and under 16. Dental treatment is also free for school-age children. Private health insurance is recommended. For specialist treatment, visitors are required to travel to neighbouring islands (eg Antigua or Guadeloupe).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is safe to drink. Bottled water is available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the following Monday. If two public holidays fall on a Saturday and on the next following Sunday, the next following Monday and Tuesday shall be public holidays. If two public holidays fall on the same day, the next following day other than a Saturday or Sunday shall be a public holiday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>St Patrick's Day :
							18 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							11 June </p><p>August Monday :
							06 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p><p>Festival Day :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Montserrat by travellers aged 16 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 225g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1.18L of wine or spirits.<br />
&bull; 177ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Gifts up to a value of EC$500, including the items above.<b><br />
</b></p>
<p>You must declare fresh fruit, vegetables and meat for inspection.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unauthorised firearms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>East Caribbean Dollar (XCD; symbol EC$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of EC$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of EC$1, and 25, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents. US Dollars are also accepted.<br /><br />The East Caribbean Dollar is tied to the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are two banks, a credit union and a building society.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most businesses accept credit cards, but not all. Both banks have ATMs.</p><p>Both banks have ATMs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800/0900-1400, Fri 0800-1500, depending on the bank. Banks close at 1300 on Wednesdays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>eVisa: US$50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>eVisas are valid for multiple entries within one year of the date of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors who do require a visa should apply online (<a href="http://www.immigration.ms">www.immigration.ms</a>). If you need a visa and don't have a credit card, you can apply at your nearest British Embassy or Consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>eVisas are usually approved and issued online within 24 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[16.736000]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-62.189017]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>102 sq km (39.4 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5,154 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>51.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Plymouth is still officially the capital, but was mostly destroyed by pyroclastic flows in August 1997. The government headquarters are currently in Brades. There are plans to turn Little Bay into the new capital.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Self-governing British Overseas Territory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montserrat is one of the Leeward Islands group in the Eastern Caribbean. It is a volcanic island with black sandy beaches and lush tropical vegetation. There are three main volcanic mountains on the island and Chances Peak is its highest point at 915m (3,002ft). The Soufri&egrave;re group of hills houses the volcano which began erupting in July 1995 and to date is continuously active. The Great Alps Waterfall, previously one of the most spectacular sights in the West Indies, has been destroyed by the volcano.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic, Anglican, Methodist and other Christian denominations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Casual clothes are acceptable. Beachwear should be confined to the beach or poolside. The lifestyle is generally peaceful, combining many English influences with West Indian. The people are usually friendly and relaxed. All visitors are made welcome.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 60Hz. Most villas and guest houses are wired to accept 110-volt appliances. British-style plugs with three square pins and North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without grounding pin) can both be used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Premier Donaldson Romero since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor Andrew Pearce since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arawak and Carib Indians were the first residents of Alliouagana, 'land of the prickly bush', until Christopher Columbus claimed it for <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a> in 1493, whereupon he named the island Santa Maria de Montserrat. It was not until 1632 that the British colonised the island, which is still a British Overseas Territory. The actual settlers were mainly of Irish Catholic origin, who appreciated the presence of an ocean between them and Oliver Cromwell. Irish surnames among the present population reflect this history. Between 1871 and 1956 the island was administered as part of the Federal Colony of the Leeward Islands.</p>
<p>At this point the federation was dissolved; since then Montserrat has been a British colony administered by a Governor appointed by the British government.</p>
<p>For the most part, the major political issue since 1960 has been independence. While a significant minority has backed this option, it has failed to attract a majority owing to uncertainty about the island's economic future. The main reason is its vulnerability to the elements; Montserrat is located in the Caribbean hurricane zone. However, damage from tempests was nothing compared to that wrought by the eruption of a volcano in 1997.</p>
<p>This rendered almost half the island uninhabitable, and much of the 12,000 population left the island. Many original inhabitants have returned to Montserrat, but the island has been left more dependent than ever on aid and support from the British government. The southern part of the island, which bore the brunt of the eruption, has been partially repopulated, but the overriding priority for the government has been to bring economic and social life back to the devastated island. This has been a difficult and gradual process, hampered by disagreements.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Montserrat Government in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7520 2622.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.ms</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7520 2622.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>180-186 Kings Cross Road<br/>London<br/>WC1X 9DE<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Diplomatic representation]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Montserrat is a quiet, laid-back island where you can hike, birdwatch, snorkel, or enjoy a couple of drinks over a game of dominoes.</p>
<p>The tiny Caribbean island was dealt a devastating blow when the Soufri&egrave;re Hills volcano erupted massively in 1995 and again in 1997. Almost half the island was rendered uninhabitable, including the capital, Plymouth, which today stands half-submerged in volcanic ash and mud. The effects were not limited to physical destruction. Montserrat's economy was severely damaged, and around two-thirds of the 12,000 population left the island.</p>
<p>The volcano remains active and much of the island is still out of bounds, but this in itself is a draw for tourists looking for something beyond the usual Caribbean experience of beaches and luxury resorts.</p>Montserrat is a quiet, laid-back island where you can hike, birdwatch, snorkel, or enjoy a couple of drinks over a game of dominoes.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
