<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Morocco" ColCode="mar" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ma" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Morocco]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Morocco&rsquo;s climate is very diverse, varying with the season and region. In general the country has a tropical climate, with temperatures reaching as high as 35&deg;C (95&deg;F) and as low as 5&deg;C (41&deg;F) in the Sahara. The coast has a warm, Mediterranean climate tempered on the eastern coast by southwest trade winds whilst inland areas have a hotter, drier, continental climate. In the south of the country, the weather is very hot and dry throughout most of the year, though temperatures can drop dramatically at night, especially in the months of December and January.&nbsp;Temperatures in the Atlas Mountains can drop below zero Celsius (32&ordm;F) in winter and mountain peaks are snow capped most of the year.</p>
<p>Rain falls from November to March in coastal areas, and the country is mostly dry with high temperatures in summer and a cooler climate in the mountains. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/marrakech">Marrakech</a> and Agadir enjoy an average temperature of 21&deg;C (70&ordm;F) during the winter.</p>
<p>Owing to the relatively high winter temperatures, and summers that are dry rather than unbearably humid, Morocco is an all-year round destination. If you really want to avoid the heat, <strong>the best time to visit </strong>is during the shoulder seasons of April to May (or maybe even early June), and September to November.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are best worn during summer, with warm medium weight wear for the evenings, during the winter, and in the mountains. Waterproofing is advisable in the wet season, particularly on the coast and in the mountains. Both men and women should be careful to wear clothing that is cognisant of cultural sensitivities &ndash; long sleeves and low hems will be looked on favourably.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>) operates regular&nbsp;internal flights&nbsp;from Casablanca airport to Agadir, Dakhla, Fes, Marrakech, Ouarzazate, Oujda and Tangier. Internal flights tend to be expensive compared to other modes of travelling around the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Moroccan rail system, run by Office National des Chemins de Fer (ONCF) (<a href="http://www.oncf.ma" target="_blank">www.oncf.ma</a>) provides regular services. The network runs from Oujda in the northeast to Casablanca on the west coast, and from Tangier on the north coast to Fes and Marrakech in the interior. However, only the northern part of the country is served, and even large centres such as Agadir and Essaouira are not covered.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Moroccan road network is extensive, and continued infrastructure development means that it&rsquo;s increasingly easy to travel by car. Keep in mind that accident rates are high and road safety awareness among many drivers is negligible, so cautious drivers may prefer taking public transport or hiring a driver.</p>r<p>The high-speed toll roads connecting Tangier, Rabat, Casablanca, Meknes, Fes, Marrakech and El Jadida are of excellent quality. Coastal communities and most large towns are also well served by good roads. In the interior, south of the High Atlas Mountains, road travel becomes much more difficult, especially across the Atlas Mountains in winter.</p><p>The cheapest and most popular way to get around Morocco is to make use of the country&rsquo;s extensive bus network. Buses serve most communities, and private operators compete for custom on the more popular routes. The major bus companies are Compagnie de Transports Marocains (<a href="http://www.ctm.ma" target="_blank">www.ctm.ma</a>), Trans Ghazala (<a href="http://transghazala.ma" target="_blank">transghazala.ma</a>), and Supratours (<a href="http://www.supratours.ma" target="_blank">www.supratours.ma</a>).</p><p>Metered &ldquo;Petit Taxi&rdquo; are available in major towns. Larger, &ldquo;Grand Taxi&rdquo; are usually Mercedes cars, used for travel outside medinas and to areas outside towns. These can be shared, but fares should be agreed before departure as they don't have meters.</p><p>Foreign driving licences are accepted, as well as International Driving Permits. Third-party insurance is required. You must carry your licence and insurance documentation at all times. A Green Card is also necessary. Insurance can be arranged locally.</p><p>Traffic drives on the right in Morocco and the wearing of seat belts is compulsory. The speed limit is 40-60kph (25-37mph) in cities and built-up areas, rising to 80kph (50mph) on more major roads and up to 120kph (75mph) on motorways. No alcohol at all is allowed in the bloodstream when driving.</p><p>There is no national breakdown service. Hire cars contain contact details in case of emergency.</p><p>International and local car hire companies have offices in major towns, cities and airports. Car hire is generally expensive, and prices vary with the season. The minimum age for driving a hired car is 18, although many hire companies require drivers to be 21 or over.</p><p>Bike hire is available in most major towns - although attempting to cycle through city traffic is inadvisable. For those travelling longer distances, bikes can be transported on trains and buses.</p><p>Traffic drives on the right in Morocco and the wearing of seat belts is compulsory. The speed limit is 40-60kph (25-37mph) in cities and built-up areas, rising to 80kph (50mph) on more major roads and up to 120kph (75mph) on motorways. No alcohol at all is allowed in the bloodstream when driving.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are extensive bus services in Casablanca and other main towns. Casablanca also has a super-modern rapid transit tram system. Urban-area petits taxis are plentiful and have metered fares. Taxi drivers are not usually tipped, although it is common to round fares up at least to the next dirham on short trips.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Morocco</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tangier</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Morocco</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">rabat</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Morocco</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">marrakech</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Morocco</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">fes</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Morocco's national carrier is Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>). Other airlines operating flights to Morocco from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>), Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) and TUI (<a href="https://www.tui.co.uk/flight/" target="_blank">https://www.tui.co.uk/flight/</a>).</p>
<p>The busiest international airports are in&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/agadir">Agadir</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/casablanca">Casablanca</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/fes">Fes</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/marrakech">Marrakech</a>, Ouarzazate, Rabat, and Tangier. July to September is peak season in Morocco, so fly outside the summer months to take advantage of cheap deals.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/marrakech">Marrakech</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 3 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 9 hours 40 minutes (including stopover).</p>
<p>To Casablanca: from London - 3 hours 20 minutes; New York - 6 hours 50 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in ticket cost.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Casablanca Mohammed V International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.onda.ma<p>Casablanca Mohammed V International Airport is located 30km (19 miles) south of Casablanca.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+212 522 539 040</p>]]><b>Marrakech Menara Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.onda.ma<p>Marrakech Menara Airport is located on the immediate outskirts of Marrakech, 6km (4 miles) to the southwest of the city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+212 52 444 7910</p>]]><b>Rabat-Salé Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.onda.ma]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Tangier Ibn Battouta Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.onda.ma/ONDA/An<p>The airport is 11km (7 miles) from the city (journey time - 20 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Fes - Saiss International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.onda.org.ma/<p>Fes Airport is located at Saiss, 15km (9 miles), south of the city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(212) 3562 4800 or 3562 4799 or 090 000 800 (call centre)</p>]]><b>Agadir Al-Massira Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.agadir-airport.com<p>Agadir-Al Massira Airport is located 20 km (13 miles) southeast of central Agadir.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+212 288 39112.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travelling by sea to Morocco is a popular alternative to flying. The main ports are Tangier (<a href="http://www.tmpa.ma" target="_blank">www.tmpa.ma</a>) and Nador in Morocco proper, and the Spanish-held ports of Ceuta (<a href="http://www.puertodeceuta.com" target="_blank">www.puertodeceuta.com</a>) and Melilla. Several lines from Europe serve these ports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rail links between Morocco and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/algeria">Algeria</a> are suspended. English travellers can catch trains from London St Pancras to Algeciras in Spain changing in Paris, Marseille, Barcelona, and Madrid, then catch a ferry to Morocco from Algeciras. It will take around 26 hours for the journey to Algeciras from London St Pancras, then another 90 minutes for the ferry journey to Morocco.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An InterRail pass no longer covers Morocco, but gets you as far as the port at Algeciras, where pass holders get a 30% discount on ferry routes to Tanger Med.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best road link is from southern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> via passenger/car ferries. The road link on the north Algerian border is closed due to ongoing political disputes but border links with Morocco&rsquo;s other neighbour <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mauritania">Mauritania</a> in the south are still open.</p>
<p>The bus company Compagnie de Transports Marocains (<a href="http://www.ctm.ma" target="_blank">www.ctm.ma</a>) operates a bus service from most Moroccan cities to destinations in France, Spain&nbsp;and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a>&nbsp;in conjunction with Eurolines.</p><p>The road between Morocco and Mauritania is a route only for the very determined. There are warnings of landmines and high instances of banditry in the country&rsquo;s far southwest, but the roads are generally well-maintained tarmac. However this turns into sandy &lsquo;piste&rsquo; immediately on entering Mauritania, and with the added risk of landmines, a guide is strongly recommended. The&nbsp;border closes at&nbsp;1800 daily.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Privately run t&eacute;l&eacute;boutiques can be found throughout the country, with an attendant to provide advice, change, and phonecards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good in towns and cities, and across the west of Morocco, but is a little more erratic east and further south.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Access is unrestricted and is widely available in business centres, hotels and in internet caf&eacute;s. A one-month prepaid unlimited internet access card&nbsp;for laptops, iPhones and smartphones is available from Maroc Telecom (who also have the best national coverage).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The press is subject to government censorship in Morocco, and although King Mohammed VI eased some restrictions on the press when he came to power, issues such as Western Sahara, the monarchy, and corruption remain highly sensitive. The government manages ten of Morocco's television channels under state run Soci&eacute;t&eacute; Nationale de Radiodiffusion et de T&eacute;l&eacute;vision&nbsp;(SNRT).</p>
<p>Two other popular channels include 2M TV, which is partially owned by the state, and Medi1 TV, which is privately owned with some investment from the public sector permitted. The government owned SNRT also includes four national and five regional radio channels. Satellite dishes are widely used, giving access to a range of foreign TV stations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes up to one week and can be unreliable.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1200 and 1430-1830, Sat 0830-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Hassan Tower</p><![CDATA[<p>The Hassan Tower, the grandiose minaret of a vast yet incomplete mosque, is Rabat's most famous landmark. Begun in 1195, the minaret was intended to be the largest in the Muslim world, soaring some 86m (260ft) into the sky. Construction was abandoned, however, upon the death of the sultan, Yacoub al-Mansour, in 1199 and the tower instead rises to just 44m (140ft). Two hundred columns mark out the area where the mosque was to stand. Today, the site also houses the Mosque and Mausoleum of Mohammed V, the grandfather of the present king of Morocco, which is one of the few sacred sites in the country that non-Muslims are allowed to enter.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be entertained in Djemaa El Fna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Djemaa el Fna is the hub of life in Marrakech, and locals and tourists alike flock here to watch the daily spectacle unfold. As night falls, the vast square comes alive as a thronging, open-air stage filled with acrobats, storytellers, snake-charmers and musicians, all perfumed with the smoke from a hundred food stalls. Unchanged for centuries, this is surely one of the world&rsquo;s &lsquo;must see&rsquo; cultural wonders.</p>]]><p><b>Be soothed by Jardin Majorelle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The antithesis of bustling Djemaa el Fna, Jardin Majorelle is an immaculately presented garden created in the 1920s by French artist Jacques Majorelle. Purchased and restored to its former glory sixty years later by fashion designer Yves Saint Laurent, today this oasis blossoms with rare botanical specimens: palms, cacti and bamboo, surrounding limpid ornamental pools heavy with water lilies.</p>]]><p><b>Drink in the Cascades D’Ouzoud</b></p><![CDATA[<p>What could be more of an attraction in an arid, semi-desert country than roaring waterfalls plunging through a burst of greenery? The Cascades d'Ouzoud in the Central Atlas is just that, making them a popular stopping point between Marrakech and Fez. Try the spring water here - so cold and refreshing you won&rsquo;t want to leave.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy Tangier’s bohemian vibe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head back to the decadent bohemian days of Tangier in the Grand Socco and Petit Socco, where among tax-exiled aristocrats and international spies, some of the 20th century's greatest writers, Beat poets, and rock stars like the Rolling Stones found their inspiration. Even today, this port town&rsquo;s raffish &lsquo;ask no questions&rsquo; vibe creates a thrilling ambiance.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Drâa Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Dr&acirc;a Valley is a ribbon of fertile green in the sandy semi-desert, scattered with Berber villages and impressive kasbahs, some built into the valleys rock walls themselves. The valley is a wonderful place to explore, and never more spectacular than in the evenings, as the dipping sun sets fire to the red earth.</p>]]><p><b>Get lost in Fez</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Unravel the mystery of Fes, a refined ancient centre of sacred learning and imperial power. Labyrinthine streets are anchored by the soaring minarets of the Al-Qarawiyin and Al-Andalus mosques (not open to visitors) and centuries of history are captured at the Dar Batha Museum. Fez&rsquo;s medina is a UNESCO World Heritage site, and by square kilometre is the largest continuously populated medieval city in the Islamic world.</p>]]><p><b>Get windswept on the Atlantic Coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Morocco&rsquo;s Atlantic coast is a beach-lovers dream.  Here, you might stay in Asilah, the little whitewashed town near the shores favoured by locals, relax in Agadir, where huge stretch of sand are replete with western comforts, or wander the beautiful and wild deserted shores of the Oued Massa, Souss Massa and El Houceima National Parks.</p>]]><p><b>Go birdwatching in Merja Zerga National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This biological preserve is famous among twitchers for its spectacular array of birdlife. Ask a local guide to take you out on the Blue Lagoon – a shallow salt lake that attracts vast flocks of migrant wildfowl, waders and flamingos. December and January are the best months for bird watching.</p>]]><p><b>Haggle for goods in Marrakech Souk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This legendary, bustling and chaotic bazaar is the city&rsquo;s pulse, and entering its vast and shadowy canopy-covered labyrinth north of the Djemma el Fna always elicits a thrill. Everything from carpets to cardamom can be found down these twisting lanes - and remember, the haggling&rsquo;s all part of the fun.</p>]]><p><b>High in the High Atlas Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the spectacular mountain range that runs nearly the full length of eastern Morocco, and challenge yourself with a trek to the summit of its highest peak, Jebel Toubkal, standing at 4,167m (13,671 ft). As your breath returns you&rsquo;ll be rewarded by magnificent views. The trip can be made in a day, but most trekkers take a leisurely three.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Casablanca</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Inside the urban sprawl lies a charming whitewashed Old Town, where faded works of art deco from the city&rsquo;s day as a French protectorate sit alongside intricate Moorish architecture (including the largest mosque outside Mecca). Casablanca&rsquo;s citizens generally tend to be among the most westernised and culturally progressive in the country.</p>]]><p><b>Make a detour to Tinerhir</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Clustered around a verdant palmerie in the shadow of the High Atlas, this sun-bleached city is still just a small blip on the tourist radar, but offers much to enjoy. Explore the crumbling old Jewish Quarter, pick up a bargain in the bustling town souk, or escape the heat with a wander through the fragrant oasis that runs for miles through the centre of the city.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Chellah in Sala Colonia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An ancient necropolis at the heart of the old Roman city of Sala Colonia, the Chellah is one of the most magical sights in Morocco. Perhaps the most important tomb here belongs to Abu al-Hassan, a legendary Merenid ruler and empire builder known to history as the &lsquo;Black Sultan&rsquo; of Morocco due to his dark complexion.</p>]]><p><b>Relax in sunny Essaouira</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its picture-postcard medina and fortress ramparts jutting into the sea, not to mention great seafood restaurants, boutique hotels, and a charming souk, this historic, romantic, artistic seaside town on the coast west of Marrakech is a perennial favourite of many. The broad, blustery beach, perfect for world-class windsurfing, seals the deal.</p>]]><p><b>Seek adventure in the Todra and Dades gorges</b></p><![CDATA[<p>These stunning, red-cliffed sister canyons arguably offer some of Morocco&rsquo;s most beautiful scenery and are at their best in late spring and early summer when roses carpet the canyon floor. There&rsquo;s also rock-climbing and white-water rafting available here, but most people simply come to lose themselves in the sublime surroundings.</p>]]><p><b>Spend lazy days in Chefchaouen</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This breathtaking old town, known for its medina comprising of painted blue houses scattered down a slope in the heart of the Rif Mountains, is one of Morocco&rsquo;s prettiest. Because it was once claimed by Spain as part of Spanish Morocco in the 1920s, the architecture through its steep and winding cobbled streets is a unique blend of traditional Arabic and Andalusian.</p>]]><p><b>Sweat it out in the Sahara Desert</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Witness the vast and empty majesty of the Sahara from its western edges at Ouzina and Merzouga. Venture out across the shifting ocean of sand, where trekking by camel  means you can visit nomad settlements, oases, and the mighty dunes of Erg Chebbi.</p>]]><p><b>Trek through the Rif Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This fascinating and scenic range in the country&rsquo;s north is the stronghold of the Berber people. Wonderful trekking opportunities avail, notably through the fir forests in the Talassemtane National Park.</p>]]><p><b>Walk around Aït Benhaddou</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This fortified <em>ksar</em> (city) and UNESCO World Heritage Site lies on the former caravan route between Marrakech and the Sahara. It is most famous as the setting for various high-profile Hollywood films, including <em>Gladiator</em>, <em>The Mummy</em>, <em>The Last Temptation of Christ</em>, <em>The Sheltering Sky</em>, <em>Kingdom of Heaven</em> and <em>Prince of Persia</em>.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around Meknes and Volubilis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Although smaller and more relaxed than Marrakech and Fez, Morocco&rsquo;s third imperial city is equal in charm. The ancient streets are easily navigated without a guide, and their 17th century renovations by Sultan Moulay Ismail make them a gorgeous showcase of Islamic architecture. </p>
<p>Outside the town are the ruins of Volubilis, the largest site of Roman remains in North Africa. Considered the ancient capital of the Roman-Berber kingdom of Mauretania, Volubilis once again illustrates the cultural diversity and richness of Moroccan history.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$281.4 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Clothing and textiles, automobiles, electrical components, inorganic chemicals, transistors, citrus fruits, vegetables, fish, and crude minerals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude petroleum, gas and electricity, textile fabric, telecommunications equipment, wheat, and plastics.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Spain, China, USA, and Italy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The service industry, including a booming tourism sector worth US$19 billion in 2016, accounts for 18.5% of the GDP. Remittances from Moroccans living abroad (mostly in Europe) are another major source of revenue. Financial unease in Europe contributed to an economic slowdown across the country in 2012, but in general terms the economy is one of the most stable in the region. The unemployment rate currently sits at 9%, with 15% of the population living below the poverty line. <br />
<br />
A large number of Moroccans are still employed in agriculture, where they grow cereals, vegetables and citrus fruits, while fishing remains another vital field. Industry accounts for around a quarter of GDP, of which the textile and garment industry employs a rapidly growing number of Moroccan women as well as generating export income. Mining also generates revenue for Morocco, the world's second largest exporter of phosphates. Although the country has small oil and gas reserves, it imports the bulk of its needs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Morocco is an Arabic-speaking Muslim country (although French is commonly used for foreign negotiations), and as such requires the appropriate cultural sensitivity, particularly when doing business. Business meetings are formal, and dress should likewise be formal, smart, and subdued. Women should take particular care to ensure that their legs are covered below knee level and arms are covered with long sleeves. For men a suit and tie is appropriate, and pantsuits are appropriate for women.</p>
<p>Appointments should be arranged well in advance, and should avoid times of the five daily prayers. If you are invited to dine, dress formally and remove your shoes when you are entering the home of a host. Do not bring alcohol and remember that traditional Moroccan etiquette dictates that men and women dine at different tables.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1230 and 1500-1830.<br />
Government office hours: Mon-Thurs 0830-1200 and 1430-1830, Fri 0830-1100 and 1500-1830.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>American Chamber of Commerce in Morocco</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (22) 250 736
					Website:http://www.amcham-morocco.com/
					Address: Apt. 6,67 Boulevard Massira Al Khadra,Third Floor,Casablanca,]]><b>Fédération des Chambres de Commerce et d'Industrie du Maroc</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (37) 767 881
					Website:http://www.fcmcis.ma
					Address: Hassan-Rabat,6 rue d'Erfoud,BP 218,,]]><b>British Chamber of Commerce for Morocco</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (22) 448 860
					Website:http://www.britishchambers.org.uk
					Address: Casablanca,65,Avenue Hassan Seghir,,20000]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Fusion isn't a new trend in Morocco, where the cuisine is a blend of Mediterranean, Arabic, Jewish, Persian, West African, and Berber influences. Meals range from the <em>diffa</em>, an elaborate multicourse feast featuring couscous and grilled meats, to quick <em>brochettes </em>(kebab) from a roadside stall. Produce is seasonal, grown locally and typically without chemical pesticides or fertilisers.</p>
<p>Tagines, the fragrant stews of meat, vegetables or fish, are named after the distinctive conical earthenware vessel they&rsquo;re cooked in, and are a Moroccan main staple. Flavours revolve around a subtle array of spices, and every spice shop traditionally has its own secret <em>ras el hanout</em> spice blend recipe.</p>
<p>Restaurants range from buffet diners to high-end establishment serving gourmet fare. Many now offer &agrave; la carte menus in addition to traditional three-course fixed-price dinner menus. Restaurants in cities and large resorts&nbsp;are cosmopolitan, featuring a good selection of cuisines, including typical Moroccan fare, plus French, Italian, Spanish and fusion dishes.</p>
<p>The best way to experience the true flavour of Moroccan cuisine, however, is to sample the street food. Djemaa el Fna square in the centre of Marrakech sees an explosion of pop-up food stalls after dark, and most other cities have their own foodie quarters. Scrumptious local specialities such as almonds, olives, and a rainbow array of spices can be found in souks across the country.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Harira</em> (a spicy tomato-and-lentil-based soup).<br />
&bull; <em>Pastilla</em> (a traditional Andalusian pie typically filled pigeon-meat, layered with flaky dough and dusted with cinnamon and sugar).<br />
&bull; <em>Couscous</em> (a savoury semolina dish cooked with local vegetables and/or meat).<br />
&bull; <em>Tajine</em> (a rich, fragrant stew, with some combination of lamb, chicken or fish with onions, olives, almonds, tomato, herbs or dried fruit).<br />
&bull; <em>Mechoui</em> (slow-roasted stuffed lamb or beef).<br />
<br />
<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Laws on alcohol are fairly liberal (for non-Muslim visitors) and bars in most tourist areas stay open late. Wines, beers, and spirits are available to tourists. Muslims are forbidden to drink alcohol. By law, no one is allowed to drink alcohol in view of a mosque or during Ramadan, although tourist establishments sometimes flout this rule. Locally produced wines, beers, and mineral waters are reasonably priced, but imported drinks tend to be expensive.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tipping waiting staff is expected (if service is satisfactory), usually up to 5 dirams on small bills, and around 10% for larger bills.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Morocco offers a variety of nightly distractions, including bars, discos and restaurants, often with live music or belly dancing as part of the evening's entertainment. The party usually gets started around midnight, when dining tables are shoved out of the way to accommodate serious hip-shaking, and the fashionable make their entrance in nightclubs.</p>
<p>Club culture is centred around Marrakech and Casablanca, where palatial discos and cocktail lounges blend Eastern and Western culture. Late-night cafes are a way of life in cosmopolitan Tangier, while Agadir is infamous for its resort-style nightlife. Most large hotels offer entertainment in the form of bars or boutique clubs.</p>
<p>There are also casinos in Marrakech, Mohammedia, Tangier, and Agadir. Be prepared for little or low-key entertainment in smaller centres. High-stakes entertainment can't compare to the cheap, fantastic thrills of <em>halqa</em>, the street theatre performances by acrobats, musicians and cross-dressing belly dancers who perform for spare change in city squares across Morocco, especially Tangier and the Djemaa el-Fna in Marrakech (UNESCO's World Heritage site for oral history).</p>
<p>Most Moroccan cities are relatively safe after dark, but it&rsquo;s wise for female clubbers not to venture out alone or in small groups. Bear in mind that alcohol is only served in a small number of establishments.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopping is not just a pastime in Morocco &ndash; it&rsquo;s the way of life. The unique souks (traditional covered bazaars) and markets found throughout the country&mdash;from the enormous labyrinths in Marrakech and Fez to the earnest everyday bustle of rural town markets&mdash;are one of Morocco&rsquo;s greatest visitor attractions.</p>
<p>At the other end of the scale, Morocco Mall, stretching across 10 hectares (25 acres) of Casablanca, is North Africa&rsquo;s largest shopping centre. The larger souks are often loosely divided into quarters hosting different trades and vendors, such as spice merchants, pottery sellers, jewellery-makers, and leather-workers.</p>
<p>Haggling is a traditional necessity, so never pay regard to initial prices. Instead fix an items value in your mind then negotiate towards it unhurriedly (Moroccans never rush their bargaining), and don&rsquo;t be afraid to simply walk away if the price isn&rsquo;t right.</p>
<p>For visitors the main draw in Morocco is the range of handcrafts. Traditional metal-work lamps and the distinctive blue-and-white glazed earthenware from Fez are ever popular and relatively inexpensive purchases. However, it&rsquo;s a misconception that another specialty here, rugs and carpets, are also cheap. They aren&rsquo;t &ndash; and the best hand-knotted examples usually carry a four-figure price tag.</p>
<p>If you venture out of the city and into the High Atlas, look out for local specialities such as argan oil, rose water, olive oil, Berber jewellery, and precious minerals. Foodstuffs&mdash;including walnuts, dates, preserved lemons, almonds and saffron&mdash;also make tasty souvenirs.</p><p>Mon-Thurs 1000-1230 and 1530-1900, Fri 0900-1100 and 1530-1900. Shops in new towns are often open Friday afternoons and Sundays.</p><p>Souvenirs sold at the roadside&mdash;particularly minerals, gems and argan oil&mdash;are often fakes. The skill exhibited by Moroccan gem painters, however, gives some false crystals value in their own right.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Morocco&rsquo;s tourist industry continues to flourish, with forecasts predicting ever increasing numbers of visitors, so there&rsquo;s no shortage of hotels in every budget-range, class, and style.&nbsp;Choose from&nbsp;eco-lodges and converted casbahs in the mountains, luxury and package resorts spanning the beaches of the Atlantic coast, and historic riads in the city medinas.</p>
<p>Indeed, riads, being an accommodation type specific to Morocco, harbour a special attraction for many visitors. A riad is a traditional Moroccan house designed around a central open-air courtyard or garden. Most are found in the medinas of larger cities, and are popular for their privacy and wonderfully authentic features. Many are centuries old and include decorative beam work and original Arabic mosaic tiling.</p>
<p>One of the most popular choices for a stay in Morocco&mdash;especially for those looking for the simple pleasures of sun, sea and sand&mdash;is a holiday resort. Most of the country&rsquo;s big resorts are along the Atlantic coast. Agadir is still the largest, offering an array of hotel complexes to suit all budgets, and its vast beach remains a firm favourite. All-inclusive resorts in formerly modest seaside towns, such as El Jadida, are becoming increasingly popular.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Morocco&rsquo;s tourist industry continues to flourish, with forecasts predicting ever increasing numbers of visitors, so there&rsquo;s no shortage of hotels in every budget-range, class, and style.&nbsp;Choose from&nbsp;eco-lodges and converted casbahs in the mountains, luxury and package resorts spanning the beaches of the Atlantic coast, and historic riads in the city medinas.</p>
<p>Indeed, riads, being an accommodation type specific to Morocco, harbour a special attraction for many visitors. A riad is a traditional Moroccan house designed around a central open-air courtyard or garden. Most are found in the medinas of larger cities, and are popular for their privacy and wonderfully authentic features. Many are centuries old and include decorative beam work and original Arabic mosaic tiling.</p>
<p>One of the most popular choices for a stay in Morocco&mdash;especially for those looking for the simple pleasures of sun, sea and sand&mdash;is a holiday resort. Most of the country&rsquo;s big resorts are along the Atlantic coast. Agadir is still the largest, offering an array of hotel complexes to suit all budgets, and its vast beach remains a firm favourite. All-inclusive resorts in formerly modest seaside towns, such as El Jadida, are becoming increasingly popular.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Morocco&rsquo;s tourist industry continues to flourish, with forecasts predicting ever increasing numbers of visitors, so there&rsquo;s no shortage of hotels in every budget-range, class, and style.&nbsp;Choose from&nbsp;eco-lodges and converted casbahs in the mountains, luxury and package resorts spanning the beaches of the Atlantic coast, and historic riads in the city medinas.</p>
<p>Indeed, riads, being an accommodation type specific to Morocco, harbour a special attraction for many visitors. A riad is a traditional Moroccan house designed around a central open-air courtyard or garden. Most are found in the medinas of larger cities, and are popular for their privacy and wonderfully authentic features. Many are centuries old and include decorative beam work and original Arabic mosaic tiling.</p>
<p>One of the most popular choices for a stay in Morocco&mdash;especially for those looking for the simple pleasures of sun, sea and sand&mdash;is a holiday resort. Most of the country&rsquo;s big resorts are along the Atlantic coast. Agadir is still the largest, offering an array of hotel complexes to suit all budgets, and its vast beach remains a firm favourite. All-inclusive resorts in formerly modest seaside towns, such as El Jadida, are becoming increasingly popular.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever <HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid <HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus <HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies <HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria <HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A <HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria <HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria "><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are decent medical facilities in all main cities, including emergency pharmacies (see postings in pharmacy windows listing the nearest &lt;em&gt;pharmacie du garde&lt;/em&gt;, or after-hours pharmacy) and clinics in major hotels outside normal opening hours. Government hospitals provide free or minimal charge emergency treatment. However, do not expect Western standards of treatment &amp;ndash; with a healthcare system that&amp;rsquo;s vastly underfunded, public hospitals tend to be run down, lacking in facilities and may not be able to provide a comprehensive range of treatments. It is recommended that visitors take out travel insurance that will cover medical treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water sources outside main cities and towns may be contaminated and sterilisation is advisable. Bottled water is the best bet and is available everywhere. Milk is unpasteurised, so boil before drinking. Meat and fish should be freshly cooked and served hot. Vegetables are typically served cooked. If eating fruit, try to stick to fruit that can be peeled before eating. Most produce is grown organically, without chemical pesticides or fertilisers but it&amp;rsquo;s highly likely to have been washed in unsterilised water.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Malaria is extremely rare in Morocco and is limited to rural Chefchaouen. Travellers visiting the province between May and October might want to consider taking malaria tablets and using some form of mosquito repellent to avoid bites, especially if sleeping outside. If venturing into higher altitude areas such as the mountains, take care to acclimatise first, as altitude sickness can bring on nausea and dizziness. Visitors should wear sunscreen and drink plenty of water to avoid heatstroke and sunburn.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Independence Manifesto Day :
							2018<br/>11 January </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Throne Day :
							30 July </p><p>Oued Ed-Dahab Day :
							14 August </p><p>Revolution Day :
							20 August </p><p>King Mohammed IV's Birthday :
							21 August </p><p>Green March Day :
							06 November </p><p>Independence Day :
							18 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Morocco without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400g of tobacco products.<br />
&bull; 1 litre of spirits and 1 litre of wine.<br />
&bull; 150ml of perfume or 250ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Gifts to the value of Dh2,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms and ammunition, narcotics, absinthe, publications containing &ldquo;immoral, sexual or offensive&quot; material, and plants and plant products considered a threat to national flora.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must obtain permission to export expensive cultural artefacts. Exporting national currency, the Moroccan dirham, is forbidden.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Moroccan Dirham (MAD; symbol Dh) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of Dh200, 100, 50, and 20. Coins are in denominations of Dh10, 5 and 1, and 50, 20, 10 and 5 centimes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Moroccan Dirhams can only be obtained in Morocco. The most convenient way to obtain Dirhams is through an ATM, where official rates automatically apply, but daily withdrawal limits can seem low for customers paying cash for rugs in the souks. National currencies should be exchanged at official bureaux de change only (identified by a golden sign); changing money in the street is illegal. There is no commission charge and visitors will be issued with a receipt that they must keep in order to exchange Moroccan currency back into the original national currency upon departure. The Euro and US Dollar are widely accepted, even preferred. However, you won&rsquo;t be able to change Northern Irish or Scottish bank notes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major credit cards are accepted in larger restaurants, hotels, guesthouses and the occasional shop in the souks, with Visa and Mastercard being the most widely accepted companies.</p><p>Cash can be withdrawn from ATMs in larger towns, although service in smaller towns can be erratic. Most major hotels now have reliable ATMs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are accepted in some areas but are not advised, as the exchange can be problematic and it can be difficult to find a bank able to cash them. However, some of the main tourist hotels can cash cheques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0830-1230 and 1500-1830, Fri 0830-1200 and 1500-1830.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA "><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU "><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian "><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British "><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian "><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Morocco, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by UK and US nationals; the passports of Canadian and Australian citizens must be valid at least six months past the date of expected departure. EU citizens should check with the relevant embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa: &pound;18. Fee varies according to the exchange rate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa: 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are usually processed within two weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors who do require a visa must provide pay slips and bank statements from the previous three months with their application.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets are allowed but you must have a vaccination history from your Vet. This should be legalised by the British Agricultural Department, and then by the British Foreign Office.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[31.889010]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-6.350975]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>710,850 sq km (274,461 sq miles; including disputed Western Sahara).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>33,986,655(UN estimate June 2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>48&nbsp;per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rabat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Morocco is located on the westernmost tip of north Africa, bordering Algeria to the east, Mauritania and the disputed territory of Western Sahara to the south, the Atlantic ocean to the west, and the Mediterranean to the north.</p>
<p>Running through the middle of the country is the Atlas mountain range. The Middle Atlas range sweeps up from the south, rising to over 2,000m (6,562ft). It&rsquo;s known for woodlands of pine, oak and cedar, open pastureland, and small lakes. The Rif Mountains run along the north coast. Often snow-covered in winter, Morocco's mountains are home to the country's significant indigenous Berber population.</p>
<p>The long stretch of Atlantic coast down Morocco's western side features cool breezes and long sandy beaches. It is separated from the mountainous region by wide swathes of fertile plains. To the north is the Mediterranean coast, just a stone's throw from the European continent &ndash; Gibraltar is one hour&rsquo;s ferry ride.</p>
<p>The Sahara&mdash;the largest desert in the world&mdash;stretches its toes into southern Morocco. Far from being featureless, it is dotted with fascinating traditional villages and cool oases.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Morocco is predominantly Muslim with Jewish, Christian, and Hindu minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Morocco's culture is a blend of religious and ethnic traditions, encompassing Berber, Arab, African, Mediterranean, and Jewish influences. Greetings involve a handshake and friendly inquiries after health, happiness and family &ndash; no business is discussed until after these pleasantries. Friends may tack on the cheek an air-kiss or two. Moroccan chattiness makes everyday interactions more pleasant, if longer; patience and extroversion are assets. In the souks, vendors to call out to customers, joking and striking up conversations before bargaining begins. When offered tea, it's polite to at least take a sip.<br />
<br />
Although casual gear is widely acceptable, wearing any clothing that reveals arms or legs is disrespectful. Swimsuits, shorts, sleeveless tops, and clingy clothing should be confined to the beach or poolside for both men and women. Women travelling alone can expect help and friendship, but will avoid undue attention if they cover up, ideally in local garb. Sexual relations outside marriage (including homosexual conduct) are theoretically punishable by law, but this is rarely enforced. Smoking is widespread, though prohibited in enclosed public spaces. Drinking alcohol in view of a mosque is highly disrespectful and alcohol licences are expensive, but alcohol is often served discreetly indoors or on terraces.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz, depending on age and location of building. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Saadeddine Othmani since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Mohammed VI since 1999.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Whether you&rsquo;re exploring the ruins of Volubilis, strolling through the streets of an ancient medina, shopping for spices in a centuries-old souk, or following a chain of pack mules up to a remote Berber village, you can&rsquo;t escape the power of Moroccan history. In the valleys of the High Atlas, the descendants of the country&rsquo;s original nomadic inhabitants still live in a remarkably similar style to their ancient ancestors. Architecture in urban areas often carries traces of the Roman and Islamic occupations that helped shape modern Morocco.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s history is tied up with the story of the Berber tribes, who repelled the Ancient Roman colonialists with a campaign of harassment, and later survived through a cycle of rising and falling Islamic dynasties. The largely Berber Istiqlal (independence) party aggressively contested the brief French occupation of Morocco during the early 20th century and control was eventually ceded to a line of Moroccan kings. Throughout the latter part of the century borrowing, corruption, poverty, and civil discontent took their toll.</p>
<p>Since King Mohammed VI was enthroned in 1999, however, Morocco has instituted sweeping political and economic changes. Poverty is still widespread and unemployment high, but initiatives to attract foreign investment and tourism are bringing new opportunities.</p>
<p>The human rights record is markedly improved and today ranks among the cleanest across Africa and the Middle East. Women have benefitted from education initiatives, a new legal code that protects their rights to both divorce and custody, and new protections for Berber (Amazigh) culture including the introduction of Tamazight (written Berber) in schools.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s first municipal elections in 2002 were hailed as a step towards democratisation, but Islamist and other political factions are closely monitored, as are news media. Further progress was made during the Arab Spring, which saw thousands of protestors take to the streets of Rabat, Casablanca, Tangier, and Marrakech to demand a new constitution and a change in government. Their peaceful tactics paid off and in spring 2011, the King announced his intention to stamp out corruption and reform the constitution. Immediate changes included handing more executive authority to the prime minister and parliament and making Berber an official national language alongside Arabic.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; Morocco&rsquo;s cinema history stretches back to 1897 when Louis Lumi&egrave;re, one of the first ever film makers in history, made <em>Le Chevrier Marocain</em>.</p>
<p>&bull; UNESCO considers the al-Qarawiyin University, founded in Fez in AD 859, to be the oldest in the world.</p>
<p>&bull; Astapor, an ancient city in Game of Thrones, was filmed in Essaouira.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Morocco in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 462 7979.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofmorocco.us</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 462 7979.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Consular section: Mon-Thurs 0930-1700, Fri 0930-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1601 21st Street NW<br/>Washington, D.C<br/>20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Morocco in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7581 5001.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.moroccanembassylondon.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7581 5001.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0930-1600. Fri 0930-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Kensington<br/>49 Queen's Gate Gardens<br/>London<br/>SW7 5NE<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Moroccan Consulate in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7724 0624</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.moroccanconsulate.org.uk/en/index.html</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7724 0624</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1400 (for visas).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Paddington<br/>Diamond House, 97-99 Praed Street<br/>London<br/>W2 1NT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Morocco]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+212 537 633 333</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-rabat</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+212 537 633 333</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0800 1615, Fri 0800-1300&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Souissi<br/>28 Avenue S.A.R. Sidi Mohammed<br/>Rabat<br/>10105 (BP 45)<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Morocco is a heady mix of cultures, religions, ancient traditions, and modern sensibilities. It conjures up images of mint tea and tagine, date plantations and minarets, labyrinthine medinas and pungent spice stalls.</p>
<p>One of the more liberal countries in North Africa, Morocco&rsquo;s biggest drawing card is Marrakech, a giddying and grandiose city that Winston Churchill described as &ldquo;simply the nicest place on Earth to spend an afternoon.&rdquo; This sentiment rings true for many travellers today.</p>
<p>Each city has a distinctive and different character. Tangier, in the north, is the gateway to Africa, and is characterised by its white-washed buildings, sandy beaches and burgeoning cultural scene.&nbsp;Further down the coast lies cosmopolitan Casablanca, the faded coastal town of Essaouira and the lively beach resort of Agadir, favoured by sun-seekers and surfers. Inland&nbsp;Fez&nbsp;captivates travellers with its dusty souks, high-sided streets, and maze of stunning riads (traditional houses built around a central courtyard).</p>
<p>The blend of ancient and colonial architecture that characterises Morocco&rsquo;s main cities makes them beautiful propositions: Marrakech, Essaouira, Fez, and T&eacute;touan are all on UNESCO&rsquo;s World Heritage list and are home to an increasing collection of cultural attractions. And when sightseeing begins to pall, visitors can retreat to a traditional hammam, sample the country&rsquo;s delectable cuisine or barter for bargains in the souks.</p>
<p>Beyond the cities, awesome landscapes await. Carving Morocco in two are the Atlas Mountains, home to the monumental gorges of Todra and Dades, the palmeries of Tinerhir, and the beautiful Berber city of Ouarzazate, where active travellers will find skiing aplenty. Then there&rsquo;s Merzouga, famous for camel-trekking and birdwatching, and Toubkal, North Africa&rsquo;s highest mountain.</p>
<p>The epic waves of Western Sahara prove an adventure too far for most travellers. Government forces continue to occupy this disputed territory, even though Moroccan sovereignty is not recognised by the United Nations. The issue remains a sensitive subject.</p><p>Morocco is a heady mix of cultures, religions, ancient traditions, and modern sensibilities. It conjures up images of mint tea and tagine, date plantations and minarets, labyrinthine medinas and pungent spice stalls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
