<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Mozambique" ColCode="moz" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mz" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Mozambique]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Climate varies according to area. Inland is cooler than the coast and rainfall higher as the land rises, with most rain between January and March. Hottest and wettest season is October to March. From April to September the coast has warm, mainly dry weather tempered by sea breezes.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical lightweights, with warmer clothing for evenings. Rainwear advisable all year round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>LAM-Linhas A&eacute;reas de Mo&ccedil;ambique&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.lam.co.mz/" target="_blank">www.lam.co.mz</a>) offers domestic flights linking Maputo with Beira, Chimoio, Inhambane, Lichinga, Nampula, Pemba, Quelimane and Tete. Flights are frequently delayed or cancelled and baggage is often lost or tampered with. Air-taxi services are also available, and are the safest means of transport outside the cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFM (<a href="http://www.cfm.co.mz" target="_blank">www.cfm.co.mz</a>) runs Mozambique's railways. Services include a train from Maputo to Ressano Garcia on the South African border and from Maputo to Chicualacuala on the Zimbabwean border. Most trains have three classes, but there are few sleepers and no dining or air-conditioned cars. For seats and sleepers, it is necessary to book in advance. All train services are subject to disruption. Services from Beira have been suspended due to reconstruction work. See CFM's website for a list of current routes.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving after dark can be hazardous owing to vehicles travelling without headlights. Car-jacking is a risk, so keep your doors locked. Although now cleared from main routes, mines may still be present in remote areas; check with the local authorities for up-to-date advice.</p>l<p>Tarred roads connect Maputo with Beira and Beira with Tete.&nbsp;It's possible to travel by road in southern Mozambique though flood damage can cause serious delays.</p><p>Rarely available outside large towns.</p><p>A national driving licence is valid for up to 90 days. Third-party insurance is compulsory and is available at most land borders.</p><p>You must carry a reflective triangle and reflective clothing in your car at all times.</p><p>You can hire cars from international and local agencies in Maputo and Beira.</p><p>You must carry a reflective triangle and reflective clothing in your car at all times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Maputo has a fairly extensive bus service, with modern buses gifted by China.&nbsp;Taxis are metered and drivers expect a tip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is LAM-Linhas A&eacute;reas de Mo&ccedil;ambique (<a href="http://www.lam.co.mz/" target="_blank">www.lam.co.mz</a>). South African Airways (<a href="http://www.flysaa.com" target="_blank">www.flysaa.com</a>) operates flights from the UK and the USA to Mozambique via Johannesburg.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 17 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Nampula Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 4km (2.5 miles) east of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Beira Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 13km (8 miles) from the city (journey time - 15 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Maputo International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport  is 3km (1.8 miles) northwest of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cargo vessels call at Maputo and Beira, but there are no regular passenger services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A train runs from Johannesburg and Pretoria to the Mozambique border at Ressano Garcia where there is a connection to Maputo. There is also a service connecting Maputo with Bulawayo, Zimbabwe, changing trains at Chicualacuala. Rail services are sometimes sporadic and unreliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone operators. Coverage is expanding to all main cities in most provinces.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet cafes in Maputo and other cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Postal services are available in main centres. Airmail to Europe usually takes five to seven days, but sometimes longer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Delve into the Indian Ocean</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go diving and snorkelling with dolphins, rays and dugong (manatee) in the country's crystal-clear Indian Ocean waters. Mozambique has a growing number of resorts that are well equipped for subaquatic activities. Highlights for divers include the reefs of Inhambane, the Bazaruto Archipelago or Quirimbas National Park.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a night out in Pemba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Pemba, a vibrant and rapidly growing coastal city that nestles on the shores of the Indian Ocean. Embrace the sweltering temperatures on the beach at Wimbe, just outside town, before heading into the Old Town for a few snifters. As well as a lively selection of bars, there are also some fine restaurants in the city.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy fantastic birdwatching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pack your binoculars because Mozambique is an excellent place to go birdwatching. Many brightly coloured species can be found along the coast, not to mention Gorongosa National Park and Marromeu National Park, which attract twitchers from around the world.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Quirimbas National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bask in the sun and balmy waters of Quirimbas National Park. Dive and snorkel off its shores to appreciate the park's abundant marine life and coral reefs. Quirimbas, which stretches for 110km (68miles) along the coastline of northern Mozambique, is also home to a variety of land-bound wildlife including elephants, lions, leopards and wild dogs.</p>]]><p><b>Go fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mozambique offers world-class sports fishing. Black, blue and striped marlin, sailfish, dorado, kingfish, barracuda and dogtooth tuna are all possible to catch in the Mozambique Channel. The Bazaruto Archipelago is one of several popular spots for game fishing. Many fishing resorts operate a catch and release policy.</p>]]><p><b>Go on safari</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a safari through some of the country's 12 different national parks and reserves. The Big Five (elephant, lion, leopard, buffalo and rhino) can all be found here, and plenty more besides. There is a huge variety of landscapes to enjoy from coastal areas to mountains.</p>]]><p><b>Hike national parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bring your walking boots because the cool mountains of the north and the various national parks offer good hiking. Landmines used to present a danger, but don't be deterred: in 2015 Mozambique was declared free of the deadly weapons planted during the civil war.</p>]]><p><b>Keep your eyes peeled in Gorongosa National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the jewel in Mozambique's crown: the Gorongosa National Park. Located 80km (50 miles) northwest of Beira, and open from April to October, access is provided by an airstrip at Chitengo. It's worth the effort getting there: visitors can expect superb birdwatching, plus glimpses of buffalo, elephants, hippos, zebra and more.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in the capital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't head straight out of Maputo: it's one of Africa's more appealing capitals, with wide avenues, relaxed street cafes and a lively cultural scene. The city museum and market are worth a look, as are the Central Railway Station and curious Iron House, both designed by Gustave Eiffel.</p>]]><p><b>Marromeu National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Venture out to the little-visited Marromeu National Park, not far from Beira, at the mouth of the Zambesi River in Sofala Province. The main attractions are buffalo and birds, but lions, elephants and leopards are also present. It is possible to camp in the park overnight.</p>]]><p><b>Relax in a luxury lodge on a white sand beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't miss the stunning Bazaruto Archipelago, which comprises five tropical islands plus surrounding islets and coral reefs. Located 20km (12 miles) from the Vilanculos and Inhassoro, this beautiful area features white sandy beaches, clear waters and rich marine life including the dugong (manatee). There are plenty of luxury lodges providing accommodation.</p>]]><p><b>Relax on a beautiful beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mozambique is not short of coastline and boasts some spectacular white sandy beaches. Popular beaches include Ponta do Ouro, Malugane (in the south), Inhambane with its beach resort of Tofo, Xai-Xai, Vilankulo and Chonguene.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in time</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hop across by bridge to tiny Ilha de Moçambique (Mozambique Island), near Nampula in the north, which was the capital of the country under the Portuguese. It is a fascinating place, dotted with 17th- and 18th-century buildings and mosques, many of them from the colonial period. It has been declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site.</p>]]><p><b>Track down some elephants</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a trip to the Maputo National Reserve, also known as Maputo Elephant Park, which is on the Maputo River, 79km (49 miles) south of the city. It's also home to leopard, antelope, crocodiles, hippos, flamingos and jackals. It combines lakes, wetlands, swamp forests grasslands and mangroves.</p>]]><p><b>Visit a historic island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hop on a boat to Inhaca Island in the south of Mozambique not too far from the capital, Maputo. The island has 40km (25 miles) of beaches and reefs, a historic lighthouse and a museum of marine biology. It is a very popular spot for diving.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$6.3 billion (2006).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cotton, cashew nuts, sugarcane, tea and cassava (tapioca).</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, vehicles, fuel and chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Netherlands, South Africa, Portugal and Zimbabwe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following the civil war, the Mozambican economy picked up strongly in the late 1990s. Devastating floods, drought and trade-related disputes in the new millennium have intermittently undermined progress, and required aid donors to step in. Growth was at a healthy 7.9% in 2006, but inflation was also high at 13.2%.<br /><br />In mid 2006, the World Bank relieved Mozambique from much of its long-term foreign debt burden, and remaining debts were rescheduled under the IMF's Heavily Indebted Poor Countries (HIPC) initiative.<br /><br />Agriculture is the mainstay of the economy. Forestry is increasing in importance. Fishing is both an important source of food and a vital export earner. Manufacturing industry produces one quarter of GDP: products include processed foods, textiles, drinks, cement and fertiliser. Mining operations produce coal, salt, bauxite, gemstones and marble. In addition, natural gas is extracted from onshore fields and piped to South Africa.<br /><br />Mozambique is a member of the Southern African Development Conference.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits are advised. Prior appointments are recommended. A knowledge of Portuguese is normally necessary for business dealings, although there are translation facilities available in Maputo. January is the main holiday month, so this should be avoided for business trips.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1230 and 1400-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Câmara de Comércio de Moçambique</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 492 904
					Website:http://www.ccmusa.co.mz/
					Address: Rua Mateus Sansão Mutemba 452,CP 1836,Maputo,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The cuisine in Mozambique is predominately African, but heavily influenced by the Portuguese with some Far Eastern influences. As you might expect from a coastal country, seafood is a speciality. Lunch is usually the main meal of the day. Soup is often served as a starter followed by main dishes usually accompanied by rice, potatoes or both. Restaurants are found in main towns and hotels, but street food is available in most places.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Piri-pirichicken:</strong> Chicken marinated in lemon juice, garlic and a spicy chilli sauce (made of lemon juice, garlic, chilli, and oil). Usually served with chips.<br />
<strong>Shellfish:</strong> All shellfish is good in Mozambique and the country is famous for prawns often grilled with piri-piri sauce.<br />
<strong>Matapa:</strong> Sauce of ground peanuts and cassava leaves served with rice. It often includes seafood. <br />
<strong>Wusa:</strong> Stiff maize porridge.<br />
<strong>Pao:</strong> Portuguese white bread rolls baked in wood-fired ovens.<br />
<strong>Prego roll:</strong> Steak covered in piri piri sauce in a bread roll.<br />
<strong>Toasted cheese sandwiches:</strong> A commonly sold snack.<br />
<strong>Malasadas:</strong> Local doughnuts sold in markets.<br />
<strong>2M:</strong> Popular local beer.<br />
<strong>Tipo Tinto:</strong> The national rum.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Not generally expected outside Maputo. In Maputo and other tourist-exposed areas, around 5% of the bill is normal (depending on standards of service and the place itself).</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Maputo has a lively nightlife, particularly on weekends. <em>Feira Popular</em> is the main forum of evening activity with various bars and discos, some with live music. The style of music in clubs varies from typical Mozambican rhythms to Western pop music. Most major towns have cinemas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases include basketwork, reed mats, woodcarvings, masks, printed cloth and leather articles.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1230 and 1400-1730, Sat 0800-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels of international standard are found mainly in the cities of Maputo and Beira. Accommodation in smaller towns is generally of a lower standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is possible to rent holiday cottages, bungalows and <em>rondavels</em> (traditional circular dwellings) cheaply.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels of international standard are found mainly in the cities of Maputo and Beira. Accommodation in smaller towns is generally of a lower standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels of international standard are found mainly in the cities of Maputo and Beira. Accommodation in smaller towns is generally of a lower standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Full health insurance, preferably including Medevac, is essential. Medical facilities are scarce. It is advisable to carry basic medical supplies including medications and sterile syringes.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Some milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Heroes' Day :
							03 February </p><p>Women's Day :
							07 April </p><p>Workers' Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							25 June </p><p>Victory Day :
							07 September </p><p>Armed Forces Day :
							25 September </p><p>Peace and Reconciliation Day :
							04 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Family Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Mozambique without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 750ml of spirits.<br />
&bull; A reasonable quantity of perfume (opened).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics and unauthorised firearms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mozambique Metical (MZN; symbol MT) = 100 centavos. Notes are in denominations of MT1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50 and 20. Coins are in denominations of MT10, 5, 2 and 1 and 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 centavos.<br /><br /><strong>Note:</strong> The new Metical replaced the old Metical (MZM) on 1 July 2006. 1 MZN = 1,000 MZM. The old notes ceased being legal tender on 31 December 2006.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are bureaux de change at the airports. Money can also be changed at banks. It is advisable to take US Dollars or South African Rand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are increasingly accepted in Maputo, but not generally beyond the capital.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not commonly accepted, and where accepted are slow to process and often attract high rates of commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0730-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for a minimum of six months beyond the intended date of departure from Mozambique is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist and Visit: &pound;50 (single-entry); &pound;80 (multiple-entry).</p>
<p>One-day express service: &pound;120 (single-entry); &pound;150 (multiple-entry).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: one day to one month, renewable to a maximum of 90 days, provided you apply for an extension before the visa expires.</p>
<p>Multiple-entry visa: one day to 90 days for tourism multiple-entry visas and up to 180 days for business multiple-entry visas. Those wishing to travel to return to Mozambique after visiting Kruger National Park in South Africa should apply for a multiple-entry visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>High commission or embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three working days for visa processing. Visas can also be issued within 24 hours (express service) for an additional fee.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend single-entry 30-day visas to a maximum of 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-17.905972]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[35.346971]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>799,380 sq km (308,642 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>28,751,362 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>31.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Maputo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mozambique borders Tanzania to the north, Zambia and Malawi to the northwest, Zimbabwe to the west, and South Africa and Swaziland to the southwest. To the east lies the Indian Ocean and a coastline of nearly 2,500km (1,550 miles) with beaches bordered by lagoons, coral reefs and strings of islands. Behind the coastline, a vast low plateau rising towards mountains in the west and north accounts for nearly half the area of Mozambique. The landscape of the plateau is savannah - more or less dry and open woodlands with tracts of short grass steppe.</p>
<p>The western and northern highlands are patched with forest. The Zambezi is the largest and most important of the 25 main rivers which flow through Mozambique into the Indian Ocean. The major concentrations of population (comprising many different ethnic groups) are along the coast and in the fertile and relatively productive river valleys, notably in Zambezia and Gaza provinces.</p>
<p>The Makua-Lomwe, who belong to the Central Bantu, live mainly in the area north of Zambezia, Nampula, Niassa and Cabo Delgado provinces. The Tsonga, who are the predominant race in the southern lowlands, provide a great deal of the labour for the South African mines. In the Inhambane coastal district are the Chopi and Tsonga, while in the central area are the Shona. The Makonde inhabit the far north. Mestizos and Asians live in the main populated area along the coast and in the more fertile river valleys.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christian (mainly Roman Catholic), Muslim and Hindu. Many also follow traditional beliefs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is the customary form of greeting. The courtesies and modes of address customary in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/portugal">Portugal</a> and other Latin countries are still observed. Casual wear is acceptable. Formal dress is seldom required.<br /><strong><br />Photography:</strong> Visitors should not take photographs of soldiers, airports, bridges or government/public buildings, since this is illegal. Only photos of beaches and other tourist sites may be taken.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. South African-style three-pin (round) plugs are used in the capital and most tourist areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Carlos Agostinho do Ros&aacute;rio since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Filipe Nyusi since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bantu tribes moved into an area, part of which is now Mozambique, from central and western Africa during the third century. The 11th-century Shona Empire, the main ethnic group in modern Zimbabwe, covered part of Mozambique and relations between the two peoples are still very close.</p>
<p>Mozambique attracted the attention of Arab and Indian traders in the 10th century. The first European expedition to Mozambique was led by the Portuguese explorer Vasco da Gama, who arrived in 1498. Thereafter, Portuguese influence gradually displaced the Arabs and Indians.</p>
<p>The Portuguese colonialists gradually moved inland, usurping the local rulers and taking over land and mineral resources. By the 18th century, they had developed Mozambique into a major centre for the slave trade, which continued to thrive for decades after its official banning in 1842.</p>
<p>Mozambique continued as a Portuguese colony until 1951 when it became an overseas province. The economy expanded rapidly during the 1950s and early 1960s, attracting thousands of Portuguese settlers to the country.</p>
<p>It was around this time that the first nationalist groups began to form. The main nationalist movement, FRELIMO, began a guerrilla war, which ended in 1974 following a military coup in Portugal. The new left-wing government in Lisbon had no wish to maintain an empire and independence negotiations began immediately. Mozambique became independent in 1975, and FRELIMO took power in a one-party state.</p>
<p>Then a 16-year-long civil war ensued. The National Resistance Movement (RENAMO), set up by the white-run Rhodesian government and then backed by apartheid South Africa and the US, fought a guerrilla war against FRELIMO from 1976 until the a ceasefire was brokered in 1992.</p>
<p>Elections were held in 1994 and won by FRELIMO. The new government was confronted with hundreds of thousands of refugees, as well as large numbers of demobilised soldiers from both sides, massive social and economic dislocation, and the destruction of virtually all health and education services.</p>
<p>Despite some setbacks, the Chissano government made steady progress in tackling these problems during the late 1990s, and in 1999 FRELIMO prevailed once again with Armando Guebuza becoming president. In the 2015 election, he was succeeded by Filipe Nyusi, also from FRELIMO.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Apparently the name of the country arose from Musa al Big the name of an Arab who was living on Ilha de Mozabique when the Portuguese arrived.<br />
&bull; Over 22 years, more than 170,000 landmines were cleared from Mozambique. In some places specially trained rats were used to locate the mines. The country was declared free of the deadly weapons in 2015.<br />
&bull; Mozambique is home to five of the seven endangered species of sea turtles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Mozambique]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>2135 6000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>2135 6000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-12.30 and 1300-1600. Fri 0800-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Avenida Vladmir Lenine, 310<br/>Maputo City<br/>P.O. Box 55<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Mozambique in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 293 7146. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embamoc-usa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 293 7146. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1700; Fri 0900-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1525 New Hampshire Avenue NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mozambique High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7383 3800.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mozambiquehighcommission.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7383 3800.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1300 and 1400-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>21 Fitzroy Square<br/>London<br/>W1T 6EL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mozambique&rsquo;s messy post-colonial history and poor infrastructure mean that most visitors are cut from fairly intrepid cloth. But travelling this enigmatic and underexplored country is well worth the occasional bump in the road, both literal and metaphorical.</p>
<p>First and foremost amongst the country&rsquo;s many attractions is its pristine Indian Ocean coastline &ndash; all 2,414km (1,500 miles) of it &ndash; which offers palm-fringed beaches, warm tropical waters, abundant marine life, great fishing, excellent diving, fantastic snorkeling and a number of idyllic islands from which you can enjoy all of the above in sweet isolation.</p>
<p>And then there are the parks. Though much of the country&rsquo;s big game was wiped out during the desperate days of the Mozambican Civil War (1977-1992), sterling conservation efforts have seen several national parks restored to something like their former glory. Their remoteness and relative inaccessibility, compared to the parks in neighbouring South Africa, mean you&rsquo;ll never be jostling for space with the masses.</p>
<p>Mozambique&rsquo;s Portuguese heritage and faded art deco charm characterises much of the capital, Maputo, in the form of colourful, crumbling and sometimes bullet-ridden colonial buildings, which stand in stark contrast to the more modern parts of this vibrant port city. The music, the nightlife and the food are equally interesting and eclectic; head to the bustling fish market to enjoy what many locals will tell you is the best seafood in East Africa.</p>
<p>There is also good hiking with little-visited mountains dotted throughout the Mozambican hinterland, but extreme caution should be taken due to the large amount of leftover landmines.</p>
<p>Since peace returned to the country in 1992, Mozambique has been trying to piece itself back together and realise its substantial tourism potential. But for now, a large part of the country&rsquo;s appeal lies in its relative obscurity from the more beaten paths of Southern Africa.</p><p>Mozambique&rsquo;s messy post-colonial history and poor infrastructure mean that most visitors are cut from fairly intrepid cloth. But travelling this enigmatic and underexplored country is well worth the occasional bump in the road, both literal and metaphorical.</p>
<p>First and foremost amongst the country&rsquo;s many attractions is its pristine Indian Ocean coastline &ndash; all 2,414km (1,500 miles) of it &ndash; which offers palm-fringed beaches, warm tropical waters, abundant marine life, great fishing, excellent diving, fantastic snorkeling and a number of idyllic islands from which you can enjoy all of the above in sweet isolation.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
