<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Myanmar" ColCode="mmr" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="mm" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Myanmar]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Myanmar has a monsoon climate with three main seasons. The hottest period is between February and May, when there is little or no rain and temperatures can rise above 40&deg;C (104&deg;F). The rainy season is generally from May to October, giving way to dry, cooler weather from October to February. The coast and the mountains see significantly more rainfall than the arid central plains, which include Mandalay and Bagan, and roads can become impassable during the rainy season in those areas. <br />
<br />
Overall, the best months to visit are from November to February. The only notable downside (other than the fact that places are busy with other tourists) is that river travel can be slow as water levels are low, meaning that boats have to travel more slowly; this is particularly notable on long journeys as ferries cannot travel overnight for fear of being grounded on sandbanks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are recommended throughout most of the year. A light raincoat or umbrella is needed during the rainy season. Warmer clothes are advised for cooler season and some evenings, particularly in hilly areas, on ferries or for trips on Inle Lake. It's also a good idea to wrap up when travelling on buses, as the drivers tend to overuse the air-conditioning.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air travel is an efficient and relatively cheap way to get around Myanmar, and is particularly appealing given that bus and train journeys between major tourist sites tend to be long and often uncomfortable. Myanmar National Airlines (<a href="http://www.flymna.com" target="_blank">www.flymna.com</a>) covers all major domestic routes including some out-of-the-way places.</p>
<p>Private airlines include Air Mandalay (<a href="http://www.airmandalay.com/">www.airmandalay.com</a>), Yangon Airways (<a href="http://www.yangonair.com/">www.yangonair.com</a>), Air KBZ (<a href="http://www.airkbz.com" target="_blank">www.airkbz.com</a>), Asian Wings Airways (<a href="http://www.asianwingsair.com">www.asianwingsair.com</a>), Golden Myanmar Airlines (<a href="http://www.gmairlines.com/">www.gmairlines.com</a>) and Air Bagan (<a href="http://www.airbagan.com">www.airbagan.com</a>). These cover all the main tourist destinations, including Heho (for Inle Lake) and Nyaung U (for Bagan).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/myanmar/yangon-international-airport">Yangon International Airport </a>.</p><p>Many of the airlines operating in Myanmar had strong links to the military junta, and some of the owners have been subject to international economic sanctions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Myanmar has about 8,000km (5,000 miles) of navigable rivers, and one of the best ways to see the country is by boat. The most popular route is Mandalay-Bagan, as tourist boats run it regularly, but on other routes (such as Bhamo-Mandalay) visitors instead travel with locals. There are also a few upmarket river cruise boats on the Irrawaddy River.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The state-run railway serves most of Myanmar, with the principal line being Yangon to Mandalay (journey time - 16 hours). The two main classes are ordinary and upper (with reclining chairs), although some trains have first class (between the two) and oversubscribed sleeper carriages. Services are regularly afflicted with delays caused by climatic, technical and bureaucratic difficulties. In addition, visitors should be aware that much railway equipment is decrepit and journeys are often uncomfortable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With trains slow and unreliable, road travel is the best way to get around if you are on a budget. It is worth noting, however, that many routes are off-limits to foreigners &ndash; usually when they run through sensitive border areas or regions where the government is in conflict with ethnic minority militias.</p>r<p>Many roads are poorly maintained and can become impassable in the rainy season, from May to October.</p><p>Long-distance buses are usually cheaper and faster than trains running the same route. Most buses run overnight, typically arriving at an inconvenient pre-dawn hour.</p><p>Taxis are easily available in Yangon, Mandalay and a few other large cities and popular tourist destinations. In Yangon, there are blue government taxis with set fares. Taxi drivers do not expect a tip and it is wise to pre-arrange fares. Elsewhere, motorbike taxis (where passengers ride pillion) are more common, alongside pick-ups (small pick-up trucks with seating in the back, running set routes) and cycle rickshaws (which have a sidecar).</p><p>Foreign licences are not accepted, but an International Driving Licence can be exchanged for a local driving licence at the Department for Road Transport and Administration in Yangon.</p><p>There is no legal requirement to use seat belts, and they may not be provided. Motorcycles have been completely banned from the streets of central Yangon. There are also some places, such as Bagan, where foreigners are not allowed to hire motorbikes. Visitors must remember that, under Burmese law, the driver of a car involved in an accident with a pedestrian is always at fault.</p><p>There is no national breakdown service.</p><p>The amount of bureaucracy involved means that foreigners rarely hire self-drive cars: you&rsquo;d need a special permit and to have a local with you in the car at all times. It&rsquo;s easy enough, however, to hire a car and driver for a day or more.</p><p>It&rsquo;s possible to hire bicycles in most towns visited by tourists, usually from accommodation or travel agents, although in some places (Bagan and Nyaungshwe for example) there are several separate rental outlets. The bikes are usually quite basic and/or old, and are generally used for day trips and short rides around town rather than for multi-day rides.</p><p>There is no legal requirement to use seat belts, and they may not be provided. Motorcycles have been completely banned from the streets of central Yangon. There are also some places, such as Bagan, where foreigners are not allowed to hire motorbikes. Visitors must remember that, under Burmese law, the driver of a car involved in an accident with a pedestrian is always at fault.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Yangon has a circular rail service for commuters, which is a great way to see daily suburban life. There are also antiquated and overcrowded bus services in some cities; more common are pick-ups, small trucks with seating at the back which cover fixed routes. Unmetered taxis, usually cars or motorbikes, are available in cities, as are cycle rickshaws; it is wise to pre-arrange fares.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is MAI - Myanmar Airways International (<a href="http://www.maiair.com" target="_blank">www.maiair.com</a>). Usually the cheapest way to get to Myanmar is either via a Middle Eastern airport, for example with Qatar Airways (<a href="http://www.qatarairways.com" target="_blank">www.qatarairways.com</a>), or via a regional hub such as <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangkok">Bangkok</a>.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/myanmar/yangon-international-airport">Yangon International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 15 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 24 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Low-cost carrier Air Asia (<a href="http://www.airasia.com" target="_blank">www.airasia.com</a>) serves both Yangon and Mandalay. This makes possible a cheap open-jaw route flying into Yangon and out of Mandalay, saving on travel time within Myanmar if you plan to visit both the south and the north of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the airfare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Low-cost carrier Air Asia (<a href="http://www.airasia.com" target="_blank">www.airasia.com</a>) serves both Yangon and Mandalay. This makes possible a cheap open-jaw route flying into Yangon and out of Mandalay, saving on travel time within Myanmar if you plan to visit both the south and the north of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Yangon International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://yangonairport.aero<p>The airport is located approximately 15km (9 miles) north of central Yangon.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+95 1 533 428</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main port, as far as passenger services is concerned, is Yangon. From here it is possible to take smaller boats up rivers including the Irrawaddy (the country&rsquo;s main artery) and the Chindwin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no international passenger rail routes into Myanmar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Entering Myanmar overland is far from straightforward and not recommended. The borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/laos">Laos</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangladesh">Bangladesh</a> are completely closed to foreigners, while the crossing between Moreh (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>) and Tamu (Myanmar) requires a permit which can take several months to arrange. The border crossing from Ruili (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>) to Muse (Myanmar) has long been closed to all but organised tour groups, who receive special permits.</p>
<p>That leaves the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/thailand">Thai</a> border crossings as the only realistic options for most travellers. It is possible to cross at four points but only three are accessible with a Tourist Visa for onward travel: Ranong/Kawthaung, Mae Sot/Myawaddy and Mae Sai/Tachiliek. Rules and regulations change frequently so it&rsquo;s best to check border access with the authorities in advance. In general, therefore it is much better to fly into the country rather than to enter overland.</p><p>Rules on border crossings are particularly subject to change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International calls are best made using a VOIP service such as Skype at an internet caf&eacute;, although that is dependent on getting a usable connection. Otherwise, it&rsquo;s possible to make international calls from some hotels (at inflated prices), at public call offices (try asking in post offices) or at the small private call centres found either in the street or in shop. These often just consist of a telephone on a counter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International roaming is only just being developed in Myanmar, and only works with a limited range of providers so it should not be relied upon. Visitors can either hire a standard local SIM card from the airport, or buy a special SIM card which lasts for a month and cannot be topped up even during that time. The latter costs around $24 and comes with $20 in credit. It&rsquo;s theoretically possible, if expensive, to make international calls using these SIM cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet censorship is now much reduced and there are internet cafes in most towns; many hotels and guesthouses, particularly at mid-range and above, offer Wi-Fi. Wherever you connect, however, the service tends to be slow and unreliable. It is possible to access all major webmail services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government has reduced the degree of media censorship compared to the days of the military junta, when radio, television and newspapers were all merely government mouthpieces. Nevertheless, most media organisations are still either completely or partly owned by the state, and the regular Reporters Without Borders report on press freedom still ranks Myanmar within the bottom few countries in the world.</p>
<p>All broadcast media stations are state-run, and local people have long turned to foreign radio stations for more accurate news about their own country. This includes the Democratic Voice of Burma (DVB). The station's video journalists (VJs) are known for their bravery when filming in the country &ndash; something which can be witnessed in the award-winning documentary <em>Burma VJ</em>.</p>
<p>For decades, daily newspapers have been state-controlled and heavy with propaganda, including the English-language <em>New Light of Myanmar </em>and <em>Myanmar Times</em>. In 2013 the government started providing licences for private companies to publish daily newspapers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Service to Europe is unreliable and can take a very long time. To ensure despatch, it is advisable to go to the post office personally. Important letters and parcels can be sent through EMS (Express Mail Service) for which there are counters at major post offices.</p><p>Typically, Mon-Fri 0930-1630, sometimes Saturday mornings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be bowled over by Bagan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Covering an area of 67sq km (26sq miles), the astonishing archaeological site of the ancient city of Bagan is dotted with the remains of some 2,000 temples, pagodas and stupas, mostly dating from the 11th century. The most atmospheric way to explore is by hot-air balloon, but you can also roam the site by bicycle, on foot or by horse and cart.</p>]]><p><b>Catch a puppet show</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mandalay preserves many of Myanmar's ancient arts, including traditional dance and Burmese marionette theatre, with stunningly colourful wooden puppets. Also keep an eye out for <em>anyeint </em>(comedy) in Mandalay; the most famous comedians in the country are the Moustache Brothers, who were repeatedly arrested for satirising the government at the height of the regime's power.</p>]]><p><b>Climb into the hills of Shan State</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The parts of Shan State open to foreigners provide some of the country&rsquo;s best hiking opportunities and, unusually for Myanmar, offer the chance to stay in local homes or monasteries. Walk through stunning valleys to remote ethnic minority villages close to the northern town of Hsipaw, or take the three-day trek between Kalaw and Inle Lake.&nbsp;Please check the security situation before you travel.</p>]]><p><b>Count the Buddhas at Pindaya caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The journey to the town of Pindaya from either Kalaw or Nyaungshwe passes through some of the lushest farmland in Myanmar, but the main attraction here is below the ground. The Shwe Oo Min caves are packed with thousands of Buddha images, installed here over three centuries.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise the Irrawaddy River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It's hard to overstate the importance of the Irrawaddy River, which winds its way along pretty much the entire length of the country. A trip on the river offers a fascinating back window onto rural life in Myanmar, with rustic local ferries and long-distance tourist boats that cruise the river between Mandalay and Bagan.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy the slow pace of life in Hpa-an</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Snoozing beside the Thanlwin River, the small town of Hpa-an, in the southeast of the country, is the leaping off point for visits to Buddhist monasteries and karst mountains topped by sacred pagodas. It's a tough climb to the summit of Mt Zwegabin, but the views from the top are stupendous.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Mandalay’s lost cities</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The hills around Mandalay are studded with the remains of former royal capitals. Sublime Sagaing is a jumble of hillside pagodas, while the highlight at Inwa is a famous 19th century teak monastery. Teak was also used to build the stunningly photogenic U Bein Bridge in Amarapura. Alternatively take a river trip to Mingun to see the world's largest intact hung bell.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the mystery of Mandalay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Founded in 1857, the former royal city of Mandalay isn't as old as you might have thought, but the old town inside the city walls is rich in palaces, stupas, temples and pagodas. Take a walk up Mandalay Hill at sunset and help young monks to practice their English, or marvel at the gold-leaf-encrusted Buddha image inside Mahumuni Pagoda.</p>]]><p><b>Gaze at golden Yangon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Yangon (formerly Rangoon) is a captivating collection of temples, markets, food stalls and fading colonial architecture. Highlights include the golden Shwedagon Pagoda, one of the most spectacular Buddhist monuments in the world, the gem and handicraft stalls of Bogyoke Aung San Market, and the fascinating colonial district around Sule Paya.</p>]]><p><b>Join the crowds at a Burmese festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Myanmar has an extensive calendar of Buddhist festivals, many timed to coincide with the full moon. Most feature music and dance, colourful processions and festival food. Highlights include the Amanda Pagoda Festival in January/February, the Pindaya Cave Festival in March, Maha Thingyan (New Year) in March and the Thihoshin Pagoda Festival, Pakkoku, in June/July.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Hsipaw</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The sleepy town of Hsipaw, northeast of Mandalay, is Myanmar's most popular backpacker hangout, but things here are very low-key. Trains rumble here from the British-era hill station of Pwin Oo Lwin, and the town has a lively market, golden pagodas and hikes to waterfalls, hot springs and ancient ruins in the surrounding hills.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Mrauk U</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The collection of temples in the former capital of Rakhine &ndash; once a powerful independent empire with territory stretching as far west as Bangladesh &ndash; are as mesmerising as the temples of Bagan, and still form the centre of a thriving community. This area has seen violence against Rohingya Muslims; check the security situation before you travel.</p>]]><p><b>Meditate with monks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Yangon's Mahasi Sasana Yeik Tha Meditation Centre is a famous destination for travellers seeking to learn more about Theravada Buddhism. Those able to commit to at least six weeks (requiring a special visa) can learn the rituals and philosophy of Burmese Buddhism and participate fully in the daily routines of monastery life.</p>]]><p><b>Ponder the physics of the balancing boulder</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The temple town of Kyaiktiyo is famed across Asia for its balancing boulder, which forms the centrepiece of the Kyaiktiyo Pagoda. Pilgrims trek or ride packed trucks to the pagoda to gaze at the tiny stupa crowning a boulder which climbs precariously to the edge of rocky outcrop, held in place, locals believe, by the power of prayer.</p>]]><p><b>Roam through Myanmar’s national parks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Myanmar offers rich opportunities for ecotourism, with national parks teeming with wildlife, including elephants, tigers, leopards and bears. The best parks include the Alaungdaw Kathapa National Park (northwest of Monywa); Hlawga National Park (near Yangon); Popa Mountain Park (central Myanmar); Lampi Island (Myeik Archipelago); and Shwesettaw Wildlife Sanctuary (located in Minbu).</p>]]><p><b>Row out onto Inle Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Beautiful Inle Lake was one of the first places in Myanmar to be opened to tourism, and it still ranks high on the list of must-sees. As well as floating villages, floating plantations and floating markets, the lake is famous for its leg-rowers and its ancient stupas. The most popular place to stay is Nyaungshwe on the lakeshore.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll the sand Ngapali Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Idyllic Ngapali in the far west of Myanmar is the most famous stretch of sand in the country, but it's hard to get here from Yangon other than by flying. Closer to the capital, Chaung Tha near Pathein is a popular escape for locals, while Ngwe Saung has a growing collection of upmarket beach resorts.</p>]]><p><b>Tour the temples of Bago</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the easiest trips from Yangon, Bago has its own collection of Buddhist buildings and monuments, including the impressive golden Shwemawdaw Pagoda – technically, the tallest stupa in the country – as well as the Shwethalyaung Buddha, which is considered one of the most beautiful reclining Buddhas in Asia.</p>]]><p><b>Trek to hill tribe villages from Keng Tung</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hidden away in the dense jungles of Shan stage, Keng Tung is where Burmese culture melts into the tribal traditions of northern Thailand. This peaceful town is dotted with Thai-style pagodas, and local guides offer trips into the hills to visit the fascinating villages of Lisu, Lahu-Si and Akha people.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around Shwedagon Pagoda</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rising above the rooftops of Yangon like a golden candlestick, the mighty Shwedagon Pagoda is one of the wonders of the Buddhist world. The stupa rises 112m (367ft) into the air, covered in sheets of real gold and crowned with a symbolic umbrella coated in thousands of carats of diamonds and rubies. Joining the crowds that circle the sacred stupa is one of Myanmar's most sublime experiences.</p>]]><p><b>Watch traditional sports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Myanmar's national game, <em>chinlone</em>, is played with a woven cane ball. Teams of six players aim to keep the ball in the air for as long as possible, using any part of the body except the hands. Look out for impromptu matches in public places. Another sport to watch for its Burmese boxing, the local version of <em>muay thai</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$67.40 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Natural gas, wood products, agricultural products and marine products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fabric, petroleum products, fertiliser, plastics and machinery.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Thailand, China (PR),India, Singapore and Japan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While rich in natural resources, Myanmar's development has been hindered by its politics. Decades of cronyism and corruption mean that a small elite has become exceptionally wealthy at the expense of the vast majority, with many people living in extreme poverty. The largest single sector is traditional agriculture, mainly livestock and fishing. Teak wood is the country's other main export, much of it felled and traded illegally.<br />
<br />
Myanmar has significant deposits of tin, copper, zinc, gemstones, silver, oil and coal: commercial exploitation provides some income, with several mining projects, some of them very controversial, being carried out in association with Chinese companies. Further significant sources of revenue include opium trafficking and gemstone mining, both of which were largely controlled by the military government and used to finance substantial arms purchases (required since the authorities have been engaged in civil war against various ethnic minority groups since independence). Although the government inaugurated in 2016 is nominally civilian, many of the same people are still in charge and the same cronies continue to enrich themselves.<br />
<br />
There are few reliable economic statistics for Myanmar; the government has long reported growth as significantly higher than international estimates and understated the black market. After years of political isolation, however, Myanmar became a member of ASEAN in July 1997. Economic change accelerated in June 2012 when, in response to political reforms and the release of many political prisoners, the EU and US dropped many of their sanctions against trade with Myanmar.</p>
<p>The result is that many potential investors, who until recently may have been deterred by the government's appalling human rights record, are now looking to make a profit in Myanmar. In the meantime the army continues to deal brutally with ethnic minorities in the north of the country, and it remains to be seen whether the recent political reforms after the 2015 democratic elections are fleeting or deeply rooted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>People in Myanmar tend to dress conservatively and lightweight suits are recommended during the day. Locals may wear a <em>longyi</em>, a traditional skirt-like garment (they are worn by men and women, with different types of pattern).</p>
<p>Most commercial business transactions will be conducted in English. Business cards in Burmese script can be useful, and should be given and received with two hands.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b/><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Burmese cuisine treads a line somewhere between Indian and Southeast Asian cooking, but is subtly different to both. Dishes feature abundant spices, but tend to include less chilli than in Thailand or India, with an emphasis on sour, bitter and salty flavours.</p>
<p>Many dishes in Myanmar are topped with a layer of oil to keep off bugs, but not all dishes are as oily as people expect. Noodle soups and salads are very popular, and the local tofu &ndash; made from yellow split peas &ndash; is delicious.</p>
<p>Preserved vegetables crop up prominently in Burmese cooking, including pickled bamboo shoots and pickled tea leaves &ndash; a local delicacy. Marking the shift from Indian subcontinent to Southeast Asia, many dishes feature fish sauce or <em>ngapi</em>, a fermented paste of ground shrimp. Chinese food and Indian food is also popular, particularly <em>biryani</em>, Indian spiced fried rice.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong><span style="color: black;">Lethok son:</span></strong><span style="color: black;"> Spicy vegetarian rice salad.<br />
</span><strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1">Mohinga:</span></strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1"> Burmese fish soup with noodles, the national dish.<br />
<o:p></o:p></span><strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1">Oh-no khauk swe:</span></strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1"> A soup of rice noodles, chicken and coconut milk.<br />
<o:p></o:p></span><strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1">Shan khauk swe:</span></strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1"> A dish predominately eaten by the Shan, but popular around the country, it consists of rice noodles either in broth or dry, usually with chicken.<br />
<o:p></o:p></span><strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1">Athoke:</span></strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1"> Various &lsquo;salads&rsquo; served cold, made from noodles, ginger, tofu, chicken and other ingredients.<br />
<o:p></o:p></span><strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1">Biryani:</span></strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1"> Indian-style fried rice with spices and chicken. <br />
<o:p></o:p></span><strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1">Burmese curry:</span></strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1"> Most meals feature some kind of curry dish, usually quite mildly spiced and oily, and traditionally accompanied by a selection of side dishes like <i>ngapi </i>(fish paste) as well as rice and soup.<br />
<o:p></o:p></span><strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1">Lahpet:</span></strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1"> A tasty dish of fermented tealeaves, usually eaten as dessert and considered to be a key part of Myanmar&rsquo;s culinary heritage.<br />
<o:p></o:p></span><strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1">Htanyet:</span></strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1"> Jaggery, unrefined palm sugar, eaten at the end of a meal.<br />
<o:p></o:p></span><strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1;mso-bidi-font-style:
italic">Peh-hin-ye:</span></strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1;mso-bidi-font-style:
italic"> Indian-style dhal (lentil) soup.<br />
</span><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1"><o:p></o:p></span><strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1">Htamin:</span></strong><span style="color:black;mso-themecolor:text1"> Rice, the foundation of any Burmese meal.Green tea: Provided free in many restaurants.<br />
<strong>Black tea:</strong> Drunk with milk and sugar in teahouses, which are important social hubs. <br />
<strong>Alcohol:</strong> Locally produced beer, rum, whisky and gin are generally available.<br />
<strong>Coffee:</strong> Usually sold in instant form except for in a few Western-style cafes.</span></p>
<!--[if gte mso 9]><xml>
<o:DocumentProperties>
<o:Revision>0</o:revision>
<o:TotalTime>0</o:totaltime>
<o:Pages>1</o:pages>
<o:Words>148</o:words>
<o:Characters>849</o:characters>
<o:Company>Columbus Travel Media Ltd</o:company>
<o:Lines>7</o:lines>
<o:Paragraphs>1</o:paragraphs>
<o:CharactersWithSpaces>996</o:characterswithspaces>
<o:Version>14.0</o:version>
</o:documentproperties>
</xml><![endif]-->  <!--[if gte mso 9]><xml>
<w:WordDocument>
<w:View>Normal</w:view>
<w:Zoom>0</w:zoom>
<w:TrackMoves />
<w:TrackFormatting />
<w:PunctuationKerning />
<w:ValidateAgainstSchemas />
<w:SaveIfXMLInvalid>false</w:saveifxmlinvalid>
<w:IgnoreMixedContent>false</w:ignoremixedcontent>
<w:AlwaysShowPlaceholderText>false</w:alwaysshowplaceholdertext>
<w:DoNotPromoteQF />
<w:LidThemeOther>EN-GB</w:lidthemeother>
<w:LidThemeAsian>JA</w:lidthemeasian>
<w:LidThemeComplexScript>X-NONE</w:lidthemecomplexscript>
<w:Compatibility>
<w:BreakWrappedTables />
<w:SnapToGridInCell />
<w:WrapTextWithPunct />
<w:UseAsianBreakRules />
<w:DontGrowAutofit />
<w:SplitPgBreakAndParaMark />
<w:EnableOpenTypeKerning />
<w:DontFlipMirrorIndents />
<w:OverrideTableStyleHps />
<w:UseFELayout />
</w:usefelayout></w:overridetablestylehps></w:dontflipmirrorindents></w:enableopentypekerning></w:splitpgbreakandparamark></w:dontgrowautofit></w:useasianbreakrules></w:wraptextwithpunct></w:snaptogridincell></w:breakwrappedtables></w:compatibility>
<m:mathPr>
<m:mathFont m:val="Cambria Math" />
<m:brkBin m:val="before" />
<m:brkBinSub m:val="&#45;-" />
<m:smallFrac m:val="off" />
<m:dispDef />
<m:lMargin m:val="0" />
<m:rMargin m:val="0" />
<m:defJc m:val="centerGroup" />
<m:wrapIndent m:val="1440" />
<m:intLim m:val="subSup" />
<m:naryLim m:val="undOvr" />
</m:narylim></m:intlim></m:wrapindent></m:defjc></m:rmargin></m:lmargin></m:dispdef></m:smallfrac></m:brkbinsub></m:brkbin></m:mathfont></m:mathpr></w:donotpromoteqf></w:validateagainstschemas></w:punctuationkerning></w:trackformatting></w:trackmoves></w:worddocument>
</xml><![endif]--><!--[if gte mso 9]><xml>
<w:LatentStyles DefLockedState="false" DefUnhideWhenUsed="true"
DefSemiHidden="true" DefQFormat="false" DefPriority="99"
LatentStyleCount="276">
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="0" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Normal" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="heading 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 7" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 8" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 9" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 7" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 8" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 9" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="35" QFormat="true" Name="caption" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="10" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Title" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="1" Name="Default Paragraph Font" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="11" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Subtitle" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="22" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Strong" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="20" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Emphasis" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="59" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Table Grid" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Placeholder Text" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="1" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="No Spacing" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1 Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2 Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1 Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Revision" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="34" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="List Paragraph" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="29" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Quote" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="30" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Intense Quote" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2 Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1 Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2 Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3 Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid Accent 1" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1 Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2 Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1 Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2 Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1 Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2 Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3 Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid Accent 2" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1 Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2 Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1 Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2 Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1 Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2 Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3 Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid Accent 3" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1 Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2 Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1 Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2 Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1 Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2 Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3 Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid Accent 4" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1 Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2 Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1 Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2 Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1 Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2 Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3 Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid Accent 5" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1 Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2 Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1 Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2 Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1 Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2 Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3 Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid Accent 6" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="19" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Subtle Emphasis" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="21" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Intense Emphasis" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="31" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Subtle Reference" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="32" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Intense Reference" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="33" SemiHidden="false"
UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Book Title" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="37" Name="Bibliography" />
<w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" QFormat="true" Name="TOC Heading" />
</w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:lsdexception></w:latentstyles>
</xml><![endif]-->  <!--[if gte mso 10]>
<style>
/* Style Definitions */
table.MsoNormalTable
{mso-style-name:"Table Normal";
mso-tstyle-rowband-size:0;
mso-tstyle-colband-size:0;
mso-style-noshow:yes;
mso-style-priority:99;
mso-style-parent:"";
mso-padding-alt:0cm 5.4pt 0cm 5.4pt;
mso-para-margin:0cm;
mso-para-margin-bottom:.0001pt;
mso-pagination:widow-orphan;
font-size:12.0pt;
font-family:Cambria;
mso-ascii-font-family:Cambria;
mso-ascii-theme-font:minor-latin;
mso-hansi-font-family:Cambria;
mso-hansi-theme-font:minor-latin;
mso-fareast-language:JA;}
</style>
<![endif]-->    <!--StartFragment-->                        <!--EndFragment-->]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Many towns have night food markets where it's possible to fill up cheaply between around 1700-2100. Restaurants rarely stay open much later than 2200.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It is not traditional to tip in restaurants or elsewhere.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Western-style nightlife is almost non-existent outside of Yangon, where there are a few bars and nightclubs (many of them connected to high-end hotels) catering primarily to expats and wealthy locals. Much more common throughout the country are beer stations, essentially restaurants which place more of an emphasis on drinking than on food. These usually have at least one beer on draught, which is cheaper than buying bottles, and serve barbeque or Chinese dishes, or sometimes both. Beer stations tend to have a predominantly male clientele, and sometimes have entertainment such as &lsquo;fashion shows&rsquo; or karaoke.</p>
<p>Cultural events are quite rare, although local rock and pop groups (particularly the ubiquitous Iron Cross) are popular. Yangon is the best bet for tracking down this kind of entertainment. Mandalay has a handful of nightly cultural shows aimed at tourists, covering traditional dancing, marionettes and a mix of slapstick and political satire called <em>a-nyeint</em>. The main English-language proponents of <em>a</em>-<em>nyeint</em> are the Moustache Brothers, two of whom have served significant jail time for mocking the military junta and don&rsquo;t go easy on the current government either. There are many cinemas in Yangon and Mandalay, some of which show English-language films. In other towns and cities there may be a cinema or two.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Myanmar&rsquo;s cities are not shopping destinations on a par with regional favourites such as Bangkok or Singapore, but there are still some bargains to be found. Souvenirs include jewellery &ndash; some of the most interesting being made from petrified wood or from jade &ndash; plus art and handicrafts such as marionettes, Buddha figurines and tapestries. Lacquerware is available throughout the country, with the Bagan style particularly popular with tourists, although quality and prices vary significantly. The plainer styles of Shan state are also worth seeking out. The western town of Pathein is known for its handmade parasols, which are sold throughout Myanmar.</p>
<p>A good place to shop in Yangon is Bogyoke Aung San Market, open Tues-Sun 1030-1700, which sells luxury items, handicrafts, foodstuffs, clothing, jewellery and consumer goods. Yangon also has several large shopping centres, including the modern Junction Mall which has facilities such as a cinema and a rooftop swimming pool. Due to sanctions, major international brands have largely been absent from Myanmar although this may change as the country opens up.</p>
<p>Mandalay is known as the cultural capital of the country and is therefore a good place for traditional handicrafts. One unusual gift from Mandalay is the gold leaf which is applied to Buddha images at pagodas, which you can see being pounded on 36<sup>th</sup> Street. There&rsquo;s also a large jade market in Mandalay, although you really need to know what you&rsquo;re looking at if you want to bag a bargain. The glitziest shopping centre in Mandalay is Diamond Plaza, which has a large supermarket in the basement.</p>
<p>Outside of these two cities the options are significantly more limited. Artists in Bagan sell their work direct to tourists or through touts, however, and boat trips on Inle Lake usually include visits to workshops making things like cheroots (basic hand-rolled cigars) or silver jewellery.</p><p>Mon-Sun 0930-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign visitors are only allowed to stay in officially licensed accommodation in Myanmar, which means that in some towns there are only one or two options available. Advance booking is advisable, particularly from November to March, as tourist numbers have swollen in recent years and the stock of accommodation has not yet caught up. In some key tourist destinations, particularly Nyaungshwe (for Inle Lake), Nyaung U (for Bagan), Mandalay or Bagan, it is not unusual for budget accommodation to be completely full on a given date. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> The Ministry of Hotels and Tourism (<a href="http://tourism.gov.mm/en_US/hotels-resorts/">http://tourism.gov.mm/en_US/hotels-resorts/</a>) grades hotels on a scale of one to five stars, with establishments displaying their grade on a plaque at reception.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like hotels, guest houses must be licensed. It&rsquo;s a time-consuming and expensive process, which is one reason why few new guest houses have opened in Myanmar despite soaring tourist numbers. Many of the existing guest houses in places such as Nyaungshwe have, however, been building new blocks to increase the number of rooms which they offer. Guest houses typically offer a range of accommodation, with or without private bathroom and with or without air-conditioning. Single occupancy is sometimes charged at only half the double room rate, but more often at around three-quarters.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign visitors are only allowed to stay in officially licensed accommodation in Myanmar, which means that in some towns there are only one or two options available. Advance booking is advisable, particularly from November to March, as tourist numbers have swollen in recent years and the stock of accommodation has not yet caught up. In some key tourist destinations, particularly Nyaungshwe (for Inle Lake), Nyaung U (for Bagan), Mandalay or Bagan, it is not unusual for budget accommodation to be completely full on a given date. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> The Ministry of Hotels and Tourism (<a href="http://tourism.gov.mm/en_US/hotels-resorts/">http://tourism.gov.mm/en_US/hotels-resorts/</a>) grades hotels on a scale of one to five stars, with establishments displaying their grade on a plaque at reception.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign visitors are only allowed to stay in officially licensed accommodation in Myanmar, which means that in some towns there are only one or two options available. Advance booking is advisable, particularly from November to March, as tourist numbers have swollen in recent years and the stock of accommodation has not yet caught up. In some key tourist destinations, particularly Nyaungshwe (for Inle Lake), Nyaung U (for Bagan), Mandalay or Bagan, it is not unusual for budget accommodation to be completely full on a given date. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> The Ministry of Hotels and Tourism (<a href="http://tourism.gov.mm/en_US/hotels-resorts/">http://tourism.gov.mm/en_US/hotels-resorts/</a>) grades hotels on a scale of one to five stars, with establishments displaying their grade on a plaque at reception.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are hospitals and clinics in cities and larger towns, and regional health centres in outlying areas, although the quality of healthcare is generally low in Myanmar. Many hospitals lack basic equipment and medication, a situation not helped by high levels of corruption, and international-standard facilities are both scarce and expensive. Health insurance covering medical evacuation is strongly recommended. It is advisable to carry a remedy against minor stomach upsets and other basic illnesses. Pharmacists sell most medicines without prescription.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled. Some travellers avoid Burmese food for their evening meal, as the curries are cooked in the morning then left in pots throughout the day. Chinese dishes, on the other hand, are usually cooked to order.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against Japanese B encephalitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Malaria is considered to be a risk throughout the country except for in Yangon or Mandalay. Consult a doctor or travel clinic for advice on whether malaria prophylaxis is required; in any case, take precautions to avoid mosquito bites. This is also important as a way to avoid dengue fever, a serious disease which is also carried by mosquitos.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Buddhist festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Independence Day :
							2018<br/>04 January </p><p>Union Day :
							12 February </p><p>Peasants' Day :
							02 March </p><p>Armed Forces Day :
							27 March </p><p>Maha Thingyan (Water Festival) :
							13 April </p><p>Myanmar New Year :
							17 April </p><p>May Day :
							01 May </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							19 July </p><p>National Day :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be taken into Myanmar without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes, 50 cigars or  250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; 150ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of US$500.</p>
<p>Officially, you must declare valuable jewellery; failure to do so may result in you being refused permission to export it on departure.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Counterfeit currencies and goods, pornography, narcotic drugs and psychotropic substances, playing cards, and goods bearing the image of the national flag, the emblem of Buddha or the pagodas of Myanmar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arms and ammunitions, pornography, antiques, endangered species, narcotic drugs and psychotropic substances.</p>
<p>You can export gems, jewellery and silverware purchased from authorised shops, but you should obtain paperwork for anything of significant age or value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kyat (MMK; symbol K) = 100 pyas. Notes are in denominations of K10,000, 5,000, K1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1. Notes below K50 are very uncommon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The local currency is used by tourists to pay for everyday expenses such as restaurant meals, bus travel, taxis and shopping. Piror to 2014, other expenses, such train tickets and museum entry fees, had to be paid for in US dollars, but this system has been scrapped. In some situations, notably paying for hotel rooms, prices are quoted in dollars although kyat are accepted at a poor exchange rate. <br />
<br />
It is essential to ensure that any US dollars brought for use in the country &ndash; whether to be exchanged or spent &ndash; are recent issues and absolutely pristine: any tears, folds or marks may lead to a note being rejected. High-value dollar notes usually receive the best exchange rate, but it&rsquo;s also useful to have lower denominations to spend as hotels etc. may not have change. Euros are also exchanged at banks, and may be accepted at government-run museums, but are less useful when paying for hotel rooms or other expenses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards can be used only in a handful of top-end hotels in Yangon and Mandalay, although this situation is changing quickly as sanctions are eased and international companies seek to do business in Myanmar. There are ATMs throughout Yangon, Mandalay, Bagan, Taungoo and Pyinmana accepting Visa, MasterCard, Maestro and Cirrus-branded cards. Two of these are situated in Yangon International airport. In rural areas, it is unlikely that credit or debit cards will be accepted; it is best to check with your card company prior to travel.</p><p>Until late 2012 there were few ATMs in Myanmar and it was impossible for foreigners to use them. This is changing and there are now ATMs accepting foreign MasterCard and Visa cards in Yangon, Mandalay and a few other locations.  Only kyat can be withdrawn, however, which means that it is still reccomended for visitors to bring dollars as emergency cash to pay for trains, planes, museum entry and (for the best rates) hotels. It is generally unwise to rely entirely on ATMs since if your card does not work then you may be unable to obtain money in any other way. It is also recommended to carry small change as large notes may be difficult to change. Euros are now also accepted in banks, but exchange can be time consuming.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not currently accepted, although this may change. Check with your tour agency prior to travel, and bring plenty of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars in cash.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 1000-1400, and sometimes Saturday mornings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Myanmar, a passport valid for at least six months beyond the date of intended departure is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A visa on arrival, costing US$20 and valid for 24 hours, is theoretically available for those in transit who have evidence of an onward flight. The service is periodically withdrawn however, and airline staff may not allow you to fly into Myanmar without a visa in your passport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>eVisa: US$50; business eVisa: US$70.</p>
<p>Tourist visa in advance: &pound;14.</p>
<p>Single-entry business visa in advance: &pound;20; six-month multiple-entry business visa in advance: &pound;100; 12-month multiple-entry business visa in advance: &pound;200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>eVisa/tourist visa: 28 days within three months of issue; business eVisa/single-entry business visa: 10 weeks within three months of issue; multiple-entry business visa: 10 weeks within six or 12 months of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy) or, if eligible, online (<a href="http://evisa.moip.gov.mm">http://evisa.moip.gov.mm</a>). If you apply for an eVisa, you must print out the approval letter and bring it with you to show immigration officers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three to five working days for visa processing if applying to the embassy and three days if applying online.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are not required to demonstrate that they have sufficient funds to visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets must be accompanied by a health certificate and inspected at the airport&rsquo;s animal quarantine counter. For cats and dogs the health certificate must show that the animal has been vaccinated against rabies at least a month before arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[21.405972]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[96.108009]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>676,578 sq km (261,227 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>54,363,426 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>83.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nay Pyi Taw.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Myanmar is roughly diamond-shaped &ndash; with a long southeastern &lsquo;tail&rsquo; &ndash; and extends 925km (575 miles) from east to west and 2,100km (1,300 miles) from north to south. It is bounded by China, Laos and Thailand in the east, by Bangladesh and India in the north and by the Indian Ocean in the west and south. The Irrawaddy River runs through the centre of the country and fans out to form a delta on the south coast; Yangon stands beside one of its many mouths.</p>
<p>North of the delta lies the Irrawaddy basin and the arid plains of central Myanmar, which are protected by a horseshoe of mountains rising to over 3,000m (10,000ft). To the west are the Arakan mountains and the Chin, Naga and Patkai Hills; the Kachin Hills are to the north; to the east lies the Shan Plateau, which extends to the Tenasserim coastal ranges. The Kachin range includes Southeast Asia&rsquo;s highest mountain, Hkakabo  Razi which reaches 5,881m (19,295ft).</p>
<p>Intensive irrigated farming is practised throughout central Myanmar, and fruit, vegetables and citrus crops thrive on the Shan Plateau. Much of the land and mountains are covered by subtropical forest, although this coverage has been reduced by extensive logging particularly for teak.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>89% Theravada Buddhist. The remainder are Hindu, Muslim, Christian and animist. Many Buddhists also hold some animist beliefs, including worship of <em>nats</em> (spirits) which are rationalised as being disciples of the Buddha.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the normal form of greeting, but only with the right hand; the left hand is associated with using the toilet. Full names are used, preceded by U (pronounced <em>oo</em>) in the case of an older or well-respected man's name, <em>Aung</em> for younger men and <em>Ko</em> for adult males; a woman's name is preceded by <em>Daw</em>. There are no inherited family names.</p>
<p>Courtesy and respect for tradition and religion is expected; for instance, shoes and socks must be removed before entering any religious building and it is customary to remove shoes before entering a traditional home (in modern residences this may not be observed any longer except in bedrooms). When sitting, avoid pointing the soles of the feet towards people or in the direction of Buddha images as this is considered offensive. Dress should be modest, so both men and women should avoid shorts cut above the knee (a few local men wear shorts, but really long trousers are more appropriate if you can tolerate them in the heat). Mini-skirts and tight or revealing clothing should not be worn.</p>
<p>Penalties for drug-trafficking range from five years' imprisonment to a death sentence. Homosexuality is illegal, although Yangon does have a very discreet gay scene.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with two round pins (European-style), three round pins (South African-style) or three square pins (British-style) are used; some hotel sockets can accept multiple types.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Win Myint since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Win Myint since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Known as Burma under British colonial rule, a name still used by many foreign governments, Myanmar was populated through three waves of migration: by the Hmon people from what is now <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cambodia">Cambodia</a>; by Mongol people from the eastern Himalayas; and, finally, by Thai peoples from northern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/thailand">Thailand</a>. The first unified state was founded at Pagan (now Bagan) in 1057, but the capital was ravaged by Kublai Khan in 1287.</p>
<p>A succession of dynasties rose and fell along the Irrawaddy, before the British arrived, conquering the south of the country in 1852. After the fall of Mandalay in 1886, Burma became a province of British India, marking the start of a troubled colonial period.</p>
<p>During WWII, the Japanese expelled the British from Burma, but opposition to Japanese occupation grew rapidly. Burmese General Aung San led an uprising against occupying forces, and Burma gained its independence in 1948. He was assassinated the same year, allegedly by his closest political rival.</p>
<p>A military coup in 1962 ushered in the regime of General Ne Win, who imposed a totalitarian socialist dictatorship. In 1988, after years of bizarre policies and isolationism, a popular uprising by students and Buddhist monks was brutally suppressed, with thousands killed. Ne Win relinquished his official title, but continued to wield considerable influence in the new State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC).</p>
<p>Diverse resistance movements found a spokesperson in Western-educated Aung Sang Suu Kyi, daughter of Aung San, who won a convincing victory in the first Burmese election, held in 1990, as head of the National League for Democracy (NLD). The result was ignored by the junta and Suu Kyi began a 15-year period of house arrest and persecution.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s troubles continued with the 2007 Saffron Revolution, where protests over fuel prices were supressed, with the death and imprisonment of thousands. After general elections, which were boycotted by the NLD, Thein Sein was elected President of Myanmar, but real power continued to reside with the military.</p>
<p>Aung San Suu Kyi was released in 2010 and many sanctions against Myanmar were dropped in 2012, but a new wave of violence began with riots against the minority Muslim Rohingya people. New elections in November 2015 were won decisively by the NLD, with a transition to civilian government having taken place in January 2016.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know? </strong><br />
&bull;	Myanmar is one of only three countries to not adopt the metric system; the local measure of weight is the <em>peiktha</em>. <br />
&bull;	Burmese people wear yellow paste made from tree bark on their faces as a sunscreen.<br />
&bull;	While Myanmar is nominally Buddhist, locals also venerate animist spirits known as <em>nats</em>, who are believed to reside on Mount Popa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Myanmar]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+95 137 0865.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-rangoon</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+95 137 0865.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thu 0800-1630; Fri 0800-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>80 Strand Road<br/>Rangoon<br/>Box No 638<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Myanmar in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 332 3344.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mewashingtondc.org/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 332 3344.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1200 and 1300-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2300 S Street NW<br/>Washington DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Myanmar in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44  0207148 0740.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.londonmyanmarembassy.com/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44  0207148 0740.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 100-1200 and 1500-1600&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Berkeley Square<br/>19A Charles Street<br/>London<br/>W1J 5DX<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Once a pariah state, Myanmar &ndash; previously known as Burma &ndash; is fast becoming the must-see destination in Southeast Asia, helped by an incredible array of tourist sights: golden stupas as tall as skyscrapers, ancient ruins, fascinating hill tribes, unexplored jungles, peaceful beach resorts, legions of monks, and mesmerising cities made legendary by writers like Rudyard Kipling and George Orwell.</p>
<p>Ruled by a secretive military junta, Burma was closed for decades to the outside world. When it finally opened, travellers were initially restricted to a handful of locations: the magnificent temples of Bagan, the floating villages of Inle Lake, the monasteries of Mandalay, and Yangon, the former capital, with its colonial relics and towering pagodas.</p>
<p>That was then. With the end of the travel boycott called by Aung San Suu Kyi, travellers are queuing up to visit Myanmar, captivated by the idea of seeing what Asia was like before the tourists arrived. Nevertheless, the government still controls where visitors can go and what they can see, and many people have qualms that their tourist dollars help fund the military, which stands accused of widespread abuses.</p>
<p>Those who do visit discover a fascinating, and famously friendly culture on the threshold between tradition and modernity. Monasteries are the foundation of Burmese society and even in rapidly expanding Yangon life is focused on Buddhist rituals. The sense of devotion is tangible at the awe-inspiring Shwedagon Paya, which towers over Yangon like an enormous golden pillar.</p>
<p>As Myanmar has opened up to the outside world, travellers have pushed beyond the Bagan-Inle-Mandalay triangle, visiting peaceful outposts like Kalaw, Hsipaw and Kengtung and trekking to remote tribal villages. Smaller numbers make it to the jungles of northern Myanmar or the rain-drenched ports of the far south and west. Myanmar even has its own patch of the Himalaya, accessed from remote Putao in the far north.</p>
<p>Through it all, the mighty Irrawaddy River snakes like a twisting Burmese python, offering some of the most atmospheric river journeys in Southeast Asia. Nevertheless, Myanmar remains a controversial destination, promising significant challenges as well as rewarding experiences.</p><p>Once a pariah state, Myanmar &ndash; previously known as Burma &ndash; is fast becoming the must-see destination in Southeast Asia, helped by an incredible array of tourist sights: golden stupas as tall as skyscrapers, ancient ruins, fascinating hill tribes, unexplored jungles, peaceful beach resorts, legions of monks, and mesmerising cities made legendary by writers like Rudyard Kipling and George Orwell.</p>
<p>Ruled by a secretive military junta, Burma was closed for decades to the outside world. When it finally opened, travellers were initially restricted to a handful of locations: the magnificent temples of Bagan, the floating villages of Inle Lake, the monasteries of Mandalay, and Yangon, the former capital, with its colonial relics and towering pagodas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
