<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Namibia" ColCode="nam" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="na" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Namibia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With a staggering 300 days of sunshine each year, Namibia is a year-round destination, although some may prefer to avoid the heat of high summer. The cold Benguela current keeps the Atlantic coast of the Namib Desert cool and rain-free for most of the year, with a thick coastal fog that lends a mysterious edge to the area. January and February are the hottest months, when daytime temperatures in the heart of the Namib can exceed 40&ordm;C (104&ordm;F), but nights are usually cool. Winter nights can be fairly cold, but days are generally warm and pleasant.<br />
<br />
Inland, the rain falls exclusively in summer (November to March). The Caprivi Strip has a unique tropical climate, with heavy rainfall that often leads to flooding between December and March. The weeks following the March rains are ideal for birdwatching, but less good for spotting game, as the animals are more dispersed than in the dry season. The Fish River Canyon hiking route is closed from mid-September to mid-April due to the risk of floods. <br />
<br />
For travellers seeking a real wildlife experience, the winter months of April and June are the best time to visit, as the bush will be sparser and the dry weather will lead to frequent congregations at the waterhole.  </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pack light cottons, with slightly heavier cottons or light woollens for evening. Inland, shoes are essential during the day as the ground is very hot. For walking or trekking, ankle-height boots are recommended as there are poisonous snakes in the desert including the Cape Cobra. Neutral colours are recommended for safaris and game viewing. At Sossusvlei, a pair of sunglasses is crucial, as the reflection of the sunlight on the dunes and Dead Vlei is near-blinding.<br />
<br />
Light cottons, with slightly heavier cottons or light woollens for evening. Inland, shoes are essential during the day as the ground is very hot.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the vast distances involved, travelling by air is often the most practical way to get around. Air Namibia (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.airnamibia.com.na">www.airnamibia.com.na</a>) offers flights between Windhoek and most major centres from Hosea Kutako and Eros Airports.</p>
<p>Companies offering charter flights to Namibian cities as well as safari destinations such as Sossusvlei and Damaraland include Skeleton Coast Safaris (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.skeletoncoastsafaris.com">www.skeletoncoastsafaris.com</a>), Wilderness Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.wilderness-air.com">www.wilderness-air.com</a>), Desert Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.desertair.com.na">www.desertair.com.na</a>) and African Profile Safaris (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.profilenamibia.com">www.profilenamibia.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With the exception of its dedicated luxury services, rail travel in Namibia is not geared towards tourism: progress is slow, the network is limited and most trains run overnight. The main routes on the TransNamib passenger network (+264 61 298 2301; <a href="http://www.transnamib.com.na" target="_blank">www.transnamib.com.na</a>) are between Windhoek and Keetmanshoop, Walvis Bay, Swakopmund and Tsumeb. First- and second-class carriages are available and light refreshments are offered on some services. On overnight voyages, seats in first-class compartments convert to four couchettes and those in second class to six couchettes.</p>
<p>The luxury Desert Express runs between Swakopmund and Windhoek, a 20-hour journey which includes several stops to give travellers the opportunity to go on safari, see the Namib Desert, walk in the dunes and admire the stars. A three-course dinner is included, as well as overnight accommodation with ensuite showers. The Northern Desert Express is a luxury service to Etosha National Park.</p>
<p>Other tourist rail services include Rovos Rail (tel: +27&nbsp;12 315 8242, in South Africa; <a href="http://www.rovos.co.za" target="_blank">www.rovos.co.za</a>)  which runs nine-day trips from Pretoria to Swakopmund or vice versa, stopping at the Fish River Canyon and Etosha National Park en route. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Namibia boasts some of the best roads in Africa, and many are tarmac. Distance presents the main challenge with as much as three hours between towns on main roads and more when you venture further into the wilderness.</p>
<p>Petrol stations are few and far between, so top up on fuel whenever possible and keep a large bottle of emergency water in the car in case of breakdown. Always keep a charged mobile phone handy.</p>
<p>Bush roads are either gravel or dirt and require a 4-wheel drive vehicle. Some bisect Namibia&rsquo;s network of dried out rivers and as a result, flood during the rainy season. If travelling along the Caprivi Strip, stay on the tarred road and avoid travelling at night.</p>l<p>Roads are generally well maintained but away from the main highways surfaces are gravel or dirt, not tarmac.</p><p>Intercape (<a href="http://www.intercape.co.za" target="_blank">www.intercape.co.za</a>) operates scheduled services between Windhoek and Walvis Bay, Swakopmund, Grootfontein, Rundu and Katima Mulilo. Only two items of baggage are allowed per person and fares include meals.</p><p>Taxis are only commonly found in Windhoek. Most are &lsquo;shared taxis&rsquo;, which operate more like buses with multiple pick-up and drop-off points. Several private taxi companies operate in Windhoek and include Express Radio Taxis (tel: +264 239 739) and Swartz CA Taxi (tel: +264 215 412).</p><p>A valid European, Australian or US driving licence is acceptable for up to 90 days but you require an International Driving Permit for longer stays.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 23 years. The speed limit is 60kph (50mph) in built up areas (although it does go up to 80kph on some public roads), 100kph (62mph) on gravel roads and 120kph (75mph) on tarmac roads. Seatbelts are compulsory, and the use of mobile phones when driving is illegal.</p><p>AA Namibia (Automobile Association of Nambia) (+264 61 224 201; <a href="http://www.aa-namibia.com" target="_blank">www.aa-namibia.com</a>) is part of the international AA network.</p><p>Cars and 4-wheel drive vehicles, with or without camping equipment, can be hired for pick-up at Windhoek Airport. You can also hire vehicles in Windhoek city centre and some other cities. Both major international and local firms are available.</p><p>Namibia is a vast desert country and thus unsuitable for bike transport.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 23 years. The speed limit is 60kph (50mph) in built up areas (although it does go up to 80kph on some public roads), 100kph (62mph) on gravel roads and 120kph (75mph) on tarmac roads. Seatbelts are compulsory, and the use of mobile phones when driving is illegal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Namibia is relatively hard to get to, with only one direct flight available from Europe. As that flight, operated by national carrier Air Namibia (<a href="http://www.airnamibia.com.na" target="_blank">www.airnamibia.com.na</a>), goes to and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/frankfurt">Frankfurt</a>, multiple stops are necessary for everyone else.</p>
<p>Travellers from the UK can take a connecting flight to Frankfurt or fly with South African Airways (<a href="http://www.flysaa.com">www.flysaa.com</a>) via <a href="http://i/johannesburg">Johannesburg</a>. Flights are most expensive during the peak game-viewing season which runs from May to September, and over the Christmas period.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 18 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Namibia&rsquo;s main airport is Hosea Kutako International. Unless you&rsquo;re travelling direct from Frankfurt, it&rsquo;s worth having your bags wrapped in order to avoid problems while changing planes. Thanks to the tight connection time on the British Airways/Air Namibia route, taking a change of clothes in your hand luggage is also handy &ndash; it isn&rsquo;t unusual for bags to arrive a day behind their owners.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Namibia&rsquo;s main airport is Hosea Kutako International. Unless you&rsquo;re travelling direct from Frankfurt, it&rsquo;s worth having your bags wrapped in order to avoid problems while changing planes. Thanks to the tight connection time on the British Airways/Air Namibia route, taking a change of clothes in your hand luggage is also handy &ndash; it isn&rsquo;t unusual for bags to arrive a day behind their owners.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Windhoek Hosea Kutako International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airports.com.na<p>The airport is 42km (25 miles) from the city (journey time - 30 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Namibia&rsquo;s main ports are Walvis Bay and L&uuml;deritz.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The rail service that connected Keetmanshoop with Upington in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa">South Africa</a>&nbsp;is no longer running and has been replaced by&nbsp;a regular bus run by Intercape (<a href="http://www.intercape.co.za" target="_blank">www.intercape.co.za</a>). From Keetmanshoop, connections to Windhoek are available, while on the South African side, onward trains to Johannesburg and Cape Town on the Trans Karoo line run frequently.</p>
<p>See Trans Namib (<a href="http://www.transnamib.com.na" target="_blank">www.transnamib.com.na</a>)and South African Railways (<a href="http://www.southafricanrailways.co.za" target="_blank">www.southafricanrailways.co.za</a>) for more information and timetables.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cape-town">Cape Town</a>, the N7 freeway runs all the way up the Western Cape into Namibia, crossing the border at Vioolsdrift (also known as Noordoewer).</p>
<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/johannesburg">Johannesburg</a>, follow the N14 to Upington and connect with the N10 freeway leading to Grunau in Namibia, brushing past the Augrabies National Park en route. Other border crossings include those at Vellorsdrif, Ariamsvlei and Klein Menasse.</p>
<p>The Trans-Kalahari Highway links Walvis Bay and Windhoek with Gaborone <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/i/botswana">(</a><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/botswana">Botswana</a>) and Gauteng, (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa">South  Africa</a>).</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s also possible to enter Namibia from Botswana via the Mata Mata gate in Kgadigadi  National Park, provided that you plan to spend at least two nights within the park and stop for immigration at Twee Rivieren.</p>
<p>The Trans-Caprivi highway runs through the Caprivi strip and via Botswana into <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/zimbabwe">Zimbabwe</a>. An entrance fee applies to passenger cars and is payable at the border.</p>
<p>Coach travel is available on the Intercape  Mainliner<strong>&nbsp;</strong>(<a href="http://www.intercape.co.za/" target="_blank">www.intercape.co.za</a>). Routes run to Windhoek from Cape  Town and Johannesburg (via Upington), as well as to and from Livingstone (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/zambia">Zambia</a>) and Victoria Falls (Zimbabwe).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Namibia has an excellent fixed-line telephone network run by Telecom Namibia (<a href="http://www.telecom.na" target="_blank">www.telecom.na</a>). Domestic calls are reasonably priced, although international calls can cost upwards of N$20 (&pound;1.40) per minute.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MTC (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.mtc.com.na">www.mtc.com.na</a>) is Namibia&rsquo;s service provider but has roaming arrangements with international provider. However, it operates on GSM 900/1800, which is compatible with European and Australian networks but not with those from North America or Japan. Check with your mobile provider whether they will be able to provide coverage through the MTC network during your stay. MTC does offer prepaid service called Tango, which involves a one-off purchase of a sim card and pay-as-you-go thereafter. Although coverage is generally good, it can be sporadic outside urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafés in Walvis Bay, Swakopmund and Windhoek. Most youth hostels and some game lodges will offer internet services. Expect to spend around N$15 (£1.04) per hour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Press freedom is provided for by the constitution and respected by the government. Opposition views are broadcast. English-language dailies include <em>The Namibian</em> (also printed in Oshiwambo) and <em>The Namibia Economist</em>, while the main Afrikaans newspaper is <em>Die Republikein. Allgemeine Zeitung</em> is published daily in German. The state-owned Namibian Broadcasting Corporation (NBC) broadcasts nationwide and most homes will also subscribe to South African satellite channels. NBC&rsquo;s output varies in quality and the channel caused a scandal a few years ago by accidentally broadcasting porn (being watched by an inept controller at the time) during peak viewing time. Desert TV is a Windhoek-based private station. State-run radio is operated by NBC but there are several private music stations including Radio Kudu, Radio 99 and Radio Energy. BBC World Service and Voice of America are broadcast on short wave.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While Namibia's internal post is annoyingly slow, international post is more reliable and mail will usually get to its destination within two weeks.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600; Sat 0830-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Etosha National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Take a game drive in Etosha National Park, the third largest game reserve in Africa, which is home to vast herds of elephants, zebras, giraffes, wildebeest and antelopes, as well as hyenas and big cats. The mammoth Etosha salt pan is surrounded by over 22,000sq km (8,500 sq miles) of grasslands and low bush which is brilliant game-viewing territory.</p>]]><br/><p>Fish River Canyon</p><![CDATA[<p>This is one of the last great wildness treks, an impressive three-day endurance test strictly for the fit and hardy. Hikers need to join an organised trip with an experienced guide, and be self-sufficient throughout the trek. Due to the risk of flooding and the high summer temperatures the hiking trail is only open from 1 May to 31 August. Whilst in the area, you can also visit the Quiver Tree (Kokerboom) Forest to see these bizarrely elegant giant aloes, once used by the San people to make quivers for their arrows and now protected.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Birdwatching in the Caprivi Strip</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Africa's top 10 birdwatching destinations, the Caprivi Strip is a place of tropical rainforest, green hills and slow-flowing rivers. As a result, its avian population comprises more than 339 species, including some unique to the region.  Along with birds, the region is home to hippos, crocodiles, lions, giraffes, waterbuck, and antelopes.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Sossusvlei's dunes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Leave early to climb giant Dune 61 before sunrise for a truly once-in-a-lifetime view. As the sun climbs, the colossal dunes seem to shift shape and colour. It's mindbendingly beautiful. Visit the nearby Dead Vlei to see a bizarre landscape that's more Dr. Seuss than Mother Africa.</p>]]><p><b>Do conservation work at AfriCat Foundation</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This non-profit rehabilitation centre (<a href="http://www.africat.org" target="_blank">www.africat.org</a>) cares for cheetahs, leopards, lions and endangered wild dogs on a rescue-and-release basis. There's a luxury lodge for overnight visitors, and activities include tracking rehabilitated cheetahs, spotting hyenas on foot, and leopard safaris in a game-viewing vehicle.</p>]]><p><b>East Caprivi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bordered by the Kwando, Linyanti, Chobe and Zambezi rivers, this region of riverine forest, swamps and flood plains has several safari lodges offering whitewater rafting, canoeing trips, fishing, hiking and game viewing, particularly in the Mudumu and Mamili National Parks.</p>]]><p><b>Eat out in Swakopmund</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Founded by the Germans, Swakopmund doesn't just look like Dusseldorf in the desert – it makes food like it too. As a result, the city is one of the best places to eat in Africa, heavy on the meat and potatoes, but no less delicious for that. If you want to see how it's grown, take a trip to a desert asparagus farm.</p>]]><p><b>Etosha National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a game drive in Etosha National Park, the third largest game reserve in Africa, which is home to vast herds of elephants, zebras, giraffes, wildebeest and antelopes, as well as hyenas and big cats. The mammoth Etosha salt pan is surrounded by over 22,000sq km (8,500 sq miles) of grasslands and low bush which is brilliant game-viewing territory.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Lüderitz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sandwiched between the Namib desert on one side and the rough Atlantic sea on the other, the fact Lüderitz exists at all is surprising in itself. The gateway to the Sperrgebiet (Forbidden Area), Lüderitz is quaintly Teutonic, boasting surreal German Art Deco architecture, and thoroughly Bavarian style cafes and pubs. The nearby Lüderitz peninsula is also worth a visit thanks to its enormous flocks of flamingos.</p>]]><p><b>Fish River Canyon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Even if you're not hiking through this huge gorge, second only to the Grand Canyon, you can drive up to the edge and admire its humbling scale. Whilst in the area, you can also visit the Quiver Tree (Kokerboom) Forest to see these bizarrely elegant giant aloes, once used by the San people to make quivers for their arrows and now protected.</p>]]><p><b>Fish River Canyon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This is one of the last great wildness treks, an impressive three-day endurance test strictly for the fit and hardy. Hikers need to join an organised trip with an experienced guide, and be self-sufficient throughout the trek. Due to the risk of flooding and the high summer temperatures the hiking trail is only open from 1 May to 31 August.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the Skeleton Coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Despite the ominous (and well deserved) name, the Skeleton Coast is strikingly beautiful. Take a three-day nature trail along the Ugab riverbed and gravel plains of the forbidding wind-whipped Skeleton Coast Park, where you'll find desert-adapted plant species such as welwitschia, lithops and delicate lichens. Get an eerie close up look at the shipwrecks scattered along the coast, most of which have become seaweed-coated Cape Cormorant colonies.</p>]]><p><b>Kolmanskop and Elizabeth Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once packed with hopeful diamond hunters, Kolmanskop and Elizabeth Bay are long abandoned towns half-buried in sand. With a special permit from Luderitz, you can explore the windswept relics of these pioneer towns before they are completely swallowed by the Namib Desert, never to be seen again. See www.ghosttowntours.com.</p>]]><p><b>Kunene elephants</b></p><![CDATA[<p>During the 1980s, most of the 3000 desert elephants that lived in Namibia's Kunene were killed by hunters and poachers. Thanks to the efforts of dedicated local conservationists, their population currently stands at around 600. Several volunteer programmes are available, including Elephant Human Relations Aid (<a href="http://www.desertelephant.org" target="_blank">www.desertelephant.org</a>) which allows elephant enthusiasts to lend a hand.</p>]]><p><b>Meet the Himba in Kaokoland</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn about tribal customs and desert survival techniques by visiting the kraal (homestead) of the Himba, an indigenous semi-nomadic community in the Kaokoland region of northern Namibia. You'll find a real warmth and playfulness about the Himba, who live in unusual beehive mud huts.</p>]]><p><b>Oktoberfest in Windhoek</b></p><![CDATA[<p>During Oktoberfest, expect to see lederhosen-clad locals swilling steins and singing oompahs while the scent of sauerkraut and the sound of thigh-slapping fill the air. There's even a competition to see which waitress can carry the most beer. It's bizarre, but so totally worth it.</p>]]><p><b>Safari in Namib Naukluft National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its rolling red dunes, rocky escarpments and flat, dusty savannah, Namib Naukluft National Park is a great place to indulge in a safari. The Namib Naukluft  is part of the Namib Desert, believed to be the world's oldest desert. Here, oryx, hyena and gemsbok stroll over the burnt orange dunes tufted with grasses that stretch into the horizon.</p>]]><p><b>See Damaraland’s rock art</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Surviving in Damaraland's bizarre lunar landscape of scrubby veld and basalt rocks might look like a tough call but people have done for millenia. Early inhabitants left behind fascinating rock engravings, of which the White Lady of the Brandberg is best known. The fantastical Petrified Forest, a collection of around 50 fossilised trees is nearby, as is Burnt Mountain, Namibia's highest peak.</p>]]><p><b>Tour Windhoek</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The attractive Namibian capital features German colonial architecture including the iconic Christuskirche. A tour of the Windhoek lager brewery is recommended, and the National Museum, housed within the Alte Feste fortress is worthwhile. In the centre of Post St Mall, there's a quirky display of the meteorites that hit Namibia during the Gibeon meteor shower.</p>]]><p><b>Track black rhinos in Damaraland</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the planet's most endangered species, black rhinos are well-protected in Namibia thanks to excellent conservation work and fearful penalties for poachers. Rugged Damaraland is home to a desert-adapted variety, which you can track as part of an ongoing initiative to monitor and protect the animals from poachers.</p>]]><p><b>Watch seals at Cape Cross</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This isolated stretch of rocky shore near Walvis Bay is home to a huge, malodorous Cape fur seal colony. Around November, plenty of young pups can be seen huddled next to their mothers. Organised tours can be arranged from Swakopmund – just prepare for a nose-wrenching experience.</p>]]><p><b>Waterberg Plateau Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Waterberg Plateau Park is a mountain reserve with striking red sandstone cliffs and natural springs as well as rare animal species, including Namibia's only colony of Cape vultures. The park is home to black and white rhino, sable antelope and blue wildebeest. Self-guided bush walks are well signposted and four to eight day loops are available.</p>]]><p><b>West Caprivi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Here, a good place to stop is the Popa Falls Rest Camp (www.nwr.com.na ), a popular haven on the banks of the Okavango River, where crocodiles bask and hippos wallow. About 12km (7 miles) to the south is Mahango Game Reserve, with elephants, buffalo and lechwe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$12.3 billion (2012).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Diamonds, uranium, lead, beef, fish.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, petroleum products and fuel, construction materials, machinery, chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>South Africa, UK, Spain, Angola and USA.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The mining industry is one of Namibia&rsquo;s key sources of income and provides more than half of the country&rsquo;s foreign exchange income. Namibia is on of the largest producers of uranium in the world. Other minerals extracted include silver, copper, lead, zinc, tungsten and some of the world's highest-quality diamonds.</p>
<p>Livestock dominates the agricultural sector, with huge cattle and game farms making up the largest part of the industry. A substantial proportion of the workforce is engaged in subsistence farming of crops such as wheat, maize and millet but their yield is under constant threat from desertification. Even in a good year, Namibia only grows around 50% of the cereal its population consumes and has to import the remainder. Namibia also has an active commercial fishing industry centred around Walvis  Bay and its sardine-packed waters. Manufacturing is mainly devoted to processing raw materials and agricultural produce.</p>
<p>Tourism, particularly eco-tourism, is a key part of the economy and one of the country&rsquo;s biggest employers. Although it is dominated by the white Afrikaaner population, the industry is increasingly geared towards benefitting the local people who live in remote safari areas via initiatives such as conservancies and training schemes for would-be chefs, guides and hotel managers.</p>
<p>Namibia&rsquo;s biggest trading partner is <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa">South Africa</a>, followed by the UK, the USA, Angola, the Netherlands and Spain, and generally involves the exchange of raw materials for manufactured goods. Recent economic policy has seen many former state enterprises transferred to the private sector. The economy has performed reasonably well during the last decade but inflation has recently accelerated. Annual growth in 2012 was 4.6% with inflation at 6.3%. Official unemployment figures hover around 50%, although this does include subsistence farmers and tribal hunter-gatherers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits are advised. Prior appointments are necessary. English is widely spoken in business circles, although a grasp of Afrikaans is an advantage. The best times for business are February to May and September to November.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Namibia Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (61) 228 809
					Website:http://www.ncci.org.na
					Address: ,PO Box 9355,Windhoek,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>What you eat in Namibia depends largely on where you are and who you&rsquo;re with. Although certain foods are common to all of Namibia&rsquo;s ethnic groups, each has their own specialities &ndash; some more appealing than others. Game meat, particularly kudu, oryx and other antelope is very common and even forms part of the in-flight offering on Air Namibia flights (much better than the chicken, it should be noted). Other game meat on offer includes buffalo, and occasionally, giraffe, while seafood is plentiful and excellent &ndash; particularly in Swakopmund and Walvis Bay. Braais (barbecues) are very common among Afrikaaner and German groups, while most African tribes eat plenty of mealie pap (a doughy maize paste) and <em>oshifima</em>, the millet version often served with meat or vegetable stews. South African dishes such as bobotie (a meat pie with a savoury egg custard crust) are also common.</p>
<p>Most restaurants will offer Teutonic or international fare, although thanks to Namibia&rsquo;s desert environment which makes fruit and vegetables especially expensive, menus tend to be heavy on the meat. More German influence can be seen in Namibia&rsquo;s konditoreien (cake shops), where you can tuck into classics like apple strudel, sachertorte (chocolate cake) and kirschtorte (Black Forest gateau). Afrikaaners also know their way around the dessert trolley, with <em>koeksesters</em> (mini doughnuts dripping with honey) and melktart (milk tart) among the nicest. Breakfasts tend to be a spin on eggs and <em>boerewors</em> (sausage) although don&rsquo;t be surprised to find a strange meaty extra such as curried kidneys thrown in with your scrambled eggs.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Biltong<strong> </strong>(an air-dried meat, which is a bar snack staple, usually made from beef or kudu). <br />
&bull; <em>Rauchfleisch</em> (smoked meat). <br />
&bull; Game such as antelope, ostrich or zebra cooked on a braai (barbecue). <br />
&bull; <em>Potjiekos</em> (one-pot bush stew, usually cooked over a camp fire, and made with just about anything although chicken and vegetable is common). <br />
&bull; Seafood, especially oysters, on the coast.<br />
&bull; Kalahari truffles (a distant cousin of the European black and white truffle varieties found on Swakopmund restaurant menus, served up thinly sliced and drizzled with olive oil alongside a thick ostrich steak.)</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is customary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With most visitors to Namibia heading into the wilderness on safari, nightlife tends to be concentrated around the camp bar. Most of these are convivial, if quiet, and you&rsquo;ll find staff ever ready to come and share a drink with you. The majority of towns will have a little pub, many attracting a crowd of local farmers supping on pints of beer and chewing the fat over a plate of biltong. For more serious party opportunities, head to Windhoek, Walvis Bay or Swakopmund, all of which offer a variety of activities after dark. Windhoek, as you&rsquo;d expect, has the most to offer and benefits from a growing range of cigar bars, jazz clubs, arty cafes, cinemas, theatres and clubs. Visit during Windhoek Karnival in March or Oktoberfest to get the best of the action.<br />
<br />
Joe&rsquo;s Beerhouse (<a href="http://www.joesbeerhouse.com" target="_blank">www.joesbeerhouse.com</a>) is a local institution, which serves up a game-heavy snack selection, washed down with local beer. It&rsquo;s fun and friendly, with boozing sessions extending into the small hours. Also worth a visit is Club Thriller, which is located in a rough part of town and is best done as a group. Beyond the unnerving weapons search at the door, you&rsquo;ll find upbeat African tunes and a friendly crowd. At La Dee Da&rsquo;s nightclub, you can dance to African beats beneath Namibia&rsquo;s largest national flag. Swakopmund&rsquo;s night scene is concentrated around several lively late-night pubs, often filled with overlanding groups. The old train station has been renovated into a casino if you fancy a flutter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Namibia may not have much of a reputation for retail therapy, but there&rsquo;s plenty on offer if you know where to look. Windhoek is where you&rsquo;ll find international brands, most of which are South African. The capital has several shopping malls, the best of which is Post St Mall, although it&rsquo;s worth noting that most of the curios on offer there are cheap imports from Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>Local crafts such as wood carvings, karosse rugs and Herero dolls can be bought in curio shops and at the Windhoek Street Market, held every second Saturday. Precious gems are another big draw for Namibian shoppers, and the best are to be found at the House of Gems in Windhoek, which sells gorgeous jewellery. Also worth picking up are <em>Swakopmunder </em>leather shoes, most of which are made from kudu skins. Swakopmund also has plenty of gift shops for souvenirs.</p>
<p>In Rundu and other areas in the north east, you&rsquo;ll find traditional San handicrafts including arrow heads and ostrich egg jewellery. Crafts and curios can also be found at regional craft centres and safari lodges. Visitors may reclaim VAT on goods of a minimum value of N$250.00 at Hosea Kutako International Airport, Eros Airport and Walvis Bay Airport, although the process is notoriously tricky to understand and follow.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700; Sat 0900-1300. Some bigger supermarkets are also open Sun 1100-1300 and 1600-1900.</p><p>Be extremely careful if you're contemplating buying a piece that looks as if it could be made from an exotic skin or material. Buying and selling products made from protected animals such as elephants, black rhinos, cheetah and leopards is forbidden and attracts harsh punishment. However, you are likely to see some ivory on sale in and around Windhoek. This is usually the legitimate product of park culling operations and will be clearly marked.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[Hotels in Namibia range from unimaginably luxurious to basic in the extreme.  Safari lodges tend to dominate the luxe side of the market, with everything from private pools to personal butler service included as part of the deal. Others meanwhile offer the bare minimum with nothing more than a comfy bed and possibly breakfast thrown in. Campsites are everywhere but youth hostels and other budget accommodation are limited. The big international chains are represented in the capital but the majority of hotels are locally run affairs.<p>Namibia's hotels can be of good quality, some with conference facilities, in Windhoek, Swakopmund and thinly scattered throughout the country. As accommodation is limited and demand in the most popular areas is high, visitors are advised to book hotels in Namibia well in advance.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded on a scale of 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>B&B's aren't particularly widespread in Namibia and nearly all are concentrated in the main hubs of Windhoek, Swakopmund and Walvis Bay, although Outjo and Okahandja each have one. Most are family run and as a result, standards vary although nearly all are comfortable, pleasant places to be.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[Hotels in Namibia range from unimaginably luxurious to basic in the extreme.  Safari lodges tend to dominate the luxe side of the market, with everything from private pools to personal butler service included as part of the deal. Others meanwhile offer the bare minimum with nothing more than a comfy bed and possibly breakfast thrown in. Campsites are everywhere but youth hostels and other budget accommodation are limited. The big international chains are represented in the capital but the majority of hotels are locally run affairs.<p>Namibia's hotels can be of good quality, some with conference facilities, in Windhoek, Swakopmund and thinly scattered throughout the country. As accommodation is limited and demand in the most popular areas is high, visitors are advised to book hotels in Namibia well in advance.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded on a scale of 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[Hotels in Namibia range from unimaginably luxurious to basic in the extreme.  Safari lodges tend to dominate the luxe side of the market, with everything from private pools to personal butler service included as part of the deal. Others meanwhile offer the bare minimum with nothing more than a comfy bed and possibly breakfast thrown in. Campsites are everywhere but youth hostels and other budget accommodation are limited. The big international chains are represented in the capital but the majority of hotels are locally run affairs.<p>Namibia's hotels can be of good quality, some with conference facilities, in Windhoek, Swakopmund and thinly scattered throughout the country. As accommodation is limited and demand in the most popular areas is high, visitors are advised to book hotels in Namibia well in advance.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded on a scale of 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Because Namibia&amp;rsquo;s size medical facilities are spread out, with most lodges offering little more than basic medical care. As a result, serious accidents will require an expensive transfer to hospital in Windhoek, or in extreme cases, to medical facilities in &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa"&gt;South Africa&lt;/a&gt;. As a result, travel insurance is essential, and taking out a comprehensive policy is worthwhile. This is doubly the case if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to take part in sports such as quad biking or off-roading. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
While Namibia isn&amp;rsquo;t plagued by the tropical diseases that afflict its northern neighbours, it does experience the occasional outbreak of malaria, while dysentery (most often seen in campers who haven&amp;rsquo;t properly treated their water supply) can also occur. It is advisable to consult your doctor well in advance of travelling about immunisations and assembling a first aid kit if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to drive long distances or stay in a remote area.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, while safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available and is advised for the first few weeks of the stay. Drinking water outside main cities and towns may be contaminated and sterilisation is advisable. Water taken from lakes and rivers is generally a bad idea and cannot be regarded as entirely safe to drink without prior boiling. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against meningococcal meningitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. The measles, mumps and rubella (MMR) vaccine is also recommended for travellers born after 1956 who have not previously received the inoculation. A rabies vaccination is sometimes required, particularly if your plans involve some degree of interaction with wild animals.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday, unless that Monday is also a holiday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Independence Day :
							21 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Workers' Day :
							01 May </p><p>Cassinga Day :
							04 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Africa Day :
							25 May </p><p>Heroes' Day :
							26 August </p><p>International Human Rights Day :
							10 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Family Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following may be imported into Namibia by persons over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes and 50 cigars and 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine and 1L of spirits.<br />
&bull; 50ml of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Gifts to the value of N$1,250.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include narcotics, automatic weapons, military weapons, unnumbered weapons, toxic and poisonous substances.</p>
<p>Hunting rifles need a permit issued by customs when entering the country. Special authorisation is required for the import of endangered species. Plants or plant materials require a permit obtained in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited exports include endangered species, narcotics, stolen property, ivory, rhino horn, and protected cultural artefacts.</p>
<p>You must obtain permits in order to export the following: military weapons, ammunition, explosives, firearms, conflict diamonds and minerals, pornography, and products which violate national intellectual property protection law (eg counterfeit goods).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Namibian Dollar (NAD; symbol N$) is in note denominations of N$200, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of N$5, N$1, 50 cents, 10 cents and 5 cents. It is linked to the South African Rand (R) on a 1:1 basis (South African Rand = 100 cents). The South African Rand is also acceptable as currency in Namibia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available in banks and at bureaux de change, as well as at Hosea Kutako International Airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, Mastercard and Visa are accepted. Credit cards are not usually accepted at petrol stations, so bear this in mind when you visit the ATM. Setting aside an emergency petrol cash fund is a good idea if you&rsquo;re planning to drive.</p><p>Although ATMs can be found in most towns, it&rsquo;s worth making sure that you&rsquo;ve got enough cash handy at all times, as towns can be few and far between. Make sure you notify your bank of your travel plans before you go: Namibia is among the countries that trigger an automatic account freeze (fraud protection) if you fail to tell your bank beforehand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or South African Rand. In general, you can expect a better exchange rate for traveller&rsquo;s cheques than for cash.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1530; Sat 0900-1100. Note that at the end of the month, when many government employees are paid, queues at the banks can be several hours long.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Namibia, a passport valid for six months from date of entry with one blank page is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above. If you require a visa, you must have at least three blank pages in your passport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;It's compulsory to carry ID at all times; a photocopy is sufficient if you leave your passport in your hotel safe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry tourist visa: &pound;60; multiple-entry tourist visa: &pound;90.</p>
<p>Single-entry business visa: &pound;90; multiple-entry business visa: &pound;120.&nbsp;</p>
<p>An additional administrative fee of &pound;35 applies to all visa types.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Valid for up to three months, for stays of up to three months from the date of entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at high commission).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you plan to work or study in Namibia, you must obtain a temporary work or study permit from the high commission or embassy in your own country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing takes three days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While tourists are rarely required to prove they have enough money to see them through their trip, those applying for visas must be able to show officials that they have enough to support themselves for the duration of their stay in Namibia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Three-month visa extensions are available from the Ministry of Home Affairs in Windhoek.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must obtain a permit to bring a pet into Namibia. You should submit your application no more than three days before your arrival date; forms are available from the high commission/embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-22.149042]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[17.179992]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>824,292 sq km (318,261 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,513,981 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Windhoek.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Namibia is a large, mostly arid country in southwest Africa with Angola to the north, Botswana to the east, and South Africa to the south. In the northeast corner, the Caprivi Strip, a narrow panhandle of tropical Namibian territory juts towards Victoria Falls, forming borders with Angola, Zambia, Botswana and South Africa.   To the west is a 1,280km long stretch (795 miles) of perhaps the loneliest coastline in the world, with foggy shores lashed by the Atlantic and littered with shipwrecks.</p>
<p>Along the entire length of the country, the huge shifting dune fields of the Namib Desert spread inland for up to 130km (81 miles). The most stunning sand dunes can be found in Sossusvlei National Park.   In the far northwest, the Kaokoland Mountains run parallel to the Skeleton Coast, while further inland lies the Etosha Pan, a dried-out saline lake surrounded by grasslands. The Etosha National Park is the third largest in Africa, remaining largely free of human influence.</p>
<p>In the interior, the Central Plateau runs from north to south, sloping away into the vast sand basin of the Kalahari. Windhoek, the capital, perches on this plateau. The Kalahari has a geography all of its own, with inselbergs, or isolated mountains that create microclimates and habitats for organisms not adapted to life in the desert.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Christians make up 80-90% of the Namibian population, of which 50% are Lutheran. Other denominations include Roman Catholic, Anglican, Methodist, Dutch Reformed and Mormon. Between 10 and 20% hold indigenous beliefs. The Muslim and Jewish populations are tiny with the two religions making up less than 3% of Namibian believers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the high number of religious believers, Namibians are on the whole a conservative people. As a result, homosexuality isn&rsquo;t really understood and is barely tolerated, while modest clothes, although not expected, are appreciated. Generally though, Namibians are friendly, entertaining people who will deal with you politely and expect the same in return.</p>
<p>Western customs are generally accepted as the norm, so usual courtesies should be shown when meeting new people or visiting someone&rsquo;s home. In rural areas, visitors should follow the advice of a local guide when it comes to indigenous etiquette. Giving a proper greeting is particularly important and those who are standoffish or blunt are regarded as extremely rude. Many can be fairly blunt themselves, particularly among straight-talking Afrikaaners.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Outlets are of the South African three-pin type (two small round pins over one larger round pin).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Saara Kuugongelwa-Amadhila since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Hage Geingob since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Namibia's prehistory dates back more than 750,000 years, when the first settlers moved in to brave the hostile Namib and Kalahari heat. Although the earliest people were basic hunter-gatherers, the Boskop – ancestors of the San people – had developed a structured society more than 20,000 years before the birth of Christ, making it one of the world's oldest civilisations.</p><p>Sadly for the Boskop and the San who followed, their period of dominance was not to last with Bantu and Khoikhoi agriculturalists moving in and displacing them. Later, during the 16th century, the Herero people arrived from the Zambezi Valley, followed in the 19th century by a new Bantu group, the Owambo, who settled along the Kunene and Okavango rivers.</p><p>Although European had known about Namibia since 1486, when Portuguese Captain Diago Cão sailed along the coast as far as Cape Cross, it wasn't until the 17th century when Dutch settlers from Cape Colony (now South Africa) began to take an interest. In 1844, the first German settlers appeared, followed by the British who, attracted by its huge sardine shoals, promptly annexed Walvis Bay.</p><p>German colonisation proper began with Lüderitz and quickly extended outwards and upwards to include the whole of Namibia, barring Walvis Bay, which remained in British hands. Settlement began as the Nama-Herero wars raged, giving the Germans the opportunity to sweep in and take over. Then followed one of the darkest periods in Namibia's history – the German extermination of nearly 80 per cent of the Herero population. The genocide was interrupted by the outbreak of World War 1 intervened and from 1918 onwards, Namibia became a British protectorate overseen by the South Africa.</p><p>Although South Africa became fully independent in 1967, Namibia did not and as a result, the full force of apartheid was visited on the country. Throughout the 1950s, despite pressure from the UN, South Africa tightened its grip on Namibia leading to uprisings among the black population, as well as some whites, and the eventual formation of SWAPO (South West African Peoples Organisation). SWAPO spent the next 30 years battling to rid Namibia of the South African occupiers, at one point asking for help from Cuba. In 1988, a ceasefire was negotiated between SWAPO, Cuba and South Africa and independence followed two years later.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• Tourism accounts directly or indirectly for nearly 20 per cent of all jobs in Namibia.</p><p>• After Mongolia, Namibia has the second lowest population density of any country.</p><p>• Although the Namibian music industry is largely undeveloped, local folk music is popular as are Western music styles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Namibia ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(61) 274 800.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(61) 274 800.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1300 and 1400-1700; Fri 0800-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>116 Robert Mugabe Avenue<br/>Windhoek<br/>P.O. Box 22202<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Namibian High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7636 6244.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.namibiahc.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7636 6244.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>6 Chandos Street<br/>London<br/>W1G 9LU<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Namibian Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 986 0540.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.namibianembassyusa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 986 0540.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1605 New Hampshire Avenue NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From the seemingly endless sand dunes of the Namib Desert to the tropical wetlands of the Caprivi Strip, Namibia is a country of epic landscapes, bountiful wildlife and few people.&nbsp;Its greatest assets are the rugged Namib and Kalahari deserts, which support a surprising diversity of fauna including rare black rhinos, cheetahs, elephants, springbok and vast flocks of ostriches.</p>
<p>Namibia can be a harsh and unforgiving land, and nowhere is this more evident than along the Skeleton Coast. A windswept wasteland of dark green scrub and calcified sand dunes, it is littered with the rusting carcases of ships washed ashore by the merciless Atlantic Ocean.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not all hostile. The area is also home to the colourful Himba people whose love of elaborate hairdos and jewellery have made them one of the most photographed tribes in the world. Their home overlaps another of Namibia&rsquo;s natural marvels, Etosha National Park, which boasts an abundance of wildlife: everything from the tiny Cape sparrow to the magnificent African elephant can be found here.</p>
<p>Towns and cities are few and far between in Namibia, thanks to its low population. Even the capital, Windhoek, is not much larger than a medium-sized British settlement. But the city&rsquo;s lively nightlife, colonial architecture, thriving culinary scene and excellent beer make it a pleasant place to while away a few days &ndash; even if the town planners did make a habit of naming roads after dictators. Anyone fancy a stroll down Robert Mugabe Drive?</p>
<p>Namibia&rsquo;s second city, Swakopmund, is lighter on the dictator nomenclature, but none the worse for it. The coastal town has a sunny charm that is all its own. Appearing like a mirage in the desert, the city is home to palm-fringed beaches, a gorgeous collection of colonial buildings and a sizeable German-speaking population.</p>
<p>And just outside the city lie the rusting remains of the Martin Luther, an abandoned steam locomotive that tried to tame this wild land and failed &ndash; a metaphor, surely.</p><p>From the seemingly endless sand dunes of the Namib Desert to the tropical wetlands of the Caprivi Strip, Namibia is a country of epic landscapes, bountiful wildlife and few people. Its greatest assets are the rugged Namib and Kalahari deserts, which support a surprising diversity of fauna including rare black rhinos, cheetahs, elephants, springbok and vast flocks of ostriches. However, Namibia has much more to offer than wildlife and landscapes: its cities offer beautifully-preserved colonial architecture, lively nights, tasty cuisine and excellent beer, while it's colourful coastal resorts allow visitors to kick back on palm-fringed sands and bask in the sizzling African sun.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
