<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Nepal" ColCode="npl" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="np" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Nepal]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Monsoon season begins around the end of June and lasts until the end of September. About 80% of Nepal's annual rainfall is during that period, so the remainder of the year is pretty dry. Spring and autumn are the most pleasant seasons; winter temperatures drop to freezing, with a high level of snowfall in the mountains, while high summer can be blisteringly hot. Summer and late spring temperatures range from 28&ordm;C (83&ordm;F) in the hill regions to more than 40&ordm;C (104&ordm;F) in the Terai.<br />
<br />
In winter, average maximum and minimum temperatures in the Terai range from a brisk 7&ordm;C (45&ordm;F) to a mild 23&ordm;C (74&ordm;F). The central valleys experience a minimum temperature often falling bellow freezing point and a chilly 12&ordm;C (54&ordm;F) maximum. Much colder temperatures prevail at higher elevations. The Kathmandu Valley, at an altitude of 1,310m (4,297ft), has a mild climate, ranging from 19-27&ordm;C (67-81&ordm;F) in summer, and 2-20&ordm;C (36-68&ordm;F) in winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight and tropical clothes with umbrella are advised for June to August. Between October and March, lightweight clothes are worn in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kathmandu">Kathmandu</a>, with a coat for evenings and warm clothing for the mountains. When trekking in the mountains, high quality trekking gear that can handle minus temperatures is recommended all year round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Destinations such as Lukla, Pokhara, Simikot, Jomsom, Janakpur and Bharatpur are served by domestic flights. Nepal Airlines (<a href="http://www.nepalairlines.com.np" target="_blank">www.nepalairlines.com.np</a>) operates an extensive range of scheduled services, dropping trekkers at the main hiking routes. Yeti Airlines (<a href="http://www.yetiairlines.com/" target="_blank">www.yetiairlines.com</a>) and Buddha Air (<a href="http://www.buddhaair.com/" target="_blank">www.buddhaair.com</a>) are also popular carriers. Internal flights can be booked via Nepal Air Flight (<a href="http://www.nepalairflight.com" target="_blank">www.nepalairflight.com</a>). Morning flights tend to be affected less by inclement weather.</p>
<p><strong>Note: </strong>Airfares must be paid in foreign currency by foreign nationals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferries are used for river and lake crossings, but tend to be overcrowded.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is not currently possible to travel across Nepal by train.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International Driving Permits are required to drive in Nepal. Drivers should be cautious; driving standards are poor and so are the roads. Car hire is not available in Nepal, but it is possible to hire drivers. Tourist buses run frequent service throughout the country.</p>l<p>The road infrastructure in Nepal is limited. Road quality is also poor; potholes abound and landslides frequently close roads, particularly mountain roads which can be impassable during monsoon season (June to August).</p><p>Tourist buses provide transport to destinations throughout the country. They tend to be better equipped, more comfortable and safer than local buses. They also make stops on long journeys for lunch and tea. You can book tickets through hotels and tour operators.</p>
<p>Local buses are cheaper, but tend to be packed and poorly maintained. Conductors collect tickets on board.</p><p>Taxis drivers are ubiquitous. Fares are cheap by Western standards, but do negotiate a price before entering the cab. Tipping is appreciated but not expected.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is valid in Nepal for 15 days, after which a local licence is required. A temporary licence is available from local authorities on presentation of a valid national driving licence.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18.</p><p>There's no national breakdown service. You need to find a local mechanic.</p><p>There are no self-drive hire cars in Nepal. Travellers must hire a car and driver.</p><p>You can hire bicycles and motorcycles in larger towns and cities. You need an international driving licence to rent a motorbike, but some vendors turn a blind eye if you don&rsquo;t have one. Helmets and facemasks are advised. Check the horn works too &ndash; you may need it.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are frequent bus services in populous towns and cities. Private minibuses are also available.</p>
<p><strong>Taxi: </strong>Metered taxis are plentiful in Kathmandu; at night, the meter reading plus 50% is standard. Private taxis are more expensive and fares should be agreed before departure.</p>
<p><strong>Tempos: </strong>These metered three-wheel scooters are slightly cheaper than taxis.</p>
<p><strong>Rickshaws: </strong>These operate throughout Kathmandu. Fares should be negotiated in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Nepal</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sunauli</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Nepal</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">pokhara</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Nepal</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">lukla</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tribhuvan International Airport in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kathmandu">Kathmandu</a> is the only international airport in Nepal. Approximately 30 airlines link it with destinations throughout Europe, Asia and the Middle East including Qatar Airways (<a href="http://www.qatarairways.com" target="_blank">www.qatarairways.com</a>), Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>) and Nepal Airlines (<a href="http://www.nepalairlines.com.np" target="_blank">www.nepalairlines.com.np</a>).</p>
<p>The peak seasons for travelling to Nepal are from September to November and March to May. Flights to Kathmandu are most expensive during these times. To keep costs down, travel on the edge of these seasons and book in advance.</p>
<p>There are no direct flights to Nepal from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nepal/kathmandu-tribhuvan-international-airport">Kathmandu Tribhuvan International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 14 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 21 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All taxes are included in ticket prices for international flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Kathmandu Tribhuvan International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.tiairport.com.np<p>Kathmandu Tribhuvan International Airport is located 6km (4 miles) east of Kathmandu.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+977 1 411 3033</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nepal is a landlocked country and not accessible by water.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is not possible to travel from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> or India and into Nepal by train. However, Indian Railways (<a href="http://www.indianrail.gov.in/" target="_blank">www.indianrail.gov.in</a>) runs passenger trains to Gorakhpur, which is near the Bhairahwa border. Cycle-rickshaws and taxis are available there for onward journeys.</p>
<p>There are plans to construct railway lines between Nepal and India, and Nepal and China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is not possible to travel through Nepal by train.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are seven designated entry points to Nepal by road; six in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a> (Kakadvitta, Birgunj, Bhairahawa, Nepalgunj, Dhangadi and Mahendranagar) and one on the China/Tibet border (Kodari).</p>
<p>As a general rule, border towns don&rsquo;t provide much in the way of sightseeing and accommodation; get in and get moving. You can purchase visas at Kakadvitta, Birgunj, Bhairahawa, Nepalgunj, Gaddachowki, and Kodari providing you have cash and a passport-size photo.</p><p>Tourists entering the country in vehicles must have an international carnet and an international driving licence. Be advised that strikes (known locally as <em>bandas)</em>&nbsp;frequently bring Nepal to a grinding halt. During these strikes the roads close, so keep an eye on the news before you travel.</p>
<p>Border offices at the India-Nepal border have fixed hours (0600 to 2200). These hours are not always reliable, and long lines can form. While you may be able to find immigration officers who will let you in, don&rsquo;t count on it. Many tourist and local buses arrive early to secure their spot in line and move through inspection as quickly as possible.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is sporadic and variable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet cafes in Kathmandu, Patan and Pokhara – many with high-speed broadband links. Internet services are also provided by hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>English-language newspapers available in Nepal include <em>The Himalayan Times</em>, <em>The Kathmandu Post</em>, <em>Rising Nepal </em>and <em>The Nepali Times</em>. Other dailies include <em>Kantipur </em>and <em>Annapurna Post</em>. <em>The International Herald Tribune</em>, <em>Newsweek </em>and <em>Time </em>can all be found in Kathmandu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Postal services are available in most centres. Make sure letters are hand-cancelled at the post office (post boxes should not be used for important communications).</p><p>The general post office in Kathmandu (near the Dharahara Tower) is open Mon-Fri 1000-1700. Main hotels will also handle post.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Float on Phewa Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>After a trek up the Himalayas – or a night on the local beers – take a well-earned rest on the limpid waters of Phewa Tal in Pokhara. Whether you paddle yourself or hire someone to do it for you, make sure you visit Barahi Mandir, an island and temple in the middle of the lake.</p>]]><p><b>Go on safari at Chitwan National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nepal's oldest national park, Chitwan is home to endangered Bengal tigers, one-horned rhinos and mugger crocodiles, not to mention numerous bird species. Visitors can explore the park on elephants or in a safari vehicle. It's also possible to spend the night in watchtowers, listening to the roar of the jungle.</p>]]><p><b>Go underground at Siddha Gufa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At 437m (1,434ft) deep, Siddha Gufa is the largest cave in Nepal and lays claims to some spectacular stalactites and stalagmites, not to mention a myriad of otherworldly rock formations. Located just outside the village of Bandipur, the cave can be accessed by bus from Pokhara.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Mount Everest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The tallest mountain in the world, climbing Everest is the ultimate test of physical endurance. But if you can't make it to the summit, or even base camp, you can view this peak in all its glory from the window of a plane. Most domestic airlines offer scenic flights, which are available from Pokhara and other locations.</p>]]><p><b>Paraglide over Pokhara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pokhara has been touted as one of the best places in the world to go paragliding, thanks to its unique geothermal patterns and stunning landscapes. Several companies offer flight instruction, equipment rental and transport to and from the landing sites. Is there a better way to explore the world's highest country?</p>]]><p><b>Party in Thamel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once you've finished sightseeing in Kathmandu, have a well-earned beer in the lively Thamel district of the city. Packed with bars, clubs and restaurants, you won't struggle to find a glass of the local brew in these parts. As well as pints of Khukuri, you will also find local cuisine, fellow travellers and loud music.</p>]]><p><b>Photograph Pokhara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Described as the "jewel of Himalaya," Pokhara is a lakeside city of extraordinary beauty. Set to the backdrop of the snow-capped Annapurna mountain range, travellers fall for the city's many charms while visiting temples, shopping in traditional bazaars and boating on Phewa Lake.</p>]]><p><b>Pilgrimage to Buddha’s birthplace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The birthplace of Gautama Buddha, Lumbini is arguably the most important pilgrimage site in the world for practicing Buddhists. This spiritual site is not just a draw for religious devotees, though: the shimmering, golden temples and pristine grounds attract many tourists too.</p>]]><p><b>Raft the Marsyangdi River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Crashing through mountains are a series of rivers, which offer perfect conditions for white water rafting. From the swirling challenges of the Marsyangdi River, to the scenic Trisuli River, thrash it out on the country's exhilarating waterways, which are certain to get your heart racing and adrenaline pumping.</p>]]><p><b>Relax in Namche Bazaar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Clinging to the side of the Himalayas, the hillside town of Namche Bazaar is a hub for those exploring the Everest region. Bakeries and pool houses treat those who have walked from Lukla, and Wi-Fi accessible spots can comfort those missing home. Though badly shaken by the earthquakes, it&rsquo;s open for business.</p>]]><p><b>Scout for souvenirs</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Peruse Tibetan handicrafts and artefacts at the hugely impressive Boudhanath stupa, a centre of Tibetan exile culture, just a short ride from central Kathmandu. Alternatively, visit the lively bazaar in the bucolic hill town of Gorkha – the ancestral home of the Shah Dynasty and residence of the original Gurkha soldiers.</p>]]><p><b>Spot temples in Kathmandu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many of Kathmandu's religious monuments were destroyed during the 2015 earthquakes, including the landmark temple of Kasthamandap in Durbar Square. It's not all bad news. Incredibly the UNESCO-listed Hindu temple of Pashupatinath escaped relatively unscathed, as did Swayambhunath Stupa (also known as Monkey Temple), which offers sweeping panoramas and playful primates.</p>]]><p><b>Take part in a festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nepal's calendar is packed with all manner of festivals. Highlights include <em>Holi</em>, a spring festival where paint is thrown over all and sundry; Tibetan New Year; the light festival of Tihar; and <em>Dashain</em>, the longest and liveliest festival on the calendar. Check our calendar to see when exact dates fall.</p>]]><p><b>Try traditional yoga</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Feel the stresses and strains of daily life ebb away from you at one of the many yoga retreats in Nepal. Kathmandu, Lumbini and Pokhara are teeming with centres offering yoga, meditation and various other traditional treatments, which are revered in Nepal for their healing qualities.</p>]]><p><b>Veer off the beaten path at Annapurna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The trail to Everest Base Camp is a well-trodden one, so if you don't want to jostle for space with fellow hikers try the Annapurna Circuit. It's slightly quieter and offers epic mountain vistas. While accessible without a guide, inexperienced hikers are advised to seek assistance locally.</p>]]><p><b>Visit artsy Patan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The city of Patan has long-standing artistic traditions and is renowned for its beautifully crafted, artisanal goods. It is also a place of unremitting beauty where UNESCO listed landmarks meet opulent palaces and art galleries. Its most impressive landmarks include Patan Durbar Square, Krishna Mandir, the Royal Bath, Kumbheshwor Temple and the Golden Temple.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$21.14 billion (2016)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Clothing, carpet, leather, jute goods, workers</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Gold, machinery, petroleum products and fertilizer</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>India, Japan, China, EU, UK</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nepal is one of the world's least developed countries and its economy is largely supported by tourism, agriculture and the service industry. Foreign aid continues to push development forward, but the country has a large external debt.</p>
<p>An estimated 70% of the working population finds employment in agriculture and forestry, while approximately 10% work in tourism. With the global economy picking up and more Chinese people travelling, the tourism industry in Nepal &ndash; which has eight of the ten largest mountains in the world &ndash; has huge potential.</p>
<p>Neighbouring India plays a major role in the economy and agreements have been signed with several other governments, including China. The UN Commission on Human Rights has conducted several assessments on Nepal, reporting gradual improvements in infrastructure and health.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When conducting business in Nepal, you may be welcomed with a traditional pranāmāsana greeting. This gesture is made by pressing both palms together in front of your chest (fingers pointing upwards), bowing and saying &lsquo;Namaste&rsquo;. It is custom to reciprocate this introduction. Handshaking has crept into Nepali business life, but try to refrain from giving too firm a handshake, which might seem aggressive. Sometimes Nepali people shake with both hands.</p>
<p>When attending business meetings in Nepal, a suit and tie is recommended. Temperatures are more moderate in Kathmandu than other parts of the country, but it can get hot and stuffy in the summer and cold in the winter so dress accordingly.</p>
<p>A little bit of politeness goes a long way when you&rsquo;re doing business in Nepal and it can be helpful to learn a few key phrases before heading into meetings. Elders are always shown the utmost respect, so bear this in mind.</p>
<p>Nepal is open for business six days a week &ndash; offices are generally open 1000 to 1700 Sunday through Friday. These hours can be affected by blackouts, which are a regular feature in Nepal. Most blackouts are planned in advance to help the country save power. Newspapers report anticipated outages and apps can be downloaded to review schedules.</p><p>Typically Sun-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Nepal Incentive and Convention Association</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 449 4411
					Website:
					Address: ,,Kathmandu,PO Box 4258]]><b>Nepal-Britain Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 204 2770
					Website:http://www.nbcci.org/
					Address: PO Box 24714,1448/30,Madan Bhandari Path - 4,New Baneshwor,Kathmandu,]]><b>Federation of Nepalese Chambers of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 426 2061
					Website:http://www.fncci.org/
					Address: Teku,PO Box 269,Pachali Shahid Shukra,Milan Marg,Kathmandu,]]><b>Nepal Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 423 0947
					Website:http://www.nepalchamber.org/
					Address: Kantipath,PO Box 198,Kathmandu,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Sandwiched between India and China, Nepal&rsquo;s cuisine is heavily influenced by its neighbours &ndash; although dishes tend to be simpler and less varied.</p>
<p>Meals are typically spicy and meaty, although that&rsquo;s not to say you can&rsquo;t find good vegetarian cuisine. Indeed, the national dish is <em>dal bhat </em>(lentil curry), which, like most dishes, is accompanied with rice and thin pancake-like bread known as <em>chapatti</em>.</p>
<p>Nepal&rsquo;s unreliable electricity supply restricts the ability to refrigerate produce, which, perversely, has a positive effect because it means most food is prepared to order.</p>
<p>Adventurous gastronomes should venture into the markets to sample fresh fruits including umpteen varieties of bananas, which are some of the sweetest you&rsquo;ll ever taste.</p>
<p>At the higher end of the market, Kathmandu has developed an international culinary scene where diners can find dishes from all over the world. Chefs artistically prepare five-star menus, and food competitions have aimed to encourage budding restauranteurs.</p>
<p>Bakeries and caf&eacute;s are scattered around tourist towns, where patrons can quaff Nepali tea (ask for it <em>kaalo</em> [black] or with <em>chini </em>[sugar]).</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><em>&bull; Dal bhat </em>(lentils and rice)</p>
<p><em>&bull; Tarkari </em>(spiced vegetables)</p>
<p><em>&bull; Thukpha</em> (Tibetan stew of noodles and meat)</p>
<p>&bull; Rotis (flat pancake-like bread made from wheat or rice flour)</p>
<p>&bull; Chapatti (similar to <em>roti</em> but thinner)</p>
<p>&bull; Choyla (diced and roasted water buffalo, spiced and eaten with rice)</p>
<p>&bull; <em>Cel roti</em> (Nepali equivalent of a donut; circular, fried dough)</p>
<p>&bull; <em>Pani puri </em>(round pastries filled with spices, potatoes, and water)</p>
<p>&bull; <em>Momos </em>(handmade dumplings filled with meat or veggies; order them friend or steamed)</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>It is considered rude to eat with your left hand. Utensils are provided in most tourist destinations, but locals still eat with their hands. Bring your own water bottle to be eco-conscious or buy bottled for cheap on the street.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Only expected in tourist hotels and restaurants; 10% is sufficient.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18, although that&rsquo;s not strictly enforced &ndash; you&rsquo;ll never be asked for an ID at a bar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kathmandu's nightlife may not be considered wild, but there are plenty of late bars, live music spots and nightclubs in which to have a good knees-up. Most are located around Thamel and near the city's 5-star hotels. Many restaurants put on traditional Newari dance shows for tourists – particularly in Pokara – and there are a couple of casinos for those who fancy trying their luck.</p><p>In Thamel Hollywood blockbusters are shown in bars and restaurants, while local cinemas play a range of Bollywood films. In Pokhara, the nightlife centres around snooker halls and dance bars, which play Bollywood pop music until the early hours.</p><p>Live music is ubiquitous in Lakeside, and drinks can be found on the cheap throughout the day. Nepalis do like to drink, so if that's your thing you will make friends easily. In mountain towns near Lukla, if you stay up late enough, you can toast with porters and guides who will muster the strength to wake up early and lug large loads up the mountain despite putting back glass after glass of <em>Kuhkari rum</em> late into the evening.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you like shopping you&rsquo;ll love Nepal&rsquo;s many and varied markets. These lively bazaars are packed with vibrant wares and hard-haggling hawkers. Popular buys include locally made garments such as pashmina scarves, sweaters, <em>topis </em>(lopsided caps), mittens, socks, Tibetan dresses, woven shawls and multicoloured jackets.</p>
<p>Other common items include the <em>Khukri </em>(the national knife), <em>saranghi </em>(a small, four-stringed viola played with a horse-hair bow), papier-m&acirc;ch&eacute; dance masks, Buddhist statuettes and bamboo flutes. Teas and spices are also popular.</p>
<p>With its burgeoning arts scene, Kathmandu and Patan are exciting places to shop for traditional and modern paintings and sculptures. More practically speaking, Thamel and Lukla are packed with outlets selling outdoorwear for those thinking of heading into the mountains.</p><p>Sunday through Friday, 1000-2000 in most tourist areas.</p><p>Antiques cannot be taken out of the country and must be inspected by the Department of Archeology.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kathmandu has an ever expanding selection of international hotels. During peak trekking season (spring and autumn) these get particularly busy, so it is advisable to book well in advance. Comfortable hotels and inexpensive guest houses can also be found in Pokhara, and around the Royal Chitwan National Park in the Terai.</p>
<p><strong>Note: </strong>A government tax is added to bills, which varies according to the standard of the hotel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kathmandu has an ever expanding selection of international hotels. During peak trekking season (spring and autumn) these get particularly busy, so it is advisable to book well in advance. Comfortable hotels and inexpensive guest houses can also be found in Pokhara, and around the Royal Chitwan National Park in the Terai.</p>
<p><strong>Note: </strong>A government tax is added to bills, which varies according to the standard of the hotel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kathmandu has an ever expanding selection of international hotels. During peak trekking season (spring and autumn) these get particularly busy, so it is advisable to book well in advance. Comfortable hotels and inexpensive guest houses can also be found in Pokhara, and around the Royal Chitwan National Park in the Terai.</p>
<p><strong>Note: </strong>A government tax is added to bills, which varies according to the standard of the hotel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid and Polio<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid and Polio"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The most convenient hospital for visitor care is Patan Hospital in Lagankhel. Other hospitals include the Western Regional Hospital and the Manipal Hospital in Pokhara and the Mission Hospital in Tansen. Pharmacies in Kathmandu offer a wide range of Western drugs at low prices. In Kathmandu, you can get certain vaccinations free at the Infectious Diseases Clinic. Full medical insurance is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and advised. Avoid dairy products likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against Japanese B encephalitis, meningococcal meningitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Altitude sickness is a hazard for trekkers – it is important to gain altitude gradually and come down to a lower altitude immediately if experiencing headaches, nausea or dizziness. Obtain further advice from the Himalayan Rescue Association. It is advisable, particularly when in rural areas, to carry a medical kit.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Hindu festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Martyrs' Day :
							2018<br/>30 January </p><p>Rashtriya Prajatantra Divas (National Democracy Day) :
							18 February </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Constitution Day :
							09 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Nepal by foreign visitors without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes and 50 cigars and 20g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1.15L of spirits or wine or 12 cans of beer.<br />
&bull; Medicine not exceeding Rs10,000 in value.<br />
&bull; Canned food not exceeding Rs1,000 in value.<br />
&bull; Fresh fruit not exceeding Rs2,000 in value.<br />
&bull; 50g of gold ornaments and 100g of silver ornaments.</p>
<p>All baggage must be declared on arrival and departure. Certain goods including cameras, videos and electronic goods may only be imported duty-free if they are exported on departure. They may not be left in Nepal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include narcotics, beef and plastic bags less than 20 microns thick.</p>
<p>Restricted items include firearms and ammunition, radio equipment and poppy seeds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Goods of historical, archaeological or religious importance, wild fauna, narcotics, firearms and ammunition, and certain herbs and woods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nepalese Rupee (NPR; symbol Rs) = 100 paisa. Notes are in denominations of Rs1,000, 500, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of 50, 25 and 10 paisa.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong>(a) Visitors should bear in mind that foreign visitors other than Indian nationals are required to pay their airline tickets, trekking permits and hotel bills in foreign currency. (b) Taking Nepalese currency outside the country is prohibited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is illegal to exchange currency with persons other than authorised dealers in foreign exchange (banks, hotels and licensed money changers). Visitors should obtain Foreign Exchange Encashment Receipts when changing currency and keep them, as these will help in many transactions, including getting visa extensions and trekking permits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express is widely accepted, with MasterCard and Visa in tourist shops, hotels, restaurants and agencies. ATMs are widely available in Nepal, however, it is not possible to withdraw cash in the mountains. Those embarking on treks should take enough cash for the duration of their trek.</p><p>American Express is widely accepted, with MasterCard and Visa in tourist shops, hotels, restaurants and agencies. ATMs are widely available in Nepal, however, it is not possible to withdraw cash in the mountains. Those embarking on treks should take enough cash for the duration of their trek.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers cheques are accepted at banks and major hotels. If trekking, it is important to bear in mind that cash is necessary. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Banks in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kathmandu">Kathmandu</a> valley are open Sun-Thurs 0930-1530 and Fri 0930-1330. Licensed money changers are open 12 hours per day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Nepal, a passport valid for six months is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa on arrival: US$25 (15 days); US$40 (30 days); US$100 (90 days).</p>
<p>Multiple-entry tourist visa in advance: &pound;20 (15 days); &pound;35 (30 days); &pound;75 (90 days).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are valid for 15, 30 or 90 days. Visas obtained from the embassy must be used within six months of the date of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). Visas can also be obtained on arrival from the immigration authorities at all entry points (with fees payable in US Dollars or Pounds Sterling) provided travellers are in possession of valid travel documents, two passport photos and the relevant fee. Applications for business visas must be made to the Department of Immigration.</p>
<p>Note that certain nationals not listed in the chart must obtain a visa in advance and cannot obtain a visa on arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 24 to 48 hours if applying in person and two to three days from the date of receipt if applying by post.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend tourist visas at the Department of Immigration and Pokhara Immigration Office for a total of 120 days. An additional 30-day visa may be granted on reasonable grounds from the department.   Over the course of a calendar year, a tourist cannot stay in Nepal for more than 150 days altogether.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[28.264020]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[83.930998]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>147,181 sq km (56,827 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>28,850,717 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>214.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kathmandu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nepal is a landlocked kingdom sharing borders with Tibet to the north and India to the west, south and east. The country can be divided into six zones: the Terai, the Chure hills, the Mahabharat range, the Pahar zone, the Himalaya and the Trans-Himalaya.</p>
<p>The greater part of the country lies on the southern slope of the Himalayas, extending down from the highest peaks through hill country to the upper edge of the Ganges Plain. The hilly central area is crossed by the Lower Himalayas, where there are eight of the highest peaks in the world, leading up to Mount Everest. Wildlife in Nepal includes tigers, leopards, gaur, elephants, buffalo, deer and rhinos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mainly Hindu (85%) and Buddhist (8%), with a small Muslim minority (4%).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Be careful to respect local customs: Never step over the feet of a person - always walk round; never offer food and drink that you have tasted or bitten; never offer or accept anything with the left hand - use the right or both hands; it is rude to point at a person or statue with a finger (or even with a foot).<br />
<br />
Often when people shake their head, it means 'yes'. Footwear should be removed when entering houses, especially kitchens and shrines. Do not stand in front of a person who is eating. Shaking hands is not a common form of greeting; instead, press the palms together in a prayer-like gesture (<em>Namaste</em>).<br />
<br />
Casual-wear is suitable except for the most formal meetings or social occasions. However, bikinis, shorts, bare shoulders and backs may not be appreciated. Men only remove their shirts when bathing. Overt public displays of affection, especially near religious places, are inappropriate.<br />
<br />
Seek permission before entering a temple, and do not take leather articles inside them.<br />
<br />
<strong>Photography: </strong>Always ask permission first. In general, photography is allowed outside temples and at festivals, but not inside temples or at religious ceremonies; however, there is no hard and fast rule, and the only way to be sure of not giving offence is to ask first and accept the answer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. There are frequent power cuts. Plugs usually have two or three round pins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister K.P. Sharma Oli&nbsp;since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Bidhya Devi Bhandari since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nepal was established as a kingdom in 1768 by Prithvi Narayan Shah, who unified a group of neighbouring principalities in the Himalayas. An ambitious man, Shah attempted to expand into nearby <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tibet">Tibet</a>, but his plan was thwarted by the Chinese during what became known as the Sino-Nepalese War (1788-1792).</p><p>Barely 20 years later and the country was fighting unsuccessfully again, this time with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">Britain</a> over disputed borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>. In losing the Anglo-Nepalese War (1814-1816), Nepal ceded a lot of territory and political power to Britain, whose presence in Nepal destabilised the country and helped Jang Bahadur Rana to power in 1848.</p><p>Under Rana's rule, the monarchy was stripped of power and an undemocratic dynasty of hereditary prime ministers was established. This suited the British – who were well-respected by Rana – and in 1923 they granted Nepal independence.</p><p>However, rather than being liberated, Nepal slid into obscurity under Rana, leading to growing dissatisfaction within the country and, ultimately, a coup, in which his regime was overthrown in 1951.</p><p>With Rana gone, the monarchy was restored and the Nepalese Congress Party – comprised mainly of anti-Rana rebels – was installed in government. With Nepal back on the map, visitors returned, including New Zealander, Edmund Hillary, who became the first person to scale Mount Everest in 1953.</p><p>But by 1960 Nepal was once again thrown into turmoil; realising that a monarchy and democratic government were incompatible, King Mahendra dissolved parliament.</p><p>Bowing to growing disquiet, his successor, King Birendra, held a referendum in 1979 to decide the future of Nepali politics. However, its people voted, by a small minority, to maintain the status quo, which failed to placate critics. In 1990, once again, unrest forced the king's hand and he agreed that a new democratic constitution was necessary.</p><p>The following year Nepal held its first democratic elections in 50 years. Yet the nineties were characterised by economic failure, which laid the foundations for the Nepalese Civil War. The armed conflict – between the Maoist Communist Party of Nepal and the beleaguered government – lasted a decade and reached its nadir in 2001, when a state of emergency was declared.</p><p>In the same year, Crown Prince Dipendra, heir to the throne, went on a drunken rampage, murdering the King and several family members before committing suicide.</p><p>Eventually, in 2006, a peace deal was signed, which brought the Maoists into mainstream politics and curtailed the power of the monarchy further (a year later, the monarchy was abolished).</p><p>Nepal has been largely peaceful since and Nepal's most recent elections in 2013 – which are disputed by Maoists – show signs of forward momentum. But, politically speaking, there's still a mountain to climb.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[The British Embassy in Nepal]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+997 (1) 423 7100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-kathmandu</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+997 (1) 423 7100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0815-1230 and 1330-1700; Fri 0815-1315.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Lainchaur<br/>PO Box 106<br/>Kathmandu<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Nepal in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 020 7229 1594.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.nepembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 020 7229 1594.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1200 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Kensington<br/>12A Kensington Palace Gardens<br/>London<br/>W8 4QU<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Nepal in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 667 4550.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.nepalembassyusa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 667 4550.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1200 (visa section). Application submission 0930-1500. Pick-up 14.00-16.00.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2131 Leroy Place NW<br/>Washington DC<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Officially the highest country on Earth, lofty Nepal is commonly referred to as the &ldquo;roof of the world.&rdquo; That seems like a fitting moniker for this Himalayan nation, where soaring, snow-capped mountains disappear into the clouds like stairways to heaven.</p>
<p>Mount Everest is the star attraction. Tourists come in their droves to climb, hike and admire the world&rsquo;s tallest peak, which flirts with the stratosphere at 8,848m (29,029ft).&nbsp;But this charming country is much more than just mountains.</p>
<p>The birthplace of Gautama Buddha, Nepal is an important pilgrimage site for millions of Buddhists, who come from far and wide to visit the UNESCO World Heritage Site of Lumbini, a temple complex where Buddha once lived.</p>
<p>Holy places abound in Nepal, but not just of the Buddhist variety; Hinduism has a strong foothold in the country and there are many Hindu temples scattered across the country (though some have been severely damaged by the 2015 earthquakes).</p>
<p>Also hit hard was the Nepali capital, Kathmandu, which is encircled by soaring mountain ranges. A beautiful, bustling city it stands at a cultural crossroads between India and China, whose influences can be seen in the architecture and tasted in the cuisine. Meanwhile, a Western vibe prevails in the lively Thamel district, which is lined with bars.</p>
<p>Kathmandu is a good starting point for travellers venturing into the jungle at Chitwan National Park, which is home to Bengali tigers, crocodiles and one-horned rhinos, plus myriad bird species. Phewa Lake is another draw for tourists, as are the hiking trails in the Himalayas.</p>
<p>Wherever you go though, wide smiles will be there to greet you; Nepalese people are amongst the friendliest in the world and it&rsquo;s not uncommon to be invited into a stranger&rsquo;s home for tea.</p>
<p>Sitting atop the world, Nepal is just one step away from heaven &ndash; and for those who have discovered the country&rsquo;s many charms, it feels like it too.&nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp;Officially the highest country on Earth, lofty Nepal is commonly referred to as the &ldquo;roof of the world.&rdquo; That seems like a fitting moniker for this Himalayan nation, where soaring, snow-capped mountains disappear into the clouds like stairways to heaven.</p>
<p>Mount Everest is the star attraction. Tourists come in their droves to climb, hike and admire the world&rsquo;s tallest peak, which flirts with the stratosphere at 8,848m (29,029ft). But this charming country is much more than just mountains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
