<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Netherlands" ColCode="nld" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="nl" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is never a bad time to visit the Netherlands, which has a moderate climate with warm summers (average 19&deg;C/66&deg;F) and relatively mild winters (average 3&deg;C/37&deg;F). That said, mid-April to mid-October is probably the best time to go, although coastal resorts and big cities like <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amsterdam">Amsterdam</a> do get busy during the summer holidays (July-August) - higher prices reflect the increased demand. To see the country&rsquo;s famed bulb fields burst with colours, plan a trip to the Netherlands between mid-April and mid-May. You won't be disappointed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Summers are generally warm with changeable periods, but excessively hot weather is rare. Pack a light jacket or sweater even in mid-summer. Winters can be fairly cold with the possibility of some snow. Rainfall is ever a possibility, and rainwear is advisable year-round.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Due to Holland's small size, there are no scheduled domestic flights in the Netherlands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are regular ferry services to the Wadden Islands (Ameland, Schiermonnikoog, Terschilling, Texel and Vlieland) across the Ijsselmeer (former Zuyder Sea) and Schelde Estuary. There is also a service to the Frisian Islands across the Waddenzee. The main ferry operator is Teso (tel: +31 222 369 600, within the Netherlands only;&nbsp;<a href="https://www.teso.nl" target="_blank">www.teso.nl</a>).</p>
<p>Numerous operators offer river and canal cruises from main centres around the Netherlands. Note: No cars are permitted on Vlieland. Cruise ships regularly call at Passenger Terminal Amsterdam&nbsp;(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ptamsterdam.nl/">www.ptamsterdam.nl</a>), close to the city centre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The highly developed rail network is efficient and cheap, and connects all towns. Both intercity and local trains run at least half-hourly on all principal routes. Rail and bus timetables are integrated, and there is a common fare structure throughout the country.</p>
<p>NS (tel: +31 30 751 5155; <a href="http://www.ns.nl" target="_blank">www.ns.nl</a>) is the national rail company and operates most services within the country. Regional rail-bus companies cover routes in the more remote areas of the north and east of the country. You can buy tickets at ticket offices or machines in the stations; e-tickets are also available via the NS website.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dal Voordeel:&nbsp;</strong>grants travellers a 40% discount on rail travel throughout the Netherlands during off-peak hours and weekends. The discount also applies for up to three travelling companions. Available online from the NS website.</p>
<p><strong>InterRail Benelux Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Belgium, Luxembourg and the Netherlands. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 27 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from the InterRail website (<a href="https://www.interrail.eu/en/interrail-passes/one-country-pass/benelux" target="_blank">https://www.interrail.eu</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is an excellent road system, although it can become very busy at times around major centres. There is a chronic shortage of parking space in central Amsterdam, and the rush hours (0700-0900 and 1700-1900) should be avoided throughout the whole country. There are only two toll roads in The Netherlands: the Western Scheldt Tunnel and the Dordtse Kil.</p>r<p>Buses provide regional transport within The Netherlands, while intercity travel is covered by the train network. Among the main operators are Conexxion (tel: 0900 266 6399, within the Netherlands only; <a href="https://www.connexxion.nl" target="_blank">www.connexxion.nl</a>) and Arriva (tel 0800 023 2545, within the Netherlands only; <a href="https://www.arriva.nl" target="_blank">www.arriva.nl</a>). For enquiries about routes, use <a href="http://9292.nl" target="_blank">9292.nl</a>.</p><p>Taxis are metered and have an illuminated sign on the roof. Rather than hailing taxis in the street, you should either book by phone or go to a taxi stop.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is recommended for non-EU visitors, though is not compulsory, as long as you hold a driving licence from your country of origin. EU pink format licences are accepted. A Green Card is advisable, but not compulsory. Without it, drivers with motor insurance policies in their home country are granted only the minimum legal cover in the Netherlands; the Green Card tops this up to the level of cover provided by the driver's own policy.</p><p>Drivers should be particularly aware of cyclists; often there are special cycle lanes. Speed limits are 100-130kph (62-81mph) on motorways, 80kph (50mph) on major roads and 50 or 30kph (31mph) in towns.</p><p>The yellow cars of the ANWB/Wegenwacht (Royal Dutch Touring Club) (tel: +31 88 269 2222, within the Netherlands only; <a href="https://www.anwb.nl" target="_blank">www.anwb.nl</a>) patrol major roads 24 hours a day with qualified mechanics equipped to handle routine repairs. In case of emergencies, assistance is available.</p><p>Available from airports, main hotels and many other locations in the major cities. All major international car hire companies are represented. Drivers must be at least 18 years old.</p><p>With some 29,000km (over 18,019 miles) of signposted bicycle lanes and primarily flat terrain, the Netherlands is a cyclist's dream. Two-wheel travel within and between urban areas is an economical and enjoyable alternative to driving.</p>
<p>You can hire bikes at or near all main railway stations. If you've got your own bike, you may put it on a train (in cars marked with the bicycle icon) for a fee; folding bikes travel free.</p><p>Drivers should be particularly aware of cyclists; often there are special cycle lanes. Speed limits are 100-130kph (62-81mph) on motorways, 80kph (50mph) on major roads and 50 or 30kph (31mph) in towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Getting around town is a cinch with safe, efficient and easy-to-use public transport systems the norm in cities throughout the Netherlands. Extensive networks of buses, trams and ferries operate in the largest cities, Amsterdam, Rotterdam and Den Haag; the first two feature metro lines as well. Buses generally stop running around midnight but night networks operate in the main urban areas.</p>
<p>The easiest way to pay is using an OV-Chipkaart smartcard, which can be used on public transport throughout the country. For short-term visitors, the best option is to purchase 'disposable' single card or an anonymous OV-chipkaart, allowing unlimited travel on public transport during a specified period. You can buy these at public transport outlets, in tobacco shops, in several supermarkets or at vending machines in the stations. Otherwise, it is possible to purchase a one-hour card when you get on the bus or tram.</p>
<p>Another good option for getting around town is to rent a bike; rentals are available from bike shops throughout the Netherlands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Netherlands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">the_hague</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.44</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Netherlands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">rotterdam</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Netherlands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">maastricht</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Netherlands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">groningen</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.20</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Netherlands</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">eindhoven</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.25</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national carrier is KLM (<a href="https://www.klm.com" target="_blank">www.klm.com</a>). Other airlines flying direct to the Netherlands from the UK include British Airways (<a href="https://www.britishairways.com" target="_blank">www.britishairways.com</a>), Cityjet (<a href="http://www.cityjet.com" target="_blank">www.cityjet.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="https://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>), Flybe (<a href="http://www.flybe.com" target="_blank">www.flybe.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="https://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>). Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) operates direct flights from the USA.</p>
<p>Besides Schiphol, the Netherlands' principal airport near <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amsterdam">Amsterdam</a>, the airports at Rotterdam, Eindhoven and Maastricht are also arrival  points for international flights.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/netherlands/amsterdam-airport-schiphol">Amsterdam Airport Schiphol</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/netherlands/rotterdam-airport">Rotterdam the Hague Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amsterdam">Amsterdam</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 1 hour 15 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours 20 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in ticket price.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Amsterdam Airport Schiphol </b><![CDATA[http://www.schiphol.nl<p>Amsterdam Airport Schiphol is situated  9km (5.6 miles) southwest of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amsterdam">Amsterdam</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+31 20 794 0800</p>]]><b>Rotterdam The Hague Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.rotterdamthehagueairport.nl<p>Rotterdam The Hague Airport is situated 6km (3.7 miles) northwest of Rotterdam and 25km (15.5 miles) southeast of The Hague.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+31 10 446 3444</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports are<strong> </strong>Rotterdam (<a href="https://www.portofrotterdam.com" target="_blank">www.portofrotterdam.com</a>), Amsterdam (<a href="https://www.portofamsterdam.com" target="_blank">www.portofamsterdam.com</a>), Dordrecht (<a href="https://cms.dordrecht.nl/binnenhavengeld" target="_blank">cms.dordrecht.nl/binnenhavengeld</a>), Groningen (<a href="http://www.groningen-seaports.com" target="_blank">www.groningen-seaports.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eurostar (tel: +44 1233 617 575;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.eurostar.com" target="_blank">www.eurostar.com</a>) operates direct high-speed trains from London St Pancras International to Amsterdam (journey time - 3 hours 40 minutes) and Rotterdam (journey time - 3 hours). Currently, there is no direct Eurostar service from the Netherlands to the UK, but you can take a&nbsp;Thalys (tel: +31 30 233 1676; <a href="https://www.thalys.com">www.thalys.com</a>) high-speed train from Amsterdam (2 hours) or Rotterdam (1 hour 10 minutes) to&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brussels">Brussels</a>&nbsp;before continuing your journey to London St Pancras International via the Eurostar.&nbsp;</p>
<p>As an alternative to the Channel Tunnel, rail travellers can take the Dutch Flyer (tel: +44 844 576 2762, in the UK; <a href="http://www.stenaline.co.uk/ferry-to-holland/rail-and-sail" target="_blank">www.stenaline.co.uk/ferry-to-holland/rail-and-sail</a>), a rail-and-sail package, departing twice daily from London's Liverpool Street station to the port  of Harwich. From there, a ferry crosses to Hoek van Holland, with an ongoing rail connection to Rotterdam, Den Haag or Amsterdam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 30 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, or 5 days in 15 days or 7, 10, 15 days in a month across all countries.&nbsp;The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Both passes can only be used by European citizens and residents. The Global Pass allows for two train journeys in your country of residence, whereas the One-Country Pass is not valid for any journeys within your country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 28. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from the InterRail website (<a href="https://www.interrail.eu/en/interrail-passes" target="_blank">https://www.interrail.eu/en/interrail-passes</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 22 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 5 or 7 days in one month, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in up to four bordering countries and lets you choose from 27 European countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 28) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Eurotunnel (tel: +44 844 335 3535, in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>; <a href="https://www.eurotunnel.com" target="_blank">www.eurotunnel.com</a>) runs shuttle trains for vehicles between Folkestone and Calais. Driving time from Calais to Amsterdam is approximately 4 hours.</p>
<p>Flixbus (<a href="https://www.flixbus.nl" target="_blank">www.flixbus.nl</a>) and Eurolines (tel: +44 871 781 8181, in the UK; <a href="http://www.eurolines.co.uk" target="_blank">www.eurolines.co.uk</a>) offer daily buses from Victoria Coach Station in London, stopping at Amsterdam Sloterdijk Station and Amsterdam Duivendrecht Station respectively, with additional stops in Rotterdam and Den Haag (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hague">The Hague</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public telephone booths no longer exist in The Netherlands. There are public pay phones at the airports. They can be used with coins, a credit card or with special vouchers.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. There are no roaming charges within the EU. To avoid high roaming costs it is advisable to buy a local SIM card. Coverage is universal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is ubiquitous in The Netherlands. There are also many internet cafes and some internet access centres. In Amsterdam computers are available to use free of charge in libraries and public buildings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Dutch have a unique approach to public broadcasting. Programmes are made by a variety of groups, some reflecting political or religious currents in society, others representing interest groups. These organisations are allocated airtime on TV and radio, in line with the number of members they have. The TV market is very competitive, with many private stations also currently flourishing. The Dutch also have one of the highest cable take-up rates in Europe. Every province has at least one local public TV channel. Freedom of press and free speech is guaranteed by the constitution. Among the leading daily newspapers are Het Parool, De Telegraaf and the left-of-center NRC Handelsblad. For Dutch news in English, see www.dutchnews.nl.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Stamps are available from all post offices as well as from tobacconists and kiosks selling postcards and souvenirs. Mail within Europe takes approximately two to five days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700. Some post offices in major towns are also open on late shopping nights (Thurs or Fri) and Sat 0900-1200/1230. There are all-night post offices in Amsterdam and Rotterdam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Tulips at Keukenhof Gardens</p><![CDATA[<p>With some 4.5 million tulips and 15 kilometers of footpaths, Keukenhof gardens (<a href="http://www.keukenhof.nl" target="_blank">www.keukenhof.nl</a>), south of Haarlem, makes the ultimate outing for ogling Holland's famed flower. The bulb fields in and around Keukenhof burst into colour from the end of March to mid May.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Afsluitdijk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Drive or cycle across the Afsluitdijk, a 30km (19 mile) barrier built in the 1930s to close off the Zuiderzee from the North Sea, creating the now freshwater IJsselmeer. Motorists can stop at a lookout point halfway across the road linking Friesland with Noord-Holland.</p>]]><p><b>Amsterdam</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Holland's emblematic capital (<a href="https://www.iamsterdam.com" target="_blank">www.iamsterdam.com</a>) brims with romance, culture and kicks. Take a candlelit cruise along the canals, lined with narrow-fronted buildings dating from the city's heyday as a trading centre, browse the paintings of the Dutch masters at the Rijksmuseum or join the punters prowling the alleyways of the Red Light District.</p>]]><p><b>Amsterdam Arena</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy a football match at one of the top Dutch stadiums, Amsterdam Arena, home of the famous Ajax (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ajax.nl/">www.ajax.nl</a>), PSV's Philips Stadium in Eindhoven (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.psv.nl/">www.psv.nl</a>) or De Kuip (Feijenoord stadium), in Rotterdam, where Feyenoord play (<a href="https://www.feyenoord.com" target="_blank">www.feyenoord.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Anne Frank House</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The historic house (<a href="http://www.annefrank.org/en" target="_blank">www.annefrank.org/en</a>) where teenager Anne Frank, her family and four other Jews hid from the Nazis during World War II is today a permanent exhibition dedicated to her memory. In August 1944, they were betrayed to the Germans. Anne died at the Bergen-Belsen concentration camp; however her father survived and published her diary, which is on display here.</p>]]><p><b>Arnhem</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a trip to Arnhem (<a href="http://www.vvvarnhemnijmegen.nl/arnhem" target="_blank">www.vvvarnhemnijmegen.nl/arnhem</a>), in southeastern Holland, scene of WWII's 'Operation Market Garden', in which the city's Rhine crossing proved a 'Bridge too Far' for the allied forces attempting to bring an early conclusion to hostilities.</p>]]><p><b>Bloemenveiling Aalsmeer (the Aalsmeer Flower Auction)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get up early to witness trading at Bloemenveiling Aalsmeer (the Aalsmeer Flower Auction) (<a href="https://www.royalfloraholland.com" target="_blank">www.royalfloraholland.com</a>). Close to Schipol airport, the auctions take place in five halls at what is  the world's largest commercial building at 999,000 sq m (10.7million sq ft). It's best to arrive by 7 am; Thursdays are busiest.</p>]]><p><b>Boat tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a glass-topped boat tour round Amsterdam's many waterways and harbour. It is an excellent way to see the city's most interesting areas. Another option is to take a boat tour (<a href="https://www.lovers.nl" target="_blank">www.lovers.nl</a>), which links most of the major cultural attractions.</p>]]><p><b>Cheese markets</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the spectacle of one of Holland's cheese markets. The best are Waagplein, in Alkmaar (<a href="https://www.alkmaar.nl" target="_blank">www.alkmaar.nl</a>), where every Friday from mid-April to mid-September, thousands of wheels of cheese are lined up in rows by the central weighing house, taste-tested and carted away by guildsmen in traditional costume. The town of Edam holds a similar market on Wednesdays in summer.</p>]]><p><b>Corpus Experience, Leiden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the interior workings and health of the human body at Corpus, a new visitor attraction near Leiden (<a href="https://corpusexperience.nl" target="_blank">corpusexperience.nl</a>). The attraction also incorporates a medical information centre with changing exhibitions.</p>]]><p><b>Delft</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Watch the skills of the porcelain makers at the Royal Delft pottery (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.royaldelft.com/">www.royaldelft.com</a>), in the town of Delft. Also home town of Johannes Vermeer, it now features a centre (<a href="https://www.vermeerdelft.nl">www.vermeerdelft.nl</a>) dedicated to the painter of The Milkmaid and other masterworks of light.</p>]]><p><b>Diamond trading</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit one of Amsterdam's diamond traders, and watch craftsmen cutting and polishing the precious stones. Among the best known is Gassan, in Nieuwe Uilenburgerstraat (<a href="https://www.gassan.com/nl/juweliers" target="_blank">www.gassan.com/nl/juweliers</a>), where stones can be selected and mounted in jewellery on the spot.</p>]]><p><b>Dutch National Railway Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relive history at the Het Spoorwegmuseum (Dutch National Railway Museum) (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.spoorwegmuseum.nl/">www.spoorwegmuseum.nl</a>), at Maliebaanstation in Utrecht, with its extensive collection of historic rolling stock and memorabilia. A regular train link connects the museum with Utrecht Central.</p>]]><p><b>Gouda</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stroll around the historic city of Gouda, following the Cheese Map (available from the local tourist office; <a href="http://www.welkomingouda.nl" target="_blank">www.welkomingouda.nl</a>), which leads visitors around the various landmarks, including the Weighhouse Museum, associated with cheesemaking in the city.</p>]]><p><b>Haarlem</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A brief train ride from Amsterdam, Haarlem makes a serene alternative to the capital. Its beautifully preserved historic core centres on the Grote Kerk, a magnificent Gothic church. Admire the paintings of 17th-century master Frans Hals, then zip over to Zandvoort, a major beach resort.</p>]]><p><b>Hoge Veluwe National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a trip to the Hoge Veluwe National Park (<a href="https://www.hogeveluwe.nl" target="_blank">www.hogeveluwe.nl</a>) near Arnhem, among whose attractions is an underground museum dedicated to subterranean life, and the Kr&ouml;ller-M&uuml;ller Museum (<a href="http://krollermuller.nl/bezoek" target="_blank">krollermuller.nl/bezoek</a>) which contains 90 Van Gogh paintings and over 180 Van Gogh drawings as well as numerous masterpieces from other famous masters such as Monet, Seurat and Picasso. Bicycles are available free of charge to visitors.</p>]]><p><b>Leiden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A longtime intellectual centre, Leiden (<a href="https://www.visitleiden.nl/nl/landingpage" target="_blank">www.visitleiden.nl/nl/landingpage</a>) is the site of the country's first university, dating from 1575. Among the dozen museums dispersed along its canalways is De Lakenhal, with masterworks by native son Rembrandt van Rijn, and the Boerhaave natural sciences museum, which holds the microscopes used by van Leeuwenhoek.</p>]]><p><b>Maastricht</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to the far southeast of The Netherlands to see the medieval architecture of Maastricht (<a href="http://www.vvvmaastricht.nl/de/home.html" target="_blank">www.vvvmaastricht.nl/de/home.html</a>), Holland's oldest fortified city. Highlights include the basilica churches of Our Lady and St Servatius, and spectacular caves in the surrounding hills.</p>]]><p><b>Madurodam</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy a miniaturised flavour of the whole of The Netherlands at Madurodam (<a href="https://madurodam.nl" target="_blank">madurodam.nl</a>), which replicates many aspects of the country in 1:25 scale, incorporating windmills, a cheese market and what is claimed as the world's most extensive miniature railway.</p>]]><p><b>Museums and galleries</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See some of the many great works of art, including those of Dutch painters such as Rembrandt, Van Gogh and Vermeer displayed in Amsterdam's many museums and galleries, including the Rijksmuseum (<a href="https://www.rijksmuseum.nl" target="_blank">www.rijksmuseum.nl</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Nationaal Park Zuid Kennemerland</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cycle or hike through the Kennemerland national park (<a href="http://www.np-zuidkennemerland.nl/299/en" target="_blank">www.np-zuidkennemerland.nl/299/en</a>), a unique ecosystem skirting the coast west of Haarlem. Paths weave through woods, by lagoons, and up along massive dunes, which stretch 20km up the coast. Bright blooms enhance the golden sands in spring.</p>]]><p><b>Rent a bicycle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rent a bicycle and join the Dutch on the country's most popular form of transport. There are around 29,000km (18,019 miles) of designated cycle tracks around The Netherlands, which due to its generally flat landscape, is ideal.</p>]]><p><b>Rotterdam</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Standing at the mouth of the Rhine river, the port of Rotterdam (<a href="http://www.rotterdam.nl" target="_blank">www.rotterdam.nl</a>) is a showcase for innovative architecture. Ride the high-speed lift up Euromast in Rotterdam (<a href="http://www.euromast.nl" target="_blank">www.euromast.nl</a>), and dine at a height of 100m (328ft) overlooking the world's biggest harbour. Then, if you're brave, ascend even higher to 185m (605ft) with the Euroscoop experience. Step back into history at De Zaanse Schans village (<a href="http://www.dezaanseschans.nl" target="_blank">www.dezaanseschans.nl</a>), a short distance from Amsterdam, with its traditional houses, working windmills, clog factory, cheese farm, boat builder's and several museums.</p>]]><p><b>Royal Palace (Koninklijk Paleis)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Royal Palace (<a href="https://www.paleisamsterdam.nl/en" target="_blank">www.paleisamsterdam.nl/en</a>), which dates from 1648, was originally Amsterdam's town hall; it is regarded as the most important cultural and historical building from 17th-century Amsterdam. The building's exterior was originally made of white stone, although none of the white is actually visible today, whilst famous painters including Rembrandt and Ferdinand Bol were brought in to contribute to the interior. Today, the palace, which has been state property since 1936, houses an impressive collection of furniture left behind by Napoleon who made it his home in 1808, as well as chandeliers and clocks from this period. The palace is the official residence of the Dutch Royal Family. Its interior is open to the public.</p>]]><p><b>The Hague</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Seat of Dutch government and royalty, as well as of the International Court of Justice, Den Haag (<a href="https://denhaag.com/en">denhaag.com/en</a>) thrills architecture fans with its rich catalogue of palaces and government buildings. As an added attraction, the adjacent seaside resort of Scheveningen features a vast sandy beach.</p>]]><p><b>Tulips at Keukenhof Gardens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With some 4.5 million tulips and 15 kilometers of footpaths, Keukenhof gardens (<a href="https://keukenhof.nl" target="_blank">keukenhof.nl</a>), south of Haarlem, makes the ultimate outing for ogling Holland's famed flower. The bulb fields in and around Keukenhof burst into colour from the end of March to mid May.</p>]]><p><b>Utrecht</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Home to Holland's biggest university, Utrecht (<a href="http://www.visit-utrecht.com" target="_blank">www.visit-utrecht.com</a>) boasts a youthful, active vibe. The old centre, laced by canals, is a pleasure to stroll. Climb the elegant tower of the 14th-century Dom (cathedral) tower or visit the town's many museums, including one dedicated to the work of Dick Bruna, creator of <em>Miffy,</em> in the Centraal Museum (<a href="http://centraalmuseum.nl/en/" target="_blank">centraalmuseum.nl/en/</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Wadden Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the Waddeneilanden, an island chain off the coast of Friesland. Served by regular ferry services in summer, the five isles are fringed on their North Sea side by fine sand beaches. Cycling is the accepted way to get around and <em>wadlopen</em> (hiking the mud flats at low tide) is a popular activity.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$846 billion (2018 estimate).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, chemicals, fuels and food, natural gas.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transport equipment, oil, chemicals, fuels, food and clothes.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>EU countries (mainly Germany, France, UK and Belgium), and China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Netherlands has a typical developed European economy. It is also the world's second-largest exporter of farm produce (after the USA), accounting for 16% of total export earnings. Dairy products, meat, vegetables and flowers are the main products. Industry is concentrated in agriculture, petrochemicals and plastics, pharmaceuticals, synthetic fibres and food processing.<br />
<br />
There is also a wide range of light industries, including the manufacturing of electronic goods (Philips, of Eindhoven is a major global brand), although the historically strong textile industry has been in long-term decline. By contrast, The Netherlands has developed a strong base in advanced technological industries including computing, telecommunications and biotechnology. Deposits of natural gas (the only mineral resource of any size) meet much of the country's energy needs. <br />
<br />
Service industries are also important, representing 70% of the economy, notably transport through the world's busiest container port at Rotterdam. The Netherlands has derived substantial benefits from its membership of the EU, with whose members the bulk of its trade takes place. It has generally been a strong proponent of further economic integration within Europe and joined the Eurozone upon its inception in 1999.<br />
The largest conference and exhibition centres are RAI in Amsterdam ( <a href="http://www.rai.nl/" target="_blank">www.rai.nl</a>), the Jaarbeurs centre in Utrecht (<a href="https://www.jaarbeurs.nl" target="_blank">www.jaarbeurs.nl</a>), MECC in Maastricht (<a href="http://www.mecc.nl/" target="_blank">www.mecc.nl</a>), and Ahoy in Rotterdam (<a href="https://www.ahoy.nl" target="_blank">www.ahoy.nl</a>). There are numerous hotels offering conventions and meetings facilities, and The Netherlands is well supplied with 'unique' venues, such as Eindhoven's Evoluon (<a href="http://www.evoluon.com/" target="_blank">www.evoluon.com</a>) and Corpus (<a href="https://corpusexperience.nl" target="_blank">corpusexperience.nl</a>) at Leiden.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Dutch are known for directness in business - they like to cut to the heart of the matter. Appointments are necessary and promptness is expected. The Dutch expect a certain standard of dress for business occasions. Following introduction, business cards are exchanged. Don't use first names with associates unless first asked to do so. Best months for business visits are March to May and September to November.<br />
<br />
Practical information can be obtained from Holland Trade and Invest (tel: (088) 602 80 60; <a href="https://www.hollandtradeandinvest.com" target="_blank">www.hollandtradeandinvest.com</a>). The majority of Dutch businesspeople speak extremely good English, and promotional literature can be disseminated in English. However, interpreters can be booked through Congrestolken (tel: (020) 625 2535; <a href="http://congrestolken.nl" target="_blank">congrestolken.nl</a>). <br />
<br />
Alternatively, they can be booked through The Netherlands Chamber of Commerce in the country of departure. There are also many secretarial agencies in The Netherlands which are able to supply short-term help to visiting business travellers. The principal venue for trade fairs is the RAI Exhibition Centre in Amsterdam (<a href="http://www.rai.nl/" target="_blank">www.rai.nl</a>).</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>The Netherlands Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 088585 15 85.
					Website:http://www.kvk.nl/
					Address: ,Koninginnegracht 13,The Hague,2514 AA]]><b>The Netherlands British Chamber of Commerce in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: +44 (0)3333 44 07 99.
					Website:http://www.nbcc.co.uk/
					Address: ,8 Northumberland Avenue,London ,WC2N 5BY]]><b>The Netherlands Chamber of Commerce in the USA</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (212) 265 6460
					Website:http://netherlands.org/
					Address: ,535 Fifth Avenue,New York City,NY 10017]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>'Typical' Dutch food tends to be wholesome and hearty, rather than elegant. Large towns, however, have a wide range of restaurants specialising in international dishes. In fact, The Netherlands boasts with more than 100 Michelin-starred restaurants. Indonesian cuisine, a spicy legacy of Dutch colonisation in the East Indies, is particularly good in the Netherlands.</p>
<p>A Dutch breakfast usually consists of fresh bread, cheese, sausage, butter and <em>hagelslag</em> (chocolate sprinkles), jam and often a boiled egg, along with a cup of strong coffee. Lunch is a rapid affair, such as <em>broodjes</em> (sandwiches). Dinner, eaten between 1800 and 1900, is a more substantial meal, usually some combination of meat or fish with potatoes and veggies.   Holland is famous for its cheeses, available in<em> jonge</em> (young), <em>belegen</em> (mature) and <em>oude</em> (old) versions; the last tends to be the crumbliest and earthiest.   Beer is good, with pilsener-style lagers the most popular. <em>Jenever</em>, aka Dutch gin, flavored with juniper berries and served chilled, is usually knocked back in a single go.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Vlaamse frites</em> (French fries, though literally translated as Flemish fries) is a popular snack, customarily served with a gob of mayonnaise, though curry or peanut sauce make more exciting toppings.</p>
<p>&bull; <em>Erwtensoep</em>, thick pea soup flavored with sausage, makes a filling repast; some version of it is often served by the local pub in winter.</p>
<p>&bull; <em>Poffertjes</em> - tiny pancakes often laced with Grand Marnier and dusted with confectioners sugar--are a teatime favourite.</p>
<p>&bull; Herring fillets are widely available from street stalls and accompanied by pickles and onions; smoked eel (<em>gerookte paling</em>) is another seafood speciality.</p>
<p>&bull; <em>Stamppot</em> is a hearty, traditional mash-up of potatoes with endive, turnips or some other earthy vegetable, customarily accompanied by smoked sausage.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>All hotels and restaurants include 15% service and VAT. It is customary to leave small change when paying a bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>16 to drink beer and wine, 18 to drink spirits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Dutch like to have fun, and have a reputation for an open-minded approach, so a night out in The Netherlands can be something of an eye-opener for the first time visitor. Large cities are well-supplied with sophisticated nightclubs and discos, but the late-opening bars and cafes are just as popular. There are no official licensing hours, so it is possible in the big cities to get a drink more or less at any time.<br />
<br />
There are theatres and cinemas in all major towns - the arts are popular in Holland and play a big role in life.  Amsterdam is a cosmopolitan city, with some of the liveliest nightlife in Europe. The brown cafes are an institution - Holland's equivalent of the local pub. Its famous (or infamous) red light district, <em>de Wallen</em>, is a magnet for visitors, and there are numerous bars, clubs and 'coffee' shops (for those in search of a different sort of stimulant, namely marijuana) in the vicinity. Interestingly, although tobacco smoking is now banned in enclosed public spaces, joints rolled purely with marijuana can still be consumed in these places, which are also evident in most other Dutch cities.<br />
<br />
Rotterdam has an excellent selection of nightclubs, and a lively harbourside caf&eacute; and restaurant scene, while The Hague leans heavily on theatre and dance. University city Utrecht offers a large casino and the lively nightlife scene associated with a large student population.<br />
<br />
Another popular option is a dinner cruise through the canals and harbour aboard a glass-topped boat. There are legal casinos in several main towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases include Delft blue pottery; earthenware from Makkum and Workum, both in Friesland; silverware from Schoonhoven; cheese from Gouda and Edam; glass and crystal from Leerdam; and diamonds from Amsterdam. Items that show up all over the place include porcelain costume dolls, <em>Jenever</em> (Dutch gin), miniature windmills, and, of course, wooden clogs (blank or painted).</p><p>Mon 1200-1800, Tues-Fri 0900-1800 and Sat 0900-1700. In Amsterdam, Rotterdam and other big cities, supermarkets are open 0800-2000/2100. In large city centres, shops are open Sunday 1200-1700. In many towns, there's evening shopping till 2100 on Thursday or Friday and stores open on the first Sunday of the month.</p><p>Bulbs and plants may not be exported except by commercial growers, or by individuals with a health certificate from the Plant Disease Service. A reasonable number of bulbs for personal use are allowed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Netherlands has a wide range of accommodation, from luxury hotels in the big cities to modern motels along motorways and holiday villages in the countryside. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Netherlands has a unique and extensive network of B&amp;Bs for two-wheeled travellers,  run by the organization <em>Vrienden op de Fiets</em> (<a href="http://www.vriendenopdefiets.nl" target="_blank">www.vriendenopdefiets.nl</a>). Arrangements are widely varied, from luxurious homes to city apartments to refurbished camper vans in the yard. For the annual membership fee of &euro;8 (plus &euro;10 for non-Europeans), you get a directory of homes, located wherever there's a bike path (in other words, everywhere) and a membership card, which you must present on arrival. Members stay for &euro;19 per night per person, which includes a Dutch breakfast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Netherlands has a wide range of accommodation, from luxury hotels in the big cities to modern motels along motorways and holiday villages in the countryside. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Netherlands has a wide range of accommodation, from luxury hotels in the big cities to modern motels along motorways and holiday villages in the countryside. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading</strong>: There is the Hotelstars Union grading system from 1 to 5 stars.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;In the event of an emergency during your visit to The Netherlands, dial 112. EU residents are entitled to free or reduced-cost treatment providing they have a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC), which can be obtained free of charge via &lt;a href="http://www.ehic.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.ehic.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Travellers from other countries should find out if they are covered by other reciprocal arrangements. Australia, for example, has such an agreement as long as long as citizens carry their Medicare card. Comprehensive insurance is advised for all other nationals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dutch hospitals are of a very high standard, and staff at local pharmacies are trained to be able to advise on minor complaints.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;According to Oxfam, The Netherlands is the best country in the world for having the most plentiful, nutritious, healthy and affordable diet. Suffice to say, then, travellers couldn't be in a better place as far as food quality and hygiene is concerned. As in most developed nations, tap water in The Netherlands is safe to drink.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;People visiting The Netherlands have a low risk of contracting diseases, but medical professionals advise travellers to make sure they are up-to-date on routine vaccinations before every trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis A and B are present around the world and can be transmitted through contaminated food, sexual contact and contaminated needles. Speak to your doctor to see if vaccinations are right for you. Rabies is present in bats in The Netherlands, but is not found in dogs. If you are planning to go caving in The Netherlands or work with bats, it may be worth having a rabies vaccination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the biggest health risk in The Netherlands is that of sunburn. It might not always feel hot during the summer months, but the UV rays are still strong - be sure to pack plenty of sunscreen and make sure you stay hydrated.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Queen's Day :
							30 April </p><p>Liberation Day :
							05 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Netherlands is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragrance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes</p>
<p>&bull;&nbsp;400 cigarillos</p>
<p>&bull;&nbsp;200 cigars</p>
<p>&bull;&nbsp;1kg of tobacco</p>
<p>&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% volume,</p>
<p>&bull;&nbsp;20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume</p>
<p>&bull;&nbsp;90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine)</p>
<p>&bull;&nbsp;110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into the Netherlands&nbsp;by persons 17 years of age and older without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 or &euro;300 if arriving by private aircraft or yacht.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Counterfeit goods, endangered plant and animal species, arms and ammunition, narcotics, antiques without an export permit from the country of origin, and uncertified plants, meat and dairy products from outside the EU.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Counterfeit goods, uncertified plant and animal products, endangered plant and animal species, arms and ammunition, and unlicensed cultural artefacts.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol &euro;) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money exchange is possible at banks, post offices, at many hotels and at exchange offices. Exchange offices are indicated by the letters GWK. GWK is a national organisation with currency exchange offices at major railway stations, at Schiphol Airport and at the border crossings with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belgium">Belgium</a>. Hotels tend to charge high commissions. <em>Verkoop</em> means sell, while <em>Koop </em>means buy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted.&nbsp;</p><p>ATMs are widely available. ATMs accept bank cards with a Cirrus logo, some ATMs also accept cards with the PLUS logo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700. Only major banks are open on Saturdays. GWK Travelex offices are open seven days a week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Some countries like France and Austria have reintroduced border controls. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors from some countries not listed above do require a transit visa; check with the embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Netherlands is part of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60/&pound;53. Reductions are available for some nationals and for children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications must be made in person at the relevant embassy/consulate. UK residents requiring visas should apply to the Netherlands Visa Application Centre (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/Netherlands/UK" target="_blank">www.vfsglobal.com/Netherlands/UK</a>), which charges an additional fee of &pound;23.68. All visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow up to 15 days for visa processing. Applications which require further enquiry may take up to two months however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa applicants must show proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EU nationals staying longer than three months must register with the Immigration and Naturalisation Service (<a href="https://www.ind.nl" target="_blank">www.ind.nl</a>). Non-EU nationals must apply for a residence permit if staying beyond three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet from another EU country, your animal requires a pet passport, microchip and rabies vaccination certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[52.342008]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[5.527998]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>41,543 sq km (16,039 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>17,020,000 (2016 World Bank).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>488 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amsterdam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Netherlands shares borders to the south with Belgium and to the east with Germany, while the North Sea lies to the north and west. Large areas of The Netherlands have been reclaimed from the sea and consequently one-fifth of the country lies below sea level. The country is flat and level and is criss-crossed by rivers and canals.</p>
<p>Areas reclaimed from the sea, known as <em>polders</em>, are extremely fertile. The landscape is broken by the forest of Arnhem, the bulb fields in the west, the lakes of the central and northern areas, and coastal dunes that are among the most impressive in Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>24% Roman Catholic, 6.7% Dutch Reformed Church, 6% Calvinist, 4.9% Muslim, 42% other religions or none.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Dutch are a tolerant breed and there is little you can do or say to ruffle them (except perhaps to display your own intolerance of, say, ethnic minorities or alternative lifestyles). Their straightforwardness can sometimes strike foreigners as blunt, if not plain rude. Conversely, the Dutch will expect you to be direct as well: yes means yes, not 'maybe.'</p>
<p>It is customary to shake hands when seeing someone you know or when being introduced to someone; women and men or women and women may kiss each other on alternating cheeks three times. You may be fashionably late for social gatherings but not for business meetings. Casual wear is generally acceptable, except for business functions or at smart restaurants, bars and clubs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Mark Rutte since 2010.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Willem-Alexander since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Netherlands&rsquo; position at the threshold of the sea has historically been both a blessing and a curse. From its earliest settlement, inhabitants made efforts to keep their heads above water, as remains evident from the artificial mounds they constructed along the coast of Friesland. In modern times, vast public works projects have been undertaken, such as the Delta Project, built to protect the province of Zeeland after major floods in 1953. But the country has also taken advantage of its position and prospered from its overseas trade. Much of its productive farmland stands upon lands reclaimed from the seabed.<br />
<br />
Defenceless against the onslaught of foreign powers in its nascent stages, the Netherlands was ruled by a succession of overlords. The forts of Nijmegen and Maastricht are evidence of Roman domination at the start of Christian era. During feudal times, the Franks took over, then the Holy Roman Empire. In the Middle Ages some measure of independence emerged under the Dukes of Burgundy and the region began to prosper from a thriving cloth industry.<br />
<br />
Conflict erupted in the 16th century as Spain wielded its imperial power to suppress the rise of Protestantism in the northern provinces. Allying with the Catholic provinces to the south, Holland revolted against the Spanish and declared independence in 1588. A period of economic prosperity and cultural flowering ensued in the 17th century now recognised as Holland&rsquo;s golden age. During this period, the country became a colonial power in Asia, Africa, the Caribbean and South America while the settlement of New Amsterdam in 1625 established a beachhead in North America. Concurrently, shipbuilding and related industries flourished. Wars with England over control of sea trade checked Holland&rsquo;s ascendance, and France annexed the country in 1795. After the defeat of Napoleon at Waterloo, Prince William I of Orange became king and the 17 northern and southern provinces of the Netherlands reunited only to be severed again in 1830, as Belgium declared independence.<br />
<br />
The 19th century saw a shift to an industrialised society. The country managed to stay out of World War 1, but a few decades later succumbed to the onslaught of the Nazis, who systematically decimated Holland&rsquo;s Jewish population. After World War 2, the Netherlands developed a progressive social welfare system and saw major migration from Morocco, Turkey and the former Dutch colonies of Surinam and the Antilles as a response to labour shortages.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; The World Happiness Report ranks the Netherlands the sixth happiest nation in the world.</p>
<p>&bull; The age of the Dutch Masters in the 17th century produced many painters including Rembrandt and Vermeer.</p>
<p>&bull; Famed Dutch actors include Rutger Hauer, Michael Huisman (<em>Game of Thrones</em>) and Famke Janssen.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Royal Netherlands Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7590 3200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.netherlandsandyou.nl/your-country-and-the-netherlands/united-kingdom</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7590 3200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; consular section: Mon-Fri 0830-1200 and 1330-1530 (by appointment only). Closed first and third Wednesday of every month.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>38 Hyde Park Gate<br/>London<br/>SW7 5DP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Royal Netherlands Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 244 53 00.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://dc.the-netherlands.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 244 53 00.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Embassy: Mon-Fri 0830-1630; consular and visa section: Tue-Fri 0850-1230 (by appointment only).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>4200 Linnean Avenue NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in the Netherlands]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+31 (0)70 427 0427</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/netherlands</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+31 (0)70 427 0427</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Currently not open to the public.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Lange Voorhout 10<br/>The Hague<br/>2514 ED<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As flat as a local <em>pannenkoek</em>, the Netherlands is a land of colourful tulip fields and canals, sophisticated cities and some of the most striking coastline in Northern Europe. It punches well above its weight culturally, laying claim to the likes of Van Gogh, Rembrandt and Mondrian, amongst others.</p>
<p>At the head of the state sits the country's constitutional monarchy, whose palaces dominate many of the larger cities, including The Hague and the capital city, Amsterdam. The latter, renowned for its step-gabled houses, ubiquitous bikes, seedy red light district and hazy coffeeshops, is bisected by a UNESCO-listed network of waterways, many of which are spanned by beautiful, latticed bridges.</p>
<p>To the south lies Rotterdam, an industrial port city that has benefitted from a complete makeover in recent years, acquiring a slew of excellent museums and an unlikely affinity for hip-hop in the process.</p>
<p>The butt of many a northern joke, the southern city of Maastricht lies in the much-maligned Limburg region. Despite the teasing, this is a city of delicate beauty, dotted with churches, bisected by a mighty river and home to what is almost certainly the best bookshop in the world, Selexyz Dominicanen.</p>
<p>Back towards the coast, the Netherlands becomes more stereotypically Dutch, with vast colourful fields of tulips dotted with windmills and dairy farms producing the wheels of cheese for which the country is so famous. The low-lying Dutch countryside is scattered with a network of charming towns and villages such as Edam, Haarlem and Leiden, which have changed little over the centuries.</p>
<p>Best of all though, are the sandy, North Sea beaches of Zeeland, which stretch for an almost unbroken 650km (403-miles). With more sunshine than any other part of the Netherlands, Zeeland is the Dutch riposte to the Caribbean &ndash; and with better cycling trails and museums, if not the hot weather, to boot.</p><p>As flat as a local <em>pannenkoek</em>, the Netherlands is a land of colourful tulip fields and canals, sophisticated cities and some of the most striking coastline in Northern Europe. It punches well above its weight culturally, laying claim to the likes of Van Gogh, Rembrandt and Mondrian, among others.</p>
<p>At the head of the state sits the country's constitutional monarchy, whose palaces dominate many of the larger cities, including The Hague and the capital city, Amsterdam. The latter, renowned for its step-gabled houses, ubiquitous bikes, seedy red light district and hazy coffeeshops, is bisected by a UNESCO-listed network of waterways, many of which are spanned by beautiful, latticed bridges.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
