<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="New Caledonia" ColCode="ncl" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="nc" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[New Caledonia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is generally warm and subtropical. The cool season runs from April to August whilst the hottest period is from September to March. The main rains are between January and March. The seasons are less defined on the east coast than the west. Climate is tempered by trade winds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical lightweights, with jackets and sweatshirts for evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Domestic flights are run by Air Cal&eacute;donie<em>&nbsp;</em>(<a href="http://www.air-caledonie.nc" target="_blank">www.air-caledonie.nc</a>), with regular services from Noum&eacute;a to airfields on the island, and the other smaller islands. The principal local airport is Magenta Airport, 6km (4 miles) from Noum&eacute;a city centre. From here, Air Cal&eacute;donie operates regular flights to Touho (east coast), Kon&eacute;, Koumac, Belep (west coast), and to the neighbouring Ile des Pins and the Loyalty Islands: Mar&eacute;, Ouv&eacute;a, Lifou and Tiga.</p>
<p>Light aircraft and helicopters are available from Air Aliz&eacute;<em> </em>(<a href="http://www.airalize.com/" target="_blank">www.airalize.com</a>), Air Loyaut&eacute;<em>&nbsp;</em>(<a href="http://www.air-loyaute.nc/" target="_blank">www.air-loyaute.nc</a>), H&eacute;licoc&eacute;an<em> </em>and<em> </em>Helisud (<a href="http://www.helisud.nc" target="_blank">www.helisud.nc</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An inter-island, high-speed catamaran, 'Betico', runs regularly to Ile des Pins and Loyalty Islands from Grande Terre (<a href="http://reservation.betico.nc" target="_blank">reservation.betico.nc</a>).&nbsp;Boats can be hired or chartered to visit smaller islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The road network consists of 5,000km (3,125 miles) of paved and unpaved roads.</p>r<p>RAI (tel: +687 277 766;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.rai.nc" target="_blank">www.rai.nc</a>) operates a fleet of modern coaches between towns in New Caledonia.</p><p>Charges are for time and distance. There is a surcharge after 1900 and on Sundays.</p><p>International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>International and local companies all have representatives in the capital. Drivers must be aged 21 or over (in some cases, 25 or over).</p><p>You can hire bikes, motorbikes and scooters.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Karuia Bus (<a href="http://www.karuiabus.nc" target="_blank">www.karuiabus.nc</a>) runs public buses in the capital. You can buy tickets from the driver or save money by purchasing them in advance from vending machines or sales outlets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">touhoacute</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tontouta</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tiga</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1 hour 25 minutes*</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">thio</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">poindimie</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ouveacutea</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">40 minutes</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">mareacute</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">40 minutes</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">lifou</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">40 minutes</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">koumac</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1 hour five minutes</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">koneacute</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">iledes_pins</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">25 minutes</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">hienghene</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bourail</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Caledonia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">belep</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1 hour 45 minutes*</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Aircalin&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.aircalin.nc/" target="_blank">www.aircalin.nc</a>). British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) flies from the UK to Tokyo and Sydney; from either city, you can catch a connecting flight to New Caledonia with Aircalin.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 23 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 29 hours (including stopovers).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Nouméa - La Tontouta International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.tontouta-aeroport.nc<p>The airport  is 50km (31 miles) from the city (journey time - 45 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The international port is Noum&eacute;a, served by various shipping lines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There is a 24-hour service for international calls. International calls are bookable at the post office or through hotels. Most hotels have direct dial facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies companies including Telstra, Optus and Vodafone Australia. However it may be easier to buy a carte liberte from any local post office – this gives you a prepaid SIM card to make national and international calls. The card is valid for 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public access is available in several internet cafes and at cyber points (computers available for public use in local businesses/ISPs).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Media operates relatively freely.<em> Les Nouvelles Cal&eacute;doniennes </em>is a French-language daily. <em>L</em>'<em>Hebdo</em>, <em>Les Infos</em> and <em>T&eacute;l&eacute; 7 Jours</em> are French-language weeklies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The New Caledonia Post and Telecommunications Office (OPT) has approximately 50 branches throughout the island, providing postal and banking services. The main post office, located on rue Eugène Porcheron, is open Mon-Fri 0745-1115 and 1215-1530. Airmail take around four days to get to Australia and New Zealand; one week to get to Europe.</p><p>The post office, located on rue Eugène Porcheron, is open Mon-Fri 0745-1115 and 1215-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire Amedée's towering lighthouse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the tallest in the world, Amedée Lighthouse was constructed in Paris during the reign of Napoleon III to prevent ships wrecking on the reef. Once completed in France, the iron tower was shipped to this coral reef in pieces. Visitors can climb the 247 steps to enjoy sweeping views.</p>]]><p><b>Cast off on a fishing expedition</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax on a fishing expedition. The coral barrier reef off Nouméa is excellent for underwater spearfishing, as are waters around the Loyalty Islands. Ouvéa Island's lagoon is rich in fish including the chance to catch a giant trevally. The main location for freshwater fishing is Yaté Lake, open January to October.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the tranquil Ile des Pins</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Venture over to the Ile des Pins, discovered by Captain Cook in 1774, and lying 70km (45 miles) off Grande Terre. This exceedingly beautiful island has many white sand beaches, turquoise lagoons, lush rainforests, pines, orchids and ferns not to mention archaeological remains. Day trips are available from Nouméa.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the visually dramatic east coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hienghéne has a striking lagoon surrounded by 120m-high (400ft) black cliffs. The region is dotted with churches and Melanesian villages, forests, coconut palms and beautiful beaches. At the southern point of this coast is Yaté, a village surrounded by lakes, waterfalls and rich wooded countryside.</p>]]><p><b>Kayak the largest lagoon in the world</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Surrounded by a coral reef barrier 1,600km (994 miles) long, New Caledonia boasts the largest lagoon in the world. With excellent swimming and scuba diving, the most exciting way to explore is by kayak. H2O Odyssee in Nouméa offer four-day trips along the Forgotten Coast (Côte Oubliée) and reach land only accessible by paddle.</p>]]><p><b>Saddle up and go horse riding</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Horseback excursions are an excellent way to see the best of Grande Terre from simple pony rides to major expeditions crossing the mountain range, mustering cattle and camping in the mountains. Guided tours can be organised from Nouméa, Dumbea, La Foa, Bourail, Thio and the Koné villages. </p>]]><p><b>See humpback whales in the southern lagoon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go whale watching in New Caledonia's southern lagoon. Mating season for humpback whales begins in mid-July and the great creatures can still be spotted come September. During this time catamaran and cruise boat excursions cast off from Nouméa, whilst the massive mammals can be glimpsed near the Loyalty Islands at Lifou.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out submerged ships with wreck diving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy some superb snorkelling, diving in marine reserves and around sunken shipwrecks. Favourite sites include the bays off Nouméa, the Amédée Lighthouse Reserve (including shark feeding), La Dieppoise (Royal Navy shipwreck), Ilot Maître and the peaceful Prony Needle, whilst the Tenia Horn, the Fault and the Hienghene Reef are all waiting to be discovered.</p>]]><p><b>Tackle the trade winds with a windsurf board</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try your hand at windsurfing. The Bay of Anse Vata and Côte Blanche, both in Nouméa, are the most popular locations. With trade winds averaging between 20-40km (12-25mph), conditions are ideal for both beginners and the more assured, whilst international competitions attract some of the world's best windsurfers and make for exhilarating shoreline viewing.</p>]]><p><b>Take a stroll around Nouméa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Grande Terre's busy little capital Nouméa, which overlooks one of the world's largest sheltered natural harbours. It's home to attractive squares, a cathedral, museums, a market, many old colonial houses and Aquarium des Lagons, one of the world's leading centres of coral reef scientific research.</p>]]><p><b>Take a traditional boat out to sea</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take to the water and explore the world's largest lagoon. Excursions in a traditional Melanesian outrigger canoes can be organised at the Ile des Pins, whilst sailing boats can be chartered with or without a skipper. New Caledonia's fantastic coral reefs are best goggled at through a glass-bottomed boats. </p>]]><p><b>Take in spectacular panoramas at Mont-Dore</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Soak up some scenery at Mont-Dore, a mountain surrounded by magnificent coastal views. On the way, stop at the Melanesian village of St Louis and the Plum Lookout for a spectacular vista across the surrounding reef. Also in the south, Blue River Provincial Park is well worth a visit for its breath-taking landscape.</p>]]><p><b>Tread a trail through Grande Terre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Strike out on a hiking trip across Grande Terre. Starting in Prony, the Grande Randonnée trail heads north and takes in some of the country's most sublime scenery, before finishing in Dumbéa. At over 100km (62 miles), the well-marked trek is split into eight connecting hikes that can be enjoyed separately or as one walk over several days.</p>]]><p><b>Uncover New Caledonia's rich culture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For a cultural fix, visit Nouméa's South Pacific Commission Building and New Caledonia Museum to see a collection of native handicrafts; try the Museum of Maritime History for artefacts from numerous local wrecks; and the Tjibaou Cultural Centre for concerts, plays and exhibitions celebrating indigenous culture.</p>]]><p><b>Wind along the west coast beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the pure white sand beaches, rainforest and offshore atolls of the west coast. There are elaborate and beautiful caves and rock formations shaped by Pacific breakers at Bourail, whilst further north is Koné, an important archaeological site following the discovery of ancient Lapita pottery believed to have its origins between 2000 and 1000 BC.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$8.8 billion (2007).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Ferronickels, nickel ore and fish.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, fuels, chemicals and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Japan, Singapore, Australia and Taiwan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The mainstays of the country's economy are mining, tourism and, to a lesser degree, agriculture and fishing. The agricultural sector produces cereals, fruit and vegetables, as well as copra and coffee for export. The fishing industry trawls primarily for shrimp and tuna, the bulk of which is sold to Japan.<br /><br />A small light-industrial sector has grown up in the last two decades, producing building materials, furniture and processed foods, largely for domestic consumption. In the mining sector, New Caledonia is the world's largest producer of nickel after Canada and the USA, and has about one-quarter of the world's known deposits; this generates 90% of the country's export revenue. There are also deposits of cobalt, iron, manganese, lead and zinc.<br /><br />Tourism is the major service industry and remains the most dynamic sector in terms of economic development. <br /><br />Subventions from France are essential to the territory's economic wellbeing. And, by virtue of its link with France, New Caledonia is an Associate Member of the EU.<br />Conferences and conventions take place at major hotels such as Le Meridien, Park Hotel and Novotel Surf Nouméa, as well as at the Chamber of Commerce, the Tjibaou Cultural Centre and the South Pacific Commission, all situated in Nouméa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Appointments should be made. Businesspeople generally work long hours and take long lunch breaks, but business lunches are rare as most businesspeople go home at lunchtime. Prices should be quoted in Euros or French Pacific Francs. The best time to visit is May to October.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1130 and 1330-1730; Sat 0730-1130.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 243 100
					Website:http://www.cci.nc
					Address: 15 rue de Verdun,BP M3,98849 Nouméa Cédex,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The choice of eating places and food on New Caledonia is excellent; costs vary from moderate to expensive. In Nouméa, choose from street stalls serving local cuisine to gourmet restaurants and bistros serving up an international feast - African, Chinese, French, Indonesian, Italian and Spanish cooking can all be found here.  Eating out in other areas such is generally confined to hotel restaurants and snack bars.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Pacific spiny lobsters, prawns, crabs.<br />
&bull; Mangrove oysters. <br />
&bull; Salads of raw fish marinated in lime juice.<br />
&bull; <em>Bougna</em> (fish or chicken wrapped in banana leaves and cooked on hot stones covered with sand).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>There is no tipping.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Early evening marks the start of Happy Hour, which generally takes place between 1700 and 1830 in Noum&eacute;a&rsquo;s various karaoke and piano bars. There are plenty of discos and a few casinos situated in the Anse Vata and the Baie des Citrons areas. Nightclubs in Noum&eacute;a are lively with both European and local floorshows and music is a pulsating mixture of Pacific and international rhythms. For a less strenuous night out there are also several cinemas, which show French films.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Caledonia has the best shopping in the South Pacific if you're looking for designer goods as many of the brands aren't available on other islands in the Pacific. In Noum&eacute;a, boutiques sell fashionable French clothes, mainly casual but sometimes haute couture. Other purchases include luxury French goods such as perfume, jewellery and footwear, and silk scarves, sandals and handbags from France and Italy can also be found. Duty-free items are also sold. Local items include curios made of shells, coral, woodcarving, ceramics, hand-painted materials and aloha shirts.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1100 and 1400-1800, Sat 0730-1100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels are mostly small and intimate. Prices range from moderate to expensive. Modern 3- and 5-star hotels have been built or fully renovated in the Anse Vata area and there is also bungalow-style accommodation in more remote parts of the main island and the outer islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels are mostly small and intimate. Prices range from moderate to expensive. Modern 3- and 5-star hotels have been built or fully renovated in the Anse Vata area and there is also bungalow-style accommodation in more remote parts of the main island and the outer islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels are mostly small and intimate. Prices range from moderate to expensive. Modern 3- and 5-star hotels have been built or fully renovated in the Anse Vata area and there is also bungalow-style accommodation in more remote parts of the main island and the outer islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;New Caledonia offers a wide range of efficient medical services in both public and private hospitals, and an adequate selection of chemists. Hotels can generally recommend an English-speaking doctor or dentist. However more serious cases may require evacuation to France or Australia. Health insurance is advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and generally regarded as safe to drink. Bottled water is available and is advised for the first few weeks of the stay. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							08 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Bastille Day :
							14 July </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>French Treaty Day :
							24 September </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Armistice Day :
							11 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>New Year's Eve :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into New Caledonia by travellers aged 17 or over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of table wine and 1L of spirits over 22% volume, or 2L of fortified wine less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; 50ml of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; 500g of coffee and 100g of tea.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of XPF30,000 (reduced to XPF15,000 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include narcotics and counterfeit goods.</p>
<p>Restricted items include plants, animals and their products, endangered species, arms and ammunition, and medicines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics and counterfeit goods.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>French Pacific Franc (CPF). Notes are in denominations of XPF10,000, 5,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of XPF100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1.<br />
<br />
New Caledonia is part of the French Monetary Area. Australian and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand">New Zealand</a> dollars are widely accepted in shops, hotels and restaurants. The French Pacific Franc is tied to the Euro. For further details on the Euro, see <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> section.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchange facilities are available at the airport and at main branches of banks, but may charge a steep commission. However, Euro exchange is in theory free from commission.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express and Visa are widely accepted; Diners Club and MasterCard have more limited use. ATMs are available in Nouméa, but sometimes have a maximum weekly withdrawal limit.</p><p>ATMs are available in Nouméa, but sometimes have a maximum weekly withdrawal limit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros. There is, however, a charge for each transaction.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0730-1545.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter New Caledonia, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by EU nationals and for three months by&nbsp;all other nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Caledonia is not part of the Schengen area. You can only visit on a Schengen visa if it is clearly marked on your visa sticker, so be sure to advise the consulate in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay visa: &euro;9; long-stay visa: &euro;99.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay visa: up to three months; long-stay visa: for visits longer than three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>French Consulate (or consular section at embassy). In the UK, the consulate has outsourced the visa application process to TLScontact (<a href="http://www.tlscontact.com/gb2fr" target="_blank">www.tlscontact.com/gb2fr</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 15 working days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Any visitor to New Caledonia may be asked for proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay. Visa applicants must show a recent bank statement when applying.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EU nationals (other than French citizens) can only extend their stay beyond three months with special permission from the local authorities; they do not have the right of abode or the right to work in New Caledonia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-20.992023]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[165.018956]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>18,575 sq km (7,172 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>266,431 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>14.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Noum&eacute;a.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>French Overseas Territory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Caledonia consists of 400km-long (249 miles) mainland Grande Terre, the Ile des Pins (Isle of Pines) to the south, the Loyalty Islands to the east (Mar&eacute;, Lifou, Tiga and Ouv&eacute;a), the Belep Archipelago in the northwest, and numerous islands and islets (Huon &amp; Surprise, Christfield, Walpole, Beaut&eacute;mps-Beaupr&eacute;, Astrolabe and the Bellona reef).</p>
<p>Grande Terre is divided by a range of mountains (Ch&acirc;ine Centrale), the highest points of which are Mount Panc&eacute; in the north (1,629m/5,344ft) and Mount Humboldt in the south (1,618m/5,308ft). Various species of trees can be found here. This unusual relief divides Grande Terre into the East coast which is humid and open to trade winds, fertile and exotic with lush tropical vegetation, and the West coast which is dry and temperate, filled with niaouli trees, cattle and beautiful beaches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vast Christian majority, with 59% Roman Catholic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a casual atmosphere, and local traditions still prevail alongside European customs. Casual wear is the norm, but smart restaurants require a more formal style of dress. Long trousers are required for men at night in restaurants and casinos.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President of the government Philippe Germain since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Emmanuel Macron since 2017, represented locally by High Commissioner Thierry Lataste &nbsp; since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Discovered and named by explorer Captain James Cook (it&rsquo;s said the terrain reminded him of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom/scotland">Scotland</a>) in 1776, the island of New Caledonia became a French colony in 1853 and a French Overseas Territory in 1946. The indigenous population has attempted to free themselves from French rule on several occasions, including the Kanak Revolt of 1878.  </p>
<p>In recent years, intermittent conflicts between the Melanesians and the French have occurred, and majority of Kanaks (Melanesians) now support the <em>Front de Liberation Nationale Kanak et Socialiste</em> (National Kanak Socialist Liberation Front, FLNKS) created in 1984 and led, until his assassination in 1989, by the charismatic Jean-Marie Tjibaou. The Front is the largest party backing independence, which remains the overriding political issue in the territory. In 2014 a referendum is scheduled which may finally see New Caledonia devolve from French rule. </p>
<p>New Caledonia is an incredibly important hotspot for biological diversity in because of its unique and complex ecological systems. Unlike its neighbours it is not volcanic, but a fragment of an ancient continent that drifted away some 250 million years ago. As such its flora and fauna have evolved in isolation, and are now quite unique. A wide variety of endemic species have flourished here.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[French Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7073 1000. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambafrance-uk.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7073 1000. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>58 Knightsbridge<br/>London<br/>SW1X 7JT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[French Embassy in the USA ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 944 6000. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambafrance-us.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 944 6000. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Visa appointments are available Mon-Fri 0845-1200. Appointments can be booked online.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>4101 Reservoir Road NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Pacific island of New Caledonia is a nature lover&rsquo;s paradise. Punching well above its weight, the island lays claim to impressive natural features including the largest lagoon in the world and a 1,500km-long (930 mile) coral reef, second only in size to Australia&rsquo;s Great Barrier Reef.</p>
<p>Inscribed as a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 2008, New Caledonia&rsquo;s vast coral reef offers some of the most spectacular diving in the world. Not only is it an important nesting site for green turtles, but it also supports an astonishing variety of tropical fish, seabirds, sharks, whales and dugongs, also known as sea cows.</p>
<p>Visitors will find an equally diverse mix of wildlife inland. New Caledonia is famed for its flying foxes and myriad exotic birds, including the highly intelligent Caledonian crow, which fashions hooks from branches to pick its insect prey from trees.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not all about the wildlife, though. This former French colony, which is now classed as a special collectivity of France, is a fascinating melting pot of Melanesian and French culture. This unlikely fusion is most visible in the capital, Noum&eacute;a, where luxury hotels, gourmet restaurants and plush boutiques compete with Melanesian cuisine, dance and other local traditions.</p>
<p>This juxtaposition is not always harmonious however, and conflicts between France and New Caledonia sometimes flare up, reflecting their differing attitudes on self-government, French nuclear testing in the region and more. There&rsquo;s been an appetite for independence for sometime now and the territory seems to be slowly moving towards sovereign status. France will be the poorer for it.</p><p>The Pacific island of New Caledonia is a nature lover&rsquo;s paradise. Punching well above its weight, the island lays claim to impressive natural features including the largest lagoon in the world and a 1,500km-long (930 mile) coral reef, second only in size to Australia&rsquo;s Great Barrier Reef.</p>
<p>Inscribed as a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 2008, New Caledonia&rsquo;s vast coral reef offers some of the most spectacular diving in the world. Not only is it an important nesting site for green turtles, but it also supports an astonishing variety of tropical fish, seabirds, sharks, whales and dugongs, also known as sea cows.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
