<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="New Zealand" ColCode="nzl" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="nz" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ever since the Maori christened New Zealand &lsquo;The Land of the Long White Cloud&rsquo;, weather has featured in the minds of local people. Sat in the middle of the Roaring Forties (a region with strong westerly winds), New Zealand enjoys an ocean temperate climate, making it pleasant most of the year round with occasional periods of cool, rain and wind.</p>
<p>There is, however, a wide range of conditions from north to south, with subtropical weather in the north and more temperate conditions in the south. Generally, the north has no extremes of heat or cold; winter can be quite cool in the south, with snow in the mountains. The eastern areas often experience drought conditions in summer; the west, particularly in the South Island, has more rain.</p>
<p>New Zealand&rsquo;s seasons are directly opposite to those of the northern hemisphere although it&rsquo;s often possible to have all four represented in one day. Spring (September/October) is beautiful as new blooms emerge, yet the peaks stay snow-capped; summer (November to March) enjoys the best overall weather; autumn (March/April) is a time of spectacular colours, especially on the South Island; winters (April/May to August September) tend to be wet and cool. There's great winter skiing in the centre of the North Island and in the South Island's Southern Alps, where heli-skiing is particularly popular. The best time to visit, taking into account the climate, crowds and other conditions, is October/November or March/April. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are worn in the North Island most of the year and in summer in the South Island. Medium weights are worn during winter in South Island. Rainwear is advisable throughout the year, and essential if visiting South Island's rainforest areas. A hat and sunblock are essential during the summer thanks to the ozone depletion above New Zealand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Those with limited time to explore New Zealand can take advantage of the widespread network of internal flights to travel around more quickly. Air New Zealand (<a href="http://www.airnewzealand.co.nz" target="_blank">www.airnewzealand.co.nz</a>) and Jetstar (<a href="http://www.jetstar.com" target="_blank">www.jetstar.com</a>)&nbsp;operate domestic flights between the major airports.</p>
<p>Several smaller airlines, including Air Nelson and Mount Cook Airline, are wholly owned by Air New Zealand and are grouped together as Air New Zealand Link. They serve many of the smaller airports throughout the two islands.</p>
<p>Soundsair (<a href="http://www.soundsair.com" target="_blank">www.soundsair.com</a>) flies between Wellington and Picton daily (journey time - 25 minutes), allowing passengers to hop between the North and South Islands. Stewart Island Flights (<a href="http://www.stewartislandflights.com" target="_blank">www.stewartislandflights.com</a>) operate services between Invercargill and Stewart Island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The North and South Islands are linked by modern ferries operating between Wellington and Picton, carrying passengers and vehicles across the Cook Strait.&nbsp;Interislander (tel: 0800 802 802, in New Zealand; <a href="http://www.interislander.co.nz" target="_blank">www.interislander.co.nz</a>) (journey time - 3 hours 30 minutes) and Bluebridge (tel: +64 4 471 6188 ; <a href="http://www.bluebridge.co.nz" target="_blank">www.bluebridge.co.nz</a>) (journey time - 3 hours 30 minutes) ferries run all year.</p>
<p>Boat services operate between Auckland and the various islands in the Hauraki Gulf. A passenger ferry also sails between Bluff on the South Island and Oban on Stewart Island. Reservations on all ferry services are highly recommended, particularly if you're taking a vehicle.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand's passenger train service is limited to commuter trains in Auckland and Wellington and a handful of scenic routes aimed at tourists.</p>
<p>KiwiRail Scenic Journeys (tel: +64 4 495 0775 or 0800 872 467, in New Zealand only; <a href="http://www.kiwirailscenic.co.nz" target="_blank">www.kiwirailscenic.co.nz</a>) operates three scenic long-distance routes. The Northern Explorer runs between Auckland and Wellington with good views of forests, gorges and volcanic peaks. The Coastal Pacific runs between Christchurch and Picton (September to May only) along the east coast between the snow-capped Kaikoura Mountains and past the Kaikoura coast, which is famous for whale watching. Due<strong> </strong>to extensive damage to the track, the Coastal Pacific train has been suspended for the remainder of the 2017 season.<strong>&nbsp;</strong>The TranzAlpine runs between Christchurch and Greymouth through spectacular landscapes of gorges and river valleys and across the snow-capped Southern Alps.&nbsp;All services are one-class travel only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Scenic Rail Pass offers unlimited travel on KiwiRail trains available for seven, 14 or 21 days, and includes a journey on the Interislander ferry. Sale of all rail passes has been temporarily suspended due to recent earthquake damage to the Coastal Pacific network. For more information visit KiWiRail Scenic Journeys (http://www.kiwirailscenic.co.nz).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best way to explore New Zealand is by road, allowing you flexibility and the ability to travel at your own pace. There are a number of good value car and campervan hire options. Alternatively, for longer stays, consider buying your own vehicle for the duration of your trip.</p>l<p>Main roads are paved, but some quieter roads are not.</p><p>Bus and coach travel in New Zealand is straightforward and affordable, with services operating throughout the North and South Islands, connecting the main urban centres and popular rural areas. The largest national operator is Intercity (<a href="http://www.intercity.co.nz" target="_blank">www.intercity.co.nz</a>), which has main offices in Auckland, Wellington, Christchurch and Dunedin, and can take you just about everywhere. The company also runs a sightseeing arm, Newmans Coach Lines. There are also a number of smaller operators providing services linking destinations around the country.</p>
<p>There are no seat classes to choose from on coaches. Smoking is strictly prohibited on board.</p><p>There are metered taxis in urban areas throughout the country.</p><p>All international driving licences are recognised by New Zealand. If your licence isn't in English, you must bring an accurate translation. Motor insurance is not a legal requirement in New Zealand because New Zealand law has removed the right of accident victims to sue a third party in the event of an accident.</p><p>Drive on the left and give way to traffic crossing or appearing from the right. The speed limit is 100kph (62 mph) on the open road and 50kph (31mph) in built-up or urban areas. Signposting follows the standard international symbols and all distances are displayed in kilometres. Drivers and passengers are obliged to wear seatbelts in both the front and back of a car, while children under the age of five must be properly strapped into an approved child seat. Cyclists and motorbike riders must wear helmets when on the road.</p><p>AA (tel: 0800 500 222, in New Zealand; <a href="http://www.aa.co.nz" target="_blank">www.aa.co.nz</a>) operates emergency breakdown services.</p><p>Major international and local car hire firms have offices at airports and most major cities and towns. It&rsquo;s recommended to hire vehicles from members of Rental Vehicle Association New Zealand (www.rentalvehicle.co.nz).</p><p>Plenty of people set out to explore New Zealand by bicycle. The roads are generally good and the weather is pleasant for cycling. Although there are plenty of hills and some strenuous terrain to cross, there are also wide-open plains and easier sections through which to cruise. Popular scenic trails include the Hauraki Rail Trail, Redwoods Whakarewarewa Forest and Huka Falls Trails.</p>
<p>Bicycle hire in New Zealand is widely available if you're not bringing your own bike. By law, all cyclists must wear an approved safety helmet.</p><p>Drive on the left and give way to traffic crossing or appearing from the right. The speed limit is 100kph (62 mph) on the open road and 50kph (31mph) in built-up or urban areas. Signposting follows the standard international symbols and all distances are displayed in kilometres. Drivers and passengers are obliged to wear seatbelts in both the front and back of a car, while children under the age of five must be properly strapped into an approved child seat. Cyclists and motorbike riders must wear helmets when on the road.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are good local bus services in the main towns and cities, as well as trolleybuses in Wellington and historic trams in Christchurch. Both Auckland and Wellington have zonal fares with pre-purchase tickets and day passes.</p>
<p>For public transport information and advice on journey planning in and around Auckland, contact Auckland Transport (AT) (tel: +64 9 366 6400; <a href="http://at.govt.nz" target="_blank">at.govt.nz</a>) . Metlink (tel: 0800 801 700, in New Zealand; <a href="http://www.metlink.org.nz" target="_blank">www.metlink.org.nz</a>) runs buses, trains and ferries in and around Wellington.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Zealand</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">n_plymouth</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Zealand</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">dunedin</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">*12.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Zealand</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">christchurch</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">*7.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">*5.20</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">New Zealand</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">auckland</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of options for flights to New Zealand from all over the world. Seven airports in New Zealand cater for international flights. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/auckland">Auckland</a> Airport and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/christchurch">Christchurch</a> International Airport are the principal arrival points for the North and South Island respectively, but <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/wellington">Wellington</a> International Airport, Palmerston North International Airport and Hamilton International Airport also serve the North Island, while Dunedin International Airport and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/queenstown">Queenstown</a> Airport operate on the South Island.</p>
<p>The national airline is Air New Zealand (<a href="http://www.airnewzealand.co.nz" target="_blank">www.airnewzealand.co.nz</a>), which flies from numerous international destinations, including the UK (via Los Angeles).&nbsp;Flights to New Zealand from the UK are available with a number of different airlines, including Qantas, Emirates, Singapore Airlines and Malaysian Airlines, all involving a stopover.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand/auckland-international-airport">Auckland International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand/christchurch-international-airport">Christchurch International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/queenstown/queenstown-airport">Queenstown Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand/wellington-international-airport">Wellington International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Auckland: from London - 24 hours (including stopover); New York - 22 hours (including stopover); Los Angeles - 13 hours.</p>
<p>Given the country&rsquo;s relative distance from other major destinations, consider purchasing a round-the-world ticket and stop off on the way to New Zealand. Popular stopovers en route include <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangkok">Bangkok</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brisbane">Brisbane</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brunei">Brunei</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dubai">Dubai</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hong-kong">Hong Kong</a>, Kuala Lumpur, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/fiji">Fiji</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tahiti-and-her-islands">Tahiti</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/san-francisco">San Francisco</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sydney">Sydney</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/qatar">Qatar</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tokyo">Tokyo</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tonga">Tonga</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The high season for flights to New Zealand is during the summer months (December to February). Although shoulder seasons are slightly less busy, New Zealand&rsquo;s popularity requires passengers to book well in advance, even during the winter months (when the airports are full of skiers and winter sports enthusiasts).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Usually included in the airfare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The high season for flights to New Zealand is during the summer months (December to February). Although shoulder seasons are slightly less busy, New Zealand&rsquo;s popularity requires passengers to book well in advance, even during the winter months (when the airports are full of skiers and winter sports enthusiasts).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Auckland International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aucklandairport.co.nz<p>Auckland Airport is located 21km (14 miles) south of Auckland.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>0800 247 767</p>]]><b>Christchurch International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.christchurchairport.co.nz<p>Christchurch International Airport is located 12km (7.5 miles) northwest of Christchurch city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+64 3 353 7777</p>]]><b>Wellington International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.wellingtonairport.co.nz<p>Wellington International Airport is located 8km (5 miles) southeast of Wellington city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+64 4 385 5100</p>]]><b>Queenstown Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.queenstownairport.co.nz<p>Queenstown Airport is located 9km (6 miles) to the northeast of central Queenstown, in the lakeside settlement of Frankton.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+64 3 450 9031</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International shipping lines sailing from the USA and Europe serve the major ports of Auckland, Opua and Wellington in the North Island, and Christchurch, Dunedin, Lyttelton and Picton in the South Island.&nbsp;It&rsquo;s also possible to sail between New Zealand, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> and some of the surrounding Pacific Islands on a yacht, although this isn&rsquo;t a regular way of accessing the country.</p>
<p>There are no regular passenger ships from the UK&nbsp;or Europe to New Zealand. However, a number of round-the-world cruise ships stop here during routes around Australia and the Pacific Islands and on expedition cruises to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/antarctica-0">Antarctica</a>.</p>
<p>Regular freight liners carrying cargo sometimes offer passenger berths, although this is a slow way of reaching the destination and these do not supply the same level of comfort or amenities as dedicated passenger vessels.</p>
<p>For further details on travelling to New Zealand by boat, contact Tourism New Zealand (<a href="http://www.newzealand.com" target="_blank">www.newzealand.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Most public phones take cards purchased from bookstalls; some also accept credit cards, but very few still accept coins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet caf&eacute;s in cities and town central business districts. Travellers can access the internet at many hotels and youth hostels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand's media scene is very liberal and the broadcasting sector was deregulated in 1988. Television stations include the state-owned Television New Zealand (Channels One, Two, Six and Seven), the private TV3 and Prime TV, and the public Maori Television. Radio broadcasters include Radio New Zealand, the Pacific Island-focused Niu FM, and the Maori-language Ruia Mai.</p>
<p>The English-language daily newspapers with the highest circulation include the <em>New Zealand Herald</em>, <em>The Dominion Post</em>, <em>Otago Daily Times</em> and <em>The Press</em>. For current affairs, look out for a copy of North and South. Other quality periodicals include <em>New Zealand Geographic</em>, <em>New Zealand Wilderness</em> and <em>New Zealand Outside</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes four to five days and to the USA three to 10 days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700 and Sat 0900-1230 in some larger towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Explore Tongariro National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Originally a gift to Queen Victoria from the Tuwharetoa Maori chief Te Heuheu Tukino IV in 1887, Tongariro National Park was the first national park in New Zealand and the fourth oldest in the world. The park is of religious and cultural importance to the Maoris who first occupied the area in the ninth century when they arrived from Polynesia. They believed the region's mountains had god-like ancestors, and the core of the park centres around three active volcanoes, Tongariro, Ngauruhoe and the largest, Ruapehu, which erupted in a spectacular fashion in 1995 and again in 1996. Some areas resemble a lunar landscape, which has been created by flowing lava, alongside forests and tussock lands. The Tongariro Crossing (<a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz" target="_blank">www.doc.govt.nz</a>), completed by about 70,000 hikers every summer, is considered to be one of the best one-day walks in the country, offering magnificent volcanic scenery and fine views of Lake Taupo and Mt Taranaki. Mt Ruapehu is also the focal point for skiing on the North Island, with resorts at Whakapapa and Turoa providing access to New Zealand&rsquo;s largest ski area, where there are lots of ski runs and options for cross-country and ski touring.</p>]]><br/><p>Venture through Fiordland National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>At nearly 1.2 million hectares (3 million acres) in size, Fiordland National Park is New Zealand&rsquo;s largest national park &ndash; a breathtaking stretch of coastal landscape that typifies the country&rsquo;s natural splendour. Created in 1952, it is a land of ice, beech forests, mountains and waterfalls that tumble into the ocean below. One of the park&rsquo;s most famous sights is Milford Sound, which is the largest glacier-carved fiord on New Zealand&rsquo;s coastline and attracts large numbers of sightseers and cruise ships every year. Popular activities in the park include hiking, sea kayaking, diving, cycling, golf, fishing and sailing. The Milford Track, which stretches some 53.5km (33 miles) from Glade Wharf to Sandfly Point, has been described as the finest walk in the world, taking visitors on a rugged, alpine journey through the park&rsquo;s most breathtaking scenery. Visitors should, however, note that a permit is required for the track and the hut accommodation along its length, and these must be booked through the Visitor Centre in Te Anau.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the beauty of Coromandel Peninsula</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Easily accessible from Auckland, the Coromandel Peninsula is an attractive holiday destination. Covered in native rainforest, it has superb white-sand beaches. Explore the beautiful west coast, walk through the scenic reserves, skydive in Whitianga or kayak off-shore before retreating to the warm pools at Hot Water Beach.</p>]]><p><b>Check out Christchurch</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The 'Garden City' of Christchurch was rocked by a devastating earthquake in February 2011, which killed 181 people and badly damaged the centre of town. However, the resilient city has largely returned to normal. The centre is filled with neo-gothic architecture reminiscent of an old English university town. Visit the Christchurch Art Gallery (<a href="http://www.christchurchartgallery.org.nz" target="_blank">www.christchurchartgallery.org.nz</a>), which is home to an impressive collection of local, home-grown art, punt along the River Avon, visit the earthquake-damaged Anglican cathedral, or soak up the atmosphere from one of the city&rsquo;s bustling caf&eacute;s.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Aoraki/Mt Cook</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The effort in making the steep climb up Aoraki/Mt Cook is repaid with outstanding views over alpine glaciers, snow-capped peaks and crystal-clear lakes. Standing 3,754m (12,316ft) tall, Aoraki/Mt Cook is the highest mountain in New Zealand. The mountain, which attracts climbers from all over the world, stands in Aoraki/Mt Cook National Park (<a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz" target="_blank">www.doc.govt.nz</a>), on New Zealand's South Island. If using your feet seems like too much effort, take the TranzAlpine (<a href="http://www.tranzscenic.co.nz" target="_blank">www.tranzscenic.co.nz</a>) train and enjoy one of the world's finest rail trips, journeying coast to coast through the Southern Alps.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Maori culture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Auckland Museum (<a href="http://www.aucklandmuseum.com" target="_blank">www.aucklandmuseum.com</a>) is filled with Maori and Pacific Island collections and the Te Papa Tongarewa Museum of New Zealand (<a href="http://www.tepapa.govt.nz" target="_blank">www.tepapa.govt.nz</a>) in Wellington has a heavy emphasis on Maori heritage, treasures and biculturalism. In Rotorua's cultural centres, see how young Maori learn the skills of traditional bone, wood and greenstone carving. Visit a <em>marae</em> (a Maori meeting house) and enjoy a concert of traditional songs and the <em>haka</em> (a Maori challenge usually witnessed before All Blacks rugby matches) and sit down to a <em>hangi</em> (a delicious feast cooked in an earth oven).</p>]]><p><b>Engage with the marine life</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Poor Knights Islands (near Whangarei) are particularly renowned among divers for their marine life, geology and clear waters; there are also a number of wrecks deliberately sunk here for divers to explore &ndash; for other dive sites, contact New Zealand Underwater (<a href="http://www.nzunderwater.org.nz" target="_blank">www.nzunderwater.org.nz</a>). Swim with dolphins in the Bay of Islands (north of Auckland), the Coromandel Peninsula, Kaikoura (South Island), Curio Bay in the Catlins and Whakatane. Stay dry but witness giants of the deep when whale watching on the eastern coast of South Island &ndash; whales are attracted to a deep ocean trench just off the coast of Kaikoura. Most sightings occur from April to August. For more information, contact Whale Watch (<a href="http://www.whalewatch.co.nz" target="_blank">www.whalewatch.co.nz</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy the sun in Nelson</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At the far northwest corner of the South Island stands Nelson, the sunniest region in New Zealand. The bright, bohemian city is the focal point of the region, which boasts everything from long golden beaches of the Abel Tasman National Park to tranquil twin pools in the Nelson Lakes National Park. The curving 30km-long (19-mile) sand bar, Farewell Spit, where thousands of wading and wetland birds nest in the summer, is also accessible by 4-wheel-drive.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Rotorua</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The bubbling mud pools, colourful thermal lakes and performing geyser at Wai-O-Tapu (<a href="http://www.waiotapu.co.nz" target="_blank">www.waiotapu.co.nz</a>), and the boiling whirlpools, steam jets and sulphur pools of Hell&rsquo;s Gate are among the best of Rotorua's thermal attractions. Visitors can also check out the volcanoes at nearby Tongariro to see the explosive aftermath of previous eruptions.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Waitomo Caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Waitomo Caves are a set of more than 300 limestone caverns, where explorers can abseil into the 'lost world'; they are especially famous for their glow-worm grottos. You can also try black-water rafting or tubing, where participants float through the cave system on custom-made tyres. The more adventurous can also try canyoning and clambering up and down waterfalls whilst underground.</p>]]><p><b>Fjords and Milford Sound</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Breathtaking fjords indent the lower west coast of the South Island. Cruise around Milford Sound in the shadow of iconic Mitre Peak or dive into its icy-cold waters to see red and black corals. Kayak around Doubtful Sound to escape the crowds and discover cascading waterfalls.</p>]]><p><b>Get active in Queenstown</b></p><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand's main centre for outdoor sports lies on the shore of stunning Lake Wakatipu, beneath giant craggy mountains. Vibrant and bursting with energy, this is the perfect year-round base for testing your nerves on any of the many adrenaline-fuelled activities on offer. Try bungee jumping, caving, rafting, jetboating, skydiving, skiing and much more before returning to the atmospheric food and nightlife scene.</p>]]><p><b>Go east to Napier</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Razed by an earthquake in 1931 and subsequently rebuilt in the Art Deco style of the time, the laid-back coastal town of Napier now boasts one of the world's finest collections of lovingly preserved Art Deco buildings. Walk along the two central streets, Emerson and Tennyson, to see some of the finest examples, or head to the National Tobacco Company building to admire the intricately detailed interior; visit at night to see it imaginatively lit.</p>]]><p><b>Go white-water rafting</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Popular rivers for this thrilling sport include the Wairora (near Tauranga), the Mohaka (in Hawke's Bay) and the Kaituna (near Rotorua), which features the world's highest commercially rafted waterfall at 7m (23ft). Black-water rafting through underground caves is a rare opportunity to experience. Alternatively, tackle the three- to five-day canoe journey on the Whanganui River to see some of the North Island's finest scenery.</p>]]><p><b>Head up to Auckland</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A good starting point when exploring New Zealand&rsquo;s largest, most multicultural city, is the distinctive Sky Tower (<a href="http://www.skycityauckland.co.nz" target="_blank">www.skycityauckland.co.nz</a>) &ndash; a syringe-shaped tower that offers fantastic views of the city, its beaches and the coast. It&rsquo;s also possible for the particularly brave tourist to abseil down the side of the building to the street (a drop of over 100m/328ft). Additionally, explore the waterfront and harbour area; visit the National Maritime Museum (<a href="http://www.nzmaritime.org" target="_blank">www.nzmaritime.org</a>) and Auckland Museum (<a href="http://www.aucklandmuseum.com" target="_blank">www.aucklandmuseum.com</a>); or walk through The Domain, an old volcanic cone, to find the Winter Garden. Alternatively, sail across to North Shore to visit the pretty bays and eastern suburbs, or explore the islands dotting the Hauraki Gulf.</p>]]><p><b>Hike through the countryside</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Known locally as &lsquo;tramping&rsquo;, this is one of the principal pastimes for New Zealanders. Do as they do and tramp though stunning national parks and protected forest areas. Popular walks include the government-designated Great Walks, including the Abel Tasman Coastal Track, the Lake Waikaremoana Track, the world-famous Milford Track, the Routeburn Track and the remote Rakiura Track; other routes such as the Hollyford, Greenstone and Dusky tracks are just as spectacular but less well-known and so less busy. Contact the Department of Conservation (DOC) (<a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz" target="_blank">www.doc.govt.nz</a>) for more information.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the slopes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand is the leading ski and snowboard destination in the southern hemisphere. The best time to hit the slopes for skiing, snowboarding and winter mountaineering is from June to September. On the North Island, the biggest ski areas are on Mt Ruapehu. There are excellent ski slopes in the South Island in the Southern Lakes region and at Mt Hutt. A unique alternative is to glacier ski and glacier walk in the Southern Alps.</p>]]><p><b>Hunt for fish</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Fishing for brown and rainbow trout is particularly popular. Salmon fishing is best in the Rakaia, Rangitata, Waimakariri and Waitaki rivers. For further information on seasons and permits, contact the New Zealand Professional Fishing Guides Association (tel: (06) 868 4214; <a href="http://www.fishingguides.co.nz" target="_blank">www.fishingguides.co.nz</a>) or New Zealand Fish and Game (tel: (04) 499 4767; <a href="http://www.fishandgame.org.nz" target="_blank">www.fishandgame.org.nz</a>). There is also some superb sea and big-game fishing available off the coast of the North Island, where the warm Pacific waters are home to marlin and snapper. A number of charter organisations can arrange fishing trips.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the Franz Josef and Fox Glaciers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>These two breathtaking ice tongues are located at the heart of Westland National Park. They&nbsp;extend right down from the summits through the forest, and to the coastal zone, a unique phenomenon not found anywhere else in the world. The 12km-long (7.5-mile) Franz Josef and Fox Glaciers are the two largest glaciers of the 140 or so that lie within the park&rsquo;s boundaries. Take to the air in a helicopter to see the scale of the glaciers or drive or walk out to the snout of each ice wall for a closer look.</p>]]><p><b>Pump up the adrenaline </b></p><![CDATA[<p>This is the world's prime destination for bungee jumping, where daredevil participants dive off a tall bridge or other structure with an elastic cord strapped to their ankles. Famous jump-off points include the Kawarau River Bridge, the Nevis, the Pipeline, and the Ledge (all near Queenstown), Taupo and Mangaweka (North Island) and Hanmer Springs (South Island). Alternatively, try bridge swinging: falling then swinging along a gorge whilst harnessed to a cable. New Zealand is also the birthplace of zorbing, which involves being strapped into or diving into a zorb (an inflatable transparent plastic ball) with a bucket of water, which is then rolled down a grassy hill or onto a river.</p>]]><p><b>See stunning wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Good bird-watching spots include Taiaroa Head (near Dunedin) &ndash; known for colonies of royal albatross&nbsp;&ndash; and Stewart Island, which represents your best chance to see an elusive kiwi in the wild. Cape Kidnappers in Hawkes Bay is home to the only gannet colony in the world. In Dunedin, in the Otago Peninsula, you may see rare yellow-eyed penguins and fur seals. Some of the world's oldest trees are in the forests of the Northland Forest Park, including the famous kauri, many of which date back centuries. Offshore island reserves, such as Tiritiri Matangi Island north of Auckland and Kapiti Island north of Wellington, protect a number of endangered species that no longer survive on the mainland.</p>]]><p><b>Set sail in the harbour or jetboat down the river</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Auckland, dubbed 'the city of sails', is a perfect spot for sailing and yachting. Cruise the harbour in tall ships or sailboats, visit vineyards on neighbouring islands, or go further afield on an excursion to the remote maritime reserves in the Bay of Islands, Hauraki Gulf and Marlborough Sounds. Or for a faster pace, take a high-speed jetboat trip, which is guaranteed to leave you breathless and soaked as these high-powered craft hurtle down rivers at dizzying speeds. Trips run on many of the country's best-known rivers, including Queenstown's Shotover River and on the Waikato River beneath the Huka Falls.</p>]]><p><b>Surf along the coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand surf is truly spectacular. Some of the best breaks are located at Mahia Peninsula (near Gisborne), Muriwai, Palliser Bay (near Wellington) and Piha. You can also ride one of the best left-hand breaks in the world at Raglan. Beginners should start by bodysurfing or by riding boogie boards. For more information visit Surf.co.nz (<a href="http://www.surf.co.nz" target="_blank">www.surf.co.nz</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Taste local wines </b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wine is produced in areas the length and breadth of New Zealand. A great place to enjoy a tipple is the wine-growing region of Hawke's Bay. Around 70 wineries allow visitors in to sample the region's respected red wines, particularly Pinot Noir. The Marlborough province in the South Island also has world-class wineries producing white, sharp Chardonnay and crisp Sauvignon Blanc. For more information, contact New Zealand Winegrowers (<a href="http://www.nzwine.com" target="_blank">www.nzwine.com</a>). For a more potent tipple, visit the South Island's whisky distilleries, including Southern Distilleries Ltd. (tel: (03) 208 9907;<a href="http://www.hokonuiwhiskey.com" target="_blank">www.hokonuiwhiskey.com</a>), reputed to be the world's southernmost distillery, at Timaru.</p>]]><p><b>Uncover Stewart Island/Rakiura</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Remote and rugged, Stewart Island has a rich Maori heritage and a mass of wilderness to explore and enjoy. With just one town and barely any roads, it has hundreds of hidden beaches, bays and sandy coves. Fishing is the lifeblood of the islands and seafood here is exceptional. Hikers tackle the 10-day circuit of the top half of the island or sections of trail, whilst wildlife enthusiasts and birdwatchers come to see kiwi in their natural habitat.</p>]]><p><b>Unearth the history of the Bay of Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of New Zealand&rsquo;s most historic regions, the Bay of Islands is also the setting for one of the North Island&rsquo;s most popular resort areas. The main towns, Paihia, Waitangi and Russell are the hub for excursions to sail, dive, swim with dolphins and explore this picturesque part of the country. Waitangi is also home to the Waitangi Treaty Grounds, where the historic Treaty of Waitangi was signed in 1840 between Maoris and the British Monarchy.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Wellington</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whilst not New Zealand&rsquo;s largest city, the capital is its cultural centre. The spectacular Te Papa Tongarewa Museum of New Zealand (<a href="http://www.tepapa.govt.nz" target="_blank">www.tepapa.govt.nz</a>), on the city's pretty waterfront, is Wellington's star attraction. Window shop and people watch on 'alternative' Cuba Street or the more upmarket Courtenay Place; stroll through the Botanic Gardens (<a href="http://www.wellington.govt.nz" target="_blank">www.wellington.govt.nz</a>); tramp up to the top of Mt Victoria for panoramic views; or cruise around the harbour or hire a kayak. There&rsquo;s also an enormous number of good quality caf&eacute;s and restaurants to sample.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$186 billion (2013 est.).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Dairy, meat, wood and wood products, fish and machinery.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, vehicles and aircraft, petroleum, electronics, textiles and plastics.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Australia, China, Germany, Japan, United Kingdom and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand is primarily thought of as an agricultural country and, although the sector employs less than 7% of the workforce and contributes just 5% of GDP, it accounts for 30% of the country's export income, primarily from wool, meat, dairy and wood products. Energy-related natural resources, principally coal but also natural gas, have been heavily developed. There are also deposits of iron, gold and silica.</p>
<p>Between the mid-1980s and mid-1990s, New Zealand underwent one of the most radical economic transformations of any Western industrialised country, with wholesale privatisation, abolition of subsidies, tariff barriers and corporate regulations, and dismantling of many welfare systems (although spending has risen sharply to tackle the pensions crisis afflicting the developed world). The reforms have also led to New Zealand being more dependent on foreign trade.</p>
<p>Like the global economy, New Zealand slipped into a recession in 2008, amid drought, high energy costs and a housing market slump. The economy pulled out of recession late in 2009, however, and achieved 1.7% growth in 2010 and 2% in 2011. Despite this growth, trade sectors remain delicately poised.</p>
<p>Australia is New Zealand's largest trading partner, and the two governments have established a completely free trading regime. New Zealand is a member of the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD), the South Pacific Forum, the Pacific Islands Forum and the Asian-Pacific Economic Co-operation (APEC) forum.</p>
<p>The largest conference centres are in Auckland, Christchurch and Wellington. Many hotels also have facilities. There are more than 20 regional convention bureaux in New Zealand, most of which are members of Conventions and Incentives New Zealand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business attire is generally conservative; suits are usually worn but jackets may soon be discarded and shirtsleeves rolled up. A more informal dress code also exists in most restaurants and bars, although the smartest restaurants may still prefer a jacket and tie.</p>
<p>Conducting business in New Zealand is the same as most other Western countries; appointments are necessary and punctuality is appreciated. Business cards are exchanged. The business approach is fairly conservative and visitors should avoid the period from Christmas to the end of January. The best months for business visits are February to April and October to November. Business hours are generally Monday to Friday, 0900 to 1700.</p>
<p>There are no cultural pitfalls to watch out for, unless dealing directly with Maori (who will outline any protocols before meetings), and the only noticeable difference lies with the nature of the country's people. New Zealanders are notably friendlier, more informal and more relaxed than most other Western nations.</p>
<p>Dinner is seen as a time for socialising and not business, so meetings mainly take place over lunch. Invitations to dine out or to visit someone's home are far more readily issued than in many other countries, and are genuine. The native host will expect to pay for a meal or a round of drinks but guests can step in and pay their turn without creating arguments or offence.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Wellington Employers' Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (04) 473 7224.
					Website:http://www.wecc.org.nz/
					Address: 3-11 Hunter Street,Level 2, Lumley House,Wellington 6011,]]><b>Conventions and Incentives New Zealand</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (09) 486 4128.
					Website:http://www.conventionsnz.com/
					Address: Takapuna,PO Box 331-202, Suite 3, Level 1, 15 Huron Street,Auckland,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand boasts some superb cuisine, most of which is prepared in the distinctive Pacific Rim style, drawing from the heritage of the cultures in the region. Every region has a speciality and it&rsquo;s possible to travel around the country sampling them in restaurants, at barbecues, farmers markets and at wine and food festivals. For something truly alternative, head to the Hokitika Wildfoods Festival on the West Coast of the South Island to try huhu grubs, worm sushi and chocolate-dipped chillies.</p>
<p>New Zealand has a reputation as a leading producer of meat and dairy produce with lamb, beef and pork on most menus. Venison is also widely available. A variety of fish, including snapper, grouper and John Dory can be found. Seasonal delicacies such as whitebait, oysters, crayfish, scallops and game birds are recommended. The kumara, a native sweet potato, is a common accompaniment, while kiwi fruit, feijoa and tamarillo are celebrated fruits. Those with a sweet tooth should try hokey pokey ice cream and the national desert, pavlova, a rich concoction of meringue, cream and fresh fruit. New Zealand is also establishing a reputation for French-type cheeses: bleu de Bresse, brie, camembert and montagne bleu.</p>
<p>For a traditional treat, try a hangi, a Maori-style feast cooked in an earth oven under heated river rocks, which often includes chicken, wild boar and lamb, as well as vegetables.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Kumara (native sweet potato).<br />
&bull; Feijoa (local fruit) and golden-fleshed <em>Zespri Gold,</em> kiwi fruit from the Bay of Plenty.<br />
&bull; Battered fish and chips from Gisbourne.<br />
&bull; Salmon and green-lipped mussels from Marlborough.<br />
&bull; Paua (abalone) from Stewart Island.<br />
&bull; <em>Toheroa</em> (clam) from Ninety Mile Beach.<br />
&bull; Oysters from Bluff.<br />
&bull; Hangi in Rotorua.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Picnic areas with barbecue facilities are provided at roadside sites. Restaurants are usually informal, except very exclusive establishments. Waiter service is typical to that of other Western nations, but self-service and fast-food chains are also available. Some restaurants invite customers to 'BYO' (bring your own liquor). Bars have counter service and public bars are very informal. Lounge bars and 'house bars' (for hotel guests only) are sometimes more formal and occasionally have table service. There is some variation in licensing hours in major cities and some hotel bars open Sunday, providing a meal is eaten. In most hotels and taverns, licensing hours are 1100-2300, except Sunday.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Service charges and taxes are not added to hotel or restaurant bills. Tips are not expected. The size of the gratuity is entirely discretionary, but 5-10% is typical.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>The minimum drinking age in a bar is 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand has an active and varied entertainment industry that&rsquo;s set up to cater for people who want a casual drink, cultural experience or a more hedonistic experience. Animated DJ and live music venues provide a vibrant night out, especially in the larger cities, which also host a range of nightclubs, cabaret shows and concerts. Lively entertainment districts such as Auckland&rsquo;s Viaduct Harbour and Britomart and Wellington&rsquo;s Courtenay Place and Cuba Quarter offer a variety of music and live entertainment options, so there&rsquo;s something to suit everyone from pub-goers to clubbers.</p>
<p>Classical music, dance and theatre can be taken in whilst visiting Auckland and Wellington in particular. Theatres also offer good entertainment ranging from drama, comedy and musicals to pop concerts and shows; you can book concert tickets online through Ticketek (<a href="http://www.ticketek.com" target="_blank">www.ticketek.com</a>). In large cities, there are often professional performers or guest artists from overseas &ndash; check the 'What's On' section of local papers (also <a href="http://www.newzealand.com" target="_blank">www.newzealand.com</a>). Smaller towns have restaurants and local pubs with plenty of individual character and charm. There are also six casinos in New Zealand: one each in Auckland, Hamilton, Christchurch&nbsp;and&nbsp;Dunedin, and two in&nbsp;Queenstown. Smoking is prohibited inside all these venues.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide range of shopping available in New Zealand. Regular centre-of-town retail areas sit alongside modern shopping centres, whilst factory outlets sell well-known brands at reduced rates. There is a wealth of high-quality goods on sale, including traditional arts and crafts in Maori, South Pacific and contemporary New Zealand style. </p>
<p>Special purchases include distinctive jewellery made from New Zealand greenstone (a kind of jade) and from the beautiful translucent paua shell, which has an unappealing, drab exterior but a stunning interior or iridescent blue, green and purple swirls and hues.</p>
<p>Maori arts and crafts are reflected in a number of items such as the carved greenstone tiki (a unique Maori charm) and intricate woodcarvings often inlaid with paua shell; look in specialist art and craft or museum shops for the best examples, particularly in Nelson, Golden Bay and Coromandel. Wood studios use native timbers including kauri, rimu and totara to craft attractive bowls, ornaments and other objects; the traditional swirls and patterns from customary Maori arts and early carvings are represented in numerous designs, which are very popular for their aesthetic appeal, cultural heritage and symbolic meaning. Glass art is also popular in Nelson and has attracted worldwide praise.</p>
<p>Other items of note include woollen goods, lambswool rugs, merino knitwear, possum fur products, leather and skin products. The ubiquitous All Black rugby jerseys and memorabilia are widespread, with the best cotton-made shirts available from the Canterbury Clothing Company. For something a little more stylish, look out for award-winning local labels such as Karen Walker, Nom*D, World and Zambesi. Alternatively, take a flavour of your trip home with you by buying New Zealand wine, manuka honey or avocado oil.</p><p>All shops and businesses are open Mon-Sat 0900-1700, as a minimum; there are local variations. Many stores and most shopping centres are also open Sun 1000-1300 and in the evenings in major resorts.</p><p>All goods and services are subject to a 15% Goods and Services Tax (GST), which is always included in the advertised price. Visitors cannot reclaim this tax.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand offers a wide range of top-class hotels, luxury lodges, exclusive boutique retreats, motels, traditional pub rooms, moderately priced accommodation and guest houses. Rates on the whole are cheaper in rural areas, while every city and town also offers a choice of budget hotels and motels. Budget accommodation, often with self-catering facilities, is increasingly popular. Boutique accommodation is almost always in a historic or heritage building or landmark, offering a high standard of amenities and often including breakfast. Wilderness hideaways are spread throughout the country and worth the effort for an exclusive, highly individual evening.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in New Zealand are graded from 1 to 4 stars. Motels are graded on a separate scale of 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Usually located in restored, older buildings; guest houses, bed and breakfast hotels and private hotels offer moderately priced accommodation, often with shared bathroom facilities, but with generally high standards.</p>
<p>A number of established companies can arrange farm holidays where visitors stay with a family as a guest, sharing bathroom facilities. Many farms are conveniently located for outdoor activities such as fishing, skiing and horse trekking. Prices usually include breakfast and dinner. Homestays and farmstays are an excellent way of spending time with your hosts and gaining an insight into local life. There is an eclectic mix of hosts and homes to stay in and although you are encouraged to interact with your hosts, guests have their own room.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand offers a wide range of top-class hotels, luxury lodges, exclusive boutique retreats, motels, traditional pub rooms, moderately priced accommodation and guest houses. Rates on the whole are cheaper in rural areas, while every city and town also offers a choice of budget hotels and motels. Budget accommodation, often with self-catering facilities, is increasingly popular. Boutique accommodation is almost always in a historic or heritage building or landmark, offering a high standard of amenities and often including breakfast. Wilderness hideaways are spread throughout the country and worth the effort for an exclusive, highly individual evening.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in New Zealand are graded from 1 to 4 stars. Motels are graded on a separate scale of 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand offers a wide range of top-class hotels, luxury lodges, exclusive boutique retreats, motels, traditional pub rooms, moderately priced accommodation and guest houses. Rates on the whole are cheaper in rural areas, while every city and town also offers a choice of budget hotels and motels. Budget accommodation, often with self-catering facilities, is increasingly popular. Boutique accommodation is almost always in a historic or heritage building or landmark, offering a high standard of amenities and often including breakfast. Wilderness hideaways are spread throughout the country and worth the effort for an exclusive, highly individual evening.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in New Zealand are graded from 1 to 4 stars. Motels are graded on a separate scale of 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;New Zealand has an advanced and sophisticated health care system; medical facilities, both public and private, are of a high standard and staff are well trained. Long-staying visitors with a valid permit to stay for two or more years and short-term British visitors are entitled to health care services on the same basis as New Zealand citizens. Travellers from other countries should find out if they are covered by reciprocal health care arrangements. Australia, for example, has such an agreement as long as long as citizens carry their Medicare card. Comprehensive medical insurance is strongly recommended before travelling to cover any additional charges. Trips to the doctor will incur a fee, with prescription charges on top of that. Dentists and hospital services are also expensive. Visitors bringing in a quantity of medicines ought to ensure that they have a doctor&amp;rsquo;s certificate to avoid complications and potential problems at New Zealand customs.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water is considered safe to drink. Water from lakes, waterways and rivers ought to be boiled first to ensure that it is free from Giardia, a water-borne bacterial parasite that can cause diarrhoea and vomiting. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wildlife:&lt;/strong&gt; Sand-flies are found throughout the country but are especially common in the south, around Fiordland. Their bite isn&amp;rsquo;t poisonous but can cause an itchy irritant. Use environmentally friendly repellents to reduce the risk of being bitten. New Zealand has virtually no dangerous animals; the exception is the katipo spider, which although rare, can be found on the North Island and parts of the South. It has a painful bite that can be fatal if untreated; antivenom is widely available. The white-tailed spider, introduced from &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia"&gt;Australia&lt;/a&gt;, also delivers a nasty bite but again, these are uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural disaster:&lt;/strong&gt; Because of its location in a seismically active area of the world, New Zealand is periodically affected by natural disasters such as volcanic eruptions and earthquakes. These events are generally rare but can have a dramatic and devastating impact. If visitors are caught in an earthquake, they should take cover under a table or stand in a doorway; if they are outside, they should keep away from buildings, trees and rock formations that might fall. Monitor local news for updates and warnings and follow any advice or directions given by local authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other risks:&lt;/strong&gt; Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Due to a thinning of the ozone layer over New Zealand, sunburn can occur quicker than in other areas of the world and precautions should be taken; such as shortening exposure time to the sun, wearing hats and applying high-factor sun protection. New Zealand has one of the highest rates of skin cancer in the world and the risk should not be underestimated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, the country is also affected by severe cold weather, with high winds, heavy rain and snowfall possible during the winter months. Travellers visiting at this time should ensure they are properly equipped and dressed for these conditions. Local emergency services and disaster response forces are well-equipped and qualified to help.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Each province also observes its particular anniversary day as a holiday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Waitangi Day :
							06 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>ANZAC Day :
							25 April </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							04 June </p><p>Labour Day :
							22 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into New Zealand by persons of 17 years of age and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 50 cigarettes or 50g of tobacco or cigars or a mixture of all three weighing no more than 50g.<br />
&bull; 4.5L of wine or beer.<br />
&bull; 3 bottles of 1.125L of spirits or liqueurs.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of NZ$700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Because of the importance of agriculture and horticulture to the New Zealand economy, it is illegal to import most foodstuffs (meat, meat products, honey, fruit and dairy). Customs and agricultural officers view any breach of the laws extremely seriously and travellers are fined on the spot. Take care when importing wood products, such as golf clubs, shoes and items made from animal skin and feathers. For further information, contact the nearest embassy, high commission or consulate.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The import of the following items is also prohibited: drugs, counterfeit goods, firearms and weapons (unless a special permit is obtained from the New Zealand police), ivory in any form, tortoise or turtle shell jewellery and ornaments, medicines using musk, rhinoceros or tiger derivatives, carvings or anything made from whalebone or bone from any other marine animals, cat skins or coats, and certain drugs (eg diuretics, depressants, stimulants, heart drugs, tranquillisers, sleeping pills) unless covered by a doctor's prescription. The New Zealand Customs Service website (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.customs.govt.nz">www.customs.govt.nz</a>) contains comprehensive advice for travellers and details all restricted items. There are heavy fines in place for those caught breaking these rules.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are export restrictions on firearms and ammunition, drugs, wildlife, plantlife, antiquities and works of art.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand Dollar (NZD; symbol: NZ$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of NZ$100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of NZ$2 and 1, and 50, 20 and 10 cents.<br />
<strong><br />
</strong><strong>Note:</strong> In November 2006, the New Zealand Reserve Bank introduced new, smaller 50-, 20- and 10-cent coins. The old 5-cent coin has been phased out. Old coins can only be exchanged at the Reserve Bank.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchange facilities are widely available throughout New Zealand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted.</p><p>ATMs are common and are available in all major towns and cities as well as at the country&rsquo;s airports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Can be exchanged at official rates at trading banks, large hotels and some shops. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars, Euro, Pounds Sterling or Australian Dollars. American Express, Visa and Thomas Cook cheques are the most frequently accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1630, except public holidays. Some larger city centre branches also open on Saturday until 1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter New Zealand, a passport valid for at least one month beyond the intended period of stay is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals which have a visa waiver agreement (including all those listed in the chart above) do not require a transit visa, nor do any travellers stopping at a New Zealand airport whose final destination is Australia. Some other nationals do require a transit visa however and should check with the nearest New Zealand embassy/high commission before travelling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On arrival, all visitors are required to complete a Passenger Arrival Card before passing through customs or passport control. These cards are usually given out during in-bound flights but are also available in the arrivals area of the airport. Visitors from countries which have a visa waiver agreement with New Zealand do not need a visa for visits of up to three months (six months for UK visitors). All other nationals require a visitor&rsquo;s visa. Work, business and student visas are also available for people travelling in these capacities.</p>
<p>Visitor visa: NZ$165; transit visa: NZ$145.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitor visa: maximum stay of nine months in an 18-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To apply for a visitor visa, go to your nearest New Zealand embassy/high commission or apply online through Immigration New Zealand (<a href="http://www.immigration.govt.nz">www.immigration.govt.nz</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is illegal to work on a visitor permit, except for Australians who can legally work without a visa or permit. All other nationalities must obtain a work visa, which allows you to enter the country, then a work permit, which allows you to work after your arrival. There are application forms available on Immigration New Zealand's website.</p>
<p>The exception to this rule are working holiday visas, which are available to a number of nationalities aged 18 to 30. The visa is valid for 12 months (or 23 months in some cases) and only issued to people genuinely interested in temporary employment.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three to four weeks for visa processing. Online applications are usually faster.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visitors making an application for a visitor permit need to demonstrate they have sufficient money to support themselves whilst in the country (typically NZ$1,000 per month).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend visitor visas as long as the total time you spend in New Zealand doesn't exceed nine months in an 18-month period or, in some cases, you may be allowed to stay for a maximum of 12 months. Applications are looked at on an individual basis and visitors need to prove they have sufficient funds to continue their stay. You can apply at any Immigration New Zealand office.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets need to undergo medical tests and must be given a microchip implant, a rabies vaccination and rabies titre test before entering New Zealand. Cats and dogs from some countries require a period of quarantine on arrival and an import permit is also required for all pets; download forms and check individual country requirements on the Ministry for Primary Industries website (<a href="http://www.mpi.govt.nz">www.mpi.govt.nz</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-41.666769]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[172.941021]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>270,534 sq km (104,454 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,565,185 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>16.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wellington.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand encompasses two major islands stretching north and south that are separated by the Cook Strait; a third, less substantial island, Stewart Island, is located 30 km (19 miles) off the tip of the South Island across Foveaux Strait. The three main islands are fringed with numerous smaller islands.</p>
<p>The more developed North Island (116,031 sq km/44,800 sq miles) is home to the main cities, including the country's largest city Auckland. The island&rsquo;s rolling green hills are dotted with sheep and horses, and the central heartland pulses with geothermal activity; boiling mud pools, geysers and active volcanoes. The dramatic South Island (153,540 sq km/59,283 sq miles), is a stunning microcosm of snow-covered alps, fjords, glaciers and charming British-style towns such as Christchurch and Dunedin. Stewart Island (1,746 sq km/674 sq miles) is largely undeveloped and an excellent indication of what much of the country must have once looked like. Its permanent population is slightly over 400, most of whom live in the only major settlement, Oban.</p>
<p>There are four associated territories: the Cook Islands, which lie 3,500km (2,175 miles) northeast of New Zealand; Niue, 920km (570 miles) west of the Cook Islands; Tokelau, three atolls about 960km (600 miles) northwest of Niue; and the Ross Dependency, which consists of over 700,000 sq km (270,270 sq miles) of the Antarctic.<br />
<br />
<strong>Note:</strong> The Cook Islands and Niue have separate individual sections in the <em>World Travel Guide</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>55% Christian: Anglican, Presbyterian, Roman Catholic and Methodist are all represented.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Should a visitor be invited to a formal Maori occasion, the <em>hongi </em>(pressing of noses) is common. Casual dress is widely acceptable. New Zealanders are generally very relaxed and hospitable. Stiff formality is rarely appreciated and, after introductions, first names are generally used. Smoking is restricted where indicated; it is banned in pubs and restaurants as well as on public transport and in public buildings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs have three angled flat pins. Most hotels provide 110-volt AC sockets (rated at 20 watts) for electric razors only.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General Dame Patsy Reddy since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>According to legend, New Zealand was created by a mythical demi-god Maui-Tikitiki-a Taranga, from the Polynesian homeland of Hawaiki. Using his magical jawbone as a hook and his blood as bait, Maui caught a great fish, which became the North Island of New Zealand. The South Island is Maui&rsquo;s canoe and Stewart Island is the anchor.</p>
<p>New Zealand, first settled by Polynesians (the Maori) in the 13th century, has a long history of conflict. The arrival of European explorer Abel Tasman in 1642 confirmed the existence of a southern continent but the first encounter with the Maori was hostile and Abel Tasman never actually set foot on the land.</p>
<p>Captain James Cook charted the country&rsquo;s coastline more than 100 years later, in 1769. His first encounter with the Maori ended in bloodshed but he persevered and established a friendly relationship. After Cook spread the word, European whalers, sealers and settlers arrived to plunder the rich marine resources and establish a new life.</p>
<p>In 1840, the Treaty of Waitangi &ndash; a land ownership agreement between the British and the Maori &ndash; was signed, transferring New Zealand to the British crown. The treaty established British law in New Zealand but guaranteed Maori authority over their land. It is held to be New Zealand&rsquo;s founding document and the original can be viewed in Wellington.</p>
<p>A series of land wars between 1843 and 1872 ended with the defeat of the Maori and vast areas of Maori land were confiscated. In 1975, the Waitangi Tribunal was convened to settle Maori land claims and address this land grab. It has become a permanent commission of enquiry and a means of addressing issues affecting contemporary Maori.</p>
<p>New Zealand became self-governing in 1852 and gained the status as an autonomous dominion of the British Empire in 1907. New Zealand became an independent member of the British Commonwealth in 1947. Queen Elizabeth II remains the head of state, although the monarch has no active role in running the country. As part of the British Commonwealth, New Zealand has tended to follow the United Kingdom and Australia with support in numerous wars over the years.</p>
<p>Helen Clark became New Zealand's first woman prime minister in 1999 and was succeeded by the incumbent John Key in 2008.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; Government incentives and stunning locations have attracted a slew of recent Hollywood films to be shot in New Zealand, including <em>Avatar</em>, <em>The Lord of the Rings</em>, <em>The Hobbit</em>, <em>King Kong</em> and <em>The Last Samurai</em>.</p>
<p>&bull; Rugby union is considered the national sport and the international team, the All Blacks, perform the haka, a traditional Maori challenge before matches.</p>
<p>&bull; Dunedin is a UNESCO City of Literature.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[New Zealand Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 328 4800.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.nzembassy.com/usa</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 328 4800.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>37 Observatory Circle NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[New Zealand High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7930 8422. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.nzembassy.com/united-kingdom</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7930 8422. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>80 Haymarket<br/>New Zealand House<br/>London<br/>SW1Y 4TQ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in New Zealand]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+64 4924 2888.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/new-zealand</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+64 4924 2888.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Thorndon<br/>44 Hill Street<br/>Wellington 6011<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely held to be one of the most breathtaking countries on the planet, New Zealand is a phenomenal travel destination. The rugged mountains and remote valleys that thrust the destination into the world&rsquo;s spotlight through <em>The Lord of the Rings</em> trilogy tell only part of the story &ndash; you&rsquo;ll also find beaches, fjords, lakes and gorgeous swathes of forest, not to mention age-old Maori culture, forward-looking cities and, famously, a world-class array of outdoor activities. Not only does it pack a punch as hard as an All Black tackle, but it's also incredibly easy to travel around. What&rsquo;s not to love?</p>
<p>Split into two main landmasses &ndash; the North and South Islands &ndash;New Zealand is a deceptively diverse and complicated destination that rewards both first-time and repeat visitors. The North Island is less visually dramatic than its southern counterpart, but it is home to around two thirds of the country&rsquo;s inhabitants. The majority of the major urban centres are here, including the capital, Wellington, and the increasingly dynamic city of Auckland. But nature is still a major player, thanks to volcanoes, thermal regions and the magnificent Bay of Islands.</p>
<p>The South Island is home to far fewer people, but boasts the country&rsquo;s most spectacular scenery. Empty beaches, soaring mountain ranges, glaciers, fjords, wide-open expanses &ndash; they&rsquo;re all here. Outdoor enthusiasts can take their pick from tramping (hiking), cycling, climbing, white-water rafting, caving, zorbing, sky-diving, bungee jumping and more. Christchurch, a city bouncing back with extraordinary creativity from earthquake damage, is also here.</p>
<p>New Zealand has also developed into one of the cleanest and greenest countries in the world. There are 14 national parks throughout the country and almost a quarter of New Zealand is protected land. What else? There&rsquo;s wildlife, wine and a cultural resurgence that&rsquo;s seeing local films, literature and art gaining more and more attention.</p>
<p>A blend of Maori and European culture, coupled with breathtaking landscapes, provides New Zealand with a truly unique character.&nbsp;</p><p>Widely held to be one of the most breathtaking countries on the planet, New Zealand is a phenomenal travel destination. The rugged mountains and remote valleys that thrust the destination into the world&rsquo;s spotlight through <em>The Lord of the Rings</em> trilogy tell only part of the story &ndash; you&rsquo;ll also find beaches, fjords, lakes and gorgeous swathes of forest, not to mention age-old Maori culture, forward-looking cities and, famously, a world-class array of outdoor activities. Not only does it pack a punch as hard as an All Black tackle, but it's also incredibly easy to travel around. What&rsquo;s not to love?</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
