<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Nicaragua" ColCode="nic" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ni" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Nicaragua]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate in Nicaragua differs according to region, so the best time to go varies. The climate is tropical for most of the country and so hot all year round, with temperatures of around 27ºC (81ºF) all year round. In the lower lying areas temperatures range from 22ºC (72ºF) to 30ºC (86ºF), whilst in the mountains it will be cooler; generally hovering between 12ºC (53ºF) and 20ºC (68ºF).</p><p>Most tourists visit during the dry season, which runs from December to May. The rainy season is from June to November and the on the Pacific side the rainy season runs from May to November. The climate on the Atlantic northwestern side can be very temperamental and generally receiving the highest volumes of rainfall in the country.</p><p>The peak time for visiting Nicaragua is from December to March, so those wishing to avoid the crowds may want to consider travelling during the shoulder season months of May and November.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are required throughout the year – bring shorts, t-shirts, and beach wear if you'll be visiting the coast. Waterproofs are advisable during the rainy season. Warmer clothes are advised for the northern mountains; think woolly knits and layers that allow you to wrap up warm as the temperature drops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Given the relative size of the country and the difficulty of some ground travel routes, internal flights are worth considering. La Coste&ntilde;a Airlines (<a href="http://www.lacostena.com.ni" target="_blank">www.lacostena.com.ni</a>) offers domestic flights from Managua to a handful of destinations, including the Corn Islands, Bluefields, Puerto Cabezas and San Carlos. The period around Easter, Christmas and New Year can get booked up.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A twice-weekly boat service runs between Bluefields and the Corn Islands. A twice-weekly ferry service runs from Granada to Ometepe Island and San Carlos, but it&rsquo;s easier to get to Ometepe from San Jorge, where there&rsquo;s an almost hourly boat service to the island. There are regular services from San Carlos to Granada, the Solentiname Archipelago, El Castillo and down the San Juan River to the Caribbean coast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no passenger rail service at present.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lack of road safety is probably the biggest single hazard to travellers in Nicaragua. Road signs are often poor to non-existent. Vehicles don&rsquo;t always use their lights and driving at night is not recommended. Many vehicles are in poor condition, travel very slowly and break down or stop without warning.</p>
<p>Drivers should be especially careful on curves and hills, as many drivers pass or park on blind corners. Speed limits vary depending on the type of road but traffic rules are rarely enforced. Watch out for bicycles, motorbikes, mopeds and oxcarts, and people and animals walking in the road.</p>r<p>The Pan-American Highway, which connects the northern and southern borders, and some main roads connecting major towns and cities, are in good condition but other roads can be potholed or unpaved, and can be difficult to navigate in the rainy season.</p><p>Most Nicaraguans travel by bus and many of them are knee-crunching former American school buses. Most major destinations have an express service which may be a more comfortable minibus. It&rsquo;s more expensive than a regular service but can halve the travel time. You need to buy your express ticket in advance from the (often chaotic) bus terminal or from the driver. Drivers are usually friendly and helpful, although it helps to speak some Spanish.</p><p>There are taxis at the airport and in towns and cities. With unmetered taxis, agree a fare before you set off. Most city taxis are <em>colectivos</em> that stop and pick up other people. They have set in-town fares &ndash; a map of each area in the city determines the price. No tip is expected.</p><p>Valid national driving licences and international driving licences are accepted, as long as you are over 21 and they&rsquo;re accompanied by a passport. Insurance is essential.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18 years. Speed limits vary according to the type of road but are rarely enforced. Seat belts must be worn at all times and driving licences must be in the driver's possession when driving. Make sure you carry an emergency triangle and fire extinguisher.</p><p>If you break down in a rental car, contact your rental agency.  There are no official breakdown services in Nicaragua, so if you&rsquo;re driving your own vehicle try to get your car into a safe place and make your way to the nearest garage.</p><p>Major international car hire companies have offices at Managua International Airport and in Managua, Granada, San Juan del Sur, Chinandega, Masaya, Matagalpa and Pe&ntilde;as Blancas. Consider a 4-wheel drive if you&rsquo;re venturing into the mountains or jungle and check your insurance carefully to see what it covers.</p><p>You can often see whole families on rickety old bikes in the countryside, but a sturdy mountain bike is recommended for difficult terrain. It&rsquo;s easier to rent a bike &ndash; especially in Granada, San Juan del Sur, Ometepe and Le&oacute;n &ndash; than bring your own, but if you do make sure you bring spare parts too, as finding them in Nicaragua can be problematic. Also bring the relevant paperwork to prove that the bike is yours.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18 years. Speed limits vary according to the type of road but are rarely enforced. Seat belts must be worn at all times and driving licences must be in the driver's possession when driving. Make sure you carry an emergency triangle and fire extinguisher.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The bus and minibus services in cities and towns are good, if basic. The buses are often crowded &ndash; don&rsquo;t attempt them with luggage &ndash; and pickpocketing is common. Bus stations can be large, chaotic and confusing. It&rsquo;s not recommend travelling on buses after dark; if possible use radio-dispatched taxis. If you get a taxi on the street, use an authorised taxi which has red plates and the driver&rsquo;s identification number, name and photograph clearly visible on the dashboard. Always agree the fare before you set off.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Nicaragua</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">rivas</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Nicaragua</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">matagalpa</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Nicaragua</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">granada</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Nicaragua</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">esteli</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no direct flights from Europe; you have to fly via the USA. The most common routes from the UK are via Miami with American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>), via Atlanta with Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) or via Houston with United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>).&nbsp;To get from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a> to Managua you need to fly via another gateway US city, usually Miami or Houston, or via San Salvador on Avianca (<a href="http://www.avianca.com" target="_blank">www.avianca.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 15 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Departure tax of US$35 is normally included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Augusto Cesar Sandino International Airport  </b><![CDATA[http://www.eaai.com.ni/index.php?lang=en<p>The airport  is 12km (7 miles) north of the city (journey time - 15 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nicaragua has five international ports are all served by national and international cargo ships: Corinto and Puerto Sandino on the Pacific, and El Rama, El Bluff and Puerto Cabezas on the Atlantic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are three land crossings into Nicaragua from Honduras: Los Manos, El Guasaule and El Espino. There&rsquo;s only one road crossing into Nicaragua from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/costa-rica">Costa Rica</a> at Pe&ntilde;as Blancas. Ticabus (<a href="http://www.ticabus.com" target="_blank">www.ticabus.com</a>) runs routes between Nicaragua and the following: Costa Rica,&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/honduras">Honduras</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/el-salvador">El Salvador</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guatemala">Guatemala</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mexico">Mexico</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/panama">Panama</a>. Transnica (<a href="http://www.transnica.com" target="_blank">www.transnica.com</a>) runs from Nicaragua to Costa Rica and Honduras.</p><p>Try to get to the border crossing as early as possible to avoid long queues.  On entering Nicaragua, there will be people offering to help you with your paperwork or carry your luggage for a small tip; just decline politely but firmly.</p>
<p>You have to complete an immigration form, have your passport stamped and pay US$10 for a tourist card, US$2 for immigration and US$1 for the local municipality, all at different windows of the immigration office. Motorists have to pay an extra US$6 per person for insurance. Make sure you get all the correct stamps and keep all the receipts, as you will need to produce them when you leave. There is a US$3 charge on leaving. There are toilet facilities on both sides of the border that charge a nominal sum but accept both <em>colones</em> and <em>c&oacute;rdoba</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Nicaragua has an extensive landline network and public payphones are available in most areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies so if you're planning to use your phone in Nicaragua, check with your provider before travelling. Coverage is limited to urban areas and wild areas (such as remote forest or mountainous regions) will not have signal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet access is available in all main towns, where there are lots of internet cafes and most hotels will have Wi-Fi access for guests. Connection speeds are however, likely to be slower, and in remote areas, quite intermittent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nicaraguan media represents both pro- and anti-government views. The main papers of note are Spanish language newspapers <em>La Prensa</em> and <em>El Nuevo Diario. </em>Nicaraguans love watching television, and there are several television networks and over 100 radio stations. Cable TV is available in most urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most larger towns have an Enitel telecommunications and postal office. The postal service however, can be quite unreliable. Mail sent to the USA should arrive within five to 10 working days; for post to Europe, it may take longer.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1730.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Discover the beaches, turtles and party life of Rivas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The department of Rivas is home to surf and party capital, San Juan del Sur, as well as some of Nicaragua's most stunning – and often deserted – Pacific beaches, including El Coco, Marsella and Ocotal. The beach at La Flor Wildlife Reserve is where thousands of Olive Ridley turtles come to lay their eggs; you can watch them between July and January.</p>]]><p><b>Don’t miss Managua</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Most visitors bypass Managua, the sprawling and frankly ugly capital, which was devastated by the country's bloody revolution. But if you're stopping over it's worth visiting the National Museum, listening to a concert in the Rubén Darío National Theatre, or catching a baseball game, the country's favourite sport, at the Dennis Martinez National Stadium.</p>]]><p><b>Escape to the Corn Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Big Corn and Little Corn are two isolated Caribbean atolls that were once a haven for pirates. Now Little Corn in particular is a pocket-sized paradise that ticks all the boxes – turquoise waters, palm-fringed white-sand beaches, stunning coral reefs and a relaxed vibe. Go snorkelling, diving, horseback riding, or just swinging in a hammock. Get there by plane or boat from Bluefields.</p>]]><p><b>Go eco on Isla Ometepe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rising out of Lake Nicaragua, this idyllic twin-coned volcanic island is home to friendly fishing and farming communities. Stay in one of the village's small eco-lodges; climb steep Concepción or the easier but muddier Maderas; search for petroglyphs; cycle around the island or simply lounge on the lakeshore beaches.</p>]]><p><b>Hike through the forests of Domitila Wildlife Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Close to Granada, the privately owned Domitila Wildlife Reserve is one of the last remaining areas of dry tropical forest on the Pacific coast. It's home to many mammals, including howler monkeys and wild cats, as well as numerous birds, butterflies and insects. Stay the night in a rustic cabin, and then take an early morning hike or horseback ride along the trails.</p>]]><p><b>Hop around the Solentiname Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set in a remote corner of Lake Nicaragua, this archipelago is made up of 36 tropical islands and islets; a haven for hikers, birdwatchers and art lovers. San Fernando, Mancarrón, La Venada and Mancarroncita are the largest, home to a community of primitivism artists and Los Guatuzos Wildlife Refuge, a maze of forest and waterways that teems with wildlife.</p>]]><p><b>Learn Spanish in Granada</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This picture-perfect colonial city on the shore of Lake Nicaragua makes the ideal base for exploring. Stroll around its cobbled streets and visit its ancient churches, kayak around its tiny islands, dine in its upmarket restaurants and, if you have time to fit in around excursions, try some Spanish lessons at a non-profit school or look at volunteering opportunities.</p>]]><p><b>Look out for jaguars in Indio Maíz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For the ultimate jungle adventure, explore the dense forest of the Indio Maíz Biological Reserve in the far southeast, which has more species of birds, trees and insects than the whole of Europe. Day hikes are run from nearby El Castillo or San Juan del Norte; go with an indigenous Rama Indian guide and, if you're lucky, you might spot an elusive jaguar.</p>]]><p><b>Meet Masaya’s artisans</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are two good reasons to visit the arty city of Masaya. Shop till you drop at the famous handicraft market where you can meet the skilled artisans and learn about the region's fascinating folklore at the small museum. And head to Masaya Volcanic National Park, where you can hike around the ash-covered landscape and peer into a still-smoking crater.</p>]]><p><b>Paddle down the Rio San Juan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once an important transit route between the oceans, the river now forms the watery border with Costa Rica. Winding through remote towns and flanked by wildlife-filled forest, it still has an intrepid feel. Explore the fortress town of El Castillo, sail all the way to the Caribbean on a <em>panga</em> boat, or kayak along its banks to spot the many birds and animals.</p>]]><p><b>Penetrate the mists of Jinotega</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Known as the 'City of Mists' for its wisps of high-altitude cloud, the birthplace of the Nicaraguan Revolution is now a peaceful city known for its cool climate, stunning valleys, pine forests and granite peaks. It makes a good base for exploring the surrounding coffee farms and nature reserves, lakes and rivers.</p>]]><p><b>Rappel into Somoto Canyon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This geological wonder in northern Nicaragua is one of the oldest rock formations in Central America, dating back some 13 million years. Today, the whole canyon is protected as a National Monument; you can hike along its rocky trails to scenic viewpoints, take a boat tour, try rubber tubing along its crystal-clear water, or rappel down its vertical walls.</p>]]><p><b>Share the passion of León’s poetry and politics</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Colonial León is the former capital with the lively, cultured feel of a university city. Home to the largest cathedral in Central America, colourful, socio-political murals grace the walls and it's a hotbed for Nicaragua's twin passions: politics and poetry. Or if you prefer more physical adventures, try land-surfing down nearby Cerro Negro, the country's youngest volcano.</p>]]><p><b>Stay with a family in Estelí’s nature reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The country's third biggest city has a friendly, small-town feel with walls still covered in revolutionary murals from the 1980s. Nearby, Miraflor Natural Reserve offers hiking, riding and birdwatching through dry and cloud forest, famous for its hundreds of species of orchids. Accommodation is in basic cabins, or stay with a family to get a real taste of rural life.</p>]]><p><b>Surf off San Juan del Sur</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This one-time sleepy surfing hangout is now a bustling resort offering a plethora of attractions, from whale-watching cruises to horseback riding, with plenty of bars, restaurants and hotels to cater for all tastes and budgets. Maderas and Remanso surfing beaches are a short drive away, and you can take boats to other popular surf spots.</p>]]><p><b>Wake up and smell the coffee in Matagalpa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you want an authentic Nicaraguan caffeine hit, visit a coffee plantation in this temperate town in the northern highlands. Nearby, Finca Esperanza Verde is an eco-lodge, nature reserve and organic coffee farm set in tranquil cloud forest. It runs an award-winning reforestation programme and all tourism income is ploughed back into community projects.</p>]]><p><b>Zipline over Mombacho Volcano</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mombacho's imposing cone can be seen from the historic city of Granada and the volcano's nature reserve is the perfect place to discover the flora and fauna of the cloud forest, including beautiful orchids in season. Local guides lead hikes from the peak to its craters, with spectacular panoramic views; or take the Miravalle Canopy Tour for a thrilling zip-line adrenaline rush.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$11.28 billion (2013).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Coffee, beef, gold, sugar, peanuts.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Consumer goods, machinery and equipment, raw materials, petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>US, Venezuela, Mexico, Costa Rica, Canada.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nicaragua is the poorest country in Central America and the second poorest in the Western Hemisphere, with widespread poverty (42.9% below the poverty line in 2009) and an estimated unemployment rate of 7.2% (2013).</p><p>Inflation was at an estimated 7.4% in 2013, although GDP grew by an estimated 4.2%, largely due to an increase in demand for Nicaraguan exports and increased consumer spending at home.</p><p>The Dominican Republic-Central America-United States Free Trade Agreement (CAFTA-DR) has been in effect since April 2006 and has improved export opportunities for many agricultural and manufactured goods. Close to one-third of GDP is derived from agriculture, timber and fishing, and livestock and dairy production has been growing steadily. Export products, especially coffee and gold, have benefited from the recent rise in international commodity prices. Around two-thirds of Nicaragua's exports are to the US.</p><p>Struggling with a high public debt, Nicaragua has relied on a Poverty Reduction and Growth Facility (PRGF) with the International Monetary Fund (IMF). The most recent programme ended in 2011 and they are currently in negotiations for a new programme. It also depends heavily on foreign aid and remittances from Nicaraguans living in the US, Costa Rica and elsewhere, which reached over US$1 billion in 2012. Foreign direct investment is also on the rise.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Suits are usually worn for meetings at financial institutions but a smart shirt and trousers/skirt are acceptable for all other meetings. Punctuality is important, although typically meetings start late. Small talk is an integral part of most meetings but topics such as politics, religion or socioeconomic issues are best avoided, and the host should be left to turn the conversation to business. Meetings tend to end naturally rather than at a set time, and it's perceived as rude to rush off without stopping to chat. Knowledge of Spanish is an advantage, although many businesspeople speak English. Ask at the embassy for interpreter services. The best time to visit is December to April but bear in mind that hotels are often fully booked around Easter week, Christmas and New Year.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700. Some offices close for an hour at lunchtime (around 1230-1330).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cámara de Comercio de Nicaragua</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 268 3505
					Website:http://www.caconic.org.ni/
					Address: ,Rotonda Güegüense 400m al sur 20 varas este,Managua,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>At the heart of Nicaraguan cuisine are rice and beans, ubiquitous in different variations throughout Central America. The staple rice-and-beans dish, <em>gallo pinto</em>, keeps Nicaraguans going all day, served with everything from eggs for breakfast to steak for dinner.</p><p>Other typical dishes include grilled beef and chicken, <em>patacones</em> (fried green plantain chips), and freshwater fish like <em>guapote</em> (bass). Along the Atlantic coastline, with influences from the Caribbean islands, spices and coconut milk are often added to fish dishes, as well as various sweet and sticky pastries based on coconut. The country has an abundance of exotic fruits, such as <em>guanábana</em> (soursop), <em>maracuyá</em> (passion fruit) and <em>carambola</em> (star fruit), which are turned into delicious drinks. And don't miss the excellent rum.</p><p>Nicas tend to have breakfast early and then have long, leisurely lunches to avoid the midday heat. Many mid-range restaurants offer a <em>comida corriente</em>, a three-course set menu that works out cheaper than ordering a la carte. Street food should be avoided unless you have a cast-iron stomach.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gallo pinto</strong>: Fried rice mixed with beans, often served with sour cream and tortillas.<br />
<strong>Nacatamales:</strong> Corn dough filled with pork or chicken, rice and vegetables, all wrapped inside a banana leaf and boiled.<br />
<strong>Vigor&oacute;n:</strong> Yucca, <em>chicharr&oacute;n</em> (pork) and salad.<br />
<strong>Sopa de Mondongo:</strong> Tripe and vegetables soup.<br />
<strong>Rondon:</strong> Traditional local stew (from &ldquo;run down,&rdquo; Caribbean slang for &ldquo;cook&rdquo;) made of whatever meat and vegetables are available.<br />
<strong>Rosquillas:</strong> Cinnamon-topped corn biscuit rings.<br />
<strong>Tresleches:</strong> A sponge cake with milk, condensed milk and cream.<br />
<strong>Nicaraguan rum:</strong> One of the best is Flor de Ca&ntilde;a, an award-winning rum which comes in various guises (white, amber, light and dry).<br />
<strong>Pinolillo or pinol:</strong> Cornmeal and cacao-based drink, mixed with water or milk and served sweetened or unsweetened.<br />
<strong>Liquados:</strong> Fruit juice mixed in a blender with water or milk.<br />
<strong>Chicha:</strong> Fermented corn drink.<br />
<strong>Local beers:</strong> Nicaraguan beers are light lagers, always served ice-cold. Victoria and To&ntilde;a are the most popular brands.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>In upmarket restaurants, 10 to 15% is customary, but it's optional elsewhere. If you want to tip, it's better to give it direct to your server.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sociable Nicas love nothing better to go out to eat and drink, often in large groups. Dancing is always on the agenda and discotecas – from glitzy clubs to dingy bars – play everything from hip-hop to salsa, merengue and booty-shaking reggaeton. If you don't know your left foot from your right, there are often classes available.</p><p>Bars and cafés open by the week in Granada, from sophisticated cocktail bars in colonial courtyards (usually on the west side of the plaze), to more rustic beer joints on the lakeshore.</p><p>Student-filled León is bursting with bars that are open late most of the week, especially around the Teatro Municipal. Some even have a cultural slant, with poetry readings and discussions. Conversely, try laidback San Juan del Sur – it's main strip has a party feel, with happy hour cocktails, open mic nights, film nights, DJ's and live bands.</p><p>Managua's Zona Rosa is the up-and-coming party district, with clubs, bars, restaurants, clubs and a casino. The Zona Viva, around the Galerías Santo Domingo shopping mall, is another popular bar-hopping spot.</p><p>In rural areas, the drinking dens are more homespun and male oriented, and it's not Saturday night without a fight, so don't hang around until the bitter end.</p><p>Theatre is underfunded and limited but León, Granada and Managua's theatre are the places for performance arts. You're more likely to catch a dance troupe at one of the many saint's days and festivals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Masaya Market is the handicrafts mecca, where you'll find hand-embroidered clothing, wood carvings and hand-woven cotton hammocks, much of it made by artisans from the surrounding villages. Look out for black pottery from Jinotega, coconut shell jewellery from the Caribbean coast and finely carved cups made out of jicaro gourds from Rivas as well.</p><p>Shopaholics will love Granada, where there's everything from colonial-era antiques to high-end souvenirs and the work of local cooperatives, including hand-made jewellery and quirky bags made out of recycled materials. Wicker furniture, such as the ubiquitous rocking chairs, is beautifully made but difficult to transport.</p><p>In the Solentiname Archipelago, you can pick up colourful primitivist paintings of the islands' natural beauty direct from the artists, along with brightly painted balsa wood carvings of birds and animals.</p><p>Esteli is the place to go if you hanker after a pair of hand-tooled leather cowboy boots. They come in every shade imaginable and can be custom-made in a couple of days. Smokers can pick up good quality cigars too, including organic brands, hand rolled in the region's tobacco farms.</p><p>If you're in Managua, head to the Roberto Huembes market, where there's a wide selection of crafts from around the country. For a more sedate shopping experience, the Galerias, Metrocentro and Multicentro Las Americas malls have craft shops with higher prices than the markets plus a 15% sales tax, as do many of the high-end hotels.</p><p>Shops and shopping malls are open Mon-Sun 1000-2000. Markets open Mon-Sun 0900-1800.</p><p>Keep an eye on your belongings at crowded markets. Prices aren't generally marked up but if you want to haggle, you might get a discount of around 5-10%. There are few or no ATMs in rural areas and some retailers don't accept credit cards, so carry cash. US dollars are usually accepted, as well as córdobas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Up until a few years ago, Nicaragua's hotel scene was lacking. Corporate hotels in the main cities catering to business travellers were available but that was the main extent of it. Over the past few years the tourist industry has expanded, as visitors seek an off-the-beaten-track alternative to Costa Rica. As such, its hotel industry has grown, and whilst in Managua and Granada you'll find those 4- and 5-star hotels with conference facilities, there are now other options, and new hotels catering for different kinds of traveller. From charming boutique properties converted into hotels in Leon and San Juan del Sur, to intimate lodges that can be found in the jungle - ecotourism is taking off here and some excellent hacienda-style accommodation and lodges can be found. A 15% tax is levied on all hotel bills. <br/><br/><strong>Grading: </strong>Accommodation is graded using a star rating system. For more information, contact the Nicaraguan Institute of Tourism (INTUR)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guest houses are found throughout the country. Although usually more limited in their facilities, these can offer decent value for money, and are a good option for those on stricter budgets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Up until a few years ago, Nicaragua's hotel scene was lacking. Corporate hotels in the main cities catering to business travellers were available but that was the main extent of it. Over the past few years the tourist industry has expanded, as visitors seek an off-the-beaten-track alternative to Costa Rica. As such, its hotel industry has grown, and whilst in Managua and Granada you'll find those 4- and 5-star hotels with conference facilities, there are now other options, and new hotels catering for different kinds of traveller. From charming boutique properties converted into hotels in Leon and San Juan del Sur, to intimate lodges that can be found in the jungle - ecotourism is taking off here and some excellent hacienda-style accommodation and lodges can be found. A 15% tax is levied on all hotel bills. <br/><br/><strong>Grading: </strong>Accommodation is graded using a star rating system. For more information, contact the Nicaraguan Institute of Tourism (INTUR)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Up until a few years ago, Nicaragua's hotel scene was lacking. Corporate hotels in the main cities catering to business travellers were available but that was the main extent of it. Over the past few years the tourist industry has expanded, as visitors seek an off-the-beaten-track alternative to Costa Rica. As such, its hotel industry has grown, and whilst in Managua and Granada you'll find those 4- and 5-star hotels with conference facilities, there are now other options, and new hotels catering for different kinds of traveller. From charming boutique properties converted into hotels in Leon and San Juan del Sur, to intimate lodges that can be found in the jungle - ecotourism is taking off here and some excellent hacienda-style accommodation and lodges can be found. A 15% tax is levied on all hotel bills. <br/><br/><strong>Grading: </strong>Accommodation is graded using a star rating system. For more information, contact the Nicaraguan Institute of Tourism (INTUR)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Each department of Nicaragua has a public hospital. These do not charge for emergency services, but do charge for supplies and medicines. There is an extensive network of health posts and health centres in rural areas, but their resources can be limited. There are several private hospitals/clinics in Managua. Many doctors and hospitals require payment in cash before treatment, although some private hospitals may accept credit cards. International travellers are strongly advised to take out full medical insurance before departure. The number for medical emergencies is 118. There is also a free hotline specifically for tourists in need of immediate assistance - if you've had an accident, lost important travel documents or been the victim of any crime, call 101.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tap water in Managua has been tested and declared safe to drink. Nicaragua's water is treated and chlorinated, but beyond the capital, it is advised to drink bottled water and avoid ice cubes. Milk in rural areas may be unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended and there are occasional cases of cholera. There has also been an increase in reported cases of dengue fever; to help avoid mosquito bites, cover up and use repellent. Although the risk of rabies is low, you're advised not touch or pet any stray dogs and animals that you may come across. If swimming, do take care to look out for any signs or warnings regarding strong currents and riptides.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Many local holidays are also observed.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Below are listed Public Holidays for the January 2014-December 2015 period.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Holy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Sandinista Revolution Anniversary :
							19 July </p><p>Battle of San Jacinto :
							14 September </p><p>Independence Day :
							15 September </p><p>All Soul's Day :
							02 November </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items can be imported into Nicaragua by travellers aged 21 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 20 packs of cigarettes or 50 cigars or 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 5L of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; 2kg of confectionery.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of US$500 (provided you've been out of the country for at least 72 hours).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Restricted items include fresh food, live animals and plants and their products. A special permit is required for firearms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Archaeological items, artefacts of historical or monetary value, and gold.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nicaraguan Gold Córdoba (NIO; symbol C$) = 100 centavos. Notes are in denominations of C$500, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of C$5 and 1, and 50, 25, 10 and 5 centavos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged at the airport, at banks and at official bureaux de change in major cities. US Dollars are the most easily exchanged currency and are also accepted as payment throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are widely accepted by hotels, restaurants and medium to large sized businesses. Smaller businesses and mom-and-pop operations may deal in cash only.</p><p>There are ATMs in most tourist areas. Whilst the majority are reliable and will work with cards, there's always the chance that they won't work, so plan accordingly. Most ATMs give Cordobas and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars. When paying in cash, notes in less than perfect condition may not be accepted; don't accept any that are ripped or have marks on them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These can only be changed in some banks and are not widely accepted. There may be a fee for cashing them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1630, Sat 0830-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Nicaragua, a passport valid for at least six months from the date of arrival is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above. US travellers only require a passport valid for the duration of their stay.</p>
<p>Nicaragua is party to the Central America Border Control Agreement (CA-4). Under the terms of this agreement, tourists may travel within any of the CA-4 countries (El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras and Nicaragua) for a period of up to 90 days, without completing entry and exit formalities at border immigration checkpoints. This period begins at the first point of entry into any of the CA-4 countries. Fines are applied for travellers who exceed this 90-day limit, although a 30-day extension can be made before the 90 days limit expires.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitor visa: NIO200 (ordinary); NIO400 (three months); NIO800 (six months); NIO1,600 (one year).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Up to a year.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 24 hours for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[12.904032]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-84.922007]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>130,370 sq km (50,336 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6,150,035 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>45.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Managua.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nicaragua is the largest country in central America, bordering Honduras to the north and Costa Rica to the south. To the east lies the Caribbean, and to the west the Pacific. In the north are the Isabella Mountains, while the country's main feature in the southwest is Lake Nicaragua, 148km (92 miles) long and about 55km (34 miles) at its widest. The island of Ometepe is the largest of the 310 islands on the lake. These islands have a reputation for great beauty and are one of the country's main tourist attractions.</p>
<p>Lake Managua is situated to the northwest. Volcanoes, including the famous Momotombo, protrude from the surrounding lowlands northwest of the lakes. The country's main rivers are the San Juan, the lower reaches of which form the border with Costa Rica, and the Rio Grande. The Corn Islands (Islas del Maiz) in the Caribbean are two small beautiful islands fringed with white coral and palms. They are very popular as holiday resorts with both Nicaraguans and tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>75% Roman Catholic; 15% Protestant; 10% other.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nicaraguans greet each other with a handshake, or for someone you know well, a kiss on the cheek and a hug. Casual dress is fine in most situations, although some formality will be expected in business situations. Puncutality is not a strong suit of Nicaragua, and it's not unusual for people to turn up 20-40 minutes late for a meeting. If invited to someone's home it is customary and polite to give the host a small gift. If offered something to eat, try to accept or at least try it; refusal may cause some offence.</p><p>Whilst travelling around Nicaragua, be prepared to be stared at, especially if visiting more rural areas – this is more out of curiosity than anything else. The same goes for conversations; while you may get a few very blunt questions, it is generally not out of rudeness. <br/><strong>Photography: </strong>Avoid photographing military sites or personnel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>120 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins are used; not all sockets have space for a grounding pin however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Daniel Ortega since 2007.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Daniel Ortega since 2007.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ruthless dictators, oppression and natural disasters have characterised Nicaragua&rsquo;s fascinating though troubled history.</p>
<p>Originally, the country was occupied by migrating ethnic groups, from South and Central America. Arriving in 1524, the Spanish took control and stayed for around 300 years, enslaving the indigenous population, building the cities of Granada and Le&oacute;n and fending off attacks from Dutch, French and British pirates. Conflict in Europe gradually weakened Spain&rsquo;s hold over the New World and Nicaragua finally became independent in 1821, becoming a fully independent republic in 1838.</p>
<p>In 1909, the United States began to exert its power over the fledgling nation, opening military bases over the coming years to steer an election in its favour. But Augusto Sandino &ndash; who later gave his name to the Sandinistas &ndash; launched a guerrilla campaign that forced them out by 1933.</p>
<p>However, a new internal power stood in their way: the paramilitary National Guard led by General Anastasio Somoza. In 1934, he ordered the arrest and execution of Sandino and his senior commanders. Two years later he became president and established a brutal and corrupt dictatorship that lasted for almost half a century.</p>
<p>When Somoza was assassinated in 1956, his sons Luis and Anastasio took over. In the early 1960s, the Marxist Frente Sandinista de Liberaci&oacute;n Nacional (FSLN), or Sandinistas, formed but soon disbanded. A turning point came in 1972, when an earthquake in Managua killed over 10,000 people and left 500,000 homeless. The government siphoned off much of the international relief money and opposition to them began to grow amongst all social classes.</p>
<p>The Sandinistas regrouped and, after a short but bloody conflict, the government was overturned in 1979. They then began a programme of agrarian reform that gave land back to the peasants, nationalised industry and set up health and literacy programmes.</p>
<p>But peace was short-lived. In 1981, the United States set about toppling the Sandinistas, with Ronald Reagan&rsquo;s anti-communist campaign funding the Contra guerrilla forces. The Sandinistas lost popularity during the Contra war but Daniel Ortega survived as leader and, after losing the 1990, 1996 and 2001 elections, he was re-elected in 2006 and, controversially, again in 2011.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Nicaraguans sometimes call themselves &ldquo;pinoleros&rdquo;, after the soft drink, pinol, which is popular throughout the country.<br />
&bull;	Nicaragua plans to build an inter-ocean canal to rival Panama's, almost 120 years after it was first proposed.<br />
&bull;	US president Franklin D. Roosevelt once said of ruthless dictator Anastasio Somoza: &ldquo;He may be a son of a bitch, but he&rsquo;s our son of a bitch.&rdquo;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Nicaragua in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7938 2373.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7938 2373.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>58-60 Kensington Church Street<br/>Vicarage House, Suite 12<br/>London<br/>W8 4DB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Nicaragua in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 939 6570.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 939 6570.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Costa Rica]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(506) 2258 2025.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/costa-rica</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(506) 2258 2025.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0830-1600, Fri 0830-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Apartado 815 - 1007<br/>Edificio Centro Colón, Paseo Colón and Streets 38 and 40<br/>San Jose<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fabled land of lakes and volcanoes, Nicaragua also lays claim to vibrant colonial cities, deserted beaches and wildlife-rich rainforests. It&rsquo;s Costa Rica, without the crowds &ndash; for now, at least. The largest country in Central America, Nicaragua is also the safest and one of the cheapest. That visitor numbers are increasing should come as no surprise.</p>
<p>What Nicaragua lacks in standout cultural attractions it compensates for with natural beauty. Its reefs and rainforests are hotbeds of biodiversity and teem with jaguars, monkeys and myriad bird species (though how this idyll will look after the Nicaragua Grand Canal has been built remains to be seen).</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s wild landscapes are fertile ground for thrill-seekers. Visitors can go hiking, biking, kayaking and wild swimming in the country&rsquo;s iconic crater lakes. They can ride some of the world&rsquo;s biggest waves, speed along zip-lines above the jungle or scuba dive along shelves of iridescent coral. Too much like hard work? Then kick back on the twin peaks of Ometepe Island, overlooking the shimmering Lake Nicaragua, or catch a boat into the Ind&iacute;o Maiz Biological Reserve, the largest area of virgin rainforest north of the Amazon.</p>
<p>Those hankering for the city life should head to Le&oacute;n or Granada, two of Central America&rsquo;s pretties colonial cities. They&rsquo;re hubs for travellers and gateways to nearby attractions. From Le&oacute;n you can climb the Maribios volcanic chain, snowboard down the slopes of still-rumbling Cerro Negro or pick coffee beans in the temperate northern highlands. Granada, meanwhile, is the ideal base to explore Masaya&rsquo;s volcanic park, zip-line over Mombacho&rsquo;s cloud forest and take a cooling swim in Laguna de Apoyo.</p>
<p>Surfers head for San Juan del Sur in search of the perfect wave &ndash; they often find it &ndash; and to imbibe its buzzing party scene. Others abscond to the Corn Islands, an archipelago that has everything you'd expect from the Caribbean, minus the sky-high prices. So grab a beer and join the party &ndash; it&rsquo;s only just begun.</p><p>Fabled land of lakes and volcanoes, Nicaragua also lays claim to vibrant colonial cities, deserted beaches and wildlife-rich rainforests. It&rsquo;s Costa Rica, without the crowds &ndash; for now, at least. The largest country in Central America, Nicaragua is also the safest and one of the cheapest. That visitor numbers are increasing should come as no surprise.</p>
<p>What Nicaragua lacks in standout cultural attractions it compensates for with natural beauty. Its reefs and rainforests are hotbeds of biodiversity and teem with jaguars, monkeys and myriad bird species (though how this idyll will look after the Nicaragua Grand Canal has been built remains to be seen).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
