<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Nigeria" ColCode="nga" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ng" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Nigeria]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Varies from area to area. The southern coast is hot and humid with a rainy season from March to November. During the dry season, the <em>Harmattan</em> wind blows from the Sahara. The north's rainy season is from July to September. Nights can be cold in December and January.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are worn, with a warm wrap advisable in the north. Rainwear is essential during the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria's aviation industry can be unreliable, with new operators springing up (and shutting down) regularly. One of the most reliable internal airlines is Arik Air (<a href="http://www.arikair.com" target="_blank">www.arikair.com</a>), which operates domestic flights as well as to regional and international destinations. Whichever airline you book with, lengthy delays are common and flights may be cancelled at short notice. Charter facilities are available in Lagos from Aero (<a href="http://www.flyaero.com" target="_blank">www.flyaero.com</a>). Domestic flights can be expensive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferry services operate along the south coast and along the Niger and Benue rivers. For timetables and prices, enquire locally. Metro Ferry (<a href="http://www.metro-ferry.com" target="_blank">www.metro-ferry.com</a>) operates daily ferry services around Lagos. River boats ply the Niger river but are often overloaded and dangerous.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>At 1,126km (700 miles), the Lagos-Kano (via Ibadan-Oyo-Ogbomosho-Kaduna-Zaria) link is the longest railway in the country, stretching from the south to the north. The journey takes 31 hours. Trains also run from Port Harcourt to Maiduguri (via Aba-Enugu-Makurdi-Jos). These two lines link up Kaduna and Kafanchan.</p>
<p>There is also a branch line from Zaria to Gusau and Kaura Namoda. A daily service runs on both main routes. Sleeping cars are available, which you must book in advance. There are three classes and some trains have restaurant cars and air conditioning. Trains are generally slower and less reliable than buses, but cheaper.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria's road network is extensive but is in bad shape outside of major cities. Traffic is a serious problem in Lagos, while road safety in general is a major cause of loss of life. Exercise caution when travelling by road, especially at night, and wear seat belts when possible (not all cars, especially older vehicles, are equipped with them in the back seats).</p>
<p>In the north you may encounter military checkpoints; carry your passport with you at all times. Traffic police regularly ask for bribes. Other drivers can also prove a hazard, particularly truck drivers who may not always take frequent breaks.</p>r<p>The national road system links all the main centres, although in some areas secondary roads become impassable during the rains. Reports of armed robberies in broad daylight on rural roads in the northern half of Nigeria have been reported and appear to be increasing.</p><p>Companies like ABC Transport (<a href="http://www.abctransport.com" target="_blank">www.abctransport.com</a>) and Greener Line operate long-distance coach services that are much cheaper than flying. Conditions and levels of comfort vary.</p><p>Buses and taxis (or 'bush taxis' in the shape of Ford Transit vans) run between the main towns. Taxis (yellow, or black and orange) can be hailed in the street in most places but it's best to call ahead in major urban areas. Try Easy Taxi (<a href="http://www.easytaxi.com/ng" target="_blank">www.easytaxi.com/ng</a>) in Lagos. It's best to haggle for a rate before jumping in, since metered fares can be extremely high in Lagos and Abuja.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>The speed limit for cars is 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 80kph (50mph) on highways and 100kph (62mph) on expressways. Seat belts are compulsory for drivers and front-seat passengers.</p><p>There is no national breakdown service; motorists are advised to use independent services.</p><p>Cars are best hired with drivers for reasons of safety, insurance and bureaucracy. In Abuja and Lagos, try Avis (<a href="http://www.avisng.com" target="_blank">www.avisng.com</a>) or ask your hotel to recommend a reliable local company. Elsewhere in Nigeria, hotel staff can point you in the direction of a trustworthy firm.</p><p>With its pollution and accident record, Lagos is far from a cyclist's paradise. In rural areas, bikes are more common.</p><p>The speed limit for cars is 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 80kph (50mph) on highways and 100kph (62mph) on expressways. Seat belts are compulsory for drivers and front-seat passengers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public transport in Lagos operates in rather chaotic conditions. The city suffers from chronic traffic congestion, which makes it impossible for transport to operate efficiently, especially during the rush hours. There are many private bus companies and several thousand private minibuses. Taxis in Lagos are yellow and both fares and tip should be agreed in advance. A ferry service runs to Lagos Island.</p>
<p>Transport in Abuja is easier to negotiate than in Lagos, since there is less traffic, but prices remain high for journeys by taxi. It is wise to avoid travelling during rush hour in both cities if you are able.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating direct flights from the UK to Nigeria include Arik Air (<a href="http://www.arikair.com" target="_blank">www.arikair.com</a>), British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>)&nbsp;and Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>). Med-View Airline (<a href="http://www.medviewairline.com/" target="_blank">www.medviewairline.com</a>) is currently prohibited from flying to the EU due to safety concerns. From the USA, you can fly from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/houston">Houston</a> to Lagos with United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>).</p>
<p>The peak time to fly is usually during school holidays or festive periods, especially Christmas, Easter and Eid-al-Fitr. The cheapest times of year to fly are usually outside of these periods, although flight prices do not vary dramatically from one season to another. Flights between London and Lagos tend to get booked up quite far ahead of time, especially during festive periods.</p>
<p>Major airports that are located in Nigeria are:&nbsp;<a href="http://i/nigeria/lagos-murtala-muhammed-international-airport">Lagos Murtala Muhammed International Airport</a>., Nnamdi Azikwe International Airport, Mallam Aminu Kano International Airport and Port Harcourt International Airport.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 6 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/houston">Houston</a> - 11 hours 25 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 14 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some airlines permit higher baggage allowances in all travel classes when flying to Nigeria; Arik Air allows passengers to take two 30kg bags as hold luggage. These are often issued at no cost, and allow Nigerians to fly back from Europe to Nigeria with heavy purchases.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some airlines permit higher baggage allowances in all travel classes when flying to Nigeria; Arik Air allows passengers to take two 30kg bags as hold luggage. These are often issued at no cost, and allow Nigerians to fly back from Europe to Nigeria with heavy purchases.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Lagos Murtala Muhammed International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.faannigeria.org<p>Lagos Murtala Muhammed International Airport is situated in the suburb of Ikeja, 12km (7 miles) northwest of Lagos.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+234 1 493 3385</p>]]><b>Abuja International Airport </b><![CDATA[http://abuja.airport-authority.com/<p>The airport is 35km (22 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Mallam Aminu Kano International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 8km (5 miles) north of Kano.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports are Lagos, Port Harcourt and Calabar. Other important ports include Warri and Sapele.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria shares land borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/benin">Benin</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/niger">Niger</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/chad">Chad</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cameroon">Cameroon</a>. One of the most popular land routes into Nigeria is via Benin. You can drive fairly easily from Accra in <a href="http://i/ghana">Ghana</a> to the Nigerian border via <a href="http://i/togo">Togo</a> and Benin; expect at least one full day's drive from Ghana's border with Togo to Nigeria's border with Benin. The road is generally in good condition and a 4-wheel drive isn't required; however visas for all transiting countries are necessary.</p>
<p>Some travellers extend this route, going overland from Europe (via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a>) to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/morocco">Morocco</a> (by car ferry) and onwards through <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/senegal">Senegal</a>, The Gambia, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guinea">Guinea</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sierra-leone">Sierra Leone</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/">Liberia</a> and Ivory Coast. This route is generally free of security concerns but the roads can prove hazardous during the rainy season. Check the UK&nbsp;Foreign and Commonwealth Office travel advisory before setting out. It is not recommended to cross into Nigeria from Niger or Chad due to security concerns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is average.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet and e-mail services are available in Internet cafes in Lagos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria's media scene is one of the most vibrant in Africa. State-run radio and TV services reach virtually all parts of the country and operate at a federal and regional level. All 36 states run their own radio stations, and most of them operate TV services. Despite high levels of violence, the private press still occasionally criticises the Government.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe is unreliable and takes up to three weeks. Delivery may be more reliable through international couriers who are represented in major towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the art deco at Ibadan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pleasant Ibadan is worth a visit for its adventurous architecture; there are colonial buildings, art deco gems and buildings emblazoned with traditional Nigerian emblems. The city itself (Nigeria's third largest, after Lagos and Kano) has a large university and vibrant student nightlife.</p>]]><p><b>Appreciate the bygone beauty of Emir's Palace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Circumnavigate the walled old town of Kano, formerly the largest of the ancient Hausa cities, and soak up its lingering medieval atmosphere. Founded at least 1,000 years ago, it was of strategic importance on the trans-Saharan trade routes. Visit the Emir's Palace, which remains an outstanding example of Hausa architecture, and pop by the glorious Gidan Makama Museum. Security an issue in Kano these days, so heed the latest travel advice.</p>]]><p><b>Bring out the binoculars for Gashaka Game Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria's most scenic national park, the Gashaka Game Reserve near Yola provides opportunities to view over 500 species of birds. As well as being home to some highly endangered species, including the rare Adamawa mountain reedbuck, the park features large African elephant and giant eland.</p>]]><p><b>Cool down in Calabar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Calabar is a pleasant town in a beautiful setting, high on a hill above the Calabar River. It has a Mediterranean feel, with its whitewashed houses, clean(ish) streets and slightly cool climate. Don't miss the giant cast iron hand sculptures in the park outside the slave museum; shacked but cut at the wrist, they represent breaking free from the past.</p>]]><p><b>Discover ancient Ile-Ife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ile-Ife, the ancient name of the town of Ife, is another recess of Yoruba culture, and includes the Ife Museum, which has many fine bronze and terracotta sculptures dating back to the 13th century. Traditional Yoruba rulers are known as Oònis, visit the palace to see the Yemolu Well, from which only the incumbent can drink.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the brilliant, bustling Benin City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Modern Benin City is a rapidly developing metropolis, but there are a few reminders of its long Yoruba history. The old city's moat and wall survive in places, and the National Museum houses an interesting collection of Benin royal art. The Oba's Palace is worth visiting, although permission needs to be obtained in Lagos.</p>]]><p><b>Hike up Shere Hills for fantastic views</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Shere Hills offer some of the West Africa's best hiking. Lace up your boots and trail up towards the high peaks of about 1,800m (5,900ft). Not all of the routes are marked, and you may want to take a guide with you in case you lose your way. The views are spectacular.</p>]]><p><b>Pack a picnic and head for Jos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Picnic without breaking a sweat in Jos, a favourite holiday spot on account of its location 1,200m (3,900ft) above sea level, meaning it has a pleasantly cool climate. The nearby Assob Falls and the many streams and dams that come from them, make this an extremely pretty area.</p>]]><p><b>Scale the seven Olumirin Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Local legend has it that the seven Olumirin Falls descend from a huge pot of water at the top of the cliff. Indeed, these falls close to Akure are supposedly bestowed with all kinds of magical powers. They also represent a feat of strength, for travellers fit and cautious enough to climb to the top, the views are magnificent.</p>]]><p><b>See ancient monoliths in Cross River National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Journey through the Cross River National Park from the town of Ikom, which has curious carved monoliths set in circles, believed to be ancient monuments assembled in reverence to ancestors. In the Rainforest Conservation area, you'll find majestic mountains and rolling hills, with wildlife including leopards, buffalos, chimpanzees, gorillas, baboons and elephants.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out the Palace of the Emir of Zazzau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If security conditions allow access to the north, Zaria's old city is unmissable. Far more enjoyable to stroll around than Kano, there are a number of beautiful old buildings, not least the Palace of the Emir of Zazzau. The gate of the palace is a colourful mosaic whilst sandstone walls, adobe mud compounds and mosques line the ancient streets nearby.</p>]]><p><b>Swim beneath the Gurara Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Niger state's Gurara Falls, at a height of about 20m (66ft), are well off the beaten track, and that's part of what makes them such a special place to visit. Unlike other big waterfalls in Africa, you won't have to compete with hordes of tourists, and can swim in the small pools at the bottom of the cascading falls. </p>]]><p><b>Uncover Nigeria's ancient past at the National Museum in Lagos</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The National Museum at Onikan on Lagos Island houses numerous exhibits of Nigeria's ancient civilisations and has a craft centre, which sells examples of Nigerian craft at fixed prices. There's a nice collection of Nigerian art inside the exhibition halls. Cameras are not allowed inside.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the sacred shrine of Osogbo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Worship the Yoruba goddess of fertility in Osogbo, home to the famous Osun Shrine and sacred grove of Oshun. Every year, towards the end of August as the rainy season finishes, thousands of childless women head to the Osun Festival to seek the help of the Yoruba goddess of fertility.</p>]]><p><b>Watch wildlife and unwind in warm springs, Yankari National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Yankari National Park, in the east of the country, is a particularly good spot for bird-watching. Animals that can be viewed here include elephants, crocodiles and monkeys. The park has accommodation, restaurants and a swimming pool – though visitors keen on bathing should head instead to the Wikki Warm Spring.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$510bn (2013).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum and related products, cocoa and rubber.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, chemicals, transport equipment, manufactured goods, food and live animals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Brazil, China (PR), UK, Spain, The Netherlands, France, Germany and Italy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria became Africa's biggest economy in 2014, taking the title from South Africa. It's also the continent's largest oil producer, earning 90% of the country's export income and underpinning its economy for decades. Nigeria also has vast quantities of natural gas, coal, tin, iron ore, zinc and uranium, many of which remain untapped. Nigeria is expected to be among the world's 20 biggest economies by 2020. Per capita GDP was US $2800 per year, while national GDP for 2013 was US $510bn. Yet Nigeria has a significant wealth gap, with about 60% of its population living in poverty.</p>
<p>Agriculture occupies well over half of the population, who produce rice, maize, cassava, sorghum and millet as staples, as well as groundnuts, cocoa, palm oil and rubber as cash crops. But it only accounts for about 21% of Nigeria's GDP. Timber and livestock rearing have both developed during the last 20 years. Nonetheless, successive governments have failed to restore Nigeria's one-time self-sufficiency in food.Manufacturing was established during the 1960s, principally with oil money, and now includes food processing and the production of vehicles, textiles, pharmaceuticals, paper and cement.</p>
<p>Recent economic performance has been determined mainly by the state of the world oil market. Governmental deregulation of fuel prices and the privatisation of Nigeria's four oil refineries in 2003, coupled with the rise in oil production, contributed to Nigeria's recent dramatic GDP growth. Nigeria is the dominant member of the West African economic cooperation organisation, ECOWAS, as well as a leading member of the oil producers' cartel, OPEC.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>English is spoken in business circles. It is common for business meetings to take place without a prior appointment, although these should be made for government visits. Business deals will often progress at a slower pace than is common in Europe. Owing to the prevalence of commercial fraud targeting foreigners, business travellers should contact both their local Nigerian Embassy and Chamber of Commerce before travelling to Nigeria.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600 (government offices); 0830-1700 (private businesses). However, offices in the northern states may close at 1300 as Muslim workers may take part in prayer services at 1400; business resumes after this.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Nigerian High Commission's Nigerian Information Service Center in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7839 1244
					Website:http://www.nigeriahc.org.uk
					Address: ,9 Northumberland Avenue,London WC2N 5BX,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Lagos, Abuja and other major cities have a big selection of restaurants, serving everything from traditional Nigerian dishes to French baguettes, excellent sushi and good hamburgers. In short, European, North American and Asian tastes are well catered for, and you'll also find a range of different cuisines from across the African continent.</p>
<p>Although there are self-service cafes, mainly in department stores, most restaurants have table service. In the north, meat is more popular than in other areas, although it's important to note that pork is forbidden in devout Muslim areas such as Kano. Spirits are expensive, as are imported wines and beers. Larger hotels and clubs have bars and cocktail lounges, and there are standalone nightspots in most urban areas.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Yam.<br />
&bull; Sweet potatoes.<br />
&bull; Suya (dried barbecued liver and beef on sticks) and kilishi (spiced dried meat).<br />
&bull; In the east, egussi soup (stew of meat, dried fish and melon seeds).<br />
&bull; In the south, goat meat and bush meat (particularly antelope) are considered a delicacy.<br />
&bull; Cassava (Nigeria is the world's largest producer of cassava, and cassava stews and dishes are popular).<br />
&bull; Fufu or sakora (a doughy, starchy dish made from sticky cassava or plantain, used like bread to scoop up soups and sauces).<br />
&bull; Dodo (delicious, fried, caramelised plantain slices, often served at roadside canteens).<br />
&bull; Boli and epa (baked plantains served with peanuts).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Unless a service charge has been included, a 10% tip is expected for most services.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>The legal drinking age in Nigeria is 18, although in practice this is rarely enforced. Note that in parts of northern Nigeria's Kano state, alcohol is banned.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria certainly knows how to party. In the south of the country, wherever you are you can bet your bottom Naira that there's a good nightclub nearby. Lagos and Abuja are famous for their slick, expensive clubs that attract a monied crowd, hip new DJs, jazz bands and big names from the 90s in Europe.</p>
<p>Don't miss New Africa Shine, a club modelled on the late Nigerian singer Fela Kuti's The Shrine club in Lagos, and now the home of 'Felabration!', the musical. Deuces club on Victoria Island in Lagos is one of the city's smoothest venues; expect men in milky white suits, women in expensive heels and bottles of champers that will leave your pockets empty. Baccus in Ikoyi is one of Lagos' oldest clubs and always attracts a fun crowd, while the studenty Koko Lounge (E-Centre, 1-11 Commercial Avenue) in Lagos's hipster district of Yaba proves that you can still shake it on lemonade pockets. There are also fun street markets all over the country, often with live entertainment: north of Oyo in Ogbomosho is noteworthy. And if you're lucky enough to be invited to a Nigerian wedding, you'll get to experience the best party of all.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria is now Africa's biggest economy and spending power is increasing. There's great shopping to be found across all sectors and for all budgets, from rural market bargains to fine art sales in Lagos. Nigeria's markets are often big, buzzing and stuffed with everything from food to jewellery and books to batteries. If you're in Lagos, head to Lekki market, which has a serious selection of Nigerian souvenirs to take back home with you; think beaded necklaces, long silver earrings, wooden carved masks, colourful wax cloth (which you can also take to tailors just outside the market, to be made into outfits for men, women or children), tablecloths, paintings and scarves. Just be prepared to bargain.</p>
<p>Ikot Ekepne is the centre for beautiful baskets and carvings, and at Oron there is a museum renowned for its exhibits of Ibibio and Efik carvings. In Kano in the north, Kurmi Market has lots of tourist souvenirs, including the richly embroidered horse blankets and decorations used at festivals. Other purchases in markets around the country include herbs, beadwork, basketry and ceremonial masks. It's worth looking for adire (patterned, indigo-dyed cloth), batiks and pottery from the southwest, leatherwork and kaduna cotton from the north, and carvings from the east. Designs vary greatly, with many towns having their own distinctive style, but the famous indigo dye pits in Abeokuta are well worth a visit. On sunny days, you can watch the adire and batik fabrics being dyed using cassava paste and wax, and learn to tell the difference between authentic Nigerian cloth and patterns that are mass-produced in China.</p>
<p>The African Artists Foundation (AAF) on Ikoyi in Lagos (<a href="http://www.africanartists.org" target="_blank">www.africanartists.org</a>) is a great place to start if you're interested in picking up some contemporary Nigerian fine art. There are regular exhibitions and gallery openings by renowned and up-and-coming painters, sculptors and photographers, such as Joseph Eze and Obinna Makata. Baronet Art Gallery sells hip metal artwork, while the Hourglass Art Gallery (<a href="http://www.hourglassgallery.com" target="_blank">www.hourglassgallery.com</a>) is a good stop for paintings. But a word of warning: art, like most things, does not come cheap in Lagos.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700, Sat 0800-1630, with some stores open on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are first-class hotels in Lagos and in the major towns, but they are heavily booked and advance reservation is essential. Lagos is one of the most congested cities in Africa, and the majority of good hotels are on Lagos Island. Hotels are generally very expensive, but there is a variety of alternative accommodation. Further information can be obtained from the Nigeria Tourism Development Corporation (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).<br />Government-run <strong>catering rest houses </strong>are scattered throughout the country and offer accommodation in colonial-style rest houses. In many towns, <strong>Christian missions </strong>are able to offer good basic accommodation at a reasonable price. The universities have <strong>guest houses </strong>for visiting academics, but may be able to accommodate other visitors. Most of the big towns have <strong>sporting clubs </strong>which offer cheap accommodation and eating facilities, and can be used by visitors who take temporary membership. Port Harcourt is the centre of the national oil industry and offers a large selection of accommodation to the industry, which is also available to tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are first-class hotels in Lagos and in the major towns, but they are heavily booked and advance reservation is essential. Lagos is one of the most congested cities in Africa, and the majority of good hotels are on Lagos Island. Hotels are generally very expensive, but there is a variety of alternative accommodation. Further information can be obtained from the Nigeria Tourism Development Corporation (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).<br />Government-run <strong>catering rest houses </strong>are scattered throughout the country and offer accommodation in colonial-style rest houses. In many towns, <strong>Christian missions </strong>are able to offer good basic accommodation at a reasonable price. The universities have <strong>guest houses </strong>for visiting academics, but may be able to accommodate other visitors. Most of the big towns have <strong>sporting clubs </strong>which offer cheap accommodation and eating facilities, and can be used by visitors who take temporary membership. Port Harcourt is the centre of the national oil industry and offers a large selection of accommodation to the industry, which is also available to tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are first-class hotels in Lagos and in the major towns, but they are heavily booked and advance reservation is essential. Lagos is one of the most congested cities in Africa, and the majority of good hotels are on Lagos Island. Hotels are generally very expensive, but there is a variety of alternative accommodation. Further information can be obtained from the Nigeria Tourism Development Corporation (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).<br />Government-run <strong>catering rest houses </strong>are scattered throughout the country and offer accommodation in colonial-style rest houses. In many towns, <strong>Christian missions </strong>are able to offer good basic accommodation at a reasonable price. The universities have <strong>guest houses </strong>for visiting academics, but may be able to accommodate other visitors. Most of the big towns have <strong>sporting clubs </strong>which offer cheap accommodation and eating facilities, and can be used by visitors who take temporary membership. Port Harcourt is the centre of the national oil industry and offers a large selection of accommodation to the industry, which is also available to tourists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The government-provided health care facilities are of a poor standard and are subject to shortages of drugs, equipment, materials and even electricity. It is advisable to take a sufficient supply of drugs or medication to meet personal needs. However, there are some adequate private facilities where the standards approach those of Europe. Doctors and hospitals often expect immediate cash payment for health services. There is no reciprocal health agreement with the UK. Medical insurance is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against meningococcal meningitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Workers' Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							01 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Nigeria by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200g of tobacco products.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits and 1L of wine.<br />
&bull; 284ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Gifts to the value of ₦50,000 (excluding jewellery, photographic equipment, electronics and luxury goods).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include birds and birds' eggs, pork, beef, water containing added sugar or sweeteners, certain medicines and mosquito repellent coils. For a full list see <a href="http://www.customs.gov.ng" target="_blank">www.customs.gov.ng</a>.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All banned imports as well as maize, timber, raw hides or skin, endangered species, and artefacts and antiquities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Naira (NGN; symbol ₦) = 100 kobo. Notes are in denominations of ₦500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of ₦1 and kobo 25, 10, 5 and 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government of Nigeria has fixed an artificially high rate for local currency (the Naira) in terms of its value in exchange for foreign currencies. However, trading on the black market is extremely dangerous and could lead to arrest. Therefore, visitors are advised to exchange currency at the official rate and at approved exchange facilities, which often include major hotels. Inter-bank transfers are frequently difficult, if not impossible, to accomplish.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are rarely accepted in Nigeria and, because of the prevalence of credit card fraud, their use is ill-advised.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Facilities for changing traveller's cheques are limited to Abuja and larger towns, but exchanging them can be problematic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon 0800-1500, Tue-Fri 0800-1330.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Nigeria, a passport valid for a minimum of six months beyond the date of departure is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa: &pound;20 (normal service); &pound;70 (one-day express service). Business visas are free for all nationals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist: up to six months. Multiple-entry visas are available in certain cases.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy or high commission). In the UK, you should apply through Online Integrated Solutions (OIS) (<a href="http://oisservices.com" target="_blank">oisservices.com</a>), which processes visas on behalf of the high commission. OIS charges an additional &pound;72 service charge.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow five days for visa processing or one day for the express service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When applying for a visa, you must provide evidence of sufficient funds to cover your stay in Nigeria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[9.081999]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[8.675277]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>923,768 sq km (356,669 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>181,526,056 (UN estimate 2016)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>204.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Abuja.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria has borders with Niger to the north, Chad (across Lake Chad) to the northeast, Cameroon to the east and Benin to the west. To the south, the Gulf of Guinea is indented by the Bight of Benin and the Bight of Biafra. The country's topography and vegetation vary considerably.</p>
<p>The coastal region is a low-lying area of lagoons, sandy beaches and mangrove swamps, which merges into an area of rainforest where palm trees grow to over 30m (100ft). From here, the landscape changes to savannah and open woodland, rising to the Central Jos Plateau at 1,800m (6,000ft). The northern part of the country is desert and semi-desert, marking the southern extent of the Sahara.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>50% Muslim (mainly in the north and west of the country), 40% Christian (mostly in the south) and 10% traditional beliefs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands with everyone is customary on meeting and departing. In Yorubaland, it is a sign of respect for women to curtsey when introduced and to enquire after relations, even if this is a first meeting. Unless the visitor knows someone well, it is unusual to be invited to a Nigerian's home. Most entertaining, particularly in Lagos, takes place in clubs or restaurants. A small gift of appreciation is always welcome and business souvenirs bearing the company logo are also acceptable. Casual wear is suitable and a lightweight suit and tie are only necessary for businesspeople on formal meetings; on most other occasions men will not need to wear a jacket, although a tie might be expected.</p>
<p>Women should dress modestly, and respect local customs regarding dress, particularly in the Muslim north. It is inadvisable for women to wear trousers. There are over 250 tribes in Nigeria, the principal groups being the Hausa in the north, the Ibo (or Igbo) in the southeast and the Yoruba in the southwest. The larger of the minor groups are the Fulani, Idoma, Igala, Igbirra, Kanuri, Tiv and Nupe in the north; the Efik, Ekoi, Ibibio and Ijaw in the east; and the Edo, Itsekiri, Ijaw and Urhobo in the west. A result of this ethnic variety is the diversity of art, dance forms, language, music, customs and crafts. Nigerians have a very strong sense of ethnic allegiance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are most commonly used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Muhammadu Buhari since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Muhammadu Buhari since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The states of Kanem and Borno, which flourished on the shores of Lake Chad from about AD 10 onwards, were the first imperial states in the region, founded on control of trans-Saharan trade routes. In the 15th century, the Portuguese began trading but, by the end of the 19th century, the British had conquered present-day Nigeria. Full independence was achieved in 1960, but ever since the country has endured numerous changes of government and Nigeria's army has chosen to intervene on several occasions to thwart a perceived threat.</p>
<p>The greatest crisis came about in the mid-1960s, when the eastern part of the country – styling itself the Republic of Biafra – attempted to secede. A three-year civil war followed at the end of which the secessionists were defeated and up to 30,000 people of Ibo origin were dead. General Murtala Mohammed overthrew the government in 1974 but was assassinated in 1976 and replaced by army chief of staff General Olusegun Obasanjo.</p>
<p>A series of coups and attempted coups followed, until elections in 1993 were won by Moshood Abiola, a former publisher who had been put up as a purely token opposition candidate. The military annulled the elections and returned the country to military rule.</p>
<p>Sani Abacha emerged as the new military strongman and, over the next five years, presided over an increasingly oppressive regime that attracted particular criticism for its treatment of the Ogoni people. After their leader, the renowned writer Ken Saro-Wiwa, was executed along with eight colleagues Abacha suffered increasing diplomatic isolation, including from Nelson Mandela.</p>
<p>Obasanjo returned to power in elections after Abacha's death in 1998 and faced the task of dealing with growing religious conflict that continues to this day. Several northern states adopted strict sharia law in 2000 and in 2002 more than 200 were killed after Muslim outrage over the planned Miss World beauty pageant in Kaduna.</p>
<p>After 2007 oil production began to soar although clashes between Muslims and Christians intensified as Goodluck Jonathan was elected president in 2010, with a spate of deadly Christmas Day attacks killing at least 40 in 2010. Boko Haram militants claimed responsibility for the deaths of thousands in the next few years, and a state of emergency was declared in three northern states in 2013. The attacks continued into 2014, when Nigeria overtook South Africa as Africa's biggest economy.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; In the 2014 ebola outbreak Nigeria was the first country to eliminate the threat.</p>
<p>&bull; Nigeria is Africa&rsquo;s most populous country.</p>
<p>&bull; Fela Kuti, perhaps the best known musician to emerge from Nigeria, is widely credited with pioneering the fusion of local styles with American jazz and soul to produce Afrobeat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Nigeria in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 986 8400.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.nigeriaembassyusa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 986 8400.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 1000-1300 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>3519 International Court NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nigeria High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7839 1244.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.nigeriahc.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7839 1244.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1730, 1000-1300 (visa submission); 1530-1630 (visa collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>9 Northumberland Avenue<br/>London<br/>WC2N 5BX<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Nigeria]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+234 (9) 462 2200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/nigeria</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+234 (9) 462 2200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1600; Fri 0800-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Mississippi<br/>19 Torrens Close<br/>Maitama Abuja<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From the loud laughter of traffic-choked Lagos to the green-fringed villages that line rivers and streams, Nigeria is one of the most exciting places to visit in Africa.</p>
<p>Once known only for oil and chaos, the country is changing rapidly. It has a rising middle class, a dynamic arts scene and more miles of golden sand than you can shake a bucket and spade at. Its national parks are home to some of the last remaining endangered species in West Africa, while its mountains offer a cooler climate and spectacular views of the most populous country in Africa.</p>
<p>Those 177 million people are as diverse as the nation itself; in the north, you'll see men in colourful Muslim dress lining prayer mats on Fridays, while their southern counterparts play checkers before church. The cuisine too is varied; there are hot and spicy dishes, fresh fish and meat, fast food and imported fare.</p>
<p>But Nigeria's greatest asset &ndash; its wealth of native races and religions, its vibrant population &ndash; have also proven its downfall on countless explosive occasions, and military overthrows, coups and assassinations have been numerous. The situation is particularly fraught in northern Nigeria, which is home to the jihadist group, Boko Haram (meaning &ldquo;Western education is forbidden&rdquo;).</p>
<p>For all its domestic difficulties, Nigeria remains a major regional power and lays claim to the biggest economy in Africa &ndash; if you want to feel the excitement of an emerging country, this land will blow you away.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s full of surprises, too. Visitors can find themselves dancing the night away at a Nigerian wedding party, sipping champagne with supermodels, haggling for art in Lagos&rsquo; hipster district, Yabi, and swimming beneath cascading waterfalls in the mountains.</p>
<p>Though Nigeria is a loud and brash destination, it also has a quieter, more reflective side that deserves to be seen. In fact it has so many faces that at times it feels more like a continent than a country.</p><p>From the loud laughter of traffic-choked Lagos to the green-fringed villages that line rivers and streams, Nigeria is one of the most exciting places to visit in Africa.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Once known only for oil and chaos, the country is changing rapidly. It has a rising middle class, a dynamic arts scene and more miles of golden sand than you can shake a bucket and spade at. Its national parks are home to some of the last remaining endangered species in West Africa, while its mountains offer a cooler climate and spectacular views of the most populous country in Africa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
