<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Niue" ColCode="niu" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="nu" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Niue]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical climate bathed by southeast trade winds, Niue has warm days and pleasantly cool nights. The wet season is from December until March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Loose, natural fabrics; a cover-up for the evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main road round Niue is mostly sealed and most roads connecting the main town with inland villages are also sealed. These are supplemented by a number of rough tracks. The easiest way to get around is by hiring a car, motorbike or bicycle. Most accommodation providers run airport shuttles.</p>l<p>Taxis are available, and a shuttle connects accommodation with local restaurants.</p><p>Along with your national driving licence, you must obtain a local licence from the Niue Police Department.</p><p>You can hire cars, vans and motorbikes on the island, although it's best to make reservations before arrival.</p><p>A limited number of mountain bikes are available to hire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air New Zealand (<a href="http://www.airnewzealand.com/" target="_blank">www.airnewzealand.com</a>) flies to Niue from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/auckland">Auckland</a> weekly, with twice-weekly services between April and October.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/auckland">Auckland</a> - 3 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>NZ$34, which you must pay in cash on departure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Niue International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 5km (3 miles) south of Alofi.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International calls can also be made directly from the telephone or with the assistance of an operator. There are telephones in hotels, motels and guest houses. Services are run by the Telecommunications Department located at the Commercial Centre in Alofi, which also provides fax facilities, and is open 24 hours a day. Dial 999 for the police, fire or hospital.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The island has a wireless Internet service provided by the <em>Niue Internet Users Society</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Niue Post Office is open Mon-Fri 0830-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Alofi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Alofi: take a look at the Women's Club Town Hall with its handicraft shop, and peruse Alofi Market on Fridays.</p>]]><p><b>Avaiki Cave</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a peek into the huge, gaping Avaiki Cave, reported to be where the first settler's canoe landed here. It is most accessible at low tide, and has a deep pool overhung by large stalagmites.</p>]]><p><b>Explore by bicyle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the coastline and frangipani-scented interior on two wheels. Cycling is easy and enjoyable thanks to a good network of quiet, sealed and relatively flat roads. If you're game, there is an annual race around the island's ring road in September.</p>]]><p><b>Game fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take advantage of Niue's sheer drops from reefs into deep ocean, which make land-based game fishing a unique experience here. Red bass, wahoo, tuna, sailfish and marlin abound. Traditional outrigger canoes and motor boats can be arranged for line-fishing expeditions.</p>]]><p><b>Go caving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Niue has an extensive cave system, both under and over the sea. Some caves were even used as homes by islanders until the mid 1800s. Some can be found without help, but for the better ones take a guide.</p>]]><p><b>Matapa Chasm</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See Matapa Chasm with its fabulous swimming and snorkelling area, encased by steep cliffs overhanging a deep pool. Niueans sometimes jump from the overhanging cliffs into the deep water.</p>]]><p><b>Niue traditions</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Catch a glimpse of Niue's oldest traditions. Every month there are traditional coming-of-age haircutting and ear-piercing ceremonies held in various locations. However, prior permission must be sought to witness these.</p>]]><p><b>Palaha Cave</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Brave the slippery entrance to Palaha Cave, a dramatically sculpted and oddly coloured cavern that joins with many smaller caves; there is also a delightful little pool at its mouth, which locals recommend as the best spot to enjoy a romantic sunset (provided there is a low tide).</p>]]><p><b>Reef walk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go on a reef walk around Niue's raised reef at low tide.</p>]]><p><b>Rich marine life</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the clear and unpolluted waters, rich marine life and beautiful underwater landscape by scuba-diving. Keep an eye out for turtles, dolphins, water snakes, whales and all manner of fish. For further information, contact <em>Niue Dive</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.dive.nu/">www.dive.nu</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Swim and snorkel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are good swimming and snorkelling locations at Vaitafe, Avaiki and Limu, with its colourful coral, rich marine life and nice beach. Avatele Bay is another excellent location, and visitors can watch fishermen in their canoes and dinghies.</p>]]><p><b>Talava Arches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Talava Arches at low tide. These are a group of extraordinary arches and caverns, many containing stalactites and stalagmites, which may be visited at low tide. The archway was noted by Captain Cook in the 18th century.</p>]]><p><b>Togo Chasm</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Togo Chasm, on the island's eastern side, which is a beautiful area with tropical rainforest, towering coral pinnacles, white sand, palms and a hidden pond reputed to be home to a monstrous eel.</p>]]><p><b>Tropical rainforest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a walk on the wild side: Venture into the tropical rainforest within Huvalu Forest Conservation Area, full to the brim with flora and fauna, none of it poisonous or harmful to visitors.</p>]]><p><b>Whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Have a close encounter with whales: Humpbacks shelter in the bays around Avatele and Tamakautoga between June to October, sometimes as close as 50m (150ft) from the water's edge. It is even possible to go swimming, snorkelling or diving with them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$10 million (2003).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Root crops, coconuts, honey and fruit.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food, live animals, manufactured goods, machinery and fuels.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>New Zealand, Fiji, Cook Islands and Australia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is limited agriculture, producing coconuts, honey, yams, cassava and sweet potatoes. But weather is inclement and two-thirds of the land is unsuitable for cultivation. Some livestock is reared for local consumption.<br /><br />Tourism is worth about US$1 million annually, but there is still a budgetary shortfall. This is largely made up for by aid from New Zealand. Niue began developing an offshore financial services industry in the 1990s, but the International Banking Repeal Act of 2002 terminated all offshore banking licences. The island suffers an ongoing population drain as its educated youth leaves in search of work abroad.<br /><br />Economic growth was reported as 6.2% in 2003. Inflation was 4% in 2005 and unemployment was 12% in 2001.<br />Matavai Resort conference rooms can seat 50 to 60 people or 120 theatre-style.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is the usual form of greeting and leaving. Lightweight suits are recommended for business. Official invitations will always state the dress code required: 'formal' means a jacket and tie for men and 'fiafia' means casual dress is acceptable. <br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1530 or 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Matavai Resort</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 683 4360
					Website:
					Address: ,PO Box 133,Alofi,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Many ceremonies and social events stem from the processing of food. One community ritual is based on the extraction of <em>nu pia</em> starch from arrowroot, which is used in traditional dishes and soups and often given as a gift. Another ritualised ceremony surrounds <em>ti</em> root, which is made into a sweet drink or eaten as a sweet with coconuts.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; The <em>luku</em> fern is another indigenous plant used in Niuean cooking and is boiled, stir-fried or baked in an earth oven with coconut cream and chicken or corned beef.<br />
&bull; Other popular foods include shellfish, taro, kumara, coconuts, pawpaw, bananas, tomatoes, capsicum and many varieties of yam.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Restaurants do not have service charge or tax.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Not encouraged.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of nightclubs. Hakupu Village also hosts a traditional <em>fiafia</em> (cultural night) once a week beginning with a tour of the village, followed by a traditional feast with dancing and singing (advance booking is recommended).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Niuean women are especially regarded for the quality of their weaving, producing hats, baskets, handbags and mats from indigenous plants, such as pandanus, which make excellent buys for the visitor. These are available to visitors at a handful of shops and can also be found at village show days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1600; sometimes Sat 0800-1600. There are generally one or two small stores in most villages around the island which are open in the evenings and during weekends.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are less than 90 guest rooms on the island, divided between a resort and a mere handful of hotels, motels and guest houses.<br /><br /><strong>Anaiki Hotel</strong><br />Located next to the Avaiki Caves at Makefu. This accommodation has four units in a long block (single/double/triple), breakfast included. A hot plate is provided for heating up simple meals.<br /><br /><strong>Coral Gardens Motel<br /></strong>Five self-contained studio-room chalets and a bar. Situated near a tropical coral garden close to Alofi and Makefu and in close proximity to popular reefs and swimming pools.<br /><br /><strong>Kololi's Motel</strong><br />Built in the centre of Alofi, it provides a range of rooms, including a large bedroom suite, a large double bedroom, two double rooms and a twin room with shared bathroom facilities. There is a kitchen and barbecue area, or meals can be provided.<br /><br /><strong>Matavai Resort<br /></strong>Situated on a cliff top, with views overlooking Dolphin Bay and the bays of Avatele and Tamakautoga, this resort is just 10 minutes from Alofi, has 22 rooms plus two executive suites. The main building houses a restaurant, a bar, conference facilities and two freshwater swimming pools. They also offer wedding packages.<br /><br /><strong>Namukulu Motel<br /></strong>With sea and reef views, this motel is situated a 10-minute drive from Alofi and a few minutes walk from Limu. It consists of three self-contained chalets which can sleep up to four people. There is a licensed restaurant and bar nearby, as well as opportunities for snorkelling, swimming and cycling.<br /><br /><strong>Peleni's Guest House</strong><br />A former family home in the centre of Alofi, it consists of three bedrooms with shared cooking, bathroom and lounge facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are less than 90 guest rooms on the island, divided between a resort and a mere handful of hotels, motels and guest houses.<br /><br /><strong>Anaiki Hotel</strong><br />Located next to the Avaiki Caves at Makefu. This accommodation has four units in a long block (single/double/triple), breakfast included. A hot plate is provided for heating up simple meals.<br /><br /><strong>Coral Gardens Motel<br /></strong>Five self-contained studio-room chalets and a bar. Situated near a tropical coral garden close to Alofi and Makefu and in close proximity to popular reefs and swimming pools.<br /><br /><strong>Kololi's Motel</strong><br />Built in the centre of Alofi, it provides a range of rooms, including a large bedroom suite, a large double bedroom, two double rooms and a twin room with shared bathroom facilities. There is a kitchen and barbecue area, or meals can be provided.<br /><br /><strong>Matavai Resort<br /></strong>Situated on a cliff top, with views overlooking Dolphin Bay and the bays of Avatele and Tamakautoga, this resort is just 10 minutes from Alofi, has 22 rooms plus two executive suites. The main building houses a restaurant, a bar, conference facilities and two freshwater swimming pools. They also offer wedding packages.<br /><br /><strong>Namukulu Motel<br /></strong>With sea and reef views, this motel is situated a 10-minute drive from Alofi and a few minutes walk from Limu. It consists of three self-contained chalets which can sleep up to four people. There is a licensed restaurant and bar nearby, as well as opportunities for snorkelling, swimming and cycling.<br /><br /><strong>Peleni's Guest House</strong><br />A former family home in the centre of Alofi, it consists of three bedrooms with shared cooking, bathroom and lounge facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are less than 90 guest rooms on the island, divided between a resort and a mere handful of hotels, motels and guest houses.<br /><br /><strong>Anaiki Hotel</strong><br />Located next to the Avaiki Caves at Makefu. This accommodation has four units in a long block (single/double/triple), breakfast included. A hot plate is provided for heating up simple meals.<br /><br /><strong>Coral Gardens Motel<br /></strong>Five self-contained studio-room chalets and a bar. Situated near a tropical coral garden close to Alofi and Makefu and in close proximity to popular reefs and swimming pools.<br /><br /><strong>Kololi's Motel</strong><br />Built in the centre of Alofi, it provides a range of rooms, including a large bedroom suite, a large double bedroom, two double rooms and a twin room with shared bathroom facilities. There is a kitchen and barbecue area, or meals can be provided.<br /><br /><strong>Matavai Resort<br /></strong>Situated on a cliff top, with views overlooking Dolphin Bay and the bays of Avatele and Tamakautoga, this resort is just 10 minutes from Alofi, has 22 rooms plus two executive suites. The main building houses a restaurant, a bar, conference facilities and two freshwater swimming pools. They also offer wedding packages.<br /><br /><strong>Namukulu Motel<br /></strong>With sea and reef views, this motel is situated a 10-minute drive from Alofi and a few minutes walk from Limu. It consists of three self-contained chalets which can sleep up to four people. There is a licensed restaurant and bar nearby, as well as opportunities for snorkelling, swimming and cycling.<br /><br /><strong>Peleni's Guest House</strong><br />A former family home in the centre of Alofi, it consists of three bedrooms with shared cooking, bathroom and lounge facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The Niue Health Centre offers medical and dental treatment. There is a 24-hour on-call emergency service. Patients will be asked for on-the-spot payment. Complicated cases will be sent to New Zealand. International travellers are strongly advised to take out full medical insurance before departure.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Drinking water is from natural spring and rain water, but it is also recommended that you boil water prior to drinking. Imported bottled water is also available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Takai Commission Day :
							2018<br/>02 January </p><p>Waitangi Day :
							06 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>ANZAC Day :
							25 April </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							04 June </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items can be imported into Niue by persons of 18 years of age or older without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 227g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 3 bottles of spirits (up to 3.5L) or 3 bottles of wine (up to 3L) or 8L of beer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms and ammunition, and glass beer bottles (only cans are permitted).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Artefacts, coral and valuable shells.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The New Zealand Dollar (NZD; symbol NZ$) is legal tender (see <em><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand">New Zealand</a> </em>section). Niue sometimes produces commemorative coins which, when available, may be obtained at the treasury.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Bank of the South Pacific in Alofi, the only commercial bank in Niue, can exchange currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted in most hotels and resorts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0900-1500; Fri 0830-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Passports are required by all nationals referred to in the chart above to enter Niue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Entry permit: free.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Entry permit: 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You should be able to provide proof of funds to cover your stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your stay, contact the Immigration Office, PO Box 67, Alofi, Niue (tel: +683 4349).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-19.037973]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-169.829974]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>262 sq km (101 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,612 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alofi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Self-governing territory in 'free association' with New Zealand. (New Zealand retains responsibility for external affairs.)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Niue is an isolated island located 480km (298 miles) east of Tonga, 560km (348 miles) southeast of Western Samoa, 980km (609 miles) west of Rarotonga and 2,400km (1,500 miles) northeast of New Zealand.</p>
<p>Affectionately known as 'the rock', Niue is reputedly the largest upraised coral atoll in the world. It has 2,500 hectares (6,178 acres) of the most undisturbed forests in the world, designated tapu areas by the locals, where no humans were allowed to set foot for centuries.</p>
<p>Now all the tapu forests, except the one controlled by Hakupu village, are penetrable. These forests are full of lush undergrowth, coconut palms and some of the oldest-known ebony trees on earth. Light and scattered forest covers approximately 14,000 hectares (34,594 acres). At the edge of the forest, the coast gives way to coral outcrops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most people belong to the Ekalesia Niue, a Protestant denomination; also Latter Day Saints (Mormon), Jehovah's Witness, Roman Catholic, Seventh Day Adventist and other Christian denominations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Niuean children are bestowed with gifts of money or handmade mats and cloths from their relatives upon coming of age, when girls have their ears pierced and boys receive their first haircut. It is polite to ask permission before entering private land. Niueans consider Sunday as a serious day of rest and most attend church both in the morning and afternoon. While many people play golf, go swimming or sightsee, certain activities, such as boating and fishing, are not allowed on Sunday. For further information on Sunday protocol, contact the Niue Tourism Office (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>). Clothing is usually casual, cool and comfortable but women often wear a hat and cover their shoulders for church and men wear long trousers. Swimming attire is not acceptable in towns or villages.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs have three flat, angled pins, as in New Zealand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Premier Toke Talagi since 2008.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by high commissioner Kirk Yates since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the inhabitants of Niue descend from settlers from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tonga">Tonga</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/samoa">Samoa</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/fiji">Fiji</a>, who arrived between AD 600-1000, developing their own particular culture. The first Europeans reached Niue in the wake of Captain Cook's expedition to the region in 1774. Administered by the London Missionary Society from 1846, it became a British Protectorate in 1900. The island was then formally annexed to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand">New Zealand</a> in 1901, as part of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cook-islands">Cook Islands</a>. In October 1974, Niue was granted 'self-government in free association with New Zealand', making it the smallest self-governing state with that status. This also allows Niueans to retain New Zealand citizenship while maintaining self-government in their own country. <BR/><BR/>The only formal political party is the Niue People's Party (NPP), which has dominated politics on the island since its formation in 1987. Although it has not always enjoyed an absolute majority, it has been able to govern with the support of independents. The current premier is the veteran Mititaigimimene Young Vivian who took over following the most recent poll in April 2002. <BR/><BR/>The major problems facing Niue are chronic population decline caused by emigration and the fragility of the island's status as an offshore tax haven (see <I>Economy </I>section), which is under threat from new measures designed to tackle international money laundering. Niue is also vulnerable to Pacific cyclones: in January 2004, the island suffered serious damage from Cyclone Heta.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Niue High Commission in New Zealand]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(04) 499 4515.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(04) 499 4515.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Thorndon<br/>Level 1 Molesworth House, 101 Molesworth St<br/>Wellington<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Laidback, friendly and unremittingly beautiful, tiny Niue is an idyllic retreat from the modern world.</p>
<p>The island nation&rsquo;s rugged coastline, crystal clear waters and coral reefs offer excellent diving, snorkelling and whale watching. Birdwatchers are also well catered for: parakeets, white-tailed terns and other exotic birds and butterflies can be spotted darting among hibiscus and orchids.</p>
<p>Despite its remote location in the South Pacific, Niue is rarely short of visitors, with regular flights from Auckland bringing planeloads of sun-seeking Kiwis. At the same time however, there are only a handful of hotels, so it never feels crowded &ndash; sometimes it&rsquo;s easy to imagine you have the island all to yourself.</p>
<p>Arrive between July and October, and you can not only witness the annual humpback whale migration, but even join them for a swim. And if your trip doesn&rsquo;t coincide with these gentle cetaceans, spinner dolphin pods are resident year-round.</p>
<p>The island is literally the tip of an undersea mountain, so head offshore and the land plunges rapidly into the deep. You can hook marlin, wahoo and skipjack tuna without having to sail miles from the coast.</p>
<p>Directly beneath the water&rsquo;s surface, snorkellers and divers can explore an underwater paradise of hidden caves and chasms rife with colourful sea creatures. And above water, Niue&rsquo;s limestone caves conceal fossils, secret passageways and ancient burial places, while alluring trails lead you through tropical rainforest to secluded sandy coves. There&rsquo;s even room for nine holes of golf.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re feeling particularly adventurous, sign up to the Rally of the Rock, an annual bike ride that takes Lycra-clad participants through a mixture of bush tracks and paved roads.</p>
<p>Whatever you do in Niue, it&rsquo;s usually not long before you&rsquo;ve got to know half the island&rsquo;s population, who make sure you have the time of your life. </p><p>Laidback, friendly and unremittingly beautiful, tiny Niue is an idyllic retreat from the modern world.&nbsp;The island nation&rsquo;s rugged coastline, crystal clear waters and coral reefs offer excellent diving, snorkelling and whale watching. Birdwatchers are also well catered for: parakeets, white-tailed terns and other exotic birds and butterflies can be spotted darting among hibiscus and orchids.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
