<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="North Korea" ColCode="prk" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="kp" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[North Korea]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Moderate with four distinct seasons. The hottest time is July to August, which is also the rainy season; coldest is from December to January, winters in the far north can be very severe. Spring and autumn are mild and mainly dry.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are worn during the summer. Light to mediumweights are advised in the spring and autumn, and medium to heavyweights in the winter. Waterproofs are advisable during the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are chartered flight routes available with Air Koryo (<a href="http://www.airkoryo.org" target="_blank">www.airkoryo.org</a>), such as journeys from Pyongyang to remote sites like Paekdusan. All flights should be arranged through your tour company.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although an extensive rail network was built by the Japanese during WWII, this has been slowly crumbling since the division of the Korean peninsula in the 1940s. There are still occasional train services running from Pyongyang to Chongjin, Sinuiju and Haeju, but as the timetables are not published and the trains are notoriously slow, it is hardly worth the effort.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most tourists to North Korea travel the country by coach with their group, and all transport is arranged by your tour company. Public buses in Pyongyang are strictly for locals only.</p>r<p>The quality of major roads is good; many are dual carriageways. It is quite possible you will travel in a coach from one city to another without seeing another vehicle on the road.</p><p>There are no taxi services for tourists in North Korea.</p><p>International driving licences are not recognised in North Korea. If you wish to drive within the country, you need to sit a local driving test and obtain a local licence.</p><p>Car hire is not possible in North Korea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pyongyang has a metro system. However, while a carefully stage-managed five-station ride is on the itinerary of most visitors, it is rarely possible to use other forms of public transport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">North Korea</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">nampo</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">North Korea</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kaesong</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">North Korea</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">diamond_mt</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to North Korea's capital Pyongyang are almost always through the national airline Air Koryo (<a href="http://www.airkoryo.org" target="_blank">www.airkoryo.org</a>), and are organised as part of your tour. All of these flights begin and end in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/beijing">Beijing</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>. The only other airline to fly to North Korea is Air China (<a href="http://www.airchina.com" target="_blank">www.airchina.com</a>), although this airline is rarely used by Western tour agencies.</p>
<p>Some of the tour agencies that offer itineraries within North Korea include Koryo Tours (tel: +86 10 6416 7544; <a href="http://www.koryogroup.com" target="_blank">www.koryogroup.com</a>), Young Pioneer Tours (tel: +86 29 8621 2359; <a href="http://www.youngpioneertours.com" target="_blank">www.youngpioneertours.com</a>) and Regent Holidays (tel: +44 20 3131 5057; <a href="http://www.regent-holidays.co.uk/" target="_blank">www.regent-holidays.co.uk</a>). However, once you're inside the country, you'll soon discover that all tours are essentially run by the same government-run Korean International Travel Company.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Pyongyang: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/beijing">Beijing</a> - 2 hours.</p>
<p>To Beijing: from&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>&nbsp;- 10 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 13 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Pyongyang Sunan International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport (Sunan) is 24km (15 miles) from the city (journey time - 45 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>North Korea has a number of cargo ports, including Chongjin, Haeju and Hungnam, but the last passenger route (between Wonsan and Niigata, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a>) has been suspended indefinitely.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a sleeper train service connecting Pyongyang and Beijing, and many tour agencies will offer this service in one direction. Twice a month, there is also a train that arrives in Pyongyang from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's not possible to enter North Korea by car. There is an irregular bus service from Dandong, China to Sinuiju, North Korea, but this is currently only available for Chinese citizens.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Some hotels in Pyongyang provide direct international calls although this may be expensive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Limited GSM 900 network. <em>SUNNET </em>is the only network provider.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Access to the Internet is unavailable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Radio and TV sets in Korea (Dem Rep) are pre-tuned to government stations with Kim Jong-un propaganda. Press outlets and broadcasters are all under direct state control. The country's economic hardships or famines are not reported. However, after the historic Korean summit in Pyongyang in 2000, media outlets toned down their fierce denunciations of the Seoul government. Ordinary Koreans (Dem Rep) caught listening to foreign broadcasts risk harsh punishments, such as forced labour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Services are extremely slow and limited outside the capital. Airmail takes about 10 days to reach Western Europe.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-2100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Climb the Tower of the Juche Idea</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rising high across the Taedong River from the Kim Il-Sung Square, this flame-topped tower represents the national socialist ideology of Juche, often translated as 'Self-Reliance'. The tower is made of over 25,000 granite blocks and stretches 170m (557ft) into the Pyongyang sky. A trip to the top by lift (ideally early in the morning) offers a fine view over the capital.</p>]]><p><b>Drop in on embalmed dictators at Kumsusan Palace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A decadent mausoleum for two communist leaders, Kumsusan Palace of the Sun displays the embalmed bodies of both Kim Il-sung, founder and 'Eternal President' of North Korea, and his son and successor Kim Jong-il. Built in 1976, this gigantic grey palace is surrounded by a large square and a moat. Foreign visitors are only permitted twice a week, but most tours include a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a rare slice of ancient history at Taedongmun</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A rare historic monument in an overwhelmingly-20th century city, Taedongmun is the eastern gate of what was once an inner defensive wall of Pyongyang castle. The construction dates from 1635, though it sits on the site of an original 6th century gate. It is one of North Korea's few protected historical structures.</p>]]><p><b>Escape to the country in Kumgangsan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Kumgangsan, or Diamond Mountain, is perhaps the most famous mountain in North Korea, rising over 1,630m (5,347m). It is part of the country's largest national park, consisting of a range of mountains along the east coast of the country. Its unspoilt, diverse environment is popular with birdwatchers, photographers and botanists.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Pyongyang Film Studios</b></p><![CDATA[<p>These film studios, in the suburbs of Pyongyang, produce multiple films per year. While most focus on North Korean victories over the Japanese and the Americans, there's also been the occasional Western (a popular genre with Kim Jong-il). Any visit here includes exploring the sets used for historic films, including a Japanese street and some European-style buildings.</p>]]><p><b>Have a look inside Myohyangsan Mountain</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Myohyangsan, which means 'exotic fragrant mountain', offers pleasant walks and climbs through a contrasting scenery of waterfalls, woods and Buddhist pagodas. But it's what is underneath the mountain that's most impressive. Miles of corridors and rooms carved into the mountain display thousands of gifts presented by foreigners to Kim Il-sung and his son.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the slopes at Masikryong Ski Resort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>North Korea's only ski resort, Masikryong sits at the summit of the 1,360m (4,462ft) Taehwa Peak and offers a quiet and peaceful skiing experience during winter. That's because the vast complex, consisting of nine runs spread over an area 940 square miles (plus a luxury hotel, an ice rink, a swimming pool and multiple restaurants) struggles to pull in the locals.</p>]]><p><b>Keep an open mind at Mangyongdae</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located just outside the capital, and a popular destination with tour groups, Mangyongdae is the supposed birthplace of Kim Il-sung. Visitors will find rows of humble huts and barns that are said to have played host to the Great Leader's early years (although most appear to have been built far more recently). There is also a museum and – rather unexpectedly – a funfair.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about Korean mythology at Chollima Statue</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located just north of the Mansudae Grand Monument, this bronze sculpture is a fascinating mix of Communist ideology and traditional Korean mythology. It depicts a noble, socialist man and woman gloriously riding a Chollima – a mythical Korean steed (akin to Pegasus) that could cover hundreds of miles per day and was considered untameable.</p>]]><p><b>Listen to propaganda aboard USS Pueblo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the regime's most treasured possessions, this captured US warship (or intelligence ship, depending on who you believe) is moored on Pyongyang's Potong River as a museum ship. Visitors will undertake a guided tour of the ship and watch a propaganda video of the ship's capture, the 'humane' release of its crew and the significance of North Korea's victory.</p>]]><p><b>Peer across the border at Panmunjom</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This heavily-guarded post on the border between the two Koreas is on the agenda of even the most whistle-stop tours. Visitors will learn (one side of) the story of the Korean War and will be taken into the Armistice Talks Hall where peace was brokered between North and South Korea. Expect to be watched at all times by the wary American troops across the border.</p>]]><p><b>Roam the foothills of Paekdusan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Paekdu, on the Chinese-North Korean border, is the peninsula's highest mountain, at 2,744m (9,002ft). It also has great geological significance (as an extinct volcano with one of the world's deepest crater lakes) and mythical status (it is, according to local mythology, the birthplace of the first Korean kingdom). As a visitor, the surrounding natural beauty – forest, waterfalls, streams and abundant wildlife – is also rather special.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the vastness of Kim Il-sung Square</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pyongyang's main square periodically plays host to North Korea's huge military parades. But even when it isn't, it's a worth visiting for the imposing concrete buildings surrounding the square. Take a trip inside the Grand People's Study House (home to an extensive local library collection) and the Korean National Art Gallery (home to the country's best socialist realist art).</p>]]><p><b>Visit old town Kaesong</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Many ancient buildings in Kaesong, capital of the peninsula during the Koryo Dynasty, bear witness to Korea's long imperial history. Highlights include; Sonjuk Bridge, a small stone structure dating back to 1216; the 14th century tombs of King Kongmin and his Mongolian queen; and the traditional Korean old town with original Joseon-period buildings.</p>]]><p><b>Walk under the Arch of Triumph</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Marking the precise spot where Kim Il-sung first addressed the Korean people after the end of the Japanese occupation in 1945, Pyongyang's giant triumphal arch is, quite deliberately, ever-so-slightly taller than its famous cousin in Paris.</p>]]><p><b>Witness the vanity of Mansudae Grand Monument</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Unveiled in 1972 to celebrate the 60th birthday of president Kim Il-sung, this gigantic bronze statue on a hill in Pyongyang is venerated by North Koreans. Foreign tour groups are routinely requested to bow in front of statue and present flowers at its feet. Since 2012, Kim Il-sung has been accompanied by an equally-enormous statue of Kim Jong-il.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$40 billion (2012, estimated).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Minerals, textiles, agricultural and fishery products, coal and iron ore.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, coking coal, machinery, textiles and grain.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China and South Korea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Until 1971, North Korea had a similar GDP per capita to its neighbour South Korea. But today, while South Korea has one of the world's largest economies, North Korea is recognised as one of the poorest and least developed nations anywhere on earth.</p>
<p>This downturn is down to several factors. One is a considerable loss of trade with the former Soviet Union in the 1990s. Another is a series of serious floods and natural disasters which have wreaked havoc on the country in recent years. And a third is stagnation &ndash; North Korea has yet to adopt the political or economic reforms seen in its neighbours China and Russia.</p>
<p>Economic data is hard to come by. In 2012 the Bank of Korea estimated that the GNP of North Korea at that time was US$21.8 billion, while America's Central Intelligence Agency estimated US$40 million. The North Korean government purports to have a full employment rate, though swathes of the population live in extreme poverty with up to a third of children suffering malnutrition.</p>
<p>Pyongyang isolationism has led to a lack of trade with the US and its allies in Europe and beyond. However, there is believed to be around US$300 million of trade between North and South Korea, and an even more crucial $6.6 billion of trade across the border with China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you somehow find yourself on a business trip to North Korea, it is important to remember that formality is valued highly here. Suits are required at all times and colleagues or clients should be greeted with a firm handshake and perhaps a slight bow. Expect to be introduced by a third party, rather than directly, and have business cards ready to exchange on meeting.</p><p>Note that business transactions generally take place outside the office in the evenings, as foreign visitors are not permitted to enter North Korean workplaces.</p><p>Generally Mon-Sat 0800-1700. However, workers are often required to arrive at work earlier and leave later in order to undertake community reading and exercise sessions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>DPRK Committee for the Promotion of External Economic Cooperation</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 381 6163
					Website:
					Address: Central District,Jungsongdong,Pyongyang,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Cuisine is one of the few things that unite North and South Korea. The two countries have a shared culinary heritage, and previous visitors to South Korea will instantly feel at home in a North Korean restaurant. Main dishes are largely based upon warm rice, meat and vegetables, though it&rsquo;s the side dishes that really make the meal.</p>
<p>As with everything else in North Korea, your dining experiences will be limited by your government approved guides, yet most itineraries serve up a good variety of the country's gastronomy. Do stick to Chinese, Japanese and Korean dishes, as experience of Western cooking is limited.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Kimchi:</strong> Cabbage or radish fermented in a brine of ginger, garlic, scallions and chilli.<br />
<strong>Bibimbap:</strong> White rice topped with vegetables, chilli, soy sauce, raw egg and sliced beef.<br />
<strong>Bulgogi:</strong> Grilled beef marinated in soy sauce, sugar, sesame oil, garlic and pepper.<br />
<strong>Japchae:</strong> Sweet potato noodles stir-fried in sesame oil with sliced vegetables and beef.<br />
<strong>Gimbap: </strong>North Korea&rsquo;s take on sushi. <br />
<strong>Bindaetteok:</strong> A fried pancake of ground mung beans, green onions and kimchi.<br />
<strong>Miyeokguk:</strong> A very nutritious vegetable soup made of seaweed.<br />
<strong>Boshintang:</strong> A traditional North Korean soup with a main ingredient of dog meat.<br />
<strong>Tteok: </strong>Sticky rice cakes variously filled with honey, sesame, nuts and dried fruits.<br />
<strong>Soju:</strong> A clear spirit, similar to Japanese sake, but made from sweet potato or barley.<br />
<strong>Makgeolli:</strong> A cloudy, off-white and sweet rice wine of around 8% alcohol.<br />
<strong>Taedonggang:</strong> A brand of state-owned North Korean beer brewed in Pyongyang.<br />
<strong>Daechucha</strong>: A traditional tea made by diluting the juice of jujubes into boiling water.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tourists do not need to tip in restaurants or bars.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Unknown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like everything in the country, tourist access to nightlife is strictly controlled. In reality, most visitors' experience of North Korean nightlife will be confined to their hotels. Those staying in Pyongyang's 47-storey Yanggakdo Hotel can enjoy foreign drinks in the hotel bar, or karaoke in the hotel nightclub, while anybody staying in the city's soon-to-open Ryugyong Hotel may enjoy even more in-hotel entertainment options.</p><p>The same is true throughout the rest of the country – it is only in the hotels that tourists are able to unwind with a beer or glass of wine. Nevertheless, there is some limited after-dark entertainment offered to tourists by the state. These include taking in a show at Pyongyang's Moranbong Theatre, oohing-and-aahing at the impressive state circus, and watching the latest Chinese release at the International Cinema.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As a communist country, North Korea is not the place for scratching that retail itch. However, there are a few state-approved souvenir shops and booths &ndash; usually attached to museums or within hotels &ndash; that offer a heady mix of tacky tourist trinkets and one-of-a-kind mementos.</p>
<p>Popular souvenirs and gifts include North Korean stamps, propaganda posters and postcards, obsolete currency, local artworks that glorify the regime and a locally-produced tourist map (and guide) of the country. Less popular but equally prevalent souvenirs include the varied items of shoddy embroidery, the copied cassettes, CDs and DVDs, the tourism t-shirts and the selection of panacea tea products (such as the 'Hangover Chaser Tea with liver booster').</p>
<p>Perhaps the most interesting purchases of all are the propaganda books, which are printed in multiple languages. Two particular highlights include Kim Il-sung's musings on his own Juche philosophy (often beautifully packaged), and a tome for locals revealing the horrors of living in present-day America, where women and black people are constantly in fear of their lives.</p>
<p>Your tour guide may also conduct a tour of North Korea's most decadent department store, offering a fascinating insight into the luxury products on offer to the country's elite. However, you are unlikely to find anything here that you'll be able to take out of North Korea.</p>
<p>Please note that credit cards are useless in North Korea &ndash; you cannot pay by card and there are no ATMs anywhere in country. If you do plan to shop, bring US dollars with you in cash.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pyongyang has a few first-class hotels where foreign visitors stay, although groups cannot know in advance which one will be used. All other towns have at least one first-class hotel for use by groups. Visitors must stay in designated tourist hotels (rather than in local <em>yogwan</em>). These are generally of reasonable standard, and are graded as deluxe, first, second and third class.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pyongyang has a few first-class hotels where foreign visitors stay, although groups cannot know in advance which one will be used. All other towns have at least one first-class hotel for use by groups. Visitors must stay in designated tourist hotels (rather than in local <em>yogwan</em>). These are generally of reasonable standard, and are graded as deluxe, first, second and third class.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pyongyang has a few first-class hotels where foreign visitors stay, although groups cannot know in advance which one will be used. All other towns have at least one first-class hotel for use by groups. Visitors must stay in designated tourist hotels (rather than in local <em>yogwan</em>). These are generally of reasonable standard, and are graded as deluxe, first, second and third class.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;'People's Hospitals' and clinics are found throughout the country, but resources can be limited and basic. At present, emergency medical flights are not permitted into the country. Tourist sites generally provide medical facilities. International travellers are strongly advised to take out health insurance.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Bottled water is widely available and considered fine to drink. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Diarrhoeal diseases are common. Hepatitis B is endemic in the area. Hepatitis E also occurs, as does tuberculosis. Epidemics of Japanese encephalitis and dengue fever may occur. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Day of the Shining Star (Kim Jong-il's Birthday) :
							16 February </p><p>Day of the Sun (Kim Il-sung's Birthday) :
							15 April </p><p>Army Day :
							25 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							27 July </p><p>Liberation Day :
							15 August </p><p>Independence Day :
							09 September </p><p>Foundation of the Korean Workers' Party :
							10 October </p><p>Constitution Day :
							27 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Information on quantities of cigarettes, alcohol etc is unavailable at the time of writing.</p>
<p>You must declare items such as cameras and MP3 players at the border. Mobile phones and video recorders may be confiscated upon entry and returned when you leave.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arms, drugs and pornography. It is inadvisable to bring books about North Korea printed in the West or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-korea">South Korea</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Won (KPW; symbol ₩) = 100 chon. Notes are in denominations of ₩100, 50, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of ₩1, and 50, 10, 5 and 1 chon.<br />
<br />
Hotels tend to only accept cash payments in local currency whilst shops prefer US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currencies may be changed at the Trade Bank (Mon-Sat 0900-1200 and 1400-1700) or at some hotels. Convertible currencies include Australian, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china/hong-kong/hong-kong-international-airport">Hong Kong</a> and US Dollars, Euros, Pounds Sterling and Yen.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Main hotels in Pyongyang will accept credit and debit cards such as Mastercard and Visa. However, American Express is not usually accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally not accepted. However, US Dollars are often accepted as an alternative method of payment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter North Korea, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa fees vary hugely depending on the time of application and nationality of the applicant; check with the consulate/embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications should be made by an officially recognised tour operator. Your tour operator will usually submit your visa application to the North Korean embassy in your home country or in Beijing and inform you when it has been approved. You can then contact the embassy directly to pick up your visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If your tour operator applies via the embassy in Beijing, you can usually collect the visa from the embassy the day before the tour begins.</p>
<p>If your tour operator applies via the embassy in your country of residence (if available), the tour operator will inform you once your visa application has been approved and you can usually receive your visa on the same day if you attend the embassy in person or within a week by post.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[40.279002]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[126.663011]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>120,538 sq km (45,540 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>25,281,327 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>207.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pyongyang.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Communist Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Democratic People's Republic of Korea shares borders in the north with China, in the east with the Sea of Japan, in the west with the Yellow Sea, and in the south with the demilitarised zone (separating it from the Republic of Korea). Most of the land consists of hills and low mountains and only a small area is cultivable. Intensive water and soil conservation programmes, including land reclamation from the sea, are given high priority. The eastern coast is rocky and steep with mountains rising from the water and this area contains most of the waterways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buddhism, Christianity and Chundo Kyo are officially cited as the main religions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Discretion and a low political profile are advised.<br /><br /><strong>Photography</strong>: It is strongly advised to ask permission before taking a photo. Photographs of Korean officials or guarded buildings should be avoided.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 60Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are commonly used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Premier Pak Pong-ju since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>First Chairman Kim Jong-un since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The story of the Korean peninsula stretches far back into the annals of history. Following the ancient inhabitants of the island &ndash; it is believed to have been inhabited for half a million years, with the earliest pottery dating to around 8,000 BC &ndash; came the foundation of the Old Joseon Kingdom in 2333BC.</p>
<p>Centuries of independent states, occupied regions and royal dynasties followed, culminating in a brief Korean Empire between 1897 and 1910.&nbsp;Then the Japanese came and annexed Korea, distantly ruling the country for more than three decades. When <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a> was defeated in 1945, a power struggle took place between the south of the peninsula, protected by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> forces, and the north, backed by both the Soviet Union and by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>. Two states were subsequently declared in 1948, with a division at the 38th parallel.</p>
<p>Unresolved tensions of the division led to Kim-il Sung's northern forces invading the south in 1950, sparking the costly <a href="http://www.history.com/topics/korean-war" target="_blank">Korean War</a>. Despite the subsequent bloodshed, the conflict finally ended in 1953 with the peninsula still divided at those pre-war borders. Although a ceasefire was declared, there was never a peace treaty, so North and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-korea">South Korea</a> remains at war today.</p>
<p>Since then, the North's Democratic People's Republic of Korea has remained a Soviet style republic under the rule of the Kim dynasty &ndash; first Kim il-Sung, then Kim Jong-il and now Kim Jong-un.</p>
<p>In recent decades, while the South Korean economy has prospered, North Korea has remained heavily dependent on foreign aid. Following the collapse of the Soviet Union, that aid fell dramatically and the economic situation has been precarious ever since. With its people suffering food shortages and even famines, the country regularly accepts foreign aid.</p>
<p>Today, North Korea remains one of the world's poorest and least-developed countries. While there are regular talks held with foreign powers, the country's increasing isolationism and nuclear brinksmanship (resulting in sanctions) mean the future of North Korea is uncertain.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; Kim Jong-il reportedly spent &pound;700,000 per year on Cognac, while his people scraped by on an average annual salary estimated at &pound;956 per year.<br />
&bull; In 2013 Transparency International named North Korea joint most corrupt country in the world, along with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/afghanistan">Afghanistan</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/somalia">Somalia</a>.<br />
&bull; North Korea bases its calendar on Kim Il-sung&rsquo;s birth date: 15 April 1912.<br />
&bull; In 2014 <a href="http://www.hrw.org/world-report/2014/country-chapters/north-korea" target="_blank">a UN report into human rights abuses</a> claimed that North Korean citizens face &ldquo;unspeakable atrocities.&rdquo;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Democratic People's Republic of Korea in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 8992 4965.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 8992 4965.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1230 and 1400-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>73 Gunnersbury Avenue<br/>London<br/>W5 4LP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in North Korea]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>2381 7982.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-pyonyang</p><p><b>Tel:</b>2381 7982.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1800; Fri 0900-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Munsu-Dong Compound<br/>Pyongyang<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps the world's most insular, provocative and challenging country, North Korea is hardly the archetype of an alluring holiday destination. Yet more and more foreigners are signing up for tours of the socialist state. The reason? There's simply nowhere else on Earth quite like it.</p><p>North Korea – or the Democratic People's Republic of Korea (DPRK) – is a totalitarian socialist state with an elaborate cult of personality built around the Kim dynasty.</p><p>Its isolation and ideology means that independent travel is impossible. Instead, there are a number foreign agencies that offer tours of the country with government-approved guides, regaling sightseers with propaganda-skewed tales of local history, while steering them clear of interaction with the general public.</p><p>All approved tours begin and end in the country's capital, Pyongyang. A city of more than 2.5 million inhabitants, the long working hours and strict curfew can often make it appear empty – yet there's an abundance of socialist sites for the foreign visitor to enjoy.</p><p>Highlights include the flame-topped Juche Tower (a monument to the state's socialist ideology), the Mansudae Grand Monument (bronze statues of former leaders Kim Il-sung and Kim Jong-il) and USS Pueblo (an American ship captured in 1968 and now on permanent display).</p><p>Beyond the capital most excursions include visits to Myohyang-san (a mountain with a palace carved into it), Panmunjom (the tense military border between North and South Korea) and Mangyongdae (a North Korean village said to be the birthplace of Kim Il-sung).</p><p>And then there's the food. Sharing a culinary heritage with South Korea, the North boasts a similar smorgasbord of delicacies, offering visitors an authentic taste of this most inauthentic of countries.</p><p>North Korea might not be the most easygoing destination, but if you can accept its tyrannical leadership and take everything you are told with a pinch of salt, there are plenty of incredible experiences to be had in the world's most mysterious country.</p>North Korea (Democratic People's Republic of Korea) shares borders with China, the Sea of Japan, the Yellow Sea and the demilitarised zone (separating it from the Republic of Korea).]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
