<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Norway" ColCode="nor" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="no" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Norway]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best time to visit is between mid May and mid August, unless you're coming to ski, in which case the best time is December to Easter. Hikers and those in search of outdoor pursuits including wildlife watching should aim to visit in the summer months when the warmer weather makes getting out and about in the Norwegian countryside a real pleasure. Better still, the summer is low season, which means accommodation and transport deals aplenty.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>European according to the season. Light to medium-weights are worn in summer. Warmer clothing, gloves and hats are necessary during the winter. Waterproofing is advisable throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Domestic flights are operated by Norwegian (<a href="http://www.norwegian.com" target="_blank">www.norwegian.com</a>), SAS (<a href="http://www.flysas.com" target="_blank">www.flysas.com</a>) and Wider&oslash;e (<a href="http://www.wideroe.no" target="_blank">www.wideroe.no</a>). A comprehensive network of scheduled services links numerous domestic airports. Norwegians are among the world's most likely to choose this mode of transport for getting around their own country due to the long distances involved, and the terrain, which makes surface transport slow.</p>
<p>Norwegian domestic operators tend to offer competitive fares, so if you shop around you&rsquo;re likely to find that air travel costs little more than the equivalent rail or bus fare. Charter sea or land planes are available at many destinations. Reduced fares are available for families, children under 12 years of age, groups and pensioners.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All coastal towns are served by ferries, catamarans and hydrofoils. The Hurtigruten (Coastal Express) (tel: +44 203 7335934, in the UK; <a href="http://www.hurtigruten.co.uk" target="_blank">www.hurtigruten.co.uk</a>) from Bergen to Kirkenes (near the Russian border) is a 12-day round trip that leaves daily and stops at 35 ports on the west coast.</p>
<p>Various ferry trips are available (half price in spring and autumn). There are also numerous companies operating cruises on Norway's spectacular fjords, including Norway Fjord Cruise AS (tel: +47 5765 6999; <a href="http://www.fjordcruise.no" target="_blank">www.fjordcruise.no</a>),&nbsp;P&amp;O (tel: +44 333 300 0105 in the UK; <a href="http://www.pocruises.com/norwegian-fjords-cruises/">http://www.pocruises.com/norwegian-fjords-cruises/</a>) and Fred Olsen Cruise Lines (tel: +44 845 591 8649; <a href="http://www.fredolsencruises.com/find-your-holiday/norwegian-fjords-cruises">http://www.fredolsencruises.com/find-your-holiday/norwegian-fjords-cruises</a>)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>NSB (Norwegian State Railways) (tel: 8150 0888, in Norway only or +47 6105 1910; <a href="http://www.nsb.no/?lang=en_US" target="_blank">www.nsb.no</a>) runs all rail services. The main internal routes are: Oslo-Trondheim (Dovre Line); Trondheim-Bod&oslash; (Nordland Railway); Oslo-Bergen (Bergen Railway); and Oslo-Stavanger (S&oslash;rland Railway).</p>
<p>Overnight sleeper services operate on some routes, including the Oslo-Bergen, Oslo-Trondheim and Trondheim-Bod&oslash; lines.</p>
<p>You must reserve seats on express trains. There are buffet/restaurant cars on some trains, and sleepers on long-distance overnight services. Heavy luggage may be sent in advance. Children under four years of age travel free; children four to 14 years of age pay half fare.</p>
<p>NSB operates a minipris ticketing system which involves putting tickets up for sale in batches with early bookings resulting in cheaper fares. Minipris tickets must be bought at least one day in advance, are non-refundable and cannot be changed but can give you savings of up to 75% of the standard fare. Purchase them online, via the NSB app or at ticket machines. See <a href="http://www.nsb.no/en/our-tickets/minipris">www.nsb.no/en/our-tickets/minipris</a> for more information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Norway. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 28years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes.</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Norway Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Norway. Available to non-European nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The road system is of variable quality but is supplemented by numerous car ferries across the fjords. While the majority of roads are open year-round, the smaller mountain passes are often blocked during the winter, often at short notice. Despite the paucity of fast roads, traffic is generally light apart from in the capital where traffic jams are a daily occurrence.</p>
<p>There are also countless tunnels and the country is home to three of the world&rsquo;s 10 longest road tunnels, including the longest &ndash; the L&aelig;rdal to Aurland, which is 24.51km (15.2 miles) long. Hazards include sharp bends and steep gradients, particularly on mountain roads, and the country&rsquo;s large moose population can also prove dangerous if they are attempting to cross.</p>
<p>Contact Vegtrafikksentralen (tel: 175; <a href="http://www.vegvesen.no" target="_blank">www.vegvesen.no</a>) for the latest traffic conditions.</p>r<p>The road system is of variable quality but is supplemented by numerous car ferries across the fjords. While most roads are open year-round, the smaller mountain passes are frequently blocked during the winter, often at short notice. Despite the paucity of fast roads, traffic is generally light apart from in the capital where traffic jams are a daily occurrence.</p>
<p>There are also countless road tunnels and the country is home to some of the world&rsquo;s longest, including the L&aelig;rdal to Aurland tunnel, which is 24.51km (15.2 miles) long. Hazards include sharp bends and steep gradients, particularly on mountain roads, and the country&rsquo;s large moose population can also prove dangerous if they are attempting to cross.</p>
<p>Contact Vegtrafikksentralen (tel: 175; <a href="http://www.vegvesen.no">www.vegvesen.no</a>) for the latest traffic conditions.</p><p>Norway has a very reliable, extensive bus network and numerous long-distance coach operators, the biggest of which is the Nor-Way Bussekspress (tel: +47 22313150; <a href="http://www.nor-way.no" target="_blank">www.nor-way.no</a>) which links most of the major Norwegian cities.</p>
<p>The Lavprisekspressen (tel: +47 6798 0480; <a href="http://www.lavprisekspressen.no" target="_blank">www.lavprisekspressen.no</a>) runs from Oslo to Stavanger via Kristiansand and between Oslo and Trondheim. It's considerably cheaper than the Nor-Way Bussekspress, and you can only buy tickets online.</p><p>Travelling by taxi in Norway can be expensive and is usually unnecessary thanks to the excellent (and cheap) public transport system. Taxis are, however, easy to find and can be waved down on the street, from designated ranks or booked by phone. Most taxis are metered and all taxis operated by registered companies such as Oslo Taxi (<a href="http://www.oslotaxi.no">www.oslotaxi.no</a>), Norgestaxi (<a href="http://norgestaxi.no">norgestaxi.no</a>) and Taxi S&oslash;r (<a href="http://www.taxisor.no">www.taxisor.no</a>) accept credit and debit cards. Each company also has its own taxi app. Drivers usually speak English.</p><p>An International Driving Permit or national driving licence and log book are required. A Green Card is strongly recommended (if you have more than third-party cover on your domestic policy). Without it, if you have motor insurance in your own country, you're allowed the minimum legal cover in Norway; the Green Card tops this up to the level of cover provided by your own policy.</p><p>The minimum age for driving is 18. Tolls are charged on certain cross-country roads, underwater tunnels and in certain cities such as Bergen, Oslo and Trondheim. There are severe penalties (usually involving imprisonment) for drink driving. Fines for illegal parking are high and fines for speeding even higher, so keep an eye on your speedometer, and watch out for speedboxes. Seat belts are compulsory.</p>
<p>Children under under 135 cm (4.5ft) must travel in the back of the car in an appropriately sized child restraint. It is obligatory for all vehicles to drive with dipped headlights at all times. This includes motorcycles and mopeds. Carrying spare headlight bulbs is recommended. The national speed limit is 80kph (50mph) but drops to 70kph (43mph) when going past houses or businesses. In residential and built-up areas, the limit is usually 30kph (19mph). On some dual carriageways and motorways, it's 110kph (68mph).</p>
<p>Foreign-registered cars must display an oval nationality sticker, and UK registered cars are also required to carry a vehicle registration form (Form V5) which is available from the DVLA. Snow chains or winter tyres are advised during the winter (however, most urban areas now levy a toll on vehicles with studded tyres). More information on driving in Norway is available from the Norwegian Automobile Association (NAF) (+47 23 21 31 00; <a href="http://www.naf.no" target="_blank">www.naf.no</a>).</p><p>Available in airports and most towns, but costly. If you&rsquo;re planning a long hire, it&rsquo;s worth thinking about picking up your car in neighbouring Sweden where rental rates are considerably cheaper.&nbsp;Low speed limits, difficult roads and parking, and high insurance make public transport more practical and convenient.</p>
<p>Numerous international car hire companies operate, including Hertz, Avis and Budget. The minimum age for car hire is 19 in Norway, although some companies may insist on a higher minimum age (up to 25).</p><p>Some tourist offices, campsites and hostels rent bikes out to tourists. If you want to bring your own, it&rsquo;s worth bearing in mind that most buses, express ferries and nonexpress trains will charge an excess baggage fee to carry them while express trains won&rsquo;t take them at all. The Nor-Way Bussekspress (express bus service) also regards bikes as excess baggage and charges the equivalent of a child&rsquo;s fare to carry them.&nbsp;ShareBike and Oslo Bysykkel are Norwegian bike sharing providers operating in Oslo.</p><p>The minimum age for driving is 18. Tolls are charged on certain cross-country roads, underwater tunnels and in certain cities such as Bergen, Oslo and Trondheim. There are severe penalties (usually involving imprisonment) for drink driving. Fines for illegal parking are high and fines for speeding even higher, so keep an eye on your speedometer, and watch out for speedboxes. Seat belts are compulsory.</p>
<p>Children under under 135 cm (4.5ft) must travel in the back of the car in an appropriately sized child restraint. It is obligatory for all vehicles to drive with dipped headlights at all times. This includes motorcycles and mopeds. Carrying spare headlight bulbs is recommended. The national speed limit is 80kph (50mph) but drops to 70kph (43mph) when going past houses or businesses. In residential and built-up areas, the limit is usually 30kph (19mph). On some dual carriageways and motorways, it's 110kph (68mph).</p>
<p>Foreign-registered cars must display an oval nationality sticker, and UK registered cars are also required to carry a vehicle registration form (Form V5) which is available from the DVLA. Snow chains or winter tyres are advised during the winter (however, most urban areas now levy a toll on vehicles with studded tyres). More information on driving in Norway is available from the Norwegian Automobile Association (NAF) (+47 23 21 31 00; <a href="http://www.naf.no" target="_blank">www.naf.no</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nearly every town in Norway has a network of local buses which operate around the city centre and outlying areas. The train network covers most major cities, while the capital Oslo also has metro, ferry and tramway services.</p>
<p>Bergen also has a good bus and tram network, a funicular and an aerial tramway giving access to two of the surrounding mountains. Trondheim has a comprehensive bus network, and one tram line linking the city centre with Lian, a major ski centre high above the city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Norway</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">trondheim</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.45</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Norway</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tromsoslash</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">20.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Norway</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">stavanger</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Norway</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bergen</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">8.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major airlines running direct flights to Norway from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollo">www.ba.com</a>), Norwegian (<a href="http://www.norwegian.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.norwegian.com</a>), Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.ryanair.com</a>) and SAS (<a href="http://www.flysas.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollo">www.flysas.com</a>). From the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, there are direct flights with Norwegian and SAS.</p>
<p>Major airports in Norway are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/norway/oslo-airport">Oslo Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/norway/bergen-airport">Bergen Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/stavanger-airport">Stavanger Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/oslo">Oslo</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours; from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours 20 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Oslo Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.osl.no<p>Oslo Airport is located 50km (31 miles) north of Oslo</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+47 915 06400</p>]]><b>Bergen Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.avinor.no<p>Bergen Airport is situated in Flesland, 16km (10 miles) south of Bergen city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+47 6703 1100</p>]]><b>Trondheim Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.avinor.no/en/airport/trondheim/frontpage<p>The airport  is around 25km (16 miles) from the city centre (journey time - 30 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Sandefjord (Torp) Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.torp.no<p>The station is approximately 8km (5 miles) from the airport, and a taxi journey to the station takes about 10 minutes.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>3342 7000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Norwegian ports offering marina facilities include <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bergen">Bergen</a> (<a href="http://www.bergenhavn.no" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.bergenhavn.no</a>), <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/oslo">Oslo</a> (<a href="http://www.ohv.oslo.no" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.ohv.oslo.no</a>), Kristiansand (<a href="http://www.kristiansandhavn.no" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.kristiansandhavn.no</a>) and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/stavanger">Stavanger</a> (<a href="http://www.stavanger-havn.no" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.stavanger-havn.no</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From the UK, you can take a Eurostar train to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brussels">Brussels</a>, an ICE train to Hamburg, then catch connections to Oslo via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/copenhagen">Copenhagen</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/gothenburg">Gothenburg</a> (March to October only). NSB (Norwegian State Railways) (tel: +47 6105 1910; <a href="http://www.nsb.no" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.nsb.no</a>) operates international services from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/oslo">Oslo</a> to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/stockholm">Stockholm</a> and Gothenburg. Throughout the year, you can travel by train to Copenhagen and catch an overnight ferry from Copenhagen to Oslo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong>&nbsp;offers unlimited first or second-class travel in up to 30 European countries, including Norway, for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 15 days, or seven, 10 or 15 days in one month across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bosnia-and-herzegovina">Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina </a>and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/montenegro">Montenegro</a>.</p>
<p>The One-Country Pass does not apply to travel in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 28. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from InterRail (<a href="http://www.interrail.eu" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.interrail.eu</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong>&nbsp;offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 22 days, one, two or three months, five or seven days in a month, and 10 or 15 days days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in two to four bordering countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 28) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The only direct international road connection routes are from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sweden">Sweden</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/finland">Finland</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a> in the far north. For travellers from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, Eurolines (tel: +44 8717 818 177;<a href="http://www.eurolines.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">www.eurolines.co.uk</a>) operates daily services to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/oslo">Oslo</a> from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/amsterdam">Amsterdam</a>;and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/copenhagen">Copenhagen</a>. Other international bus services to Norway depart from northern Finland, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/gothenburg">Gothenburg</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/stockholm">Stockholm</a> in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sweden">Sweden</a> and Murmansk in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia">Russia</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Numbers starting with 800 are usually toll-free while those beginning with 9 are mobile numbers. The international access code is 00. International calls are often prohibitively expensive, so ask for Telekort (Telenor phonecards) when visiting post offices and Narvesen kiosks. Unfortunately, Telekort cards can be hard to find, so it&rsquo;s often easier to use a prepaid card bought from a private company who issue you with a PIN and a local access number.&nbsp;If you have a laptop or a smartphone with you, Wi-Fi calling is far the cheapest option.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with many international mobile phone companies. Mobile phones cannot be hired. Coverage is mostly good, but may be patchy in mountainous areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many internet caf&eacute;s throughout Norway and you can also access the Internet via public libraries, often free of charge. Wi-Fi is widespread.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Norway's public broadcaster NRK has had competition from private local and national stations. Press freedom is guaranteed by the constitution and public radio and TV broadcast without interference from the government.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel receptions, shops and kiosks selling postcards will sell stamps. Airmail within Europe takes two to four days.</p><p>These vary from place to place but are generally Mon-Fri 0830-1600 and Sat 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Hardanger Fjord</p><![CDATA[<p>Hardanger Fjord, which is located 75km (47 miles) east of Bergen, is one of the most popular tourist destinations in Norway. This scenic area offers virtually every kind of natural landscape available in the country, from scenic waterways, apple and cherry orchards, and hiking trails, to mountain plateaux. The area also contains Hardangervidda, Norway's largest national park, two of Norway's largest glaciers, Folgefonna and Hardangerjøkulen, and some of Norway's most popular waterfalls, including Vøringfossen, Steinsdalsfossen and Låtefossen. There are also various museums in the area, including Hardanger folkemuseum (Hardanger Folk Museum) and Hardanger Fartøyvernsenter (Hardanger Ships Preservation Centre) treeboat museum.</p>]]><br/><p>Hardanger Fjord</p><![CDATA[<p>Hardanger Fjord, which is located 75km (47 miles) east of Bergen, is one of the most popular tourist destinations in Norway. This scenic area offers virtually every kind of natural landscape available in the country, from scenic waterways, apple and cherry orchards, and hiking trails, to mountain plateaux. The area also contains Hardangervidda, Norway's largest national park, two of Norway's largest glaciers, Folgefonna and Hardangerj&oslash;kulen, and some of Norway's most popular waterfalls, including V&oslash;ringfossen, Steinsdalsfossen and L&aring;tefossen. There are also various museums in the area, including Hardanger folkemuseum (Hardanger Folk Museum) and Hardanger Fart&oslash;yvernsenter (Hardanger Ships Preservation Centre) treeboat museum.</p>]]><br/><p>Nidaros Cathedral (Nidarosdomen)</p><![CDATA[<p>According to Norwegian history, King Olav Haraldsson, who was killed in the battle of Stiklestad in 1030 and who subsequently became Norway&rsquo;s patron saint several days later, was buried on the exact spot where <em>Nidaros Cathedral</em> in Trondheim now stands. Construction of the church began in 1070 after pilgrims began to flock to St Olav&rsquo;s grave, but it was not completed until 1300, when it was widely reputed to be the most beautiful church in Norway. Now restored after fire damage and years of decay and pillage endured during the Reformation, it is particularly renowned for its fine stone statues on the exterior and the quality and quantity of stained glass in the Gothic interior. Norway&rsquo;s monarchs are still crowned and buried in the cathedral and there are regular music recitals under the high-vaulted arches. Visitors can admire the <em>Crown Jewels</em> on display and also climb the tower for fine views over Trondheim.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bergen funicular</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a ride to the summit of one of the seven mountains surrounding the former Hanseatic port of Bergen (<a href="http://www.visitbergen.com/" target="_blank">www.visitbergen.com</a>), for panoramic views of the country's longest fjord - Sognefjord – to the north and the beautiful Hardangerfjord in the south.</p>]]><p><b>Bergen harbourside</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stroll around the picturesque wooden warehouses in Bergen's historic Bryggen harbourside area &ndash; a UNESCO World Heritage site since 1979. Explore the fish market nearby (<a href="http://www.visitbergen.com" target="_blank">www.visitbergen.com</a>), or take a trip out to Troldhaugen, former home of composer Edvard Grieg (<a href="http://griegmuseum.no/en">griegmuseum.no</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Coastal voyage</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience the midnight sun at the North Cape in the far Arctic and make the most of the extra daylight by enjoying the coastline from the deck of one of the Hurtigruten ships (<a href="http://www.hurtigruten.co.uk" target="_blank">www.hurtigruten.co.uk</a>), which call at 35 different ports on the voyage north.</p>]]><p><b>Folk culture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience traditional Norwegian folk culture, music, dance and food at one of the regular summer events at the Norske Folkemuseum (<a href="http://www.norskfolke.museum.no/" target="_blank">www.norskfolke.museum.no</a>): an open-air collection of historic buildings on Bygdøy Island outside Oslo. The programme changes daily, so check the website before you go.</p>]]><p><b>Fredrikstad</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Check out Gamlebyen in Fredrikstad, one of Scandinavia's best-preserved fortress towns. Also of interest is the nearby Hvaler archipelago, a summer paradise made up of hundreds of tiny islands - and home to Norway's first marine national park, opened in 2009 (<a href="http://www.opplevfredrikstad.com" target="_blank">www.opplevfredrikstad.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Glacier hike</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a hike on Jostedalsbreen, mainland Europe's largest glacier, and centrepiece of a large national park (<a href="http://www.jostedal.com/" target="_blank">www.jostedal.com</a>). A mecca for outdoor adventure lovers, the park offers plenty of adrenaline sports such as mountain kayaking as well as the more sedate Glacier Bus.</p>]]><p><b>Hardanger Fjord</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hardanger Fjord, which is located 75km (47 miles) east of Bergen, is one of the most popular tourist destinations in Norway. This scenic area offers virtually every kind of natural landscape available in the country, from scenic waterways, apple and cherry orchards, and hiking trails, to mountain plateaux. The area also contains Hardangervidda, Norway's largest national park, two of Norway's largest glaciers, Folgefonna and Hardangerj&oslash;kulen, and some of Norway's most popular waterfalls, including V&oslash;ringfossen, Steinsdalsfossen and L&aring;tefossen. There are also various museums in the area, including Hardanger folkemuseum (Hardanger Folk Museum) and Hardanger Fart&oslash;yvernsenter (Hardanger Ships Preservation Centre) treeboat museum.</p>]]><p><b>Historic Oslo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go royal-spotting at the Kongelige Slott (Royal Palace), which is open to visitors from late June to mid-August (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.kongehuset.no/">www.kongehuset.no</a>), or delve into the city's military past at &Aring;kershus Castle (<a href="http://www.forsvarsbygg.no/no/festningene/finn-din-festning/akershus-festning/english/ ">www.forsvarsbygg.no</a>), which stands within walking distance of the city centre.</p>]]><p><b>Ibsen's birthplace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For those in search of a literary treat, Skien, the birthplace of playwright Hendrik Ibsen (<a href="http://www.telemarkmuseum.no/en/henrik-ibsen-museum/">http://www.telemarkmuseum.no/en/henrik-ibsen-museum/</a>), is a must visit. His childhood home provides a compelling insight into the life of this distinguished Norwegian and includes a comprehensive multimedia exhibition.</p>]]><p><b>Lakeside cabin</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get away from it all and spend a few days in a lakeside mountain hytte, or cabin, enjoying fishing and nature walks. But beware of elk and other large wildlife (<a href="http://www.norgesbooking.com" target="_blank">www.norgesbooking.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Maelstrom</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the Saltstraumen - the world's most powerful whirlpool (<a href="http://visitbodo.com/en/saltstraumen/ ">http://visitbodo.com/en/saltstraumen/</a>). A strong tidal current located some 30km (19 miles) east of the northern city of Bod&oslash;; careful timing is required as the action only happens four times a day. A multimedia visitor centre is nearby.</p>]]><p><b>Medieval wooden churches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Be sure to see one of Norway's 28 surviving wooden medieval stave churches (<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.stavechurch.org" target="_blank">www.stavechurch.org</a></span>), dotted around the southern half of the country. The oldest is the UNESCO World Heritage-listed Urnes Stave Church, by Sognefjord, dating from 1130 (<a href="http://www.sognefjord.no/" target="_blank">www.sognefjord.no</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Northern Lights</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Few sights are more hauntingly beautiful than that of the aurora borealis or Northern Lights – a natural phenomenon caused by magnetised particles emitted by the sun. You'll have to brave the winter cold of Norway's Arctic region (October to March) to see them but it's well worth it.</p>]]><p><b>Norway in a nutshell</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a 'Norway in a Nutshell' tour from Bergen (<a href="http://www.norwaynutshell.com/" target="_blank">www.norwaynutshell.com</a>). You can choose to spend between one and three days on the trip, which takes in scenic rail and bus journeys as well as cruises along Norway's best fjords.</p>]]><p><b>Oslo museums</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't miss the capital's excellent collection of museums, including the Thor Heyerdahl Kon-tiki Museum (<a href="http://www.kon-tiki.no/" target="_blank">www.kon-tiki.no</a>), the Munch Museum (<a href="http://munchmuseet.no/en/">http://munchmuseet.no/en/</a>) and the Viking Ship Museum (<a href="http://www.khm.uio.no/" target="_blank">www.khm.uio.no</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Preikestolen (Pulpit Rock)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Perched on top of a jutting 600m-tall (1969 ft) cliff overlooking the cerulean blue waters of Lysefjord, Pulpit Rock is worth the hike for the stunning views alone. Just outside of Stavanger, the rock can also be reached via a cruise along Lysefjord from the city centre.</p>]]><p><b>Røros</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This small but picturesque mountain town near the Swedish border is a UNESCO World Heritage site. It was a copper mining and smelting settlement from the 17th century until the 1977 (<a href="http://www.verdensarvenroros.no/" target="_blank">www.verdensarvenroros.no</a>). Discover the Old Town, the wooden church and the Mining Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Saint Olav Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the annual festival celebrating Christianity's arrival in Norway in 1024 at Stiklestad, a little over two hours' drive northwest from Trondheim. Centrepiece of the July event is the St Olav Drama, an open-air recreation of&nbsp;that occurred just prior to the Battle of Stiklestad (<a href="http://www.stiklestad.no/" target="_blank">www.stiklestad.no</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Sami culture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn about the culture of the semi-nomadic Sami people of Norway's northern Lapland at the Várjjat Sámi Musea (<a href="http://www.varjjat.org/" target="_blank">www.varjjat.org</a>) at Varangerbotn in eastern Finnmark. Or stay in a Sami tepee on an organised tour of Lapland (<a href="http://www.sami-siida.no/" target="_blank">www.sami-siida.no</a>, Norwegian only).</p>]]><p><b>Skiing and snowboarding</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Norway has thousands of kilometres of marked trails of varying difficulty for enthusiastic skiers and snowboarders, all of which take in stunningly pretty terrain. The 1994 Winter Olympics complex at Lillehammer (<a href="http://www.lillehammer.com" target="_blank">www.lillehammer.com</a>) is just a couple of hours north of Oslo by road.</p>]]><p><b>Svalbard</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Made famous by Philip Pullman's <em>His Dark Materials Trilogy</em>, Norway's most northerly landmass, Svalbard, is the only place in Europe where the polar bear can still be seen. Although glaciers cover 60% of it, Svalbard's soaring mountains and dramatic crags make it worth seeing whether you want wildlife or not.</p>]]><p><b>Tromsø brewery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy a beer or two at the world's most northerly brewery in Troms&oslash; &ndash; which claims to be Europe&rsquo;s most northerly city. Once you&rsquo;ve had your fill of the local brew, head over to visit the picturesque university and cathedral, and revel in the scenic surroundings. (<a href="https://www.visittromso.no/en">https://www.visittromso.no/en</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Trondheim</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relive Norway's former capital city Trondheim's past glories at the magnificent Nidarosdomen (Nidaros Cathedral) (<a href="http://www.nidarosdomen.no/" target="_blank">www.nidarosdomen.no</a>), and visit the city's Ringve Museum (<a href="http://www.ringve.com/" target="_blank">www.ringve.com</a>), which is home to an extensive collection of historic musical instruments.</p>]]><p><b>Vøringsfossen waterfall</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take in the stunning views at Norway's most famous waterfall, situated close to the main road between Oslo and Bergen. Another nearby waterfall, Mardalsfossen, boasts the longest drop in northern Europe clocking up almost 300m (984ft) from top to bottom. (<a href="http://www.fjordnorway.com/" target="_blank">www.fjordnorway.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Ålesund</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Often overlooked in favour of the bigger municipal centres, &Aring;lesund is home to an unparalleled collection of picturesque Art Nouveau buildings, built a century ago after its wooden edifices were razed by a fire. The city is also becoming increasingly accessible with a number of airlines serving it directly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$370.56 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, natural gas, refined petroleum products,&nbsp;non-fillet fresh fish products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Motor vehicles,&nbsp;passenger and cargo ships, machinery and equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK, Germany, The Netherlands, France and Sweden.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Norwegian economy is dominated by its oil and gas industry, which accounts for nearly 22% of GDP and 60% of export earnings. There is little cultivable land in Norway, but many farmers breed livestock, combining this with forestry to supply Norway's numerous sawmills. Consequently, wood products and paper are both thriving industries.</p>
<p>Offshore fishing has been in decline for some time, although a large number of fish farms have been established, making Norway the world's largest supplier of salmon. Heavy engineering industries, principally shipbuilding and machinery, have also declined (although Norway retains a large merchant fleet).&nbsp;Although the country&rsquo;s economy was hit by the collapse in oil prices after 2015, it is recovering strongly.  Norway maintains a very high standard of living.</p>
<p>Norway has been a major oil and gas exporter since the mid-1970s, after discovering large deposits of both in the North Sea. Proven oil reserves are estimated to be in the region of 6.37 billion barrels (0.5% of the global total). Much of the income is invested in a fund, now worth over US$1 trillion, for such time as the oil and gas run out.</p>
<p>Norway is a member of the European Free Trade Association (EFTA) and as such trades freely with the EU. Large conference centres are available in the big cities, particularly in Oslo, while most of the larger hotels around the country offer meeting facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Smart dress is expected of businesspeople in Norway and prior appointments are necessary. Norwegian businesspeople tend to be formal and reserved, and punctuality is essential. Business cards are usually exchanged during meetings. The best months for business visits are February to May and October to December.</p>
<p>Morning meetings usually take place in offices, while early afternoon and lunchtime appointments frequently take place in restaurants. If a late-morning meeting is arranged, it is good practice to issue a lunch invitation but bear in mind that whoever extends the invitation usually pays for the meal. Traditionally, lunch is a light snack but in a business context, it may involve a more substantial meal.</p>
<p>English is widely spoken, and in the business community, the language is usually spoken to a very high standard. Most Norwegians also speak Danish and Swedish, and knowledge of French and German is common. Normal business hours are between 8am and 4pm, with employees leaving their offices promptly to return home for middag (dinner), eaten at around 1700. However, when an invitation is offered to either dine out or eat at the home of a business colleague, the meal will often be scheduled for slightly later in the evening. Criticism of, or jokes about, peoples, cultures or systems should generally be avoided as many Norwegians pride themselves on their political correctness.</p>
<p>Norwegians are direct and ready to negotiate, with minimum small talk. Trust is important and, in negotiation, Norwegians are less likely to indulge in tactical dealing and will be more interested in the facts of the product than personality or social skills. Visitors should make a fair pitch with room for a little adjustment but not an initial offer that could subsequently be seen as a negotiating tactic, as this may be perceived as dishonest.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Innovation Norway</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 2200 2500
					Website:http://www.innovasjonnorge.no/
					Address: ,PO Box 448 Sentrum,Oslo,104]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Fish is a staple, along with meat, potatoes and other root vegetables. The favourite traditional hot snack is the <em>p&oslash;lse</em>, a type of sausage. The roadside <em>kro</em> (traveller's restaurant) is a good choice if you want to sample traditional Norwegian fare.</p>
<p>Breakfasts are often enormous with a huge variety of fish, meat, cheese, sweet whey cheese and bread served buffet-style with coffee and boiled or fried eggs. Open sandwiches are topped with meat, fish, cheese and salads. Popular dinner dishes include meatballs (<em>kj&oslash;ttboller</em> or <em>karbonader</em>) with boiled potatoes, boiled fish and <em>bacalao</em>, a spiced dried cod stew.</p>
<p>Alcohol tends to be limited in availability and expensive, although beer and wine are generally available in restaurants. Licensing laws are strict and alcohol above 4.7% ABV for home consumption is sold only by the state through <em>Vinmonopolet</em> (special monopoly stores). Beer and cider is sold in general stores.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Brunost</em> (a sweet brown cheese made with whey).<br />
&bull; Roast wild elk, or reindeer.<br />
<em>&bull; Lutefisk</em> (baked preserved cod).<br />
<em>&bull; Gr&oslash;t</em> (a form of porridge).<br />
<em>&bull; Multer</em> (cloudberries - a summer delicacy).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Waiters expect a tip of no more than 5% of the bill.&nbsp;A 10-15% tip is not unusual if the diner is very happy with the service.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18 (for beer, wine and other drinks up to 22% ABV), and 20 (for drinks over 22% ABV).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most villages have at least one caf&eacute;/restaurant where you can find a decent meal, although you can expect to pay handsomely for the privilege. Bigger towns and cities boast a thriving arts scene including theatre, music and cultural events. Restaurants, nightclubs and bars, including Irish pubs tend to be concentrated in city centres.&nbsp;Bergen, Oslo, Stavanger and Trondheim are well supplied with a wide array of watering holes, many of which also offer food.</p>
<p>Oslo's nightlife centres on the Aker Brygge waterside area, the city centre, and the Majorstua district. Most Norwegians tend to go 'out on the town' only on Fridays and Saturdays. This is in no small part due to the high prices of food and drink, and the fact that the working day starts early. At weekends, it is normal for Norwegians to enjoy a<em> forspiel</em> (drinks at home), before venturing out as late as 2300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most towns have plenty of shops selling Norwegian handicrafts such as traditional knits, silverwork and woodcarving. Silversmiths and potteries are common and well worth visiting for unique homeware and jewellery. Traditional items include printed textiles and silver, enamel, pewter, glass and porcelain jewellery, crockery and trinkets. In the major cities, expect to find branches of all the major international chains but don&rsquo;t forget to check out the work of the excellent local fashion designers such as Per Spook.<br />
<br />
VAT is levied at 25% on most goods, which considering that nearly everything is horribly expensive, feels pretty steep. However, you can obtain tax-free cheques from any of the 3,000 shops carrying the sticker 'Tax free for tourists'. These shops save visitors between 11 and 18% of the price paid by residents. VAT refunds are paid in cash at airports, ferries, cruise ships and border crossings.</p><p>Mon-Wed and Fri 0900/1000-1700/1800, Thurs 0900-2000 and Sat 0900-1300/1500. Supermarkets are normally open Mon-Fri 0900-2000 and Sat 1000-1800. Shops are closed on Sunday. <em>Kiosken</em> (small shops offering limited essentials) and petrol station shops are open late in the evenings and on Sundays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Norway is bursting with first class establishments, many of which are family run. The big chains &ndash; Kempinski, Radisson and so on &ndash; are all present in larger towns and cities. Business hotels often drop their rates at weekends and during the summer low-season in many areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Pensjonat</em> (guest houses) are generally smaller and offer less elaborate facilities than hotels. British-style B&amp;Bs don&rsquo;t really exist in Norway with the closest equivalent being rooms offered in private houses. Local tourist offices will have information about these, but keep an eye out for roadside signs with <em>rom</em> or <em>husrom</em> on them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Norway is bursting with first class establishments, many of which are family run. The big chains &ndash; Kempinski, Radisson and so on &ndash; are all present in larger towns and cities. Business hotels often drop their rates at weekends and during the summer low-season in many areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Norway is bursting with first class establishments, many of which are family run. The big chains &ndash; Kempinski, Radisson and so on &ndash; are all present in larger towns and cities. Business hotels often drop their rates at weekends and during the summer low-season in many areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health risks in Norway are few, with most visitors likely to suffer nothing more serious than a few blisters from hiking or insect bites in the summer. Standards of health care are high but as with everything else in Norway, healthcare is expensive, so insurance is a must. Travellers should find out if they are covered by reciprocal health care arrangements. Australia, for example, has such an agreement as long as long as citizens carry their Medicare card. Pharmacies are called &lt;em&gt;apotek&lt;/em&gt; and can be found on every high street. In an emergency, you can get treatment from the nearest public hospital free of charge. Dial 113 toll-free for an ambulance. Most operators also speak English.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food in Norway is safe to eat although care should be taken when purchasing food from unlicensed/roadside stalls. Norwegian tap water is safe to drink, although drinking from fjords, streams and rivers &amp;ndash; however clean they look &amp;ndash; isn&amp;rsquo;t recommended as even the most inviting-looking water can harbour parasites. Water that has been boiled or treated with iodine or chlorine tablets is usually safe to drink.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccination for tick-borne encephalitis is sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Holy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>May Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Constitution Day :
							17 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Andre Juledag :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items can be imported into Norway without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 250g of tobacco products and 200 leaves of cigarette paper.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits over 22% volume and 1.5L wine less than 22% volume and 2L of beer up to 4.7% volume. You can exchange the spirits allowance for 1.5L of wine and beer and can exchange the wine allowance for the equivalent amount of beer. You can also exchange the tobacco allowance for 1.5L of wine or beer&nbsp;but you can&rsquo;t exchange the alcohol allowance for tobacco.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of Kr6,000 (if out of Norway for more than 24 hours) or Kr3,000 (if out of Norway for less than 24 hours). Note this includes any alcohol or beer.<br />
&bull; 10kg of meat and meat products, cheese and foodstuffs (except dog and cat food).</p>
<p>You must be over 18 years old to import tobacco and alcohol. You must be over 20 years old to import spirits over 22% volume.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items are prohibited without special permission: drugs and medicines (other than prescription medication), spirits over 60% volume, weapons and ammunition, fireworks, potatoes, meat and dairy products from outside the EEA, mammals, birds and exotic animals, and plants and their parts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Endangered species or eggs of endangered species, antiques (except with a permit), or more than 15kg of fish that you've caught yourself (except salmon, trout or Arctic char, for which there is no limit).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Norwegian Krone (NOK; symbol Kr) = 100 &oslash;re. Notes are in denominations of Kr1,000, 500, 200, 100 and 50. Coins are in denominations of Kr20, 10, 5 and 1. The &oslash;re coin is now out of circulation and only exists as a digital currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Available at banks and bureaux de change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa, Eurocard, MasterCard, Diners Club and American Express cards are all widely accepted throughout Norway.</p><p>Mini-Banks (the Norwegian name for ATMs) are widespread although withdrawal fees vary from bank to bank.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted in banks, hotels, some shops and by airlines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Wed and Fri, 0800-1530 hrs (1500 hrs in summer); Thurs, 0815-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals from a Schengen member state holding a valid national ID card. EU nationals do not require any length of validity on their travel documents, other than to cover the duration of their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Norway is a member of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60 (&pound;51.42). Reductions are available for nationals of some countries and for children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). UK residents requiring Schengen visas should apply via the Norway Visa Application Centre (<a href="http://vfsglobal.com/norway/unitedkingdom">http://vfsglobal.com/norway/unitedkingdom</a>), which charges an additional service fee of &pound;18.66. All visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least two weeks for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa applicants must show proof of funds to cover their stay in Norway.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is only usually possible to extend a Schengen visa in exceptional circumstances such as <em>force majeure</em> or for humanitarian reasons.</p>
<p>Non-EU/EEA nationals must apply for a residence permit if staying longer than 90 days. EU/EEA nationals do not require a residence permit, but must register with the police. The Norwegian Directorate of Immigration has further details on its website (<a href="http://www.udi.no">www.udi.no</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you're bringing a pet from an EU/EEA country, your animal requires a pet passport, microchip and valid rabies vaccination certificate. Dogs also require treatment for tapeworm.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[58.790978]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[7.822266]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>385,186 sq km (148,721 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5,271,958 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>14.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Oslo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Norway is bordered to the north by the Arctic Ocean, to the east by Finland, the Russian Federation and Sweden, to the south by the Skagerrak (which separates it from Denmark) and to the west by the North Sea. The coastline is over 25,000km (15,534 miles) long, its most outstanding feature being the numerous fjords. Most of them are from 80km to 160km (50 to 100 miles) long, and are usually flanked by towering mountains. Much of northern Norway lies beyond the Arctic Circle and consequently, mostly takes the form of rugged tundras. The south is covered with pine and larch forests, and dotted with lakes, rivers and mountains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>According to 2016 figures, just under 78% of Norwegians identify themselves as Christian. 71.5% of Norwegians belong to the Church of Norway &ndash; an Evangelical-Lutheran denomination. Another 6% belong to other Christian denominations such as Catholicism. Of the non-Christian religions  the largest group are Muslims, followed by Buddhists, Hindus, Sikhs, Baha&rsquo;i and Jews, all of which account for 3.5% of the population. 16% of Norwegians identify themselves as having no religious affiliation at all.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal courtesies should be observed and follow similar lines to those of other European countries, with a few regional exceptions, for example, guests refraining from drinking until the host has toasted their health. Hosts and hostesses often expect an invited guest to offer small gifts on arrival for a meal. Punctuality is expected if invited out for dinner. Lunch, generally a light open sandwich snack known as a <em>matpakke</em>, takes place between 11.30am and 12pm, while dinner is very early - around 5pm.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Erna Solberg since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Harald V since 1991.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From Norse warriors to Vidkun Quisling, Norway&rsquo;s history boasts enough twists and turns to fill a Viking epic. Early Norse civilisation bore cultural fruit in the shape of Viking epics and&nbsp;the ferocity of Viking warriors is still remembered today. The age of the Vikings came to an end with the advent of Christianity and the death of King Harald Hardrada in the battle of Stamford Bridge in 1066 but their legacy lives on, with the Viking period remaining one of the best-known in Norwegian history.</p>
<p>The years up to 1905 saw Norway lose its sovereignty, first to Denmark and then to Sweden, when it was handed to Stockholm in 1814 by the Danes who were forced to concede it as a result of being on the losing side in the Napoleonic Wars. After much wrangling, Norway finally gained independence in 1905 following a referendum. Its newly won autonomy wasn&rsquo;t to last and the Germans invaded in 1940, installing a puppet government led by Vidkun Quisling whose name was to become a by-word for treachery. Norway regained its independence as a constitutional monarchy after the Nazis were defeated in 1945.<br />
<br />
One of the most divisive issues in contemporary Norwegian politics has been the country's relationship with the rest of Europe. Norwegians are fiercely protective of their independence and concerns about the effect of European Union membership on the country&rsquo;s major industries have meant that the electorate has consistently voted to remain outside the EU. However, Norway did join the European Free Trade Area (EFTA), which represents most of the European nations, which are not members of the EU.<br />
&nbsp;</p>
<p>Further afield, the Norwegians have established a considerable reputation for handling delicate conflict negotiations, particularly in hosting and mediating the negotiations leading up to the 1994 Israeli-Palestinian peace accord &ndash; one of the major foreign policy coups of recent times.</p>
<p>Usually a peaceful and stable country, July 2011 saw twin attacks on the government quarter in Oslo and the Labour Party youth summer camp at Ut&oslash;ya Island, resulting in 77 deaths &ndash; Norway&rsquo;s largest loss of life in a single incident since World War 2.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; The sperm whale is the largest predator in Norwegian waters and the brown bear the largest on land.</p>
<p>&bull; In 2015 Norway&rsquo;s King Harald V became the world&rsquo;s first reigning monarch to set foot on Antarctica when he visited Queen Maud Land, a Norwegian dependency.</p>
<p>&bull; The Hardangerj&oslash;kulen glacier appears as the ice planet Hoth in the film <em>Star Wars Episode V &ndash; The Empire Strikes Back</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Norway]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+47 2313 2700.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/norway</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+47 2313 2700.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon, Tue, Thur and Fri 0900-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Thomas Heftyes Gate 8<br/>Oslo<br/>0244<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Royal Norwegian Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 020 7591 5500.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.norway.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 020 7591 5500.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1500 (general enquiries). Mon, Tue and Fri 1000-1230. Thurs 1220-1500 (enquiries to consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>25 Belgrave Square<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8QD<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Royal Norwegian Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 333 6000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.norway.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 333 6000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Mon-Fri 0900-1600 (Passports applications Mon-Fri 0900-1100. Appointment needed).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2720 34th Street NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From precipitous glaciers to steep-sided gorges and crystalline fjords, Norway&rsquo;s natural beauty is impossible to overstate. The unspoilt wilderness of the Arctic north is one of the few places where the sun shines at midnight during the summer and where the magnificent Northern Lights brighten the skies during the long winter nights.</p>
<p>Further to the south, the picturesque cities of Oslo, Trondheim and Bergen are brim-full of buildings showing off Scandinavia&rsquo;s age-old flair for design in cosmopolitan surroundings. Oslo is the present-day capital and financial centre, while the country&rsquo;s second city, Bergen, is a picturesque former Hanseatic trading port and gateway to the fjords of Norway. Stavanger is the focal point of the Norwegian oil industry and former capital, Trondheim, is a long-established centre of Christian pilgrimage, and more recently, technical research.</p>
<p>Though the weather can be a tad grim in Bergen, the UNESCO-listed waterfront adds a flash of colour with its wooden warehouses and shimmering harbour. Oslo&rsquo;s waterfront is no less beautiful and has an ice-white Opera House that could give Sydney&rsquo;s version a run for its money.</p>
<p>Stunning though the cities are, the real wonders of Norway are to be found outdoors. In the far north, the glacier-covered sub-polar peninsular of Svalbard is one of the few areas where polar bears can be seen in the wild and Norway&rsquo;s miles of Arctic tundra double up as a destination for skiing and spotting the Northern Lights.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, a ferry trip along Geirangerfjord must rank among the world&rsquo;s prettiest voyages with pine-topped cliffs giving way to icy green water, regularly topped up by the waterfalls that cascade down the fissured sides of the ravine. Indeed, you&rsquo;d be hard pushed to find a part of Norway&rsquo;s northern fjord area that isn&rsquo;t strikingly beautiful, with snow-capped peaks and looming forests almost everywhere you look.</p><p>From precipitous glaciers to steep-sided gorges and crystalline fjords, Norway&rsquo;s natural beauty is impossible to overstate. The unspoilt wilderness of the Arctic north is one of the few places where the sun shines at midnight during the summer and where the magnificent Northern Lights brighten the skies during the long winter nights.</p>
<p>Further to the south, the picturesque cities of Oslo, Trondheim and Bergen are brim-full of buildings showing off Scandinavia&rsquo;s age-old flair for design in cosmopolitan surroundings. Oslo is the present-day capital and financial centre, while the country&rsquo;s second city, Bergen, is a picturesque former Hanseatic trading port and gateway to the fjords of Norway.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
