<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Oman" ColCode="omn" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="om" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Oman]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Because Oman is so large and the terrain diverse, the climatic conditions are as varied as the geography. The most popular time to visit is from October to April when the weather is warm and sunny and temperatures range from a very pleasant 25&deg;C (77&deg;F) to around 35&deg;C (95&deg;F) during the day. It is cooler at night, ranging in temperature from 17&deg;C (63&deg;F) to 19&deg;C (66&deg;F).</p>
<p>From May to August, it is very hot and humid at the coastal areas, while the interior generally remains hot and dry. Between May and September, the southern Dhofar region has its own microclimate. Known as the khareef, the area catches the Indian Ocean&rsquo;s monsoon season and temperatures can be 10-15&deg;C (18-27&deg;F) lower than the rest of the country. Most of the rain falls during the winter months and varies according to the region. Other than in Dhofar, it is rare to see rain between May and November. The coastal areas and the interior plains average 20-100mm (0.8-4 inches) of rainfall annually but this can rise to around 900mm (35 inches) in the mountains. It is common to see snowfall on the highest mountain peaks during the winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons are advisable throughout the year, with a warm wrap for cooler winter evenings, mountain excursions and overworked air-conditioning in shops and restaurants. When touring, khaki or beige are more suitable colours to wear than white, as the dry, dusty conditions can discolour clothing.</p>
<p>Oman is a Muslim country and, while it is relatively moderate, visitors should be sensitive to its customs. Women should not bare shoulders or show low cleavage and should not wear short shorts or short skirts. Long shorts should ideally be below the knee. They should also carry a large scarf or pashmina with them at all times in case they need to cover their head. This is essential when visiting mosques. Men should only wear long, baggy shorts, and preferably trousers outside hotels. Swimming costumes are confined to hotel pools and beachwear should be modest. Most hotels do not require women to cover up when swimming, although women may choose to do so when bathing in the sea on public beaches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Oman Air (<a href="http://www.omanair.com" target="_blank">www.omanair.com</a>) operates domestic flights to Salalah and Khasab from Muscat International Airport. Oman is a large country so internal flights are an excellent way of visiting the far south (Salalah) and remote Musandam Peninsula in the north.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>National Ferries Company (tel: 2449 5453; <a href="http://www.nfc.om" target="_blank">www.nfc.om</a>) operates vessels from Muscat to Khasab, Lima to Khasab, Lima to Dibba, Shinas to Khasab via Dibba, and Shannah to Masirah.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no rail services in Oman, but there are plans to construct a rail network connecting the country with the rest of the Gulf region. See <a href="http://www.omanrail.om" target="_blank">www.omanrail.om</a> for updates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Oman has a fast and modern network of roads and motorways with good connections between Muscat and major towns. Principal routes run from east to west, connecting Muscat to Sohar, and from north to south. Sudden rainfall can cause flash flooding in dry riverbeds and roads that cross them.</p>r<p>There are excellent roads in Muscat and between Muscat and other major towns in Oman. Unpaved roads open up less-visited parts of Oman for those with 4-wheel drive vehicles.</p><p>Apart from taxis, the only way of getting around Oman is by coach or shared minibus operated by Mwasalat (<a href="http://mwasalat.om" target="_blank">mwasalat.om</a>). There are regular daily services between the major cities.</p><p>Few of the orange and white taxis are metered so you should agree fares in advance. Shared taxis and minibuses (<em>baisa</em> buses) are popular, especially with Omani women who generally sit next to other women.</p><p>Long-term residents need a local licence, obtainable from the police by presenting a national driving licence or International Driving Permit. Police passes are required for residents travelling to the United Arab Emirates.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. The speed limit on major highways is 120kph (74mph), reduced to 100kph (62mph) within city limits, and enforced by speed cameras. In built-up areas, speed limits are usually 60-80kph (37-50mph).</p>
<p>Traffic laws are strictly imposed. Heavy penalties are imposed for drinking and driving; 48-hour prison sentences are imposed if traffic offences are caused by driving under the influence of alcohol. Seat belts should be worn at all times. On-the-spot fines are imposed if caught using a mobile phone while driving. It is also forbidden to drive on the beaches.</p>
<p>If you are involved in a major road traffic accident remain with your car and call the Royal Oman Police on 9999. Further details are available at <a href="http://www.rop.gov.om" target="_blank">www.rop.gov.om</a>.</p><p>The Royal Oman Police (tel: 9999) respond to emergency calls but many roads outside the capital area are infrequently used and waiting times are long. There are large parts of the Sur to Muscat road that have no mobile phone signal, so if you break down, you need to wait for help or hitch a ride to the nearest town.</p><p>Many international firms have offices at the airport and at hotels in Muscat and Salalah. Most visitors can use their own national driving licence or International Driving Permit. The minimum age to hire a car ranges from 21 to 25 depending on the company. As distances are long, check if there is a daily mileage limit. There is excellent off-road driving, so you may want to hire a 4-wheel drive vehicle.</p><p>The north is sharply mountainous, with few paved roads, so only suits the adventurous off-road cyclist. The south of the country can experience quite severe weather, with towns and cities huge distances apart, making finding food and lodging difficult and cycling a less attractive proposition.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. The speed limit on major highways is 120kph (74mph), reduced to 100kph (62mph) within city limits, and enforced by speed cameras. In built-up areas, speed limits are usually 60-80kph (37-50mph).</p>
<p>Traffic laws are strictly imposed. Heavy penalties are imposed for drinking and driving; 48-hour prison sentences are imposed if traffic offences are caused by driving under the influence of alcohol. Seat belts should be worn at all times. On-the-spot fines are imposed if caught using a mobile phone while driving. It is also forbidden to drive on the beaches.</p>
<p>If you are involved in a major road traffic accident remain with your car and call the Royal Oman Police on 9999. Further details are available at <a href="http://www.rop.gov.om" target="_blank">www.rop.gov.om</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Taxi or hire car are the easiest modes of transport. It is perfectly safe for women to drive around, although some may prefer to wear a headscarf to avoid attracting unwanted attention.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Oman</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sur</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Oman</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sohar</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Oman</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">salalah</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">10.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Oman</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">nizwa</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Oman Air (<a href="http://www.omanair.com" target="_blank">www.omanair.com</a>), operates direct flights from the UK to&nbsp;Muscat. Alternatively, there are plenty of indirect options with other carriers in the region, including flights with Emirates (<a href="http://www.emirates.com" target="_blank">www.emirates.com</a>), Etihad Airways (<a href="http://www.etihad.com" target="_blank">www.etihad.com</a>), Gulf Air (<a href="http://www.gulfair.com" target="_blank">www.gulfair.com</a>), Qatar Airways (<a href="http://www.qatarairways.com" target="_blank">www.qatarairways.com</a>) and Turkish Airlines (<a href="http://www.turkishairlines.com" target="_blank">www.turkishairlines.com</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/oman/muscat-international-airport">Muscat International Airport </a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 7 hours 35 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 15 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The new Muscat International Airport is expected to open in 2016 or 2017. The new Salalah International Airport opened in 2015.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The new Muscat International Airport is expected to open in 2016 or 2017. The new Salalah International Airport opened in 2015.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Muscat International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.omanairports.co.om<p>The airport is located roughly 40km (25 miles) west of central Muscat.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+968 2451 9223</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Port of Salalah (<a href="http://www.salalahport.com" target="_blank">www.salalahport.com</a>), Port of Sultan Qaboos (<a href="http://www.pscoman.com" target="_blank">www.pscoman.com</a>), Port of Sohar (<a href="http://www.portofsohar.com" target="_blank">www.portofsohar.com</a>), Port of Duqm (<a href="http://www.portofduqm.com" target="_blank">www.portofduqm.com</a>), Khasab Port and Port of Shinas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no rail services in Oman, but there are plans to construct a rail network connecting the country with the rest of the Gulf region. See <a href="http://www.omanrail.om" target="_blank">www.omanrail.om</a> for updates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The road network covers most of the country and there are good road connections with the United Arab Emirates (UAE), where it is possible to drive a hire car over the border with additional insurance. There is a road between Yemen and Oman and one linking Oman with Saudi Arabia. MWASALAT (<a href="http://mwasalat.om" target="_blank">mwasalat.om</a>)&nbsp;operates buses between Muscat and Dubai in the UAE.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public telephones use phonecards which are available from petrol stations, supermarkets and some smaller shops. They are available in denominations of 1.5, 3 and 5 Rials. It is cheaper to make outgoing international calls between 2100 and 0700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies. Coverage is variable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a few internet cafés in Oman's main cities. All the luxury hotels have business centres with Wi-Fi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government operates Oman TV and Radio Oman. Private, Omani-owned radio and TV stations are now emerging however, such as Hala FM, a private, Arabic music station. The use of satellite dishes is permitted.</p>
<p>A press act allows the government to censor publications for political or cultural reasons. There are more than 20 publications, including dailies and weeklies. English-language newspapers include <em>The Oman Daily Observer</em> and <em>The Times of Oman</em>. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes three to four days and to the USA takes three to five days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the grandeur of the Grand Mosque</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Encrusted in gold, crystals and Italian white marble, Muscat's Grand Mosque is dominated by a 10-tonne crystal chandelier, which is lit by no fewer than 1,122 bulbs, and a 21-tonne carpet woven in one piece by 600 Iranian women. It took six years to build the mosque, whose huge gold dome and tall minarets dominate the skyline.</p>]]><p><b>Climb the battlements of a desert fort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Oman's long military history comes alive in its desert forts, built to fend off rival sultanates and colonial empires. Muscat's Al Jalali Fort was founded by the Portuguese, while the Nakhal Fort predates even the arrival of Islam in Oman. Nizwa Fort is perhaps the most famous fortification, built in classic Arabian style in the 1650s.</p>]]><p><b>Cool off in a wadi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The wadis (seasonal stream beds) of Oman are islands of green in the desert landscape, and the most popular escape from the dust and heat of the cities. Wadi Shab near Sur rises to scenic waterfalls and there are dozens of other wadis, dotted with palms and pools. Then there are the <em>jabals</em>, Oman's rugged mountains, famous for their dates and pomegranates.</p>]]><p><b>Dive into the Arabian Sea</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Oman is a stunning destination for watersports, with teeming coral reefs and rich waters for deep-sea fishing further offshore. Elsewhere, you can windsurf, sail, or ride jet skis and speedboats to remote hidden coves. Tour operators in Muscat and Salalah run bespoke trips, or you can organise your own fun in the sun off the desert island of Masirah.</p>]]><p><b>Drift on a traditional dhow</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At Khasab, the capital town of the Musandam Peninsula, traditional <em>dhows </em>have been used by fishing families for centuries. These iconic Omani boats still ply the waters near Khasab, and some are used for dolphin-spotting tours in the azure waters of the bay. The Musandam Peninsula is often described as the Norway of Arabia because of its beautiful <em>khors</em> (fjords).</p>]]><p><b>Drop into Barka fish market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>About 80km (50 miles) from Muscat, the coastal town of Barka is famous for its lively fish market. It's fascinating to watch locals bidding for fish of all colours, shapes and sizes on the bidding floor, while fishermen land the night's catches on the huge beach outside, running up the sand with filled crates and fish threaded on lines.</p>]]><p><b>Explore mosques, museums and markets in Muscat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The capital of Oman is squeezed between the mountains and the sea, with tall minarets rising above its rooftops. Dotted in between the imposing mosques are fascinating museums, royal palaces and markets, or you can always just wander along the Corniche, enjoying the sea breezes, and take in the views from the Al Jalali and Al Mirani forts.</p>]]><p><b>Find the vision of Arabian Nights in Nizwa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This atmospheric town is renowned for its early-morning livestock market, winding alleyways and silver handicrafts. Nizwa was the country's capital during the 6th and 7th centuries, but the iconic fort that rises above the rooftops dates from the 17th century, a time of warring tribes and insecurity. The towers and battlements have been impressively restored.</p>]]><p><b>Gaze at the colours of the Bimmah Sinkhole</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This enormous sinkhole is mesmerising, with its wonderful sandstone arch rising over a pool of luminous turquoise water (a result of salt and fresh water mixing together). It's worth the long climb down (and back up again) to dip your toes in the water and to get a closer view of the 40m-wide (130ft) basin.</p>]]><p><b>Haggle at Muttrah Souk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This small but labyrinthine souk in Muscat is the place to haggle for gold, silver and other trinkets you thought you could never afford. It's an atmospheric spot and a good place to pick up frankincense and spices at bargain prices. The good news is that the vendors are not too persistent here.</p>]]><p><b>Have a beach picnic</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Locals and expats from across the Gulf love to spend the weekends with a picnic and the company of friends on the sultanates's beautiful beaches. Resorts such as Ras al Hadd offer acres of white sand, where rare sea turtles come to nest each summer, and there are more fine strips of sand at Al Mughsayl, Khalouf, and Tiwi.</p>]]><p><b>Look out from the walls of Al Rustaq Fort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A vision of desert beauty, the mighty walls of Al Rustaq Fort rise out of a sea of date palms. The complex has been beautifully restored; as you wander the maze of corridors, stairways, and state rooms, remember that this was the former home of Nasir bin Murshid, the Omani king who drove the Portuguese from their castles.</p>]]><p><b>Meet a genie at Bahla Fort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This is the most impressive fort in a country studded with medieval fortifications. One of Oman's many World Heritage Sites, the fortress was founded in the 13th century, and many areas have been beautifully restored, while other parts lie in picturesque ruins. Before you leave, buy a souvenir pot from local Bahla potters but don't rub it – Bahla is famous for genies!</p>]]><p><b>Ride a camel across the dunes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It's hard to imagine a more Arabian experience than riding a camel across Sharqiya Sands in the Empty Quarter. On a camel safari, you'll spend the days rolling across the sands, then make camp as dusk falls, for a barbecue of mutton kebabs and a night under the most amazing starry sky.</p>]]><p><b>Roll into the Empty Quarter</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The largest desert in the Arabian Peninsula, the Rub' al-Khali, or Empty Quarter, rolls north from Salalah across the peninsula towards Saudi Arabia. Few people have ever crossed the desert from side to side, but you can enter the fringes on exhilarating off-road trips, exploring dramatic dunes that are the living image of Arabia.</p>]]><p><b>Seek eagles in Al-Ansab</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Al-Ansab wetland near Muscat is a winter roost for migrating eagles, as well as 280 other species of birds. The Omanis have used trained birds of prey for hunting for centuries. To see flamingos, spoonbills and flocks of wading birds head to Barr Al-Hickman, one of Oman's 16 national nature reserves.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the views from Jabal Shams</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ascent of 3,028m (9,934ft) Jebel Shams (Mountain of the Sun), either on foot or by 4-wheel drive jeep, offers stunning views over the shadows of Wadi Ghul, the Grand Canyon of Arabia. Dotted around the mountains are traditional villages where you can pause to haggle for goat-hair carpets from wandering weavers.</p>]]><p><b>Wadi Sahtan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The beautiful ravine of Wadi Sahtan in the Rustaq region is a favourite destination for 4-wheel drive guided jeep tours. En route, you'll pass ancient villages, beautiful green pools, 14 million date palms, and craggy cliffs, stopping off for a picnic lunch beneath the towering peaks. Plus, you'll get to drive through surging streams along the way.</p>]]><p><b>Watch a blowhole blow its top</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Al Mughsayl blowholes near Salalah put on an amazing natural water display during the monsoon, when sea levels rise and currents become more active. Water surges though submerged channels, forcing a gushing geyser of water high into the air. It's quite a spectacle, and nearby Al Mughsayl Bay Beach is rather spectacular too.</p>]]><p><b>Watch nesting sea turtles</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Turtles have been nesting on the beaches of Oman since prehistoric times, and the nesting season from July to October is the prime time to see them. At beaches such as Ras Al Jinz and Ras Al Hadd, you can see the awesome spectacle of females hauling themselves up the beach at night to lay their eggs, before slipping back to the sea.</p>]]><p><b>Watch water surge down Wadi Darbat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Beautiful Wadi Darbat in the heart of Oman's southern, subtropical region of Dhofar, is famed for its natural mud baths, but it's just as interesting to stroll along the wadi, particularly in autumn, when water from the mountains forms magnificent waterfalls which cascade from a height of 100m (330ft).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$57.4 billion (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, liquiefied natural gas, fish, metals and textiles.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, transport equipment, manufactured goods, food and livestock.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China (PR), United Arab Emirates, Japan, Korea (Rep) and Thailand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Natural gas accounts for nearly 80% of Oman's revenue and the government has invested heavily in liquefied natural gas facilities, which have spurred development mainly in the northern city of Sohar. Unlike its neighbours, Oman does not have bountiful supplies of oil, although the government is taking steps to increase its production. There are mineral deposits of copper, which is almost exhausted, chromite, gold, silver, marble, gypsum and limestone, manganese ore, zinc, cobalt and coal. Agriculture earns revenue from the cultivation of dates, limes, alfalfa and some livestock.</p>
<p>Revenues are used to develop the country's infrastructure and to boost industries such as tourism and construction, as outlined in Oman&rsquo;s 25-year economic development programme, Vision 2020. Tourism has taken a key place in the master plan and is expected to account for 3% of GDP by 2020, with 80% of jobs in the sector being held by Omanis by the same year. According to figures from the Ministry of Tourism, it is estimated that tourism&rsquo;s direct contribution to GDP stood at 2.9% in 2009 (US$1.3 million). Excluding oil and gas, the sector&rsquo;s total contribution to the economy was 4.7% in 2009 and the number of employees in hotels stood at 7,546.</p>
<p>For the past decade, major parts of the economy have been privatised and foreign investment is being actively encouraged to develop the tourism infrastructure such as hotels, roads and airports. Annual growth in 2010 was a respectable 4.5%. However, with such a young population (55% are under 20 years old), unemployment among young Omanis remains high. </p>
<p>Oman is a member of various pan-Arab political and economic organisations - but not OPEC.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Men should wear suits and ties for business and formal occasions. English is usually spoken in business circles, but a few words or phrases of Arabic will be useful and welcome. Appointments are essential and punctuality is gradually becoming more important in business circles. Business cards are widely used.</p><p>Sun-Thurs 0800-1300 and 1430-1700. Government office hours are Sun-Thurs 0800-1400. All offices are closed on Fridays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Oman Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 24 707 674
					Website:http://www.chamberoman.com/
					Address: Postal Code 112,PO Box 1400,Ruwi,]]><b>Ministry of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 24 813 500
					Website:http://www.mocioman.gov.om/
					Address: Postal Code 113,PO Box 550,Muscat,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The cuisine of Oman recalls its role as a key trading post between east and west. The spices used in stews and soups came to Oman by way of the spice trade from India, but the traditions of grilled meat and preserved fruit came by land from the Arabian peninsula.</p><p>Muscat is the dining centre of Oman and the best place to try some of the more interesting dishes of the Sultanate, including spectacular seafood hauled fresh from the Arabian Sea.</p><p>As a rule, Omani cooking is less spicy than in other parts of the Gulf, with lots of dishes based on lamb and chicken, usually served with rice, or fried together with rice in local versions of India's <em>biryani</em>. Some of the tastiest dishes are reserved for big religious festivals. Locals eschew alcohol in favour of strong coffee, flavoured with cardamom and served with dates and other sweet treats.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ruz al mudhroub</strong>: A special rice dish served with fried fish.<br />
<strong>Maqdeed:</strong> Dried shredded meat, often served at festivals.<br />
<strong>Muqalab</strong>: Tripe cooked with crushed or ground spices.<br />
<strong>Arsia:</strong> Lamb meat cooked with rice.<br />
<strong>Mishkak</strong>: Skewered meat grilled on charcoal, marinated in a pepper, cardamom, clove and tamarind sauce.<br />
<strong>Shuwa</strong>: Meat cooked slowly for up to two days in underground clay ovens, marinated with herbs and spices.<br />
<strong>Mashuai</strong>: Spit-roasted kingfish served with lemon rice.<br />
<strong>Maqbous</strong>: Rice with saffron cooked over spicy red or white meat; also call <em>kabsa. <br />
</em><strong>Halwa: </strong>A sticky, gelatinous sweet made from dates or sugar and flavoured with saffron, cardamom and rosewater; nuts and preserved fruits are often added.<br />
<strong>Lokhemat: </strong>Balls of flour and yeast flavoured with cardamom and deep-fried, served with sweet lime and cardamom syrup.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslims are forbidden to drink alcohol, but most hotel bars and restaurants have a bar for guests. Visitors are only allowed to drink alcohol if they purchase drinks from licensed hotels and restaurants. To buy alcohol for home consumption, Western nationals must obtain a licence from their embassy.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tipping is not expected but becoming more common; 10% should be given in hotels and restaurants with licensed bars, but is not expected in more casual restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>The legal drinking age (for non-Muslims only) is 21.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You&rsquo;ll find the main nightclubs and bars in Muscat and Salalah, although most of the nightlife centres in the hotels. A new convention centre with an 8,000-seat auditorium is being built, which will double as an entertainment and sports venue. It will include new hotels and shopping facilities and is due to open in 2014.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>As part of its long-term plan, the country is investing in more entertainment venues such as the Oman Royal Opera House which opened in 2011. It will showcase Oman&rsquo;s cultural heritage, as well as bringing international music to the local audience and visitors. Famous names to grace the venue will include Placido Domingo, Andrea Bocelli, soprano Ren&eacute;e Fleming, cellist Yo Yo Ma and the London Philharmonic Orchestra, the American Ballet Theatre and trumpeter Wynton Marsalis with New York City's Jazz at Lincoln Centre Orchestra.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>The Royal Opera House shares the grounds with a small theatre, restaurants, luxury shops and extensive gardens.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>There are a number of modern cinemas in Muscat, such as the Al-Shatti Multiplex, Ruwi and Star, showing a variety of international films.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>There is very little in the way of nightlife in other Omani towns with the exception of Salalah which comes alive during the <em>khareef</em> (rainy season in July and August) with festival activities.</p>
<br />
<br />]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional souvenirs include silver and gold jewellery, khanjars (Omani daggers), coffeepots, saddles, frankincense (the sap of a tree that grows in Dhofar in the south of Oman), hand-woven textiles, goat-hair carpets, baskets and camel straps. Antique khanjars (over 50 years old) may not be exported. It is wise to check with the Ministry of National Heritage and Culture for the necessary documentation before purchasing.</p>
<p>The two main souks (markets) are located in Muttrah and Nizwa, although most towns have a souk of some description. The Muttrah souk is fairly small compared to souks in other countries, its shops in winding streets stacked high with gold, silver, frankincense and other trinkets. The vendors will try to encourage you into their shops but they are fairly good-natured and not too persistent once they know you are not going to buy. Nizwa used to be one of the Arab world&rsquo;s biggest souks, but modernisation has stripped it of some of its old-world charm. It is known for its silver, and you can still see artisans of all types working.</p>
<p>Muscat has several large shopping malls including the Markaz Al-Bahjah and Lulu complexes and Muscat City Centre, which boasts nearly 150 shops. Here, you&rsquo;ll find famous international women&rsquo;s fashion brands such as Mexx, Monsoon and Mango alongside electrical, cosmetics, sports and jewellery shops. The centre&rsquo;s Magic Planet indoor family entertainment area offers games simulators, arcades and themed rides. You can find other modern shops around Shatti Al-Qurum. </p><p>Sun-Fri 1000-1300 and 1600-2100 (precincts 2200); Sat 1600-2100. Opening hours may vary during Ramadan.</p><p>Western-style shopping malls are air-conditioned and comprise shops, car parks, cafés, food courts and play areas for children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Official travel advice states that it is illegal to live together or share the same hotel room with someone of the opposite sex to whom you aren't married or closely related. Homosexuality is also illegal in Oman.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s planners have focused primarily on top-end hotel development in an effort to attract high-spending visitors looking for sun, sand in a &lsquo;different&rsquo; destination; hotels include The Sifawy boutique hotel in Jebel Sifah, Six Senses Zighy Bay Resort and Spa and the Millennium Resort Mussanah, the latter two just under an hour&rsquo;s drive from Muscat. Although they offer luxury accommodation in beautiful locations, the downside of many Omani hotels is their relative inaccessibility to neighbouring towns.</p>
<p>Muscat offers the biggest density and variety of luxury hotels, with international names such as Marriott gracing the capital. There are also three international resorts in Salalah and one in the northern Musandam Peninsula. However, if you are travelling around, in many towns there may be few hotels so it is wise to book first.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a growing number of bed and breakfast establishments mainly aimed at Gulf Cooperation Council members around Muscat and Nizwe, although they remain few and far between. Often beautifully furnished and cheaper than staying in a hotel, they are popular with visitors who enjoy staying with local people and learning their customs. The owners will often advise you on the best places to visit and how to get there, as well as providing you with excellent hospitality.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Official travel advice states that it is illegal to live together or share the same hotel room with someone of the opposite sex to whom you aren't married or closely related. Homosexuality is also illegal in Oman.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s planners have focused primarily on top-end hotel development in an effort to attract high-spending visitors looking for sun, sand in a &lsquo;different&rsquo; destination; hotels include The Sifawy boutique hotel in Jebel Sifah, Six Senses Zighy Bay Resort and Spa and the Millennium Resort Mussanah, the latter two just under an hour&rsquo;s drive from Muscat. Although they offer luxury accommodation in beautiful locations, the downside of many Omani hotels is their relative inaccessibility to neighbouring towns.</p>
<p>Muscat offers the biggest density and variety of luxury hotels, with international names such as Marriott gracing the capital. There are also three international resorts in Salalah and one in the northern Musandam Peninsula. However, if you are travelling around, in many towns there may be few hotels so it is wise to book first.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Official travel advice states that it is illegal to live together or share the same hotel room with someone of the opposite sex to whom you aren't married or closely related. Homosexuality is also illegal in Oman.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s planners have focused primarily on top-end hotel development in an effort to attract high-spending visitors looking for sun, sand in a &lsquo;different&rsquo; destination; hotels include The Sifawy boutique hotel in Jebel Sifah, Six Senses Zighy Bay Resort and Spa and the Millennium Resort Mussanah, the latter two just under an hour&rsquo;s drive from Muscat. Although they offer luxury accommodation in beautiful locations, the downside of many Omani hotels is their relative inaccessibility to neighbouring towns.</p>
<p>Muscat offers the biggest density and variety of luxury hotels, with international names such as Marriott gracing the capital. There are also three international resorts in Salalah and one in the northern Musandam Peninsula. However, if you are travelling around, in many towns there may be few hotels so it is wise to book first.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Oman has an extensive public health service (free to Omani nationals), with many hospitals and health centres. Standards are generally comparable to those in the UK although treatment varies according to the location. Hospital emergency treatment is available. Health insurance is essential. Visitors who cannot pay for their treatment may be prevented from leaving the country until the debt is paid. In an emergency, call the ambulance and fire services on 999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travellers are urged to seek medical advice before travelling to Oman and to ensure that all appropriate vaccinations are up-to-date. Further information on vaccination requirements, health outbreaks and general disease protection and prevention can be obtained from NHS Direct (tel: 0845 4647, in the UK) or from the websites of the National Travel Health Network and Centre (NaTHNaC - &lt;a href="http://www.nathnac.org/travel" target="_blank"&gt;www.nathnac.org/travel&lt;/a&gt;) or NHS Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Fit For Travel (&lt;a href="http://www.fitfortravel.nhs.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.fitfortravel.nhs.uk&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The British Foreign &amp;amp; Commonwealth Office advises that you should practise safe sex and take precautions to avoid exposure to HIV/AIDS. In the 2010 Report on the Global AIDS Epidemic, the UN AIDS/WHO Working Group estimated that 1,100 adults aged 15 or over in Oman were living with HIV; a prevalence percentage of 0.1% compared to 0.2% in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While in Oman, it is important to drink plenty of water to avoid dehydration in the hot climate. You should use high-factor sunscreens and avoid sunbathing between the hours of 1100 and 1500 when the sun is at its hottest.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;While tap water is generally safe to drink, most Omanis drink bottled water and this is widely available. You can safely drink carbonated drinks in cans and bottles. Outside the capital area and main towns, you should boil or sterilise water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice. Use iodine tablets and portable water filters to purify water if bottled water is not available. Avoid ice cubes in your drinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food bought in the main supermarkets can be regarded as safe. Outside the capital area, milk may be unpasteurised and if so, should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products unless you know they have been pasteurised. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is advisable to avoid food and drinks bought from street vendors. Wash your hands often with soap and water, especially before eating. If soap and water are not available, use an alcohol-based hand gel.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended, the latter particularly for those who might be exposed to blood or body fluids, may have sexual contact with locals or be exposed through medical treatment ie, for an accident. There have been cases of malaria in the enclave of Musandam, but it is extremely rare.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Renaissance Day :
							23 July </p><p>Birthday of HM Sultan Qaboos :
							18 November </p><p>National Day :
							18 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Oman without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; Up to 2L or 24 cans of alcoholic beverages (non-Muslims over the age of 21 only).<br />
&bull; 400 cigarettes. <br />
&bull; 100ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; 10 DVDs.</p>
<p>Meat products officially require an Islamic slaughter certificate and import licence. Medicines in their original packaging and with the original label should be accompanied by a prescription or medical certificate. Certain medicines may be illegal in Oman and may be treated as narcotics, so you should check with your nearest embassy before you go.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The import and use of narcotics and obscene material are forbidden and can lead to imprisonment. There are severe penalties for drug offences including, in some cases, the death penalty. 'Soft' drugs are treated as seriously as 'hard' drugs. The possession of small quantities of cannabis can lead to a 12-month prison sentence and deportation.</p>
<p>The list of banned imports also includes leaves, flowers, seeds and stems of cannabis, raw or prepared opium, weapons, firearms and ammunition, fireworks, and alcoholic drinks (unless you are a non-Muslim).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All the materials mentioned above are banned for export unless authorised by the General Inspector of Police and Customs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Omani Rial (OMR) = 1,000 baiza. Notes are in denominations of OMR50, 20, 10, 5 and 1, and 500, 250, 200 and 100 baiza. Coins are in denominations of 50, 25, 10 and 5 baiza.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Currency is easily exchanged in banks, money exchange centres and major hotels. It is advisable to take US Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major credit cards are accepted here, including to a lesser extent American Express. ATMs are widely available throughout the county.</p><p>ATMs are widely available throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers should be wary of using traveller's cheques in Oman as they are difficult to exchange. International hotel chains are more likely to accept them, but smaller hotels, shops and banks are likely to refuse. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sat-Wed 0800-1200 and Thurs 0830-1130.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Oman, a passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single parents, or other adults travelling alone with children, may be required to provide documentary evidence of parental responsibility on entering and leaving the country. To check what is required, contact the nearest Oman Embassy.</p>
<p>For children under 18 travelling unaccompanied, a consent letter is required from one parent, as well as a photocopy of their father's passport. Children should apply for a visa in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An air transit visa allows you to enter the country only once and stay for a maximum of 72 hours provided you have sufficient funds and a valid ticket for onward travel. A road transit visa allows you to travel overland for up to three days. Both cost OMR5.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A single-entry 30-day visa on arrival is OMR20 and may be extendable for a fee.</p>
<p>A cruise visitor visa is free for visits of less than 48 hours and OMR5 for up to 96 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: 30 days.</p>
<p>Visas can be extended for another 30 days for OMR20.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On arrival (if applicable), at the nearest Oman embassy/consulate, or online via the Royal Oman Police website (<a href="http://www.rop.gov.om">www.rop.gov.om</a>).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Contact the Oman embassy or consulate. Residence visas can be renewed on the Royal Oman Police website (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.rop.gov.om">www.rop.gov.om</a>). Single parents in Oman need documentary evidence of parental responsibility when obtaining a residence visa for their child/children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A single-entry visa originally valid for 10 days can be extended for a further 10 days at a cost of OMR5. A 30 day single-entry visa can be extended for one month at a cost of OMR20.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[21.009989]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[56.853980]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>309,500 sq km (119,499 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,654,471 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>10.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Muscat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sultanate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Sultanate of Oman occupies the southeastern edge of the Arabian Peninsula and a total area of 309,500 sq km (119,500 sq miles or roughly the same size as Italy) including the coastal islands of Masirah, Halanyat and Salama, plus Musandam and Madha, which are completely surrounded by the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p>It is bordered by the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia to the northwest, the Republic of Yemen to the southwest and the United Arab Emirates to the north. Oman has 2,092 km (1,300 miles) of coastline on the Gulf, Arabian Sea and the Gulf of Oman. The interior is covered by a vast expanse of desert with around 82% of the landmass occupied by deserts and valleys. The Hajjar mountain range, which occupies around 15% of the country&rsquo;s landmass, forms an arc extending from the northwest of the country to the southeast. The highest mountain is Jabal Shams, at around 2,980m (9,777ft).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Predominantly Muslim, including Shi'ite Muslim, Sunni Muslim and the Ibadi strand of Islam, the latter practised by 60% of the population (the only country in the world to do so). There are facilities for the worship of other religions. Around 13% of the population are Hindu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is the usual form of greeting. A small gift, either promoting your company or country, is well received. Dignity and respect are key in Omani culture and public criticisms are rare. As far as dress is concerned, it is important that women dress modestly beyond the hotel grounds, ie long skirts or dresses (below the knee) with covered shoulders; men should wear trousers and shirts with sleeves. Tight-fitting clothes should be restricted to hotel restaurants to avoid giving offence, although this is not strictly followed by some Westerners. Shorts should not be worn in public and beachwear is prohibited anywhere except the beach. Collecting seashells, abalone, corals, crayfish and turtle eggs is also prohibited. Dumping litter is forbidden. It is polite not to smoke in public, but generally no-smoking signs are posted where appropriate; smoking is banned in public places in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/muscat">Muscat</a>. Homosexual behaviour is illegal.</p>
<p><strong>Photography:</strong> Visitors should ask permission before attempting to photograph people or their property. 'No Photography' signs exist in certain places and must be observed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sultan and Prime Minister Qaboos bin Said Al Said since 1970.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sultan and Prime Minister Qaboos bin Said Al Said since 1970.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The ancient history of Oman is steeped in mystery. Primitive men lived in this part of the Arabian Peninsula as early as 100,000 years ago, and the region was incorporated into the Persian Achaemenid Empire in the 6th century BC. With the birth of the Prophet Mohammed in the 7th century, Oman followed the lead of Persia and converted to Islam, leading to the rise of a string of Islamic dynasties.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>In 1507, the sultans lost their prized possession of Muscat to Portuguese invaders, and while the colonial administration was fiercely resisted, and lasted little more than century, this period saw the construction of many of Oman&rsquo;s famous fortresses. With the restoration of Islamic rule, Oman became a major trading empire, with colonies as far afield as central Africa and Zanzibar. The cornerstones of the Omani economy were the spice trade and slavery, which was only abolished in 1970.</p>
<p>Close ties have been maintained with the UK since 1798, when a treaty of friendship was signed. Oman became a British protectorate in 1891 and Britain continued to play a guiding role in the politics of Oman through to the 1950s, when the nation gained its independence. In 1913, Oman was split in two, with the coast ruled by the sultan and the interior ruled by separate religious leaders, but the nation was reunited in 1959.</p>
<p>Since the accession of Sultan Qaboos bin Said Al Said in a bloodless coup in 1970, Oman has undergone significant political, economic and industrial reform, particularly in industry, communications, transport and education. Ahead of most surrounding nations in the Gulf, women gained the vote for local <em>majlis </em>(councils) in 1997, and universal suffrage was introduced in 2002.</p>
<p>Today, the sultan remains the head of state and head of government but he is advised by an elected council of ministers, which acts as a cabinet. Oil forms a major part of the nation&rsquo;s considerable wealth, and thanks to its long history cooperation with Europe, Oman plays an important role in promoting regional stability. However, there has been local opposition to the continued power of the ruling clan, and the use of Oman as staging post for Western military operations in the region.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know? </strong><br />
&bull;	Oman is one of the world&rsquo;s oldest producers of Frankincense, an aromatic resin that has been used as a perfume since Biblical times.<br />
&bull;	The first horse in Arabia is said to have been kept by the Uzd tribe of Oman; all Arabic racehorses are said to be its descendants. <br />
&bull;	Oman was one of the last countries in the world to abolish slavery, in 1970.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Oman]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>2460 9000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-muscat</p><p><b>Tel:</b>2460 9000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Sun-Thurs 0730-1430; Sun-Wed 1100-1330 and Wed 0800-1030 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>116 Mina Al Fahal<br/>Muscat<br/>PO Box 185 <br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Sultanate of Oman in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 387 1980.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 387 1980.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1600; Mon-Fri 0930-1230 (consulate).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2535 Belmont Rd NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Sultanate of Oman in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7225 0001.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.omanembassy.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7225 0001.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1530; 0930-1230 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>167 Queen's Gate<br/>London<br/>SW7 5HE<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Camel treks, desert camping and 4-wheel drive safaris through mighty canyons are just some of the adventures awaiting visitors to Oman. From frankincense plantations and atmospheric souks that speak of vanished centuries to gleaming modern cities and 5-star hotels fronting on to perfect beaches, Oman is everything you would want from Arabia.</p>
<p>What marks this desert kingdom out from its neighbours is a complex history of interaction with the outside world. From the ports of Muscat and Salahat, Omani traders roamed across the Arabian Sea, pushing back the borders of the Portuguese empire in Africa and founding trading outposts as far afield as Zanzibar and Mozambique, before aligning with the British after the abolition of slavery.</p>
<p>The result, thirteen centuries later, is an outwardly conservative, but strikingly open Islamic society, with a firm belief in the importance of its own traditions but a strong acceptance of other cultures. Many regard Oman as the most welcoming of all the Arabic nations; this is a place where foreigners are invited to sit and sip tea and eat dates out of genuine hospitality, rather than as a preamble to selling souvenirs.</p>
<p>The ruling sultans have taken great pains to preserve the traditional crafts and customs of their ancient civilisation, and the cities of Oman feel much more historic and lived-in than the skyscraper cities appearing elsewhere in the Gulf. The borders of Oman are guarded by a staggering 2,000 desert fortresses, most meticulously restored. It&rsquo;s easy here to feel transported back to the days of <em>Arabian Nights</em>.</p>
<p>Along the coastline, enigmatic dhows still sail from port to port, while rugged wadis (river valleys) snake into the interior, studded with date-palm plantations, dramatic rock formations and hidden pools. Beyond, immaculately tarmacked highways cross the desert to neighbouring Yemen, Saudi Arabia and United Arab Emirates, though many chose to fly to avoid endless drives through barren desert scenery.</p>
<p>More than anything though, Oman is a place to feel safe and at ease. The Omanis are gracious hosts, and visitors will find traditional Arabian hospitality and Islamic culture at its very best.</p><p>Camel treks, desert camping and 4-wheel drive safaris through mighty canyons are just some of the adventures awaiting visitors to Oman. From frankincense plantations and atmospheric souks that speak of vanished centuries to gleaming modern cities and 5-star hotels fronting on to perfect beaches, Oman is everything you would want from Arabia.</p>
<p>What marks this desert kingdom out from its neighbours is a complex history of interaction with the outside world. From the ports of Muscat and Salahat, Omani traders roamed across the Arabian Sea, pushing back the borders of the Portuguese empire in Africa and founding trading outposts as far afield as Zanzibar and Mozambique, before aligning with the British after the abolition of slavery.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
