<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Pacific Islands Of Micronesia" ColCode="pam" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="pi" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Pacific Islands Of Micronesia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With 2,000 islands spread over 7.8 million sq km (3 million sq miles) of the Pacific Ocean, the islands have a variety of weather. The period from November to April is the wet season, when humidity is highest, while cooler and less humid period from May to October is the most pleasant time to visit. The climate can generally be described as tropical in this part of the world, but the cooling sea breezes prevent really extreme temperatures and humidity. For regional climate charts, see under the individual sections.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens, and rainwear.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The region's major airline is United&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>). Consult individual entries for further information.</p>
<p>Scheduled inter-island travel, charters and sightseeing are offered by several local airlines. There is excellent provision for travelling from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guam">Guam</a>, Majuro and Saipan to the various islands. Flights between the islands tend to be rarer. Airlines include:</p>
<p>Air Marshall Islands:<em> </em>This government-owned airline runs charters, sightseeing tours and point-to-point flights between Majuro and other islands in the Marshalls, though services are not always reliable.</p>
<p>United:<em>&nbsp;</em>Operates between islands in all four groups, and to Guam, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/hawaii">Hawaii</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a> and The Philippines. Several smaller airlines fly to Guam.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flight durations from <strong><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a></strong> to destinations in the Pacific vary considerably depending on the route taken. The most common route includes stopovers on the west coast of North America&nbsp;and Honolulu. The flight time from London to Honolulu is 18 hours (including stopover) and from Honolulu to the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pacific-islands-micronesia/marshall-islands">Marshall Islands</a>&nbsp;is 5 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Majuro Marshall Islands International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Rota International Airport </b><![CDATA[http://cpa.gov.mp/rotarpt.asp]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Saipan International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is situated 5km (3 miles) south of Chalan Kanoa.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Tinian International Airport </b><![CDATA[http://www.cpa.gov.mp/tinapt.asp]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Pohnpei International Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Koror Babeldaob</b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong>&nbsp;Koror, Majuro, Pohnpei, Saipan, Tuik and Yap.</p>
<p>There are numerous boats for touring, ranging from small speed boats to large glass-bottomed boats for fishing, sightseeing, sunset cruising, scuba-diving and short-distance travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Variable – there are international satellite links on the Marshall islands; there are payphones in Saipan and most hotels, restaurants and other public facilities have telephones which visitors can use in the Northern Marianas Islands while phonecards are available and calls can be made from most hotels in Koror, Palau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is basic access and services on the islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes approximately 10 days. Post offices are located in the centre of each state.</p><p>Palau: Mon-Fri 0800-1600, Sat 0900 to 1000; Marshall Islands: Mon-Fri 1000-1530, Sat 0900-1545; Northern Mariana Islands: Mon-Fri 0900-1600, Sat 0900-1200; Federated States of Micronesia: Mon-Fri 0830-1630. Closed on the weekends.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>Palau: US$144.7 million (2005); Marshall Islands: US$144 million (2005); Northern Mariana Islands: US$633.4 million (2000): Federated States of Micronesia: US$232 million (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Palau: fish and handicrafts; Marshall Islands: copra cake, coconut oil, handicrafts and fish; Northern Mariana Islands: garments; Federated States of Micronesia: fish, garments, banana, kava and betel nut.</p>
<p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Palau: fuel, food and beverages, and manufactured goods; Marshall Islands: food, consumer goods, machinery and petroleum products; Northern Mariana Islands: food, construction equipment and materials, petroleum products; Federated States of Micronesia: food and manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Palau: USA, Japan, Singapore and Korea (Rep); Marshall Islands: USA, Japan, Australia and New Zealand; Northern Mariana Islands: USA and Japan; Federated States of Micronesia: Japan, USA, Hong Kong and Guam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In all four territories, subsistence agriculture is a key employer. Copra, coconuts, cassava and sweet potatoes are the major crops: yields are sufficient in some cases to sustain export markets. Fishing is similarly important. The Marshalls and Palau have developed small-scale light industries engaged in food-processing, boat-building and the like.</p>
<p>Service economies based on tourism and financial services have generally proved difficult to establish owing to the remoteness of the territories and the lack of infrastructure. Micronesia, Palau and the Northern Marianas have gone furthest in their efforts to overcome these obstacles. In particular, the establishment of an air link with Japan gave a major boost to tourism in the Northern Marianas but the lack of available workers led to the recruitment of large numbers of foreign workers (which accounts for the huge growth in the islands' population).</p>
<p>The region as a whole continues to rely heavily on foreign aid, mostly from the USA, from which it will receive millions of dollars in annual aid until 2023 when Trust Fund will eventually provide the islands with annual payments in perpetuity.</p>
<p>The Marshall Islands also has an offshore financial services industry. However, in 2002 the Marshall Islands were one of seven countries 'named and shamed' for their failure to tackle the issue of money-laundering.</p>
<p>As members of the Pacific Islands Forum, the islands have agreed to participate in a free trade zone, known as PICTA (Pacific Island Countries Trade Agreement), set up in 2002. Supporters of the Agreement contend that it will bring much-needed trade to the region; critics maintain that the islands are being run over by the globalisation bandwagon and small, fragile economies are being forced to open up before they are ready.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits or shirt and tie are usually worn. Appointments should be made and calling cards are exchanged. The best time to visit is May to October.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700.<br />
<br />
<strong>Government office hours: </strong>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300-1700. There may be some local variations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels serve continental, Chinese, Japanese, Western-style and local cuisine.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; On some remote islands, the arrival of a stranger calls for a feast of fish, clams, octopus, sea cucumber and eels. <br />
&bull; Breadfruit (pounded, boiled, baked or fried).<br />
&bull; Taro, rice and cassava (tapioca).<br />
&bull; Coconut crabs.<br />
&bull; Mangrove clams.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Although some dining rooms serve buffet-style fare, table service is usual and operates at a leisurely pace; see individual sections for further details.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[*No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;All the Federated States have good government hospitals in the main cities. There are also dental services and private health clinics throughout the islands. Be aware that doctors and hospitals may ask for cash payment for health services. On the Northern Mariana Islands, there is a major, modern hospital on Saipan and routine facilities on Rota and Tinian. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of Palau&amp;rsquo;s healthcare facilities are centralised on the main island of Koror. There are two private clinics, and a decompression chamber too. Premises tend to be American-style but facilities may be quite limited. In the event of an emergency call 488 2558. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As health care is not free, health insurance is recommended. Full medical facilities are available but are not free. Scuba-divers are advised there are only three decompression chambers in the Federated States (Yap, Pohnpei and Chuuk). Their availability varies and there is very little experience in treating dive injuries. Health insurance is highly recommended. Certain emergency cases are referred to Hawaii and Guam.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated, and whilst relatively safe may cause mild abdominal upsets. The most common ailment to strike travellers is diarrhoea. This can be  avoided by practising good sanitation; washing hands and making sure any  meat and fish are thoroughly cooked. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst Palau&amp;rsquo;s water is generally safe to drink, you may want to stick to bottled water on the islands, to minimise any risks. Drinking water outside main towns may be contaminated and sterilisation is advisable.&amp;nbsp; Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat. &lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Palau is generally safe, although visitors should be aware that petty crime is on the increase. Take the usual common sense precautions – wear sunscreen, try to avoid the midday sun between noon and 1500, and keep hydrated.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into the Republic of Palau&nbsp;by travellers aged 21 and over without incurring customs duty:<br />
&bull; 20 cigarettes (1 pack only). <br />
&bull; 1 bottle of alcohol.<br />
<br />
The following goods may be imported into the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pacific-islands-micronesia/northern-mariana-islands">Northern Mariana Islands</a> without incurring customs duty:<br />
&bull; 600 cigarettes manufactured in the USA&nbsp;and 200 cigarettes from elsewhere.<br />
&bull; 2.3L of spirits.<br />
&bull; 3.8L of wine and Japanese sake.<br />
&bull; A reasonable quantity of perfume.<br />
You must be at least 21 years old to import alcohol.</p>
<p>The following items may be imported into the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pacific-islands-micronesia/marshall-islands">Marshall Islands</a> by passengers without incurring customs duty:<br />
&bull; 600 cigarettes or 454g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of alcoholic beverages (passengers over 21 only).<br />
<br />
The following goods may be taken into the Federated States of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pacific-islands-micronesia/federated-states-micronesia">Micronesia</a> without incurring customs duty by travellers aged over 18 years and above:<br />
&bull; 600 cigarettes or 454g of cigars or tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of alcoholic beverages (over 21s only).<br />
&bull; A reasonable amount of perfume for personal use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pacific-islands-micronesia/palau">Palau</a> and Federated States of Micronesia: narcotics and firearms; you also need a certificate to import plants and animals into the Federated States.</p>
<p>Northern Mariana Islands: unlicensed firearms, mangoes from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/philippines">Philippines</a>, meat (except from continental <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/hawaii">Hawaii</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guam">Guam</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/canada">Canada</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand">New Zealand</a>), and pre-cooked or dried noodles with powdered meat.</p>
<p>Marshall Islands: firearms, ammunition, explosives and indecent publications, while imports of animals, fruit and plants need certification from the Quarantine Division of the Ministry of Resources and Development.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Palau: shells and natural artefacts.</p>
<p>Marshall Islands: coral, turtle shells, certain other natural resources, and artefacts of historical value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar (USD; symbol US$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of US$1,000, 500, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of US$1 and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.<br /><br />Japanese Yen are accepted on many islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign exchange services are limited on some islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard and Visa are accepted in most hotels and tourist-oriented facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar traveller's cheques are advised.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 1000-1500, Fri 1000-1800. There are some local variations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[7.425554]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[150.550812]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>7,800,000 sq km (3,000,000 sq miles) of which 1,846 sq km (713 sq miles) is land.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Approx. 376,000 (estimate)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>See individual country sections for further details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Each archipelago is composed of hundreds of island groups, within which there are many islands varying widely in topography. A more detailed description is given under the individual section for each country. There are three distinct population groups: Malayans who passed through Indonesia and The Philippines; Melanesians coming from the islands of the southwest Pacific; and Polynesians who inhabited the South Pacific.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic and Protestant with Mormon and Baha'i minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Western understanding of private property is alien to many parts of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pacific-islands-micronesia/federated-states-micronesia">Micronesia</a> and personal possessions should be well looked after, though not necessarily under lock and key; outside main tourist areas, where normal precautions apply, it is usually sufficient just to keep items out of sight. All land, however, does have an owner and before using it, protocol in many areas demands that permission is sought; in places this includes use of footpaths as there is not necessarily immediate right of way. A clearly expressed desire to be courteous will usually see the visitor through; see individual sections for further details.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110/120 volts AC, 60Hz. American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without grounding pin) are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The area has a turbulent history of foreign control and political change. Despite upheavals and foreign influences from Spanish, German, Japanese and US governments, many people of this vast island area have maintained much of their cultural heritage and traditions, while others have lifestyles inspired mainly by the teachings of 19th-century missionaries. Having come under UN Trusteeship, administered by the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, at the end of World War II, all of the Pacific Micronesian states have now reached final political settlements. See individual country sections for further details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Micronesia comprises four archipelagos: the Federated States of Micronesia (Caroline Islands), the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands and the Republic of Palau.</p><p>The area has a turbulent history of foreign control and political change. Despite upheavals and foreign influences from Spanish, German, Japanese and US governments, many inhabitants have maintained their cultural heritage and traditions, while others have lifestyles inspired mainly by the teachings of 19th-century missionaries. Having come under UN Trusteeship, administered by the USA, at the end of World War II, all of the Pacific Micronesian states have now reached final political settlements.</p><p>Collectively, the islands are known for the dramatic tropical nature, pristine beaches and great diving opportunities. By contrast, the area has witnessed some of the darkest moments in recent history, with shipwrecks littering the sea beds, heavy nuclear weapons testing having been staged in the area, and the islet Tinian having the dubious privilege as being the launchpad from which the American B-29s set off for Japan to drop the Atom bomb. The inhabitants of the islands have nevertheless remained resilient in the face of history, and visitors can typically expect a warm welcome.</p><p>See individual country sections for further details.</p><p>Micronesia comprises four archipelagos: the Federated States of Micronesia (Caroline Islands), the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands and the Republic of Palau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
