<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Pakistan" ColCode="pak" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="pk" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Pakistan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan has three seasons: winter (November to March) is warm and  cooled by sea breezes on the coast; summer (April to July) has extreme  temperatures and the monsoon season (July to September) has the highest  rainfall on the hills. Karachi has little rain. Global warming is  starting to become apparent in Pakistan with warmer winters, glacial  melt and a slight dip in temperature in the summer months.<br/><br/>The best time to visit southern Pakistan is between November and March, when the days are cool and clear. The best time to visit northern Pakistan, for trekking, is from April to October; outside of these months it will be snowy and very difficult to reach many mountainous places. Bear in mind that the monsoon plays havoc with travel in Pakistan and is not to be taken lightly, as we have witnessed recently with the devastating floods of 2010, which were the worst in 80 years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wear lightweights, with warmer clothing, including base-layers and woollens, for upland areas in the winter. Good trekking boots are a must for mountain explorers, as are walking poles and thermals. Visitors can buy woollen socks and sweaters at a very good price in the bazaars of Pakistan, but they might not be up to western standards and will be quite heavy. <br/><br/>Rainwear is advised for the monsoon season so if you are to spend any time in the cities during this time, do not rule out the possibility of bringing along some wellington boots as the rain can be torrential resulting in very flooded lanes. It's easiest to buy the necessary shalwar kameez (tunic and baggy trousers) when you land in Pakistan - this is essential for women, and optional, but advisable for the heat more than anything, for men. In the intense heat it may be tempting to lose layers – in respect of local customs, and to spare yourself unwanted harassment and disapproval, it is far wiser to cover up in cool, white flowing cottons, like the Pakistanis do, thus keeping the sun off too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Domestic services are operated by Pakistan International Airlines (<a href="http://www.piac.com.pk" target="_blank">www.piac.com.pk</a>), Shaheen Air (<a href="http://www.shaheenair.com" target="_blank">www.shaheenair.com</a>) and Airblue (<a href="http://www.airblue.com" target="_blank">www.airblue.com</a>). There are many daily flights between Islamabad, Karachi, Lahore, Multan, Peshawar, Sukkur, Faisalabad and Quetta.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traffic along the Indus River is almost exclusively commercial. Many goods are carried to Punjab and the north from the main port at Karachi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan Railways (tel: +92 117) operates the extensive rail network, much of which is a legacy of British rule. The main line, from Karachi to Lahore, Rawalpindi and Peshawar, has several daytime and overnight trains. Most other routes have several daily trains. Even first-class compartments can be hot and crowded. Travel in air-conditioned coaches is advised, as are reservations on long-distance journeys and overnight service.</p>
<p>Trains are of these classes: air-con sleeper, first-class sleeper, air-con lower class (both seat and sleeper versions), parlour car, economy-seat class, second-class seat and second-class sleeper.</p>
<p>Children under three years of age travel free. Children aged three to 11 years pay half fare. Concessions are available for tourists (on presentation of a certificate issued by the Pakistan Tourism Development Corporation), excluding Indian nationals travelling by rail. A discount of 25% is offered to individuals and groups, and 50% for students. Details are available from railway offices in Pakistan.</p>
<p>Karachi to Lahore is approximately 20 hours; to Rawalpindi is 28 hours and to Peshawar is 32 hours; Lahore to Rawalpindi is 5 hours. Trains can be a good way to travel along Pakistan&rsquo;s vast distances, but they get very booked up and busy. This can be a particular problem for travellers boarding at intermediate points. Long-haul trains are often subject to delay.</p>
<p>Always secure luggage to racks with locks and chains, if travelling overnight by train; it's wise to wear an underclothes money belt to keep valuables safe. There can sometimes be incidents on the rail network in Baluchistan and Sind. There have also been a number of derailments.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The roads in Pakistan can be chaotic and dangerous, particularly outside the major cities where drivers face hazards such as animals, mountain passes and extreme weather.</p>
<p>While travellers might note the presence of car hire facilities in Pakistan&rsquo;s major cities, it's not advisable for foreigners to rent a car in Pakistan. Hiring a car with a driver is a much more sensible option.</p>l<p>The highway network between cities is poorly maintained and caution should be taken when driving at night as roads are badly lit. It's advised that tourists to Pakistan travel with local drivers or guides. When driving it's advised to keep doors and windows locked at all times.</p><p>Daewoo Express (<a href="http://www.daewoo.com.pk" target="_blank">www.daewoo.com.pk</a>) is the most popular inter-city bus company in Pakistan. It operates an advanced transport network, calling at most major towns and cities in the country.</p><p>24-hour radio taxi firms exist in most of the country&rsquo;s large cities. By international standards the fares are cheap. Taxis are black and yellow or just yellow; make sure you are on a meter or at least agree a price beforehand.</p><p>Renting a car requires a deposit or an imprint of a credit card. A passport is also required.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18.</p><p>Car hire is available in all major cities, and most major airports, but driving in Pakistan can be a dangerous enterprise. A safer and less stressful option is to hire a car and driver, which you can do through companies such as Rent A Car Pakistan (tel: +92 21 3497 1418; <a href="http://www.rentacarservice.pk" target="_blank">www.rentacarservice.pk</a>).</p><p>The Karakoram Highway, from Islamabad to Kashgar in China, is a popular and demanding bike journey for the fit and adventurous. While cycling is not recommended in and around the cities, further afield in areas such as the Potwar Plateau, between Islamabad and Peshawar, cycling is much safer.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Extensive bus and minibus services operate in Lahore, Karachi and other towns, although services can be crowded. Taxis and auto rickshaws are widely available. Note that they may not operate after sunset during Ramadan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan International Airlines (PIA) (<a href="http://www.piac.com.pk" target="_blank">www.piac.com.pk</a>) flies direct from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/birmingham">Birmingham</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/manchester">Manchester</a> to Islamabad, Lahore and Karachi. PIA also flies direct to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/copenhagen">Copenhagen</a> and other European cities.</p>
<p>Etihad (<a href="http://www.etihadairways.com" target="_blank">www.etihadairways.com</a>) run indirect services from the&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, Europe and the Middle East to several Pakistani cities, as do Emirates, Gulf Air and Kuwait Airways.</p>
<p>While Karachi, Lahore and Islamabad are home to major international airports, there are also international airports in Quetta, Gwadar, Peshawar, Sialkot, Multan, Rahim Yar Khan, Faisalabad and Peshawar.</p>
<p>Flights tend to be cheaper outside of school holidays when many British Pakistanis visit family. They&rsquo;re also cheaper during the cooler months, rather than peak season, which runs from November to March.</p>
<p>Buy domestic tickets while in Pakistan; you will find they are much cheaper than pre-booked tickets.</p>
<p>Major airports are: Allama Iqbal International Airport (LHE), <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pakistan/karachi-jinnah-international-airport">Karachi Jinnah International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pakistan/islamabad-benazir-bhutto-international-airport">Islamabad Benazir Bhutto International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 7 hours 45 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 13 hours 45 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Islamabad Benazir Bhutto International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.islamabadairport.com.pk<p>Islamabad Benazir Bhutto International Airport is located 10km (6 miles) southeast of Islamabad, in the city of Rawalpindi.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+92 51 9928 0300</p>]]><b>Allama Iqbal International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.lahoreairport.com.pk<p>Allama Iqbal International Airport is located approximately 15km (9 miles) from the city of Lahore, Pakistan.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+92 42 990 31000</p>]]><b>Peshawar Bacha Khan International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 4km (2.5 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Karachi Jinnah International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.karachiairport.com.pk<p>Karachi Jinnah International Airport is situated 14km (9 miles) east of central Karachi.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+92 21 9907 1111</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Karachi (also known as Kemari) is Pakistan's port for goods, together with Port Qasim. No passenger boats or ships for the general public sail to or from Pakistan at present.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For more information contact Pakistan Railways (tel: +92 117). A rail link extends from Quetta (via the border crossing at Taftan) to Zahedan, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iran">Iran</a>; the service (journey time - around 30 hours) runs twice a month from Quetta. Main routes are Karachi-Lahore-Rawalpindi-Peshawar, Karachi-Quetta, Quetta-Lahore-Peshawar and the international train to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors exiting Pakistan by land routes are subject to a road toll. Travel to the federally administered tribal areas and the border areas with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/afghanistan">Afghanistan</a> is not recommended. For further information, visitors should seek official advice.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Interstate calls are half price after 1800, but there are no cheap times for international calls. Whilst phone cards are available, not all PCO (public call offices) booths will accept them, nor will all top-end hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is largely limited to main cities. Prepaid SIM cards are available, often with good value starter pack offers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet is available in urban areas where internet cafes can be found, but the service may be erratic. Hotels often charge far higher rates than internet cafes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Former President Pervez Musharraf's rule was marked by increased freedom for the print media and liberalisation of broadcasting policies; the state's monopoly has been diminished by the expansion of private radio and TV stations. In 2005, issued licences for private FM radio stations totalled around 100, but private stations are not allowed to broadcast news. Pakistani censorship, however, remains far more rigorous than in India. The Pakistani Government uses a range of legal and constitutional powers to curb press freedom. The country's law on blasphemy has been used against journalists. Nevertheless, Pakistan's print media are among the most outspoken in South Asia. Media rules were tightened in 2007 after an opposition campaign against President Musharraf.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail takes four to five days to reach Western Europe. It is reliable but slow. Note -  you are not allowed to send any CDs or DVDs out of the country. This is due to the high volume of software and media trafficking in Pakistan.</p><p>General post offices in major cities offer 24-hour services (<a href="http://www.pakpost.gov.pk" target="_blank">www.pakpost.gov.pk</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Drive on the world's highest highway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Karakoram Highway is the world's highest paved road, reaching an elevation of 4,693m (15,397ft) as it meanders through the Himalaya, Hindu Kush and Pamir mountain ranges. Following the ancient Silk Road through breath-taking scenery, the highway offers views over the Indus River and of the beautiful Gilgit and Hunza valleys.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Pakistan’s modern capital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its cutting-edge architecture, leafy parks and world-class cultural sites, Islamabad is a modern metropolis that likes to surprise. Viewed best from Daman-e-Koh – a terraced garden with excellent panoramas over the city – Islamabad is home to some extraordinary sights, not least the magnificent Faisal Masjid, one of the most unusual looking mosques in all of Asia. The Pakistan Museum of Natural History, Lok Virsa Museum and National Gallery of Pakistan also warrant a visit. The latter is home to an impressive four-storey art gallery and a 400-seat auditorium.</p>]]><p><b>Feast your eyes on Lahore</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The capital of Pakistan's Punjab province, Lahore is home to some of the country's finest architecture. Must see sights include the UNESCO listed Shalimar Gardens and the magnificent Badshahi Mosque, which is a beautiful example of Mughal architecture rivalled only by the Taj Mahal. Other must see sights include the Gate of Chauburji, Mughal Jahangir's tomb and Gawalmandi Food Street, which serves some of the finest fare in the land.</p>]]><p><b>Follow the iconic Khyber Pass</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travellers are currently not advised to visit the Khyber Pass. Readers have reported lately that they were refused a permit to travel along this iconic route, due to on-going security fears along the Pakistan-Afghanistan border. Those who are successful will experience the madness of this dusty trade route, where thousands of brightly coloured trucks jostle for space on what used to be part of the Silk Road.</p>]]><p><b>Go on a pilgrimage to Ziarat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The beautiful city of Ziarat is located amongst juniper forests in the province of Baluchistan. Aside from the scenery, the most famous attraction here is Ziarat Residency, the wooded house where Pakistan's founder, Muhammad Ali Jinnah, spent his final days. Another popular pilgrimage site is the shrine of Baba Kharwari – a disciple of Indian revolutionary, Nana Saheb – who has been attributed with causing a number of miracles.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the slopes at Malam Jabba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Blown up by the Taliban in 2006, Pakistan's Malam Jabba ski resort reopened in 2011 – and now it's better than ever. Perched some 2,804m (9,200ft) up in the Karakoram mountain range, Malam Jabba is equipped with state-of-the-art facilities and plans are afoot for a new hotel, cable car and piste.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in cosmopolitan Karachi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated on the shores of the Arabian Sea, Karachi is Pakistan's former capital and its largest city. The bustling port is home to the magnificent Quaid-e-Azam's Mazar, the mausoleum of the founder of Pakistan, which is made exclusively out of white marble. Other places of interest include the National Museum of Pakistan, Port Grand, Sadaar Bazaar and Clifton Beach; Karachi's answer to Venice Beach. A good spot for people watching, visitors can also ride camels and eat the local speciality – roasted corn on the cob.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about Buddhism at the Taxila Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This museum has an extraordinary collection of art from the ancient kingdom of Gandharan, which incorporated modern day northern Pakistan and Afghanistan. The Kingdom of Gandharan (1500-500 BC) was a centre of Buddhist and Hindu culture and the museum showcases many fine exhibits from this period including temple friezes, Buddhist sculptures and ancient coins.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Mohatta Palace Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In 1927, Shiv Rattan Mohatta, a successful Marwari entrepreneur, commissioned a palatial house in the affluent seaside neighbourhood of Clifton, Karachi. Mohatta made his fortune as a ship handler and enlisted the services of Ahmed Hussein Agha, one of the first Muslim architects of India. Today his palace has been converted into the Mohatta Palace Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Peek at Pakistan’s peaks</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan contains five of the world's highest peaks and several of the world's largest glaciers. The northern areas are the most popular for trekking, with Gilgit and Skardu being good starting points for trips. Those visiting Kashmir can see some of the highest mountains in the world, including the famous Nanga Parbat and the second-highest mountain in the world, K2. The Baltoro Glacier and the Batura Glacier are the largest outside the polar regions.</p>]]><p><b>Roam the ruins of Mohenjo-Daro</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Dating back to 2600 BC, Mohenjo-Daro is a fascinating, albeit somewhat dusty, archaeology site in Sindh province. Home to one of the world's first major settlements before it was abandoned in the 19th century, today only ruins remain and they are in a poor state – this UNESCO World Heritage Site is suffering the effects of erosion and poor maintenance. Despite that, it's still worth a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Roam yet more ruins at Takht-i-Bahi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Another UNESCO World Heritage Site, the beautiful Buddhists monastic complex of Takht-i-Bahi is located approximately 80km (49 miles) from Peshawar in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa province. Constructed in the 1st century BC, Takht-i-Bahi is the most complete Buddhist monastery in Pakistan.</p>]]><p><b>Stimulate your senses at Anarkali Bazaar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the oldest bazaars in Asia, Anarkali is a place that will awaken your senses. Listen to the tinkle of glass bangles, feel the fine silk wares and smell the spices wafting from the traditional food stalls. And don't forget to tuck into the famous <em>chaat</em> of Anarkali Bazaar – the reason why many school children make a detour here on their way home.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the Chitral Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sitting in the shadow of the Hindu Kush, is Chitral Valley. A wild and beautiful place, most visitors to this rugged region base themselves in Chitral, a laidback, welcoming town that feels quite different to the rest of Pakistan. Chitral is also conveniently located for a visit to the Kalash Valleys, where the Kalash people, the last of the non-Islamic tribes of Kafiristan, live. This valley is noted for its hot springs and trout-filled rivers.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Qila Bala Hisar fort in Peshawar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ancient city of Peshawar is often overlooked due to on-going problems in the region. However, those travelling to this dusty metropolis will be rewarded for their perseverance by the magnificent sight of Qila Bala Hisar fort, which was used by King Timur Shah Durrani (1773-1793) as the winter capital of the Afghan Durrani Empire. The fort can be found in the old town, which is characterised by ubiquitous donkey carts, ancient bazaars and traditional Mughal architecture.</p>]]><p><b>Watch a traditional polo match</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Polo is a popular sport in the northern towns of Gilgit and Chitral, where they play a wild form of the traditional game: pomp and snobbery is replaced by live music and a lot of bravado from the crowd. The first game of the season tends to be after the Spring Festival, towards the end of March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$236.6 billion (2014)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Textiles, rice, leather goods, sports goods, carpets and rugs.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum and petroleum products, machinery, plastics, transport equipment and edible oils.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, China, United Arab Emirates, India and UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Once a great agricultural land, exporting many kinds of fruit and cotton, the economy has been hit by internal strife and upheaval in the region. A country where power cuts are now the norm, the economy is flagging.</p><p>The EIU predicts and annual growth of nearly 4% a year until 2018. Inflation is at 9.2% with a moderate growth in GDP. Pakistan stands at 110th in terms of doing business out of amongst 189 economies of the world covered by the World Bank.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Image is everything in Pakistan's modern business society, so dress the part when attending meetings. Men should wear a shirt and tie, and women should avoid wearing skirts.</p><p>Appointments should be made in advance, but business is done at a leisurely pace so be patient and expect interruptions during a meeting (Pakistanis have an open door policy). Most meetings are held at the office or in the best hotel in town. All Islamic festival days are upheld and are usually days off for celebration. Some businesses create a religious working environment for their employees as part of developing personnel imbued with honesty, loyalty and required sense of duty. So be prepared for regular breaks for prayer time.</p><p>Mon-Thurs and Sat 0900-1700; Fri 0900-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Federation of Pakistan Chambers of Commerce (FPCCI)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 587 3691
					Website:http://www.fpcci.com.pk
					Address: Main Clifton,Federation House,Karachi,]]><b>Overseas Investors' Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 242 6076 ,241 0814
					Website:http://www.oicci.org
					Address: Talpur Road,Chamber of Commerce Building,Karachi 74000,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Pakistani cuisine is based on masala (hot and spicy) sauces accompanying chicken, lamb, prawns and a wide choice of vegetables. Its flavours are drawn from its Afghani, Turkish and Iranian roots.</p><p>Pakistan is dry, hot and dusty – the perfect climate in which to enjoy a cool and refreshing <em>lassi </em>yogurt drink. This popular drink can be sweet or savoury but is most often fruit-flavoured</p><p>Pakistanis have a sweet tooth. <em>Jalebis</em>, those crispy, orange swirls that are cooked on the side of the street throughout the subcontinent, are ever present, as are all kinds of variations on <em>halwa</em> (an egg and carrot based dessert). A good breakfast option is a fried <em>paratha</em> (unleavened bread) with egg.</p><p>There are plenty of snacks to pick up on your travels throughout Pakistan including <em>pakora</em>, the gram flour deep-fried vegetable balls, and <em>kachori, </em>the lentil-filled pastries.</p><p>Pakistanis are big meat eaters. While there are designated meat-free days in Pakistan, most meals will come with meat.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><em>&bull; Chappali </em>(beef kebab) and a peshawari  nan<br />
<em>&bull; Kheer</em> (rice pudding) served in a clay pot<br />
&bull; Biryani (seasoned rice with mutton, chicken and yoghurt)<br />
&bull; Fried fish and rumali roti (a Karachi speciality)<br />
<em>&bull; Sag gosht</em> (spinach and lamb curry)<br />
<em>&bull; Shish</em> kebab (charcoal-grilled meat on skewers)<br />
<em>&bull; Shami </em>kebab (patties of chopped meat fried in ghee or butter)<br />
&bull; Halwa (desserts made with eggs, carrots, maize cream, semolina and nuts)</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol may be bought at major hotels by visitors who have been issued a Liquor Permit from the Excise and Taxation Office. Wine is expensive and only available in upscale restaurants. Pakistani-brewed beer is available, as are canned carbonated drinks. There are no bars since there are strict laws concerning alcohol, and it is illegal to drink in public. Waiter service is provided in the larger hotels and restaurants. Visitors should avoid drinking water from the tap; bottled water is available everywhere, but it is necessary to make sure it comes in properly sealed plastic bottles.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most high-end hotels and restaurants add a 10% service charge. Other tipping is discretionary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With alcohol consumption prohibited in Pakistan, there is little Western-style nightlife. A night out is likely to involve visiting a cinema or restaurant, many of which show international as well as Pakistani films.</p><p>Lahore has the liveliest nightlife thanks to the Al Hamra Art Centre, which puts on popular theatre performances and musical events throughout the year. After the show, patrons head to the fantastic Gawalmandi Food Street, which is a one-stop shop for delicious Pakistani food. Others choose to stroll around Racecourse Park or go for a coffee at the Fortress Stadium.</p><p>Karachi's nightlife tends to centre round shopping on Tariq Road or the beach promenade at Clifton. Well-heeled diners can be found tucking into buffet dinners at one of the city's many top end hotels. Others head to the culinary Mecca that is Burns Road, which serves gorgeous street food in chaotic surrounds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Pakistan the major towns have craft centres where handicrafts from different regions are sold. Special purchases include carved wooden tables, trays, onyx ware, silver trinkets, pottery, camel-skin lamps, woodwork, brassware, glass bangles, gold ornaments, hand-embroidered shawls, rugs and carpets, silk, cashmere shawls and <em>saleem shahi </em>slippers with upturned toes.</p><p>However, bazaars often provide the most interesting shopping. Peshawar (Old City) is home to some of the best bazaars in the country; they specialise in rugs, woollen hats <em>(topis)</em>, leather <em>chappals</em> (shoes) and <em>chadors</em> (a type of light woollen blanket). In Peshawar and Karachi visit the Meena Bazaar (ladies only). It is a maze of shops mainly selling women's wear.</p><p>It is expected that the customer should bargain for goods and as a tourist you will be asked to stop and look, or to pause for chai. The Saddar district of Karachi is good for souvenir style shopping and this is where the famous Zainab Market can be found. In Lahore try the Anarkali Bazar, which is believed to be the oldest bazaar in South Asia.</p><p>Air-conditioned shopping malls with food courts and shops are popping up all across the country, especially in Karachi. Malls can be a great way to beat the heat and offer a wide-range of international cuisine. Popular malls in Karachi include The Forum, Park Towers and Dolmen Mall. In Lahore, for a modern experience, try the Pace shopping centre.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0930-1300 and 1500-1830. Bazaars stay open longer.</p><p>There are restrictions on what you can bring out of the country. If you are in doubt about antiques, it is safest to ask a museum curator. If you are carrying pieces of furniture of any description, at the airport you will be asked to produce receipts. Jewellery must be worth less than $500 (US) if bought in Pakistan, again keep receipts. Most foreigners at the airport are subject to baggage inspection upon departure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan offers a wide range of accommodation. Modern well-equipped hotels can be found in most major towns and offer excellent facilities such as swimming pools and sports facilities. There are also cottages, Dak bungalows and rest houses in all principal hill stations and health resorts. A government room tax of up to 17.5% is added to the cost of accommodation. In all cases it is advisable to book well in advance and check reservations.<br/><br/>The Pakistan Tourism Development Corporation (PTDC) manages two hotels, as well as 38 well-furnished and moderately priced motels throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Homestays and guesthouses are popular throughout Asia and do exist in Pakistan also, although there isn't much of a network as such. In the northern areas the PTDC has worked with several homeowners to turn rooms in family homes into guestrooms suitable for guests, at these you cannot expect any of the facilities of a good hotel, but the hospitality will be good, as will the home cooked food.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan offers a wide range of accommodation. Modern well-equipped hotels can be found in most major towns and offer excellent facilities such as swimming pools and sports facilities. There are also cottages, Dak bungalows and rest houses in all principal hill stations and health resorts. A government room tax of up to 17.5% is added to the cost of accommodation. In all cases it is advisable to book well in advance and check reservations.<br/><br/>The Pakistan Tourism Development Corporation (PTDC) manages two hotels, as well as 38 well-furnished and moderately priced motels throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan offers a wide range of accommodation. Modern well-equipped hotels can be found in most major towns and offer excellent facilities such as swimming pools and sports facilities. There are also cottages, Dak bungalows and rest houses in all principal hill stations and health resorts. A government room tax of up to 17.5% is added to the cost of accommodation. In all cases it is advisable to book well in advance and check reservations.<br/><br/>The Pakistan Tourism Development Corporation (PTDC) manages two hotels, as well as 38 well-furnished and moderately priced motels throughout the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Outside of the major cities healthcare is very basic.  You should take out comprehensive travel and medical insurance before travelling, including cover for medical repatriation costs. Seek medical advice before travelling to Pakistan and make certain that all appropriate vaccinations are up to date. Malaria exists in Pakistan, in coastal and low-lying areas. Dengue fever is a threat throughout. In a serious medical emergency the best option is to be evacuated. In an emergency your first point of call should be your embassy and insurance company. To call an ambulance, dial the Edhi Trust Ambulance Service on 115. The Edhi Foundation (&lt;a href="http://www.edhifoundation.com" target="_blank"&gt;www.edhifoundation.com&lt;/a&gt;) has eight hospitals in Karachi alone and a fleet of over 400 ambulances. It is funded almost entirely by private donations, 90% of which come from within the country. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Islamabad has several passable medical facilities. Shifa International (Sector H-8/4,Islamabad; tel: (51) 460 3666) -  is regarded as the best in the city. In Lahore Mayo Hospital (Hospital Road, Lahore; tel: (42) 921 1100.  In Karachi, the Aga Khan University Hospital is a good choice (Stadium Road, tel: (21) 493 0051) and takes credit cards.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. When buying bottled water check that the seal is intact and that it hasn't been tampered with. Never drink tap water and try to avoid fruit juices unless from a carton as they may have had contaminated water added to them. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from un-boiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, avoid shellfish and be wary of buffets. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled. Try to choose busy restaurants where the food will have a high turnover.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against Japanese B encephalitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis A (a food and water borne virus) and B are sometimes recommended. Long-term travellers might want to consider having an immunisation against rabies. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In the mountains altitude sickness is a real peril and anything above 3,000m (9,843ft) is considered a risk. The key to avoiding this is to ascend slowly and sleep lower than the height reached that day. Avoid alcohol and keep hydrated. Paracetamol can help with headaches associated with altitude sickness. Earth tremors are frequent and mountainous areas frequently experience floods and landslides. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It is a good idea to pack a personal medical kit. Key items to include are DEET-based insect repellent, oral rehydration salts, decongestant, anti-inflammatory tablets, sunscreen and iodine to sterilise water (not good for pregnant women or those with thyroid issues).&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>(a) Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.<br /><br />(b) Christian holidays are observed by Christians only.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Pakistan Day :
							23 March </p><p>Independence Day :
							14 August </p><p>Allama Muhammad Iqbal Day :
							09 November </p><p>Quaid-e-Azam's Birthday :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Pakistan by tourists over the age of 18 without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; Other goods to the value of US$100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alcoholic drinks, animal feed from BSE-infected countries, anti-Islamic goods, counterfeit or pirated goods, fireworks, Koran translations without accompanying Arabic text, indecent and obscene material, items that infringe intellectual property rights, weapons, and firearms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Antiques, items that infringe intellectual property rights, certain chemicals, counterfeit and pirated goods, endangered species, indecent and obscene material, intoxicating liquors, and narcotics.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan Rupee (PKR; symbol Rs). Notes are in denominations of Rs5,000, 1,000, 500, 100, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of Rs5, 2 and 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express is the most widely accepted card. MasterCard and Visa are also good, but Diners Club and other cards have more limited use. In general, unless you are travelling at the top end the entire time, cash is far more useful – only high-end hotels, airline offices, upmarket shops and restaurants will accept credit cards. In the mountains and in the countryside it is best to carry cash in rupees, and do not assume that money changing facilities will be available.</p><p>There are ATMs in all major cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally accepted at most banks, 4- and 5-star hotels and major shops, though the exchange can often be problematic. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> cheques are the most widely accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Sat 0900-1330, Fri 0900-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months beyond the intended length of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Children need their own passports. Immigration authorities will demand documentary evidence of parental responsibility, especially if the child is of Pakistani origin, before permitting the child to leave the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas are required by all nationals in the chart above and are valid for 72 hours; travellers must hold confirmed onward tickets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: &pound;134; double-entry visa: &pound;152; one-year multiple-entry visa: &pound;362; two-year multiple-entry visa: &pound;362; three-year multiple-entry visa: &pound;512. Reductions are available for Pakistani/British dual nationals. These fees include the &pound;30 service fee charged by Gerry's Visa Services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry/double-entry visas: six months from the date of issue for stays of up to three months; multiple-entry visas: one, two or three years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consulate section at embassy/high commission). In the UK, the high commission uses the company Gerry's Visa Services to process applications (<a href="http://www.visadropbox.com">www.visadropbox.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Depends on nationality (in the UK, visas are normally granted within five working days). Enquire at the nearest consulate or embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is usually possible for tourists to extend their stay. Contact the Regional Passport Office in Islamabad.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[29.316036]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[68.764999]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>796,095 sq km (307,374 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>192,826,502 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>250.1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Islamabad.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan has borders to the north with Afghanistan, to the east with India and to the west with Iran; the Arabian Sea lies to the south. In the northeast is the disputed territory of Jammu and Kashmir, bounded by Afghanistan, China and India. The land covers a huge 796,096 sq km (305,058 sq miles) making it over three times the size of the UK.</p>
<p>Pakistan comprises six distinct regions. There is the northern mountain area which has a high concentration of jaw-dropping peaks, and some of the largest glaciers outside of the polar regions - in fact five are over 45 km (28 miles) in length - as well as the Himalayan range which includes the fabled Nanga Parbat, which stands a whopping 8,125m (26,657ft) tall. The other regions are comprised by the northern plateau, which is effectively the lowlands at the bottom of the mountain ranges, the western mountains, the Balochistan plateau (which is hilly and very sparsely populated), the southeast desert which stretches into Rajasthan in India and the plain of the river Indus, which is within Sindh and the Punjab (&lsquo;Punjab&rsquo; literally means five waters, named after the Indus and it&rsquo;s four tributaries).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>97% Muslim (77% Sunni, 20% Shi'a), the remainder are Ismaili Muslims (who follow the Aga Khan as their spiritual leader), Hindu or Christian.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The right hand is used both for shaking hands (the usual form of greeting) and for passing or receiving things. Mutual hospitality and courtesy are of great importance at all levels, whatever the social standing of the host. Visitors must remember that most Pakistanis are Muslim and should respect their customs and beliefs.<br />
<br />
Smoking is prohibited in some public places and it is polite to ask permission before lighting a cigarette. It is common for visiting businesspeople to be entertained in hotels and restaurants. If invited to a private home, a gift or national souvenir is welcome. Informal dress is acceptable for most occasions. Women should avoid wearing tight clothing and both men and women should ensure that their arms and legs are covered. Pakistani society is divided into classes and within each group there is a subtle social grading. The Koran is the law for Muslims and it influences every aspect of daily life.<br />
<br />
<strong>Photography: </strong>Do not take photographs at military establishments, airports or of any infrastructure, including dams and bridges or from aircraft. The penalties can be severe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs with two or three round pins are most common.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Imran Khan since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Arif Alvi since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The territory of present day Pakistan has witnessed the rise and fall of countless empires, which have contested this land from as early as 550BC, when <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Achaemenid_Empire" target="_blank">the Achaemenid Empire</a> controlled vast swathes of Asia, Arabian and Northern Africa.</p>
<p>By 323BC the marauding Macedonian, Alexander the Great, had staked his claim to Pakistan, setting a trend for conquering that continued for the next 2000 years.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/religion/religions/islam/history/mughalempire_1.shtml" target="_blank">The Mughal Empire (1526-1857)</a> lasted longest and helped develop the region economically. Agriculture, art and commerce flourished during Mughal rule, which left behind a sophisticated administration and a wealth of architecture that still wows visitors today.</p>
<p>The British arrived in the region in the early 1800s and in 1849 the territory now known as Pakistan was incorporated into British India. It was not until 1947, as a result of a violent partition from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>, that Pakistan acquired nationhood.</p>
<p>Under pressure from Indian Muslims led by Mohammed Ali Jinnah - who is considered to be the 'father of the nation' - the British created a separate Muslim state consisting of two parts; East Pakistan (now <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangladesh">Bangladesh</a>) and West Pakistan (now a single unitary state), which were separated by 1,600km (1,000 miles) of Indian territory.</p>
<p>Political and religious disputes between the territories resulted in a civil war, which lasted for most of 1971. It was brought to an end by the intervention of India, which forced Pakistan to surrender and recognise the independence of modern day Bangladesh.</p>
<p>Pakistan&rsquo;s relationship with India remains fraught. Both nations lay claim to Kashmir and have fought wars over the territory. Pakistan presently occupies one-third of the disputed territory and India occupies the other two-thirds. The Kashmiris themselves have become weary of both sides and there is a growing appetite for independence.</p>
<p>In contrast to India, democracy failed to take root in Pakistan, which suffered prolonged periods of military rule. After decades of revolving-door politics followed by incompetence, nepotism and corruption, tackling Pakistan's huge political and economic problems remains tougher than ever.</p>
<p>Although the country has struggled to maintain a foothold on political stability, Pakistan remains a politically aware nation, with a culture broadly based around family, Islam and an acceptance of different ethnic groups living throughout the country.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; Pakistan is home to the highest paved road in the world. Perched 4,693m (15,397ft) above sea level, the Karakoram Highway links <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> with Pakistan.<br />
&bull; The name Pakistan means &lsquo;land of the pure&rsquo; in Persian and Urdu.<br />
&bull; Pakistan has the world&rsquo;s largest volunteer ambulance service, founded by Sattar Edhi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Pakistan]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(51) 201 2000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/pakistan</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(51) 201 2000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs: 0800-1615; Fri: 0800-1300&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>P O Box 1122<br/>Diplomatic Enclave, Ramna 5<br/>Islamabad<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Islamic Republic of Pakistan in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 243 6500.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofpakistanusa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 243 6500.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1230 (document submission) and 1500-1630 (document collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>3517 International Ct NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission for Pakistan in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7664 9204.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.pakmission-uk.gov.pk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7664 9204.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1730 (general opening hours); Mon-Thurs 1000-1230, Fri 1000-1200 (visa submission); 1500-1700 (visa collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>34-36 Lowndes Square<br/>London<br/>SW1X 9JN<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From the ancient Mughal city of Lahore to the snow-capped peaks of the Karakoram Mountains, Pakistan is a diverse nation defined not just by its natural beauty and architectural splendours, but by its friendly inhabitants, varied wildlife and rich culinary traditions.</p>
<p>Shame then, that political instability and sectarian violence has made large parts of the country a no-go for tourists, and prevented Pakistan from realising its potential as a top travel destination.</p>
<p>However, those daring enough to take a punt on Pakistan will be richly rewarded for their endeavours &ndash; particularly those with a penchant for the great outdoors. The North-West Frontier Province and Gilgit-Baltistan region are home to some of the world&rsquo;s most famous mountain ranges, including Himalaya, Karakoram and Hindu Kush.</p>
<p>That explorers will have these sights more or less to themselves is another boon; gone are the well-marked routes and tea houses of India and Nepal, here lies real adventure.</p>
<p>From jaw-dropping mountain scenery to bustling conurbations, Pakistan&rsquo;s vibrant cities each have their own distinct flavour. The super-sleek capital, Islamabad, is a modern metropolis bristling with contemporary architecture, world-class cultural attractions and some of the country&rsquo;s finest restaurants.</p>
<p>Lahore is the very antithesis to Islamabad. Pakistan&rsquo;s cultural capital, this ancient city abounds with UNESCO listed attractions, stunning shrines and ornate Mughal architecture. Its old town is a maze of bustling bazaars, which harbour mosques, museums and manicured gardens.</p>
<p>Karachi, the former capital and the economic powerhouse of the country, is a mega-city in every sense of the word, cramming 15 million or so into its boundaries. Meanwhile, Peshawar, in the North-West Frontier Province, remains a frontier town, sometimes dangerous and always intriguing.</p>
<p>Those seeking sun and seclusion, should explore Pakistan&rsquo;s glorious coastline, which is home to some of the most pristine, crowd-free beaches in South Asia. While those looking to evoke the spirit a Kipling-style adventure should follow the ancient trade routes of the Khyber Pass, Grand Trunk Road and Karakoram Highway.</p>
All of this and more lies in Pakistan, and all remains accessible to the more adventurous tourist.</p>From ancient cities to jaw-dropping mountain scenery, fertile valleys to bustling bazaars, Pakistan encapsulates diversity. It is a land enhanced by friendly, welcoming people, rich culinary and musical traditions, different ethnic groups, varied wildlife, sport and a wealth of architectural glories. ]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
