<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Palau" ColCode="plw" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="pw" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Palau]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Being so close to the equator, Palau enjoys a steady warm climate all year round with an annual average temperature of 30°C (86°F). Dry season runs from November to April with maximum temperatures of around 32°C (90°F) and lows of 27°C (81°F). Humidity is high all year round.</p><p>Rainy season falls between July and October, and thunderstorms are quite common but typhoons, when it can rain for days at a time, are fairly rare, as the islands are too close to the equator to be in the hurricane corridor.</p><p>For divers, the best time to go to Palau is during the dry season, from September to May, when calmer seas mean it's easier for boats to get to particular areas. Manta rays can be seen all year round, but to see the sharks you'll need to visit in March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Palau's temperate climate means that for the majority of trips, not much more than lightweight cottons, linens and beachwear will be needed. Keep a jumper on you for the evenings and if you're venturing inland. If you're planning to do some outdoor activities – hiking, kayaking, etc – then be sure to take the specialist equipment that you'll need. Rain is possible all year round so don't go without packing some sort of light rainwear – a good quality waterproof jacket may be sufficient.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belau Air (<a href="http://www.underwatercolours.com/belauair" target="_blank">www.underwatercolours.com/belauair</a>), Palau's domestic airline, flies between Koror and Peleliu and Angaur. In addition, Palau Helicopters (<a href="http://www.palauhelicopters.com" target="_blank">www.palauhelicopters.com</a>) offers scenic flights over the rock islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Palau's islands are its main attraction, and there are dozens of tour operators offering trips to the rock islands and between the main islands of Palau. Unscheduled inter-island boat services are available to Babeldaob and Kayangel and it's possible to hitch a ride with one of the local boats heading out to the islands. Several tour operators also offer private day charter of boats.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The vast majority of Palau's islands are unpaved and most don't have any road infrastructure at all. The main island of Koror has paved roads which are well-maintained, while the majority of Babeldaob Island (which is accessed via a road bridge from Koror) has less well-maintained roads which are best accessed by 4-wheel drive vehicles. The airport is located in the southern part of Babeldaob in Airai and has good quality road and public transport connections with Koror.</p>
<p>Almost all dive centres, hotels and resorts offer shuttle services to and from the airport. Most dive centres also arrange morning and afternoon pick-ups from hotels and guest houses, meaning car hire isn't always necessary.</p>
<p>Despite driving on the right, most cars are left-hand drive as they are imported from Japan, which can be slightly confusing for visitors renting a car. Koror's diminutive size and few roads however means they are easily and safely navigable.</p>r<p>The road network is extended beyond the paved roads of Koror to Babeldaob Island with many coral and dirt roads connecting to other states such as Meyungs. There is one main road through Koror and despite its small size of 14km (9 miles) in length, it does get congested during rush hour. The majority of Babeldaob's main circular road is in fairly good condition, although side roads can be less well maintained. There are few pavements, so pedestrians should take care.</p><p>There are many taxis in Koror offering comfortable travel. They are not metered and fares are fixed (drivers carry a rate sheet which you can ask to see). It's common to hire the services of a particular taxi driver for the duration of your stay and simply call them each time you need a lift. Restaurants, hotels and activity centres will happily call a taxi for you.</p><p>Drivers are permitted to drive in Palau on an International Driving Permit for 30 days, after which they must apply for a Palauan licence.</p><p>The maximum speed limit is 40kph (25mph) and it is illegal to overtake slow-moving cars (although this does happen).</p><p>Due to Palau&rsquo;s small size and its navigable roads, a breakdown doesn&rsquo;t have to be disastrous. If you encounter a breakdown in a hire vehicle, simply telephone the car hire company and they will arrange for assistance.</p><p>You can hire cars from the airport upon arrival and there are several local companies to choose from, as well as the international Budget Car Rental. Drivers must be at least 21 years of age.</p><p>You can rent bikes from a cycle-hire centre in Koror for a day or longer. It offers well-maintained mountain bikes, which are ideal for visiting Babeldaob.</p><p>The maximum speed limit is 40kph (25mph) and it is illegal to overtake slow-moving cars (although this does happen).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Koror is the main town, and due to its small size it's easy to get around on foot. Alternatively, taxis are widely available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) flies from Honolulu to Guam,&nbsp;where there is a connection to Airai International Airport (ROR) in Palau. For visitors arriving from Europe, United also offers connections in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/manila">Manila</a>. Korean Air (<a href="http://www.koreanair.com" target="_blank">www.koreanair.com</a>) and Asiana Airlines (<a href="http://www.flyasiana.com" target="_blank">www.flyasiana.com</a>) offer a direct route from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seoul">Seoul</a>, China Airlines (<a href="http://www.china-airlines.com" target="_blank">www.china-airlines.com</a>) from Taipei City and Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) from Tokyo.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights from both <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/new-york">New York</a> to Palau tend to travel via Tokyo or Guam, and take approximately 24 hours, allowing for varying stopover times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a departure tax and green fee of US$50 per person which must be paid directly at the airport upon leaving.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Koror Babeldaob</b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors who sail privately to Palau can moor at Malakal Harbour and at M-Dock on Koror and will find Naval Oceanographic charts to be most useful. US Naval Chart HO 5500 covers the entire region of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pacific-islands-micronesia/federated-states-micronesia">Micronesia</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Palau does have a rudimentary telecommunications system, and there are landlines in use, with which you can use a pre-paid phone card. However do not expect an extensive telephone network.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Depending on where you are from, it is possible to use a mobile phone on Palau as the main telecommunications operator PNCC does have a few roaming agreements in place with various international operators. However, it's best to assume that your phone's not going to work, and be pleasantly surprised if it does. If you'll be on Palau for an extended period of time, and your phone is unlocked, it may be more prudent to pick up a sim card from a local vendor and use this to make any calls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet access is readily available in Palau but by most standards it is horrifically slow. However this is slowly improving as private companies and the government invest into infrastructure supporting broadband connections. There are various WiFi hotspots on Koror that you can access (including one at the airport) but it's unlikely you'll be able to do much more than send and download emails. Most hotels will have a Wi-Fi connection that guests can use, although there may be a fee for usage. There are several internet cafes on Koror.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Palau has a free press, but most of it is state-owned. <em>Island Times</em> comes out twice weekly, whilst English-language newspaper <em>Tia Belau </em>is published once a week, as is Palauan <em>Roureur Belau</em>. The other English weekly <em>Palau Horizon</em>, closed down in 2010. The privately-owned TV station OTN is the only form of media in the hands of foreign ownership. Cable TV is popular in homes. The main radio stations are Palau Wave and T8AA Eco Paradise, a government-run station.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is one post office, located on Koror. Officially it takes around 10 working days for post from Palau to reach the USA, as most packages and letters go via Guam first. Unofficially, it make take much longer. Palau's bright stamps are often considered collector's items.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Chart a sailing boat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get out into the heart of the Rock Islands aboard a sailing yacht or dive liveaboard. Spending a few days aboard a gently rocking ship, moving from one remote, idyllic island to another is a truly memorable way to experience Palau's natural beauty and its most memorable dive sites.</p>]]><p><b>Don your wetsuit</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get active with one of the many watersports on offer. Choose from snorkelling trips, sea kayaking, sailing, sportfishing, surfing and of course diving and get out into the heart of the Rock Islands. There are several high quality outfits that offer a variety of trips and tours.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Koror</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Most people use Koror as a stepping-stone to explore the rest of Palau. But hang around in the capital, the busiest centre in the islands, and you will find many craft shops, a handful of local restaurants and some lively bars, which serve up an authentic slice of Palauan culture.</p>]]><p><b>Feed your head at Ngarachamayong Cultural Centre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover more about Palau's rich cultural heritage by paying a visit to the cultural centre, funded by a $2.5million grant from China. Palauan culture is matrilineal and the centre was founded by a group of visionary women who aim to preserve local traditions and educate locals and visitors alike.</p>]]><p><b>Go scuba diving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy Palau's many and varied dive sites – considered some of the best in the world – including the famous Blue Corner. Other top sites are Ngemelis Wall, aka the Big Drop-off; the German Channel, known for its manta rays; Siaes Tunnel, an underwater cavern where white-tip reef sharks are common; and Chandelier Cave, where underwater chambers filled with stalactites.</p>]]><p><b>Kayak around Rock Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the stunning natural beauty of the Rock Islands by kayak or canoe. Jutting out from the water, the Rock Islands are Palau's crowning glory and there are countless dive and aqua sports centres offering guided or self-guided kayak tours.</p>]]><p><b>Pay a visit to Palau Aquarium</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Understand Palau's diverse marine ecosystem better with a visit to the aquarium. Themed exhibits feature varieties of hard and soft corals, some of the region's numerous fish species as well as invertebrates such as the famous stingless jellyfish, giant clams and even crocodiles. The aquarium is part of the Palau International Coral Reef Centre.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out WWII relics</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Step back in time with Palau's abundance of WWII relics. Some of the most ferocious battles of the Pacific took place in these waters and submerged war wrecks, fighter planes, rusted machine guns and hidden bunkers rest as testament to the thousands of men who lost their lives here.</p>]]><p><b>Set sail for Peleliu Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the island of Peleliu, which forms the southern boundary of the Rock Islands. In 1985 it was designated a US National Historic Landmark, owing to the part it played in WWII. Abandoned tanks, helmets and bomb casings are still dotted throughout the island and some of Palau's best dive sites are located here.</p>]]><p><b>Swim in Jellyfish Lake</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't worry: it won't hurt. Located in one of the Rock Islands, it was cut off from the sea millions of years ago and the jellyfish have evolved to be completely stingless. Snorkelling through the dark lake amidst hundreds of thousands of jellyfish is a unique experience.</p>]]><p><b>Swim with dolphins</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Look into the eyes of a dolphin as you swim alongside it in the clear, fish-laden waters of Palau. Located just off Koror, the Dolphins Pacific is one of the world's largest marine mammal interaction, educational and research facilities and offers wonderful opportunities to swim with these magnificent creatures.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hike on Babeldaob</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Roam around Babeldaob, Palau's biggest island at about 43km (27 miles) long and 24km (15 miles) across at its widest. It is a tropical gem comprising lush, green vegetation, steep mountains, freshwater lakes and sand dunes. It offers great opportunities for hiking, driving (4x4s are recommended) or mountain biking.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Badrulchau Monoliths</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the 37 stone monoliths known as Badrulchau, concrete examples of Babeldaob's early civilisation. The basalt stone pillars, weighing up to 4,500kg each, are believed to date to around AD100 and archaeologists think they may have been the support for a building. They are found located in a field in the far north of Babeldaob Island.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around the Belau National Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn about the ancestry and rich cultural heritage of Palau with a visit to the Belau National Museum where more than 1,000 relics of the past are housed, including shell money and traditional weapons. Exhibits include photographs, art, sculptures and the traditional carved storyboards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$221 million (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Shellfish, tuna, copra, garments, yachts.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery (including cars), equipment, fuels, metals and foodstuffs.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Japan, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/philippines">Philippines</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a>, China and South Korea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Palau's main economy is tourism, most notably from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-korea">South Korea</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a> and the United States, although other services include trade in fish and shellfish, subsistence agriculture mainly in coconuts, copra, cassava (tapioca) and sweet potatoes and craft items made from shell, wood and pearls.</p><p>Indeed, 20% of the labour force is employed in agriculture, with a 4.2% unemployment rate and an inflation rate of 2.7%. From 2010 to 2011 Palau saw a 27% increase in tourist and business arrivals to the country (109,000) and there has been significant expansion of air travel from Asia and the United States allowing for easier access.</p><p>Following the end of UN trusteeship on 1st October 1994, Palau received financial assistance from the United States under the Compact of Free Association in return for unrestricted access to its lands and waterways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In general, business etiquette in Palau is the same as in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">United States</a> or Western Europe, although it can be slightly more informal. The typical greeting amongst business associates is a handshake, whether between men or women and in general, business dress is casual and ties are not normally worn. In some situations floral or Hawaiian-type shirts and shorts can be acceptable, although long trousers are the norm for more formal meetings.</p><p>While Palauan is spoken in casual situations, English is spoken in business environments and with foreigners. Polite small talk is common before meetings and gifts are appreciated although not expected if visiting from abroad. The chewing of betel nut is common for all Palauans (especially men) and this can be unusual to visitors, especially in business situations.</p><p>Mon-Fri 1000-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Airai View Hotel</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 587 3530
					Website:http://www.airaiview.com
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Palau Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 488 3400
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Palauan food is wonderfully varied and draws heavily on influences from the United States, Japan, the Philippines, Indonesia and Malaysia. This variety is seen in the range of restaurants on offer which have an eclectic mix of cuisines from Indian curries with a Palauan twist, to fresh sushi and sashimi bars, Italian, American BBQ joints, Chinese, Korean and local eateries. Fresh local seafood is the highlight of many menus and there are many exotic local dishes to try.</p><p>Local cuisine is typical of the Pacific islands and root vegetables such as taro, <em>pandan</em>, yams and pumpkin are staples (taro in particular is an important traditional food source of the Palauan people and harvested exclusively by women). Colourful, exotic fruits such as the dragon fruit, mango, passionfruit and breadfruit can be found alongside lesser known varieties such as the rambutan and soursop. Coconut is a widely used ingredient for flavouring everything from fish to soups. Rice is also an important ingredient and eaten with most meals.</p><p>American and Japanese influences are evident, with BBQ sauce smothered on grilled pork or chicken gracing many a menu alongside the freshest of sashimi, sushi and tempura. There is a wonderful blend of seafood, rice dishes, spices and root vegetables that combine to create a truly Asian fusion cuisine.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>• <em>Taro</em> (ubiquitous plant used to make dishes such as taro soup, taro salads or rosti-style taro cakes). <br/>• Fruit bat soup (whole fruit bat wings and head included cooked in a broth of coconut). <br/>• Broiled fish (a whole fish cooked with garlic, ginger and banana leaf). <br/>• <em>Tinola</em> (soup made with chicken and papaya and ginger).<br/>• <em>Ulkoy</em> (crunchy, deep fried shrimp and squash fritters). <br/>• <em>Pichi-pichi</em> (a traditional dessert made with coconut and cassava).<br/>• <em>Halo-halo</em> (milk with coconut, plantains, jackfruit and yams).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Chewing of betel nuts is common in Palau. The nut is chewed along with lime, piper leaf and often with tobacco and the excess saliva is spat out. It turns the mouth red so it is not uncommon to be talking to a local with bright red teeth!</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tipping is optional but appreciated in restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As a premier diving destination Palau's visitors tend to go to bed early and rise early, meaning it isn't known for its bounding nightlife. Having said that there are still a good few places to unwind and enjoy a few of the local Red Rooster beers.</p><p>The dive shops have small, rustic bars which tend to have a relaxed fun atmosphere for apr<em>è</em>s diving and for watching the spectacular sunsets. There are lots of lively restaurants in Koror serving a variety of international food, but for bars, Malakal has the lion's share of nightlife venues (most of which offer food too). Some of the most popular venues with foreign visitors are the restaurants with bars which have a tropical, lively atmosphere. From open air cocktail lounges, some of which have live entertainment or karaoke, to Happy Hour beers, pool halls and the more swish bars found in the hotel resorts, there is a good selection of relaxed venues where you can let your hair down.</p><p>For dancing, head to the Port area of Malakal, where there are some cha-cha clubs popular with young Palauans. Most places stay open until 0200 but if it's quiet they will close early.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Koror has a range of modern shopping facilities on offer. Several small gift shops offer a variety of traditional souvenirs and t-shirts as well as some more unusual items, and the Belau National Museum and Ormuul Gift Shop offer authentic handmade local craft items.<br/><br/>Palau's best-known art form is the storyboard. These are carvings on various lengths of wood, sometimes shaped into crocodiles, turtles or fish and painted. The storyboards depict Palauan stories taken from about 30 popular legends or recorded events. In addition to the storyboards, models of <em>bais</em> (men's meeting buses), canoes and sculptured figurines called <em>dilukai</em> are also carved.<br/><br/>Other gifts include jewellery, etchings and baskets, purses, hats and mats woven from pandana leaves and palm. In addition to these local crafts, the Palau Pacific Resort has a duty-free shop, which features locally produced items as well as designer and brand name gifts.</p><p>The WCTC Shopping Centre and, to a lesser degree, the Suangeur Shopping Centre have a range of modern shops including pharmacies stocked with international brands, clothes shops, souvenirs, furniture and toy shops amongst others. These are the main shopping zones for everyday necessities, although prices are significantly higher than in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">United States</a> and Europe for many international products.</p><p>All dive centres sell a wide range of diving equipment and accessories of major brands.</p><p>Be aware that many endangered or protected shark or marine life products are illegal in Palau so in the highly unlikely event that you are offered these be sure not to purchase them. If in doubt ask at the tourist information office. One bottle of liquor and one pack of cigarettes can be brought into Palau duty-free.</p><p>Generally Mon-Sat 0800-2100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For such a remote place Palau has a surprisingly wide variety of accommodation on Koror and the outlying islands, ranging from first-class five-star luxury resorts with all the facilities and mod-cons, to mid-priced bungalows and motels. There are plenty of beachfront properties – big spenders might like to try the Palau Pacific Resort whilst lovers of more boutique properties should head to the further flung islands. Bear in mind that Palau room rates are relatively expensive, even for rather bog standard accommodation. While Koror has the most options, visitors will find quieter and more secluded accommodation available on the southern islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Palau doesn't have B&Bs as such, but you can find guesthouses which tend to offer better value for money than hotels. Palau isn't a budget destination so you won't find rock bottom prices, but if you're on trying to make your money go further, staying at a B&B is a perfectly reasonable option. Most can be found on Koror.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For such a remote place Palau has a surprisingly wide variety of accommodation on Koror and the outlying islands, ranging from first-class five-star luxury resorts with all the facilities and mod-cons, to mid-priced bungalows and motels. There are plenty of beachfront properties – big spenders might like to try the Palau Pacific Resort whilst lovers of more boutique properties should head to the further flung islands. Bear in mind that Palau room rates are relatively expensive, even for rather bog standard accommodation. While Koror has the most options, visitors will find quieter and more secluded accommodation available on the southern islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For such a remote place Palau has a surprisingly wide variety of accommodation on Koror and the outlying islands, ranging from first-class five-star luxury resorts with all the facilities and mod-cons, to mid-priced bungalows and motels. There are plenty of beachfront properties – big spenders might like to try the Palau Pacific Resort whilst lovers of more boutique properties should head to the further flung islands. Bear in mind that Palau room rates are relatively expensive, even for rather bog standard accommodation. While Koror has the most options, visitors will find quieter and more secluded accommodation available on the southern islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Youth Day :
							15 March </p><p>Senior Citizens' Day :
							06 May </p><p>Memorial Day :
							27 May </p><p>Constitution Day :
							09 June </p><p>Labour Day :
							03 September </p><p>Independence Day :
							01 October </p><p>United Nations Day :
							24 October </p><p>Thanksgiving Day :
							29 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Banned imports include narcotics and firearms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shells and natural artefacts are banned.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Palau by travellers aged 18 years and older without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 1 pack of cigarettes (20 cigarettes).<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of alcohol.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Palau, a passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Entry permit: free.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Entry permit: 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are issued upon arrival at the airport.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your stay, contact the Bureau of Immigration (<a href="mailto:imm@palaunet.com" target="_blank">imm@palaunet.com</a>). You can extend your stay twice by 30 days up to a maximum stay of 90 days. The cost is US$50 per extension and you are advised to apply at least seven days before your current permitted stay expires.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[7.317006]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[134.402976]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>459 sq km (177 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>21,501 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>46.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Melekeok.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic in free association with the USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The stunning islands of Palau lie 1,000km (600 miles) east of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/philippines">Philippines</a> in the middle of the Pacific Ocean. Strung out like emeralds in a necklace, the archipelago stretches over 650km (400 miles) from the atoll of Kayangel in the north to the islet of Tobi in the south.  The eight main islands which are inhabited make up the bulk of Palau, but the archipelago includes more than 200 islands, and it is part of the larger Caroline Islands chain which also include the Federated States of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pacific-islands-micronesia/federated-states-micronesia">Micronesia</a>.</p>
<p>With three exceptions, all of the islands are located within a single barrier reef and represent two geological formations. The largest are volcanic and rugged with interior jungle and large areas of grassed terraces. The Rock Islands, now known as the Floating Garden Islands, are of limestone formation, while Kayangel, at the northernmost tip, is a classic coral atoll.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic majority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to everyday interactions, most Palauans expect some form of salutation, and it's considered rude not to say 'hello' or 'good morning' when encountering someone. If visiting someone's home, a small gift for the host will be highly appreciated. When it comes to eating, it's considered polite to try everything you're offered and eating more will be taken as a sign of enjoyment. The practice of chewing and spitting out the red juice of the betelnut is commonplace amongst locals.</p><p>Traditional Palauan society follows a complex matrilineal system that is still at play when it comes to rites of passage such as death, birth and marriages. The people are now amongst the most enterprising in the region, though a version of traditional beliefs – Modekngei – exists alongside the imported Christian beliefs. The political system is modelled on that of the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, and Western culture is being assimilated - not least because of the many Palauans who continue their education abroad. However the traditional government still wields a lot of influence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110-120 volts AC, 60Hz. American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without grounding pin)&nbsp;are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Tommy Remengesau since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Tommy Remengesau since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The earliest settlers arrived on the islands around 1000 BC as descendants of the Malays of Indonesia, Melanesians of New Guinea and Polynesians. The region was first visited by Europeans in the 16th century and was made part of the Spanish East Indies in 1574, although it was more than a century before the first map of Palau was drawn.</p>
<p>Following defeat in the 1898 Spanish-American war, Spain sold the islands to Germany, which exploited their natural resources until Palau was seized by Japan in 1914. The United States then took the islands in 1944 after the ferocious WWII Battle of Peleliu, which resulted in the deaths of more than 2,000 American and 10,000 Japanese soldiers. After liberation from Japanese occupation, Palau became part of the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, administered by the USA under a mandate from the UN in 1947.</p>
<p>In 1986, the governments of Palau and the USA agreed the terms of a Compact of Free Association, which allowed for virtual independence under a US defence umbrella. The Palau Compact, however, remained unsigned, because of a crucial clause forbidding the presence of any nuclear weapons on the islands, including visits by ships equipped to carry them. The USA refused to sign the Compact until the clause was rescinded and the dispute introduced a violent aspect into Palau's politics &ndash; President Haruo Remeliik was assassinated in 1985 and his successor, Lazarus Salii, committed suicide in August 1988.</p>
<p>At the presidential election of 1992, Kuniwo Nakamura won a narrow victory. The island was faced with a choice of accepting the Compact or seeking full independence &ndash; a hazardous proposition for economic reasons. In October 1994, the Compact was endorsed and Palau was admitted to the UN in December 1994. Nakamura served a second term between 1996 and 2000 after which he was replaced by president, Tommy Remengesau, who took office for a second four-year term in 2013.</p>
<p>Although wealthier than many of its near neighbours, Palau wrestles with the typical problems of all Pacific islands &ndash; isolation, a lack of infrastructure and rising sea levels caused by climate change.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The 1968 film, <em>Hell in the Pacific</em>, starring Lee Marvin was shot in Palau.<br />
&bull;	Palau has a national football team, but is not part of FIFA.<br />
&bull;	In 2012 Palau received the Future Policy Award from the World Future Council for its protection of marine ecosystems.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Palau in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 452 6814.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.palauembassy.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 452 6814.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An untamed paradise for divers and snorkellers, Paula is an archipelago of more than 500 islands, which sprout like giant mushrooms from the crystalline waters of the Pacific Ocean.</p>
<p>The island of Koror is the beating heart of the country and the entry point for most visitors. Home to most of Palau&rsquo;s inhabitants, it is far from the prettiest island in the archipelago and few choose to linger here. Those who do, however, can grab a slice of Micronesian life in the local bars and restaurants, where charismatic natives take pleasure convincing foreigners to try the local delicacy: fruit bat soup.</p>
<p>Palau is also home to some of the world&rsquo;s healthiest and most impressive UNESCO-listed reefs. Iridescent corals swirl around the islands, their marine populations teeming with a bounty few other places can match. Indeed, not a list exists that doesn&rsquo;t rank Palau&rsquo;s Blue Corner amongst the planet&rsquo;s top dive sites.</p>
<p>It isn&rsquo;t just in the tropical seas where strange creatures thrive, for Palau is also home to one of the most ecologically sensitive and unique evolutionary phenomena: Jellyfish Lake. Cut off from the sea millions of years ago, the lake&rsquo;s predator-free inhabitants have evolved to lose their poisonous sting. To snorkel slowly amongst these gentle creatures is to float through an alien world.</p>
<p>While it&rsquo;s easy to see Palau's beauty, a closer look will reveal scars from ferocious battles that took place on these shores during WWII. Ship and plane wrecks remain buried in dark lagoons, while long-forgotten bunkers and rusted machine guns are peppered across the islands. This is testament to Palau&rsquo;s tumultuous modern history, which saw it swap hands from Germany to Japan and, finally, the Untied States, before achieving independence in 1994.</p>
<p>While Palau may be remote and untamed, it is precisely these attributes that make it one of the world&rsquo;s last unspoiled natural beauties. The archipelago endures as a marvel of Mother Nature, stands proud as a centre for Micronesian culture and offers a haunting memorial to battles once fought in its turquoise waters.</p><p>An untamed paradise for divers and snorkellers, Paula is an archipelago of more than 500 islands, which sprout like giant mushrooms from the crystalline waters of the Pacific Ocean.&nbsp;The island of Koror is the beating heart of the country and the entry point for most visitors. Home to most of Palau&rsquo;s inhabitants, it is far from the prettiest island in the archipelago and few choose to linger here. Those who do, however, can grab a slice of Micronesian life in the local bars and restaurants, where charismatic natives take pleasure convincing foreigners to try the local delicacy: fruit bat soup.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
