<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Palestinian National Authority" ColCode="pal" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="PS" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Palestinian National Authority]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Palestine has a temperate, Mediterranean climate. The rainy season in Palestine is between November and April. Winter can get rather cold and wet. Southern areas can get uncomfortably hot during the summer months. Spring and autumn are the best times to visit, with temperatures of around 23°C (74°F).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The desert can get cold at night, even during the summer months, so it is advisable to carry extra layers to wear. Otherwise, lightweight clothes are advisable in summer. Warmer clothes are required for the winter months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travel within the West Bank is not possible without passing through multiple Israeli military checkpoints, which are flash points for violent incidents and have been the scene of several fatal attacks.</p>r<p>Shared taxis, often referred to as service or transit taxis, are cheaper and quicker than the local buses and go to many destinations. Normal taxis are rarely metered so it's wise to agree a price beforehand.</p><p>Full driving licence and insurance are required. An International Driving Permit is recommended.</p><p>Palestinian vehicles (white and green number plates) are not permitted to enter Jerusalem and Israel without a special permit. Israeli vehicles (yellow number plate) can enter the West Bank but not the Gaza Strip.</p><p>Most major car hire companies are located in Jerusalem. Local car hire agencies are available in major cities throughout Palestine. Fees are not cheap. Insurance is essential. A vehicle with a yellow number plate is recommended to those planning to drive to Jerusalem and Israel.</p><p>Palestinian vehicles (white and green number plates) are not permitted to enter Jerusalem and Israel without a special permit. Israeli vehicles (yellow number plate) can enter the West Bank but not the Gaza Strip.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EGGED (tel: +972 3 694 8888: <a href="http://www.egged.co.il/" target="_blank">www.egged.co.il</a>) runs route 99, which takes in all the main tourist sites in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Buses are the cheapest way to travel around urban areas, but private<strong> </strong>taxis are quicker and more reliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline, Palestinian Airlines (<a href="http://www.palairlines.com" target="_blank">www.palairlines.com</a>), operates out of El Arish International Airport, Egypt.</p>
<p>Yasser Arafat International Airport has not been in use since shortly after the 2001 uprising when <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/israel">Israel</a> bombed the radar station and tore up the runway; it currently lies in ruins. Visitors should fly to Ben Gurion International Airport, 50km (31 miles) west of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jerusalem">Jerusalem</a> in Israel, and travel overland from there.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Yasser Arafat International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.gazaairport.com]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A number of border crossings, manned by the Israeli Defence Force (IDF), are used to enter the West Bank: from Israel, the main entry point north of Jerusalem is Qalandia, to the south is Gilo, the nearest entry point to Bethlehem; from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jordan">Jordan</a> the main crossing is Allenby Bridge. The Erez border crossing between Israel and the Gaza Strip is tightly controlled by the IDF and is closed intermittently.</p>
<p>The Rafah border crossing between the Gaza Strip and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/egypt">Egypt</a> is run by the Palestinian Authority. It is closed for most of the time and currently only holders of Palestinian ID cards or Egyptian passports are allowed through when it is open, although it may be possible to obtain permission to cross in advance.</p>
<p>Passengers coming from Israel or Jerusalem are advised to find an Arab driver with a yellow number plate car or move to a Palestinian car at check points separating Israel and Jerusalem from the Palestinian territories.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage is good, including the Gaza Strip, with a few patchy areas along the northern border with Jordan and to the west of the Dead Sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Access is relatively easy although the high cost of telecommunications is a limiting factor. Over 240,000 Palestinians had Internet access in 2006 making Palestine one of the largest Internet users in the Arab world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Palestinian media is widely regarded as more liberal than much of the Arab world, but self-censorship is common due to the risk of harassment and threats from activists. The media rights group Reporters without Borders believe that violence (including murder) towards journalists markedly increased in 2005. <br /><br />The Palestinian president has jurisdiction over the Palestinian Broadcasting Corporation, the country's official broadcaster. This was imposed in 2006, most likely as a measure to prevent the strongly-Hamas government from having too much control over the media.<br /><br />The largest daily is privately-run newspaper is the Jerusalem-based Al-Quds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cheap and reliable postal services are available in Palestine but heavy packages may only be posted in Jerusalem with Israeli stamps. Post takes around one week to reach Europe and 10 days to the USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Explore the ancient city of Jericho</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With a history dating back more than 10,000 years, Jericho is quite the showstopper. Thought to be the oldest continuously inhabited city in the world, it features remnants of prehistoric settlements and many of Palestine's most important historical sites. It also stands an incredible 450m (820ft) below sea level</p>]]><p><b>Follow the old Wadi Qilt route</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hike the ancient route along the Wadi Qilt, a canyon-like valley, taking in caves, geysers, an aqueduct and St George's Monastery as you go. It is about a full day's walk from Ein Fawwar to Jericho, with the monastery in the middle.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about culture at the Arab Women's Union</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One little-known treat in Bethlehem is the Arab Women's Union. Its ethnographic museum near the Church of the Nativity features traditional pottery, embroidery and handicrafts, as well as an exhibition of the refined possessions enjoyed by Palestinian families in the British Mandate era, which stand in stark contrast to the lives of Palestinians today.</p>]]><p><b>Make a pilgrimage to the biblical town of Bethlehem</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Bethlehem, wonder at the Milk Grotto where the holy family took refuge during their flight to Egypt; a drop of Mary's milk fell to the ground, apparently turning the grotto white. Other sites include King David's Well, Herodion, Church of the Nativity, Beit Sahour and, more recently, the Israeli Separation Barrier with its incredible graffiti, including works by Banksy.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Jerusalem's Old City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get lost in Jerusalem's Old City, which dates back to the 16th century. Its labyrinthine four quarters (Arab, Jewish, Christian and Armenian) are enclosed within limestone walls. The long list of places of historical and religious significance includes the Western Wall, Church of All Nations and King David's Tomb.</p>]]><p><b>Party in buzzy Ramallah</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Not far from Jerusalem, Ramallah is also known for its buzzing nightlife and the best restaurants in Palestine. Smoke a water pipe, often referred to as an <em>argila</em>, in one of the many coffee houses or restaurants, or visit one of the many nightclubs or music venues.</p>]]><p><b>Relax in the Dead Sea</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Float like a cork in the Dead Sea, the lowest place on Earth. Its waters are four times saltier than normal seawater meaning you can't sink – so lay back, relax, and even read a paper, if you like. Home of the fabled Dead Sea scrolls and tantalising ancient history, the Dead Sea is today a well-developed tourist hub.</p>]]><p><b>Venture into the Gaza Strip</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It's rarely possible or advisable these days, but if the political climate allows, venture into the Gaza Strip to explore the numerous important historical sites such as the Omari Mosque, Napoleon's Fort, Sayyed Hashem Mosque and the Byzantine ruins in the north.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Mount of Temptation</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a walk or ride a cable car up to Jericho's Monastery of Temptation on the peak where Christ is believed to have spent 40 days and nights fasting and meditating, not to mention tempted by the Devil. Apart from the biblical significance, there are terrific views across the Jordan Valley.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Sanctuary of Abraham</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pay your respects to the Sanctuary of Abraham (Al-Haram Al-Ibrahimi) or "Tomb of the Patriarchs". It is revered by Muslims, Christians and Jews as the site of the tombs of Abraham, Isaac, Jacob and their wives and the place of David's anointment.</p>]]><p><b>Wander the ancient town of Qumran</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore Qumran where the Dead Sea Scrolls, including the scroll of Isaiah, were discovered in more than 30 caves set in desert cliffs in 1947. In the Qumran national park you'll find ruins of the town destroyed by the Romans almost 2,000 years ago. The scrolls themselves are stored in the Israel Museum in Jerusalem.</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at the ancient Pools of Solomon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Picnic in the beautiful grounds surrounding Solomon's Pools, three ancient reservoirs located about 4km (2.5 miles) south of Bethlehem. Thought to date back more than 2,000 years, these remarkable pools are named after the biblical King Solomon, who is believed to have built the First Temple in Jerusalem.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$6.6 billion (2008).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Citrus, textiles, construction materials and metal goods.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Israel and Jordan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Economic activity is severely restricted by a number of factors, not least Israeli-imposed restrictions. Economic growth in 2005 was estimated at 8.7%. Around half of Palestinians live in poverty, one in four is unemployed and nearly 50% do not have reliable access to food (2006). Since then, the imposition of sanctions by Israel and its allies in the West (following the newly-elected Hamas government's refusal to recognise Israel and renounce violence) has meant that the economy has come to a virtual standstill.<br /><br />Substantial gas reserves have been found off the Gaza Strip which will likely prove to be an extremely important part of the economy and Palestine's most valuable natural resource.<br />There are no dedicated conference and convention centres within Palestine, but Jerusalem has a number of facilities available.<br /><br /><strong>Jerusalem International Convention Centre (JICC) <br /></strong>Binyaney Ha'ooma, PO Box 6001, Jerusalem 91060, Israel <br />Tel: (2) 655 8558.<br />Website: <a href="http://www.iccjer.co.il/" target="_blank">www.iccjer.co.il</a></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most businesses are small, family-run affairs producing construction materials and textiles. Business communications can be frustrating as in many instances it is difficult to get a direct response to a question. Appointments and business cards are common practice.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The Palestinians boast a surprising amount of variety in their cuisine, given their country&rsquo;s small size. In the Galilee area, a closeness with Lebanese cuisine predominates, with stodgy meat dishes and plenty of the bulgur cereal.</p>
<p>In the West Bank, there are lots of meat, rice and vegetable dishes involving taboon, a regional flatbread cooked in a special tubular oven. In Gaza, there's a taste for fresh seafood fished out of the Mediterranean, as well as an abundance of chillies and spices.</p>
<p>Throughout the territories, skewered meat, shish kebab, hummus and baba ghanoush are popular. You'll also find subtle influences from the immigrants who have settled over the centuries, with French, Italian and Balkan touches appearing in restaurants. Typical Palestinian main courses are meat heavy and generously sized.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Musahkan</strong>: Casserole made with chicken, bread, spices and vegetables.<br />
<strong>Knafeh and baklaweh</strong>: Succulent, sweet pastries.<br />
<strong>Mansat</strong>: Lamp chops and rice with a warm yoghurt sauce topped with browned almonds.<br />
<strong>Mtabel</strong>: Mashed aubergine, tahini, onion and lemon juice.<br />
<strong>Mansaf</strong>: Traditional regional dish involving leg of lamb atop taboon, covered with yellow rice and with a goat's milk sauce poured on top.<br />
<strong>Sumaghiyyeh</strong>: Ground sumac mixed with tahini, plus stewed beef and chickpeas.<br />
<strong>Maqluba</strong>: Rice, meat and vegetables cooked in a pot and then served 'upside down' (the definition of <em>maqluba</em>).<br />
<strong>Kubbineyee</strong>: Raw meat mixed with bulgur and spices, usually eaten with pita bread.<br />
<strong>Hummus</strong>: ground chickpeas.<br />
<strong>Taybeh</strong>: The only beer brewed in Palestine.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>The typical tipping amount in a restaurant is 10%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite the troubles, the club scene in both Ramallah and Jerusalem is thriving. The nightclubs, with internationally renowned DJs and a global clientele, rival those of Europe. Ramallah is full of lively restaurants serving up international and traditional Palestinian cuisine. Unfortunately, due to the prevailing political climate, curfews are sporadically imposed which inevitably affect nightlife.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Colourful markets and meandering old streets make shopping a particularly agreeable pastime. Haggling is acceptable and especially enjoyable in the vibrant marketplaces. Special purchases include pottery decorated with geometric patterns, stained wine and champagne glasses, jewellery and oriental sweets. Cross-stitch embroidery is an ancient art and beautifully decorated clothes, cushions and cloths are very popular souvenirs. Religious ornaments crafted from local olive trees are also good buys.</p><p>0800-1900 in winter, 0800-1700 in summer. Muslim-owned shops usually close on Fridays, Christian on Sundays.  The official weekend is Friday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1-5 star range of accommodation available. Most of the best hotels are found in UN-administered Jerusalem but Bethlehem, Ramallah, Jericho, Nablus, Hebron and Gaza all have their share of places to stay and cater for all budgets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of guest houses and hostels available, catering for tourists, pilgrims, groups and backpackers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1-5 star range of accommodation available. Most of the best hotels are found in UN-administered Jerusalem but Bethlehem, Ramallah, Jericho, Nablus, Hebron and Gaza all have their share of places to stay and cater for all budgets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1-5 star range of accommodation available. Most of the best hotels are found in UN-administered Jerusalem but Bethlehem, Ramallah, Jericho, Nablus, Hebron and Gaza all have their share of places to stay and cater for all budgets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							15 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/israel">Israel</a> and the Palestinian National Authority without incurring customs duty (alcohol and tobacco can only be imported by persons aged 17 years and over):</p>
<p>&bull; 250g of tobacco products.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits and 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 3kg of food (each item may not weigh more than 1kg).<br />
&bull; Gifts and other goods to the value of US$200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted items include firearms, plants, raw meat, raw material, counterfeit currency or documents, and knives not intended for professional use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no national currency. The most commonly used is the New Israeli shekel but Jordanian Dinars and US Dollars are also accepted.<br /><br />New Shekel (ILS) = 100 agorot (singular, agora). Notes are in denominations of ILS200, 100, 50, and 20. Coins are in denominations of ILS100, 50, 10, 5 and 1, and 50 and 10 agorot.<br /><br />Dinar (JOD; symbol JD) = 100 piastres or 1,000 fils. Notes are in denominations of JD50, 20, 10, 5 and 1, and 500 fils. Coins are in denominations of JD1, 1/2 and 1/4; 10, 5, 2 and 1/2 piastres; and 1 and 1/2 qirsh.<br /><br />US Dollar (US$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of US$100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of US$1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency is easily exchanged at any bank or money exchange shops. The exchange shops are located throughout Palestine and generally have more convenient opening hours and better exchange rates than banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards are accepted by most hotels, restaurants and large companies in the main cities. Beyond <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/jerusalem">Jerusalem</a> and Bethlehem, it is advisable to carry sufficient cash. Personal cheques are generally not accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are widely accepted. The easiest, most economical currency to exchange is the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sat-Thurs 0800-1230; Sat-Wed 1500-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for a minimum of six months from the date of entry is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[31.324235]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[34.862366]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6,335 sq km (2,446 sq miles) made up of the West Bank territories, 5,970 sq km (2,305 sq miles) and the Gaza Strip, 365 sq km (141 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4.7 million (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>734.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ramallah. (Intended seat of government: East Jerusalem.)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parliamentary Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The two territories of Palestine lie within Israel, around 40km (25 miles) apart at their closest point. The West Bank is to the west of the River Jordan, bordered by Jordan to the east and Israel to the north, south and west. The Gaza Strip, in Israel's southwest, is a narrow stretch of land bordered by the Mediterranean to the west and Egypt to the south. The Great Rift Valley follows the path of the River Jordan running along the West Bank and through the lowest point in the world, the Dead Sea at 390m (1,280ft) below sea level, before continuing on into Eastern Africa. The Jordanian Valley is green and fertile; the south contains the Judean Desert.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Muslim, Christian and Judaism minority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Women in particular should dress modestly. Ramallah is less strict than other areas but bare shoulders, shorts and short skirts are still inadvisable. Visitors may choose not to eat, drink or smoke in public places between sunrise and sunset during Ramadan in order to avoid causing offence.<br /><br />Visitors should also be sensitive when taking pictures of military or police personnel and installations, and when photographing people in Muslim and Orthodox Jewish areas. It is advisable to carry identification at all times, and photocopies of the date and entry stamp on your passport.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Israeli-style plugs (one round pin beneath two round pins) are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Rami Hamdallah since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Mahmoud Abbas since 2005.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some of the earliest human remains have been found in Palestine where some agricultural settlements date back to at least 10,000 BC. During the Bronze Age, the area was dominated by Canaanite city states, before the Philistines invaded &ndash; possible from Crete, or elsewhere in the Aegean &ndash; in the 2nd millennium BC.</p>
<p>History thereafter is rather muddled in the context of biblical texts and religious belief, but the Philistines are thought to have come into conflict with Israelite tribes in the area around the turn of the 1st millennium BC. In the 8th and 7th centuries BC, the Asyrrians overran Palestine, followed later by the Persians and the armies of Alexander the Great.</p>
<p>The Romans finally established the province of Judea during the 1st century BC. Struggles with the Romans led to the destruction of the Second Temple in the 1st century AD, leaving only the Western Wall standing. Less than a century later, Hadrian renamed the territory Syria Palaestina and banished the Jews.</p>
<p>The Byzantine period up until the 7th century AD saw Palestine become a Christian province, with significant Jewish communities. The land prospered, but with the rise of the Caliphate, Jerusalem was besieged and Palestine became war-torn for centuries. Crusaders from Europe sought to retake the so-called Holy Land from Muslim rulers, succeeding in establishing a Christian kingdom between 1099 and the late 12th century.</p>
<p>In the 15th century, the Ottoman Empire absorbed the territory and largely promoted religious tolerance, controlling Palestine until the British Mandate began after World War I. A couple of years after World War II, the UN proposed a partition of Palestine between its Jewish and Arab-Palestinian populations and some three million Jews, many of whom had been persecuted by the Nazis, moved to the newly-formed state of Israel. A war between Israel and neighbouring Arab states ensued.</p>
<p>Further wars in 1967 and 1973 led to the consolidation of Israel and the enduring occupation of Palestinian territories. There have been two Intifadas, whereby the Arab-Palestinian population has risen up against the Israeli state, with bloody consequences. To date, the Israeli-Palestinian conflict remains unresolved and a source of much controversy throughout the Middle East.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Two of the world&rsquo;s biggest religions, Judaism and Christianity, were born on Palestinian soil.<br />
&bull; The Palestinian region is thought to be amongst the earliest places to have seen human habitation and civilisation.<br />
&bull; Built in the late 7th century, the Dome of the Rock in Jerusalem is regarded by many as the first great work of Islamic architecture.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With fertile river plains and scrubby desert, Mediterranean olive groves and many historical marvels, Palestine has plenty to offer. Sadly, war and outbreaks of violence have badly damaged the appeal of this hotly contested land. But despite the widely held perception, Palestine is not a tourist-free zone, with more than two million travellers arriving each year.</p>
<p>The bulk of tourists head for Bethlehem, largely through organised tours from Jerusalem. The main attraction is the Church of the Nativity, thought to mark the spot where Jesus Christ was born. There&rsquo;s also the winding Star Street, believed to be the path Mary and Joseph took on entering the city.</p>
<p>Far from just a pilgrimage site, Bethlehem is fascinating for what remains of the ancient biblical town, as well as its little medina-style streets and bustling market. Foreign investment is trickling through the city, which isn&rsquo;t as down-at-heel as many expect, with a few museums now open and lots of shops.</p>
<p>Adventurous tourists head for the Separation Barrier, just outside Bethlehem; apart from dividing Israeli and Palestinian territories, the wall is covered in spectacular graffiti by local and international artists including Banksy.</p>
<p>At present, the majority of tourists stick to Bethlehem. But Hebron in the southern West Bank is the largest city in the territory and essential viewing, not least for its fabled souks. The ancient city of Jericho is also attractive for its garden restaurants and stunning Hisham Palace, while Ramallah, the de facto capital of the Palestinian Authority, is interesting for its lively energy and ubiquitous caf&eacute;s.</p>
<p>Travel to Gaza, a densely populated slither of coastal land bordering Egypt and separated from the rest of Palestine by Israel, is nearly impossible &ndash; especially after the devastating 2014 conflict. But the West Bank remains surprisingly accessible, and while travel advice should be heeded, it is relatively safe.</p><p>With fertile river plains and scrubby desert, Mediterranean olive groves and many historical marvels, Palestine has plenty to offer. Sadly, war and outbreaks of violence have badly damaged the appeal of this hotly contested land. But despite the widely held perception, Palestine is not a tourist-free zone, with more than two million travellers arriving each year.</p>
<p>The bulk of tourists head for Bethlehem, largely through organised tours from Jerusalem. The main attraction is the Church of the Nativity, thought to mark the spot where Jesus Christ was born. There&rsquo;s also the winding Star Street, believed to be the path Mary and Joseph took on entering the city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
