<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Panama" ColCode="pan" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="pa" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Panama]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Temperatures are high across the whole country throughout the year, though cooler at high altitudes. The rainy season lasts from May to November, but even at this time of year rain rarely lasts all day &ndash; just take an umbrella for the downpours; the sun will be out again soon.  There are fewer people around at this time, too, and so prices drop for the low season. Rainfall is twice as heavy on the Pacific coast as it is on the lowlands of the Caribbean coast.</p>
<p>If you are planning to take a boat trip from Panama to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/colombia">Colombia</a>, avoid travelling from December to February, as at this time of year the seas are rough, trips get cancelled and everyone gets seasick.</p>
<p>Surfing is possible and decent all year round on the Pacific side, but the best months are from November to April.  For hiking, the dry season (December to April) is most comfortable.  The dry season is also good for diving, because you&rsquo;ll be able to see far better, but the rainy season means the rivers run high which is great for rafting.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are worn, with rainwear advisable, particularly in the rainy season.  However, keep it light: just because it rains doesn&rsquo;t mean it gets cold. Warmer clothes are needed in the highlands, especially in the dry season.  If hiking and camping at a higher altitude, things can get very chilly indeed &ndash; make sure your sleeping bag can handle it.  Hiking boots are great for the mountains, but most of the time you&rsquo;ll be in flip-flops.  Forget your mosquito repellent at your peril, and a mosquito net might come in handy too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Copa Airlines (<a href="http://www.copaair.com" target="_blank">www.copaair.com</a>) and Air Panama (<a href="http://www.airpanama.com" target="_blank">www.airpanama.com</a>) operate flights within Panama.  Smaller airports for internal flights are Marcos A Gelabert International Airport in Albrook and Enrique Malek in David, Chiriqu&iacute;.</p>
<p>Panama is widely accessible by bus, and the roads are often good.  However, Panama has several islands that are only accessed by flight or very long boat trips, and for some areas, such as Yaviza for hiking in the Dari&eacute;n, it might be more expedient for those on a tight schedule to fly rather than braving long bus journeys.</p><p>Internal flights can be influenced by the weather &ndash; confirm all flights before making your way to the airports.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Panam&aacute; Canal Railway Company (PCRC) (tel: +507 317 6070; <a href="http://www.panarail.com" target="_blank">www.panarail.com</a>) runs a scenic 76km (47-mile) passenger route from Panama City to Col&oacute;n.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a reasonably good road system throughout Panama, but foreigners driving through the country should be extremely careful of other drivers, as the standard here seems to include a degree of recklessness.  Assertiveness on the roads is a must, and get ready to use your horn.</p>r<p>Road quality isn&rsquo;t at all bad for much of Panama, as the major route is the Panamerican Highway which runs the length of this fairly thin country. Hire a 4-wheel drive vehicle for more rural areas.</p><p>Bus travel around Panama is good and the usual way to travel. There are paved roads between major destinations such as David, Boquete, Col&oacute;n and Panama City.  The Panamerican Highway is used for most major routes, and you can flag down coaches along the way, or buy tickets in city terminals.  There are many bus companies, all leaving from Panama City&rsquo;s Albrook bus terminal, of varying standards and prices &ndash; scout around and find the one that suits you. To check bus times and journey lengths, use <a href="http://www.thebusschedule.com/pa" target="_blank">www.thebusschedule.com/pa</a>.</p><p>The taxis of Panama City are metered, but make sure the driver puts it on.  Elsewhere, they are not metered, and fares should be agreed in advance. Drivers do not expect tips, but they may pick other passengers up on the way.  This is normal, but if you&rsquo;re uncomfortable with it, you should say so.</p><p>A national driving licence is usually sufficient, but an International Driving Licence is safer if you are stopped.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn by drivers and front seat passengers at all times. Children under five years must travel in the back in a fitted child seat. Motor insurance, even third party, is not a legal requirement in Panama; therefore, many Panamanians drive without it. If you are involved in an accident, the law stipulates that you should wait with your vehicle until the traffic police (<em>transito</em>) arrive.</p>
<p>Speed limits are 40kph (25mph) within cities and 100kph (62mph) on highways.</p><p>There are no breakdown services available in Panama. If anything does go wrong with your vehicle, contact your car hire service immediately for help.</p><p>Available in city centres and airport; you must be at least 21 years old to hire a car, although some companies set a minimum age of either 23 or 25. You can hire a 4-wheel drive vehicle, but plan ahead as they are popular.&nbsp;There are plenty of car hire places in Panama City and nearby Tocumen airport.</p><p>You can hire bikes in cities, notably Panama City, David and Boquete.  However, cycling around cities can be extremely perilous due to drivers seemingly regarding cyclists as fun targets.  Cyclists should ensure they are very visible, constantly alert and have plucked up all their courage.  Hostels in smaller villages sometimes rent out bikes, in which case the roads are safer.</p>
<p>Cycling around the country will require your own bicycle, which you can buy in cities.  Most main roads in Panama are surfaced well enough.  The things to be aware of are afternoon downpours in the rainy season (best to cycle early in the morning); hills in the midday heat; and, again, your safety with the traffic.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn by drivers and front seat passengers at all times. Children under five years must travel in the back in a fitted child seat. Motor insurance, even third party, is not a legal requirement in Panama; therefore, many Panamanians drive without it. If you are involved in an accident, the law stipulates that you should wait with your vehicle until the traffic police (<em>transito</em>) arrive.</p>
<p>Speed limits are 40kph (25mph) within cities and 100kph (62mph) on highways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An efficient metro, plus extensive bus and minibus services run in Panama City. The bus system can be extremely confusing for travellers, but the prices and destinations are listed in the windscreen if you feel like giving it a shot, and locals will always help if you ask for it.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Panama</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">santiago</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Panama</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">chitre</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Panama</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">chiriquiacute</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Panama's national airline is Copa Airlines (<a href="http://www.copaair.com" target="_blank">www.copaair.com</a>). From the UK, you can fly to Panama with British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) via Madrid, KLM (<a href="http://www.klm.com" target="_blank">www.klm.com</a>) via Amsterdam and American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>) via Miami. Airlines operating direct flights from the USA include American Airlines, Copa Airlines and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>).</p>
<p>Fares tend to rise in the summer months from June to August and during the peak season from ﻿December to March.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/panama/tocumen-panama-international-airport">Tocumen Panama International Airport </a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 14 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 5 hours 10 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$50, usually included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Tocumen Panama International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.tocumenpanama.aero<p>Tocumen Panama International Airport is situated approximately 17km (11 miles) east of Panama City.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+507 238 2700</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Panama&rsquo;s main port is the port of Balboa, a port of call for both passenger and freight vessels. The Panama Canal is the major route from the Atlantic to the Pacific Ocean.  It's common to get a boat into Panama from Cartagena in Colombia via the San Blas islands as one of the travel options between Colombia and Panama.  Boats usually leave from Portobelo in Col&oacute;n province.</p><p>These boats are usually private and arrange to fill berths via hostels and hotel, and so should be booked in advance.  While these boats depart frequently, they are dependent on weather conditions and can be delayed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no international rail links from Panama.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travel by road from Costa Rica into Panama is straightforward, with decent roads and reasonable borders.Overland travellers must make sure to get the requisite entry and exit visa stamps; failure to do so could cause difficulties when eventually leaving Panama.  Paso Canoas, accessed via the Panamerican Highway, is the most popular border to cross but gets exceptionally busy.  Guabito-Sixaola on the Caribbean coast is fairly informal and makes a good route towards Bocas del Toro.</p>
<p>The other option is the Rio Sereno crossing.  It is a quiet crossing and usually laid-back, but is hard to access by public transport; be careful if you&rsquo;re bringing a car or motorbike in to have all your documents properly filled out and ready to be stamped &ndash; they can be strict.  This is a good crossing for those en route to Boquete. Travelling by coach is an excellent option - the Ticabus (<a href="http://www.ticabus.com" target="_blank">www.ticabus.com</a>) runs from Costa Rica into Panama for very affordable prices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Calling home is easiest either via Skype in an internet cafe (plenty have it on their computers and headsets) or using International Phone Cards.  Hotel phone rates are typically expensive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good.  If you will be making a lot of calls within the country then it might be worth buying a local SIM card for your mobile phone.  Make sure your phone is unlocked.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes exist in main urban areas.  Many hotels are Wi-Fi enabled and you can occasionally piggyback on open networks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Freedom of the press is guaranteed in Panama, but that wasn&rsquo;t always the case: under the regimes between 1968 and 1989, the media was very strictly controlled.  The main English-language newspaper, issued twice monthly, is <em>Panama News</em>, and other daily Spanish-language papers include <em>Cr&iacute;tica Libre, La Estrella de Panam&aacute;, El Panam&aacute; Am&eacute;rica, La Prensa</em> and <em>El Siglo</em>.  The main commercial TV networks are Telemetro, RPC and Televisora Nacional (TVN); FETV is a charitable network.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes five to 10 days.  Sending post by normal Panama mail can take 14 days to the US on a good run.  If you're in a hurry or really care about the contents of your package, and don't mind spending some money, there's always DHL.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600, Sat 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Browse old and new Panama City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spread out along a wide bay, Panama City is a curiously appealing blend of colonial Spain and cosmopolitan modernity, well worth a couple of days' exploration. The historic old town is a UNESCO World Heritage Site, its narrow cobblestone streets lined with elegantly faded colonial buildings, whereas the new areas of the city are full of gleaming skyscrapers housing multinational corporations.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Baru Volcano</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Straddling the border with Costa Rica, the dormant Baru Volcano is a superb setting for a day's hiking or horseback ride, with the added potential excitement of spotting a quetzal, one of Central America's most iconic birds. Reaching 3,475m (11,400ft), it is located in beautiful Chiriquí Province, near the popular resort town of Boquete and the mountain resort, Cerro Punta.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise the Panama Canal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A cruise along the Panama Canal is a once-in-a-lifetime experience. You can do a partial trip or go from Colon all the way to Panama City. The scenery en route is beautiful and the mechanics of the canal fascinating. Also recommended is the Panama Canal Museum in the capital's Casco Viejo, which details the canal's spectacular engineering and its human and environmental cost.</p>]]><p><b>Get a taste of luxury in the rainforest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you like your jungle experience to come with luxurious trappings, visit the Gamboa Tropical Rainforest Reserve. Less than an hour from Panama City between the Chagres River and the Panama Canal, the reserve is home to a wealth of tropical wildlife, but also has a five-star resort, and tree-top eco-lodge.</p>]]><p><b>Go diving and snorkelling</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Apart from its stunning Caribbean location, the Bocas del Toro archipelago is one of Panama's top diving and snorkelling locations. You'll be amazed by the variety of marine life on offer here, but other diving hotspots include the Isla Grande, near Portobelo, where dive centres run excursions to the best reefs, and the San Blás Islands, off the northeast coast.</p>]]><p><b>Hike around Barro Colorado</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a day trip from Panama City to the island of Barro Colorado in Gatun Lake, a vast manmade stretch of water created during construction of the Panama Canal. The island is a biological reserve and reputed to be one of the world's leading natural tropical laboratories; you can hike around the island in a few hours, spotting wildlife such as monkeys, anteaters and birds.</p>]]><p><b>Join the carnival in Las Tablas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Capital of the Los Santos province of Panama, Las Tablas plays host to several bustling fiestas throughout the year, including one of the country's best Carnival celebrations. The Las Tablas Carnival involves two factions, each with a parade and its own festivities, trying to outdo the other. You don't have to take sides, just join in with both groups.</p>]]><p><b>Roam the wilderness of Darién National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The sparsely populated wilderness of the Darién Gap is one of Central America's most inaccessible regions. Nevertheless, you can explore trails in the Darién National Park, which contains sandy beaches, rocky coasts, mangroves, swamps and tropical rainforest. The park is also home to two Choco Indian tribes, as well as one of the world's greatest concentrations of bird species.</p>]]><p><b>See Panama City’s historic highlights</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Panama City's Casco Viejo is its old quarter; highlights are the Plaza de Francia, the Paseo de las Bóvedas, San José Church, with its magnificent golden Baroque altar, and the Santo Domingo Church, next to which is the Museum of Colonial Religious Art. The most impressive building in Panama City, however, is the President's Palace, an opulent 17th-century mansion overlooking the bay.</p>]]><p><b>Swing through the tree canopy</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Embark on a tree canopy adventure in the El Níspero Botanical Gardens, in central Panama's Anton Valley. Hoick yourself into a harness, climb up to the treetops and then swing from one platform to another like Tarzan on a day-trip. Get up among the birds and enjoy the greenery from their perspective.</p>]]><p><b>Take the panga to Taboga</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Escape the noise and traffic of Panama City and hop on the ferry to the island of Taboga, with its fine beaches and clean sea air. The best way to get there is by local water taxi, known as a <em>panga</em>. A longer trip by launch is necessary to get to the Pearl Islands, which are visited mainly by sea-anglers and whale-watchers.</p>]]><p><b>Tour Panama Viejo, sacked by pirates</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take an excursion to the ruins of Panama Viejo, including the square tower of the old cathedral, in the capital's western suburbs. This is the original Panama City, sacked in 1671 by celebrated Welsh buccaneer Henry Morgan, who helped undermine Spanish control of their colonies. Clamber around the crumbling walls, which also contain a museum and an excellent handicrafts market.</p>]]><p><b>Try Panama’s big Atlantic surf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Along with Venado and Rio Mar in the Pacific and Isla Grande, Bluf and Careneros in the Atlantic, Santa Catalina is known as a prime surfer's spot in Panama. Waves can reach 4.5m (15ft), and you can find good surfing almost all year round. Panama is just beginning to be discovered as a surfer's paradise, so get down there before the crowds come.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Kuna of the San Blas Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Panama's most popular adventures is to the San Blas Islands, home of the Kuna, considered the most autonomous indigenous people of Latin America. The inhabitants live a traditional agriculture and fishing-based life, supported by tourism. The colourfully dressed women produce equally vivid <em>mola</em> embroideries for sale to visitors. You can stay here in rustic lodges, snorkel off the beach, and tour the local villages.</p>]]><p><b>Witness Chiriquí’s log-throwing contest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit this western coastal province to see some of the country's most spectacular scenery, with volcanic highlands, waterfalls, and rivers, as well as banana and coffee plantations. Chiriquí is also host to Las Balserias, a Ngöbé-Bugle Indian celebration featuring a contest in which the young men toss balsa logs at one another; those who emerge unscathed may choose their partners.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$52.1 billion (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, bananas, gold, fish, prawns, coffee, clothing and sugar.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Capital goods, food, cars, chemicals, medicines and consumer goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Netherlands, Japan, Canada, China and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Panama has a relatively prosperous economy based on agriculture, light industry, revenues from the Panama Canal and the service sector. Over half the land area is given over to agriculture. The country has significant reserves of timber, particularly mahogany, and good fishing stocks. Further revenue is obtained from tolls levied on ships passing through the Panama Canal and a plethora of 'offshore' companies.</p>
<p>Reforms during the 1990s saw the privatisation of many state enterprises, overhaul of tax and social security systems, and the removal of price controls and import tariffs. Annual growth in 2015 was 5.8%, while inflation was 0.2%. Unemployment was 5.1% (of the labour force) in 2015.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Col&oacute;n Free Trade Zone established near the Canal, an 'open' shipping registry and a rapidly growing tourist industry are all important sources of revenue for Panama. The completion of a $6.2 billion Panama Canal expansion project in 2016 doubled the capacity of the canal by adding a new lane of traffic, and increasing the size of the lanes and locks to allow larger ships to pass.</p>
<p>Panama is a member of the Inter-American Development Bank. A Trade Promotion agreement with the USA was signed in 2007.  Atlapa Convention Centre in Panama City is the largest convention facility in Central America which has a capacity of 10,500 and includes lecture rooms, a theatre/auditorium and exhibition rooms. Other centres include Figali Convention Centre and Hotel El Panama.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Punctuality is appreciated and the exchange of business cards is normal. Suits are necessary for business meetings.</p>
<p>Like most of Central and South America, smart dress is essential for business in Panama. Dark, conservative suits are the norm for both genders, and trousers are fine for women. Titles are important &ndash; address people by their professional titles wherever possible &ndash; and the exchange of business cards is appropriate. If you can possibly have business cards with one side in Spanish printed, then do it.</p>
<p>When attending a business meeting, it is important that you are punctual &ndash; but don&rsquo;t take offense if the other party is not. It happens. It is customary to start with some social conversation rather than leaping into business talk &ndash; let the other party bring it up and in the meantime stick to culture and sports. Gift-giving isn&rsquo;t really necessary, though it is customary for a Panamanian businessman to take you out to dinner to celebrate the closing of a deal.</p>
<p>Business hours are typically 0800 until 1200 and then 1400 until 1800. Expect a long lunch break culture.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Hotel El Panama</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (507) 215 9000
					Website:http://www.elpanama.com
					Address: ,Via Espana 111,Panama City,]]><b>Atlapa Convention Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (507) 226 7000
					Website:http://www.ipat.gob.pa/atlapa
					Address: San Francisco,Instituto Panameño de Turimo,Via Israel,Panama City,]]><b>Cámara de Comercio Industrias y Agricultura de Panamá (Chamber of Commerce)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (507) 207 3443
					Website:http://www.panacamara.com
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Figali Convention Centre</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (507) 314 1414
					Website:http://www.panamacanalvillage.com/
					Address: Proyecto Panama Canal Village,Calzada de Amador,Panama City,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Having such a mix of cultures in the population, it is only right that Panamanians should likewise have a huge variety of cuisines, including North American, French and Spanish.</p>
<p>Native cooking is most reminiscent, however, of Creole cuisine, sometimes hot and spicy, always hearty, with rice present at every meal. Seafood is excellent and abundant, especially along the Caribbean coast, where it is off-the-boat fresh and succulent. <em>Ceviche</em>, marinated fish or seafood, is also superb, a snack usually served with ice-cold beer. Expect fish and shellfish of all kinds and in large portions, for a fraction of what you would pay in the US or UK.</p>
<p>Despite its cosmopolitan influences, Panama&rsquo;s national dish is a traditional chicken stew: <em>sancocho de gallina</em>, a filling and flavoursome dish also comprising yucca, plantain, mixed vegetables and local herbs.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ceviche</strong>: Raw fish or seafood marinated in lime juice, onions and peppers.<br />
<strong>Patacones de pl&aacute;tano:</strong> Fried plantain cakes, served with most meals.<br />
<strong>Sancocho</strong>: Panamanian chicken stew with vegetables and coriander-like herbs.<br />
<strong>Tamales:</strong> Sweet or savoury maize dough, steamed and wrapped in banana leaves.<br />
<strong>Empanadas:</strong> Turnovers filled with meat, chicken or cheese.<br />
<strong>Gallo pinto</strong>: Rice and beans, Panama&rsquo;s version is often mixed with pork.<br />
<strong>Yuca frita:</strong> Fried yucca, a side dish served with most meals.<br />
<strong>Raspados:</strong> Grated ice topped with condensed milk and syrup, eaten for dessert.<br />
<strong>Fufu:</strong> Fried fish in coconut milk, with rice and plantains<br />
<strong>Ropa vieja:</strong> Shredded beef, with rice and beans, based on a Spanish speciality popular throughout Central America.<br />
<strong>Chicha fuerte:</strong> A potent alcoholic maize-based spirit, most popular in the countryside.<br />
<strong>Chicha:</strong> A soft drink made from maize (also often refers to all soft drinks).<br />
<strong>Resbaladera:</strong> A non-alcoholic chilled grain and milk drink, similar to <em>chicheme</em>, technically Costa Rican, but drunk widely in Panama.<br />
<strong>Ron ponche</strong>: Milk, vanilla and rum-based cocktail.<br />
<strong>Panamanian beers:</strong> Panama, Atlas, and Soberana are light lagers, and Balboa is dark, more like stout.<br />
<strong>Seco Herrerano:</strong> Panama&rsquo;s national spirit, triple-distilled from sugarcane and very strong; expect a headache the next day if you don&rsquo;t take it easy.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is customary in hotels (where it is added automatically) and restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Panama City, in particular, has a wide range of nightlife, from nightclubs to classical theatre. Dancing and entertainment are available in all the big hotels, as well as many clubs. Other large towns and resorts have music, dancing, casinos and cinemas. Further details can be found in local papers.</p>
<p>Casinos in Panama City can be found in the major hotels, such as the Sheraton and the Marriot, and also in some large malls such as the Multicentro.  For something more music-based, the Casco Viejo in Panama City has a good variety of places with musical-themed nights, such as Scena Platea&rsquo;s jazz shows and salsa nights, or the Cuban music at Habana Panama and Vieja Havana.</p>
<p>Cultural shows are also available to see, complete with music, dancing and a dinner for the spectators, in various cities throughout the country, including Panama City and David.  These shows incorporate outfits from local indigenous peoples, such as <em>pollera</em> clothing which includes lots of body and head jewellery, and handmade hats.  The music is played on accordions, drums and other local instruments.  Such shows are blatant tourist attractions, but a good way to get an idea of the broad range of cultures making up the current demographic and history of Panama.</p>
<p>Western-style bars are available throughout Panama City, much more in evidence than in most other countries in Central America, another testament to the Western influence here.  You&rsquo;ll find a few typical &ldquo;Irish&rdquo; and &ldquo;English&rdquo; pubs knocking around, too.</p>
<p>Travelling to the Caribbean Coast, in traveller-friendly areas such as the Bocas del Toro, nightlife is specifically designed to cater for tourists, with rum and coke on plentiful offer and a plethora of young backpackers taking full advantage.  Water-front bars are popular and the best place to try a cocktail laced with&nbsp;<em>Seco Herrerano -</em>&nbsp;the national spirit.  Smaller towns in Panama have a more subdued nightlife scene, with local bars and a few beers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Panama is a duty-free haven and luxury goods from all over the world can be bought at a saving of at least one-third. Megamalls in Panama City are chock-full of modern and branded goods, along with giant food courts to sustain you on your shopping mission.  The Multiplaza and Multicentro Malls in Panama City centre are popular choices, as is the Albrook Mall, a short taxi ride out of the city and adjoining the main bus terminal.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re after something traditional for souvenirs, local items include leatherware, beaded necklaces made by Guaym&iacute; Indians, native costumes, jewels and precious stones, straw products, electrical equipment, handicrafts of carved wood, ceramics, papier m&acirc;ch&eacute; artefacts, macram&eacute; and mahogany bowls.  The best places for items such as these are markets: check the Balboa market or the market at Panama Viejo for such things.</p>
<p>Specific Panamanian handicrafts are <em>molas</em>: fabric panels made with intricate, colourful patters, with can be applied to clothing or bags, or framed as art.  You will also come across tightly woven baskets made by the Embera indigenous people.  It is possible to buy <em>huacas</em>, which are high-quality replicas of burial jewellery or figurines found in pre-Conquest Indian tombs.  Go carefully with these &ndash; removing genuine artefacts from the country is illegal.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1800. Some supermarkets are open 24-hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Panama has embarked on an extensive hotel expansion programme, not only in Panama City, but also in the countryside and in mountain and seaside areas. Accommodation ranges from international standard to inexpensive country inns, very simple hotels and new resort-style hotels. There is a 10% government tax added to hotel bills. For further information, contact Instituto Paname&ntilde;o de Turismo (<a href="http://www.atp.gob.pa" target="_blank">www.atp.gob.pa</a>).</p>
<p>Bear in mind, when organising where to stay in Panama, that all accommodation gets very hectic and more expensive around the main holidays, including Christmas, Santa Semana and Carnaval.  Try to book well in advance at these times, or you may find yourself with nowhere to stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of bed and breakfast places in Panama, especially in mountain towns and on the more well-populated islands such as in the Bocas del Toro province. These places are small and cosy, and breakfast is often either traditional fare complete with deep-fried plantains or something more traveller-friendly such as breads and cereals, and always plenty of fruit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Panama has embarked on an extensive hotel expansion programme, not only in Panama City, but also in the countryside and in mountain and seaside areas. Accommodation ranges from international standard to inexpensive country inns, very simple hotels and new resort-style hotels. There is a 10% government tax added to hotel bills. For further information, contact Instituto Paname&ntilde;o de Turismo (<a href="http://www.atp.gob.pa" target="_blank">www.atp.gob.pa</a>).</p>
<p>Bear in mind, when organising where to stay in Panama, that all accommodation gets very hectic and more expensive around the main holidays, including Christmas, Santa Semana and Carnaval.  Try to book well in advance at these times, or you may find yourself with nowhere to stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Panama has embarked on an extensive hotel expansion programme, not only in Panama City, but also in the countryside and in mountain and seaside areas. Accommodation ranges from international standard to inexpensive country inns, very simple hotels and new resort-style hotels. There is a 10% government tax added to hotel bills. For further information, contact Instituto Paname&ntilde;o de Turismo (<a href="http://www.atp.gob.pa" target="_blank">www.atp.gob.pa</a>).</p>
<p>Bear in mind, when organising where to stay in Panama, that all accommodation gets very hectic and more expensive around the main holidays, including Christmas, Santa Semana and Carnaval.  Try to book well in advance at these times, or you may find yourself with nowhere to stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Modern and reliable private medical services are available. According to current legislation covering sanitary matters, Panama offers healthcare facilities to all nationals and foreign travellers who may require them, independent of any reciprocal agreement with a particular country. International travellers are, however, advised to take out medical insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panama is considered to have a moderate to high risk of &lt;strong&gt;Zika virus transmission&lt;/strong&gt;.  The World Health Organisation recommends travellers to Panama protect themselves from mosquito bites by wearing light-coloured clothes that cover as much of the body as possible, sleeping under mosquito nets and using repellents that contain DEET (diethyltoluamide), IR 3535 ((3- [N-butyl-N-acetyl], aminopropionic acid ethyl-ester) or KBR3023 (also called Icaridin or Picaridin). Pregnant women are advised to postpone non-essential travel until after pregnancy and pregnant women whose sexual partners live in or travel to areas with Zika virus transmission should follow safe sexual practices or abstain from sex for the duration of their pregnancy. Women who are pregnant, at risk of getting pregnant, or planning pregnancy should seek further advice from their doctor before travelling to Panama.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and safe, especially in the larger cities. However, if you know you have a sensitive stomach and might react to water which you&amp;rsquo;re unused to, it is safer to drink bottled water, which is widely available. Drinking water outside main cities and towns may be contaminated and sterilisation is advised. Consider this especially along the Caribbean coast, in such places as Bocas del Toro and Kuna Yala; here, if you have no chance to buy bottled water, you should either boil the water for one minute or use iodine pills to disinfect the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.  In Panama City, many of the restaurants are of an exceptionally high standard and their hygiene standards match; however, if you are eating at one of the seafront restaurants where there are many excellent seafood places, try to pick one which looks busy and popular to ensure that the fish is very fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When buying street food and snacks in more rural areas of Panama, take the usual precautions: don&amp;rsquo;t buy meat unless you can see it being cooked right in front of you.  If you find yourself buying snacks out of a bus window, avoid anything with meat in it and try to go for fruit that you can peel.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;While a Yellow Fever vaccination is not required for Panama, there have been instances of the disease in the Dari&amp;eacute;n province, the San Blas islands and the east of Panama, so if you plan on visiting any of these areas it is as well to be up to date with the vaccine. Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are also sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malaria and dengue fever are also fairly common to some regions of Panama, so taking precautions against mosquito bites by using DEET and covering arms and legs in the evenings is wise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An estimated 0.9% of the population of Panama live with HIV; travellers should take the usual precautions against infection.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Below are listed Public Holidays for the January 2017-December 2017 period.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Martyrs' Day :
							2018<br/>09 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Old Panama City Day :
							15 August <b>Date to be confirmed </b>yes
							</p><p>Independence Day (from Colombia) :
							03 November </p><p>Colon Day :
							05 November </p><p>Anniversary of Los Santos Uprising :
							10 November </p><p>Mother's Day :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Panama without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 10 packs of cigarettes or 2 packets of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 5 bottles or 3.8L of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of B/.2,000.</p>
<p>You may bring in gifts, as long as you do not have more than six of each item.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fruit, vegetable and animal products, weapons, explosives, narcotics and hazardous materials.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Balboa (PAB; symbol B/.) = 100 centésimos. There is no Panamanian paper currency; coins exist in denominations of B/.10 and 1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 centésimos. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> currency was adopted in 1904 and exists alongside the Balboa coinage: B/.1 = US$1.<br /><br />US Dollar (US$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of US$100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of US$1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can change foreign currency at the bank in Tocumen International airport, and after that you'll have to see if you can find any <em>casas de cambio</em> (exchange houses), which are mostly found in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/panama-city">Panama City</a>. There is no need to exchange US Dollars, however, and they are easy to come by.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard and Visa are the most commonly used, but American Express and Diners Club are also accepted.  While you will be able to use credit cards in higher end hotels and restaurants, anywhere smaller or more local will not have the facilities, and it is wise to always have some cash to tide you over.  Many of the islands, including Isla de Coiba and Isla Contadora, have no banks and no cash machines, so carrying cash is essential.</p><p>ATM machines can be found throughout the country, especially in the cities.  ATMs are found in or next to banks, or in the streets marked by the red <em>sistema clave</em> sign.  Banks usually charge a fee to draw out funds in Panama, but it still usually works out better than changing money.  You can usually only draw up to US$500 in cash at any one time, but this amount varies between banks. ATMs can run out of cash, so try and always have some on you, in case you are unable to withdraw any immediately.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can still cash traveller's cheques at some banks, especially the larger ones in the cities, but not everywhere, and you can spend them almost nowhere.  This being the case, they are not really a recommended form of currency to rely on.  If you must carry traveller's cheques, they should certainly be in US dollars as they won't be accepted in any other form; American Express traveller's cheques are best.  You will also be charged a fee to change traveller's cheques, usually about 1% of the transaction price.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1500, Sat 0830-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Panama, a passport valid for a minimum of six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Children require their own passports.  Leaving the country, children require their birth certificates and letter of consent from both parents if either or both aren&rsquo;t present.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International travellers in transit in Panama do not require a visa provided they don&rsquo;t pass immigration and are staying less than nine hours.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visa: US$100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Three months from the date of issue and allowing stays of up to 30 days (extendable to 90 days once in Panama at the discretion of the immigration authorities).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas for temporary residence are granted to those studying in Panama, those visiting relatives, those having medical treatment or those working with international firms.  Apply to your embassy in this instance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normally five to 10 days if no authorisation is needed; up to 20 days if authorisation (which depends on nationality) is needed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers should be ready to show that they are carrying sufficient funds. You should be able to show a credit card or US$500 in cash.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa holders wishing to extend their 30-day stay to 90 days need to visit the nearest immigration office in Panama and request a <em>pr&oacute;rroga de turista</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bringing dogs and cats into Panama requires a Certificate of Good Health and a rabies vaccination, and a Quarantine for Domestic Animals form should be sent three days ahead of arrival to the Panama Minister of Health.  Then your dog or cat needs to be checked by a Panamanian vet at the airport &ndash; your best choice is to pay to have one meet your flight and get it done then and there. Please note that at certain times of year, restriction periods do apply for animals transported in a cargo hold. Contact your nearest embassy for further information.</p>
<p>Birds and reptiles require an import permit, and birds require vaccinations for chlamydia, salmonella, TB, avian flu and newcastle disease.  These vaccinations must be shown on your bird&rsquo;s Certificate of Good Health, and that and your import permit must be certified in the consulate in Panama before arrival. <br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[8.599024]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-80.410038]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>75,517 sq km (29,157 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3,990,406 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>48.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Panama City.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Panama forms the land link between the North and South American continents. It borders Colombia to the east, Costa Rica to the west, and the Caribbean and the Pacific Ocean to the north and south. The country forms an S-shaped isthmus, which runs east-west over a total length of 772km (480 miles) and is 60 to 177km (37 to 110 miles) wide. The landscape is mountainous with lowlands on both coastlines cut by streams, wooded slopes and a wide area of savannah-covered plains and rolling hills called <em>El Interior</em> between the Azuero peninsula and the Central Mountains. To the east is the Dari&eacute;n province which is a humid area of swamp and forest with few inhabitants.  The Dari&eacute;n Gap is the missing link in the Panamerican Highway, as extending the road through the dense jungle would be costly and environmentally destructive.</p>
<p>The Caribbean and the Pacific Ocean are linked by the man-made Panama Canal, cut into a gap between the Cordillera de Talamanca and the San Blas mountain range and stretching for over 65km (40 miles); the length of the canal is often referred to as 80km (50 miles) as this is the distance between deep-water points of entry.</p>
<p>Only about a quarter of the country is inhabited. The majority of the population live either around the canal and main cities of Panama City and Col&oacute;n (the two cities which control the entrance and exit of the canal) or in the Pacific lowlands and the adjacent mountains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Almost all Christian; 90% Roman Catholic (FCO figures).  Other representations include Protestants, Jews and Muslims.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the normal form of greeting and dress is generally casual. The culture is a vibrant mixture of American and Spanish lifestyles. The mestizo majority, which is largely rural, shares many of the characteristics of mestizo culture found throughout Central America. Only three indigenous tribes have retained their individuality and traditional lifestyles as a result of withdrawing into virtually inaccessible areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz (in Panama City 120 volts). North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without third grounding pin) are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Juan Carlos Varela since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Juan Carlos Varela since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Panama&rsquo;s earliest inhabitants were hunter-gatherers and lived on the land some 10,000 years ago. Apart from the remains of tribal people, archaeologists have discovered some traces of ancient life such as statues, gold ornaments, and some of the earliest ceramics ever found in the Americas.</p>
<p>The Spanish arrived in 1502 and established the original Panama City less than 20 years later. Spain transformed the entire continent, establishing its own colonial society and obliterating the ancient civilisations. Panama City was the starting point of the expedition that ended up conquering the Inca Empire.</p>
<p>After 300 years of colonial rule, the region finally gained independence from Spain in 1821 and formed the state known as Gran Colombia, which included Colombia, Venezuela, Panama and Ecuador. By the end of the century the territory was tearing itself apart and in 1903 Panama broke free from an unhappy union with neighbouring Colombia.</p>
<p>The building of the Panama Canal, which was completed in 1914, was to change everything for Panama. 75,000 labourers of all nationalities flocked to Panama at the prospect of work and building a new life for themselves, bringing in a huge influx of different cultures. The US government bought the rights to the Panama Canal Zone, assuming a huge influence in the running of the country, and the wealth generated by the canal went largely to US interests.</p>
<p>The 20th century was marked by political strife and wrestling matches over rights to the canal. Following his military coup in 1968, General Omar Torrijos Herrera imposed a dictatorship, which continued until his death in 1981. Torrijos was succeeded by his former intelligence chief, Manuel Noriega, who remained in power until 1989, by which time US relations had collapsed and financial assistance cut, in reaction to allegations of election fraud and drug trafficking. When President George Bush sent in a military invasion to wrest power from Noriega, in December 1989, the country was suffering from a crippling lack of funds.</p>
<p>Panama struggled back to economic stability throughout the 1990s, ending positively with the defining moment of its history: the official handing over of the Panama Canal by the US to Panama, successfully concluding a treaty signed in 1977. The completion of a multi-billion dollar Panama Canal expansion project in 2016 more than doubled its operating capacity. Proposed by the then-Panamanian President Mart&iacute;n Torrijos, son of the former dictator, the project was completed a decade later under the current President of Panama, Juan Carlos Varela.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	When General Noriega took refuge in the Vatican Embassy during the US invasion of 1989, they played loud rock music, including Van Halen (Panama) and the Clash (I Fought the Law), to drive him out.<br />
&bull;	Panama has 59 of the world&rsquo;s 356 species of hummingbird, including the smallest bird in the world, the 5-cm bee hummingbird.<br />
&bull;	Panama Hats come from Ecuador, not Panama; they got their name in the 19th century because they were first shipped to Panama before being exported around the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Panama]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+507 297 6550.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-panama-city</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+507 297 6550.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0730-1630, Fri 0730-1230.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Calle 53, Marbella<br/>MMG Tower, 4th Floor<br/>Panama City<br/>PO Box 0816-0794<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Panama in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 483 1407.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofpanama.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 483 1407.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1400.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2862 McGill Terrace NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Consulate General of Panama in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7493 4646.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.panamaconsul.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7493 4646.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1730.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>40 Hertford Street<br/>London<br/>W1J 7SH<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Think Panama and what springs to mind? The canal? Cigars? Straw hats? Probably all three. However, for those in the know, this slender Central American nation is much more than that; it is a land of wildlife-rich rainforests and remote indigenous communities; Miami-esque promenades and paradisiacal beaches; verdant volcanoes and the impenetrable wilderness of the Darien Gap.</p>
<p>Firstly, the canal. Though considered to be the star attraction (thousands flock here to watch container ships passing through the locks) the wild landscapes it scythes through are an altogether more exciting prospect. Here you can hike volcanoes, zip-wire over forest canopies, raft down rapids and meet one of the country&rsquo;s largest indigenous groups, the Kunas, who eke out simple, traditional lives on the sumptuous San Blas Islands.</p>
<p>The Caribbean coastline features another facet of Panamanian culture. Jamaicans and Barbadians, drafted in to build the canal, ended up settling here and an Afro-Caribbean vibe endures to this day. The nearby Bocas del Toro islands, meanwhile, are the definition of Caribbean island ideal with their palm-fringed beaches, limpid lagoons and sleepy eco-lodges.</p>
<p>The wildlife is also spectacular. Whale watching in the Golfo de Chiriqu&iacute; is a must and you never forget scuba diving or snorkeling alongside turtles in the Coiba National Marine Park. Its birdlife surpasses neighbouring Costa Rica and the most treasured sightings are the iconic harpy eagle, Panama&rsquo;s national bird, and the endangered great green macaw.</p>
<p>With so much natural beauty to imbibe, it is easy to overlook the bustling capital, Panama City. But don&rsquo;t. A metropolis divided starkly between the past and present, it is a city where crumbling colonial buildings stand in the shadows of high-rise steel and glass towers. It feels a little bit like Miami and the locals certainly give their US counterparts a run for their money in the hedonism stakes. Come join the party.</p><p>Think Panama and what springs to mind? The canal? Cigars? Straw hats? Probably all three. However, for those in the know, this slender Central American nation is much more than that; it is a land of wildlife-rich rainforests and remote indigenous communities; Miami-esque promenades and paradisiacal beaches; verdant volcanoes and the impenetrable wilderness of the Darien Gap.</p>
<p>Firstly, the canal. Though considered to be the star attraction (thousands flock here to watch container ships passing through the locks) the wild landscapes it scythes through are an altogether more exciting prospect. Here you can hike volcanoes, zip-wire over forest canopies, raft down rapids and meet one of the country&rsquo;s largest indigenous groups, the Kunas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
