<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Papua New Guinea" ColCode="png" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="pg" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Papua New Guinea]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot, tropical climate at sea level, cooling towards the highlands which also cause climatic variation from one area to another, affecting the southeast trade winds and the northwest monsoons. The majority of the rain falls between December and March due to the northwest monsoon, although Port Moresby enjoys a dry season at this time. There is frost and there are occasional snow falls on the highest mountain peaks.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical, lightweights and cottons are recommended. In the highlands,<br />warmer clothing is needed. Rainwear is advised for the monsoon season<br />(December to March).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Air Niugini (<a href="http://www.airniugini.com.pg/" target="_blank">www.airniugini.com.pg</a>) and PNG Air (<a href="http://www.pngair.com.pg" target="_blank">www.pngair.com.pg</a>) fly to all the main centres. Charter services are also available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cruises go mainly to the islands and otherwise inaccessible places on the coast. Cargo/passenger services between Lae and Madang run by Lutheran Shipping (with facilities including passenger cabins, accommodation and meals) are currently suspended following the company's liquidation.</p>
<p>For the local people in some regions of the country, rivers, particularly the Sepik, provide the main thoroughfares. In these areas it's possible to hire motorised canoes or obtain passage on a trading boat; however, apart from cruises, there are no regular public transport operators on the rivers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Owing to the rugged terrain of Papua New Guinea, road development of the interior has been slow. There is a network of roads connecting the northern coast towns of Madang and Lae with the major urban centres in the Highlands region.  There are few roads connecting the various provinces however.</p><p>Available in district centres but expensive. Although operated on a metered basis, fares can be negotiated.</p><p>A national driving licence is sufficient.</p><p>Available in principal towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Air Niugini (<a href="http://www.airniugini.com.pg" target="_blank">www.airniugini.com.pg</a>), whose international routes include direct flights from Hong Kong, Manila, Singapore and Sydney. Virgin Australia (<a href="http://www.virginaustralia.com" target="_blank">www.virginaustralia.com</a>) flies to Port Moresby from Brisbane. From Europe or North America, you need to fly via either southeast Asia or Australia.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 25 hours (two stopovers) or 31 hours (one stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 29 hours (two stopovers) or 41 hours (one stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>K30 is levied on international flights (usually included in the price of a ticket).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Jacksons International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 11km (7 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong>&nbsp;Alotau, Kieta (North Solomons), Lae, Madang, Momote (Manus), Port Moresby, Rabaul (New Britain) and Wewak (Sepik).</p>
<p>Several passenger/cruise lines and cargo lines run regular services to Papua New Guinea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes in Papua New Guinea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Coverage is limited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Services tend to be slow and sometimes unreliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Two daily newspapers are published in English: <em>The National </em>and <em>Papua New Guinea Post-Courier</em>. The most popular daily is <em>Niugini Nius</em>. For those wanting to watch TV, Commercial channel <em>EMTV</em> is the only broadcaster and hotels sometimes provide satellite channels.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes seven to 10 days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600, Sat 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Explore the Eastern Highlands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rugged mountains and verdant valleys characterise the Eastern Highlands, making it popular with hikers. But it's not just about nature: the region is a fine place to explore Papua New Guinean heritage. Bena Village, near Goroka, is a sight to behold with its megalithic ruins and thatched houses, which are decorated with human skulls. Then there's Asaro, where men coat themselves with mud and re-enact their historic revenge on a neighbouring village.</p>]]><p><b>Go scuba diving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Make the most of spectacular swimming, snorkelling and diving opportunities off the beautiful beaches of Papua New Guinea. From wrecks to reefs, Madang, Port Moresby and Rabaul offer a wide variety of dive sites. Diving excursions can also be arranged at Loloaka, Milne Bay and off the island of New Britain, where some of the region's finest sites can be found.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in the capital, Port Moresby</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Papua New Guinean capital nestles on Fairfax Harbour and is one of the least liveable cities in the world, according to <em>The Economist</em>. Don't let that put you off, though. Port Moresby has a fair share of attractions including the National Parliament, the National Museum, the Botanical Gardens and the Catholic Cathedral, built in the style of a traditional <em>haus tambaran </em>(meetinghouse). Nevertheless, most use it as gateway to the rest of the country.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Madang</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once described as the "prettiest town in the South Pacific," Madang is a popular launching pad for travellers looking to explore Papua New Guinea's extraordinary underwater world. As well as being a gateway to reefs, wrecks and crystalline waters, Madang has a variety of shops and markets, where local crafts can be bought. The scenery is also unremittingly beautiful.</p>]]><p><b>Shop for crafts in Kanganaman</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Kanganaman, a traditional Papa New Guinean village, where carvers of exceptional talent whittle wood into elaborate masks, totems and figurines. The village is also home to a beautiful <em>haus tambaran</em> (meetinghouse), which is perhaps one of the finest examples of such a building in the country.</p>]]><p><b>Soak up the scenery of the Mendi Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For a hair-raising experience with spectacular scenery, take a trip to the Mendi Valley in the Southern Highlands, also known for its limestone caves and sheer rock faces. It is also home to the <em>Huli wigmen, </em>who decorate themselves with face paint and elaborate wigs made of human hair.</p>]]><p><b>Spot birds-of-paradise</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Witness the beauty of the famous birds-of-paradise at Baiyer River Wildlife Sanctuary in the Western Highlands. Located 55km (34 miles) north of Mount Hagen, this beautiful nature reserve is also home to possums, tree kangaroos, parrots, cassowaries and bandicoots. The area boasts some great trekking opportunities.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hike on the Kokoda Trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Starting just outside Port Moresby, the Kokoda Trail offers magnificent views as it wends through ravines, rainforests and rubber plantations. The 96km (60-mile) route is not for the fainthearted: hikers must endure extreme humidity, mosquitoes and torrential rail. Other places of interest include the Wairiata National Park, Moitaka Crocodile Farm and Loloata Island.</p>]]><p><b>Trek through Chambri</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a river or jungle tour in the Chambri region, stopping at remote villages where houses are built on stilts, and the dugout canoe is still the main means of transport. Hear villagers play slit drums and see elaborate local carvings.</p>]]><p><b>Wake early for birdwatching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pack your binoculars and head to Chambri Lakes, which are home to myriad species from brahminy kites to kingfishers. Go on an early morning jungle excursion to experience a wonderful cacophony of bird song, which brings in the new day.</p>]]><p><b>While away the day in Lae Botanical Gardens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Stroll through the beautiful botanical gardens in Lae, a verdant oasis in the capital of Morobe Province. The grounds are home to roughly 2,000 different plant species and are crisscrossed by various creeks. Adjacent to the botanical gardens is the Lae War Cemetery, which holds the remains of some 2,800 soldiers who gave their lives in WWII.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$4.2 billion.</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Gold, petroleum, copper, palm oil and logs.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transport equipment, food and fuels.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Australia, Singapore, Japan, China and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although Papua New Guinea has been described as 'a mountain of gold floating on a sea of oil', it is a poor country and most of the population is engaged in subsistence agriculture. However, it boasts the largest-known supply of low-grade copper, which accounts for much of its export earnings. Other deposits include gold, chromite, oil and natural gas.<br /><br />Light industry has grown steadily, mostly to meet consumer demands. Papua New Guinea's attempts to develop a tourist industry have been undermined by poor infrastructure and past political instability. The country is also subject to extreme weather and natural phenomena, including drought, flooding and earthquakes.<br /><br />Papua New Guinea belongs to the Asian Development Bank and the South Pacific Commission. It is still dependent on large amounts of aid from Australia.<br />Some hotels provide facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business affairs tend to be conducted in a very informal fashion. A conventional suit will not be required - shirt and tie are sufficient.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1630 or 1700.<br /><br /><strong>Government office hours: </strong>Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Investment Promotion Authority</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 321 7311
					Website:http://www.ipa.gov.pg
					Address: ,PO Box 5053,Port Moresby,]]><b>Papua New Guinea Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 321 3057
					Website:http://www.pngcci.org.pg
					Address: ,PO Box 1621,Port Moresby,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Hotel dining rooms cater for most visitors and menus in main centres are fairly extensive. The more remote the area, the more likely it is that the menus will be basic. However, increasing use is made of fresh local meat, fish, vegetables and fruit. The number of European, Chinese and Indonesian restaurants is rising.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />
&bull; Traditional cuisine of Papua New Guinea is based on root crops such as taro, kaukau and yams, sago and pig (cooked in the earth on traditional feasts).<br />
<em>&bull; Mumu</em> is a traditional dish combining roast pork, sweet potatoes, rice and greens.<br />
&bull; Local fruits include pineapples, pawpaws, mangoes, passion fruit and bananas.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Waiter service is usual. Bills include a 10% sales tax.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Not customary and discouraged.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Several hotels in Port Moresby have dancing in the evenings and some organise live entertainment. The Arts Theatre stages regular performances. The local newspaper advertises programmes. Sing-sings, tribal events on a smaller scale than the biannual festival, are sometimes held.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A wide range of crafts is available in shops; alternatively, visitors can buy directly from villagers. Favourite buys include local carvings of ceremonial masks and statuettes from Angoram and the Sepik, <em>Buka</em> basketry, arrows, bows and decorated axes, crocodile carvings from the Trobriands, pottery and local art.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700, Sat 0900-1300 (some open longer and/or Sunday).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adequate and comfortable accommodation is available throughout Papua New Guinea. Generally, it is more expensive than in most Australasian states. There are hotels of international standard in Lae, Madang, Port Moresby and most major centres. Many motels also offer good value accommodation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adequate and comfortable accommodation is available throughout Papua New Guinea. Generally, it is more expensive than in most Australasian states. There are hotels of international standard in Lae, Madang, Port Moresby and most major centres. Many motels also offer good value accommodation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Adequate and comfortable accommodation is available throughout Papua New Guinea. Generally, it is more expensive than in most Australasian states. There are hotels of international standard in Lae, Madang, Port Moresby and most major centres. Many motels also offer good value accommodation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The main hospitals are Port Moresby General (Papuan region), Goroka Base (Highlands) and Angau Memorial. Visitors can use any of the private doctors or public consultation clinics. Doctors and hospitals are not free and often expect immediate payment for medical services. Hospitals are poorly equipped and sudden shortages of common medications can sometimes occur; travellers who may need ongoing or routine medical treatment are advised to obtain visas for Australia, where medical facilities are more reliable, before leaving their country of origin. Dental care outside the main centres is limited, but pharmacies in the major centres are well stocked. Health insurance is essential and must include evacuation facilities.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;HIV/AIDS is a serious health issue with the rate of infection increasing. Other sexually transmitted diseases are prevalent in urban centres. Protection with condoms is essential. Vaccinations against Japanese B encephalitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the next working day. In addition, there are various regional festivals throughout the year.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							11 June </p><p>National Remembrance Day :
							23 July </p><p>Independence Day :
							16 September </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following may be imported into Papua New Guinea by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 250 cigarettes or  250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; 1L of perfume.<br />
&bull; New goods up to a value of K1,000 (K500 for children under 18).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include counterfeit bank notes and coins, goods manufactured using prison labour, flick knives, matches containing white or yellow phosphorus, parrots, parakeets and related birds, plastic shopping bags, gaming machines, and firearm silencers.</p>
<p>Restricted items requiring special permission or certification include animals, narcotics, fireworks, fish, food, goods considered a danger to the community, pornographic and violent publications and films, goods that infringe intellectual property rights, literature advocating the overthrow by force of any country, literature inciting hostility against the Papua New Guinea government, pesticides, plumage and skins of birds of paradise and crown pigeons, rice, radioactive substances, tear gas, and vaccines.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dangerous drugs are completely prohibited.</p>
<p>Restricted exports requiring special permission include crocodiles and their parts, flora and fauna, timber, geological and fossil materials, alluvial gold, pearl-shell oysters, natural cultural property, and goods acquired illegaly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kina (PGK; symbol K) = 100 toea. Notes are in denominations of K100, 50, 20, 10, 5 and 2. Coins are in denominations of K1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 toea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchange facilities are available through trade banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express is the most widely accepted credit card; MasterCard and Visa are often accepted as well.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted by most shops and hotels. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, traveller's are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars, Pounds Sterling or Australian Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0845-1500, Fri 0845-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Papua New Guinea, a passport valid for at least six months after entry is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You don't require a transit visa if you stay within the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist/visitor visa (on arrival or in advance): free; single-entry business visa: &pound;119.60; multiple-entry business visa: &pound;239.10.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist/visitor visa: 60 days; single-entry business visa: 30 days; multiple-entry business visa:&nbsp;up to 12 months with a maximum of 60 days per stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On arrival at the airport (if eligible) or in advance at the consulate (or consular section at embassy or high commission). The multiple-entry business visa can only be issued in advance and is not available at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Processing for advance visas normally takes four working days if you apply in person and up to a week if you apply by post.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa applicants must show they have sufficient funds to cover their stay (a recent bank statement usually suffices).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>While in Papua New Guinea, you can extend a tourist/visitor visa for a maximum of 30 days; you can download the relevant form from the Immigration &amp; Citizenship Service Authority website (<a href="http://www.immigration.gov.pg">www.immigration.gov.pg</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-6.120983]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[146.858012]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>462,840 sq km (178,704 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>7,776,115 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>14.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Port Moresby.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Papua New Guinea consists of over 600 islands and lies in the middle of the long chain of islands stretching from mainland South-East Asia. It lies in the South Pacific, 160km (100 miles) north of Australia. The country occupies the eastern half of the second-largest non-continental island in the world, as well as the smaller islands of the Bismarck Archipelago (Admiralty Island, Bougainville, New Britain and New Ireland), the D'Entrecasteaux Island group and the three islands of the Louisiade Archipelago. The main island shares a land border with Irian Jaya, a province of Indonesia. The mainland and larger islands are mountainous and rugged, divided by large fertile upland valleys. Fast-flowing rivers from the highlands descend to the coastal plains. A line of active volcanoes stretches along the north coast of the mainland and continues on the island of New Britain. To the north and south of this central mountain range on the main island lie vast stretches of mangrove swamps and coastal river deltas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>90% Christian.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Papua New Guinea's culture still includes elements of a primitive lifestyle. There are universities at Lae (which is a University of Technology with a liberal infusion of Europeans and North Americans) and at Port Moresby. Casual clothes are recommended. Informality is the order of the day and although shorts are quite acceptable, beachwear is usually best confined to the beach. In the evenings some hotels expect men to wear long trousers but ties are rare. A long dress is appropriate for women on formal occasions.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. Australian-style plugs with three angled flat pins are used. Some hotels provide 110-volt outlets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General Sir Bob Dadae&nbsp;since February 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Guinea has been inhabited for some 10,000 years, but its recorded history began with the visits of Portuguese explorers in the early 16th century, followed by Dutch traders. The Dutch East India Company took control of the western half of the island in 1828, which was then split between the British and Germans in the 1880s until after World War 1 when it was transferred to the sole control of Australia before being occupied by the Japanese during World War 2.<br/><br/>After 1945, the renamed Papua New Guinea reverted to Australian administration and was granted independence in 1975. It remains a separate Commonwealth realm with Queen Elizabeth II as its head of state, but its Governor-General – currently Sir Michael Ogio – is unusual in that the post is elected by the legislature rather than appointed by government.</p><p><br/>The main problem for successive governments has been how to make the most of Papua New Guinea's abundant natural resources in order to finance its development while maintaining its natural environment. It's a delicate balancing act that has led to civil unrest, not least in 1989 when a secessionist revolt on the copper-rich island of Bourgainville flared up. It was to claim 20,000 lives before it was resolved in 2007 with local autonomy and the promise of a referendum on independence before 2020.</p><p>The tension between protecting and exploiting the country's natural assets continues as discussions around reopening the massive Panguna copper mine – once the world's largest open pit copper mine – in Bourgainville show few signs of resolution.<br/></p><p>Papua New Guinea is one of the world's most culturally diverse nations with more than a thousand cultural groups and some 852 languages recognised, of which 12 have no known speakers. It is also one of the least explored places on Earth with many undiscovered species of animals and plants thought to exist in the country's interior, as well as groups of people that have had no previous contact with the outside world.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• Papua New Guinea's capital city Port Moresby hosted the Pacific Games in 2015.</p><p>• Transport is severely hampered by the mountainous terrain and many remote villages are only accessible by air or foot. The capital is not linked by road to any other major towns.</p><p>• Sea shells were abolished as currency in 1933, although the tradition lives on in some local customs such as symbolic wedding dowries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Papua New Guinea Embassy in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 745 3680.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.pngembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 745 3680.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Suite 805<br/>1779 Massachusetts Avenue NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Papua New Guinea High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7930 0922.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7930 0922.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1400-1630.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>14 Waterloo Place<br/>London<br/>SW1Y 4AR<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Papua New Guinea]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>325 1677.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/papua-new-guinea</p><p><b>Tel:</b>325 1677.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Waigani, National Capital District<br/>Sec 411 Lot 1 &amp; 2, Kiroki Street<br/>Port Moresby<br/>Locked Mail Bag<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Papua New Guinea is a fascinating country where travellers can explore remote villages, as well as enjoying spectacular diving, stunning wildlife, scenic surfing and myriad cultures. The tribal diversity of a country with over 800 languages and 600 islands cannot easily be summarised, although in Papua New Guinea it is the tribal life that is most fascinating to the visitor.</p><p>Beyond the dizzying array of ethnic groups to get to know, there are many unique attractions, excursions and activities on offer, from discovering wrecks of World War II aircraft that lie in the jungle, to peeking inside the sacred wooden <em>haustambarans</em> (spirit houses) of towns and villages in the country.</p><p>One of the largest draws for those visiting Papua New Guinea is the country's extensive wildlife and unique ecosystem. From the mountainous highlands to the Evian-blue waters, travellers can expect to discover weird and wonderful creatures, from tree-climbing kangaroos to spectacular birds of paradise; there are almost 700 bird species on the islands. Be sure to visit the National Botanic Gardens in Port Moresby, which is probably the capital's greenest, most beautiful sport. Most of the country remains undeveloped, with the largest island of Bouganville avoiding from resort hotels and commercialisation – ideal for the independent traveller.</p><p>Above all, though, it's the inhabitants that make Papua New Guinea truly unique. Many of the hundreds of languages spoken here are kept alive by a just a few dozen people. Each ethnic group has its own proud artistic traditions, with deft handicrafts, entrancing dance performances and bracing music. If you happen to visit during a festival – to be fair, there are many of them occurring throughout the year – prepare to be spellbound by tribal concerts and elaborate headdresses. Spend a bit of time here, and you'll feel as if you've gained access to a bygone era, although it would be wrong to describe the inhabitants as stuck in the past. Anyone welcomed into their embrace will say that they are thriving.</p>Papua New Guinea is a fascinating country where travellers can explore remote villages, spectacular diving, stunning wildlife, scenic surfing and myriad cultures.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
