<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Paraguay" ColCode="pry" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="py" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Paraguay]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Subtropical with rapid changes in temperature throughout the year. Summer (December to March) can be very hot. Winter (June to September) is mild with few cold days. Rainfall is heaviest from December to March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are worn in warmer months, with some<br />warm clothes for spring and autumn. Mediumweights are best for winter.<br />Rainwear is advisable throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amaszonas (www.amaszonas.com) runs flights between Asunci&oacute;n and Ciudad del Este. These flights often fill up particularly around major holidays.</p>
<p>Air taxis are popular with those wishing to discover the Paraguayan Chaco as road access can be difficult, especially during heavy rains.  Air taxis can also be used to visit other tourist sites such as the Saltos de Monday, Yacyret&aacute; Dam and Encarnaci&oacute;n. Operators include Paraguay Air Service (<a href="http://www.pas.com.py" target="_blank">www.pas.com.py</a>).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no rail services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The major towns are all reachable by paved roads which vary between one and two lanes. Bypasses are rare, so most road trips allow you to pass through local towns. Dangerous driving is common in Asunci&oacute;n and other major cities, so drive cautiously and try not to be bullied by other road users.</p>r<p>Approximately 10% of Paraguay&rsquo;s roads are surfaced and some unsurfaced roads may be impassable in bad weather, especially between November and April. Check with locals before heading out on a rainy day. Paved highways link the largest cities in Paraguay.</p>
<p>Travelling or driving at night is not advisable due to poor lighting and the prevalence of drivers under the influence of alcohol. There are regular police checks, but corruption is commonplace and bribes may be requested in lieu of paying a fine. In the event of receiving a fine, always ask for a ticket and pay the fine at a later date rather than on-the-spot to ensure the correct amount is charged.</p><p>Taxis are commonplace in major towns and cities, but flagging them down in the street isn&rsquo;t advisable &ndash; take one from a designated taxi rank. You can book cabs in Asunci&oacute;n by using the Radio Taxi service (+595 21 311 080).</p>
<p>All taxis must use a meter, but do be aware surcharges apply after 2200 on Sundays and public holidays.</p><p>A national driving licence or International Driving Permit are both accepted.</p><p>It's obligatory to wear a seatbelt in the driver and passenger seat. Talking on a mobile phone is prohibited but like many other driving laws it is commonly broken.&nbsp;It's obligatory to carry your driving licence and proof of vehicle ownership at all times. It's recommended to have your passport to hand.</p><p>Touring and Automobile Club provides some assistance to its members (+595 21 210 550; <a href="http://www.tacpy.com.py" target="_blank">www.tacpy.com.py</a>).</p><p>You can hire cars at the airport or through local tourist agencies.</p><p>Bike hire is available along the Costanera in Asunci&oacute;n and inside Parque &Ntilde;u Guazu on the outskirts of the city. However, cycling on public roads can be daunting even for locals.</p><p>It's obligatory to wear a seatbelt in the driver and passenger seat. Talking on a mobile phone is prohibited but like many other driving laws it is commonly broken.&nbsp;It's obligatory to carry your driving licence and proof of vehicle ownership at all times. It's recommended to have your passport to hand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most urban areas have a decent bus service &ndash; fares are usually fixed regardless of the journey length. Buses also link together most major towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Paraguay</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">pedro_juan_caballero</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">11.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Paraguay</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">encarnacioacuten</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">14.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Paraguay</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">concepcioacuten</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">12.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Paraguay</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ciudaddel_este</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.05</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Paraguay has no national carrier, but the Brazilian airline TAM (<a href="http://www.tam.com.br" target="_blank">www.tam.com.br</a>) has regular flights in and of Asunci&oacute;n, linking it with other South American nations, the UK and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>. Note the airline is merging with LAN to become LATAM (<a href="http://www.latam.com" target="_blank">www.latam.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 16 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 13 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$31 for passengers departing from Asuncion and US$16 for those flying out of Ciudad del Este. This is sometimes included in the air fare; check with your airline. Transit passengers are exempt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Asunción Silvio Pettirossi International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 16km (10 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although landlocked, Paraguay has 3,100km (1,900 miles) of waterways, primarily the Paraguay and Paran&aacute; Rivers. There are five major ports &ndash; Asunci&oacute;n, Caacupemi, Villeta and San Antonio, which are situated on the Rio Paraguay and Encarnaci&oacute;n on the Paran&aacute; River.</p>
<p>The Paraguayan port authority has more information (<a href="http://www.annp.gov.py" target="_blank">www.annp.gov.py</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no rail services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From Argentina: There are long distance buses leaving from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/buenos-aires">Buenos Aires</a> to Asunci&oacute;n daily; the most common crossing is through the Clorinda/Puerto Falc&oacute;n border. Another popular crossing is between Posadas and Encarnaci&oacute;n, where motorists can take the Ruta 1 to Asunci&oacute;n or the Ruta 6 to Ciudad del Este.</p>
<p>From Brazil: There are regular buses from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sao-paulo">Sao Paulo</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/rio-de-janeiro">Rio de Janeiro</a>, Curitiba and even Brasilia (once a week). They cross the 'Friendship Bridge' that joins Foz de Iguazu with Ciudad del Este which motorists can also use to travel due west on Ruta 7 and Ruta 2 to Asuncion. There are also crossings further North between Guair&aacute; and Salto de Guair&aacute; or Ponta Por&atilde; and Pedro Juan Caballero.</p>
<p>From Bolivia: The only entry point is in the Gran Chaco; buses run from La Paz and Santa Cruz going through Villa Montes in Bolivia and arriving in Mariscal Estigarribia in the Chaco.</p><p>It is not advisable to travel at night due to poor lighting and the prevalence of drivers under the influence of alcohol. Police road checks are common, so be sure to have all documents in order. Motorists must carry a fire extinguisher, tow bar and spare tyre in the car.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Moderate internal network apart from the main cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies. Coverage is limited to urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet caf&eacute;s are available in main urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The press and broadcasters air a range of views, including those of the opposition. But journalists investigating corruption, or covering strikes and protests, risk intimidation, and media outlets sometimes face legal harassment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes five days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Catch a football game</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With Paraguay having reached the 2010 World Cup Quarter Finals and with many players in the major European leagues, football is an understandable passion in this country. Olimpia and Cerro Porteño are the two biggest teams in Asunción. A live game is a spectacular experience, although a little hairy – try and go with a local.</p>]]><p><b>Cross the border to the Iguazu Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Meeting on what is called the Triple Frontera, the point where Argentina and Brazil meet Paraguay are the Iguazu Falls, one of the most spectacular sights on earth. The hectic and often overwhelming border town of Ciudad del Este is the perfect crossing point to the falls; you can cross the "Friendship Bridge" into Brazil or head south to Presidente Franco and take a ferry to Argentina.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise the Paraguay River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spend a few days travelling the Rio Paraguay, through the Pantanal wetlands, spotting wildlife and learning about the country's extraordinary history. River tours typically depart from Concepción, stopping at towns and national parks along the way.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Paraguay’s only UNESCO sites</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't leave Paraguay without visiting the crumbling settlements erected by Jesuits missionaries in the 16th century, who travelled through the region converting the indigenous Guaraní people to Christianity. They built vast complexes and encouraged the locals to abide by fairly rigid socioeconomic structures based on Jesuit values. Only ruins remain and the best preserved sites can be found at Jesús de Tavarangué and Trinidad del Paraná, which have been declared UNESCO World Heritage Sites.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the ‘pearl of the south’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The lively waterfront area of Encarnación has earned a reputation as one of Paraguay's major tourist destinations. Locals flock to the beach during the summer season (December to February), which is brought to a close by the biggest carnival in the country.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the capital, Asunción</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Paraguay capital is situated on the Bay of Asunción, an inlet off the Paraguay River. Planned on a colonial Spanish grid system, the old town has many parks and plazas. The newly built Costanera runs alongside the river and is a great spot to relax in an afternoon or go for a jog. Close by is the lively and colourful neighbourhood of Loma San Jeronimo, which holds regular events and offers the chance to experience traditional food. Even if there are no events on, it is a worth a trip because it has great views of the city.</p>]]><p><b>Gawp at the Itaipú Dam</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the seven wonders of the modern world, the Itaipú Dam is the largest hydroelectric complex in the world. The water reservoir has attempted to offset its environmental footprint by creating a unique ecosystem for wildlife and birds. Walking tours and fishing expeditions can be arranged at the dam.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the Salto Monday waterfalls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Prepare to see the breathtaking waterfalls in Presidente Franco just south of Ciudad del Este, 326km (204 miles) east of the capital. The majestic Monday Falls, situated in a 22 acre national reserve, are 40m (131ft) high and are much less crowded than the Iguazú falls across the border.</p>]]><p><b>Pay homage to Mariscal Lopez</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Paraguay's modern history has been defined by the Triple Alliance War that ravaged the country from 1864 until 1870. The war was ended with the death of Paraguay's leader, Mariscal López, who was killed in battle at Cerro Corá. As well as a monument to the fallen leader, Cerro Corá National Park abounds with lookout points and hiking trails.</p>]]><p><b>Ride with ranchers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are dozens of estancias around the country where visitors can get a taste of rural life, ride with the cowboys, take a horse and cart tour or just sit and relax in the country drinking <em>tereré</em> (a herbal infusion).</p>]]><p><b>Tour the tea plantations</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Yerba mate tea is one of the most popular infusions in Paraguay and South America as a whole. In the 19th century it was exported as far afield as England and was exchanged for boats. The major plantations are located in the south of the country and guided tours are available from the city of Bellavista, home to two of the country's major Yerba producers (Selecta and Pajarito).</p>]]><p><b>Trek through Ybycuí National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Flora and fauna abounds in Ybycuí, Paraguay's most visited national park. Set in a mountainous area, this forested wildlife haven is crisscrossed by a series of streams and waterfalls. Guided treks depart from the visitor centre, which also provides visitors with information about the park's history – surprisingly, it was once home to a munitions factory.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind in San Bernardino</b></p><![CDATA[<p>San Bernardino is a peaceful holiday resort situated on Lake Ypacarai, some 47km (29 miles) from the capital. Owing to its beaches and limpid lake, it's very popular with locals during the summer months. It has a camping ground and several good eateries, which celebrate the town's surprising culinary diversity. The Café Frances is a must for <em>merienda</em> (tea).</p>]]><p><b>Venture into the remote Chaco</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Witness the famous Chaco, a vast, sparsely populated area consisting mainly of empty plains and forests which covers 61% of the country's total surface. It is home to major national parks including the Defensores del Chaco, Tifunque, Enciso and Cerro Cora. It is a bird watchers paradise and if you are lucky Jaguars can also be spotted at night.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the ‘seaside’ in landlocked Paraguay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Paraguay may be landlocked but the Paraná River is so wide at San Cosme y Damián that it gives the impression you have reached the coast. Impressive sand dunes along the banks of the river are a must-see and so are the Jesuit ruins in the town, which makes the perfect stop off for those travelling between Asunción and Encarnación.</p>]]><p><b>Zip line through Eco Reserva Mbatoví</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located a short drive from Asunción, this wildlife reserve specialises in adventure activities to get the adrenalin pumping. Safely tied to a security rope, visitors clamber through the forests canopy, before zip-lining down to earth. There are also guided walks for those who like to keep their feet on the ground.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$29.6 billion (2013).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Electricity, soybeans, cotton, meat, leather and timber.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, machinery, road vehicles, tobacco and consumer goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan, Brazil, Argentina, Russia and Uruguay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Paraguay's agriculture plays an important part in its economy, supplying one-quarter of GNP and almost all the country's export earnings. Production of Paraguay's principal cash crops, cotton and soya, expanded rapidly during the late 1980s and continues to grow annually. Other crops such as sugar cane, maize and wheat are also grown on a commercial scale.</p>
<p>Paraguay is one of the world&rsquo;s major beef exporters, ahead of neighbouring Argentina. Most cattle ranches are located in the remote Chaco region and mainly export to Chile, Brazil and Russia. <br />
<br />
Hydroelectric projects, undertaken jointly with Brazil and including the world's largest hydroelectric dam at Itaipu, have made Paraguay self-sufficient in energy.<br />
<br />
Despite the global recession, the economy is booming in Paraguay and unemployment is down to 6.3% (2012). Paraguay is a member of the 11-strong Latin American Integration Association (ALADI), which seeks to promote free trade and economic development within Latin America. It is also a member of Mercosur.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For formal occasions or business affairs, men should wear lightweight suits and ties or a dinner jacket in the evening; women a lightweight two-piece suit or equivalent. Most businesspeople are able to conduct a conversation in English, but Spanish is more widely spoken. Appointments and normal business courtesies apply. Most businesses shut down between December and February for the summer.</p><p>Private sector: Mon-Fri 0800-1700, Sat 0800-1200. Public Sector: Mon-Fri 0700-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cámara Nacional de Comercio y Servicios de Paraguay</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 493 321
					Website:http://www.ccparaguay.com.py
					Address: Asunción,Estrella 540-550,,]]><b>British Paraguayan Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 498 274
					Website:
					Address: Asunción,Gral Diaz 521,Edificio Internacional Faro,2nd Floor, Office 2A,,]]><b>Rediex (Ministry of Industry and Commerce)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 665 112
					Website:http://www.rediex.gov.py/
					Address: Asunción,Avenida López 3333,Villa Morra,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The restaurant scene in Asunción has boomed in recent years with a wide selection of new eateries and different cuisines. Food is generally of a good quality, particularly when traditional Paraguayan food is on the menu. Places advertising an 'international menu' such as hotel restaurants will have a wide grilled meat selection of varying standards. There is also an excellent selection of river fish, including surubí, a fish the size of a child which makes a mean stew.</p><p>Paraguayan beef is excellent and a variety of cuts are available; the bife de chorizo and tapa cuadril are some of the more popular cuts. The large Korean community in Paraguay means there is an abundance of authentic Korean food in Asunción. Pizzerias are everywhere, too, and the availability of Mexican food is on the rise.</p><p>The sub-tropical climate offers a wide range of seasonal fruits. One fruit widely available to this area of South America is the Pomelo, a large citrus fruit with a sweet grapefruit-like taste – it is usually available from May to August.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull;&nbsp;<em>Chipa</em> (maize bread flavoured with egg and cheese)<br />
&bull;&nbsp;<em>Sopa paraguaya</em> (not a soup but a savoury mixture of mashed corn, cheese, milk and onions)<br />
&bull;&nbsp;<em>Chipa Guaz&uacute;</em> (similar to Sopa paraguaya but with sweetcorn added and often prepared without onions)<br />
&bull; <em>Soyo</em> (a hearty soup of cornmeal and ground beef seasoned with fresh oregano, bay leaves and garlic).<br />
&bull;&nbsp;<em>Bor&iacute; Bor&iacute; con pollo</em> (a chicken soup used to ward off colds, the bori are small balls of maize and cheese)<br />
&bull;&nbsp;<em>Mbej&uacute;</em> (starch and cheese fried together)<br />
&bull;&nbsp;<em>Payagua Mascada</em> (A fried snack containing ground beef, garlic, onion and breadcrumbs)<br />
&bull;&nbsp;<em>Akangue Yvyguy </em>(slow-cooked cow&rsquo;s head with herbs and spices)<br />
&bull;&nbsp;<em>Surub&iacute;</em> (a fish found in the Paran&aacute; that is usually grilled, stewed or breaded)<br />
&bull; <em>Lomitos</em> (similar to a hamburger, but with filet mignon rather than processed meat)<br />
&bull; <em>Milanesas</em> (breaded meat fillet)</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are no strict licensing hours and alcohol is widely available.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is recommended, a service charge is rarely included in the bill unless in large groups</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>20</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Asunción, there are numerous bars, casinos and nightclubs offering a different ambience depending on what you are looking for. The most popular traditional music styles in Paraguay are polcas and guaranías, which have slow and romantic rhythms and which are used as serenades – the polca is often played to signal the end of a party or closing time in a nightclub.</p><p>However, a medley of music can be found on an average night out. DJs spin between western pop hits and reggae via Brazilian sertinajo and 80s rock. The best areas in Asunción for bars and clubs are the Villamorra and Carmelitas suburbs, which are about 20 minutes outside the city centre.</p><p>For a totally different experience head to Checho's La Mega, San Martin 1115 c/ Augustin Barrios, Asunción (+595 981 928 650) on a Friday night when beers are sold for mere pence (cents). The cheap prices have made this discotheque the biggest single vendor of beer in Latin America.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several modern shopping centres in the capital and surrounding towns which aren't particularly Paraguayan, but are air-conditioned – a blessing on hot days. A popular shopping street in Asunción is Calle Palma, where you can haggle with street hawkers. Special purchases include ñandutí lace, made by the women of Itagua, leather goods, wood handicrafts, silver yerba maté cups and native jewellery. There are often stalls in the main plazas in Asunción, especially the Plaza de la Democracia.</p><p>For an authentic Paraguayan experience head south of the Asunción city centre to the Mercado 4. Made famous by the film 7 Boxes, the market sells anything from fresh fruit and veg to cheap electronic goods and even Korean fast food. The labyrinth of stalls make it easy to get lost for an hour or two in the hustle and bustle, if you do decided to visit only go during daylight hours and be wary of pickpockets.</p><p>The city of Luque, due north of Asunción, is renowned for its jewellery, the main thoroughfare (Av. General Aquino) is dotted with independent jewellers allowing customers to compare prices and look for a particular design. Necklaces and earrings are the local speciality.</p><p>Ciudad del Este has a reputation for cheap electronics and other products that somehow find their way from Asia or even neighbouring Brazil. The main shopping strip is awash with different goods – it is advisable to pay a bit extra buying from a shopping centre than on the street to reduce the risk (though not entirely eliminate) of purchasing counterfeit goods.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1500-1900 and Sat 0730-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All hotels in Asunci&oacute;n are likely to be fully booked throughout the tourist season (July and August). Visitors are advised to consult a reputable travel agent for up-to-date information, or to ascertain the rates with hotels when making reservations. For further information, contact the Secretar&iacute;a Nacional de Turismo. Outside the capital, accommodation is fairly limited. <br />
<br />
Package tours to national parks in the Chaco or the waterfalls near Ciudad del Este along the Brazilian border include lodgings, but for individual travellers all accommodation must be booked in writing well in advance; details of current prices are available from the Secretar&iacute;a Nacional de Turismo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All hotels in Asunci&oacute;n are likely to be fully booked throughout the tourist season (July and August). Visitors are advised to consult a reputable travel agent for up-to-date information, or to ascertain the rates with hotels when making reservations. For further information, contact the Secretar&iacute;a Nacional de Turismo. Outside the capital, accommodation is fairly limited. <br />
<br />
Package tours to national parks in the Chaco or the waterfalls near Ciudad del Este along the Brazilian border include lodgings, but for individual travellers all accommodation must be booked in writing well in advance; details of current prices are available from the Secretar&iacute;a Nacional de Turismo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All hotels in Asunci&oacute;n are likely to be fully booked throughout the tourist season (July and August). Visitors are advised to consult a reputable travel agent for up-to-date information, or to ascertain the rates with hotels when making reservations. For further information, contact the Secretar&iacute;a Nacional de Turismo. Outside the capital, accommodation is fairly limited. <br />
<br />
Package tours to national parks in the Chaco or the waterfalls near Ciudad del Este along the Brazilian border include lodgings, but for individual travellers all accommodation must be booked in writing well in advance; details of current prices are available from the Secretar&iacute;a Nacional de Turismo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is essential. There is no British Embassy in Paraguay. The British Embassy in Buenos Aires now has overall responsibility for Paraguay and all enquiries should be directed to them at the contact details given below. British Honorary Consul in Asunci&amp;oacute;n: Dr Guillermo F Peroni; Address: Eulogio Estigarribia, 4846 C/Monse&amp;ntilde;or Bogarin, Asunci&amp;oacute;n, Paraguay; Tel: (595) (21) 210405; Fax: (595) (21) 600448; Email: &lt;a href="http://guillermo.peroni@pstbn.com.py"&gt;guillermo.peroni@pstbn.com.py&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://veronica.roa@pstbn.com.py"&gt;veronica.roa@pstbn.com.py&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated, and whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is available. Drinking water outside main cities and towns could be contaminated and sterilisation is considered essential. Milk may be unpasteurised and, if so, should be boiled. Avoid dairy products made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Heroes' Day :
							01 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							15 May </p><p>Chaco Armistice Day :
							12 June </p><p>Founding of Asunci :
							15 August </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Paraguay without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; Goods to the value of US$300 (if arriving by air or water) or US$150 (if arriving by land).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guaraní (PYG; symbol Gs). Notes are in denominations of Gs100,000, 50,000, 20,000, 10,000, 5,000 and 1,000. Coins are in denominations of Gs500, 100, 50, 10 and 5.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Paraguay maintains a free monetary exchange policy and the purchase and sale of foreign currencies is not subject to any controls or regulations. US Dollars, which are more easily negotiable than Pounds Sterling, are widely accepted throughout the country. Travellers are advised to use an official bureau de change and not deal with people offering services on the street as false banknotes are common.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted (though not in smaller hotels), while Diners Club has more limited use. ID is required, such as a passport, when making a purchase with a credit card. ATMs are widespread; many accept Cirrus, Maestro and Visa cards.</p><p>ATMs are widespread; many accept Cirrus, Maestro and Visa cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar traveller's cheques are not widely used in Paraguay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0845-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Paraguay, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: &pound;43; multiple-entry visa: &pound;67.</p>
<p>Single-entry visa on arrival: &pound;93 for Australians, &pound;52 for Canadians and &pound;110 for US nationals.</p>
<p>Multiple-entry visa on arrival: &pound;93 for Australians, &pound;103 for Canadians and &pound;110 for US nationals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>90 days from the date of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). On arrival at the airport for Australian, Canadian and US citizens.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Two to three days. Processing may take up to 30 days for some nationalities however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend your initial 90-day stay by another 90 days. You can't stay in Paraguay for more than 180 days in a 12-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-23.244014]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-58.393991]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>406,752 sq km (157,048 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6,725,430 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>16.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Asunci&oacute;n.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Paraguay is a landlocked country surrounded by Argentina, Bolivia and Brazil, lying some 1,440km (900 miles) up the River Paran&aacute; from the Atlantic. The River Paraguay, a tributary of the Paran&aacute;, divides the country into two sharply contrasting regions. The Oriental zone, which covers 159,800 sq km (61,700 sq miles), consists of undulating country intersected by chains of hills rising to about 600m (2,000ft), merging into the Mato Grosso Plateau in the north; the Paran&aacute; crosses the area in the east and south.</p>
<p>East and southeast of Asunci&oacute;n lie the oldest centres of settlement inhabited by the greater part of the population. This area is bordered to the west by rolling pastures, and to the south by thick primeval forests. The Occidental zone, or Paraguayan Chaco, covers 246,827 sq km (95,300 sq miles). It is a flat alluvial plain, composed mainly of grey clay, which is marked by large areas of permanent swamp in the southern and eastern regions. Apart from a few small settlements, it is sparsely populated.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>89.6% Roman Catholic, 6.2% Protestant.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is the usual form of greeting. Smoking is not allowed in cinemas and theatres. Dress tends to be informal and sportswear is popular.<br /><br /><strong>Photography: </strong>Avoid sensitive subjects such as military installations.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Mario Abdo Ben&iacute;tez&nbsp;since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like much of South America, the territory of present day Paraguay was once a stomping ground for semi-nomadic indigenous tribes, who jostled for space and resources in the region for thousands of years. And then came the Spanish, who built Asunci&oacute;n in 1537 and established an overseas province called Paraguay.</p>
<p>What follows is a familiar tale of European colonialism &ndash; enslavement of indigenous people, forced Christianity &ndash; which ended when the Paraguayan people overthrew the Spanish administration and declared independent in 1811.</p>
<p>Dictatorships followed, starting with Paraguay&rsquo;s first leader, Jos&eacute; Gaspar Rodr&iacute;guez de Francia. Despite ruling with an iron fist, he allowed the country to prosper economically and socially, a legacy that continued with his successor Carlos Antonio L&oacute;pez.</p>
<p>And then there was a war. Dubbed <a href="http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic/442711/War-of-the-Triple-Alliance" target="_blank">the War of the Triple Alliance</a> (1865-1870), this bloody conflict engaged <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/argentina">Argentina</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brazil">Brazil</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/uruguay">Uruguay</a> and Paraguay, and saw the latter lose two thirds of its male population and vast swathes of land. The country was in ruins.</p>
<p>Paraguay barely had time to recover before it was engaged in another conflict, known as the Chaco War (1932-1935). Fought with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bolivia">Bolivia</a>, Paraguay avoided territorial losses but some 30,000 of its men died in battle.</p>
<p>WWII and a brief civil war followed before another dictator, Alfredo Stroessner, took power in 1954. Stroessner promised &lsquo;peace and progress,&rsquo; but delivered corruption and nepotism; while the military earned fortunes from bootlegging and drug-trafficking, his Colorado Party handed out public sector jobs to friends and family, and tortured political opponents.</p>
<p>The Colorado Party continued its autocratic rule until 1993 when it held what is widely regarded as the first democratic election in Paraguayan history. Jaun Carlos Wasmosy Monti, of the Colorado Party, won the presidency which was marred by controversy &ndash; he was sentenced to four years in prison for defrauding the Paraguayan state in 2004. His successors fared little better.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Then came Roman Catholic bishop, Fernando Lugo, who won the 2008 presidential elections and brought an end to 61 years of Colorado Party rule. Lugo formed the centre-left Patriotic Alliance for Change and put land reforms and corruption at the heart of his manifesto.</p>
<p>However, <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/southamerica/paraguay/9352449/Paraguays-ousted-leader-Fernando-Lugo-denounces-coup.html" target="_blank">in 2012 Lugo was removed from office in what critics described as a coup d&rsquo;&eacute;tat</a>. The following year the Colorado Party returned to power and tobacco billionaire, Horacio Cartes, was appointed president. Like many before him, Cartes has pledged to fight corruption and tackle poverty, which afflicts some 30% of the population.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; Paraguay gained independence from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a> in 1811, but its first democratic elections didn&rsquo;t come until 1993.<br />
&bull; The vaunted Paraguayan novelist poetically described his nation as &ldquo;an island surrounded on all sides by land.&rdquo;<br />
&bull; Paraguay is one of the few South American countries to have retained its mother tongue (Guarani) as an official language.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Paraguay in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 483 6960.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embaparusa.gov.py</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 483 6960.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2400 Massachusetts Avenue NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Paraguay in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7610 4180.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.paraguayembassy.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7610 4180.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1630 (consular section, Mon-Fri 1000-1500).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Third Floor, 344 Kensington High Street<br/>London<br/>W14 8NS<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Paraguay]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(21) 328 5507.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/paraguay</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(21) 328 5507.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Av. Mariscal López y Cruz del Chaco<br/>Edificio Citicenter, Piso 5<br/>Asunción<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s a saying in Paraguay that people who visit always cry twice &ndash; once when they arrive and once when they leave. And you can see why emotions might run high in this lesser-travelled South American nation, whose beautiful, beguiling and baffling character is made all the more alluring by its relative obscurity.</p>
<p>After years in the wilderness &ndash; Paraguay has long been politically as well as geographically isolated &ndash; the country is gradually opening up to the outside world. Its tourism infrastructure remains undeveloped, but patient and pioneering travellers are rewarded for their endeavours.</p>
<p>Boasting an intoxicating blend of crumbling colonial cities, exotic natural wonders and indigenous tribes, visitors to Paraguay can also expect a warm welcome from the locals, who are unerringly polite, interested in outsiders and liberal with their dinner invitations (expect football chat to be on the menu).</p>
<p>Most travellers begin their Paraguayan adventure in the capital, Asuncion. A charming, colonial city, it&rsquo;s one of South America&rsquo;s more endearing capitals and is blessed with neoclassical fa&ccedil;ades, pretty piazzas and tree-lined boulevards.</p>
<p>It is also a place of contradictions; expensive sports cars whizz along crumbling cobbled streets, while traditional street vendors ply their trade in the shadows of modern shopping malls. Inequality is hard to ignore.</p>
<p>Outside the capital, Paraguay&rsquo;s true beauty is revealed. The east is characterised by sweeping savannahs and dense forests, which are peppered with sleepy colonial towns barely changed since the turn of the 20th century.</p>
<p>Crumbling Jesuit missions and yerba mat&eacute; plantations can be found in the southeast corner, while the largely unexplored northern region is blanketed by steamy marshes, shimmering lagoons and dense rainforests, which harbour exotic species such as the elusive puma.</p>
<p>And then there&rsquo;s the wild, western region of Chaco; one of South America's great wilderness areas, it is home for many of Paraguay&rsquo;s indigenous people, who live largely traditional lives amongst a myriad of spectacular flora and fauna.</p><p>Paraguay is a little-known landlocked country, which has found itself somewhat isolated from even its neighbours in the past by geography and politics, but is full of pretty colonial towns and untamed wilderness.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
