<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Peru" ColCode="per" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="pe" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Peru]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The weather in Peru varies according to area &ndash; the changes in altitude are so extreme that the climate goes from freezing snow in the mountains to boiling sun on the coast. Likewise, the coast covers such a large stretch of longitude that the temperature changes dramatically as you head further south.</p>
<p>On the coast winter lasts from June to September. The weather tends to be overcast and slightly damp at this time, but rarely very cold. It hardly ever rains in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lima">Lima</a> nor most of the coast, except for Tumbes and Piura, which have tropical climates.</p>
<p>During June to September, the mountainous areas are often sunny during the day but cold at night. This is high tourist season and the best time to visit most regions. Rainy season in the Andes starts in September and peaks between January and March, and this is a dreadful and occasionally dangerous time to be hiking.</p>
<p>Heavy rains in the mountains and jungle last from December to April. It is rainy and hot for most of the year, but between March and September there are occasional cold surges which might require a jumper.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For travel in Peru, a variety of clothes are necessary. You will need very lightweight clothes for summer on the coast, and thermals, hats, gloves and ski jackets for winter up in the mountains. It can become freezing at night at altitude and remain hot and sticky through the nights in the jungle. Waterproof clothing is thoroughly recommended for the rainy season, because the heavens open very suddenly, and then it pours.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>If you are travelling to the jungle you&rsquo;ll need something protective and waterproof for your feet. For any mountain hiking you&rsquo;ll need proper, supportive boots. If you&rsquo;re spending time along the coast you&rsquo;ll need sandals or flip-flops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>LA &nbsp;(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.lan.com">www.lan.com</a>), Avianca (<a href="http://www.avianca.com" target="_blank">www.avianca.com</a>)&nbsp;and LC Per&uacute; (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.lcperu.pe">www.lcperu.pe</a>) handle virtually all domestic air traffic. Routes link Lima to Andahuaylas, Arequipa, Ayacucho, Cajamarca, Chiclayo, Cusco, Hu&aacute;nuco, Iquitos, Juliaca-Puno, Piura, Pucallpa, Puerto Maldonado, Tacna, Tarapoto, Trujillo, Tumbes and other cities. Flights to Huaraz are occasionally offered. For information on internal flights, contact the Peruvian Corporation of Airports (Corpac) (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.corpac.gob.pe">www.corpac.gob.pe</a>).</p>
<p>When travelling around Peru, you have to make a decision: time or money? The bus from Lima to Cusco can take over 24 hours instead of a flight of about 1 hour 30 minutes, but it will be a fraction of the price. If taking a shorter trip to Peru, flights will leave you a lot more time at your destination.</p>
<p>You can book in advance from outside the country, or a few days in advance through local tour operators for not much more money. Some flights (of lower prices, and particularly with LAN) are for Peruvians only &ndash; if you purchase them be prepared to pay a fine.</p><p>Domestic flight schedules are often subject to last minute change &ndash; try to confirm that your flight is leaving at the time stated on your ticket before you head to the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transportation is available between Pucallpa and Iquitos (journey time - 4 to 7 days), Yurimaguas and Iquitos (journey time - 2 to 3 days) and from Iquitos to the border with Brazil and Colombia (journey time - 2 to 3 days). However, river travel can be long and uncomfortable and apart from main routes, service is sporadic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Peru Rail (tel: +51 84 581 414; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.perurail.com">www.perurail.com</a>) runs comfortable tourist trains between Puno and Cusco and between Cusco and Machu Picchu. Ferrocarril Central Andino (tel: +51 1226 6363;&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ferrocarrilcentral.com.pe">www.ferrocarrilcentral.com.pe</a>) runs a twice-monthly tourist service on renovated trains between Lima and Hu&aacute;ncayo (April to November only). This spectacular route is the second highest railway in the world (the highest being in Tibet).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Main roads in Peru are, at least, reasonably paved; others can range from extraordinarily bumpy to impassable after landslides. Landslides are frequent in the mountains during the rainy season (December to March), making for slow travel and closed roads. Take care driving on the mountain roads, which are narrow, windy and above all high up. Local drivers who know the roads well go like the clappers, but if you try it you may well go off a cliff.</p>r<p>Many mountain roads are unpaved, and almost all are badly potholed. Landslides are frequent in the mountains during the rainy season (December to March), making for slow travel.</p><p>Taking the bus is the travel method of choice in Peru; buses go in almost every direction. You can book yourself onto everything from a bus with seats that recline until fully horizontal and hostesses to bring you dinner, to a squashed-in place in the back of a pick-up truck, depending on your budget.</p>
<p>The cr&egrave;me de la cr&egrave;me of coach companies in Peru is Cruz del Sur (tel: +51 ) 311 5050; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.cruzdelsur.com.pe">www.cruzdelsur.com.pe</a>). It&rsquo;s the most expensive, but you get a nice meal and a good night&rsquo;s sleep. Other coach companies are Flores (tel: +51 1 332 1212; <a href="http://www.floreshnos.pe" target="_blank">www.floreshnos.pe</a>), Linea (tel: +51 1 424 0836; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.transporteslinea.com.pe">www.transporteslinea.com.pe</a>) and MovilTours (tel: +51 1 716 8000; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.moviltours.com.pe">www.moviltours.com.pe</a>). Otherwise just turn up at a bus station or ask around.</p><p>Many unlicensed taxi companies operate in Peru and visitors are advised to avoid these. They usually have a red and white taxi sign on the windscreen. Licensed yellow taxis are the only cabs allowed in downtown Lima. Taxis do not have meters and you should agree fares before departure (they are relatively inexpensive).</p>
<p>Extensive and safe taxi services are available by telephone in main cities. Hotels and hostels can book them for you. Taxi fares increase by 35 to 50% after midnight and on holidays. Drivers do not expect tips.</p><p>You can drive for six months on a national driving licence and up to a year on an <a href="http://www.theaa.com/driving-advice/driving-abroad/idp" target="_blank">International Driving Licence</a>. After that, you need a Peruvian licence. You can obtain permits in Peru through the Touring y Autom&oacute;vil Club del Per&uacute; (<a href="http://www.touringperu.com.pe/" target="_blank">www.touringperu.com.pe</a>). All foreign vehicles must have documentation from their own national automobile association or you can obtain it on the Peruvian border before entering the country. Always carry your driving licence, a copy of your passport and, if the vehicle is hired, a copy of the rental contract.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Seatbelts should be worn both in the front and back of a car, and also on coaches (though most people don&rsquo;t bother).&nbsp;</p>
<p>Theoretically, the speed limit is 100kph (62mph) on highways, 80kph (50mph) on other major roads and 30-60kph (19-37mph) in built-up areas. No one in Peru follows this though, driving as fast as possible. <br />
&nbsp;</p><p>There is no countrywide emergency breakdown number. Ensure that your car hire agreement includes towing services if you break down.</p><p>International firms have offices in all the major cities and bigger airports. You must be at least 25 to hire a car in Peru, and need to present your passport, national driving licence, credit card as a guarantee, and sometimes a cash deposit.</p><p>Cycling around Peru is only for the foolhardy or extremely experienced. The coastal paths are the most manageable, but they are still rarely of good quality and cover immense distances often with no facilities en route &ndash; not good if you break down. Due to road quality, other traffic and altitude, the mountains can be dangerous to cycle in.</p>
<p>If you must cycle around Peru, then you can only hire bikes of a good quality in the big towns: Lima, Huaraz and Cusco. Bringing your own bike (and repair kit) is a better option.</p>
<p>Motorbike: Motorbiking in Peru is only for enthusiasts, rather than the casual rider who thinks it looks cool. It&rsquo;s expensive to fly your bike out there, and not always straightforward to cross borders with them. It is very much a community-based form of transport, so check out <a href="http://advrider.com/forums" target="_blank">http://advrider.com/forums</a> to search for advice on where to buy bikes and recommended routes to take.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Seatbelts should be worn both in the front and back of a car, and also on coaches (though most people don&rsquo;t bother).&nbsp;</p>
<p>Theoretically, the speed limit is 100kph (62mph) on highways, 80kph (50mph) on other major roads and 30-60kph (19-37mph) in built-up areas. No one in Peru follows this though, driving as fast as possible. <br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public transport in Lima is provided by conventional buses and by minibuses (<em>combis</em>), though they are overcrowded, sometimes dangerous and not particularly useful for tourists. These operate from 0600 to 0000 on established routes; wherever possible, try to avoid using bus travel late at night. Lima also has a small, efficient metro system.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Peru</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">tumbes</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">18.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Peru</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">puno_juliaca</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30*</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">24.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Peru</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cusco</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">30.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Peru</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">arequipa</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.25</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">14.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The principal international airline in Peru is LATAM (<a href="http://www.latam.com" target="_blank">www.latam.com</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/peru/jorge-chavez-lima-callao-international-airport">Lima Jorge Chavez International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lima">Lima</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 12 hours 30 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 8 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Lima Jorge Chávez International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.lap.com.pe<p>Lima Jorge Chávez International Airport is situated 16km (10 miles) northwest of Lima.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+51 1 517 3100.</p>]]><b>Cusco Alejandro Velasco Astete International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>Situated 4km (2.5 miles) south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cusco">Cusco</a> city centre, Alejandro Velasco Astete International Airport is a nucleus in the South American travel network and caters to thousands of travellers every week.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(84) 222 611/01</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Callao and San Mart&iacute;n. Some international cruises occasionally call at Callao and Salaverry (Trujillo). Iquitos is the main river port and the major water route between Peru and Brazil, for travel through the Amazon Basin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Revived in 2016 after four years out of service, the only international rail service in Peru links the towns of Tacna in southern Peru and Arica, just over the border in northern Chile. The train makes daily journeys and takes approximately 90 minutes. Taking a <em>collectivo</em> (shared taxis which leave regularly from the bus station) is quicker and more flexible.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Panamerican Highway and two other main roads located further inland run from the north to the south of the country. There are buses from every town or city in the neighbouring countries which take you across or to borders, from where you can catch another at the other side.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Telephone cards are available in the main cities from stands and supermarkets. The best and cheapest way to call home is to find an internet café that offers internet-based calls. You'll find them all over the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies, but making calls from an international phone will be very expensive. You can rent mobile phones in Lima and the main cities, or buy Peruvian SIM cards; the company Claro is best for international calls and texts, and Movistar is good for local calls. Remember to get your phone unlocked to accommodate a foreign SIM. Coverage is sporadic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public internet booths and internet cafés are widely available in cities and most towns. Wi-Fi is becoming increasingly common in cafés, restaurants and hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Privately run broadcasters and newspapers dominate the Peruvian media scene, with the state-run media having relatively small audiences. The airwaves of Lima are home to dozens of radio stations and several TV channels. Many radio stations and regional newspapers are available beyond the capital. Almost all hotels have TVs in the rooms (they seem to be considered just as important as hot water) and you can usually find an English-speaking channel. Morning daily newspapers include <em>El Comercio</em> and <em>La Rep&uacute;blica</em>. British newspapers are not widely available but you can find them in the big cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe and the USA takes up to one week. Postal facilities are limited outside Lima. First-class airmail from Europe or North America addressed to PO boxes in Peru usually takes only a few days, but may be subject to delay. The main post office (Correo Central de Lima) is near the Plaza de Armas.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-2000; Sat 0900-1330.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Arequipa-Colca Canyon (Cañon del Colca-Arequipa)</p><![CDATA[<p>At a depth of more than 3,400m (11,333ft), the Colca Canyon is almost twice as deep as the Grand Canyon. The valley towns, such as Yanque and Chivay, which have maintained their original appearance for almost 400 years, and the many pre-Inca tombs and ruins in the area, are also worth visiting.</p>]]><br/><p>Lake Titicaca</p><![CDATA[<p>Take a cruise on Lake Titicaca, the highest commercially navigable lake in the world, which straddles the Bolivia-Peru border. Covering 8,379 sq km (3,235 sq miles), Lake Titicaca is surrounded by ancient ruins and the enormous freshwater lake is home to several small island communities, including the Uros islands made entirely from reeds.</p>]]><br/><p>Machu Picchu</p><![CDATA[<p>Ascend to Peru's top attraction, the awe-inspiring Inca city of Machu Picchu, perched atop a remote mountain northwest of Cusco. This World Heritage site, rediscovered in 1911, is arguably the most important archaeological site in South America, not to mention the most dramatically located.</p>]]><br/><p>Manu National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Delve into Manu National Park, Peru's greatest treasure in biodiversity. Covering 20,000 sq km (7,722 sq miles) of tropical rainforest, this World Natural Heritage Site is home to around 2,000 plant species, 1,200 butterfly species, 800 bird types and 200 different mammals, including monkeys, tapirs, sloth, jaguar and capybaras.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask in the year-round sunshine of Arequipa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This beautiful colonial city is the gateway to Colca Canyon and is renowned for its year-round sunshine. Explore the peaceful cloisters of the Monastery of Santa Catalina, where, for hundreds of years, nuns lived their entire lives; and visit the Museo Santuarios Andinos to see Juanita, a perfectly preserved mummy of a sacrificial Inca girl.</p>]]><p><b>Be Awed by the adobe city of Chan Chan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You can discover more archaeological treasures, at the UNESCO-protected site of Chan Chan. Home to the ancient Chimu culture, Chan Chan was the biggest pre-Columbian city in South America. The adobe city has been excavated along with its nearby <em>huacas</em> (pyramid temples) of the sun and the moon. The beautifully restored Huaca Arco Iris is covered with pre-Inca hieroglyphics.</p>]]><p><b>Be puzzled by the mysterious Nazca Lines</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a flight over the ancient Nazca Lines, vast and spectacular geoglyphs etched into the desert floor 420km (265 miles) south of Lima. The most notable designs represent animals, including birds, felines and reptiles. How they were made or why remains a mystery, but the enigmatic lines date back to between 500BC and AD500.</p>]]><p><b>Bone up on the history of Iglesia San Francisco</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See one of the few buildings to withstand Lima's 1746 earthquake, the UNESCO-listed Iglesia San Francisco. Inside visitors can gawp at an extraordinary domed roof, a vast library and masterpieces attributed to the schools of Zurburán, Rubens and Van Dyck. Oh and did we mention the eerie catacombs, which are adorned with the bones of some 25,000 souls?</p>]]><p><b>Chill in Huacachina</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This palm-fringed oasis in the southern desert near Ica, surrounded by pristine sand dunes, is a place for relaxation and fun. As well as a laidback nightlife, Huachina offers dune buggying and sand boarding, and is great for either a day trip or to chill out for a few days.</p>]]><p><b>Crack the mysteries of Caral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spread across the desert to the north of Lima are the remains of the 5,000-year-old city of Caral, deemed the most ancient city in the Americas. Consisting of a complex of pyramids and sunken plazas dating back to 2500 BC, Caral was discovered in 1994 and has opened to visitors following years of excavation.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise sky-high Lake Titicaca</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a cruise on Lake Titicaca, the highest commercially navigable lake in the world, straddling the Bolivia-Peru border. Covering 8,379sq km (3,235sq miles), Lake Titicaca is surrounded by ancient ruins and is home to several small island communities, including the Uros islands, made from reeds.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Lima's colonial centre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Trawl through five centuries of colonial history in the Peruvian capital, admiring its handsome plazas and opulent mansions with Moorish-style latticed wooden balconies. The main square, Plaza de Armas, is home to the impressive 18th-century cathedral and the lavish Government Palace. The centre has been spruced up and the paved Jirón de la Unión is lined with lively street cafes.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Cusco, ‘Navel of the Universe’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't miss a trip to the capital of the Inca Empire, Cusco. This World Heritage Site, founded in AD1100, is a fascinating mix of Inca temples and colonial Spanish palaces and churches. Narrow cobblestone alleyways are flanked with original Inca stonework, beautifully constructed by hand to withstand centuries of volcanic activity.</p>]]><p><b>Gaze in awe at mountaintop Machu Picchu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whether it's your reward at the end of the Inca Trail, or via a comfy train ride through the Andes, you cannot fail to be overawed by Peru's top attraction: the Inca city of Machu Picchu, perched atop a remote mountain northwest of Cusco. This World Heritage Site, rediscovered in 1911, is arguably the most important archaeological site in South America, and the most dramatically located.</p>]]><p><b>Get drenched at Carnival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go to Cajamarca's Carnival, which is famous throughout Peru for its annual celebrations that last for an entire month. One word of warning – the traditional Cajamarca Carnival greeting is to be soaked with water so look out for cheeky children flinging water balloons. Other special attractions include ancient Inca remains, hot springs and weird rock formations in the surrounding mountains.</p>]]><p><b>Greet the Sun God at Sacsayhuamán</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you're looking for impressive Inca ruins, the massive stone fortress of Sacsayhuamán is a great place to explore. Overlooking the city, this is the most impressive of Cusco's four neighbouring Inca sites (the others are Puca Pucara, Qenko and Tambo Machay). On 24 June, thousands gather here to celebrate Inti Raymi, a festival for the Inca sun god.</p>]]><p><b>Haggle for handicrafts in Ayacucho</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Apart from its famous 33 colonial churches, the Andean city of Ayacucho is also well known for its handicrafts. You can browse here for traditional crafts such as pottery, leatherwork, textiles and jewellery. Other places to scout for high-quality souvenirs include Cajamarca, in northern Peru, or the colourful daily market in Lima's Chinatown district.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the Inca Trail</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Puff your way around one of the world's most famous mountain treks, the (literally) breath-taking Inca Trail to Machu Picchu, the mountaintop city. This ancient trail passes snow-capped mountains, cloud forest and a string of Inca ceremonial centres, including Phuyupatamarca and Wiñay Wayna. Only recognised tour operators can purchase permits to the Inca Trail, with 500 available per day.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the hiking trails</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From the mountain-based city of Huaraz, you can head off on world-famous hiking routes. You can also get stuck into some extreme sports such as white-water rafting and ice climbing, or for those with gentler tastes, go on a nature trail to view the Puya Raimondi, the world's biggest bromeliad.</p>]]><p><b>Immerse yourself in nature in Manu National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Peru's greatest treasure in biodiversity, Manu National Park covers 20,000sq km (7,722sq miles) of tropical rainforest. This World Natural Heritage Site in southeastern Peru is home to around 2,000 plant species, 1,200 butterfly species, 800 bird types and 200 different mammals, including monkeys, tapirs, sloth, jaguar and capybaras. Eco-tour packages available range from no-frills to boutique luxury.</p>]]><p><b>Look out for condors</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Overlooking the Colca Canyon, one of the deepest gorges in the Americas, is the Cruz del Condor viewpoint. From here you can spot condors majestically soaring up from the valley below on morning thermals. You can reach the canyon from Arequipa via either a tour group excursion or a long, bumpy ride on public transport through stunning Andean scenery.</p>]]><p><b>Plunge into Colca Canyon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At a depth of more than 3,400m (11,333ft), the Colca Canyon is almost twice as deep as the Grand Canyon. Villages, such as Yanque and Chivay, which have hardly changed for centuries, and the many pre-Inca tombs, ruins, and hot springs in the area, are also worth visiting.</p>]]><p><b>Tackle the Cordillera Blanca</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The extraordinarily beautiful Cordillera Blanca trail is a 180km-long  (113 mile) paradise of snow-capped mountains, glaciers, emerald-green lakes and archaeological sites, containing a wide variety of flora and fauna. This awesome mountain range contains some of the highest peaks in the Andes, including Huascarán, at 6,768m (22,205ft), the tallest in Peru.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$189.1 billion (World Bank 2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Copper, gold, zinc, petroleum, tin, anchovies, coffee and table grapes.<strong> </strong></p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum and petroleum products, plastics, machinery, chemicals, vehicles, TV sets and telephones.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, China, Brazil, Mexico, Chile, and Colombia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Peruvian economy is divided into two distinct parts: a relatively modern industrial and service economy concentrated on the coastal plain, and a subsistence agricultural economy in the interior. Inevitably, one consequence has been huge migration from the interior to the coastal cities. Most foreign investment is directed towards Peru's major industry, mining, which accounts for about half of export earnings. Meanwhile, tourism has snowballed and now accounts for more than 4% of Peru's gross domestic product (GDP), helping to generate nearly 1.4 million jobs for the country, directly and indirectly.
</p>
<p>During the early to mid 1990s, Peru implemented important market-oriented reforms, including privatisation of key industries, trade deregulation and measures to attract foreign investment. The strategy was reasonably successful, and the country's economy is relatively stable. The unemployment rate was 7.6% in Lima in 2009, but it is estimated that up to 40% of the general workforce are underemployed. Peru's annual growth was estimated to be 9% in 2010. The inflation rate was 2% in 2009. The passing of Free Trade Agreements with the USA in 2009 and China in 2010 is expected to spur considerable growth in the next decade. Peru&rsquo;s trade agreement with the EU should be established in 2012, and negotiations with the East Asian countries are ongoing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like most South Americans, Peruvians have a very relaxed approach to time; both business and social meetings regularly start half an hour late. However, you should always be on time, regardless.</p>
<p>Breakfast and brunch business meetings are common but lunch remains an important way to entertain contacts.</p>
<p>Latin Americans take care over their clothes and overall appearance, and those doing business in Peru are advised to do the same. Politeness is very important and greetings in particular should not be rushed. Men shake hands, while women or men meeting other women often greet each other with a kiss. Business cards are usually exchanged before meetings.</p>
<p>A business trip that spans several days is likely to include an invitation for drinks or dinner at the house of a colleague. As a mark of respect, Peruvian colleagues should be addressed as <em>usted</em> (the polite form of <em>t&uacute;</em>) unless they indicate otherwise. Although the majority speak Spanish, many businesspeople speak some English. The main holiday period is January to March.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0900-1800 with a two-hour lunch break.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cámara de Comercio de Lima</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01) 463 3434
					Website:http://www.camaralima.org.pe
					Address: Jesus Maria,Avenida Gregorio Escobedo 396,Lima 11,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The hot and spicy nature of Peruvian food, created by <em>ajo</em> and <em>ají </em>(garlic and hot pepper), has become celebrated at home and abroad. However, there are plenty of non-spicy dishes going, so you'll be able to find something if you can't handle the heat.</p><p>Helped by the country's broad range of tropical and Andean landscapes, Peruvians enjoy a wide variety of fruit and vegetables – there are over 2,000 kinds of indigenous and cultivated potatoes alone.</p><p>For a traveller, the <em>menú del día</em> (menu of the day) is a good way to experience local foods at low prices, but brace yourself for lots of carbs and exotic meats, including <em>cuy</em> (guinea pig) and even fried ants. While you're at the coastal regions, take advantage of the cheap, delicious and varied fruits available from the markets.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ceviche:</strong> Raw fish marinated in lemon or lime juice, onions and hot chillies.<br />
<strong>Cuy:</strong> Roasted guinea pig, served whole, with yucca and potatoes.<br />
<strong>Causa relle&ntilde;a:</strong> Potato cakes stuffed with a range of fillings, including chicken, avocado or crabmeat.<br />
<strong>Tamales:</strong> Boiled corn dumplings filled with meat and wrapped in a banana leaf.<br />
<strong>Mazamorra morada:</strong> A dessert made with purple maize and sweet potato starch jelly cooked with lemons, dried fruits, cinnamon and cloves.<br />
<strong>Salchipapas:</strong> A sausage-and-chips fast-food snack. particularly popular in Chiclayo.<br />
<strong>Papas a la huanca&iacute;na:</strong> Sliced potatoes served on lettuce with a slightly spicy cheese sauce, and either a piece of hard-boiled egg or olives.<br />
<strong>Pollo a la brasa:</strong> Chargrilled chicken, served with chips and salad with sauces.<br />
<strong>Chicharrones:</strong> Salted pork fried in its own fat., a popular roadside snack.<br />
<strong>Pisco:</strong> The national spirit, a clear brandy distilled from grapes.<br />
<strong>Pisco sour:</strong> Peru&rsquo;s most popular cocktail, a bittersweet pisco-based drink made with lime juice, egg white and sugar.<br />
<strong>Chicha de jora:</strong> A potent maize beer popular in the Andes.<br />
<strong>Chicha morada:</strong> A non-alcoholic purple corn juice that dates back to Inca times and tastes like cold mulled wine.<br />
<strong>Inca Kola:</strong> The bottled soft drink of choice; sweet, fizzy and bright yellow.<br />
<strong>Peruvian beers</strong>: Local beers are typically light lagers include Cuzque&ntilde;a from Cusco and Arequipe&ntilde;a from Arequipa, along with Pilsen and Cristal.<br />
<strong>Peruvian wine</strong>: Traditionally quite sweet; you can visit the vineyards around Ica, on the southern coast, to try different types.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Every town has a food market, which are great places to try street food or buy ingredients for your own picnics.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Service charges of 10% are added to bills. Additional tips of 5-10% are expected in better restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nightlife is varied throughout the country. There are many good bars, pubs, discos and casinos in the major towns and tourist resorts. <em>Pe&ntilde;as</em> (clubs with traditional music and dancing) always serve snacks and some serve full meals. Here you can enjoy criolla or folk music, especially at weekends. Nightlife in Lima and Cusco has a wide array of choices, as do the beach towns of Asia and M&aacute;ncora.</p>
<p>Tourist bars set up by both locals and expats abound in the more popular traveller destinations, with happy hours. Such places usually function as caf&eacute;s during the day serving food designed to appeal to foreign taste buds, and providing free Wi-Fi. Strict dress codes and entrance prices that go as high as 50 Soles are common in upscale Lima nightspots, while in other towns standards and prices are considerably lower. Most discos, <em>pe&ntilde;as</em>, pubs and karaoke bars are open until 0300 or 0400.</p>
<p>In smaller towns and villages throughout the country you&rsquo;ll find local bars serving glasses of beer and Peruvian wine of varying qualities. Establishments that function as restaurants during the day and evening often stay open later for those wishing to stay and drink. There is a culture among the younger Peruvians to go out for <em>salchipapas</em> (sausage and chips) as an evening out or as a prelude to further entertainment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are looking for souvenirs to remind you of your trip to Peru, there are many attractive Peruvian handicrafts such as alpaca wool sweaters, alpaca and llama rugs, Indian masks, colourful weaving and silver jewellery. These are widely obtainable all over the country &ndash; they are generally cheaper in small villages but the major cities sell items of the highest quality.</p>
<p>Galleries and handicraft shops abound in Cusco and the Miraflores, Pueblo Libre and downtown districts of Lima. Big handicrafts markets in Lima are located in Miraflores (Avenida Petit Thouars, blocks 52 to 53) and Pueblo Libre (Avenida La Marina, blocks 8 to 10).</p>
<p>If you are shopping in Cusco, you&rsquo;ll find a popular handicrafts markets on Avenida El Sol, and Arequipa sells souvenirs in the streets leading from the main plaza and tiny stalls accessible from the main plaza which expand into huge areas full of things to buy as you go further in. All of these stalls expect gentle haggling, especially in the form of discounts for multiple items. When haggling, it is important not to be aggressive and not to expect massive reductions.</p>
<p>You can generally find the best deals at outdoor Andean craft markets in places such as Pisac near Cusco and the Mantaro Valley near Huancayo.</p>
<p>For more standard shopping fare such as clothes, the Miraflores district of Lima contains plenty of shops. For designer clothes and shoes at cheaper prices than you&rsquo;ll find at home, there is Lima&rsquo;s Mercado Central.</p><p>Hours vary significantly, but the standard is Mon-Sat 1000-1300 and 1600-2000.</p><p>Be very careful with what you try to take back – cultural artefacts are prohibited from being taken out of the country, as are some natural products, including feathers and animal skins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lima and Cusco have the largest choice of hotels in Peru. Other cities and areas where you can find 5- and 4-star hotels are Arequipa, Cajamarca, Chiclayo, Colca Canyon, Ica, Iquitos, Puno, the Sacred Valley and Trujillo (the grading does not always match international standards).</p>
<p>Throughout Lima and in most major towns, there are many economical <em>pensiones</em> and <em>hospedajes</em> (guest houses). The quality of accommodation in the provinces varies considerably, but hotels are frequently of a good standard. In jungle areas accommodation ranges from 5-star eco-resorts to hammocks strung outdoors, though most options fall somewhere in between. Hotel prices in the provinces are lower than in the capital. For backpackers, Lima, Cusco and Arequipa in particular have hostels where you&rsquo;ll find like-minded travellers, happy hours on drinks and dog-eared travel guides.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are classified by the star system, the highest and most luxurious being 5 stars. The level of comfort, quality of service and general infrastructure are the criteria for inclusion in each grade. Prices vary accordingly. All accommodation prices are subject to a 19% general sales tax (IGV), however foreigners who can demonstrate they live outside of Peru are not charged the tax. Showing a passport and&nbsp;<em>Tarjeta Andina de Migracion</em> (TAM Migration Card) is usually sufficient to have the tax deducted from your bill.&nbsp;Hotels of the higher categories might also add 1-13% service charges. It is advisable to reserve a room during the peak tourist season (June to September) and during major holidays such as Easter week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Many <em>hospedajes</em> and guest houses will cook you breakfast, though it is not necessarily included in the room price. But these are the closest thing you&rsquo;ll find to a bed and breakfast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lima and Cusco have the largest choice of hotels in Peru. Other cities and areas where you can find 5- and 4-star hotels are Arequipa, Cajamarca, Chiclayo, Colca Canyon, Ica, Iquitos, Puno, the Sacred Valley and Trujillo (the grading does not always match international standards).</p>
<p>Throughout Lima and in most major towns, there are many economical <em>pensiones</em> and <em>hospedajes</em> (guest houses). The quality of accommodation in the provinces varies considerably, but hotels are frequently of a good standard. In jungle areas accommodation ranges from 5-star eco-resorts to hammocks strung outdoors, though most options fall somewhere in between. Hotel prices in the provinces are lower than in the capital. For backpackers, Lima, Cusco and Arequipa in particular have hostels where you&rsquo;ll find like-minded travellers, happy hours on drinks and dog-eared travel guides.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are classified by the star system, the highest and most luxurious being 5 stars. The level of comfort, quality of service and general infrastructure are the criteria for inclusion in each grade. Prices vary accordingly. All accommodation prices are subject to a 19% general sales tax (IGV), however foreigners who can demonstrate they live outside of Peru are not charged the tax. Showing a passport and&nbsp;<em>Tarjeta Andina de Migracion</em> (TAM Migration Card) is usually sufficient to have the tax deducted from your bill.&nbsp;Hotels of the higher categories might also add 1-13% service charges. It is advisable to reserve a room during the peak tourist season (June to September) and during major holidays such as Easter week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lima and Cusco have the largest choice of hotels in Peru. Other cities and areas where you can find 5- and 4-star hotels are Arequipa, Cajamarca, Chiclayo, Colca Canyon, Ica, Iquitos, Puno, the Sacred Valley and Trujillo (the grading does not always match international standards).</p>
<p>Throughout Lima and in most major towns, there are many economical <em>pensiones</em> and <em>hospedajes</em> (guest houses). The quality of accommodation in the provinces varies considerably, but hotels are frequently of a good standard. In jungle areas accommodation ranges from 5-star eco-resorts to hammocks strung outdoors, though most options fall somewhere in between. Hotel prices in the provinces are lower than in the capital. For backpackers, Lima, Cusco and Arequipa in particular have hostels where you&rsquo;ll find like-minded travellers, happy hours on drinks and dog-eared travel guides.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are classified by the star system, the highest and most luxurious being 5 stars. The level of comfort, quality of service and general infrastructure are the criteria for inclusion in each grade. Prices vary accordingly. All accommodation prices are subject to a 19% general sales tax (IGV), however foreigners who can demonstrate they live outside of Peru are not charged the tax. Showing a passport and&nbsp;<em>Tarjeta Andina de Migracion</em> (TAM Migration Card) is usually sufficient to have the tax deducted from your bill.&nbsp;Hotels of the higher categories might also add 1-13% service charges. It is advisable to reserve a room during the peak tourist season (June to September) and during major holidays such as Easter week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;International travellers are strongly advised to take out full health insurance and should be prepared to pay up front for medical services. Bear in mind there is much scope in Peru for taking part in extreme sports activities, and you should ensure that your insurance covers you for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If choosing to take part in an adventurous activity, such as a multi-day hike over 4,000m (13,000ft) or a night-climb of a snowy mountain above 6,000m (19,700ft), you will find there are many tour companies. In the interests of your own safety, it is wise to ask other travellers for up-to-date recommendations of reputable tour operators. Check for yourself any equipment provided in advance. Be aware of your own limitations: it is very tempting to scale a mountain but if you&amp;rsquo;ve never done anything like it before you may end up being airlifted off a peak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergency telephone number all over Peru is 105, but if you have a medical emergency it is quickest to ask someone to drive you to the nearest hospital, particularly if you are in a very rural area, as waiting for an ambulance could take a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Drink only bottled water, and take purification tablets in case bottled water is unavailable. Pasteurised milk is widely available, but if you are staying in mountain towns you will also find that unpasteurised milk is often sold in shops, served in plastic bags. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. You will find that there is plenty of street food available in stores and at markets, and you should try to ensure that what you buy has been heated properly and not been left out. In particular, you will find lots of ceviche, a cold seafood dish made using raw fish, which is practically the national dish. It is heavily acidic, which must kill some bacteria; nevertheless be aware that unless the fish is very fresh the potential for food poisoning is high. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Dengue fever outbreaks are common in the Amazon Basin. Altitude sickness can be a problem if visiting the highlands, and trips should be planned so you spend stretches of time at high altitude in order to give your body time to get used to it, rather than going back and forth between mountain tops and sea level for a couple of days at a time. On arriving at a high altitude, you should take time to acclimatise, particularly before climbing any mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaccination against hepatitis B is sometimes recommended, for those who are planning to stay in Peru longer than six months or who could have sexual relations with the local population. If you do require vaccinations for your trip, ensure they are administered sufficiently in advance of your trip. The rabies vaccination, for example, is a series of three shots administered over a month.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Maundy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Feast of Saints Peter and Paul :
							29 June </p><p>Independence Day Celebrations :
							28 July </p><p>St Rosa of Lima Day :
							30 August </p><p>Battle of Angamos :
							08 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Eve (half day) :
							24 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported by visitors over 18 years of age into Peru without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 20 packs of cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 3L of alcoholic beverages.<br />
&bull; Gifts or new articles for personal use up to a value of US$500.<br />
&bull; One laptop with its own power source.<br />
&bull; One electronic tablet.<br />
&bull; Two mobile phones.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Unlicensed firearms and narcotics.<br />
&bull; Raw ham from Italy and Portugal.<br />
&bull; Salami, sausage meat, ham and cheese must be in their original packaging and unopened.<br />
&bull; Genetically modified organisms.</p>
<p>You must carry the appropriate certificates if importing plants or animals and their products.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The export of artistic or cultural articles is prohibited. Taking protected plant and animal species out of Peru is also prohibited &ndash; this can include products containing seeds and feathers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nuevo (new) Sol (PEN; symbol S/.) = 100 c&eacute;ntimos. Nuevo Sol notes are in denominations of S/.200, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of S/.5, 2 and 1, and 50, 20 and 10 c&eacute;ntimos.<br />
<br />
<strong>Note:</strong> US Dollars are also in use and accepted for payment, particularly  in tourist areas. While effectively interchangeable, it is best to use  local currency wherever possible, and it is always good for tourists to  have some local currency in small denominations, to pay for buses, taxis  and goods in some small establishments.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Only a few bureau de change in Lima and <a href="/cusco">Cusco</a> will exchange currencies other than US Dollars. Outside Lima, it is virtually impossible. US Dollars can be exchanged everywhere and banks, hotels and many shops also readily accept US Dollars (although very old, torn or damaged notes are usually rejected). It is not recommended to exchange money from street vendors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major credit cards are accepted, but usage may be limited outside of <a href="/lima">Lima</a> and tourist areas. Visa and MasterCard are the most commonly accepted. It is also sensible to carry some cash rather than rely on cards.</p><p>ATMs are now generally regarded as one of the best ways to obtain money in Peru.  They are found almost everywhere, including in small towns, although when travelling in remote places it is best to have some cash just in case the nearby ATMs are not working or have run out of money. In bigger cities, use ATMs inside banks for greater security, especially at night. Many banks have gun-carrying security guards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Banks will exchange traveller's cheques although it can be a slow process outside Lima. The ability to use traveller's cheques is also quite limited in some areas so you should check whether or not they will be accepted in the area you are visiting prior to travel. The use of ATMs is generally preferable, but if you do decide to bring traveller's cheques, the best currency to bring them in is US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800, Sat 0900-1300 (may vary during the summer).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For British and US nationals to enter Peru, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required. Canadian and Australian authorities recommend passport validity for six months from your planned date of departure from Peru.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no particular requirements when bringing children into the country provided they have their own documentation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas are not required by any nationals of the countries listed within the above table, or by anyone else provided you do not leave the transit area, your connecting flight is within 24 hours, you have all your documents and ticket for your next destination, and your luggage is checked through to your final destination.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist/business visa: &pound;24.60. Costs are subject to change according to exchange rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Up to 183 days, but you must ask for this and the discretion lies with the officer. Stamps have been issued for as few as 30 days. You can extend your visa in Peru.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Temporary residence is not available in Peru, except through business visas. You can apply for permanent residence if you have a Peruvian spouse.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least 24 hours for visa processing. It may take longer if authorisation from the immigration office in Lima is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must prove you have sufficient funds (last three statements showing a minimum of &pound;1,000) <em>only</em> if you need a visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you comply with the regulations properly, there is no quarantine for pets and you can bring them into Peru. You need a signed, legitimate vet&rsquo;s health certificate for your pet, which shows vaccinations against rabies and other diseases specific to your species of pet. You will also have to pay several fees.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-9.212963]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-75.112021]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,285,220 sq km (496,226 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>31,774,225 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>23.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lima.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Peru is a large, mountainous country on the Pacific coast of South America that borders Ecuador and Colombia to the north, Brazil and Bolivia to the east, and Chile to the south. The Pacific Ocean lies to the west. There are three natural zones:</p>
<p>The Costa region, which contains Lima (the capital), is a narrow coastal plain consisting of large tracts of desert broken by fertile valleys. The cotton, sugar and rice plantations and most of the so-far exploited oil fields lie in this area, as does the majority of the population. The best roads run along the coast, having straight, flat paths ahead of them, and travel times are usually good.</p>
<p>The highland Sierra contains the Andes, with peaks over 6,000m (20,000ft), most of the country's mineral resources (silver, zinc, lead, copper and gold) and the greater part of its livestock. Roads in this area wind up, down and around mountains, so travelling in this area is often time-consuming.</p>
<p>The Selva (jungle), an area of fertile, subtropical land, lies between the Andes and the borders with Brazil, Bolivia, Colombia and Ecuador. The Amazonian jungle has vast natural resources. The absence of land communications, however, left the area largely uncharted until full-scale oil exploration began in 1973. Even today roads barely penetrate the region. Some areas are best reached by small plane.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>81.3% Roman Catholic, 12.5% Evangelical, 3.3% other denominations, 2.9% unspecified or none.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is the customary form of greeting. Kissing on one cheek between women and between women and men is common in coastal cities. Travellers should avoid the scruffy &lsquo;backpacker&rsquo;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a> look &ndash; it is not admired and considered bad etiquette.</p>
<p>Peruvians (and Latin Americans in general) are not really confrontational people &ndash; if you are struggling with some aspect of your travel (uncomfortable rooms, late buses etc), losing your temper will not get you very far. Instead, stay patient, keep smiling and someone will help you eventually, if only to make you go away.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without grounding pin) and European-style plugs with two round pins are used. 110 volts AC is available in most 4- and 5-star hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister C&eacute;sar Villanueva since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Mart&iacute;n Vizcarra since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Before the Spanish invasion of Latin America in the early 16th century, many advanced cultures had settled in present-day Peru culminating in the vast Inca Empire. The Spanish imposed its cultural practices on the country, in everything from religion to building construction, and this quickly became very widespread as the country was brought under its control.</p>
<p>However, owing to the geography of the country, the smaller, more remote groups of indigenous peoples living in the mountains were largely untouched by Spanish culture. After centuries of colonial rule, Peru declared independence in 1821, and the revolutionary leader Sim&oacute;n Bol&iacute;var took over the running of the country.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, relations between Peru and its neighbours were not smooth, and over the next 100 years the government had its hands full trying to fight wars while keeping the economy stable. The War of the Pacific (1879-1883) between Chile and Peru all but bankrupted the country, leaving it little chance to recuperate. From 1914 onwards, Peru seemed to lurch from one military coup to another, some more destructive than others. Added to which, throughout the 1980s, it also had to combat the Sendero Luminoso (Shining Path) extremist guerrilla group belonging to the Peruvian Communist Party, resulting in thousands of deaths.</p>
<p>Since 1990, Peru has been trying to recover and sustain economic growth, and it is now one of the fastest-growing economies in South America. Despite its booming modernisation, however, tribal life remains in many ways the same today as it was before the Spanish conquest, with indigenous people still dressing in traditional clothes, living in agriculture-based communities and speaking the original languages. Quechua, which was spoken by the Incas, is still widely used in Peru, with an estimated 6 to 8 million speakers.&nbsp;Likewise, the physical characteristics of indigenous peoples remain distinctly Amerindian, whereas in the bigger cities you are more likely to see lighter skin and eyes, and more Western features.</p>
<p>Peru has suffered through surges of drug trafficking, which have threatened the recent relative peace of the country. Some estimate that Peruvian cocaine exports have overtaken those of Colombia.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Abimael Guzm&aacute;n, leader of the Sendero Luminoso movement, was finally captured in a hideaway above a ballet school in a plush Lima neighbourhood.<br />
&bull;	The Yavar&iacute; is a floating hotel on Lake Titicaca, built as an iron steamboat in England in 1861 and transported from the coast of Peru in pieces by mules.<br />
&bull;	The Callao, Lima &amp; Oroya Railway is the second-highest railway line in the world, reaching 4,783m (15,692ft) in the Andes, after a journey from sea level at Lima.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Peru in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 833 9860.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyofperu.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 833 9860.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1700 Massachusetts Ave NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Peru in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+ 44 20 7838 9223.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.peruembassy-uk.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+ 44 20 7838 9223.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1230 and 1500-1630.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Knightsbridge<br/>52 Sloane Street<br/>London<br/>SW1X 9SP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Peru]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+51 1 6173000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/peru</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+51 1 6173000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1300 and 1400-1700; Fri 0800-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Avenida José Larco 1301, Miraflores<br/>Torre Parque Mar (22nd Floor)<br/>Lima<br/>15074<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South America doesn&rsquo;t get much more evocative of generations gone by than Peru. Its mix of ancient civilisations and dramatic archaeology, set among some of the most extraordinary landscapes on the planet, means few destinations have as much to offer cultural visitors.</p>
<p>The old Inca settlement of Machu Picchu, now said to be the most visited site on the entire continent, is just the poster-child &ndash; it&rsquo;s utterly magnificent, of course, but it&rsquo;s just one of many highlights served up by the country. From mountain range to jungle, beach to desert, colonial town to cosmopolitan city, it&rsquo;s a truly wonderful place to travel.</p>
<p>The coastal capital, Lima, can seem chaotic at times, but scratch the surface and you&rsquo;ll unearth some great museums and nightclubs, not to mention some of the region&rsquo;s best food and drink &ndash; from <em>ceviche</em> (raw fish in citrus) to <em>cecina</em> (dried pork) and from Peruvian wine (yes, really) to pisco sours.</p>
<p>But the country&rsquo;s real appeal lies outside the capital. Contrasting beautifully with Lima is the ancient capital of Cusco with its winding cobbled streets and 1,000-plus years of history. It&rsquo;s the gateway for visitors to the unmissable Machu Picchu, as well as those walking the Inca trail, but it makes for a colourful destination in its own right. There&rsquo;s no better place to learn more about the country&rsquo;s earlier times and the upheaval of the Spanish conquest.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the country, the Nazca Lines, the beautifully excavated ruins of Chan Chan and the Chachapoya fortress of Kuelap boggle the mind. These extraordinary complexes are all set amid stunning landscapes.</p>
<p>But Peru doesn&rsquo;t solely involve rushing up and down mountains or traipsing around ruins. If you&rsquo;re searching for a relaxing beach destination, head to M&aacute;ncora, which is popular with sun-seekers and surfers. A little more subdued, but no less beautiful, is the quaint coastal town of Huanchaco, where you can sit on the beach and watch fishermen ply their trade on traditional reed canoes. It&rsquo;s a far cry from the lofty Andes and a testament to Peru&rsquo;s staggering diversity.</p><p>South America doesn&rsquo;t get much more evocative of generations gone by than Peru. Its mix of ancient civilisations and dramatic archaeology, set among some of the most extraordinary landscapes on the planet, means few destinations have as much to offer cultural visitors. The old Inca settlement of Machu Picchu, now said to be the most visited site on the entire continent, is just the poster-child &ndash; it&rsquo;s utterly magnificent, of course, but it&rsquo;s just one of many highlights served up by the country. From mountain range to jungle, beach to desert, colonial town to cosmopolitan city, it&rsquo;s a truly wonderful place to travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
