<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Philippines" ColCode="phl" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ph" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Philippines]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Philippines is hot year-round but sea breezes can add freshness during the winter (November to February). The typhoon season lasts from around July to October, although in recent years it seems to have been starting and finishing later &ndash; in 2010 for example there was severe flooding in North Luzon as late as November.<br />
<br />
Rainfall patterns vary across the country. In <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/manila">Manila</a>, Palawan and Coron, for example, most rain occurs in the typhoon season. Other areas (including much of the Bicol region) have no distinct dry season, with the most rain from December to February. The Visayas have only a short dry season from November to January, while in Leyte and Bohol, rainfall levels don&rsquo;t change much throughout the year. Travellers should therefore check the local climate before making plans.<br />
<br />
Most tourists visit from January to May (and particularly the first half of that period) when most of the country is undergoing its best climatic conditions. Surfers, on the other hand, are attracted to the islands during the typhoon season as it brings the biggest waves.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are worn throughout most of the year, with warmer clothes useful on cooler evenings. Rainwear or umbrellas are advisable for the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Domestic flights in the Philippines are operated by Philippine Airlines (<a href="http://www.philippineairlines.com" target="_blank">www.philippineairlines.com</a>), Cebu Pacific (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.cebupacificair.com">www.cebupacificair.com</a>), Air Asia (<a href="http://www.airasia.com" target="_blank">www.airasia.com</a>)&nbsp;and Seair (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flyseair.com">www.flyseair.com</a>).</p>
<p>Flying is one of the most efficient ways of getting around and is also reasonably affordable. Other than Manila, the only major hub is Cebu City. Important regional airports include Laoag and Tuguegarao (in North Luzon), Legazpi (in South Luzon), Puerto Princesa (in Palawan) and Davao (in Mindanao). A handful of places can be reached only by air, notably the Batanes islands off the north coast of Luzon.</p>
<p>It is essential to book in advance at Easter, All Saints&rsquo; Day and All Souls&rsquo; Day (1&ndash;2 November), Christmas and New Year, and on routes run only by SEAIR as they typically use small planes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The islands of the Philippines are connected by an intricate network of ferry services, ranging from small <em>bangkas</em> (outrigger boats) to large liners. In many places (particularly the Visayas) they are the only way to get around and see the sights. Erratic timetabling is common, and avoid overcrowded ships (particularly in bad weather).</p>
<p>2GO Travel (tel: +63 2 528 7000; <a href="http://travel.2go.com.ph" target="_blank">travel.2go.com.ph</a>) is the umbrella operator for many major ferry services. Tickets can be bought in advance, although for well-served routes it&rsquo;s usually possible to pay before boarding.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Philippine National Railways (tel: +63 2 319 0041; <a href="http://www.pnr.gov.ph" target="_blank">www.pnr.gov.ph</a>) is the sole train operator. Its single operational line, Main Line South, runs infrequent services across Southern Luzon to Legaspi via Calamba and Naga. The journey takes around 10 hours but bus services are quicker and more comfortable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Road conditions and traffic make driving in much of the country (particularly the cities) stressful at best. Defensive driving is essential, as is patience for dealing with queues of traffic in urban areas.</p>
<p>Roads spread among the islands, with highways on the Mindanao, Visayas and Luzon island groups. Driving off the main highway at night is dangerous and should be avoided.</p>r<p>The Filipino islands are serviced by dozens of private bus companies of various sizes, running buses ranging from a/c comfort with toilets to barely functioning rust buckets. There is no central information service for buses, and in many towns and cities different companies have their own terminals. Phone lines also tend to be unhelpful, so the best bet is to enquire about routes and times at hotels.</p><p>Taxis are available in cities and in many towns. Make sure meters are used, as some taxi drivers will otherwise set an exorbitant and arbitrary rate. It&rsquo;s very common to be asked for &lsquo;meter plus fifty Pesos&rsquo; or similar; either accept it or wait for another vehicle.</p><p>You can use a foreign driving licence for up to three months after arrival, after which an International Driving Permit is required. You must carry the licence or permit with you when driving.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Seat belts are compulsory, although this is widely ignored by locals.</p>
<p>Private vehicles are banned from most roads in the capital between 0700 and 1900 for one day a week. This procedure depends on the vehicle&rsquo;s licence plate (for example, plates ending in 1 or 2 are banned on Mondays).</p><p>Automobile Association Philippines (tel: +63 2 723 0808; <a href="http://www.aaphilippines.org" target="_blank">www.aaphilippines.org</a>) offers an emergency roadside service in Metro Manila and on selected highways, but only for members. There is no national breakdown service, and in rural areas drivers are likely to have to rely on passersby and local mechanics; car hire companies may also have help lines for emergencies. Signs for &lsquo;vulcanization&rsquo; indicate tyre-repair services.</p><p>Car hire is available in Manila and in major cities, with offices in airports and occasionally in large business hotels. It&rsquo;s common to hire a car with a driver, particularly to tackle Manila&rsquo;s busy traffic, and it&rsquo;s also possible to hire taxis by the day.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Seat belts are compulsory, although this is widely ignored by locals.</p>
<p>Private vehicles are banned from most roads in the capital between 0700 and 1900 for one day a week. This procedure depends on the vehicle&rsquo;s licence plate (for example, plates ending in 1 or 2 are banned on Mondays).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In most towns and cities, transport comes in three forms: tricycles, pedicabs and jeepneys.</p>
<p>Tricycles (motorbikes with sidecars) hold up to five people and are most useful for short distances. Locals commonly share the journey with strangers and pay a per-person rate. Tourists are often assumed to want private hire and may therefore pay for the whole vehicle. It's still a cheap way to get around, but negotiate a price in advance.</p>
<p>Pedicabs often look similar but are engineless and pedalled by the operator. Jeepneys, once adapted from US army jeeps, are now purpose built. They follow fixed routes with fees dependent on the length of the journey.<br />
<br />
Manila&rsquo;s Metro Rail Transit (MRT) connects North Avenue in Quezon to Taft Avenue in Pasay City. The Light Railway Transit (LRT) has two lines. The yellow line runs north to south from Baclaran terminal to Roosevelt on North Avenue; the purple line runs from west to east, from Recto in the Santa Cruz district to Santolan.<br />
<br />
<em>Calseas</em> (horse-drawn carriages) are common in parts of downtown Manila. The best place to try one is around Intramuros where drivers usually stick to the stated prices. <em>Calesas</em> are also available in a few other places, notably Vigan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Philippines</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">palawan</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Philippines</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">laoag</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.25</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Philippines</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cagayande_oro</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.25</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Philippines</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">batangas</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Philippine Airlines (<a href="http://www.philippineairlines.com" target="_blank">www.philippineairlines.com</a>) is the main carrier, with direct flights from multiple destinations, including the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.</p>
<p>The period over Easter, from Good Friday to the following bank holiday (and sometimes beyond), is a major holiday in the Philippines, as are Christmas and New Year. There may be some difficulty booking a flight during these periods.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/manila/manila-ninoy-aquino-international-airport">Manila Ninoy Aquino International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours 40 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 20 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a> - 14 hours 20 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Php750 for international departures. Children under two years of age and transit passengers are exempt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Manila Ninoy Aquino International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.miaa.gov.ph<p>Manila Ninoy Aquino International Airport is situated 7km (4 miles) south of central Manila.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+63 2 877 7888</p>]]><b>Mactan Cebu International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.mciaa.gov.ph<p>The airport  is 45km (28 miles) from the city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although the country is a fixture on international shipping routes, there are no significant passenger services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>International calls to the smaller towns must be booked through the operator.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile phone coverage is good, other than in mountainous areas and remote locations. There is 3G coverage in many urban areas. Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies, but it is cheap and easy to buy a local SIM card. Credit top-ups (known as 'load') are readily available. International calls can be made on mobile phones, but the cheapest way is through a VOIP service. Software and headsets are available in most Internet cafés.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafés are common across the country. Access is cheap and usually reasonably fast. Wi-Fi is also usually easy to find, available in many hotels and coffee shops. The main telecoms companies offer reasonably priced 3G access via smartphones or USB dongles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The media is controlled by powerful commercial interests. There is a busy TV scene, which is dominated by free-to-air networks ABS-CBN and GMA. Many radio networks are also run by TV broadcasters. Freedom of the press is guaranteed under the 1987 constitution, but it is not uncommon for controversial journalists to be murdered and the country has a poor track record for solving such crimes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes at least five days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Banaue Rice Terraces</p><![CDATA[<p>Nestled deep in the heartlands of the Cordilleras mountains and rising to an altitude of 1525m (5000ft) are the Banaue Rice Terraces. The terraces were carved out of the mountain range over 3000 years ago by the Ifugaos, the oldest mountain tribe in the area, using only the most primitive tools. The irrigation system uses gravity to harness water from the forests 1800m (2185ft) above thus ensuring a continuous supply of crops. Measured from end to end, the terraces would stretch a total length of 22,400km (13,919 miles), enough to encircle half the globe. They are often dubbed the eighth wonder of the ancient world as their age and scale is comparable to that of the official seven wonders, of which only the Pyramids of Giza remain.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Ascend to the summit of Mount Apo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rising to 2,954m (9,700ft) in the centre of Mindanao, Mount Apo ('Grandfather') is the highest peak in the country and a popular destination for trekkers. The whole Apo mountain range has spectacular waterfalls, rapids, forests, springs and mountain lakes, plus one of the longest ziplines in Asia on the southern slope of Mount Apo.</p>]]><p><b>Be amazed by the rice terraces of the Cordillera</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Breathtaking in scale, the rice terraces of North Luzon were carved out around 2,000 years ago by mountain tribes using only the most basic tools. Still farmed today, the terraces are accessible from the peaceful town of Banaue, from where it's possible to hike to isolated villages such as Batad for tribal encounters.</p>]]><p><b>Climb a volcano</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The islands of the Philippines were thrown up by the Pacific Ring of Fire, and there are active volcanoes all across the archipelago, many accessible on jungle treks. Mount Mayon near Legazpi puts on impressive lava shows, while the cones around Los Banos on Luzon island produce naturally hot mineral springs. Then there's Mount Pinatubo, which blew its top with devastating results in 1991.</p>]]><p><b>Discover old Manila</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There's more to Manila than crowds and traffic jams. In the centre are the remains of Intramuros, the Spanish walled city, still bound by parts of the massive wall that once protected it. Highlights include the historic San Agustin and Quiapo churches, Casa Manila (a reconstruction of a wealthy family's home) and the ruins of Fort Santiago.</p>]]><p><b>Dive the wrecks of Calamian Islands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Although there's plenty to explore above the surface, the Calamian archipelago north of Palawan is most famous for its amazing collection of shipwrecks, the remains of a Japanese flotilla sunk during WWII. The resort of Coron is the gateway to this diving mecca, with numerous scuba centres offering trips to the wrecks.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy the Philippines’ second city</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the middle of the Visayas, Cebu is the Philippines' second biggest city, and a much more relaxing place to arrive than manic Manila. The island is famous for its diving, festivals and guitars, which have been made here since Spanish times. The Sinulog Festival in January is one of the islands' most colourful fiestas.</p>]]><p><b>Explore colonial heritage at Vigan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>WWII saw the destruction of much of the Philippines' Spanish heritage, so the collection of Spanish-era merchants' homes in UNESCO-listed Vigan is a rare delight. Some have been turned into museums, while others function as heritage hotels. Horse-drawn carriages (<em>calesas</em>) take tourists around this approachable city.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Bacuit Archipelago</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Floating off the coast of Palawan, this collection of tiny islands is picture postcard territory, with soaring karst cliffs, crystal-clear lagoons and white sand beaches. From the resort town of El Nido, you can roam to amazing dive sites, coral lagoons and deserted beaches by <em>bangka</em> (outrigger boat) with a freshly caught seafood barbecue for lunch.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the party spirit at a Filipino fiesta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The festivals of the Philippines are riotous carnivals, with spectacular fiesta food and amazing costume parades that fill the streets with music. They&rsquo;re nominally Christian, but hark back to ancient tribal celebrations. Sinulog in Cebu City, Ati-Atihan in Kalibo, and Dinagyang in<strong> </strong>Iliolo are the top events on the cultural calendar.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back on Boracay Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The picture of postcard perfection, sandy Boracay Island may have been heavily developed, but it's still a gorgeous strip of sun, sea and palms. Whether you spend your days lazing on the beach, sipping happy hour cocktails in beach bars, kite boarding in the bay or diving the reefs just offshore, it isn't hard to see the appeal.</p>]]><p><b>Meet local tribes in scenic Sagada</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The laidback mountain village of Sagada is the gateway to the Central Cordillera, whose mountains are dotted with tribal villages, limestone caverns, and surging waterfalls. As well as beautiful scenery, cheap lodges and excellent food, Sagada is renowned for its hanging coffins, a funeral rite that harks back to ancient animist traditions.</p>]]><p><b>Meet the world's smallest monkey in Bohol</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Bohol Island is famous for its natural wonders, from the famous Chocolate Hills – a range of strangely uniform limestone hills resembling oversized chocolate drops – to the miniature tarsier, one of the world's smallest primates. Elsewhere on this laidback island are gorgeous beaches, rocky islands and Spanish-ruins, including the Baclayon Church, built in 1595.</p>]]><p><b>See another world beneath the waves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Philippines is one of the world's top diving destinations, with everything from sunken islands to stunning wreck dives on WWII warships. The wrecks of Coron are probably the single most famous diving spot, but other great dives include thresher shark encounters on Malapascua Island, and the reefs at Tubbataha, Apo and Anilao.</p>]]><p><b>See the pink sands of Santa Cruz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Off the coast of Zamboanga in Mindanao, Santa Cruz Island is famous for its sandy beach that turns pink when corals from the sea are washed ashore. It's a gorgeous spot even by the standards of the Philippines and a great place to swim, surf, windsurf, snorkel or dive.</p>]]><p><b>Snorkel with whale sharks in Donsol</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This quiet fishing village has been a magnet for tourists ever since whale sharks were 'discovered' off the coast, though local fishermen had known about them for centuries. Today, local boatmen run snorkelling tours that offer the chance to get up close and personal with these amazing gentle giants – the world's largest fish – which can grow to the size of a bus.</p>]]><p><b>Surf in Siargao</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spectacular surfing is one of the best-kept secrets in the Philippines, and this tiny island off the north coast of Mindanao sees spectacular swells from August to November, when breaks like Cloud Nine offer spectacular tube rides. The island is dotted with laidback resorts that come to life during the annual surfing contest in September/October.</p>]]><p><b>Uncover Spanish heritage in Carcar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Carcar town, two hours south of Cebu City, is home to some of the best-preserved Castillian houses, gardens and churches in the Philippines. The town is also known for its delicious <em>lechon</em> (roast pig) and <em>chicharon</em> (crispy pork rind), so make a day of it and visit the public market for a slap-up meal.</p>]]><p><b>Wakeboard on Camarines Sur</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The province of Camarines Sur is gaining increasing attention as a playground for watersports, largely thanks to the Camsur Watersports Complex near Pili. This is one of the world's top wakeboarding facilities, and nearby are stunning beaches, caves and waterfalls, with good diving and sport fishing offshore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$292.45 billion (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Electronic products, transport equipment, garments, copper products, coconut oil.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Electronic products, raw materials such as iron, machinery and transport equipment, grains and fuels.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China (PR), Japan, USA, Singapore and Hong Kong (SAR).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The agricultural sector produces rice, corn, coconuts, copra, sugar cane and bananas as the main crops. The export of timber has been suspended since 1989 due to deforestation; at the start of 2011 a new law banned all logging other than in plantations. There is a modest mining industry and offshore oil. Most recent economic development has been industrial.<br />
<br />
Financial incentives to attract foreign capital and the creation of export processing zones prompted strong growth during the early and mid 1990s. However, it also produced a skewed economy which is dominated by Manila.<br />
<br />
Following a substantial slump in 1997, the economy recovered and was been less severely affected by the 2008 financial crisis than many of its neighbours. In 2015, growth was 6.6% and inflation 1.4%. Unemployment was at 6.4%. The Philippines belongs to the Association of South-East Asian Nations and the Asian Development Bank.<br />
<br />
The Tourism Promotions Board provides information, assistance and guidance to meeting planners and incentive travel organizers. Popular locations for conferences and conventions are the Philippine International Convention Centre and the World Trade Centre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The weather is almost uniformly warm and humid and so a shirt with a tie can be worn for business visits. Formal wear for Filipino men includes the <em>barong tagalog</em> (a long shirt made from pineapple fibres), which is not tucked into trousers.<br /><br />
Filipinos have an American business style and English is widely spoken. The best months for business visits are October to November and January to May. Unless you have urgent business matters to attend to, business visits around Christmas and Easter are not recommended as delays tend to be unavoidable.<br /><br /></p><p>Usually Mon-Fri 0800-1700. Some private sector offices are open Sat 0900-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Philippine Convention and Visitors Corporation (PCVC)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 525 9318
					Website:http://www.dotpcvc.gov.ph
					Address: 300 Roxas Boulevard,4F Legaspi Towers,Metro Manila,]]><b>Philippine Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 896 4549
					Website:http://www.philippinechamber.com
					Address: Makati City,3rd Floor,ECC Building,355 Gil Payat Avenue,,]]><b>Philippine Trade and Investment Promotion Centre in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7937 1898
					Website:
					Address: Kensington Court,1A Cumberland House,London W8 5NX,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Compared to other Southeast Asian nations, Filipino cooking uses a limited palate of spices, favouring instead sour or vinegary flavours, a legacy of the Spanish era. In terms of flavour, Filipino cuisine falls somewhere between the food of Spain and China, with lots of stews, grilled fish and roast meats, usually served with rice. Pork is especially popular, particularly in the form of <em>lechon</em> – whole roast pig, served for special occasions.</p><p>The most famous Pinoy dish is <em>adobo</em>, a rich stew with garlic, soy and vinegar, and other local favourites include <em>sinigang </em>(meat or seafood in sour broth) and <em>kare-kare </em>(oxtail in peanut sauce). The seafood of the Philippines is particularly fine, and a plate of grilled, freshly-caught fish with soy-sauce and broken green chillies or <em>kalamansi </em>lime juice is a meal in itself. Look out for special delicacies at the Philippines' colourful festivals.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Adobo</strong>: Braised pork or chicken in a tangy sauce made from soy, vinegar and garlic.<br />
<strong>Lechon</strong>: Roasted whole pig, prepared for fiestas and family celebrations.<br />
<strong>Kare-kare</strong>: An oxtail stew in peanut sauce served with <em>bagoong</em> (fermented shrimp paste).<br />
<strong>Sinigang</strong>: Meat or fish in a pleasantly sour broth.<br />
<strong>Pansit canton: </strong>A Chinese-influenced dish of noodles stir fried with meat and vegetables.<br />
<strong>Sinangag: </strong>Garlic-fried rice, a popular local breakfast.<br />
<strong>Tapa: </strong>Delicious dried marinated beefsteak, often fried and served with fried rice and a fried egg as <em>tapsilog</em>.<br />
<strong>Balut: </strong>A par-boiled, fertilised duck&rsquo;s egg containing a baby chick, served as a beer snack across the archipelago.<br />
<strong>Crispy Pata:</strong> Deep-fried pig&rsquo;s trotters, served with a soy and vinegar dip.<br />
<strong>Longanisa: </strong>Spanish-style sausage, flavoured with local spices; each province has its own recipe.<br />
<strong>San Miguel:</strong> A ubiquitous Spanish lager.&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% of the bill, unless service charge is included.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Throughout Asia you&rsquo;ll find Filipino cover bands playing in hotels and bars, and this affinity for music is reflected in Manila&rsquo;s lively nightlife &ndash; as well as in the universal popularity of karaoke (known here as &lsquo;videoke&rsquo;).<br />
<br />
A night out could involve anything from the VIP area of an upmarket superclub to a table in a grungy bar with a band playing Pinoy (Filipino) rock or folk music. Manila&rsquo;s transvestite revues (some of them very glamorous) are also popular with tourists, while the Cultural Center of the Philippines provides more highbrow entertainment such as ballet, opera and classical music.<br />
<br />
Outside of Manila, nightlife options are much more restricted. In many towns the best you can hope for (outside of the annual fiesta) is a cover band in a bar, playing folk, country or reggae tunes. Exceptions tend to be university towns, such as Baguio, which has many places to sample live music. As the second city, Cebu also has a vibrant club scene.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Philippines has inherited from the US a passion for shopping centres, and every urban area of any size has at least one of these air-conditioned havens. There are also, however, plenty of more traditional covered and open-air markets.<br />
<br />
It&rsquo;s usually cheaper to buy handicrafts in their place of origin, but Manila offers opportunities to get them all in one place. The Tiendesitas shopping centre has 12 pavilions, each with a different selection of goods (from antiques to fashion and furniture), while Divisoria flea market offers a more chaotic shopping experience. Outside of the capital, Baguio is noted for its silver and handicraft stores, while Cebu City&rsquo;s Carbon market rivals Divisoria.<br />
<br />
Typical souvenirs include the barong tagalog (hand-embroidered dress shirts made from pineapple fibres), brassware from the south, guitars from Cebu, painted papier-m&acirc;ch&eacute; horses from Laguna, rattan furniture, woven grass mats (banig), antique wooden figurines of saints, carved rice guardian figures from the Cordillera mountains, pearls from Mindanao or Palawan, terracotta pots and abaca (Manila hemp) placemats.</p><p>Mon-Sat 1000-2000, but these can vary. Most department stores and supermarkets are open Sunday and there are some 24-hour convenience stores.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[Hotels in the Philippines range from five star business hotels to backpacker hostels, with the widest choice available in Manila. In other towns and cities, the choice can be more limited, although a handful of classy boutique hotels are beginning to emerge in provincial towns. Coastal settlements and small islands have resorts ranging from basic beach huts to exclusive luxury retreats.<br /><br />
Room prices in some tourist areas double or triple during peak seasons (Easter and Christmas/New Year). It's essential to book ahead at those times, and most places require a substantial deposit for a reservation at any time of year.<br /><br />
Most of the luxury hotels in Manila are in the Makati district close to the Ayala Centre. Other places with a concentration of luxury options include Boracay and Mactan (Cebu), both of which have a number of international chain hotels. Elsewhere in the country the choices at the top end are more limited, although there are some great boutique resorts tucked away on small islands or secluded beaches primarily attracting wealthy locals and Korean honeymooners.<br /><br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded in the following categories based on standards set by the Office of Tourism Services, Department of Tourism, Manila: Economy, Standard, First Class and Deluxe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[Hotels in the Philippines range from five star business hotels to backpacker hostels, with the widest choice available in Manila. In other towns and cities, the choice can be more limited, although a handful of classy boutique hotels are beginning to emerge in provincial towns. Coastal settlements and small islands have resorts ranging from basic beach huts to exclusive luxury retreats.<br /><br />
Room prices in some tourist areas double or triple during peak seasons (Easter and Christmas/New Year). It's essential to book ahead at those times, and most places require a substantial deposit for a reservation at any time of year.<br /><br />
Most of the luxury hotels in Manila are in the Makati district close to the Ayala Centre. Other places with a concentration of luxury options include Boracay and Mactan (Cebu), both of which have a number of international chain hotels. Elsewhere in the country the choices at the top end are more limited, although there are some great boutique resorts tucked away on small islands or secluded beaches primarily attracting wealthy locals and Korean honeymooners.<br /><br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded in the following categories based on standards set by the Office of Tourism Services, Department of Tourism, Manila: Economy, Standard, First Class and Deluxe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[Hotels in the Philippines range from five star business hotels to backpacker hostels, with the widest choice available in Manila. In other towns and cities, the choice can be more limited, although a handful of classy boutique hotels are beginning to emerge in provincial towns. Coastal settlements and small islands have resorts ranging from basic beach huts to exclusive luxury retreats.<br /><br />
Room prices in some tourist areas double or triple during peak seasons (Easter and Christmas/New Year). It's essential to book ahead at those times, and most places require a substantial deposit for a reservation at any time of year.<br /><br />
Most of the luxury hotels in Manila are in the Makati district close to the Ayala Centre. Other places with a concentration of luxury options include Boracay and Mactan (Cebu), both of which have a number of international chain hotels. Elsewhere in the country the choices at the top end are more limited, although there are some great boutique resorts tucked away on small islands or secluded beaches primarily attracting wealthy locals and Korean honeymooners.<br /><br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded in the following categories based on standards set by the Office of Tourism Services, Department of Tourism, Manila: Economy, Standard, First Class and Deluxe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health insurance is essential, particularly since approximately three-quarters of the hospitals are private. Call 117 for emergency services, although if you&amp;rsquo;re in Manila then it may be quicker to contact an ambulance service directly. These include Makati Medical (tel: +63 2 888 8999) and St. Luke's Hospital (tel: +63 2 789 7700).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk that's unpasteurised should be boiled. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Zika virus is a risk in Malaysia. Because Zika infection in a pregnant woman can cause serious birth defects, women who are pregnant should not travel to Malaysia. All travellers should strictly follow steps to prevent mosquito bites&amp;nbsp;and sexual exposure to Zika virus during and after the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid swimming and paddling in stagnant water and rivers; swimming pools that are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. Dengue fever is an ongoing public health concern, and is spread by mosquitoes particularly around stagnant water in urban areas &amp;ndash; unlike malaria there is no effective medication to prevent it, so it is best to take steps to avoid being bitten. Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on the weekend are observed the next working day.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>EDSA Revolution Anniversary :
							25 February </p><p>Maundy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Bataan Day (Araw ng Kagitingan) :
							09 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							12 June </p><p>National Heroes Day :
							27 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Bonifacio Day :
							30 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Rizal Day :
							30 December </p><p>New Year's Eve :
							31 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into the Philippines by travellers aged 18 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 2 cartons of cigarettes or 2 tins of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2 bottles of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; Goods to the total value of US$1,000 (US$2,000 for overseas-based Filipinos and US$250 for children under 18). You may only import one of each type of non-consumable item worth over US$200.</p>
<p>The total purchase for any calendar year may not exceed US$10,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Firearms and ammunition, explosives, publications inciting treason or rebellion against the government, obscene or immoral materials, and anything related to carrying out or advertising abortions (which are illegal in the Philippines).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Philippine Peso (PHP; symbol Php or P) = 100 centavos. Notes are in denominations of Php1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50 and 20. Coins are in denominations of Php10, 5, 2 and 1, and 25, 10, 5 and 1 centavos.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cash in Pounds Sterling or US Dollars can be exchanged in banks, hotels and some retail outlets. Always use authorised money-changers or banks in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/manila">Manila</a>. Outside the capital there is a shortage of facilities for changing foreign currency and rates may get progressively worse as you travel further away from the city. It is advisable to carry a sufficient amount of Philippine pesos when travelling to other provinces.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard and Visa (and to a lesser extent American Express and Diners Club) are accepted in major establishments throughout the larger cities of the Philippines. Elsewhere acceptance is less reliable.<br /><br />
In locations with no ATMs, you may be able to get a cash advance on a credit card for a hefty fee from travel agents or other establishments.</p><p>ATMs are widely available in cities and major tourist areas, but may not be present on smaller islands or in mountain areas. It is best to check ahead before relying on the presence of ATMs. Major banks accepting foreign cards include PNB (<a href="http://www.pnb.com.ph" target="_blank">www.pnb.com.ph</a>), BPI (<a href="http://www.bpiexpressonline.com" target="_blank">www.bpiexpressonline.com</a>) and Land Bank (<a href="http://www.landbank.com" target="_blank">www.landbank.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travellers cheques may be cashed at most banks, and are accepted by some tourist-oriented hotels, restaurants and shops. This process can, however, be long-winded and frustrating. To reduce the difficulties, visitors are advised to take travellers cheques in US Dollars and to carry their receipt of purchase as well as their passport when cashing them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter the Philippines, a valid passport is required by nationals referred to in the chart above. Nationals of some countries require six months' validity on their passport, while others (including Australia, Canada, the UK and the USA)&nbsp;need only carry a passport valid for the duration of stay; check with the embassy before you travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: &pound;25; six-month multiple-entry visa: &pound;47; one-year multiple-entry visa: &pound;70.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: valid for three months from the date of issue; multiple-entry visa: valid for six months or a year from the date of issue. The maximum stay for each entry is 59 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing at the embassy usually takes two to three working days, unless the application is referred to the Department of Foreign Affairs in Manila, in which case it can take up to two months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[12.022973]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[122.714040]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>300,000 sq km (115,831 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>103,339,458 (UN estimate 2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>348 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Manila.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Philippines lie off the southeast coast of Asia&nbsp;between Taiwan and Borneo in the Pacific Ocean and South China Sea. They are composed of 7,107 islands and islets (7,108 at low tide), 2,773 of which are named. The two largest islands, Luzon in the north and Mindanao in the south, account for 65% of the total land area and contain 60% of the country's population. Between the two lie the Visayas Islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic 86%; the rest are made up mostly of Muslims, other Christian denominations, Buddhists and Taoists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Government officials are addressed by their titles such as senator, congressman or director. Otherwise, usual modes of address and levels of politeness are expected. Casual dress is acceptable in most places, but in Muslim areas the visitor should cover up. Filipino men may wear an embroidered long-sleeved shirt or a plain white barong tagalog with black trousers for formal occasions, women wear cocktail dresses or long gowns. The Philippines are, in many respects, more westernised than any other Asian country, but there is a rich underlay of Malay culture. This is reflected, for example, in a concern for preserving <em>amor propia</em> (face) which makes direct confrontation a social taboo.</p>
<p>Smoking: There is a nationwide smoking ban in force in public places that are frequented by minors and young people like&nbsp;schools, universities, youth hostels, recreational facilities, hospitals, clinics and public kitchens.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC&nbsp;(110 volts in Baguio), 60Hz. 110 volts is available in most hotels. Plugs with two flat pins (with or without grounding pin) or two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Rodrigo Duterte since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Rodrigo Duterte since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Inhabited for some 250,000 years, by the time the Spanish arrived in the 16th century the islands had been trading with Chinese merchants for hundreds of years and Islamic settlers from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brunei">Brunei</a> lived in the south of the archipelago.</p>
<p>The Spanish turned these disparate islands into a nation named in honour of King Phillip II and introduced Roman Catholicism, which had an impact that continues to be felt today, with most Filipinos identifying themselves as Catholics.</p>
<p>Throughout the Spanish era, the mountain tribes struggled against colonial rule and a revolution began in 1896, but saw the Filipino forces defeated. The Spanish-American War (1898) ended with the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> taking possession of the Philippines, sparking the three-year Philippine-American War (1899-1902) during which atrocities were committed on both sides.</p>
<p>The American occupiers were resisted for many years, but did improve standards of education and infrastructure and finally allowed elections and commonwealth status in 1935. In WWII, the Japanese occupied the country and many of the major cities were devastated.</p>
<p>After the war, the Philippines became one of the founding members of the United Nations and democracy was restored. In 1965 Ferdinand Marcos was elected president and, together with his wife Imelda, set out to modernise the country and rein in the elite families which had long dominated the Philippines. He declared martial law in 1972, strengthening his grip on power and ruthlessly crushing dissent while plundering the country&rsquo;s coffers.</p>
<p>Marcos was deposed in 1986 at the hands of a popular uprising led by Cory Aquino, the wife of assassinated presidential rival Ninoy. Initial euphoria about a return to democracy turned to scepticism as successive administrations were accused of corruption, cronyism and self-interest.</p>
<p>Today wealth distribution remains very uneven, which goes some way to explaining the high number of Filipinos working abroad and sending money home.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The Beatles played two sell-out shows to 80,000 people in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/manila">Manila</a> on 4 July 1966, but inadvertently missed a presidential reception. The next day they were spat at and jostled as they left the country vowing never to return.<br />
&bull;	The Philippines was the first Southeast Asian country to win an Olympic medal.<br />
&bull;	The country is one of the most biologically diverse nations on the planet, home to more than 100 mammal and 170 bird species, which are not found elsewhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of the Philippines in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 467 9300.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.philippineembassy-usa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 467 9300.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1600 Massachusetts Avenue NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of the Philippines in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 207 451 1780.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://philembassy-uk.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 207 451 1780.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1400-1700 (visa applications); Mon-Fri 1600-1700 (visa collection).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>6-8 Suffolk Street<br/>London<br/>SW1Y 4HG<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Manila]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+63 2 858 2200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/philippines</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+63 2 858 2200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0800-1645.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>McKinley Hill<br/>120 Upper McKinley Road<br/>Taguig City 1634<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The <em>other</em> Southeast Asia, the Philippines is where Asia and Europe collide, over a sprawl of sand-circled tropical islands. Here, Catholic traditions meld with animist rituals and Islamic customs, creating a surreal melting pot that is unlike anywhere else in Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>You can thank the Spanish for the European influence, tangible in everything from the names of towns and <em>barrios</em> (neighbourhoods) to restaurant menus, where roast pork and paella are as common as noodles and seafood. Later, the Americans imposed their own vision and values &ndash; you can thank the US for the fastfood chains, the love of pop music, and the rainbow-coloured jeepneys that serve as local buses, evolved from military jeeps left behind from WWII.</p>
<p>With 7,107 islands, it&rsquo;s hardly surprising that many of the Philippines&rsquo; most stunning attractions can be found in or around the sea. Boracay and other islands are ringed by some of the world&rsquo;s most immaculate beaches and the waters offshore are a diver&rsquo;s paradise, with pristine reefs, astounding tropical fish, migrating whale sharks and wrecks from WWII.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s much more, though. Away from the beaches are jungles, mountains, volcanoes and hidden caverns ripe for exploration. The volcanic nature of the islands is highly obvious &ndash; natural hot springs bubble up across the Philippines and the pyramid peaks of live volcanoes such as Mount Mayon call out to trekkers who don&rsquo;t mind living dangerously.</p>
<p>It can&rsquo;t been denied that the Philippines has a seedy side &ndash; the sex industry grew up to service American GIs during the Vietnam War &ndash; but it&rsquo;s easy to avoid this gloomy scene and find more wholesome nightlife, where live bands perform note-perfect covers of any song you could name and even the smallest, palm-thatched village has a karaoke bar.</p>
<p>This isn&rsquo;t a country that stages dozens of phony cultural shows for tourists, and the islands&rsquo; vividly colourful festivals (of which there are many) are predominantly aimed at locals. So it&rsquo;s down to individual visitors to strike up conversations and discover a country where East meets West and traditional culture meets the modern world in a crash of colour and confetti.</p><p>The <em>other</em> Southeast Asia, the Philippines is where Asia and Europe collide, over a sprawl of sand-circled tropical islands. Here, Catholic traditions meld with animist rituals and Islamic customs, creating a surreal melting pot that is unlike anywhere else in Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>You can thank the Spanish for the European influence, tangible in everything from the names of towns and barrios (neighbourhoods) to restaurant menus, where roast pork and paella are as common as noodles and seafood. Later, the Americans imposed their own vision and values &ndash; you can thank the US for the fast food chains, the love of pop music, and the rainbow-coloured jeepneys that serve as local buses, evolved from military jeeps left behind from WWII.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
