<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Poland" ColCode="pol" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="pl" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Poland]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Poland&rsquo;s climate is temperate with warm (sometimes very hot) summers, crisp, sunny autumns and cold winters. Snow covers the mountainous area in the south of Poland (mid-December to April). Rain falls throughout the year.</p>
<p>The most pleasant times to visit Poland are late spring and early summer (May-June) and late summer and early autumn (September-October), when it's still warm and the crowds of tourists have either not yet arrived or already gone home. The added advantages of these shoulder seasons is that you&rsquo;ll hit the asparagus season in spring and enjoy the best hiking conditions in early autumn.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Light- to mediumweights are worn during warmer months. Medium- to heavyweight clothing is needed during winter. Rainwear is advisable all year. You might also want to bring good walking shoes/hiking boots for urban/rural exploration. In general Poles dress casually, but where there is an event on, it&rsquo;s to the nines. If you expect to attend a wedding or red-letter party, bring something dressy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>LOT Polish Airlines (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.lot.com">www.lot.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>)&nbsp;operate domestic flights. There is a comprehensive network linking all major cities.</p>
<p>As in most European countries however, the train system is fairly comprehensive (at least between cities), and goes from centre to centre obviating long trips to and from airports.</p><p>Most airports are a manageable distance of between 10 and 20km (6 and 12 miles) from city centres, with the exception of those at Szczecin and Katowice.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Polskie Koleje Państwowe (PKP; Polish State Railways) (tel: 19757, in Poland only; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.pkp.pl">www.pkp.pl</a>) operates cheap and efficient InterCity trains and links all parts of the country in a network radiating from Warsaw. There are two classes of travel (1st class is 50% more expensive then 2nd) and trains are often classified as InterCity, express, &lsquo;fast&rsquo; and &lsquo;ordinary&rsquo; (or local). For comfort and speed stick to InterCity (IC) or express (Ex) routes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Poland. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (<a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p>Eurail Poland Pass: offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Poland. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When driving in Poland you need to keep your wits about you; this can be quite a trying place for motorists, especially along country roads and at night.</p>r<p>Road quality ranges from smooth brand-new motorways to narrow, pot-holed single lanes, with horse-drawn carts, tractors and other agricultural machinery in abundance.</p><p>Poland has a comprehensive bus network run mostly by Polonus (tel: 703 403 403, in Poland only; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.pkspolonus.pl">www.pkspolonus.pl</a>) that links up even the smallest village connected by road. But buses are useful on short routes only; trains are always quicker and more comfortable.</p><p>Taxis are easily available and not too expensive in towns and cities. Hail them on the street or go to a <em>post&oacute;j taks&oacute;wek</em> (taxi stand). Avoid unlicensed pirate (called &lsquo;mafia&rsquo; in Poland) taxis.</p><p>Tourists travelling in their own cars should have vehicle registration documents, their national driving licence (driving licences of EU nationals are accepted) and third-party insurance documents. Green Card motor insurance is necessary for vehicles coming from outside the EU and Switzerland. An International Driving Permit is required for those from outside the EU.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 90-100kph (56-62mph) on main roads and 120-140kph (75-87mph) on motorways. Seat belts and warning triangles are compulsory. Trams have the right of way. Headlights must be switched on at all times.</p><p>For roadside assistance, contact the Polish Automobile and Motorway Federation, Polski Związek Motorowy (PZM) (tel: 19637, in Poland only; <a href="http://www.pzm.pl" target="_blank">www.pzm.pl</a>).</p><p>Self-drive cars are available at the airport or through various car-hire offices in town centres. All major firms are available. The minimum age for hiring a car is 21; some go as high as 23 or even 25.</p><p>Poland is a great place to get around by bicycle as most of the country is fairly flat and you can put your bike on the train to cover long distances more quickly. Dedicated cycle lanes are few and far between in most cities outside Warsaw, Cracow and Wrocław, but growing.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, 90-100kph (56-62mph) on main roads and 120-140kph (75-87mph) on motorways. Seat belts and warning triangles are compulsory. Trams have the right of way. Headlights must be switched on at all times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Warsaw:</strong> In Warsaw, the Municipal Transport Board (ZTM) is responsible for the bus, metro and tram services. ZTM tickets are valid for all services and can be purchased as a single ride or as a day, week or monthly pass. Some buses allow the purchase of tickets on board but require exact change; it is best to buy before you use any transport.</p>
<p><strong>Cracow:</strong> The MPK is the transport board responsible for public buses and trams in Cracow and the system works similarly to the one in Warsaw, except there is no metro. Public transport tickets are available in all towns at green Ruch (traffic) kiosks, hotels and post offices. Most public transport operates from 0500-2300; night buses, in the major cities, run from 2300-0500.</p>
<p>Taxis are available in all main towns. You can usually find them at ranks or order them by phone. There is a surcharge (rate 2) from 2300-0500 and for journeys out of town, as well as at weekends. Taxi drivers are not normally tipped, unless the driver has been helpful and/or the journey seamless.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Poland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">wroclaw</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.35</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Poland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">poznan</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Poland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">gdansk</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.40</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Poland</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">cracow</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.35</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Poland's national airline is LOT Polish Airlines (<a href="http://www.lot.com" target="_blank">www.lot.com</a>). Other airlines operating flights to Poland include easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>), Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) and Wizz (<a href="http://www.wizzair.com" target="_blank">www.wizzair.com</a>).</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s no real seasonal variation in prices, but Poles are particularly family orientated and those based abroad return home on key (usually religious) holidays such as Christmas and especially Easter, so book ahead at these times.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/poland/john-paul-ii-international-airport-cracow">Cracow John Paul II International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/poland/warsaw-frederic-chopin-airport">Warsaw Chopin Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/poland/poznan-lawica-airport">Poznan Lawica Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/poland/rzeszow-jasionka-airport">Rzeszow-Jasionka Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/poland/wroclaw-copernicus-airport">Wroclaw Copernicus Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/poland/gdansk-lech-walesa-airport">Gdansk Lech Walesa Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/poland/katowice-international-airport">Katowice International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/warsaw">Warsaw</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 20 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 8 hours 10 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most international flights arrive at and depart from Warsaw Chopin Airport. A second airport, Warszawa-Modlin International Airport, serves low-cost carriers. Other important airports are at Cracow, Gdańsk, Poznań and Wrocław.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most international flights arrive at and depart from Warsaw Chopin Airport. A second airport, Warszawa-Modlin International Airport, serves low-cost carriers. Other important airports are at Cracow, Gdańsk, Poznań and Wrocław.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Warsaw Chopin Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.lotnisko-chopina.pl<p>Warsaw Chopin Airport is located 10 km (6 miles) southwest of central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/warsaw">Warsaw</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+48 22 650 4220</p>]]><b>Cracow John Paul II International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.krakowairport.pl<p>Cracow John Paul II International Airport is located 11km (7 miles) to the west of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cracow">Cracow</a>'s city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+48 12 295 5800</p>]]><b>Gdansk Lech Walesa Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport.gdansk.pl<p>The airport is located 12.5km (7.5 miles) north west of Gdańsk city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>801 066 808 or 525 673 531</p>]]><b>Katowice International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.katowice-airport.com<p>The airport is located 30 km (19 miles) north of Katowice.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+48 32 392 7000.</p>]]><b>Poznan-Lawica Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport-poznan.com.pl<p>The airport is located about 7 km (4 miles) west of central Poznań.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+48 61 849 2343</p>]]><b>Wrocław-Copernicus Airport</b><![CDATA[http://airport.wroclaw.pl<p>The airport is located approximately 10km (6 miles) west of the city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+48 71 358 1381</p>]]><b>Rzeszow-Jasionka Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.rzeszowairport.pl<p>The airport is located 10km (6 miles) north of Rzeszów.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+48 17 852 0081.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Port of Gdańsk (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.portgdansk.pl">www.portgdansk.pl</a>) on the Gulf of Gdańsk is the largest Polish port and the main ferry hub for Poland in the Baltic. The Port of Gdynia (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.port.gdynia.pl">www.port.gdynia.pl</a>), just north of Gdańsk, also welcomes ships, containers and cruise liners.</p>
<p>Larger cruise ships usually dock in Gydnia, about a 45-minute drive from the Old Town in Gdańsk. Some small ships may dock at Oliwskie Pier in Gdańsk, about 6km (4 miles) from the town centre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Polskie Koleje Państwowe (PKP; Polish State Railways) (tel: 19757, in Poland only, or +48 22 39 19757; <a href="http://www.pkp.pl" target="_blank">www.pkp.pl</a>) operates EuroCity trains between Poland and a number of major European cities. All services from western Europe to Poland pass through the Czech Republic, Germany or Slovakia. The main routes link Warsaw with Berlin and Cologne, Budapest, Prague and Vienna. There are also rail services to Moscow, St Petersburg, Minsk, Kiev and Vilnius.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Poland shares a border with seven countries, so there are plenty of road crossings. There are more crossings with Germany and the Czech Republic and Slovakia to the west and the south than there are with Ukraine, Belarus, Lithuania and Russia to the north and northeast.</p>
<p>Up to a dozen different national and international bus companies offer services to/from European cities outside Poland. The biggest is Eurolines Polska (tel: +48 146 571 777; <a href="http://www.eurolinespolska.pl" target="_blank">www.eurolinespolska.pl</a>).</p><p>Poland, an EU country in the Schengen zone, no longer maintains border posts with its EU neighbours: Germany, the Czech Republic, Slovakia and Lithuania.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>You can buy telephone cards from post offices, newspaper kiosks and hotel receptions for both domestic and international calls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies; most of the country is covered. You can buy local SIM cards once in Poland and use them in unlocked GSM handsets, with top-ups available at phone shops, newspaper kiosks and some ATMs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many internet cafés in cities and Wi-Fi is available in hotels, hostels and cafés and plenty of other public spaces.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>State-owned TV (TVP) still has the largest share of the audience for its two national channels. It also operates regional programmes and the international satellite channels. TVN operates the leading commercial TV channels. Polsat also operates a digital pay-TV platform. Up to a quarter of Poles also watch foreign television channels through cable or satellite. State-owned Polskie Radio (Polish Radio) reaches just over half of the population and there are six national stations and 17 regional ones on the air.</p>
<p>There are more than 300 newspapers, most of them local or regional. Although fewer people in Poland may be connected to broadband connections than those in other EU countries (due to a delay in infrastructure in rural areas), freedom of the press and communications availability is held as an important priority.</p>
<p>The principal dailies are <em>Gazeta Wyborcza, Rzeczpospolita</em> and the tabloid <em>Super Express</em>. The biggest selling daily, <em>Fakt</em>, is a populist tabloid with over 7 million readers. Weeklies include <em>Gazeta Polska, Polityka</em> and <em>Wprost</em>. English-language publications include the weeklies <em>The Warsaw Voice</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.warsawvoice.pl">www.warsawvoice.pl</a>) and <em>New Poland Express</em> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.newpolandexpress.pl">www.newpolandexpress.pl</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Count on three days for post to reach the UK and up to a week for the USA.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1800 (0800-2000 in major cities); some offices are open on Saturday until 1300. The main post offices in major cities are open daily, 24 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Climb the Tatras Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For alpine diversions there's nowhere better than the Tatras. Zakopane is a centre for climbing and winter sports where a fairy-tale atmosphere pervades with its "gingerbread" wooden cottages – some inhabitants still wear traditional <em>goralski</em> (highlander) dress. Visit the beautiful Kościeliska Valley, Mount Kasprowy Wierch and the emerald-green glacial lake Morskie Oko.</p>]]><p><b>Delve into the Wieliczka Salt Mine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The spectacular Wieliczka Salt Mine, located just outside Cracow, is one of Poland's premier tourist attractions. Built in the 13th century, the UNESCO-listed site boasts 300km (186 miles) of shafts and tunnels, which are festooned with statues and chapels hewn out of salt by miners. Just 2km (1.2 miles) of the mine is accessible to visitors and the tourist route takes visitors 135m (445ft) underground as it passes through impressive chambers, with bas-reliefs, chandeliers and a chapel sculpted.</p>]]><p><b>Enter Lublin through the Cracow Gate</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The primary entrance into the Old Town, the Cracow Gate is considered to be the landmark symbol of Lublin. Built in the late 14th century and remodelled in 1782, its tower of red brick was part of the original city fortifications. It also houses a historical museum.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the old port city of Gdańsk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gdańsk is home to the largest Gothic church in Poland, St Mary's Basilica, while the beach resort at nearby Sopot has the Molo, Europe's longest pier at 515m (1700ft). Within easy reach are the forested Hel Peninsula and beach, the Kashubian Lakeland, and the Teutonic castles at Malbork and Gniew.</p>]]><p><b>Go hiking in Poland's nature reserves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are few things more inspiring than a march through Poland's national parks and nature reserves. Hikers should visit Kampinos National Park near Warsaw, while the Bieszczady National Park, part of the Carpathian Mountain, contains the surviving fragments of the Great Bieszczady Forest, home to lynx, wolf, wildcat and up to 120 brown bears.</p>]]><p><b>Go mushroom picking</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Going for a long meandering walk in the woods to pick mushrooms in the early autumn is a great way to spend a day in Poland. In fact, mushroom picking has been a Polish tradition for centuries, and many delicious varieties exist in the country. Just be sure to go with an experienced mushrooms expert.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the beaches of the Pomeranian coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Poland boasts some of the very best beaches in northern Europe, especially the resorts along the Pomeranian coast, such as large and fashionable Kołobrzeg or Łeba, whose beach is of fabulous white sand. The beach connects to the Słowiński National Park, known for its giant "wandering sand dunes" which can shift several metres each year.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about the Holocaust at Auschwitz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The victims of the Holocaust are remembered at Oświęcim-Birkenau (Auschwitz-Birkenau) concentration camp, now a state museum 66km (41 miles) from Cracow. Visiting is a sobering experience, but helps give you perspective on one of history's darkest periods.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about the resistance in the Warsaw Rising Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A walk through the Warsaw Rising Museum is an educational and interactive experience that anyone interested in Poland's World War II history should not miss. The museum features films, testimonials, slides and artefacts from the war when Warsaw residents were active in the resistance.</p>]]><p><b>Sail your way through the Masurian Lake District</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Masurian Lake District, consisting of over 1,000 lakes, is a favourite angling and boating destination. A popular trail can take you past several lakes and canals. Local towns such as Mikołajki and Giżycko host sea-shanty festivals and other lively events.</p>]]><p><b>See the bison in Białowieża National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Białowieża National Park is the last major refuge of the European bison as well as being home to many other rare forest-dwelling species, and trees up to 500 years old. Nature trails, cycling and exploring with a ranger are on offer.</p>]]><p><b>Soak up the medieval vibes of Cracow</b></p><![CDATA[<p>You'll immediately feel the charming medieval atmosphere of UNESCO-listed Cracow, one of Europe's most significant historical sites. In the middle of the main market square (the largest in Europe) is the Cloth Hall, which dates back to 14th-century. There's also the fascinating former Jewish quarter and its 16th-century Remuh synagogue, Wawel Castle and the Gothic cathedral. Great bars and restaurants abound.</p>]]><p><b>Travel by horse-drawn sleigh</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A horse-drawn sleigh ride is a magical experience, though be sure to have either warmed beer or heated honey vodka afterwards. Snow falls throughout Poland during the winter months so these types of rides are on offer all over the country, but principally in the Tatras at Zakopane.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Warsaw's reconstructed Old Town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Although much of it was destroyed during World War II, the Polish capital of Warsaw still deserves your attention. The Old Town was so masterfully reconstructed from original plans and paintings from the 17th and 18th centuries that it's hard to believe it's just a half a century old when you stroll its quaint cobbled streets. For an unforgettable view of the city, take a lift to the observation deck atop the Palace of Culture and Science, one of Warsaw's architectural icons.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Icon of the Black Madonna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Icon of the Black Madonna, also known as the miraculous painting of Our Lady, can be seen in the huge Jasna Góra monastery complex at Czestochowa, 100km (60 miles) north of Cracow. It is reputed to have been painted by St Luke.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Old City of Zamość</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Renaissance-style market square in Zamość with its almost perfectly preserved 16th-century town centre is just one of the many designated UNESCO World Heritage sites in Poland. The stunning Old City was built by architect Bernando Morando, who followed Italian models of the 'ideal city'.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the house of Poland's greatest composer Chopin</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The manor house where the famous Polish composer Frederic Chopin was born in Żelazowa Wola, 53km (33 miles) west of Warsaw, makes for a great day trip. Attractions include attractive gardens, summertime recitals and 19th-century instruments and furniture used by the great man.</p>]]><p><b>Wander the medieval town of Toruń</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The medieval walled town of Toruń is one of Poland's best sights. The well-preserved Gothic treasure straddling the mighty Vistula river is made up of quaint cobbled streets, redbrick houses and old fortifications. Also Copernicus was born here, as was the special <em>pierniki</em> gingerbread loved throughout Poland.</p>]]><p><b>Wander the pretty town of Wrocław</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Known as Breslau in German and long a part of the German Empire, Wrocław is a diverse city. Visually, it's unique, with some 100 bridges crossing canals or connecting the city's many islands. Important sights include the 15th-century town hall, now the City Historical Museum, the giant Racławice Panorama, and the cathedral on Ostrów Tumski (Cathedral Island).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$477 billion (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transport equipment, food and live animals, chemicals and related products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Mineral fuels and lubricants, miscellaneous manufactured goods, chemicals and related products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, France, UK, Czech Republic and Italy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following the chaos of the 'big bang' strategy of rapid post-communist transition to a market economy, Poland's economy slowly strengthened during the 1990s. By 2000, the private sector accounted for 70% of GDP and the economy was looking in good shape, though it lacked behind many of its former communist neighbours.<br />
Poland became a full member of the European Union on 1 May 2004 and plans eventually to adopt the Euro but not before 2020 at the earliest. Poland weathered the global financial crisis of 2008 well. It has a large internal economy, still manufactures a number of goods people buy, exports are booming and inflation is among the lowest in the region. Growth was 3.9% and unemployment stood at 7.9% in 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Poland, a formal approach is favoured, and it is therefore advisable to address an associate with a title and surname unless there is an established rapport.</p>
<p>Letters of introduction are extremely useful for establishing contact with businesses in Poland. Presentations should be thoroughly prepared and, at a minimum, the executive summary should be translated. Decisions are often by committee here, so negotiations may be protracted and a deal cannot be confirmed until all parties have signed.</p>
<p>Handshaking is customary, an older man will often kiss a woman&rsquo;s hand, and business cards (preferably with titles translated) should be exchanged with all participants at a meeting. The dress code is, on the whole, quite conservative. Breakfast meetings are rare, although business lunches and dinners are popular.</p>
<p>The end of communism brought the careers of many Polish people to a premature end, as the older generation was thought to represent an outdated system and inflexible attitudes. Consequently, many of those holding high positions in Warsaw's business world today are relatively young. They are also more likely to speak English and other languages.</p>
<p>Poles love to stay up late, talking and drinking, and dinner invitations are likely. The person who issues the invitation is generally the one who pays the bill. It is important for visitors to make sure that if giving a gift of flowers, there should always be an odd number.</p><p>Most offices in major industries open Mon-Fri 0830-1700. Government offices are open Mon-Fri 0830-1630. A few independent businesses may open on Saturday morning.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Krajowa Izba Gospodarcza (Polish Chamber of Commerce)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (022) 630 9600
					Website:http://www.kig.pl/
					Address: ,Ulica Trebacka 4,Warsaw,00-074]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>You've not really experienced Poland until you've had a plate of <em>pierogi</em>. Crescent-shaped and made from dough, they are a bit like ravioli in that they are stuffed with a whole range of fillings, including cottage cheese, potato and onion, minced meat, sauerkraut or even fruit, then fried or boiled.</p>
<p>There's much more to Polish food than its <em>pierogi</em>, however. A wide range of ingredients populate the kitchen here, including dill, marjoram, caraway seeds, wild mushrooms and sour cream, which is frequently added to soups, sauces and braised meats.</p>
<p>Soups play an important part at mealtimes and are usually rich and very thick. A staple soup is <em>żurek</em> made with stock, bacon, onion, mushrooms and sour cream, and is given a distinctive, almost sour taste with the addition of <em>kwas</em>, a kind of fermented rye flour. It's often accompanied by hard-boiled egg or <em>kiełbasa </em>(Polish sausage).</p>
<p>Main courses include fish dishes using trout, carp and herring, as well as stuffed cabbage leaves, pork chops and other heavy-going, meaty fare. Polish cuisine is also noticeable for its pastries; you'll find a wide selection in the <em>cukiernia</em>, a patisserie or cake shop. Poles traditionally wish each other <em>smacznego</em>, the Polish equivalent of &lsquo;bon appetit&rsquo;, at the start of a meal. They end it in a delightful way too &ndash; by saying thank you to one another!</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bigos</strong>: Sauerkraut, fresh cabbage, onions and any variety of leftover meat.<br />
<strong>Kasza gryczana</strong>: Buckwheat groats.<br />
<strong>Kiełbasa</strong>: Polish sausage.<br />
<strong>Kluski</strong>: Dumplings about the size of golf balls sometimes served on their own with cottage cheese or poppy seeds.<br />
<strong>Pierogi</strong>: Dumplings stuffed with meat, mushrooms and cabbage or cheese.<br />
<strong>Zurek</strong>: A soup made with stock, bacon, onion, mushrooms and sour cream, and is given a distinctive, almost sour taste with the addition of <em>kwas</em>.<br />
<strong>Krupnik</strong>: A thick barley potage containing a variety of vegetables and small chunks of meat. Better known than those two, though, is <em>barszcz</em> (or <em>borscht </em>&ndash; beetroot soup), which runs thin and clear and is often served in cups with small hot pasties stuffed with meat or cabbage.<br />
<strong>Gołąbki</strong>: Cabbage leaves stuffed with beef, onion and rice and baked in tomato sauce.<br />
<strong>Golonka</strong>: Boiled pig's knuckle served with horseradish and sauerkraut.<br />
<strong>Szarlotka</strong>: A dessert that's somewhere between an apple pie and a pastry.<br />
<strong>Sernik</strong>: Cheesecake made from special Polish cheese filling.<br />
<strong>Pączki</strong>: Jam doughnuts.<br />
<strong>Makowiec</strong>: Poppy seed cake.<br />
<strong>Żywiec</strong>: A fairly strong lager.<br />
<strong>W&oacute;dka</strong>: The country's national tipple is Polish vodka, which comes in many different varieties.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A tip of 10 to 15% is customary in restaurants and cafés. Usually you just add it in and tell the waiter how much you are paying in total (including the tip). Do not just hand the waiter a note and say 'thank you' at the same time, which here means 'keep the change'.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nightlife in Poland is rich and exciting, taking in everything from cultural and artistic exhibitions and performances to good old-fashioned vodka bars where you can eat cheap <em>pierogi</em> (dumplings) and drink one of the many excellent Polish beers.</p>
<p>The best-known theatres in the country are in Warsaw and Cracow, with additional well-established ones in Wrocław, Poznań, Białystok and Zakopane. Musically, the National Philharmonic and a National Opera in Warsaw are the country's most celebrated. In terms of popular music, rock and pop are as big here as they are anywhere in the world and jazz has its loyal followers. But home-grown Polish hip-hop is firmly rooted in the mainstream now and heard just about everywhere in the country.<br />
<br />
Cinema is very popular in Poland, and you can find cinemas in all sizable towns. There is a large selection of dance clubs, bars and venues for live music in most towns. Clubs often choose to stay open until the last guest leaves. The best places for clubbing are Warsaw, Wrocław, Cracow and Gdańsk. As well as clubbing, Poles love to spend the evenings in cosy bars and inns, where beer and, of course, vodka is drunk in large quantities. These are also usually venues for live music.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>More than anything else, arts and crafts are the main things to shop for on a visit to Poland. Particularly popular items that are widely available include glass and enamelware, hand-woven rugs, silverware, jewellery made with silver, dolls in regional costumes, woodcarvings and clay and metal sculptures. The nationwide chain Cepelia (<a href="http://www.cepelia.pl" target="_blank">www.cepelia.pl</a>), with branches in most big cities, is the place to head first - its shops stock a good range of local handicrafts. Another much loved item available widely is amber, especially in the north of the country in and around Gdańsk. This can be sold in many forms, from large lumps to exquisitely carved necklaces.</p>
<p>For more standard shopping experiences, Warsaw and Cracow are the best bets. Both cities have a large number of department and clothing stores, many of which are international chains. Warsaw also has the country's best selection of art on sale, ranging from smart art galleries to informal art markets. Your best bet for art, bric-a-brac, curios and the odd real antique is a chain of shops called Desa Unicum (<a href="http://www.desa.pl" target="_blank">www.desa.pl</a>). Bear in mind that the export of anything produced up until the end of WWII in 1945 is strictly controlled (though the people at Desa Unicum are very familiar with the procedures and will help with the necessary paperwork).</p>
<p>Polish posters are renowned around the world for their bold colours and striking graphics. They&rsquo;ve become major collector&rsquo;s items and the best ones are not cheap, but have a look at specialised shops and galleries in Warsaw and Cracow.</p><p>Mon-Fri 1000-1800/2000 and Sat 1000-1300/1600. 'Night shops' open 24 hours. Supermarkets and department stores are usually open daily 1000-1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major international hotel chains are represented in Poland; the largest local chain is run by Orbis (www.orbis.pl), with more than 60 properties nationwide.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Poland are graded in five categories: Luxury, 4-star, 3-star, 2-star and 1-star. In addition there are tourist hotels, boarding houses and motels, each graded into three or four categories. At the bottom of the heap are sports and workers&rsquo; hotels, many of which look they are stuck in a 1960s time warp.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Guest houses, or pensions (<em>pensjonaty</em>) can be rated on a 1- to 3-star rating, but if it hasn't been rated, it doesn't mean it's not good - it might just be very small without a lift or fire door. You&rsquo;ll often find such bed and breakfasts in the mountains and by the sea. Guest houses can range from very basic bunk houses to cosy or even luxurious accommodation with spas and conference facilities. You can often make reservations through local tourist offices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major international hotel chains are represented in Poland; the largest local chain is run by Orbis (www.orbis.pl), with more than 60 properties nationwide.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Poland are graded in five categories: Luxury, 4-star, 3-star, 2-star and 1-star. In addition there are tourist hotels, boarding houses and motels, each graded into three or four categories. At the bottom of the heap are sports and workers&rsquo; hotels, many of which look they are stuck in a 1960s time warp.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major international hotel chains are represented in Poland; the largest local chain is run by Orbis (www.orbis.pl), with more than 60 properties nationwide.</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels in Poland are graded in five categories: Luxury, 4-star, 3-star, 2-star and 1-star. In addition there are tourist hotels, boarding houses and motels, each graded into three or four categories. At the bottom of the heap are sports and workers&rsquo; hotels, many of which look they are stuck in a 1960s time warp.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The quality of medical care is generally high in Poland but not always outside cities and large towns. Chemists open 24 hours can be found in each major city, and hotels often have a nurse or doctor on call. In emergencies call 999 for an ambulance.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Insurance: If you're an EU citizen, a European Health Insurance Card (EHIC), available from health centres, covers you for most medical care. It will not cover you for non-emergencies or emergency repatriation though. Citizens from other countries should find out if there is a reciprocal arrangement for free medical care between their country and Poland. All foreigners are entitled to first-aid and ambulance services only when they have suffered an accident and require immediate medical attention; follow-up treatment and medicine must be paid for. If you do need health insurance while travelling, consider a policy that covers you for the worst possible scenario, such as an accident requiring an ambulance or an emergency flight home.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains and well water is safe to drink, but don't drink water from rivers or lakes even if it looks pristine - it may contain bacteria or viruses that can bring on diarrhoea and vomiting. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two words of caution - a lot of dishes in Polish cuisine are stuffed or wrapped. Avoid them at a cafeteria or buffet if they look like they have outlasted their shelf life. Also, Poles can be big drinkers and vodka is the national drink. You definitely won't be able to keep up with your fellow drinkers for long. Go easy and either miss a few turns or sip your drink in stages. Otherwise count on the mother of all hangovers and an upset stomach the next day.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Another one is against tick-borne encephalitis. This is spread by small insects that burrow under the skin and in recent years has become a common problem in parts of central and eastern Europe. Encephalitis is a serious infection of the brain, and vaccination is advised particularly for campers and hikers. Anyone who is considering spending a lot of time outdoors in affected areas should consider getting the jab before they leave home. Two inoculations of the vaccine will protect the recipient for a year while three doses provide protection for up to three years.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>State Holiday :
							01 May </p><p>Constitution Day :
							03 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Independence Day :
							11 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Second Day of Christmas :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Poland by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco (if arriving by air or sea).<br />
&bull; 40 cigarettes or 20 cigarillos or 10 cigars or 50g of tobacco (if arriving by land or rail).<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22%.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlicensed firearms and ammunition, narcotics, meat and dairy products from outside the EU. Endangered species require a permit.</p>
<p>You may only import small quantities of plants, fruit and vegetables for personal use, otherwise they require a phytosanitary certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Certain arts and antiquities require an export licence, eg archaeological artefacts more than 100 years old or paintings more than 50 years old. Endangered species also require a permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Złoty (PLN; symbol zł) = 100 groszy. Notes are in denominations of zł200, 100, 50, 20 and 10. The coins are in denominations of zł5, 2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 groszy. Poland is required under the terms of its accession to the European Union in 2004 to adopt the Euro as its national currency sometime in the future but this is not expected to happen for at least three years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can exchange foreign currency at all border crossing points, hotels and bureaux de change (<em>kantors</em>), some of which are open 24 hours. These are always good bets as they are fast, efficient and generally charge no commission (though it&rsquo;s always safe to double-check their rate of exchange). Hotel rates and goods in large stores may also be listed in Euros, but payment is usually expected in złoty.</p>
<br />]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted in larger establishments. You can obtain cash from Visa credit and debit cards at banks and from ATMs. MasterCard is also accepted by some ATMs.</p><p>You can obtain cash from Visa credit and debit cards at most ATMs. Most also accept MasterCard, Cirrus and Maestro cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These can be exchanged but they&rsquo;re usually more expensive and troublesome than ATM withdrawals. Also, exchanging traveller&rsquo;s cheques in Poland has been reported to be problematic; most bureaux de change (<em>kantors</em>) won&rsquo;t change them and the banks that do usually charge a commission on top of the one you&rsquo;ve already paid when buying the traveller&rsquo;s cheques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1600, Sat 0900-1300 in main cities. In smaller towns, banking hours are more limited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa fees are waived for children under six and are reduced for those between six and 12.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Poland is a signatory to the Schengen Agreement. A 90-day visa allows you to visit all the Schengen countries but you cannot exceed 90 days in total. Once your 90 days is up, you must leave the Schengen zone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay Schengen visa: &euro;60. Be sure to get one of these rather than a transit visa, which costs the same but is only good for a period of two days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applicants must book an appointment online at the closest Polish consulate or embassy in their country of residence (<a href="http://www.e-konsulat.gov.pl">www.e-konsulat.gov.pl</a>). All visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Non-EU nationals planning to stay longer than three months must apply for a temporary residence permit at the consulate.</p>
<p>EU nationals wishing to stay longer than three months must register with the Department of Nationals' and Foreigners' Affairs. See <a href="http://www.malopolska.uw.gov.pl">www.malopolska.uw.gov.pl</a>&nbsp;for more information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Between two weeks and one month, depending on the applicant&rsquo;s passport/nationality.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa applicants must prove that they have sufficient means of subsistence, both for the period of the intended stay and for the return to their country of origin or transit to a third country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay visas are only extended in emergencies (eg medical ones).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A pet must have an ISO pet microchip inserted and then be vaccinated for rabies and various other diseases at least 21 days prior to travel and not more than one year prior to travel. Contact any Polish mission abroad for more details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[52.146986]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[19.378032]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>312,685 sq km (120,728 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>38,593,161 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>123.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Warsaw.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Poland shares borders with Belarus, Ukraine, Lithuania and the Russian exclave of Kaliningrad to the east and northeast; Czech Republic and Slovakia&nbsp;to the south;&nbsp;and Germany&nbsp;to the west. To the north lies the Baltic Sea.</p>
<p>The Baltic coast provides almost 525km (325 miles) of sandy beaches, bays and steep cliffs; between Gdańsk, and the port city of Szczecin to the west there are many seaside towns offering unpolluted water and some fine beaches, with sunbeds and umbrellas available for hire. These sand and gravel deposits also form the shifting dunes of Słowiński National Park, the sand bars of Hel and the Vistula Lagoon.</p>
<p>Northern Poland is dominated by lakes, islands and wooded hills joined by many rivers and canals. The Masurian Lake District to the northeast is a patchwork of lakes and forests with Lake Hańcza, the deepest lake in Poland, located here. The longest river, the 1,090km (675 mile) Vistula, or Wisła, rises in the Tatra mountains and empties into the Baltic, cutting a wide valley between the capital, Warsaw in the heart of the country, to Gdańsk on the coast.</p>
<p>The rest of the country rises slowly to the Sudety mountains, which run along the border with the Czech Republic, and the Tatra Mountains, which separate Poland from Slovakia. To the west, the River Oder, with Szczecin at its mouth, forms the northwest border with Germany.</p>
<p>Poland counts almost two dozen national parks, covering an area of 3,200 sq km (1,235 sq miles), and including the oldest, Białowieża National Park, east of Warsaw on the border with Belarus, and one of the largest, Bieszczady National Park, part of the Carpathian mountain range.</p>
<p>These parks are home to European bison (the largest mammal in Europe), brown bears, lynx, wolves and even some wild horses. And Białowieża contains a fragment of the forest that once covered Europe prehistoric times, with some oaks dating back half a millennium. Polish forests are largely pine though, accounting for two-thirds of the total.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>More than 95% identify as Roman Catholic; Polish Autocephalous Orthodox (so-called Old Believers), Russian and Greek Orthodox, Protestants and Jews make up the other 5%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Poles are friendly, industrious people and foreigners are usually made very welcome. There are vast contrasts between urban and rural life and the Polish peasantry is very religious and conservative, maintaining a traditional lifestyle. Roman Catholicism plays an important role in daily life and criticism or jokes about religion are not appreciated, despite the general good humour of the people.<br />
<br />
Shaking hands is the normal form of greeting; an older man will often kiss a woman&rsquo;s hand. Normal courtesies are observed when visiting private homes, and it is customary to bring flowers, preferably in odd numbers. Fairly conservative casual wear is the most suitable attire, but dress should be formal when specified for entertaining in the evening or in a smart restaurant. Smoking is banned in public places, including railway stations, restaurants and bars.<strong><br />
</strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz; European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Mateusz Morawiecki&nbsp;since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Andrzej Duda since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The history of Poland begins in the Early Middle Ages with the migration of Slavs into the area, which by the 10th century had established a permanent settlement and founded the nascent Polish state. At its peak, it was one of the large nations in Europe, prospering under a commonwealth with Lithuania, but by the 18th century its territory had been reduced to little more than a buffer state between the three kingdoms of Austria, Prussia and Russia. Between 1772 and 1795, the country was carved up amongst the three countries and did not gain independence again until the end of WWI in 1918.</p>
<p>In 1926, a military regime under J&oacute;zef Piłsudski ousted the civilian administration and governed Poland until the country was once again dismembered by its powerful neighbours, Germany and the Soviet Union, under the terms of their so-called Anti-Aggression Pact of 1939. Commitments by the UK to defend Polish sovereignty were ignored when Germany invaded Poland in September 1939, starting World War II.</p>
<p>In 1941, the Germans drove the Soviet army out of Poland and were themselves ejected four years later. At the end of World War II, the Soviet-backed Polish Workers' Party formed a coalition government under Władysław Gomułka, until he was dismissed in 1948. In the same year, the Polish Workers' Party merged with the Polish Socialist Party to form the Polish United Workers' Party (PZPR).</p>
<p>In 1956, Gomułka returned to power amidst growing unrest to implement a plan of gradual liberalisation of society and the economy. After disturbances in the industrial ports of Gdańsk, Gdynia and Szczecin in 1970, Gomułka was replaced as first secretary of the party by Edward Gierek.</p>
<p>In 1981, with the backing of Moscow, the former army chief of staff, General Wojciech Jaruzelski, replaced Kania and imposed martial law in response to the Solidarity labour movement, which was banned. The early 1980s saw a tense standoff between the state and the unions, which did not ease until the Gorbachev era.</p>
<p>In 1989, following the virtual collapse of the Polish economy and the falling of the Berlin Wall, the PZPR government opened genuine negotiations with Solidarity, which was legalised, paving the way for semi-free elections. In 1990, Solidarity's Wałesa became the first popularly elected president of Poland. Poland joined NATO in 1997 and the European Union in 2004.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Poland was not a sovereign state from 1795 to 1918, but desire for a Polish nation burned fiercely unceasingly through the period.<br />
&bull; The Polish constitution was the first in Europe and the second in the world, after India. <br />
&bull; Roughly one third of Poles are thought to live abroad.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Poland]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(022) 311 0000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/poland</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(022) 311 0000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1630.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>ul. Kawalerii 12<br/>Warsaw<br/>00-468<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Poland in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7291 3520.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.london.mfa.gov.pl/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7291 3520.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1630.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>47 Portland Place<br/>London<br/>W1B 1JH<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Poland in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 499 1700.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://washington.mfa.gov.pl/en/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 499 1700.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2640 16th Street NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Underrated but increasingly popular, Poland offers a huge amount for travellers of all stripes &ndash; from the stunning old towns of Krakow, Zamość, Gdańsk and Wroclaw to the wilderness of the Białowieża National Park with its ubiquitous buffalos and epic vistas.</p>
<p>Home to Europe&rsquo;s most infamous ghetto, Warsaw was almost totally destroyed during WWII, but the Polish capital is modernising fast. Today the city blends Soviet architecture and contemporary styles, with a painstakingly recreated old town and an upbeat, progressive population.</p>
<p>Perhaps the country's biggest draw, though, is Krakow. The country's former royal capital is a wonderfully preserved architectural marvel that has somehow managed to survive Poland&rsquo;s many wars. Even the Nazis thought it was too beautiful to bomb. Jam-packed with churches, monasteries and abbeys in Gothic and Renaissance styles, the city became the first ever UNESCO World Heritage Site in 1978 (an honour it shared with Quito, Ecuador).</p>
<p>Beyond Krakow are numerous signs of Poland&rsquo;s proud cultural heritage: Ł&oacute;dź and its famous film school, from which Roman Polański and Krzysztof Kieślowski graduated; Toruń, the hometown of astronomer Nicholas Copernicus; and Warsaw, which lays claim to Marie Curie and Frederick Chopin. The country's biggest port and northern boomtown, Gdańsk, is best known as the birthplace of Lech Wałęsa's Solidarity movement, which led the country into democracy in 1989.</p>
<p>Poland's scenic beauty is as varied as it is extraordinary. The Baltic coast is pretty, while Słowiński National Park is all ethereal forests, bogs and sand dunes. The Great Masurian Lakes in the northeast are popular for kayakers, with hundreds of pristine lakes broken up by dense forest. The Krakow-Wielun Upland with its limestone caves and medieval castles is another highlight, while the Carpathian Mountains in the far south are unremittingly beautiful.</p>
<p>And the food? Polish cuisine is hearty and filling, rich in meat and game. Thick soups such as Zurek are delicious, as are pierogi, or Polish dumplings. And as for the Polish vodka, one of the finest types in the world, what better way to wash all that rich food down?</p><p>Underrated but increasingly popular, Poland offers a huge amount for travellers of all stripes &ndash; from the stunning old towns of Krakow, Zamość, Gdańsk and Wroclaw to the wilderness of the Białowieża National Park with its ubiquitous buffalos and epic vistas.</p>
<p>Home to Europe&rsquo;s most infamous ghetto, Warsaw was almost totally destroyed during WWII, but the Polish capital is modernising fast. Today the city blends Soviet architecture and contemporary styles, with a painstakingly recreated old town and an upbeat, progressive population.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
