<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Madeira" ColCode="mad" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="qm" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Madeira]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mild climate with warm summers and extremely mild winters.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mid-seasonal wear.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Aero VIP (Grupo Seven Air) (<a href="http://bookings.aerovip.pt" target="_blank">bookings.aerovip.pt</a>) operates flights between Funchal and Porto Santo (journey time - 25 minutes).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving on Madeira is fun, but it is also demanding. Few roads are straight, and even fewer on the level. Away from the coast, the mountain roads are twisting and turning and not conducive to high speeds.</p><p>Away from Funchal, the roads are generally in poor condition, although things are improving rapidly. Bad weather, however, can cause landslides, which damage the roads or close them altogether pending repairs.</p><p>You can book coach tours of the island through hotels or through the tourist office on Avenida Arriaga; these offer door-to-door service. Local bus services are there for the resident population and are not geared to the needs of tourists.</p><p>The ubiquitous yellow taxis are relatively inexpensive on both Madeira and Porto Santo, and can be hired for a whole day with an English-speaking driver as a tour guide.</p><p>A valid national driving licence and passport.</p><p>There is no central breakdown and rescue service on Madeira because all visitors use hire cars.</p><p>There are both international and local car hire companies on Madeira, offering competitive rates. You can book cars in advance, and through your hotel, online and on arrival at the airport. A word of warning, however: Madeira is very hilly, so hiring a low-powered car in the belief that you will save fuel is a false premise &ndash; you will spend a lot of time in low gears.</p><p>A number of small companies offer bike hire, but you need to be a regular cyclist to benefit from this way of getting around because of the hilly and often steep nature of the island. Try Free Ride Madeira (<a href="http://freeridemadeira.com" target="_blank">http://freeridemadeira.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Outside Funchal, the main towns are Santa Cruz, Machico (the original island capital), Santana, S&atilde;o Vicente, Porto Moniz, Calgeta, Riberia Brava and Camara de Lobos (the latter much favoured by Sir Winston Churchill). Tarmac roads link all these towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Portugal's national airline, TAP Air Portugal (<a href="http://www.flytap.com/" target="_blank">www.flytap.com</a>), operates services to Funchal from Lisbon. Airlines running direct flights from the UK to Madeira include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Monarch (<a href="http://www.flymonarch.com" target="_blank">www.flymonarch.com</a>).&nbsp;Flights are at their most expensive during the peak months of July to November.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London - 3 hours 50 minutes; New York - 11 hours (including stopover in Lisbon).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Madeira Cristiano Ronaldo Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeroportosdamadeira.pt<p>Madeira Cristiano Ronaldo Airport is located in the town of Santa Cruz, 16km (10 miles) to the northeast of the island&rsquo;s capital, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/funchal">Funchal</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>291 520 700.</p>]]><b>Porto Santo Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.anam.pt/madeira]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The major port is Funchal, now almost exclusively used by cruise ships and pleasure craft. It used to be the main container port for the Island, but a modern commercial port has been built in Cani&ccedil;al especially for commercial traffic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the architecture in Santana</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Santana is arguably the most visited village on the island. Visitors come here to imbibe the quaint rural atmosphere and marvel at its triangular-shaped houses, or <em>palheiros</em>.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Pico Ruivo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The island's highest peak, Pico Ruivo (1,862m/6,109ft) can be reached in under an hour via a paved path from a parking area to the north (Achada do Texeiro), and, not surprisingly, offers spectacular views. Even easier to conquer is the third-highest peak, Pico do Arieiro (1,818m/5,965ft) – it's road all the way, with a bar, restaurant and gift shop at the top.</p>]]><p><b>Go whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The deep waters around Madeira offer some of the best whale watching in the region. The archipelago was once an important outpost for the deadly whaling industry, but since a moratorium on hunting the mammals in 1981, the waters are once again teeming with whales – and dolphins. Tours depart from various locations throughout Madeira.</p>]]><p><b>Hike along the levadas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The <em>levadas </em>are a network of ancient irrigation channels stretching some 2,150km (1335 miles) across the island's slopes from the north of the island. Today, while they continue to provide water to remote valleys, they also represent a supply of ready-made walkways for tourists.</p>]]><p><b>Pilgrimage to Nossa Senhora de Monte</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The cable car from Funchal to Monte leads to the Nossa Senhora de Monte church. On 15 August, it becomes a centre of pilgrimage when worshippers climb the 74 steps on their hands and knees.</p>]]><p><b>Quaff Madeira wine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Madeira is renowned for its fortified wines: Malvasia, Bual, Verdelho and Sercial. Most countries limit the use of the term 'Madeira' to wines that come from the island of Madeira, to which the European Union grants Protected Designation of Origin (PDO) status. The island also produces a light, white, table wine (Vinho Verde), which is superb with salads, and is increasingly producing red table wines in the north of the island. The famous Madeira Wine Festival takes place annually in September.</p>]]><p><b>Take a toboggan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Originally used as a speedy means of descent for villagers, toboggans are today mainly used to carry tourists. Driven by two men (carreiros) dressed in white, with straw hats and black rubber boots that are used as brakes, they use ropes to control the wide, two-person wicker baskets which are mounted on wooden runners. Runs start in Monte (accessible by cable car) and descend rapidly to Livramento, a suburb of Funchal.</p>]]><p><b>Tee off for a leisurely round</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There are three fine golf courses in the Madeira archipelago: the 27-hole Campo de Golfe do Santo da Serra (<a href="http://www.santodaserragolf.com/" target="_blank">www.santodaserragolf.com</a>) an 18-hole Palheiro course (<a href="http://www.palheirogolf.com/" target="_blank">www.palheirogolf.com</a>), and Porto Santo (<a href="http://www.portosantogolfe.com" target="_blank">www.portosantogolfe.com</a>). Construction halted in 2003 on a fourth championship golf course being built in Ponta do Pargo that was designed by famous golfer Nick Faldo.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the old capital, Machico</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Machico is the original capital of Madeira and is home to a magnificent 15th-century parish church, the Chapel of Miracles (a place of pilgrimage) and a small but picturesque 18th-century fort.</p>]]><p><b>While away the day in Funchal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Madeiran capital is set on a natural sweeping bay, backed by richly vegetated slopes that rise to a skyline of rugged peaks. The town is home to a remarkable 16th-century cathedral, the Museum of Sacred Art (<a href="http://www.museuartesacrafunchal.org" target="_blank">www.museuartesacrafunchal.org</a>) and Botanical Gardens &ndash; five hectares (12 acres) of terraced hillside, planted with species from around the globe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>€5.2 billion (2010)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fruit, cereal, fish, wine (especially Madeira wine)</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food stuffs, beverages</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Portugal</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The economy is mainly based on the services sector, and tourism is the largest revenue source of the regional economic activity, providing support for commercial, transport and other activities and constituting a significant market for local products.</p><p>Agriculture is reducing, and being increasingly replaced by international trade in fine products, such as lacework, and wine. In addition to the widely known fortified Madeiran wines, the island is increasingly producing its own table wine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business etiquette is not significantly different from other European countries. Men invariably wear a suit and tie; women dress conservatively.</p><p>Normal hours are Monday-Friday 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>A few restaurants offer fine dining, but for the most part Madeiran food is simple and plentiful; even a lunch of parrot fish will come with potatoes, chips, tomatoes, yams and salad &ndash; bear that in mind if you're used to light lunches. At the start of a meal you may well be served with a basket of home-made bread, whether you order it or not &ndash; it's a delicious accompaniment to an aperitif while you take in the menu.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><em>&bull; Caldeirada </em>(fish soup)<br />
<em>&bull; Bife de atum e milho frito</em> (tuna steak and fried maize)<br />
<em>&bull; Espada</em> (black scabbard fish, often served with a baked banana)<br />
<em>&bull; Bolo de mel</em> (Madeira honey cake)<br />
<em>&bull; Estefada</em> (stew, usually lamb or beef)<br />
<em>&bull; Espetada</em> (skewered chunks of beef grilled over a charcoal fire)</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>The water around Madeira is very deep so, with a few exceptions, seafood such as crabs, langoustines and lobsters have to be imported and are therefore correspondingly expensive. Fish is plentiful and delicious.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Tipping is not generally expected since most hotels and restaurants include a service charge. A small tip for good service can be left at your discretion.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some hotels have excellent nightclubs with music for dancing and international cabaret entertainment. Folk entertainment is also included in the weekly programme of these hotels and, in most cases, non-residents are welcome.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Funchal, there is a wide variety of shops selling everyday goods, as well as many souvenirs. Special purchases include Madeira folk art such as embroidery, tapestry and wickerwork. Madeira wine is a popular gift, but can be purchased duty free at the airport.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1500-1900; Sat 0900-1300. Larger outlets and shops in principal tourist areas stay open through lunch, and often until 2200. Shopping centres are open 7/7, 1000-2200.</p><p>Goods that cannot be produced on the island, e.g. many leather items, have to be imported, and will cost more.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The island's numerous coastal hotels tend to fill up quickly during the summer and over the Christmas period, so early booking is advisable. Most hotels compensate for the lack of beaches by providing swimming pools. Rural homestays are becoming increasingly popular.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The island's numerous coastal hotels tend to fill up quickly during the summer and over the Christmas period, so early booking is advisable. Most hotels compensate for the lack of beaches by providing swimming pools. Rural homestays are becoming increasingly popular.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The island's numerous coastal hotels tend to fill up quickly during the summer and over the Christmas period, so early booking is advisable. Most hotels compensate for the lack of beaches by providing swimming pools. Rural homestays are becoming increasingly popular.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[32.760707]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-16.959472]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>741 sq km (286 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>258,686 (2014).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>359.1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Funchal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Autonomous region of Portugal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The group comprises the main island of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/portugal/madeira/madeira-airport">Madeira</a>, the smaller island of Porto Santo, the three uninhabited islets of Ilheu Chao, Deserta Grande and Ilheu de Bugio, and the Selvagens (a group of uninhabited islets located south of Madeira). The islands are hilly and of volcanic origin and the coast of Madeira is steep and rocky with deep eroded lava gorges running down to the sea. These are particularly impressive on the north coast of Madeira island. The largest of a group of five islands formed by volcanic eruption, Madeira is in fact the summit of a mountain range rising 6.5km (4 miles) from the sea bed.</p>
<p>At Cabo Gir&atilde;o, west of the capital of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/funchal">Funchal</a>, is the second-highest cliff in the world. Inland, Pico Ruivo is the island's highest point (1,862m/6,109ft) with the slightly lower Pico de Arieiro (1,810m/5,940ft) nearby. Both are destinations for sightseeing tours, commanding fine views of the surrounding mountains. Madeira's volcanic origin means that it has no sandy beaches, although there is a small beach, Prainha, near the whaling village of Canical on the extreme east of the island. Madeira itself is 56km (35 miles) long and 21km (13 miles) wide. Porto Santo is much smaller, only 14km (9 miles) long and 5km (3 miles) wide, with a long, golden sandy beach.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholics make up the vast majority of the population in Madeira, but there is also a small protestant community.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Madeirans are warm, hospitable people who revel in exhibitions, films, crafts, concerts, plays and café culture. The summer festival season is a particularly pleasant experience, with carnivals and other jamborees celebrating the archipelago's culture and produce. <br /><br />Casual wear is widely acceptable, but you shouldn't wear beach clothing in towns. Smoking has been prohibited in public indoor spaces since 2008 and the ban includes cinemas, theatres and buses. Some bars and restaurants have special licenses permitting diners and drinkers to smoke inside.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Miguel Albuquerque since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Marcelo Rebelo de Sousa since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>When the Portuguese patron of exploration, Prince Henry 'the Navigator', gathered together the finest cartographers early in the 15th century, his plan was to extend the country&rsquo;s collective knowledge of the coast of West Africa.</p>
<p>He enlisted the services of two young captains, Jo&atilde;o Gon&ccedil;alves Zarco and Trist&atilde;o Vaz Teixeira, who were blown off course on their journey. After many days at sea they found land in the form of a small island which they named Porto Santo. On reporting to their prince, they were promptly ordered to return and colonise the island. The year was 1419.</p>
<p>Today, it seems incredible that it took a further year before the discovery of the much larger island of Madeira was made. The captains had reported a dark mass of clouds visible on the southern horizon, and were encouraged to explore further afield.</p>
<p>As they approached, the huge Atlantic rollers breaking along the north coast and the turmoil of the currents at Ponta de S&atilde;o Louren&ccedil;o would have done nothing to subdue the anxieties of the superstitious sailors. But on rounding the headland they discovered the bay of Machico, the gateway to the densely forested island that they named Madeira &ndash; the name means 'wood'. Prince Henry immediately organised the colonisation of the island.</p>
<p>Sugarcane became the main driver for economic growth in the 15th and 16th century. Early settlers found the island&rsquo;s climate perfect for cultivating this cash crop, which was harvested using slave labour. When the sugar industry migrated to South America, wine became the main industry.</p>
<p>Portugal briefly lost control of the islands when the British occupied them during the Napoleonic Wars. However, they were somewhat reluctantly handed back to the Portuguese in 1814, who governed them until the Carnation Revolution of 1974. Since then Madeira has enjoyed political autonomy from the mainland.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; Former British Prime Minister Winston Churchill was a regular visitor to the fishing village of Camara de Lobos, which he liked to paint.<br />
&bull; Christopher Columbus married Filipa Moniz on the Madeira archipelago in 1478 &ndash; sadly, she died a short time later giving birth to their son.<br />
&bull; The effects of WWI on Portugal were first felt in Funchal, which was shelled for two hours by German U-boats in 1916.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Honorary Consulate in Madeira]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(0291) 212 860.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(0291) 212 860.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri (closed Wed), 1000-1230&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>9000-059 Funchal<br/>Rua Da Alfandega 10, 3C<br/>Madeira<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The &ldquo;Pearl of the Atlantic,&rdquo; Madeira is more than just a shortcut to the tropics for European holidaymakers. A land of luscious mountains, limpid lagoons and gorgeous fishing villages, this Portuguese archipelago is a destination of staggering natural beauty.</p>
<p>Floating off the coast of West Africa, Madeira&rsquo;s landscapes are indebted to the rich volcanic soil, mild climate and abundant rainfall that support an exceptional diversity of flora. Botanists take particular delight in the archipelago&rsquo;s laurisilva forests, which are inscribed on UNESCO&rsquo;s list of World Heritage Sites.</p>
<p>As well as being home to exceptional flora, Madeira has spectacular fauna, with the warm Atlantic Ocean proving the perfect habitat for marine life. The ocean offers many opportunities for adventurous travellers; from swimming with dolphins to scuba diving. Whale watching and surfing are other major selling points.</p>
<p>Golden sandy beaches are few on Madeira, found only at Calheta and Machico, and both of those have been built from imported sand. Elsewhere beaches consist of small strips of black, volcanic sand, which is enough for some.</p>
<p>On land, the fragrant eucalyptus woodlands are an ideal place for hiking, offering stunning views. But perhaps the most distinctive characteristic of Madeira is its renowned system of water channels, known as levadas. Constructed by slaves to convey water from the mountains to plantations, walking the levadas has become a major tourist attraction for Madeira.</p>
<p>Despite the lack of beach space, Madeira remains popular with foreign visitors and its coastal resorts are geared to the demands of the modern tourist, most of which arrive via the capital, Funchal, which overlooks one of the world&rsquo;s most beautiful bays. Here you can&nbsp;relax at one of the many caf&eacute;s, order a glass of Madeira wine and let the archipelago&rsquo;s charms work their magic; you won't be disappointed.</p>The "Pearl of the Atlantic," Madeira is more than just a shortcut to the tropics for European holidaymakers. A land of luscious mountains, limpid lagoons and gorgeous fishing villages, this Portuguese archipelago is a destination of staggering natural beauty. Floating off the coast of West Africa, Madeira's landscapes are indebted to the rich volcanic soil, mild climate and abundant rainfall that support an exceptional diversity of flora. ]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
