<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Portugal" ColCode="prt" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="pt" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Portugal]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not surprisingly, considering its close proximity to northern Africa, Portugal is one of the warmest European countries with an average temperature of 15&deg;C (55&deg;F) in the north and 18&deg;C (64&deg;F) in the south, while the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/portugal/azores">Azores</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/portugal/madeira">Madeira</a> are wetter and hotter respectively off the coast. It can become rainy and windy during autumn and winter, but spring and summer see temperatures soar to as high as 40&deg;C (104&deg;F) around the interior and 35&deg;C (95&deg;F) in the north.<br />
<br />
The northwest has mild winters with high levels of rainfall, and fairly short summers. The northeast experiences longer winters and hot summers. In the south, summers (May to October) are warm with very little rain except in early spring and autumn. Snow will fall in the north, but melts quickly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Light- to mediumweights and rainwear are advised (Portugal has one of the highest rainfalls in Europe). In summer, wear very light fabrics, preferably linen, as temperatures can soar and prove very uncomfortable if you have packed wrongly. Should you travel in spring or autumn, pack a combination of both.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>TAP Air Portugal (<a href="http://www.flytap.com" target="_blank">www.flytap.com</a>) runs services between Lisbon, Faro, Madeira, Porto Santo, Porto and the Azores. Charter flights are also available. The airline for the Azores is SATA (Sociedade Acoriana de Transportes Aereos) (<a href="http://www.sata.pt" target="_blank">www.sata.pt</a>), which operates its Air A&ccedil;ores service between the various islands.</p>
<p>Portugal is not a huge place, therefore it is probably wiser to drive between the mainland cities unless you want to fly between Porto and Faro at the opposite ends of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Several tour operators run cruises along the spectacular River Douro. There is no longer a ferry from mainland Portugal to Madeira.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Comboios de Portugal - CP (tel: +351 707 210 220; <a href="http://www.cp.pt" target="_blank">www.cp.pt</a>) is the Portuguese national rail service provider. Alfa Pendular trains offer the fastest rail link from Lisbon to the Algarve and from the capital to the north (Porto, Braga or Guimar&atilde;es, with stops in Coimbra and Aveiro); the Intercidades (Intercity) service covers Lisbon, Porto, Alentejo and Lisbon to Algarve routes.</p>
<p>A vast network of regional, inter-regional and suburban trains covers the country. The tourist areas of Cascais and Sintra are connected to Lisbon by frequent express trains. High-speed Alfa trains run between Lisbon and Porto via Coimbra and Aveiro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Portugal. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Portugal Pass</strong>: offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Portugal. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Cheap fares:</strong> Children between five and 13 and senior citizens get discount fares of 50%, return tickets by 10% and youth travel (Cart&atilde;o Jovem or Euro&lt;26 cardholders) by 25%. Family railcards, groups discounts and rover tickets are also available. Check Portuguese Railways online (<a href="http://www.cp.pt" target="_blank">www.cp.pt</a>) for current promotions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The routes between the main cities and towns along the coast are of sufficient standard. Some of the smaller roads further into the countryside can be rough and ready at times however, though you&rsquo;ll get there eventually. Portuguese drivers themselves can be erratic too, so be watchful at all times.</p>
<p>Petrol stations generally open 0700-2000, although some are open 24 hours.</p>
<p>Travel by motorway is subject to a Via Verde electronic toll system in your car or the usual cash and card payments, according to distance covered and type of vehicle.</p>r<p>You can travel internally by bus using operators InterCentro (tel: +351 707 200 512; <a href="http://www.intercentro.pt" target="_blank">www.intercentro.pt</a>) and its affiliate InterNorte.</p><p>Taxi drivers are not generally tipped, but passengers commonly round up the fare.</p><p>International Driving Permits or foreign driving licences are accepted. Third-party insurance is compulsory. Under the requirements of the Portuguese Road Code, those wishing to drive a car must possess a valid national/international driving licence, other official documentation with photograph, log book or rental contract and adequate car insurance. Failure to produce, on request to the authorities, any of the above will result in an on-the-spot cash fine. A Carnet de Passage is needed for a van.</p><p>The minimum age for driving is 18. Cars may be imported for up to six months. Traffic signs are international. Drivers should dip headlights in built-up areas and use side lights when parking in badly lit areas. Children should not travel in the front seat. Seat belts should be worn. Warning triangles are compulsory. It is forbidden to carry cans of petrol in vehicles.</p>
<p>Speed limits are 50kph (30mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (56mph) outside built-up areas and 100-120kph (62-75mph) on motorways.</p><p>Autom&oacute;vel Club de Portugal (ACP) (tel: +351 808 22 22 22; <a href="http://www.acp.pt" target="_blank">www.acp.pt</a>) operates a 24-hour service.</p><p>Available from major and local providers in main towns and airports, with or without driver. You must be at least 21 to 25 to hire a car.</p><p>You can take bikes to Portugal by plane and train, but not by coach. The European cycling boom is well catered for in Portugal, with several operators offering tours if you prefer to cycle in a group. Bikely (<a href="http://www.bikely.com" target="_blank">www.bikely.com</a>) provides a handy list of routes. Local bike hire is commonplace if you just want to ride for a morning or afternoon.</p><p>The minimum age for driving is 18. Cars may be imported for up to six months. Traffic signs are international. Drivers should dip headlights in built-up areas and use side lights when parking in badly lit areas. Children should not travel in the front seat. Seat belts should be worn. Warning triangles are compulsory. It is forbidden to carry cans of petrol in vehicles.</p>
<p>Speed limits are 50kph (30mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (56mph) outside built-up areas and 100-120kph (62-75mph) on motorways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transportes de Lisboa operates Lisbon's public transport, including an extensive underground system, trams, buses, and ferries across the Tagus. The city's suburban rail lines, operated by Portuguese Railways, are useful for covering longer distances. Porto also has an underground (Metro de Porto), trams and buses. Taxis are readily available in both cities, much like the rest of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Portugal</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">porto</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Portugal</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">funchal</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Portugal</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">faro</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Portugal's national airline is TAP Air Portugal (<a href="http://www.flytap.com">www.flytap.com</a>) which runs direct flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> to Portugal, as well as from other <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> cities. Alternative airlines flying to Portugal from the UK include British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>). Prices tend to increase in July and August.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/portugal/madeira/madeira-cristiano-ronaldo-airport">Madeira Cristiano Ronaldo Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lisbon/lisbon-portela-airport">Lisbon Portela</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/portugal/porto-dr-francisco-sa-carneiro-international-airport">Porto Francisco sa Carneiro International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/portugal/faro-airport">Faro Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lisbon">Lisbon</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 40 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Porto Francisco Sá Carneiro International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.ana.pt<p>Porto Francisco Sá Carneiro Airport is located 11km (6.5 miles) northwest of Porto city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+351 22 943 2400</p>]]><b>Faro Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeroportofaro.pt<p>Faro Airport is situated 4km (2.5 miles) west of Faro city centre in the Algarve region of southern Portugal.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+351 289 800 800</p>]]><b>Lisbon Portela Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.ana.pt<p>Lisbon Portela Airport is located 7km (4 miles) north from Lisbon city centre, close to the Parque das Nações district.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+351 21 841 3500</p>]]><b>Madeira Cristiano Ronaldo Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeroportosdamadeira.pt<p>Madeira Cristiano Ronaldo Airport is located in the town of Santa Cruz, 16km (10 miles) to the northeast of the island&rsquo;s capital, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/funchal">Funchal</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>291 520 700.</p>]]><b>Porto Santo Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.anam.pt/madeira]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Terceira Airport</b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Lisbon (<a href="http://www.portodelisboa.pt" target="_blank">www.portodelisboa.pt</a>), Leix&otilde;es (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/porto">Porto</a>) (<a href="http://www.apdl.pt">www.apdl.pt</a>), Funchal (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/portugal/madeira">Madeira</a>) (<a href="http://www.portosdamadeira.com">www.portosdamadeira.com</a>) and Portim&atilde;o (Algarve).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travelling from the UK, the quickest way is to travel by Eurostar through the Channel Tunnel to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a> (journey time - 2 hours 20 minutes) and, from there, to Portugal. The Sud-Expresso runs between Hendaye/Irun (linked to Paris by TGV) and Lisbon, offering first- and second-class seats, sleepers and a restaurant car. For further information and reservations, contact Eurostar (tel: +44 1233 617 575, in the UK; <a href="http://www.eurostar.com" target="_blank">www.eurostar.com</a>) or Voyages SNCF (tel: +44 844 848 5848;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p>Caminhos De Ferro Portugueses (tel: +351 707 210 220; <a href="http://www.cp.pt" target="_blank">www.cp.pt</a>) offers international rail services to Vigo and&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/madrid">Madrid</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The quickest route from the UK is via ferry from northern <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a>. For the more adventurous, there is the option of taking the ferry or Channel Tunnel to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> and driving down. Brittany Ferries (tel: +44 330 159 7000, in the UK;&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.brittany-ferries.co.uk">www.brittany-ferries.co.uk</a>) runs from Plymouth to Santander, and from Portsmouth to Santander and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bilbao">Bilbao</a>.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel (tel: +44 844 335 3535, in the UK; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.eurotunnel.com">www.eurotunnel.com</a>) operates 24 hours a day through the Channel Tunnel between Folkestone in Kent (with direct access from the M20) and Calais in France.</p>
<p>Coach travel to Portugal from the UK and other countries is possible, although it can be a long, hot and laborious journey. Eurolines (tel: +44 871 781 8177, in the UK;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.eurolines.co.uk"> www.eurolines.co.uk</a>) runs services to Portugal from Victoria coach station in London, but you need to change at the Area Suco interchange in Spain.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are call boxes in most villages and all towns; there are also public telephones in many cafés and bars, from which you can make international calls. Internet cafés in the main tourist areas are usually set up for Skype.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies and coverage exists across the whole country, but you can buy a cheap phone on arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi access is available in various hotels, restaurants and public buildings. There are internet cafés in most urban areas, and some rural ones, while post offices offer web facilities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>R&aacute;dio e Televis&atilde;o de Portugal (RTP) operates public TV and radio services, with two domestic TV channels plus two foreign ones on the mainland and in Madeira. SIC and TVI are the other commercial TV channels with TV Cabo the main pay-TV operator. R&aacute;dio Comercial and R&aacute;dio Clube Portugu&ecirc;s are two of the commercial radio channels with R&aacute;dio Renascenca the very popular Roman Catholic Church owned channel. Each region has its own Portuguese-language daily newspaper alongside nationals <em>Diario Noticias</em>, <em>P&uacute;blico</em> and <em>Expresso</em>. <em>The Portugal News</em>&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.theportugalnews.com" target="_blank">www.theportugalnews.com</a>) is an English-language newspaper published in print and online, and English newspapers are available from airports. In 2004 Madeirans were granted access to standard (RTP) services without having to pay satellite subscription charges.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to European destinations from continental Portugal and the Azores takes three days; from Madeira, up to five days. Post to the USA can take up to two weeks.</p><p>Open Mon-Fri 0900-1800, while some are also open on Saturday and Sunday. The post office at Lisbon Airport is open 24 hours a day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Algarve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Soak up some rays or take a dip in the sea along the Algarve, the sunny southern coastline boasting some of Portugal's loveliest beaches.</p>]]><p><b>Catch a traditional festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Traditional festivals with dancing, drinking and feasting, occur throughout the year. Top picks include Lisbon's festival of St Anthony (12 and 13 June) and Braga's festival of St John (23 and 24 June).</p>]]><p><b>Catch some live Fado music</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The melancholic Fado music, Portugal's best-known traditional musical form, can be heard at atmospheric bars and clubs in Lisbon or Coimbra.</p>]]><p><b>Check out castle ruins and palaces in Guimarães</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The medieval capital of Guimar&atilde;es (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.guimaraesturismo.com/">www.guimaraesturismo.com</a>) was the birthplace of the Portuguese nation. Looming above its narrow, cobbled lanes lie castle ruins and the former palace of the Dukes of Bragan&ccedil;a.</p>]]><p><b>Côa Valley Archaeological Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The C&ocirc;a Valley Archaeological Park (<a href="http://www.arte-coa.pt" target="_blank">www.arte-coa.pt</a>) is home to a magnificent collection of rock carvings from the Upper Palaeolithic period (22,000-10,000BC). The UNESCO World Heritage site only narrowly escaped destruction during a proposed dam-building project.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Belém's striking attractions</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The striking Torre de Bel&eacute;m is near the fabled spot where Vasco da Gama set sail during the Age of Discoveries. Other Bel&eacute;m attractions include the glorious Jer&oacute;nimos Monastery (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.mosteirojeronimos.pt">www.mosteirojeronimos.pt</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Discover Portugal's only national park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Portugal's only national park, Peneda-Ger&ecirc;s has&nbsp;70,000 hectares (170,000 acres) of dramatic mountain scenery, old stone villages and unrivalled adventure for outdoor enthusiasts.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Ribeira, a UNESCO World Heritage site in Porto</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This UNESCO World Heritage site in Porto has history lurking round every corner, from its neo classical Stock Exchange Palace to its romanesque-gothic Cathedral, with spectacular views along the vibrant waterfront of Cais da Ribeira (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.portoturismo.pt/">www.portoturismo.pt</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Fatima</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The spiritual shrine at Fátima has been an important centre of Roman Catholic pilgrimage since 1917 when the Virgin Mary appeared to a group of children. Experience the torchlight processions of 13 May and 13 October.</p>]]><p><b>Go golfing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Portugal has a great selection of popular championship golf courses in the Algarve and around Estoril, but Quinta da Lago (<a href="http://www.hotelquintadolago.com" target="_blank">www.hotelquintadolago.com</a>)&nbsp;is arguably the pick of the bunch.</p>]]><p><b>Lisbon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A colourful tapestry of urban life awaits in the vibrant hilltop neighbourhoods of Lisbon. Don't miss drinks in rowdy Bairro Alto, live fado in the Alfama or cafe culture in elegant Chiado. The city is home to Europe's largest oceanarium.</p>]]><p><b>Lose yourself in the Alfama district</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to the Alfama district and discover a maze-like district of steep staircases, hidden churches and traditional taverns, and an old tram that still rattles through the streets.</p>]]><p><b>Saddle up on a horse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Portugal has scores of riding centres. Hit the beach with a Lusitano thoroughbred to canter along the sand in the Atlantic surf, or if you're an experienced rider, try taking dressage lessons in Estremadura.</p>]]><p><b>See the architectural splendors of Évora</b></p><![CDATA[<p>&Eacute;vora reached its golden age in the 15th century and is now is a virtual museum of a town boasting architectural splendour. The walled old centre contains a Roman temple, a looming cathedral and picturesque plazas.</p>]]><p><b>Spend time in picturesque Tavira</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tavira is one of the Algarve's oldest and most unspoiled towns. Constructed on the banks of the River Gilhão, the picturesque settlement a smattering of gothic and Renaissance churches, a seven-arched Roman bridge, old fortifications and a pristine island beach.</p>]]><p><b>Take a cruise or wine tour in Douro Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the splendid vineyards and picturesque river of this UNESCO World Heritage site with a taste-busting wine tour or delightful river cruise. It is one of the most underrated tourist trips you will find in Europe and one to treasure forever.</p>]]><p><b>Take a trip to the hills of Sintra</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A UNESCO World Heritage site, Sintra is an idyllic town surrounded by wooded hillsides. Don't miss the former summer residence of the Portuguese royal family and the beautiful Monserrate gardens.</p>]]><p><b>View one of Portugal's iconic monasteries</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Mosteiro de Santa Maria (Monastery of Batalha) is a gothic Manueline masterpiece built to commemorate the 1385 victory over Spain in the Battle of Aljubarrota. Its elaborately carved exterior is one of the icons of Portugal.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Braga's assortment of baroque churches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Portugal's spiritual heart, Braga is a lively little city with an exquisite assortment of baroque churches, a sprawling cathedral and Roman ruins. It hosts traditional religious festivals throughout the year, including Portugal's colourful Holy Week.</p>]]><p><b>Watch motorsports at Estoril racetrack</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Petrolheads may want to check out the world-famous Estoril racetrack (<a href="http://www.circuito-estoril.pt/" target="_blank">www.circuito-estoril.pt</a>), which is located a short distance from Lisbon on Portugal's Atlantic coast. Visitors can go along to watch car or motorcycle races.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$198.9 billion (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Clothing and footwear, machinery, chemicals and cork.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery/transport equipment, chemicals, petroleum, leather and textiles.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Spain, Germany, France, UK and Angola.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Portugal was traditionally an agrarian economy, but since it joined the EU in 1986 its industrial and service sectors have grown considerably by comparison. Agriculture still employs around 10% of the workforce (unusually high by Western European standards) and contributes around 8% of GDP, producing wheat, maize, potatoes, tomatoes, olives, grapes, fish and meat and dairy products. The manufacturing sector is dominated by the textile, footwear and machinery industries.</p>
<p>Portugal joined the Eurozone upon its inauguration in 1999. Unfortunately, since then, the economy has struggled and in 2011 the country accepted a &euro;78 billion bailout from the EU and the International Monetary Fund, along with a three year aid programme that ended in May 2014. The economy has started showing signs of recovery, however. Unemployment stood at 11.9% in 2015 while inflation was 2.5%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business people are expected to dress smartly and English is widely spoken in business circles, although when visiting a small family business it is best to check in advance. When addressing someone, it is customary to use their title followed by their full name. Regardless of their degree, university graduates are usually referred to as 'Doctor' and co-workers often refer to each other as 'colleague'. Business cards are only exchanged by senior members of a company. It can be considered rude to write anything official in red ink. Business socialising focuses on eating and drinking in bars and restaurants. July and August are best avoided as many are on holiday.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1500-1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Lisbon Convention Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 210 312 700.
					Website:http://www.visitlisboa.com
					Address: ,Rua do Arsenal 15,Lisbon,]]><b>Confederação do Comércio e Serviços de Portugal (CCP)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 213 031 380
					Website:http://www.ccp.pt/
					Address: ,Avenida Dom Vasco de Gama 29,1449-032 Lisbon,]]><b>Associação Comercial de Lisboa</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 213 224 050
					Website:http://www.port-chambers.com/
					Address: Rua das Portas de Santo Antão 89,Câmara de Comércio e Indústria Portuguesa,1169-022 Lisbon,]]><b>Porto Convention Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 223 326 751
					Website:http://www.portocvb.com/
					Address: ,(Information on Conferences/Conventions),,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Portuguese cooking is not too well known in other parts of Europe, or the world for that matter; nevertheless it is definitely worth exploring properly. Seafood is a regular staple, especially the salt cod that is very much a love it or hate it thing. It forms the base of hundreds of recipes and you should try it at least once. Anchovy, bass, clams, mussels, salmon, sea bream, sole and swordfish are easier on the palate and also popular.</p>
<p>The spice peri-peri is widely used to flavour chicken and shrimp, while Goan curry spices also add extra flavour to a variety of dishes and broths eaten widely. Meat lovers can gorge on <em>espetada</em> (grilled skewers of beef with garlic), <em>leit&atilde;o</em> (suckling pig) and <em>cozido &agrave; portuguesa</em>, which mixes beef, pork, sausage and vegetables in a delicious dish. Another traditional delicacy is <em>porco &agrave; alentejana</em> (pork and clams Alentejo-style).</p>
<p>Sweets such as chocolate mousse and&nbsp;<em>arroz doce</em> (lemon and cinnamon-flavoured rice pudding), together with classic egg-yolk and sugar-based cakes, can be seen on tables up and down the country to finish off a superb meal. As you would in many other smaller European countries, take the time to seek out local shops, bars and restaurants to ask what the locals eat and drink.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>There are some fascinating local dishes dotted throughout the country, which are either variations on culinary favourites or unique creations.</p>
<p>&bull; <em>Bacalhau &aacute; br&agrave;s</em> (scrambled eggs with salted cod, potatoes and onions; popular in Estremadura).<br />
&bull;  <em>Lulas recheadas &agrave; lisbonense</em> (stuffed squid; a Lisbon speciality).<br />
&bull; <em>Tripa &agrave; moda do Porto</em> (tripe; available for those of a meaty disposition in Porto). <br />
&bull; <em>Queijadas de Sintra</em> (cheese tart found in Sintra). <br />
&bull; <em>A&ccedil;orda de mariscos</em> (shrimp stew cooked in a bread bowl).<br />
<em>&bull; Caldo verde</em> (green soup made with finely shredded green kale leaves in broth). <br />
&bull; <em>Past&eacute;is de nata</em> (traditional custard-filled tarts typical of Lisbon).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Table service is normal. There are no licensing hours.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>More often than not, a service charge is not added to hotel and restaurant bills, so tip around 10 to 15% if you are satisfied with your experience. A couple of Euros for hotel maids and porters is considered appropriate. Round up your taxi fare to the nearest five Euros should you not wish to hand over 10%. Service charge is more casual in the less touristy north than the busy south.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>The legal age to buy and drink alcohol is 18 years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not surprisingly in a country that dances to a different tune, night-time is when Portugal comes alive. Up and down the land you can wander into places that showcase native music from down the years or contemporary beats that will get your feet tapping, not to mention the other cultural treats on offer until dawn.</p>
<p>First take time to chat or people-watch at the lovely bars or caf&eacute;s, whether they overlook the sea or town square, before having a sumptuous dinner in peace or to the sound of the traditional fado. Move on to your entertainment of choice at the broad selection of nightclubs, theatres, cinemas and operas before you head to Espinho, Estoril, Figueira da Foz or Monte Gordo&rsquo;s casinos to cap off an evening with a cheeky punt.</p>
<p>Should you prefer a street parade, June is your best bet to soak up the open-air festivities, which celebrate local patron saints. With 800km (500 miles) of coastline to visit, there is also the chance to take it a notch down by watching the sunset at the fantastic array of beachside bars and restaurants.</p>
<p>Fling off your flip-flops or sandals at the nightclubs too. Specific gems standing out from the crowd include taking a stroll down the Bairro Alto in Lisbon ahead of some classic DJ sets at the bars and clubs set in former warehouses at the Santa Amaro docks on the banks of the River Tagus. Further north in Porto, seek out the Ribeira district over the River Douro for fun and frolics before carrying on to Matosinhos and Vila Nova de Gaia with your dancing shoes. Elsewhere in Portugal, you can join the lively student population in Braga, Coimbra and Evora to party the night away.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Just like any self-respecting tourist destination, Portugal has a vibrant shopping scene to take advantage of the native enterprise. Thanks to the fascinating ethnic mix inherent in the country, you can pick up Arraiolos carpets, dazzling jewels and Madeira embroideries. There is a thriving lace industry in Vila do Conde outside Porto, with Coimbra playing host to delightful blue and white pottery.</p>
<p>Should you have a penchant for metal, head down to the Algarve to buy enchanting lanterns or outdoor furniture. The jewel in this country&rsquo;s crown though is the leather industry, which centres around Lisbon for the most part.</p>
<p>If you want to pick up local leather goods a bit more cheaply than in the capital, then you can often buy them for 20% less outside Lisbon, but beware of nasty knock-offs. Some of the smaller cities and larger towns have thriving industries, which use medieval techniques passed down through generations to produce goods for tourists.</p><p>Large shopping malls are open daily 0900-2300 and often provide a welcome respite from the hot summer sun. Other than that, shops are open Mon-Fri 0900-1900 and Sat 0900-1300.</p><p>Visitors who live outside the EU can reclaim the sales tax of 23% which is included in prices (minimum spend per shop &euro;61.35). Travellers wishing to take advantage of this must ask for a tax free form at the time of purchase (available at participating stores only). This must be stamped by customs and a refund claimed before passing through passport control. See Global Blue (<a href="http://www.global-blue.com" target="_blank">www.global-blue.com</a>) for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Portugal cover the whole range from very basic accommodation to stylish luxury, using familiar rating systems. The bulk of tourist accommodation is in the Algarve, Lisbon and Porto. You can snap up bargain rooms during the low season, especially deals involving meals and extra beds for children. The large classier chains like Four Seasons, Hilton, Ritz-Carlton and Sheraton are prominent in the more built-up areas, while the cheaper chains can soften the blow on your wallet throughout the country. Comfort Inn, Holiday Inn and continental favourite Ibis all cater for families and travellers on a budget. <br />
<br />
Of course, there are plenty of Portuguese hotels across the country that will give you more of a flavour for Portugal&rsquo;s famous hospitality. Vidago Palace (<a href="http://www.vidagopalace.com" target="_blank">www.vidagopalace.com</a>) near Porto, Zenit Lisboa (<a href="http://lisboa.zenithoteles.com" target="_blank">http://lisboa.zenithoteles.com</a>) in the capital Lisbon and Hotel Quinta do Lago (<a href="http://www.hotelquintadolago.com" target="_blank">www.hotelquintadolago.com</a>) in the Algarve are higher-end examples to pamper to your every need. Seek out forums, websites and word of mouth for more reasonable gems. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are classified according to the international 1- to 5-star<strong> </strong>system and prices are officially approved. Apartment hotels are classified 2- to 4-star, motels 2- to 3-star and boarding houses 1- to 3-star (1-star is the best); there are also 4-star <em>albergarias</em>. During the low season hotels often grant substantial reductions. Children under twelve are usually entitled to a 50% reduction on the price of meals and an extra bed, if sharing a room/apartment with parents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Portugal has its own unique form of bed and breakfast called a pousada, which is government-owned. Pousadas are essentially historic buildings like castles, convents and palaces. They are not cheap, but there are sometimes special offers for honeymoon couples, plus they are largely located in areas not well served by normal hotels, making your stay more interesting. Contact Pousadas de Portugal (<a href="http://www.pousadas.pt" target="_blank">www.pousadas.pt</a>) to find out more about availability and choice, and to make bookings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Portugal cover the whole range from very basic accommodation to stylish luxury, using familiar rating systems. The bulk of tourist accommodation is in the Algarve, Lisbon and Porto. You can snap up bargain rooms during the low season, especially deals involving meals and extra beds for children. The large classier chains like Four Seasons, Hilton, Ritz-Carlton and Sheraton are prominent in the more built-up areas, while the cheaper chains can soften the blow on your wallet throughout the country. Comfort Inn, Holiday Inn and continental favourite Ibis all cater for families and travellers on a budget. <br />
<br />
Of course, there are plenty of Portuguese hotels across the country that will give you more of a flavour for Portugal&rsquo;s famous hospitality. Vidago Palace (<a href="http://www.vidagopalace.com" target="_blank">www.vidagopalace.com</a>) near Porto, Zenit Lisboa (<a href="http://lisboa.zenithoteles.com" target="_blank">http://lisboa.zenithoteles.com</a>) in the capital Lisbon and Hotel Quinta do Lago (<a href="http://www.hotelquintadolago.com" target="_blank">www.hotelquintadolago.com</a>) in the Algarve are higher-end examples to pamper to your every need. Seek out forums, websites and word of mouth for more reasonable gems. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are classified according to the international 1- to 5-star<strong> </strong>system and prices are officially approved. Apartment hotels are classified 2- to 4-star, motels 2- to 3-star and boarding houses 1- to 3-star (1-star is the best); there are also 4-star <em>albergarias</em>. During the low season hotels often grant substantial reductions. Children under twelve are usually entitled to a 50% reduction on the price of meals and an extra bed, if sharing a room/apartment with parents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Portugal cover the whole range from very basic accommodation to stylish luxury, using familiar rating systems. The bulk of tourist accommodation is in the Algarve, Lisbon and Porto. You can snap up bargain rooms during the low season, especially deals involving meals and extra beds for children. The large classier chains like Four Seasons, Hilton, Ritz-Carlton and Sheraton are prominent in the more built-up areas, while the cheaper chains can soften the blow on your wallet throughout the country. Comfort Inn, Holiday Inn and continental favourite Ibis all cater for families and travellers on a budget. <br />
<br />
Of course, there are plenty of Portuguese hotels across the country that will give you more of a flavour for Portugal&rsquo;s famous hospitality. Vidago Palace (<a href="http://www.vidagopalace.com" target="_blank">www.vidagopalace.com</a>) near Porto, Zenit Lisboa (<a href="http://lisboa.zenithoteles.com" target="_blank">http://lisboa.zenithoteles.com</a>) in the capital Lisbon and Hotel Quinta do Lago (<a href="http://www.hotelquintadolago.com" target="_blank">www.hotelquintadolago.com</a>) in the Algarve are higher-end examples to pamper to your every need. Seek out forums, websites and word of mouth for more reasonable gems. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are classified according to the international 1- to 5-star<strong> </strong>system and prices are officially approved. Apartment hotels are classified 2- to 4-star, motels 2- to 3-star and boarding houses 1- to 3-star (1-star is the best); there are also 4-star <em>albergarias</em>. During the low season hotels often grant substantial reductions. Children under twelve are usually entitled to a 50% reduction on the price of meals and an extra bed, if sharing a room/apartment with parents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;If suddenly taken ill or involved in an accident during a visit to an EEA country or Switzerland, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available for European travellers - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). This does not cover you for medical repatriation or ongoing treatment however, so you should also purchase travel insurance; you&amp;rsquo;ll need extra cover if you&amp;rsquo;re planning on taking part in any extreme sports. Non-EEA nationals are covered in Portugal, but again, comprehensive insurance is advised. While there are full state-provided health facilities, private practices are allowed to co-exist. The emergency telephone number is 112.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;You can drink tap water in major cities and towns, although you should be cautious in small villages. Thankfully, bottled water is widely available but if it's not then any questionable water should be boiled for five minutes or treated with iodine. Salads and fruit are safe to eat anywhere in Portugal. Take care with shellfish such as cooked mussels that have not opened properly and avoid undercooked meat, particularly minced meat. Ice cream is fine, unless it has been melted and refrozen.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;You will be treated on the same basis as a Portuguese resident, but you might have to make a patient contribution to the cost of your care. If you have to make such a payment, you may be able to seek reimbursement for this cost when you are back in the UK if you are not able to do so in Portugal. It is important that you ensure you are treated by a state healthcare provider, as you will not be covered for private healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be particularly careful if the healthcare arrangements have been made by a hotel or travel representative. There are state health centres throughout the country (generally open from 0800 to 2000) where you can receive treatment for minor ailments and injuries, and major emergency hospitals in large towns which remain open throughout the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though pharmacies are well stocked, take a decent supply of medication with you, and be aware pharmacies are usually closed for two hours over lunchtime. Carry a legible prescription with you to show that you legally use the medication. If you wear glasses, take a spare pair and your prescription just in case you need to get new glasses made up quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to take the usual precautions against sunburn and sunstroke, as the sun in Portugal can be blisteringly hot in the height of summer: wear high-factor sunscreen, a hat and sunglasses, and drink plenty of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaccination against hepatitis B is sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Freedom Day :
							25 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Portugal Day :
							10 June </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Republic Day :
							05 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Restoration of Independence Day :
							01 December </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% volume, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Portugal by persons over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers (reduced to &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted imports include drugs, radioactive products, offensive weapons, firearms, explosives and ammunition, and protected plants and animals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol €) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of €500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of €2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can buy or exchange Euros very easily at cambios (bureaux de change), hotels and shops. Many banks no longer offer foreign exchange, while the best rates and commissions are normally found at the bureaux in larger towns. The worst rates by far are at the airports and hotels. The best thing is to keep an eye out while you're shopping and always check the commission rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted, even outside cities, while petrol stations usually take credit cards and cash.</p><p>There are ATMs (Multibanco) at most of the larger supermarkets and shopping areas in most towns with instructions available in English if required. You can only take out a maximum of €200 and if you see six asterisks, not four, just put in your normal four numbers and hit continue. If you receive a 'service unavailable' message, it is most likely that the machine is out of cash - especially at weekends and on Monday mornings. The machine will have an icon with a cross though it.
<br/><br/>
You can also find Multibanco machines in every small town and even villages all around Portugal. You will be charged for an international transaction. Currency conversion booths spring up wherever there is a steady flow of tourists but, be warned, the closer they are to tourist attractions, the worse the rates they offer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally, Mon-Fri 0830-1530 (certain banks in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lisbon">Lisbon</a> are open until 1800). In smaller towns a bank may close for lunch, while many branches no longer offer a foreign exchange service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Australian, Canadian, US and EU passport holders do not require transit visas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Portugal is currently part of the Schengen visa scheme.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60 (children age 6-12: &euro;35,; temporary stay visa: &euro;75 (usually issued for study, medical or work purposes).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period; temporary stay visa: multiple entries within a four-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consular section of their nearest Portuguese Embassy. Some embassies (including London) also accept online applications; see&nbsp;<a href="http://www.secomunidades.pt/vistos" target="_blank">www.secomunidades.pt/vistos</a> for further information. Schengen visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointments.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Registration certificates issued to visitors from EU countries who wish to stay for longer than three months are valid indefinitely. Non-EU residents planning on staying longer than three months must apply for temporary residence permits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow up to 15 days for visa processing. Applications from some nationalities may take up to two months however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors requiring a Schengen visa must prove sufficient funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa holders can only extend their stay in exceptional circumstances such as <em>force majeure</em> or for humanitarian reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[39.642031]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-8.345996]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>92,345 sq km (35,655 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>10,304,434 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>117.2 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lisbon.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Portugal juts out into the Atlantic in the far southwest of Europe otherwise known as the Iberian Peninsula. The only country it shares a border with is neighbouring&nbsp;Spain to the north and the east, with the Atlantic Ocean hugging its 800km (500-mile) coastline to the south and west.</p>
<p>The country also comprises the Portuguese islands of the Azores and Madeira.&nbsp;The Azores lie around 1,100km (700 miles) west of Lisbon, while Madeira sits just north of the Canary Islands to the west of Morocco.</p>
<p>Outside the large urban areas, the countryside is a great deal more rural and sparse than in many other European countries. Portugal is crossed by several rivers which have their origin in Spain. These flow from east to west out into the Atlantic or north to south, the main rivers being the Minho and Douro in the north, and the Tagus and Guadiana in the south.</p>
<p>Portugal possesses a high plain of varying height intersected by deep valleys. The north of the country is rugged, mountainous and dotted with vineyards. The high northern point of the Serra da Estrela proves a popular area for skiing, while Serra de S&atilde;o Mamede further south on the Spanish border is a hiking favourite.</p>
<p>After the stunning slopes of the central regions, the vast plains of the Alentejo region stretch south of Lisbon, with a range of mountains dividing the Alentejo from the Algarve, whose wide sandy beaches and attractive bays run along the south coast.&nbsp;Approximately half the country is used for agriculture.</p>
<p>The capital, Lisbon, sits about two-thirds down the west coast. Porto is also situated on the coast in the northwest of the country. Smaller Faro nestles on the southern end of the country, its airport a busy hub for Algarve sunseekers and swathes of golfers looking for year-round sun. Braga, Coimbra and Setubal are also near the coast and rivers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholics make up around 85% of the population, but only about 20% of these regularly attend mass and take the sacraments. The remaining 15% is a mixture of Agnostic, Anglican, Atheist, Jewish, Muslim and Protestant communities, together with other religions that have been brought in through immigration over the years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Portugal is a fascinating mix of culture and folklore, depending on what part of the country you are visiting. Traditional <em>ranchos folcl&oacute;ricos</em> folklore, which is often illustrated with dance and song, tends to dominate the smaller towns and villages, with art and drama bigger in the larger towns and cities.</p>
<p>The Portuguese are warm, hospitable people who revel in exhibitions, films, crafts, concerts, plays, caf&eacute; culture and also shopping malls (to combat the summer heat!). The summer festival season is a particularly pleasant experience, with football and bullfighting also enjoyed, along with the traditional religious activities that cater for the majority Catholic population.</p>
<p>Casual wear is widely acceptable, but you shouldn&rsquo;t wear beach clothing in towns. Smoking has been prohibited in public indoor spaces since 2008 and the ban includes cinemas, theatres, buses and most restaurants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Ant&oacute;nio Costa since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Marcelo Rebelo de Sousa since 2016.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Portugal has a rich and varied history and its territory has been fought over, invaded and settled ever since prehistoric times. Romans, Visigoths and the Germanic tribes followed the Celts, Phoenicians and Carthiginians before the Moors conquered the Iberian peninsula in AD 711.</p><p>For centuries afterwards the region was part of Muslim Spain until the Christian Reconquista that saw Portuguese independence declared in 1139 by King Afonso I. Along with the British, Dutch, French and Spanish, Portugal's historic influence has due to its strong seafaring capabilities. Indeed, it was the first Western nation to establish a global empire. Its explorers led the Age of Discovery with Bartolomeu Dias reaching the Cape of Good Hope in 1488, Vasco da Gama founding a sea route to India in 1497 and Pedro Álvares Cabral discovering Brazil in 1500.</p><p>Its ascendancy wasn't to last though. After the destruction of its capital Lisbon in the 1755 earthquake, the disastrous Battle of Alcácer Quibir in Morocco in 1578 saw the childless King Sebastian I killed and Portugal united with Spain. In the decades following Portugal lost significant portions of its overseas empire, principally to Dutch companies, although it fought and won the Restoration War with Spain, which ended in 1688.</p><p>In 1807 it was occupied by Napoleon and as it turned to its British allies to fight the invasion the court of Queen Maria I transferred to Brazil where it remained until 1821. A year later Brazil proclaimed its independence.</p><p>From the second half of the 19th century until the 1980s more then 2.6 million Portuguese emigrated – more than any Western European country other than Ireland – mostly for economic reasons.</p><p>Portugal's monarchy ended after the 1910 revolution and the rest of the 20th century was defined by a series of uprising, coups and revolutions until the peaceful 1974 Carnation Revolution – so-called because barely a shot was fired and when the people took to the streets to celebrate flowers were put in the muzzles of the soldiers' guns. To this day 25 April is a national holiday known as Freedom Day.</p><p>When Portugal handed over the territory of Macau to the China in 1999 it marked the end of Europe's longest colonial empire.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• In 2001 Portugal became the first country in the world to decriminalise the usage of all common drugs, although their sale and distribution remains illegal.</p><p>• Footballer Cristiano Ronald does not have any tattoos as it would prevent him from giving blood, which he does several times a year.</p><p>• The distinctive Manueline architecture of the early 16th century is characterised by tributes to the great discoveries of da Gama and Cabral.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Portugal]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+351 21 392 4000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/portugal</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+351 21 392 4000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Santa Isabel<br/>Rue de São Bernardo 33<br/>Lisbon<br/>1250<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Portuguese Republic in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7235 5331. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://portuguese-embassy.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7235 5331. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300, 1400-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>11 Belgrave Square<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8PP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Portuguese Consulate General in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 020 7291 3770.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://portuguese-embassy.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 020 7291 3770.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>3 Portland Place<br/>Marylebone<br/>W1B 1HR<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Portugal in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 350 5493.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.embassyportugal-us.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 350 5493.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Tue 0830-1530; Wed-Fri 0830-1300 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2012 Massachusetts Ave NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like the Atlantic Ocean that laps upon its shores, Portugal throws up one or two surprises. A rich and varied land of vibrant cities and traditional villages, visitors are astounded by the country&rsquo;s stunning beaches, rolling countryside and cornucopia of UNESCO World Heritage Sites, which range from prehistoric drawings at Foz Coa to the 15th-century port of Angra do Hero&iacute;smo.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s lively capital, Lisbon, and its vibrant northern sibling, Porto, are a joy to discover. They are cities where trams rattle up and down hills and along promenades, trundling past narrow side streets and majestic plazas, bohemian caf&eacute;s and pumping nightclubs, eye-catching boutiques and restaurants both hip and homespun.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not all about Lisbon and Porto, though. Sintra plays host to the stunning National Palace, a Moorish castle and the dramatic villa of Quinta da Regaleira, while the cities of Coimbra, Guimar&atilde;es, Braga and &Eacute;vora all boast beautifully preserved medieval quarters. Unusually, the latter is home to a chapel made exclusively of human bones, which is a tad creepy.</p>
<p>Travellers in search of a rural respite can wander around ancient vineyards, trek to stone villages perched in the mountains and take full advantage of the country&rsquo;s warm and sunny weather on the magnificent southern shoreline. Drop in on sleepy sulphur spas and hop around the Pousadas &ndash; a collection of exquisite convents and monasteries, which have been lovingly converted into off-beat accommodation.</p>
<p>Imposing cliffs and secluded beaches line the Portuguese coast, a dazzling stage for all manner of outdoor adventure. Visitors can ride horses, surf waves, paddle rivers, dive shipwrecks, hike hills and explore Moorish castles and Roman ruins between rounds of golf. Madeira and Berlenga Islands beckon off shore, while the elusive remains of Atlantis await discovery in the Azores Archipelago.</p>
<p>Those seeking a more unique slice of Portuguese culture can discover the melancholic music of <em>fado</em> (Portugal's answer to the blues), study the captivating detail of Manueline architecture, get involved in a traditional festival or quaff port wine along the meandering Douro river.</p><p>Like the Atlantic Ocean that laps upon its shores, Portugal throws up one or two surprises. A rich and varied land of vibrant cities and traditional villages, visitors are astounded by the country&rsquo;s stunning beaches, rolling countryside and cornucopia of UNESCO World Heritage Sites, which range from prehistoric drawings at Foz Coa to the 15th-century port of Angra do Hero&iacute;smo.</p>
<p>The country&rsquo;s lively capital, Lisbon, and its vibrant northern sibling, Porto, are a joy to discover. They are cities where trams rattle up and down hills and along promenades, trundling past narrow side streets and majestic plazas, bohemian caf&eacute;s and pumping nightclubs, eye-catching boutiques and restaurants both hip and homespun.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
