<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Puerto Rico" ColCode="pri" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="pr" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Puerto Rico]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlike many islands in the Caribbean, any time is really the best time to visit Puerto Rico and enjoy its tropical climate. The rainy season is from April to November, but precipitation patterns and amounts vary considerably from one part of the island to the other. Even in the rainiest areas, showers are likely to be intense but brief. <br />
If you're travelling from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/san-juan">San Juan</a> to Ponce (or vice-versa), you'll notice an immediate difference once you reach the top of the mountain about halfway through your journey. The south tends to be drier than the north. In the mountainous region, you'll want a light jacket or sweater, as the higher elevation means cooler temperatures.</p>
<p>1 June to 30 November is hurricane season, though Puerto Rico is rarely affected by hurricanes. February is an excellent time to visit Puerto Rico; when temperatures are typically cold on the mainland <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>, they're usually neither too hot nor too cool in <em>la isla del encanto</em>, the island of enchantment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight tropical clothes. Light rainwear required. Dress clothes for finer dining and nightclub visits. Bathing suits, of course, are de rigeur for those who plan to enjoy the water! A hat and sunglasses will help protect you from the sun's searing rays, and if you plan to snorkel or spend lots of time in the water, a long-sleeved shirt that repels UV rays is highly recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Vieques Air-Link (<a href="http://www.viequesairlink.com" target="_blank">www.viequesairlink.com</a>) and Cape Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.capeair.com">www.capeair.com</a>) provide domestic air travel within Puerto Rico. Flying is a fast, convenient way to travel between mainland Puerto Rico and the outlying islands of Culebra and Vieques, though there is also a reliable, cheaper ferry service. Flight times vary by season. Booking in advance is recommended, regardless of your method of transportation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a ferry service between Old San Juan and Cata&ntilde;o (home to the Bacardi rum factory) and between Old San Juan and the neighbourhood of Hato Rey (home to the Plaza las Americas shopping mall). Check the ferry terminal in Old San Juan for current schedules.</p>
<p>The Puerto Rico Department of Transportation's Maritime Transport Authority or ATM (<a href="http://www.dtop.gov.pr" target="_blank">www.dtop.gov.pr</a>) runs ferries between mainland Puerto Rico and the islands of Vieques and Culebra. All ferries to the sister islands depart from the port of Fajardo. Schedules are notoriously erratic and services can be cancelled without notice. It is important to distinguish that ATM operates two different types of service. The &lsquo;ferry&rsquo; is a cargo vessel that transports cars, while the &lsquo;lancha&rsquo; is a passenger vessel; you should make it clear you want a ticket for the lancha. No hire cars can go over on the ferry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no rail service between cities. The Tren Urbano (<a href="http://www.dtop.gov.pr" target="_blank">www.dtop.gov.pr</a>) is a public train service in the San Juan metro area; however, it is not convenient and is not used frequently by locals or visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One-, seven-, 30-, and 90-day passes are available on San Juan&rsquo;s Tren Urbano.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Puerto Rico has devoted considerable resources to building its road infrastructure, and the main cities are well connected by a modern highway system. Be prepared with coins or small bills for tolls. Unlike the mainland USA, Puerto Rico sells petrol in litres. Distance may be demarcated in kilometres or in miles depending on the area.</p>r<p>The quality of highways is generally good; the same is true of local roads in major cities. Roads on the island's interior vary greatly in quality and safety, as well as in lighting; it is not advised to drive at night. Generally, traffic is heavy (the island has 4 million people and more than 2 million cars) and many visitors prefer not to drive.</p><p>There is no commercial coach service available for travel between cities. Charter coach service for groups is available through Gray Line (tel: +1 800 472 9546; <a href="http://www.grayline.com" target="_blank">www.grayline.com</a>).</p><p>Taxis are readily available in San Juan; you can hire them at the airport, hotels and major tourist sites, or hail them on the street. Be sure to ask whether the driver is charging a set rate (and what the rate is) or using a meter. In other cities, you usually need to call a taxi. Taxi safety varies considerably; not all vehicles are new, nor do all taxis have seat belts. Taxi drivers expect a 15% tip.</p><p>US or foreign licences are accepted for 120 days, after which a Puerto Rican licence is required.</p><p>Most of the USA&rsquo;s driving laws are observed in Puerto Rico. For local laws, check the Puerto Rico Department of Transportation's website (<a href="http://www.dtop.gov.pr" target="_blank">www.dtop.gov.pr</a>). Speed limits vary by type and condition of roadway. All major roadways have signage indicating the speed limit.</p><p>AAA members can request roadside assistance by calling +1 800 222 4357 and giving their membership number. Otherwise, your car hire company should be able to pick you up in the event of a breakdown; be sure to ask when renting if breakdown service is available 24 hours a day and, if driving outside the capital, how far service extends.</p><p>International and local firms are available at the airport and city agencies. Most car hire agencies require that renters be 25 years of age or older. Some companies rent to people aged 21-24, but impose a daily surcharge and/or require that a licensed driver aged 25 or older accompany him/her for the duration of the rental. It's best to check the policies of the specific agency from which you wish to rent a car before arriving on the island.</p><p>Cycling is increasingly popular in Puerto Rico, but is not recommended for visitors due to heavy car traffic, aggressive driving, and narrow roadways that make cycling dangerous.</p><p>Most of the USA&rsquo;s driving laws are observed in Puerto Rico. For local laws, check the Puerto Rico Department of Transportation's website (<a href="http://www.dtop.gov.pr" target="_blank">www.dtop.gov.pr</a>). Speed limits vary by type and condition of roadway. All major roadways have signage indicating the speed limit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Juan has local bus services (<em>guaguas</em>). <em>P&uacute;blicos</em> (share-taxis) have 'P' or 'PD' at the end of licence plate numbers and run regular routes between established points. They usually operate only during daylight hours and depart from the main plaza (central square) of a town. P&uacute;blicos must be insured by law and the Public Service Commission fixes their routes and reasonable rates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Puerto Rico</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">vieques</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45*</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Puerto Rico</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ponce</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Puerto Rico</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">mayaguumlez</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Puerto Rico</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">fajardo</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Puerto Rico has no national airline. Most airlines originate from the US mainland and major carriers with daily flights to Puerto Rico include American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>), Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) and JetBlue (<a href="http://www.jetblue.com" target="_blank">www.jetblue.com</a>). Norwegian (<a href="http://www.norwegian.com" target="_blank">www.norwegian.com</a>) flies direct from the UK.</p>
<p>Most international arrivals to Puerto Rico originate from the mainland <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> and land at <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/san-juan">San Juan</a>'s Luis Mu&ntilde;oz Marin International Airport (SJU). Airports in Aguadilla (on the northwestern coast), Ponce (on the southern coast), and Mayaguez (on the western coast) also handle incoming international flights, but the volume and frequency are significantly lower. Departures to Puerto Rico from other countries are typically seasonal; air service is not year-round.</p>
<p>The cheapest times to fly to Puerto Rico are late spring to early summer. Fares are typically more expensive during winter, particularly around Thanksgiving, Christmas, and New Year.</p>
The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/puerto-rico/san-juan-luis-munoz-marin-international-airport">San Juan Luis Munoz Marin International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London - 9 hours 15 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 4 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Note that unlike many major airports, SJU is in metropolitan San Juan and is a short taxi ride away from major hotels and tourist attractions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Note that unlike many major airports, SJU is in metropolitan San Juan and is a short taxi ride away from major hotels and tourist attractions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>San Juan Luis Muñoz Marin International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aeropuertosju.com<p>San Juan Luis Muñoz Marín International Airport is situated 11km (7 miles) southeast of Old San Juan.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+1 787 253 2329</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> San Juan, Ponce&nbsp;and Mayaguez. The Port of San Juan is currently the island's largest port, receiving both cargo and cruise ships. Ponce and Mayaguez, the island's second and third largest cities, respectively, also have major ports. Ponce's port, Port of the Americas, is the Caribbean's deepest port. Port of the Americas is currently undergoing an extensive expansion, and authorities aspire for the port to become an international shipping hub on the scale of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a> or Rotterdam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The best way to call home is by purchasing an international calling card, which you can buy at a drug store or gift shop; calling cards can be used with pay phones or hotel phones.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone operators. Be sure to ask your mobile provider if separate fees exist for roaming in Puerto Rico; some companies do not consider the island part of the USA under their contract plans and levy a separate rate for Puerto Rico.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet access is available in all cities and large towns; you can also find terminals in hotels and business centres.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Broadcasting is regulated by the US Federal Communications Commission (FCC). English-language newspaper <em>The San Juan Star</em> ceased publication in 2008, and was subsequently replaced by <em>The Puerto Rico Daily Sun</em>.</p>
<p>Other papers include <em>El Nuevo D&iacute;a</em>, <em>El Vocero</em>, and <em>Primera Hora</em>; each is published daily. Home-grown comedies, talk shows and Spanish-language soaps are staple fare on local TV stations; the multichannel offerings of cable TV are also widely available.</p>
<p>Puerto Rico's basic and cable TV services offer numerous mainland US channels, as well as domestic channels. Telemundo and Univision represent the majority of the Spanish-language market share on the island.</p>
<p>Puerto Rico has several dozen FM and AM stations; the vast majority offers programming primarily or exclusively in Spanish. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Puerto Rico post is part of the US postal system. Airmail to Western Europe takes up to one week.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700; some branches have Saturday half-day service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Cruise La Parguera’s coral cays</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located off the southwest coast, Mata la Gata is a gorgeous but hardly-known coral cay within La Parguera Nature Reserve, and a wonderful spot for swimming and snorkelling. Get there by water taxi from La Parguera's piers, but bring your own food and water supplies, as facilities on the island are minimal.</p>]]><p><b>Dive off ‘The Wall’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Puerto Rico's coral encrusted coastline provides some fantastic opportunities for divers. Its most popular diving spot, however, is La Pared (The Wall), a 35km (22 mile) coral reef located off the south western coast. Water depths range from 16m (52ft) to 457m (1,500ft), offering something for every type of diver, in particular an abundance of colourful fish in crystal clear waters.</p>]]><p><b>Explore an ancient burial ground</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Tibes Indian Ceremonial Centre is an ancient site near Ponce, well worth a visit to see its remains of ball courts, as well as a cemetery. A replica of a Taino Indian village has been built here and multiple guided tours are offered daily. There is also an on-site museum with Taino artefacts.</p>]]><p><b>Get starry eyed at Arecibo Observatory</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Site of the largest single-aperture radio telescope in the world, this international observatory is located in northern Puerto Rico, amid the distinctive karst landscape of limestone peaks and sinkholes. You can see the 8-hectare (20-acre) dish from an observatory platform in one such sinkhole at Arecibo's visitors' centre.</p>]]><p><b>Go beach hopping</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the island's beaches, which include some of the Caribbean's finest. Crashboat beach on the west coast appeals to photographers for its colourful boats on the shore. Other excellent beaches include palm-fringed Luquillo Beach in Fajardo; family-friendly Escambrón in San Juan; Combate Beach on the southwest coast, which is ideal for sunset-spotting; and Flamenco Beach in Culebra, named one of the world's best by Discovery Channel.</p>]]><p><b>Sample the cultural wonders of the ‘Pearl of the South’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The beautiful colonial town of Ponce, on the southern side of the island, is called 'La Perla del Sur' or 'Pearl of the South', for its distinctive architectural charms. Visit the excellent Museum of Art, which contains more than 1,000 paintings and 400 sculptures, ranging from ancient classical to contemporary art. Its collection of 19th-century Pre-Raphaelite paintings is considered among the best in the Americas.</p>]]><p><b>See San José Church, one of the finest in the Americas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the second-oldest church in the Western hemisphere, founded by Dominican monks in 1532. In the heart of Old San Juan, San José church has been undergoing restoration since 2002, uncovering early murals beneath 19th-century paintings. It is considered by scholars to be one of the best examples of Spanish Gothic architecture in the Americas.</p>]]><p><b>See a night-time bioluminescent display</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Puerto Rico boasts three of the world's bioluminescent bays (also called phosphorescent bays): in Fajardo, the town of La Parguera, and at Mosquito Bay on Vieques. All three offer night-time tours to see this show of natural lights dancing in the water, created by illuminated dinoflagellates, tiny sea creatures.</p>]]><p><b>See the island’s history in a mosaic</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Puerto Rico's capitol building is a must-see for architecture and history aficionados. The majestic marble capitol sits directly in front of the Atlantic Ocean as you enter Old San Juan. Don't just take photos outside; the interior dome features a gorgeous, colourful mosaic depicting the island's history. The Puerto Rican constitution is also on display.</p>]]><p><b>Swim in the only tropical rainforest in the US</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sprawling across a mountainous expanse of northeast Puerto Rico, El Yunque is the only rainforest in the US Forest Service's system. Popular walking trails include La Mina, which leads to a waterfall and natural swimming pool, with others taking in craggy outcrops and Taino petroglyphs. On a clear day, climb the look-out tower in the park for a view of mountains and ocean.</p>]]><p><b>Tour San Juan’s Museums</b></p><![CDATA[<p>San Juan has a handful of interesting museums, which are a welcome diversion on rainy days. There's the Casa de los Contrafuertes, which houses the African Heritage Museum; Casa del Callejón, a traditional Spanish-style home with exhibits that explore colonial architecture and Puerto Rican family life; and the San Juan Museum of Art and History, which is housed in a 19th-century building and is often used for concerts.</p>]]><p><b>View the highlights over Ponce</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Perched on a hill overlooking Ponce, Castillo Serrallés is the former home of rum magnate Juan Serrallés, with a museum, artworks and butterfly garden attracting some 100,00 visitors a year. Equally impressive is La Cruceta de la Vigia, a cross-shaped observatory opposite the colonial-style mansion; from the top, you can see all the way to the Caribbean Sea.</p>]]><p><b>Walk the city walls of old San Juan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Most of San Juan's old city remains are enclosed by a wall built in the 16th and 17th centuries, and which you can walk around for lovely views of the city below and the Atlantic Ocean beyond. It leads, finally, to the only remaining original doors into the old city, with its blue cobblestone streets, intimate plazas, and colonial-style homes. Standing guard over it all are the colonial Spanish fortresses of El Morro and San Cristobal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$93.5 billion (2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Chemicals, electronics, tinned tuna, rum and medical equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Clothing, petroleum and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Ireland, The Netherlands, Japan and the Dominican Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Puerto Rico has few natural resources, although some nickel and copper have been located. Mining is not currently a source of income for the island. Manufacturing has overtaken agriculture as a source of income following intensive industrialisation, but tourism is the engine of the Puerto Rican economy.</p>
<p>The island's main products are pharmaceuticals, electrical and electronic equipment, processed food, textiles, clothing, rum, petrochemicals and refined oil. There is a foreign free-trade zone at Mayag&uuml;ez. In the agricultural sector, dairy and livestock produce are now more important than sugar cane, formerly the island's main crop. Fresh fruit and vegetables are grown for export.</p>
<p>Tourism is the main service industry and has undergone steady growth. Another major source of revenue used to come from a US naval base on the island of Vieques. Despite injecting an estimated US$300 million annually into the economy, it was widely unpopular with islanders; after sustained pressure, the closure of the base was announced in 2003.</p>
<p>Puerto Rico has observer status at the Caribbean trading bloc, CARICOM. The USA and its corporations dominate the domestic economy and trade patterns, although Puerto Rico has important trading links of its own with Japan, the Dominican Republic and Venezuela.</p>
<p>Inflation sits at around 2.5% (2010), unemployment at around 12% (2011) and growth in 2010 was -5.8%. Unemployment is a persistent problem and is a hot-button political issue best avoided when discussing business. Puerto Rico has been affected negatively by the worldwide economic crisis and stimulating the economy is a top priority (as well as a considerable challenge) for the current administration.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A knowledge of Spanish is very useful, although English is widely spoken; most people in the tourist industry and the greater metropolitan areas are bilingual and the country acknowledges both English and Spanish as its official languages. Lightweight suits are advised for business meetings. Many business transactions take place over lunch or dinner; while drinking is acceptable during such meetings, it should be done in moderation.</p>
<p>Though many Puerto Ricans love politics, the topic is best avoided during business discussions unless there is a direct bearing on the matter at hand. Due to the complicated colonial history of the island and its current status as a US commonwealth, certain aspects of politics are a sensitive issue, particularly when discussed by someone with little knowledge of the island's history. </p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chamber of Commerce of Puerto Rico</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 9024033,721 6060
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Preserving its colonial culinary heritage, Puerto Rico cuisine is predominantly Spanish-based, with other European, African and indigenous influences added to the pot. Local dishes – <em>comida criolla –</em> are richly spiced, with rice and beans as the staple diet.</p><p>Seafood and tropical fruits are not as abundant on Puerto Rican menus as many visitors expect. Guava and papaya on a restaurant menu, for example, are often candied and served with cheese, as a tasty sweet-and-savoury dessert.</p><p>Many of Puerto Rico's favourite foods are fried, including <em>empanadas</em>, pasties stuffed with beef, chicken, or fish; and fried sliced plantain, <em>tostones</em>. Rich stews are popular too: <em>asopao</em> is a mixed stew of chicken and seafood, and <em>sancocho</em> a hearty beef casserole with root vegetables.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mofongo:</strong> Afro-based dish of mashed plantain, stuffed with bacon, chicken or seafood and served in a broth.<br />
<strong>Tostones:</strong> Thick sliced plantain, fried as chips.<br />
<strong>Maduros:</strong> Sweet plantains; served fried or baked as a side dish.<br />
<strong>Lech&oacute;n asado:</strong> Roast suckling pig; a holiday dish particularly popular in the mountain town of Guavate.<br />
<strong>Arroz y habichuelas:</strong> Rice and beans; the beans are typically kidney beans and are often served in liquid, separate from the rice.<br />
<strong>Quesitos:</strong> A sweet pastry stuffed with cream cheese.<br />
<strong>Pastel:</strong> A plantain-based pasty typically steamed in a plantain leaf; popular throughout Spanish America as the <em>tamal</em>.<br />
<strong>Bacalao:</strong> Salted cod prepared in one of many styles, but perhaps most commonly served as <em>serenata de bacalao </em>or <em>bacalao serenade</em>, which is a tomato-based stew, with cod, potatoes, and onions.<br />
<strong>Piraguas:</strong> Paper cones filled with shaved ice, typically flavoured with passion fruit, mango or pineapple.<br />
<strong>Pi&ntilde;a colada</strong>: Puerto Rico claims to have invented this famous rum-based cocktail, one of many tropical drinks available, with and without alcohol.<br />
<strong>Rum:</strong> Any drink featuring rum is a safe and sure bet &ndash; Barrilio, Don Q, and Bacardi are popular local brands.<br />
<strong>Beer:</strong> As elsewhere in the region, most beers are light lagers; Medalla and Silver Key are two of the leading labels.<br />
<strong>Coquito:</strong> A holiday drink, like eggnog, served around Christmas.<br />
<strong>Mavi:</strong> A soft drink popular throughout the Caribbean, made from the bark of certain trees, with added sugar, spices and sometimes carbonated.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>It is customary to leave a 15-20% tip if service gratuities are not included on the bill.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Puerto Rico's nightlife is abundant and varied. In the capital, you can sit in the squares of Old San Juan and indulge in people watching. A recommended walk is down La Princesa, a promenade along the San Juan Bay that leads to the only remaining original doors to this walled city. On weekends, you can often find artisans selling wares here; groups of older Puerto Ricans also gather here to sing <em>bohemia</em>, nostalgic, folkloric tunes. Another favourite nightlife activity in San Juan is to join locals at Plaza del Mercado in the Santurce neighbourhood. Live music, both planned and impromptu, is played here each weekend. The market, while closed at night, is ringed by bars and restaurants.</p>
<p>Hotels provide some of the entertainment, but there are also different types of clubs, both modern and more mainstream. Many Puerto Ricans favour traditional Latin dance clubs with large dance floors, which often have live bands playing salsa and merengue music. One of the most popular clubs, however, is the Nuyorican in Old San Juan, a small dive bar with live music, exuding local culture.</p>
<p>Puerto Ricans are passionate about their nightlife, and often dress up. Casinos are intimate and friendly, generally opening at noon and closing at around 0400 daily.&nbsp; Outside the capital, nightlife options are more limited, and activities tend to be low-key, family-oriented events, centred around a town's main plaza.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Special purchases are cigars, coffee, hammocks, rum, straw weavings, 	sculpture, <em>santos</em> (carved religious figures), festival masks (called <em>vejigantes</em>) 	and stringed musical instruments. Note that cigars labelled as Cuban are not 	actually Cuban; because Puerto Rico is a US commonwealth, it is bound by the terms of the US embargo against importation and sale of Cuban goods. Lace is also a popular take-home item; made in the small town of Moca, <em>mundillo</em> (literally &lsquo;little world&rsquo;) is a special, traditional form of lace-making typical of Puerto Rico that can be traced back to Spain. It remains a vibrant craft today, and is even celebrated with an annual festival.</p>
<p>Watch out for cheap souvenirs in Old San Juan's trinket shops; many of the items are not authentic and are imported. A safe bet is to shop at Puerto Rican Arts and Crafts, which certifies that all of its products (typical island arts and crafts) are made by local artists. You can also buy directly from artists at 	street fairs, which are held on Paseo de la Princesa in Old San Juan on 	weekend nights. </p><p>Mon-Wed and Sat 0900-1900, Thurs-Fri 0900-2100, Sun 1100-1700 (shopping malls). Many shops in Old San Juan have variable hours, determined by the current cruise ship schedule. Plaza las Americas, the Caribbean's largest shopping mall, is located in the upscale banking neighbourhood of Hato Rey in San Juan. Plaza las Americas has many of the same shops you would find at a mall on the US mainland, as well as a food court, cinema, and rotating events and exhibits, including antique car shows and live music presentations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Juan has modern Americanised hotels and there is similar lodging in Ponce and Mayag&uuml;ez. Many resorts are on the island's southeastern coast, including Gran Melia, El Conquistador, and Bahia Beach. Vieques has also attracted major international hotel development in recent years, most recently with a W Hotel. Most of the major American chains have properties on the island, among them Intercontinental, Ritz, St Regis, Marriott, and Hilton.</p>
<p>San Juan is also home to a number of boutique and speciality hotels representing a range of price points. Da'House and Casa Blanca, both in Old San Juan, are affordable and charming, while El Convento and The Cervantes in Old San Juan represent the higher, more luxurious end of the speciality hotel scale. La Concha, while not a boutique hotel, is an icon in Puerto Rico and is located in the capital. Renovated after decades of non-use, La Concha, so named because of a design flourish shaped like a seashell, is deemed one of the best examples of tropical modernism architecture. Its lobby and patio are also one of the hottest nightlife see-and-be-seen spots in San Juan.</p>
<p>In Ponce, you'll find several mid-range and budget chains, including Ramada and Holiday Inn. One alternative, if you're looking for local flavour, is the Hotel Melia, a family-owned property located right on the city's main plaza.  On the northwest coast, independently owned small hotels are popular and are often run by expats. These are laid-back, friendly places to stay.</p>
<p>On the island of Vieques, a number of luxurious small properties have gained a loyal following. Hix Island House, built and owned by an architect, is perhaps the best known of these.</p>
<p>One interesting alternative to traditional hotels is the parador, located primarily outside the main urban areas. Paradores (government-sponsored country inns) are independently owned lodges and villas. The paradores are certified by the government and are often family owned.</p>
<p>Note that hostels and other traditional backpacker and budget travel accommodation are not common in Puerto Rico.</p>
<p>Regardless of where you plan to stay, be sure to ask about the local hotel tax and whether any additional charges (such as resort fees, internet use fees, and parking fees) are applied to your stay. These charges can add significantly to your lodging bill.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfast lodging has not been a popular type of accommodation in Puerto Rico; however, the number of B&Bs has increased in recent years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Juan has modern Americanised hotels and there is similar lodging in Ponce and Mayag&uuml;ez. Many resorts are on the island's southeastern coast, including Gran Melia, El Conquistador, and Bahia Beach. Vieques has also attracted major international hotel development in recent years, most recently with a W Hotel. Most of the major American chains have properties on the island, among them Intercontinental, Ritz, St Regis, Marriott, and Hilton.</p>
<p>San Juan is also home to a number of boutique and speciality hotels representing a range of price points. Da'House and Casa Blanca, both in Old San Juan, are affordable and charming, while El Convento and The Cervantes in Old San Juan represent the higher, more luxurious end of the speciality hotel scale. La Concha, while not a boutique hotel, is an icon in Puerto Rico and is located in the capital. Renovated after decades of non-use, La Concha, so named because of a design flourish shaped like a seashell, is deemed one of the best examples of tropical modernism architecture. Its lobby and patio are also one of the hottest nightlife see-and-be-seen spots in San Juan.</p>
<p>In Ponce, you'll find several mid-range and budget chains, including Ramada and Holiday Inn. One alternative, if you're looking for local flavour, is the Hotel Melia, a family-owned property located right on the city's main plaza.  On the northwest coast, independently owned small hotels are popular and are often run by expats. These are laid-back, friendly places to stay.</p>
<p>On the island of Vieques, a number of luxurious small properties have gained a loyal following. Hix Island House, built and owned by an architect, is perhaps the best known of these.</p>
<p>One interesting alternative to traditional hotels is the parador, located primarily outside the main urban areas. Paradores (government-sponsored country inns) are independently owned lodges and villas. The paradores are certified by the government and are often family owned.</p>
<p>Note that hostels and other traditional backpacker and budget travel accommodation are not common in Puerto Rico.</p>
<p>Regardless of where you plan to stay, be sure to ask about the local hotel tax and whether any additional charges (such as resort fees, internet use fees, and parking fees) are applied to your stay. These charges can add significantly to your lodging bill.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Juan has modern Americanised hotels and there is similar lodging in Ponce and Mayag&uuml;ez. Many resorts are on the island's southeastern coast, including Gran Melia, El Conquistador, and Bahia Beach. Vieques has also attracted major international hotel development in recent years, most recently with a W Hotel. Most of the major American chains have properties on the island, among them Intercontinental, Ritz, St Regis, Marriott, and Hilton.</p>
<p>San Juan is also home to a number of boutique and speciality hotels representing a range of price points. Da'House and Casa Blanca, both in Old San Juan, are affordable and charming, while El Convento and The Cervantes in Old San Juan represent the higher, more luxurious end of the speciality hotel scale. La Concha, while not a boutique hotel, is an icon in Puerto Rico and is located in the capital. Renovated after decades of non-use, La Concha, so named because of a design flourish shaped like a seashell, is deemed one of the best examples of tropical modernism architecture. Its lobby and patio are also one of the hottest nightlife see-and-be-seen spots in San Juan.</p>
<p>In Ponce, you'll find several mid-range and budget chains, including Ramada and Holiday Inn. One alternative, if you're looking for local flavour, is the Hotel Melia, a family-owned property located right on the city's main plaza.  On the northwest coast, independently owned small hotels are popular and are often run by expats. These are laid-back, friendly places to stay.</p>
<p>On the island of Vieques, a number of luxurious small properties have gained a loyal following. Hix Island House, built and owned by an architect, is perhaps the best known of these.</p>
<p>One interesting alternative to traditional hotels is the parador, located primarily outside the main urban areas. Paradores (government-sponsored country inns) are independently owned lodges and villas. The paradores are certified by the government and are often family owned.</p>
<p>Note that hostels and other traditional backpacker and budget travel accommodation are not common in Puerto Rico.</p>
<p>Regardless of where you plan to stay, be sure to ask about the local hotel tax and whether any additional charges (such as resort fees, internet use fees, and parking fees) are applied to your stay. These charges can add significantly to your lodging bill.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Health services vary by region and type of hospital (public versus private). Health care is most readily available in the San Juan metropolitan area, home to several hospitals. These include Ashford Presbyterian Community Hospital, the hospital of the University of Puerto Rico, Hospital Pavia and Hospital San Francisco. Services are costly and typically must be paid for, in cash, when rendered; travel health insurance is recommended. If you have a home health insurance plan, it will probably not cover any services in Puerto Rico, but be sure to carry your card or a copy with you. Also, be sure to retain receipts for any medical care received so you can seek reimbursement from your insurance company upon your return home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a good idea to take the name and phone number of your doctor from home along with you, should you need to contact him or her for a consultation or emergency. If you have a history of medical problems, it is particularly advised to carry relevant medical records, provider contact information, and emergency care instructions with you. As with other destinations, it is also wise to carry information on your person that provides instructions about who to contact in the event of an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If taking prescription medication with you, store all medications in their original containers, with appropriate pharmacy labelling. While it can be easier to obtain some medications that are typically prescription-only in the US mainland, such as inhalers for asthma, this is increasingly uncommon and difficult and travellers should not depend upon this. Also, Puerto Rican pharmacies will not fill prescriptions that were written off-island. Prescriptions must be written by a doctor licensed and registered in Puerto Rico in order to be filled by a pharmacy on the island.  &lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water is purified in main areas. Mains water is considered safe to drink. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are considered safe to eat. As with most travel destinations, take care when eating food sold by street vendors, as they are not bound by the same rigorous health and hygiene standards governing restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended, though no vaccinations are required to enter Puerto Rico. Outbreaks of dengue fever are increasingly common, though vigorous public health initiatives are intended to help control this problem. Protect yourself by wearing appropriate clothing and by using moquito repellent. Avoid stagnant, standing water, where mosquitoes tend to breed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Take special care when enjoying beaches and oceans; Puerto Rico's waters have jellyfish, lion fish, and sharks; though attacks are rare, awareness of your surroundings is important. Also take care if you decide to cycle or walk on Puerto Rico's roadways; aggressive driving puts you at risk of injury. Violence rarely affects tourists; however, the island's rate of violence, particularly related to drug trafficking, is increasing exponentially each year.&amp;nbsp; One final risk is sun exposure; the sun here is hotter than you may be accustomed to, so use sunscreen. &lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Each town celebrates a festival or fiesta in honour of a local patron saint. These can last up to 10 days.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Birthday of Eugenio Mar :
							2018<br/>08 January </p><p>Martin Luther King, Jr. Day :
							2018<br/>15 January </p><p>Presidents' Day :
							19 February </p><p>Emancipation Day :
							22 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Jos̩ de Diego Day :
							16 April </p><p>Memorial Day :
							28 May </p><p>US Independence Day :
							04 July </p><p>Luis Mu̱oz Rivera's Birthday :
							16 July </p><p>Constitution Day :
							25 July </p><p>Jos̩ Celso Barbosa's Birthday :
							27 July </p><p>Labour Day :
							03 September </p><p>Columbus Day :
							08 October </p><p>Veterans' Day :
							11 November </p><p>Discovery of Puerto Rico Day :
							19 November </p><p>Thanksgiving Day :
							22 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In general duty-free regulations are the same for Puerto Rico as for the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>. The following goods may be imported by visitors over 21 years of age into Puerto Rico without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigars.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic beverages.</p>
<p>Further information on US customs regulations is available online (<a href="http://www.cbp.gov">www.cbp.gov</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics and dangerous drugs (unless for medical purposes), absinthe, biological materials, some seeds, fruits and plants (including endangered species of plants and vegetables and their products), unlicensed firearms and ammunition, meat and poultry products (fresh, dried or canned), any fish&nbsp;or their eggs (unless certified as disease free and canned, pickled or smoked), dairy products and eggs,&nbsp;Cuban cigars, wildlife and endangered species, dog and cat fur, some art and artefacts, imports from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/iran">Iran</a> and leather souvenirs from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/haiti">Haiti</a> (eg drums), some automobiles, counterfeit goods, merchandise from embargoed countries (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cuba">Cuba</a>, Iran, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/myanmar">Myanmar</a>, and most of&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sudan">Sudan</a>), and unauthorised cultural artefacts.</p>
<p>Note that although the embargo against Cuba has not been lifted, authorised US travellers visiting Cuba may now purchase up to US$400 of goods for personal use.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visitors leaving Puerto Rico are required to send their checked luggage through US Food and Drug Administration screening, which scans for animals, fruits, vegetables, and current prohibited items by X-ray.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar (USD; symbol US$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of US$100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of US$1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents. There is no other currency used on the island. Note that many businesses will not have change for large bills; it is advised to carry smaller bills and coins to avoid needing change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can exchange foreign currency at banks and at major hotels, though it is best to arrive with US Dollars and avoid exchange altogether. Currency exchange booths, or bureaux de change (<em>cambio</em>) are not common in Puerto Rico. There is not even a bureau de change at the international airport in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/san-juan">San Juan</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All international credit cards, and many leading debit cards are accepted. Be aware that your credit card or banking institution may impose a fee for international use of your card; ask your institution about this fee prior to your travels should you have questions.</p><p>All major ATM services are available across the island, even in small towns. Note that ATMs in Puerto Rico are called ATHs (A Toda Hora- literally, 'at all hours'). You will have the choice of English or Spanish when making your transaction. Be sure to pay attention to the local fee imposed for use of cards not affiliated with the ATM's bank. Also, be aware that many Puerto Rican ATMs/ATHs are programmed to ask for a donation for local charities; you can opt out of this request at the end of your transaction. The major banks on the island include Banco Popular, Citibank, Doral, Santander, and Westernbank. Banks often have ATMs/ATHs and even small branches located inside grocery stores. Use the typical precautions you would use at home when withdrawing money from an ATM in Puerto Rico.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller&rsquo;s cheques are increasingly <em>not</em> accepted as a form of payment, especially outside the capital and especially by small businesses. If used at all, US Dollar cheques are preferred. If you intend to use traveller&rsquo;s cheques, you are advised to call ahead to businesses to ensure they accept this form of payment. Credit cards or cash are strongly preferred by the majority of merchants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1530. Hours may vary. Note that banks are closed on all <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> holidays, as well as local holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Passport and visa requirements for entering Puerto Rico are the same as for entering the USA. Please see the USA passport &amp; visa section.</p>
<p>US travellers visiting Puerto Rico do not require a passport, but must carry a piece of government-issued photo ID.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[18.246979]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-66.647987]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>8,870 sq km (3,425 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3,680,772 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>405.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>San Juan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Self-governing US Commonwealth Territory (incorporated).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Puerto Rico is an island east of the Dominican Republic and west of the British Virgin Islands. The rougher, cooler Atlantic Ocean is on the north side of the island; the calmer, warmer Caribbean Sea is on the south side. It is the smallest island in the Greater Antilles and the largest island in the Lesser Antilles. Culebra, Mona and Vieques are among several smaller islands that are part of Puerto Rican territory. The waters surrounding the island are quite deep; the Puerto Rico trench is the deepest part of the Atlantic Ocean.</p>
<p>The island is comparatively small, 8,959 sq km (3,459 sq miles), with a central mountain range reaching an altitude of 1,338m (4,390ft) at Cerro de Punta, and surrounded by low coastal plains. The island has remarkable geographic diversity for its size, with limestone formations in the interior, a desert in the southeastern part of the island, and the rainforest. Mangroves dominate the southern shore and are an important part of the island's ecosystem.</p>
<p>San Juan, the capital, is on the northeast shore. Much of the island's natural forest has been cleared for agriculture, but the trees in the northeast corridor are protected as a national park. One of the hot-button environmental and political issues on the island is increasing development, particularly by the tourism industry with respect to hotel and resort construction. The island's nature conservancy, the Fideicomiso, has played a critical role in acquiring and protecting significant land and restoring properties for public visits and educational purposes.</p>
<p>The other main towns are Aguadilla, Arecibo, Bayam&oacute;n, Caguas, Carolina, Cayey, Fajardo, Guaynabo, Mayag&uuml;ez and Ponce.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic 85%; the remainder are Protestant and Jewish. Syncretic practices such as Santeria often exist alongside formal religion in devotees' personal expressions of faith.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the customary form of greeting among acquaintances. Casual dress is acceptable, but shorts should not be worn in hotel dining rooms or casinos, where formal dress is required after 2000. Spanish and American manners and conventions exist side by side on the island. Some hotels require formal dress.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>120 volts AC, 60Hz. American-style plugs with two flat pins (with or without third grounding pin) are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Governor Ricardo Rosselló since 2 January 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Donald Trump since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Puerto Rico was first inhabited in around 3,000 BC. When Columbus landed in 1493 on his second voyage to the New World, the island&rsquo;s inhabitants were the Tainos, Arawak people originating from South America. Claiming the territory on behalf of the Spanish Crown, Ponce de Leon governed Puerto Rico from 1508.</p>
<p>Puerto Rico was eventually ceded to the USA in 1898 at the end of the Spanish-American War. In Guanica, on Puerto Rico's southern coast, you can see a monument to the spot where &lsquo;invading&rsquo; US troops landed during the war.</p>
<p>Puerto Ricans were granted US citizenship in 1917 and in 1952 the island became a self-governing Commonwealth in association with the USA. Although seen by many as a political compromise, in practice, this gives Puerto Ricans an American passport and makes them eligible for military draft but they do not pay US federal taxes and cannot vote in US elections.</p>
<p>Their status remains one of Puerto Ricans most contentious issues. Of the main political parties, the Partido Popular Democr&aacute;tico (PPD) is broadly in favour of the existing Commonwealth status, while the Partido Nuevo Progresista (PNP) supports full state membership. A third party, Partido Independentista Puertorrique&ntilde;o (PIP) supports independence.</p>
<p>In December 1998, the third referendum in 30 years was held on the issue: voters were asked whether they wished Puerto Rico to become the 51st state of the USA, become independent, enter a compact of Free Association (similar to that which operates in a number of Pacific micro-territories) or retain the status quo. By a narrow majority, the vote for the status quo won. A further referendum in August 2012 resulted in a vote for US statehood.</p>
<p>However, the country remains in limbo, chiefly because the US Congress makes the final decision when it comes to admitting new states and, despite heavy lobbying, it has yet to accept Puerto Rico as one of the United States of America.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The pi&ntilde;a colada was invented in Puerto Rico (with the honour claimed by two San Juan bar men) and has been the national beverage since 1978.<br />
&bull;	Zuleyka Rivera Mendoza, a former actress from Puerto Rico, was crowned Miss Universe in 2006, the island&rsquo;s fifth winner of the title.<br />
&bull;	Cockfighting, outlawed in most other countries, is hugely popular in Puerto Rico &ndash; it draws large crowds and is sometimes televised.<br />
&bull;	The world&rsquo;s largest single-lens telescope is on Puerto Rico, at the Arecibo Observatory, in the northwest of the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Diplomatic Representation in the UK (US Embassy)]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7499 9000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://london.usembassy.gov</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7499 9000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>24 Grosvenor Square<br/>London<br/>W1A 1AE<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Think palm-fringed beaches, colourful colonial buildings and a harmony of Caribbean, Hispanic and American cultures, and you&rsquo;ve got Puerto Rico in a nutshell. A coconut shell, of course. Add to this swathes of tropical rainforest, warm turquoise waters and year-round sunshine and you have all the hallmarks of a perfect holiday destination.</p>
<p>Most visitors flock to Puerto Rico to bask on its pristine sands. From Rinc&oacute;n&rsquo;s rip-roaring swells to the nearly deserted shores of Vieques where wild horses roam, there really is sand and surf for every type of beach bum. Puerto Rico also has three rare bioluminescent bays: glow-in-the-dark bodies of water that produce a nighttime lightshow for kayakers and boat tours.</p>
<p>Inland, epic landscapes and cultural attractions abound. The central mountain range is riddled with limestone caves and rugged forest trails. El Yunque National Forest, by contrast, is a lush expanse of rainforest, with waterfalls and Taino petroglyphs. The Conservation Trust of Puerto Rico's various sites offer visitors a taste of the island&rsquo;s colonial history, including Hacienda Buena Vista, an old coffee plantation, and Hacienda Esperanza, an old sugar plantation.</p>
<p>Culturally, Puerto Rico integrates three &ldquo;roots&rdquo;: Taino (an indigenous group), Spanish and African. The country is in the Caribbean, but not wholly of it, influenced also by Latin America and the USA, with which it has a colonial relationship. The American influence is visible through ubiquitous US flags, shopping malls and basketball, the national sport. Historical Spanish influences are well preserved. Old  San Juan is home to two UNESCO World Heritage sites, with blue cobblestone streets and pastel-painted colonial buildings.</p>
<p>This blend of cultures makes for interesting music, food and festivals, as well as some quirks of daily life (the Spanish and English languages are fused resulting in some interesting names). Preserving cultural heritage is what Puerto Ricans do best, and it&rsquo;s what draws visitors back again and again. That and the beaches, of course.</p><p>Think palm-fringed beaches, colourful colonial buildings and a harmony of Caribbean, Hispanic and American cultures, and you&rsquo;ve got Puerto Rico in a nutshell. A coconut shell, of course. Add to this swathes of tropical rainforest, warm turquoise waters and year-round sunshine and you have all the hallmarks of a perfect holiday destination.&nbsp;Most visitors flock to Puerto Rico to bask on its pristine sands. From Rinc&oacute;n&rsquo;s rip-roaring &nbsp;swells to the nearly deserted shores of Vieques where wild horses roam, there really is sand and surf for every type of beach bum.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
