<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Qatar" ColCode="qat" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="qa" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Qatar]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Occupying a small land on the eastern coast of the Arabian Peninsula, the sovereign state of Qatar has a dry, subtropical desert climate with low annual rainfall and intensely hot and humid summers.</p>
<p>The weather in Qatar can be broadly grouped into two seasons: hot (May to October) and cool (December to February). March, April and November are transitional months, meaning the weather is hot but tolerable.</p>
<p>The best time to visit Qatar is from November to March, the cool period when temperatures are warm and the evenings can be pleasantly cool. January is the coolest month with temperatures ranging from 14&deg;C (57&deg;F) to 22&deg;F (72&deg;F). Temperatures start to climb after January and by March, the average high is back to 24&deg;C (75&deg;F).</p>
<p>Although the cool period (November to March) is the best time to visit Qatar, bear in mind that rainfall, however scarce, occurs during this period too, and the rains come mostly in heavy cloudbursts and thunderstorms.</p>
<p>The hot period (May to October) is oven-temperature hot and best avoided. July is often considered the hottest month with temperatures ranging from 32&deg;C (90&deg;F) to 43&deg;C (109&deg;F) &ndash; although it's not unusual for the mercury to reach an eye-watering high of 50&deg;C (122&deg;F) in July and sometimes August. If you're visiting during the hot period, you may find yourself seeking refuge in one of the many air-conditioned malls. After October, things start to cool down and by November, you can expect an average high of 24&deg;C (75&deg;F).</p>
<p>Because Qatar is a small and flat country, there is little regional variation in the weather, although coastal areas may be slightly cooler than inland. Doha, the capital of Qatar, is highly urbanised which can make the weather in Doha feel slightly hotter than it is. See our guide on <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/doha/weather">weather in Doha and the best time to visit</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cotton and linen are recommended during summer months but avoid wearing pure silk, which sticks to the skin with the humidity (although silk blends are great). A cardigan is useful for the over-cooled malls in the summer and a jacket is a must for cooler evenings during the winter. If you intend to take a camping trip from January to March, you'll be glad to have packed an extra layer of clothing at night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Doha has Qatar&rsquo;s only international airport and there are no internal flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Qatar itself is very easy to explore by car as it&rsquo;s a tiny country. The drive from the Saudi border in the south to Madinat ash Shamal in the very north of the country is only 160km (100 miles), taking around 2 hours 30 minutes.  Most roads lead to and from Doha; route 1 leads north to Madinat ash Shamal, the Dukhan Highway leads west to Dukhan and route 5 heads south to the Saudi border.</p>r<p>Because of the cheapness of petrol, almost everything in Qatar moves by road and there is an advanced road system which, nonetheless, is still undergoing extensive upgrades.  New expressways are being built to link Doha with other areas, and there are new road works springing up all the time.  This can make it a confusing place to drive.  Driving in Qatar is something of a competitive sport; speed and unpredictability are the two main characteristics. Areas of <em>sabka</em> (salt flats) make leaving the road to access the coast a hazard in many parts of Qatar, even in a 4-wheel drive vehicle. It's best to stick to prior tracks.</p><p>Mowasalat (<a href="http://www.mowasalat.com" target="_blank">www.mowasalat.com</a>) runs a public bus service from Doha to all areas within Qatar.</p><p>There is a choice between the old orange and white cars or newer, slightly more expensive sea-blue taxis. Both have meters. Taxis can be hired on an hourly basis, but if that&rsquo;s the case it's better to negotiate the fee in advance. Taxis are the main source of public transport within Doha.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required, but a temporary licence can be obtained on presentation of a valid national licence. Your driving licence must be kept in the car at all times.</p><p>On motorways and dual carriageways out of the city the speed limit is 120kph (75mph). Within the city on smaller roads the speed limit ranges from 50kph (31mph) to 100kph (62mph).</p><p>There is no national breakdown service but private companies do operate. Try Arabian Automobile Association (tel: 4481 0500; <a href="http://www.aaaqatar.com" target="_blank">www.aaaqatar.com</a>) if assistance is needed.</p><p>Available from local and international companies at the airport and hotels. The minimum age for driving in Qatar is 18, although some car hire companies may demand drivers are at least 21. Seat belts must be worn. Large on-the-spot fines are issued to anyone not wearing one or not carrying a driver's licence.</p><p>The chaotic traffic in Doha and throughout Qatar makes cycling inadvisable.</p><p>On motorways and dual carriageways out of the city the speed limit is 120kph (75mph). Within the city on smaller roads the speed limit ranges from 50kph (31mph) to 100kph (62mph).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Doha is Qatar&rsquo;s main city, and traffic can be frenetic and heavy. Mowasalat (<a href="http://www.mowasalat.com" target="_blank">www.mowasalat.com</a>) runs a taxi and limousine service.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Qatar Airways (<a href="http://www.qatarairways.com" target="_blank">www.qatarairways.com</a>) operates flights to Qatar from London Heathrow&nbsp;and&nbsp;New York.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/quatar/doha-hamad-international-airport">Doha Hamad International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 6 hours 45 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 12 hours 20 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Doha Hamad International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.dohahamadairport.com<p>The airport is located about 9km (5.5 miles) southeast of central Doha.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+974 4010 6666</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Doha and Umm Said are the main ports. The water traffic is mostly commercial.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no rail services in Qatar, but plans are afoot to construct a railway network connecting cities within Qatar as well as creating links to neighbouring countries, to be completed by 2030. See Qatar Rail (<a href="http://www.qr.com.qa" target="_blank">www.qr.com.qa</a>) for more details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Routes 5 and 59 link Doha with Saudi Arabia to the South; Route 59 then joins up with Route 95 into the UAE. With car insurance for both countries, the Qatar-Saudi border is open to residents of Qatar, Saudi Arabia and UAE. However, getting across the border can be difficult for foreign nationals, which means that the reality of crossing the borders is that car hire companies rarely allow drivers to leave Qatar.</p><p>Driving across borders from Qatar into Saudi Arabia is impossible for female travellers, as women are not allowed to drive in Saudi Arabia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone operators. Mobile phone use is pretty much a national addiction; coverage is excellent.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of internet cafes in Doha.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Qatari media industry is most famous for the TV News channel Al-Jazeera, which launched in 1996.&nbsp;Al-Jazeera English, a 24/7 English language news channel launched in 2006, was estimated to reach 250 million homes worldwide by 2011.&nbsp;Like all Qatari state media, it is owned by the government. And while there has been no censorship of the media since 1995, print and broadcast media tend to self-censor, and rarely criticise Qatar, Saudi Arabia or other Gulf allies.</p>
<p>The main newspapers are privately owned, but still have links to the ruling family.&nbsp;The main dailies are <em>Al-Watan</em>, <em>Ar-Rayah</em> and <em>Al-Sharq</em>, while the main English language newspapers are <em>Gulf Times</em>, <em>The Peninsula </em>and <em>Qatar Tribune.</em>&nbsp;As the expat population of Doha has grown, listings magazines have been launched, including <em>Time Out Doha </em>and <em>Qatar Happening</em>, both free. These are the best places for cultural listings and what&rsquo;s going on in the city.</p>
<p>Unlike most countries, print media in Qatar is expanding.&nbsp;Oryx Advertising is a major magazine publisher, with titles including <em>Qatar Today</em> and <em>Qatar Al Youm</em>, monthly business magazines (in English and Arabic respectively).&nbsp;It also publishes <em>Women Today</em>, the only magazine for working women and <em>GLAM, </em>a fashion magazine.</p>
<p>The Qatar Broadcasting Service is the state-run radio station, offering programmes in Arabic, English, French and Urdu.&nbsp;The BBC World Service can be received on FM in Doha.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes up to one week.</p><p>Sun-Thurs 0700-2000, Sat 0800-1100 and 1700-1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Al-Shahaniya</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tackle a sand dune on sand-skis, a quad-bike or plain Shank's pony in the dunes south of Doha, near Mesaieed - or for those with more poetry in their souls, pick a quiet ridge for a picnic.</p>]]><p><b>Catch a fish in Al-Khor</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hire a car and see the 'other side' of Qatar: the pleasant fishing towns of Al-Khor and Al-Zubara were once important for the pearling industry, while Umm Salal Mohammed and Umm Salal Ali hint at a more ancient past.</p>]]><p><b>Check out Doha Fort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Before you dive into Souq Waqif, take a look at Doha Fort; built in the 19th century by the occupying Turks, it has been used as a prison and a stamp museum among other things.</p>]]><p><b>Embark on a desert adventure</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tackle a sand dune on sand-skis or a quad-bike, or just stroll through the dunes south of Doha, near Mesaieed. For those with more poetry in their souls, pick a quiet ridge for a picnic.</p>]]><p><b>Find Ostriches and Oryx in Zekreet</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The national symbol of Qatar, oryx are shy, rarely seen animals – and are being reintroduced to the country having once been native.  The country's biggest oryx farm is on the Zekreet peninsula on the west coast, and close by is the Ostrich farm, where the birds are free to roam, so visitors can really get up close.</p>]]><p><b>Go jogging down the Corniche</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Jog along the magnificent crescent-mooned corniche to fully appreciate the spectacular skyline of the West Bay area; go early morning or at sunset to avoid the heat and join the locals.</p>]]><p><b>Head to Dukhan Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An hour's drive due west of Doha, Dukhan is the country's best beach, and popular as an overnight camping spot.  Great for families, as the beach is shallow and shelves very gently, it also offers good snorkelling and is an ideal picnic spot.</p>]]><p><b>Katara Cultural Village</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A new beachfront development in Doha that houses an outdoor amphitheatre for classical and pop concerts, theatre, art galleries, restaurants and the offices of all Qatar's cultural organisations.</p>]]><p><b>Play a round of golf at Doha Golf Club</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Play a round or two at the Doha Golf Club, which boasts both a 6743m (22,120ft) 18-hole championship course and a floodlit 9-hole course. Both are world-class standard; the Qatar Masters in March is an important event on the international circuit.</p>]]><p><b>See Arabian stallions at Al Shaqab Stud</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Horse-lovers should head to Al Shaqab for a glimpse of Sheik Haman Bin Ali Al Than's famous purebred Arabian stallions. Tours of the training grounds and stables are available, and the Riding Academy offers lessons.</p>]]><p><b>Shop in Souq Waqif</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try your bartering skills on the vendors in Souq Waqif; with a nose for a bargain you can find antique plates from China, prayer beads of amber, leather-tipped camel sticks and aromatic chests of cardamom from India.  Or simply settle in for coffee and shisha and watch the world go by.</p>]]><p><b>Take a Dhow boat ride</b></p><![CDATA[<p>There's no better way to see Doha's glittering architecture from the sea, and at sunset the light glinting off the chrome and glass makes them look even more spectacular. Old wooden fishing dhows have been converted into pleasure boats that run day and sunset cruises.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the views of Khor al-Adaid</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Book an overnight tour to Khor al-Adaid and discover the breathtaking sunset and sunrise over Qatar's inland sea. Access to this area of salt-flats and sand dunes is by 4-wheel drive, and tour prices include barbeque and camping.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Try some dune-bashing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join the locals in one of their favourite past-times; roaring up and down the dunes in 4x4s. If you don't want to take your own car into the sand (probably not advisable) quad bikes can be hired by the turn-off to the Sealine Beach Resort.</p>]]><p><b>Uncover the Lost City of Zekreet</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hidden away on the Zekreet peninsula, a few miles north of Dukhan, lies Qatar's quirkiest secret; a film-set traditional Qatari village that is entirely deserted. Rumour has it that it was used for a World Cup 2022 promotional video.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Museum of Islamic Art</b></p><![CDATA[<p>I. M. Pei's beautifully designed gallery, right on the Corniche in the heart of the city has become one of Doha's most iconic sights. Inside the space is light and airy, and the collection of Arabic art, calligraphy and ceramics is breathtaking. The outdoor terrace is a great place for evening drink, with fabulous views of West Bay.</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at Sheikh Feisal Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Twenty minutes outside Doha, the museum is an astonishing collection of everything from dinosaur relics to Formula One cars, with rooms given over to art, calligraphy, furniture, boats and motor vehicles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$165 billion (2015).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil and gas.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Consumer goods, machinery and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Japan, South Korea, India, Singapore,&nbsp;UAE and China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In a world of faltering economies, Qatar has continued to prosper in recent years; in 2010 Qatar had the world's highest GDP per capita. While agriculture is limited by climate and water resources, the Qatari government has bolstered indigenous industries such as petrochemicals and refining, ammonia, fertilisers, steel, cement and commercial ship repair. </p>
<p>Still, it&rsquo;s oil, and in particular gas reserves, which have transformed Qatar from an impoverished outcrop on the Arabian Peninsula into one of the richest countries in the world.&nbsp; By 2007, it was the largest exporter of liquefied natural gas in the world. Economic growth has slowed down since the dizzy heights of 19% growth in 2010 (2012 saw it halve to 6.2%) but the country is still outstripping the US and the majority of Europe, stuck in the doldrums of the economic crisis. Qatar is a member of OPEC and the World Trade Organisation, with petroleum accounting for more than 70% of the government's revenue, 60% of GDP and the third largest proved natural gas reserves in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Politeness and patience are key ingredients for successful business interaction. A first meeting may well focus more on polite, personal questions – family, travel arrangements etc, before moving on to business matters in a second meeting.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0800-1200 and 1600-1900. Government office hours are Sat-Wed 0700-1400. Some are open on Thursday mornings too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Qatar Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 455 9111
					Website:http://www.qcci.org/
					Address: ,PO Box 402,Doha,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Options for dining out in Qatar are pretty limited outside Doha, but within the capital there has been a marked improvement in recent years.  Chefs such as Guy Savoy, Jean-Georges Vongerichten and Gordon Ramsey have all opened restaurants in the city, and the cosmopolitan mix of population means that almost every cuisine imaginable can be found, from Thai to American, Mexican and French.</p>
<p>Within the capital area, there is a wide range of quality dining options, many but not all of which are to be found in the 5-star hotels. One of the best places to eat is in Souq Waqif, where a variety of Middle Eastern-themed eateries vie for trade; Iraqi, Persian, Qatari, Turkish and Syrian are all on offer.  For most expats and visitors, the most important meal of the week is Friday brunch, when hotels compete to lay out the widest and most varied choice of food.  Booking ahead, at any of the five-star hotels, is essential.</p>
<p>The locally caught fish is a treat whether lowered genteelly to your plate with silver service or brought sizzling to the table on kebab sticks at a more local-style cafe. If the ubiquitous Gulf menu of rice, lamb and mezze (homos, chopped salads and other appetisers) is not to your taste, then there are plenty of Indian, Chinese and Thai options to suit all budgets. The fruit concoctions - such as lemon and mint, or avocado milkshake - are irresistible in summer.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Traditional Levantine <em>shawarma</em> (spit-roasted meat shavings, served in pitta bread)<em><br />
</em>&bull; Egyptian <em>foul</em> and <em>taamiyeh</em> (deep-fried balls of mashed chickpeas)<br />
&bull; <em>Kabsa</em> (a traditional dish of rice with chicken)<br />
&bull; <em>Harees </em>(a traditional Qatari wheat and meat pudding)<br />
&bull; <em>Mashboos </em>(slow-cooked mutton served with spiced rice)</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol is widely available in most top-end restaurants and hotel bars in Doha although it is officially reserved for hotel guests or 'club members'. Drinking alcohol in public outside these establishments is prohibited. Meze (a selection of salads that often begin a meal) are an excellent option for vegetarians, and served in most Middle Eastern restaurants.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A service charge is often added to bills in hotels and most restaurants, otherwise 10% is appropriate. However in smaller establishments, tipping is not the custom, and over-generous tips from tourists often backfire through the subsequent cutting of wages.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>21.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Outside the capital, there&rsquo;s little in the way of nightlife beyond strong espresso and shisha, but with a growing expat population and increased westernisation in Doha, nightclubs and late-night bars are springing up.&nbsp;The hippest place in the city is currently the Crystal Lounge at the W Hotel (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.whoteldoha.com">www.whoteldoha.com</a>), while for something mellower Jazz at Lincoln Centre (<a href="http://www.jalcdoha.com" target="_blank">www.jalcdoha.com</a>) at the St Regis hotel offers world-class live music. <br />
<br />
There are also many cinemas showing English-language films while the Doha Players perform plays in English. The new Katara Cultural  Village (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.katara.net">www.katara.net</a>) hosts orchestral and operatic concerts and there&rsquo;s even some stand-up comedy. For live rock and pop music there is a small &ndash; but growing &ndash; number of venues, most of which are in the international hotels.</p>
<p>While Doha is a very safe city, it&rsquo;s worth being aware that in a society as traditional as Qatar, there is something of a fascination with women who are free to dress and go where they please. At clubs there tend to be many more men than women, and there may be quite a lot of staring.&nbsp;Qatari women are not allowed in any bar that sells alcohol and while there is no issue with western women drinking alcohol, getting rolling drunk is probably not the best idea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The premier national pastime in Qatar, shopping occupies much of Qataris free time, who flock to Doha&rsquo;s massive malls.&nbsp;For high-end couture, the Porto Arabia mall at the Pearl development is the place to shop for Dior and Chanel.&nbsp;On West Bay, the City Centre Mall is a vast space that combines western and Arabic chains.&nbsp;But it&rsquo;s not all westernised shopping; Doha's Souq Waqif was successfully rebuilt in the 1970s, but retained the feel and look of its original 1930s design. Locals and tourists come to buy everything from nuts and spices to jewelled abayas, onyx chess sets and bizarre salt and pepper pots made of two figures in traditional Arabic dress.&nbsp;Animal lovers would do well to avoid the animal souk.</p>
<p>The Doha Souq is the best place to go for fabrics and clothing, and there are tailors who can knock up anything from a suit to an evening gown.&nbsp;The Gold Souk is worth a visit, even if you've no intention of buying; the gleam coming off the 18 and 22-carat jewellery is blinding.&nbsp;And the good news for techies is that mobile phones and tablets are cheaper than home as they are all tax free (and cheaper than Dubai).&nbsp;Just be careful to check that they will work in the UK.</p>
<p>Bartering is standard practice, but not to the same extent as in other Middle Eastern countries; discounts of around 20% are standard.&nbsp;Ask for the 'best best price'; bartering beyond this price is considered bad manners.</p><p>Generally Sat-Thurs 0800-1200 and 1600-1900 or later, with the malls open until 2100 or 2200. Many shops are open on Friday evenings as well.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Doha has an increasing number of glitzy, five-star hotels, with manmade white sand beaches cropping up along the coastline.  The West Bay area is currently home to the city&rsquo;s glitziest addresses, including the W, and the Four Seasons, while other five-star chains have opened on the Pearl and beach areas in between. Most of the 5-star options are exquisitely packaged with marble flooring, silken drapes and Persian carpets and they all compete in the 'extreme art' of flower-arranging. Most are very family friendly, as the hotels serve a dual purpose; besides accommodation, they also tend to be where expats gather to eat, drink and socialise, as alcohol is only available in the bars of international hotels.  On Fridays (the equivalent of our Saturday) luxury hotels are full of expat families eating brunch and lazing by the pool or on the beach.</p>
<p>The new vogue in the city is for boutique hotels, and there are now five &lsquo;Souq Waqif Boutique Hotels&rsquo; which give you the chance to stay right at the heart of the souq.  Prices and luxury levels are still five star, in spite of the boutique tag.  The area around Souq Waqif is also where many of the cheaper, smaller hotels can be found, which offer more budget accommodation (although there&rsquo;s little in the city that&rsquo;s actually cheap).</p>
<p>Beyond the city, there are fewer options.  Most of the other towns are little more than Qatar Oil compounds, which cannot be entered unless in the presence of an employee.  For those prepared to drive into the hinterland, bungalow or chalet-style rooms, at Mesaieed for example, make an attractive alternative to Doha's international-style accommodation. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The B&B as a concept has not really reached Qatar yet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Doha has an increasing number of glitzy, five-star hotels, with manmade white sand beaches cropping up along the coastline.  The West Bay area is currently home to the city&rsquo;s glitziest addresses, including the W, and the Four Seasons, while other five-star chains have opened on the Pearl and beach areas in between. Most of the 5-star options are exquisitely packaged with marble flooring, silken drapes and Persian carpets and they all compete in the 'extreme art' of flower-arranging. Most are very family friendly, as the hotels serve a dual purpose; besides accommodation, they also tend to be where expats gather to eat, drink and socialise, as alcohol is only available in the bars of international hotels.  On Fridays (the equivalent of our Saturday) luxury hotels are full of expat families eating brunch and lazing by the pool or on the beach.</p>
<p>The new vogue in the city is for boutique hotels, and there are now five &lsquo;Souq Waqif Boutique Hotels&rsquo; which give you the chance to stay right at the heart of the souq.  Prices and luxury levels are still five star, in spite of the boutique tag.  The area around Souq Waqif is also where many of the cheaper, smaller hotels can be found, which offer more budget accommodation (although there&rsquo;s little in the city that&rsquo;s actually cheap).</p>
<p>Beyond the city, there are fewer options.  Most of the other towns are little more than Qatar Oil compounds, which cannot be entered unless in the presence of an employee.  For those prepared to drive into the hinterland, bungalow or chalet-style rooms, at Mesaieed for example, make an attractive alternative to Doha's international-style accommodation. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Doha has an increasing number of glitzy, five-star hotels, with manmade white sand beaches cropping up along the coastline.  The West Bay area is currently home to the city&rsquo;s glitziest addresses, including the W, and the Four Seasons, while other five-star chains have opened on the Pearl and beach areas in between. Most of the 5-star options are exquisitely packaged with marble flooring, silken drapes and Persian carpets and they all compete in the 'extreme art' of flower-arranging. Most are very family friendly, as the hotels serve a dual purpose; besides accommodation, they also tend to be where expats gather to eat, drink and socialise, as alcohol is only available in the bars of international hotels.  On Fridays (the equivalent of our Saturday) luxury hotels are full of expat families eating brunch and lazing by the pool or on the beach.</p>
<p>The new vogue in the city is for boutique hotels, and there are now five &lsquo;Souq Waqif Boutique Hotels&rsquo; which give you the chance to stay right at the heart of the souq.  Prices and luxury levels are still five star, in spite of the boutique tag.  The area around Souq Waqif is also where many of the cheaper, smaller hotels can be found, which offer more budget accommodation (although there&rsquo;s little in the city that&rsquo;s actually cheap).</p>
<p>Beyond the city, there are fewer options.  Most of the other towns are little more than Qatar Oil compounds, which cannot be entered unless in the presence of an employee.  For those prepared to drive into the hinterland, bungalow or chalet-style rooms, at Mesaieed for example, make an attractive alternative to Doha's international-style accommodation. <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels are graded from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The National Health Authority in Qatar provides free, or heavily subsidised care for nationals, expats or visitors. Visitors and expats usually have to pay some costs, so travel insurance is still advisable. There are nine hospitals in Qatar, five government-operated and four privately-run. The Hamad General Hospital (tel: 439 4444; &lt;a href="http://www.hmc.org.qa" target="_blank"&gt;www.hmc.org.qa&lt;/a&gt;) is the main hospital in Doha, while the Al Amal is a groundbreaking cancer hospital. There are numerous pharmacies in Doha, many with late opening hours. In case of emergency call the police, fire or ambulance on 999.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice from hotels and public facilities in Doha is generally safe to drink. In other areas, bottled water is a sensible precaution. In general, food hygiene standards are good and it&amp;rsquo;s fine to eat from markets and street food stalls. Use common sense and only eat well-cooked meat and fish; in the summer months, inadequate storage in the heat can cause problems.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. In the summer, temperatures can easily hit 35&amp;deg;C (95&amp;deg;F) and it is easy to get sunstroke or become dehydrated. Simple measures such as covering the head, keeping out of the midday sun and regularly sipping water help avoid this.  Respiratory problems can also be an issue due to the dust and sand in the air, particularly in the summer months.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>National Day :
							18 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Qatar without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes.<br />
&bull; Personal items and gifts up to a  value of QR3,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Alcoholic drinks, drugs, indecent materials (books, magazines etc), weapons, ammunitions, explosives and radioactive equipment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Qatari Riyal (QAR; symbol QR)= 100 dirhams. Notes are in denominations of QR500, 100, 50, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of 50, 25, 10, 5, 1 dirhams. <br/>The Qatari Riyal is tied to the US Dollar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major banks and hotels will exchange currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted.</p><p>There are ATM machines throughout Qatar, although there are fewer outside the capital, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/doha">Doha</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sun-Thurs 0730-1300. Many banks open for longer hours and open on Saturdays too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Qatar, passports must have one blank page and be valid for at least six months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In June 2017, the following countries cut diplomatic ties and closed their borders, territorial waters and airspace to Qatar, following Qatar's alleged involvement in funding Islamic militants: Bahrain, Egypt, Maldives, Saudi Arabia, UAE.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>No visa is required if you don't leave the transit area. If you do plan to leave the airport, a transit visa is available for 24 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prices may vary depending on exchange rate and nationality of the applicant.</p>
<p>Visa on arrival: QR100 / about &pound;25 (payable by credit card); tourist visa from the embassy: &pound;25.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival: 30 days; tourist visa from the embassy: one month within three months of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy) or on arrival in some cases (see above). You can also apply for a tourist visa online via the Qatar e-Government website (<a href="http://www.gov.qa">www.gov.qa</a>).</p>
<p>Nationals of countries where Qatar has no diplomatic representation may apply for visas through an alternative embassy or their hotel in Qatar, which will arrange for the visa to be collected on arrival at the airport.</p>
<p>Those wishing to visit friends or relatives in Qatar may ask them to apply to the immigration authorities in Qatar on their behalf for a visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can only apply for a temporary residence visa if you have a firm job offer or contract from an employer in Qatar.  Work permits can only be obtained by a local sponsor.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 10 working days for visa processing if applying via the embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If applying for a visa in advance, you must show a recent bank statement with a balance of at least &pound;800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourist visas cannot be extended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must obtain a permit from the Department of Animal Resources, along with a health certificate issued by a vet in your home country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[25.413972]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[51.259993]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>11,586 sq km (4,473 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,291,368 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>197.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Doha.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Emirate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Qatar is an oil-rich peninsula jutting out into the Gulf between Bahrain and the United Arab Emirates, with just one border, at the south of the country, with Saudi Arabia.  The peninsula is just 160km (100 miles) north-south, and apart from the capital, Doha, most of the towns are oil-company compounds.  The coastline stretches for 563km (350 miles), with a scattering of sandy beaches &ndash; the best of which are in the north and west.</p>
<p>Much of the country consists of sand dunes and salt flats across a low, barren plain, although towards the north of the peninsula there is scattered vegetation.&nbsp; There is also a small range of hills in the north-west, the highest of which is Qurayn Abu al Bawl, which reaches just over 100m (328ft) and is part of the Jebel Dukhan range. The country's most distinctive geographical feature is in the south of the country close to the border with Saudi Arabia; a wide area of rippling dunes surrounding an inlet of water from the Persian Gulf. Known as Khor al-Adaid, it is a favourite spot for jeep safaris and day trips from Doha.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>At least 95% of Qataris are Sunni Muslims, from the Wahhabi sect of Islam.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Beneath the surface of consumerism and western images, Qatar is an extremely traditional country and it&rsquo;s important to observe some local courtesies.&nbsp;Outside western hotels, it&rsquo;s respectful for women to cover knees and shoulders, while men should generally wear a shirt and trousers.&nbsp;When Arab men meet they usually exchange a handshake, and while this is extended to western men, it is rare for an Arab man to shake hands with a western woman. When taking photographs, seek permission before taking photos of people and be cautious taking pictures in public.</p>
<p>At business and social functions, traditional Qatari coffee is served as part of the ritual welcome. Guests are served in order of seniority - a few drops are poured before topping up the cups of the remaining party. Cups must be held in the right hand: accept two cups - taking only one cup will embarrass the host; taking more than three will embarrass everybody else. Never pass or receive items with the left hand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Abdullah bin Nasser bin Khalifa Al Thani since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Amir Sheikh Tamim bin Hamad Al Thani since 2013.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Qatar may be the richest country in the world per capita, but until the discovery of oil and natural gas in the mid-20th century most Qataris made their living from pearl fishing.</p>
<p>Until the 1970s the country had spent centuries under the control of different ruling nations. In 1825 the Ottomans, who controlled most of Arabia, elevated Sheikh Thani Bin Mohammed to the role of Sheikh of Qatar. The Al Thani family have ruled Qatar since that time and it remains an absolute monarchy, albeit first under the Ottomans and then as a British Protectorate when the Turks withdrew in 1916.</p>
<p>The British Protectorate Agreement lasted for 75 years, during which time Doha &ndash; along with other Gulf cities &ndash; suffered extreme economic problems. As the Japanese pearl industry expanded, Qatar&rsquo;s pearl fishing industry suffered and many Qataris lived in extreme poverty, in spite of the discovery of vast oil and natural gas reserves. WWII diverted Britain&rsquo;s attention from its Middle East concerns, leaving Qatar to wallow in a decade of economic gloom.</p>
<p>Finally in 1949, oil and gas production began and by the 1960s Doha was one of the wealthiest cities in the region. Due to the conservatism of the ruling emir, the country remained largely undeveloped and as the British protectorate began to draw to a close, Qatar agreed to join the other eight states (the present day UAE and Bahrain) to form a union of Arab emirates.</p>
<p>By the time the protectorate came to an end in 1971, the nine states still had not agreed on terms of the union and Qatar withdrew, announcing its independence on 3 September 1971, with Doha as its capital city.</p>
<p>In 1995, Deputy Emir, Sheikh Hamad bin Khalifa, deposed his father in a bloodless coup. An unsuccessful counter-coup was staged in 1996, but Sheik Hamad remains the ruler of Qatar and is widely credited with the country&rsquo;s move towards a more democratic society. Issues remain, however: non-government organisations have raised the alarm over Qatar&rsquo;s human rights record and its treatment of migrant workers, many of whom are building stadiums for the controversial 2022 FIFA World Cup.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Sharia law is the principal source of Qatari legislation, which affords legal status to punishments such as flogging and stoning.<br />
&bull;	In 2014 a modesty campaign was launched to advise female tourists not to wear mini skirts, sleeveless dresses, leggings and short or tight clothing in public.<br />
&bull;	Qatar spends more on art than any other nation in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the State of Qatar in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 274 1600.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://washington.embassy.qa/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 274 1600.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700 (embassy business hours); 0930-1230 (consulate section)&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2555 M St. NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20037<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the State of Qatar in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7493 2200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://london.embassy.qa/en/embassy</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7493 2200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1600 (general enquiries); 1000-1300 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Mayfair<br/>1 South Audley Street<br/>London<br/>W1K 1NB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Qatar]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+974 4496 2000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-embassy-doha</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+974 4496 2000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Sun-Wed 0800-1530. Thurs 0800-1330.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>PO Box 3 off Wahda St near Rainbow roundabout<br/>West Bay<br/>Doha<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The eyes of the world are on Qatar right now. In just forty years, this small Gulf state has been catapulted from one of the poorest countries in the region to the richest (per capita) in the world. Fuelled by oil and natural gas revenue, Qatar is developing at breakneck speed, and everything from universities to shopping malls, 5-star hotels to football stadiums (in preparation for the controversial 2022 World Cup) are springing up along the desert floor.</p>
<p>Modern Qatar is, for all intents and purposes, a city-state. Over half of the country&rsquo;s population lives in and around the capital, Doha. Most other towns are Qatari Oil compounds &ndash; quasi-communities built for foreign workers. The country does also have its share of natural beauty. Gorgeous beaches line the western coast in places like Dukhan, and the spectacular dunes of Khor al-Adaid in the south complement the city&rsquo;s many inorganic charms.</p>
<p>While the skyscrapers, malls and manmade beaches suggests that Doha is an understudy to Dubai, in reality Qatar remains a deeply traditional country, sharing far more in common with neighbouring Saudi Arabia. Thus, even as international hotel bars are permitted to serve alcohol, Qatari women are forbidden from entering them; and even as Qataris indulge in shopping sprees at Chanel or Dior, falconry and camel-racing remain popular pastimes.</p>
<p>Amidst this contradiction of custom and modernity exist a few notable spaces for reflection. The iconic Museum of Islamic Art, the Katara Cultural Village and the Museum of Modern Art give Qatar a cultural edge over some of its Emirate neighbours.</p>
<p>However, the country exemplifies the divide between haves and have-nots. Wealthy Qataris cruise around in the latest 4x4s, spending entire days in upscale shopping malls, while vast armies of immigrant workers serve as poorly paid staff or live six to a room as they build glittering skyscrapers. Paradoxical, challenging and hypocritical it may be, Qatar is never less than fascinating.</p><p>The eyes of the world are on Qatar right now. In just forty years, this small Gulf state has been catapulted from one of the poorest countries in the region to the richest (per capita) in the world. Fuelled by oil and natural gas revenue, Qatar is developing at breakneck speed, and everything from universities to shopping malls, 5-star hotels to football stadiums (in preparation for the controversial 2022 World Cup) are springing up along the desert floor.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
