<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Republic of Congo" ColCode="cog" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="cg" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Republic of Congo]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Equatorial climate with short rains from October to December and long rains between mid January and mid May. The main dry season is from June to October.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Practical lightweight cottons and linens with a light raincoat or umbrella in the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>ECAir (<a href="http://www.flyecair.com" target="_blank">www.flyecair.com</a>) and Trans Air Congo (<a href="http://www.flytransaircongo.com" target="_blank">www.flytransaircongo.com</a>) operate flights between Brazzaville and Pointe-Noire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Inland steamers ply from Brazzaville up the Congo and Ubangi. Rivers are vital to internal transport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>'La Gazelle' train connects Brazzaville with Pointe-Noire on the Congo-Ocean Railway (journey time - 14 to 16 hours). Carriages are modern and comfortable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Roads are mostly earth tracks, sandy in dry season and impassable in the wet, suitable for 4-wheel drive vehicles only.&nbsp;There are around 1,200km (750 miles) of paved roads.&nbsp;Poorly marked army checkpoints, often manned by undisciplined soldiers, exist throughout the country.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>Both local and international car hire companies are represented in Brazzaville.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brazzaville has a minibus and taxi service. Taxis are also available in Pointe-Noire and Loubomo. Taxi fares have a flat rate and fares should be agreed beforehand.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating indirect flights to the Republic of Congo from the UK include Air France (via Paris) and Royal Air Maroc (via Casablanca).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 10 hours 30 minutes (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 19 hours (including stopovers).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>XAF500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Brazzaville Maya Maya Airport </b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 4km (2 miles) northwest of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Antonio Agostinho Neto International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 5.5km (3.5 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Links with Western Europe are generally poor.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with a few international mobile phone companies. Coverage is mainly limited to Brazzaville and Pointe-Noire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Limited access. Facilities are available at some hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Broadcasts on state-run radio and television stations generally reflect government views. Broadcasts from neighbouring Congo (Dem Rep) can be received, and rebroadcasts of <em>Radio France Internationale</em>, the <em>BBC</em> and <em>Voice of America</em> are available in Brazzaville. There are now no prison terms for libel and insult but incitement to violence and racism remains punishable. All newspapers in Brazzaville are all privately-owned and some may include criticism of the government.<strong><br /></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is an unreliable internal service. Post takes four to 18 days to arrive in Europe.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730/0800-1200 and 1430-1730; and (for stamps and telegrams) Mon-Sat 0800-2000; Sun and public holidays 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Delve into Congo’s history at Diosso</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Around 20km (12 miles) from Pointe Noire are the villages of Loango and Diosso. Loango was a major embarkation port for slaves during the era of the transatlantic slave trade. The Gorges of Diosso, spectacular cliffs formed by the erosion of the sea and the wind, are well worth visiting, as are some of the remote and idyllic palm-fringed beaches nearby.</p>]]><p><b>Experience Congo’s biodiversity at Conkouati-Douli National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Not far from Pointe Noire, stretching from the Atlantic coastline into densely-forested mountains, Conkouati-Douli is Congo's most diverse park and recent investment in conservation has seen a rejuvenation of wildlife stocks previously decimated by poaching. Gorillas, elephants, buffalo and chimpanzee can be seen here, as can sea turtles laying eggs on the beach.</p>]]><p><b>Explore bustling Brazzaville</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The small, crumbling Congolese capital is situated on the banks of the mighty Congo River, with clear views across the water to DRC's capital Kinshasa on the opposite bank. Brazzaville has a number of pulsing markets and a surprisingly vibrant arts and culture scene, as well as some fascinating colonial relics and memorials.</p>]]><p><b>Get lost in D’Odzala National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the oldest parks in Africa, the arrival of African Parks and Wilderness Safaris has breathed new life into D'Odzala after decades of turmoil. Remote even by Congo's standards, the only way to access the park is on an exclusive fly-in safari. Activities include face-to-face encounters with habituated lowland gorilla families, accompanied by local BaAka (pygmy) guides.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in Pointe Noire</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pointe Noire is Congo's economic capital, but it often feels more like a small seaside town. The beachfront itself is rundown and relatively underdeveloped, but therein lies much of its charm. And there are still a number of good spots for a seaside sundowner. Away from the beach, the city has a bustling market and a few good restaurants.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the Loufoulakari Falls</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Find beautiful panoramic views of the verdant surrounding countryside at the Loufoulakari Falls, the confluence of the Congo and Loufoulakari rivers. A bumpy 80km (50-mile) drive from the capital Brazzaville, Loufoulakari is held to be the most impressive falls in the region and well worth a day trip.</p>]]><p><b>Ride ‘La Gazelle’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This air-conditioned train runs between Brazzaville and Pointe Noire a few times a week and is a much more immersive experience than taking the short flight. Though it's a slow and arduous journey, there is some striking scenery along the way. Do spend time some considering the human cost of this journey: the construction of this historic train line claimed the lives of more than 17,000 Congolese.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll around Linzolo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The first Catholic church in Congo was built in 1882 by a French priest and is located in Linzolo, 30km (19 miles) from the capital. The small city is also home to the regional seat of the World Health Organization and a very good market.</p>]]><p><b>Track gorillas in Nouabalé-Ndoki National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once referred to by National Geographic as the world's 'Last Eden', this vast and remote park in the northern corner of Congo is home to lowland gorillas, forest elephants and chimpanzees among other interesting fauna found in the swampy rainforest. The park is a UNESCO World Heritage Site.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind at Les Rapides</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Just west of Brazzaville, at Les Rapides, the Congo River can be observed in all its power and glory. These wide and untamed falls are best observed with a frosty beer in hand in the leafy garden of the bar at the river's edge, which is a popular weekend hang out with locals and tourists alike.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$5.8 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum, sawn timber, diamonds, cocoa and sugar.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, steel, foodstuffs and iron.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Germany, China, Italy, USA and Belgium.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>About 60% of the country is covered by tropical forest, roughly half of which can be exploited economically. Forestry is thus an important part of the economy and, along with agriculture, employs about two-thirds of the working population.<br /><br />Both subsistence crops (cassava, plantains) and cash crops (sugar, palm oil, coffee, cocoa) are grown; even so, Congo continues to depend on a large quantity of imported food.<br /><br />A further 20% of the workforce is employed in various industries, of which the most important is oil. The first field came on stream in 1960 and the industry now accounts for 90% of Congo's export earnings. Strengthening of the non-oil economy remains the main long-term objective.<br /><br />Unfortunately, the government's economic planning and reforms have been undermined by political instability and fractious relations with the IMF and World Bank (which have underwritten it). The USA is the largest oil purchaser, followed by France and Spain. France provides two-thirds of Congo's imports, consisting largely of machinery, transport equipment, chemicals, iron and steel as well as foodstuffs.<br /><br />Annual per capita income, at US$800, is relatively high by regional standards. Congo is a member of the CFA Franc Zone and of the Central African Economic and Customs Union (CEEAC).<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jackets and ties are not usually worn by men on business visits but are expected when visiting government officials. A knowledge of French is essential as there are no professional translators available. Normal courtesies should be observed and the best months for business visits are January to March and June to September.<br /></p><p>Usually Mon-Fri 0700-1400, Sat 0700-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Congolese cuisine incorporates French, Asian and Arabic influences into more starchy, traditional African fare. Local-style restaurants usually serve chicken, fish and goat dishes accompanied by some variation of a cassava or maize-based staple.</p><p>The major urban areas have a number of French-style bakeries and patisseries, many of which are run by Lebanese immigrants. Indian and Chinese restaurants are also not uncommon. However, often the best food and atmosphere is to be found at a simple open-air roadside grill.</p><p>In Pointe Noire, the Atlantic provides some excellent seafood, while Congo's bountiful rivers and their freshwater fish are the main source of protein for many Congolese in the hinterland.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Manioc:</strong> Cassava root, usually prepared and served in dense, chewy cubes with meat or fish.<br />
<strong>Fufu:</strong> A stiff porridge staple usually made with flour from cassava or maize.<br />
<strong>Safou:</strong> A purple-skinned fruit that resembles a large olive, usually boiled and salted before eating, which gives the pulp a buttery texture.<br />
<strong>Salt fish:</strong> A major source of protein for Congolese, a variety of salted and dried freshwater fish is found at most markets.<br />
<strong>Saka Saka/Pondu:</strong> A rich local favourite made from a base of cassava leaves, palm oil and salt fish.<br />
<strong>Goat stew:</strong> A traditional Congolese dish usually served with fufu or manioc.<br />
<strong>Pili Pili:</strong> Spicy chilli sauce, served on the side of most Congolese dishes.<br />
<strong>Plantains:</strong> A savoury banana that serves as a substitute for potatoes, best fried like chips.<br />
<strong>Makobe:</strong> Freshwater fish seasoned with chilli and cooked in large marantacee leaves.<br />
<strong>Palm wine:</strong> Fermented alcoholic beverage made from the sap of a wild palm tree.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Normally 10% in hotels and restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local groups are popular in the main towns. Brazzaville and Pointe-Noire have several nightclubs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In Brazzaville, there are shops and colourful markets. An arts and crafts centre at Poto Poto sells, amongst other things, local paintings and carved wooden masks and figures. The two main markets are Moungali and Ouenze. Avenue Foch is crowded with street vendors. Basketwork can be bought at the villages of Makana and M'Pila (3km/2 miles from Brazzaville), with pottery and an open-air market.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1200 and 1500-1800. Some shops close on Monday afternoon and a few open on Sunday morning.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are five good hotels in Brazzaville - three in Loubomo and four in Pointe-Noire. Prices and advance bookings can be obtained via <em>Air France</em>. Outside the towns mentioned above, accommodation for visitors is limited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are five good hotels in Brazzaville - three in Loubomo and four in Pointe-Noire. Prices and advance bookings can be obtained via <em>Air France</em>. Outside the towns mentioned above, accommodation for visitors is limited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are five good hotels in Brazzaville - three in Loubomo and four in Pointe-Noire. Prices and advance bookings can be obtained via <em>Air France</em>. Outside the towns mentioned above, accommodation for visitors is limited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical and dental facilities are generally very limited outside Brazzaville. Health insurance is essential. Medicines are in short supply and it is advised that visitors bring their own medicine, with official labels, into the country.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Bilharzia (schistosomiasis) is present; avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water.  Hepatitis B is hyperendemic. Meningococcal A and C have been reported and immunisation is recommended. Rabies is present. For those at high risk, vaccination before arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay. Since December 2006, outbreaks of cholera have been reported in Pointe-Noire, Kouilou and Brazzaville.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Reconciliation Day :
							10 June </p><p>National Day :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Congo by visitors over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 1 box of cigars or tobacco (women are permitted to import cigarettes only).<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of spirits and 1 bottle of wine.<br />
&bull; A reasonable quantity of perfume in opened bottles.</p>
<p>If importing expensive items such as watches and cameras, it is advisable to present the receipt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFA (<em>Communauté Financière Africaine</em>) Franc (XAF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of XAF10,000, 5,000, 2,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of XAF250, 100, 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1.<br /><br />Congo is part of the French Monetary Area. Only currency issued by the <em>Banque des États de l'Afrique Centrale </em>(Bank of Central African States) is valid; currency issued by the <em>Banque des États de l'Afrique de l'Ouest</em> (Bank of West African States) is not. The CFA Franc is tied to the Euro. However, US Dollars are the preferred currency.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Diners Club and MasterCard have limited use. Hotels in Brazzaville and Pointe-Noire accept major credit or debit cards, although prefer cash. One bank in Brazzaville has an ATM.</p><p>One bank in Brazzaville has an ATM.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros or Pounds Sterling. These are accepted only in the larger cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0630-1300 (counters close at 1130).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above to enter the Republic of Congo.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>15-day visa: &pound;60; 30-day visa: &pound;90; 60-day visa: &pound;120; 90-day visa: &pound;150; 180-day visa: &pound;300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>15, 30, 60, 90 or 180 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). In the UK, you should apply in person or by post to the honorary consulate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are usually ready to be collected the day after you submit the application.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-0.774879]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[15.347900]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>342,000 sq km (132,046 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>4,740,992 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>13.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Brazzaville.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Congo is situated in Africa, bordered to the north by Cameroon and the Central African Republic, to the south and east by the Democratic Republic of Congo, to the southwest by the Atlantic, and to the west by Gabon. The Cabinda Enclave, belonging to Angola, lies to the southwest, on the Atlantic coast. Vast areas are swamps, grassland or thick forests with rivers being virtually the only means of internal travel. The vast River Congo and its major tributaries form most of the country's border with the Democratic Republic of Congo, drawing much of its water from the swamplands in the north of the country. The narrow sandy coastal plain is broken by lagoons, behind which rise the Mayombe Mountains. Most of the population lives in the south of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority follow Christian beliefs (mainly Roman Catholic: 50%), with most of the remainder following animist belief systems (48%). There are small Protestant and Muslim minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Normal courtesies should be observed when visiting people's homes. Gifts are acceptable as a token of thanks, especially if invited for a meal. Dress should be casual, and informal wear is acceptable in most places. Mini-skirts and shorts should not be worn in most public places. Artistic carving, both traditional and modern dance, as well as folk songs, play an important part in Congolese culture, which is strongly based on tradition. Do not smoke or drink alcohol in public places during Ramadan.<br /><br /><strong>Photography:</strong> It is forbidden to photograph public buildings.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Bruno Tshibala since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Denis Sassou-Nguesso since 1997.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The small country now known as the Republic of Congo was originally part of the Kingdom of the Kongo, and the Bakongo, Bateke and Dsanga were the main peoples in the area when the Portuguese arrived in the 15th century.</p>
<p>The region later became a major centre for the European slave trade. In 1882 the territory was occupied by France, then absorbed into French Equatorial Africa in 1910.</p>
<p>In 1958, the territory became an autonomous republic within the French community before being granted full independence as a republic in August 1960.</p>
<p>Abb&eacute; Fulbert Youlou, a Catholic priest, was elected President and guided the Congo into a single-party state. A series of left-wing military governments followed until elections for the Presidency were held in 1979, and brought Colonel Denis Sassou-Nguesso to power.</p>
<p>In November 1989, the Government introduced free-market policies, promoting private enterprise and conducting several privatisations. The political reform process began in 1991 with a national conference to discuss the future of the country. This agreed to establish a Higher Council of the Republic, abolishing the principal organs of state and with a brief to prepare legislative and presidential elections for the following year.</p>
<p>These took place in the summer of 1992, bringing to power the Union Panafricaine pour la D&eacute;mocratie Sociale (UPADS) as the major party in both the National Assembly and the Senate, while its leader, Pascal Lissouba, won the presidential poll.</p>
<p>Following the disputed elections, the country descended into a bloody civil war that culminated in 1997 after Sassou-Nguesso&rsquo;s rebel troops took the capital and reinstalled their leader as President.</p>
<p>Under the banner of United Democratic Forces, Sassou-Ngessou stood at the 2002 presidential election, securing 90% of the vote amid widespread claims of vote rigging. Kignomba Mbougou, standing for UPADS (Lissouba's party) gained just 3%.</p>
<p>By 2003, the country was largely at peace, though sporadic violence between government troops and the Ninjas rebel group continued in the Pool region until the group disbanded in 2008.</p>
<p>Sassou-Nguesso was re-elected in the 2009 presidential election with 78.61% of the vote amidst an opposition boycott. He has recently made clear his intentions to change the country&rsquo;s constitution to allow him to stand for a third consecutive term in 2016, a move that has been met by angry protests from opposition parties and the public.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; The entire population of Republic of Congo, roughly four million, is less than half of the DRC&rsquo;s capital Kinshasa.<br />
&bull; During the World War II, Brazzaville was the capital of the French resistance in Africa.<br />
&bull; Congo is one of Africa&rsquo;s biggest oil producers, but petrol shortages are a regular occurrence in the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Congo in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 726 5500.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambacongo-us.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 726 5500.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0900-1600; Fri 0900-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1720 16th Street NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Honorary Consulate of the Republic of Congo in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 3077 9958.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://consulateofthecongobrazzaville.webs.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 3077 9958.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1030-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>3rd Floor - Holborn Gate (HRG), 26 Southampton Buildings<br/>London<br/>WC2A 1PN<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bordered to the East by the vast Congo River, the Republic of Congo is often confused with its bigger and more notorious sibling, the DRC, on the other side of the river, and this certainly hasn&rsquo;t done its tourist reputation any favours in recent years.</p>
<p>But for those intrepid enough to give the smaller, quieter and lesser-known Congo a try, they&rsquo;ll find that it boasts beautiful landscapes characterised by undulating virgin rainforest, waterfalls, lagoons, river rapids and swamps. These wild places are home to an abundance of interesting flora and fauna, most notably rare primate species such as mountain gorillas and chimpanzees.</p>
<p>While these iconic primates are the main attraction for the handful of tourists now trickling into the country, the forest is also home to several indigenous tribes, which have maintained their traditional way of life, almost entirely removed from Western civilization.</p>
<p>Standing in stark contrast to most of the rest of the country, Congo&rsquo;s fast-growing capital, Brazzaville, is a fascinating metropolis. Looking across the Congo River to the dilapidated sprawl of Kinshasa, the DRC capital, Brazzaville is by far the prettier and more appealing of the two cities, with a burgeoning arts scene, good food, vibrant nightlife, an interesting colonial heritage and welcoming locals.</p>
<p>Since it gained its independence from the French in 1960, the Republic of Congo has been plagued by sporadic but severe bouts of civil war and ethnic conflict, the most bloody of which followed disputed parliamentary elections in 1993 and reached its pinnacle in 1997, fuelled in part by the prize of the country's substantial offshore oil wealth, which motivated many of the warlords.</p>
<p>A peace accord was finally signed in 2003 and since then the country has slowly but surely been reimagining itself as a peaceful destination that is no longer defined by its torrid history, and one that deserves to be noticed and appreciated.</p>Bordered to the East by the vast Congo River, the Republic of Congo is often confused with its bigger and more notorious sibling, the DRC, on the other side of the river, and this certainly hasn't done its tourist reputation any favours in recent years. But for those intrepid enough to give the smaller, quieter and lesser-known Congo a try, they'll find that it boasts beautiful landscapes characterised by undulating virgin rainforest, waterfalls, lagoons, river rapids and swamps. These wild places are home to an abundance of interesting flora and fauna, most notably rare primate species such as mountain gorillas and chimpanzees.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
