<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Reunion" ColCode="reu" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="re" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Reunion]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot tropical climate. Temperatures are cooler in the hills, occasionally dropping to freezing point in the mountains at night. The cyclone season (January to March) is hot and wet.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights, with warmer clothes for the evenings.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Aero-clubs at Roland-Garros Airport hire planes for flights over the island, which are well worth the price.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roads are in a fair condition. The main road runs on a north-south axis.</p><p>Taxi ranks can be found in city centres, or you can book them by phone (telephone numbers are listed at information points at the airport). There are likely to be extra charges after 2000 Mon-Fri, on Sunday and holidays.</p><p>A valid national driving licence or International Driving Permit.</p><p>Speed limits are the same as in France (see France section).</p><p>Available from the airport and from car hire firms in Saint-Denis. You can also hire camper vans. Petrol prices are similar to those in France.</p><p>Speed limits are the same as in France (see France section).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main airline to serve R&eacute;union is Air France&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) from Paris. Air Austral (<a href="http://www.air-austral.com" target="_blank">www.air-austral.com</a>)&nbsp;and Air Mauritius&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.airmauritius.com" target="_blank">www.airmauritius.com</a>) operate daily flights between R&eacute;union and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mauritius">Mauritius</a>. South African Airways (<a href="http://www.flysaa.com" target="_blank">www.flysaa.com</a>) flies direct from the USA to Johannesburg, from where you can take a connecting flight to R&eacute;union with Air Austral.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London - 14 hours (including stopover); New York - 22 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Saint-Pierre Pierrefonds Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.pierrefonds.aeroport.fr<p>The airport is 5km (3 miles) from Saint-Pierre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main port:&nbsp;</strong>Port R&eacute;union.</p>
<p>There is a limited passenger service to Mauritius; contact Mauritius Shipping Corporation (tel: +230 217 2284, in Mauritius; <a href="http://www.mauritiusshipping.net" target="_blank">www.mauritiusshipping.net</a>). Both freight and passenger lines (a large number are French) dock at Pointe-des-Galets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are Internet cafes in towns throughout Réunion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>TV and radio services are provided by the French public overseas broadcaster, <em>RFO</em>.<strong><br /></strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes up to three weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Delve into the warm turquoise waters</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Good swimming and diving are to be found along the Sous le Vent coast, especially at Saint-Gilles-des-Bains, which has a lagoon shielded from the open ocean by a reef. Though the reefs are protected habitats, scuba-diving and snorkelling are permitted. Surfing can be practised in Saint-Gilles, Saint-Paul and Saint-Pierre.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the island’s flora</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Inhale the scent of Réunion's exquisite tropical flowers, trees and fruit across the island; tours aim to show the visitor some of the many endemic species. Alternatively, head to the well-kept Jardin de l'Etat botanical gardens in the capital Saint-Denis, or the Jardin L'Eden tropical gardens at Saint-Gilles-des-Bains.</p>]]><p><b>Hike through volcanic valleys</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A special feature of Réunion is its so-called cirques – large volcanic valleys surrounded by mountains, creating natural amphitheatres of about 10km (6 miles) in diameter. The most beautiful is probably Salazie, with its magnificent waterfalls, especially those known as Le Voile de la Mariée (The Bride's Veil) near Hell-Bourg.</p>]]><p><b>Relax on Réunion’s beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Réunion does not have extensive beaches, but those on the west coast are beautiful with yellow, black or white sands. Some of the best beaches are to be found at Saint-Gilles, Saint-Leu (where the Coral Turtle Farm is worth a visit) and Étang-Sale. These are mostly shallow coral, running out to a reef.</p>]]><p><b>Take a tour of Saint-Denis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Saint-Denis, the capital, is surrounded by mountains on three sides and has several places of interest, including the Natural History Museum and the Léon Dierx Art Gallery with its collection of French Impressionist paintings. There are various temples, a mosque and a cathedral, a sign of the cultural and religious variety of the island population.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the mountain air</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Réunion has over 600km (370 miles) of marked footpaths, and good climbing can be had among its volcanic peaks. Cilaos, once infamous as a refuge for escaped slaves, with impressive views of Le Bras Sec and Îlet à Cordres, rises approximately 1,220m (4,000ft). Piton des Neiges is the island's highest point, while Mafate is its most secluded valley, still inaccessible by road.</p>]]><p><b>Tour the market at Saint-Paul</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The island's many communities gather together in Saint-Paul for the lively street market that occurs every Friday afternoon and Saturday morning. Situated along the seafront of the island's first capital, stalls selling local produce and handicrafts abound, as do pop-up kitchens selling traditional Creole fare.</p>]]><p><b>Trek across an active volcano</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Réunion has some fantastic trekking opportunities, none more so than the path to Nez-de-Boeuf (Ox's Nose) mountain, which affords a splendid view over the Rivière des Remparts, 1,000m (3,300ft) below. Both the 8km-wide (5 miles) Enclos Fouque crater and the 2,632m (8,632ft) summit of the active volcano Piton de la Fournaise can be explored on foot.</p>]]><p><b>Wander through the magical Bébour forest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tamarind trees and large prehistoric-looking ferns dominate the Forêt de Bébour-Bélouve, in the centre of the island. Mosses hang from the tree branches in the humid air, while rare endemic birds dart among them. Best accessed from the town of Plaine-des-Palmistes, the forest is almost deserted on weekdays despite being a popular weekend retreat.</p>]]><p><b>Witness the Hindu festival of Cavadee</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Réunion's mixed heritage has left an island bursting with cultural spectacles. The island's Tamil community, for instance, perform the <em>cavadee </em>(burden dance) during the colourful Hindu festival of Thaipusam in January or February. Taking place in Saint-André, it requires devotees to carry heavy burdens while performing additional acts of devotion such as skin piercing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$4.6 billion.</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Sugar, rum and molasses, perfume essences and lobster.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Manufactured goods, food, tobacco, machinery and equipment, raw materials and petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/japan">Japan</a>, Comoros Islands, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sugar cane is the principal crop and export earner in this mainly agricultural economy. Other crops include vanilla, tobacco, and plants such as <em>vétiver</em> and <em>ylang-ylang</em>, used in tropical essences. Sugar and rum production are the principal industries; others include the manufacture of construction materials, metal goods, textiles and electronics.<br /><br />The service sector, including transport, telecommunications, finance and tourism, provides three-quarters of the country's economic output. Tourism has grown particularly rapidly in recent years, and is now worth about US$300 million annually to the island's economy.<br /><br />However, the Réunion economy is far from self-sustaining and relies on large injections of aid from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> and, more recently, the European Union, to cover its trade and budgetary deficits (as an integral part of France, Réunion belongs to the EU). The most pressing problem for the government is a very high level of unemployment, which has been around 35 to 40% for the last decade. <br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The atmosphere is relaxed and friendly; suits will only be required for the most formal of meetings. A sound knowledge of the French language will be useful, since there are no formal interpreter services available. Prices should be quoted in Euros, and all trade literature should be in French.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1400-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Délégation Régionale au Commerce, à l'Artisanat et au Tourisme</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 407 758
					Website:
					Address: Avenue de la Victoire,Préfecture de la Réunion,97400 Saint-Denis,]]><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie de la Réunion</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 942 000
					Website:http://www.reunion.cci.fr
					Address: BP 120,5 bis rue de Paris,97463 Saint-Denis,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Reunion's unique flavours come from many centuries of mixed French, Malagasy, Chinese and Indian influences, and it's not uncommon to receive dishes from multiple continents served on the same plate.</p><p>Though almost every meal contains chillies and spices such as ginger, dishes are not overly spicy. They typically consist of rice and pulses served together with vegetables and fish or meat curry or stew.</p><p>Being an island, fish including tuna and swordfish are popular options, while chicken and French-style sausages are also common.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Rougail</strong>: Spicy condiment made from tomatoes, lemon and pistachio nuts, as well as the term for various stews (see below).<br />
<strong>Rougail saucisses</strong>: Full-flavoured stew containing sausage, tomatoes and turmeric, served with rice.<br />
<strong>Civet de zourites</strong>: Baby octopus cooked in red wine, herbs and spices.<br />
<strong>Br&egrave;des</strong>: Delicious local vegetable rather like spinach served fried with onion, chilli and ginger as a side dish.<br />
<strong>Carri tangue</strong>: Curried meat of a hedgehog-like animal.<br />
<strong>Achard</strong>: Salad of mixed fruits and vegetables.<br />
<strong>Cabri massal&eacute;s</strong>: Traditional spicy Indian goat dish straight from the subcontinent and often served on banana leaves.<br />
<strong>Zambrokal</strong>: Stir-fried rice with beans, peas, meat, sausage, or anything else left in the cupboard.<br />
<strong>G&acirc;teau sosso</strong>: Sweet cake made from corn.<br />
<strong>Bouchons</strong>: Dumpling-like wraps filled with pork, beef or chicken and often served as a bar snack.<br />
<strong>L&rsquo;americain</strong>: Grilled sandwiches containing meat or fish and cheese, topped with French fries.<br />
<strong>Dodo</strong>: Officially branded under the name Bourbon, this is the island&rsquo;s favourite lager.<br />
<strong>Caf&eacute; Bourbon</strong>: Arab coffee.<br />
<strong>Rhum arrange</strong>: White rum with vanilla, orchids, aniseed and cinnamon.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Licensing hours are largely unrestricted.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Widely practised; 10% is normal.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>16, though purchasing age is 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local handicrafts include lace and embroidery, coral jewellery and basketwork. Tamarind wood, olive wood and ironwood provide the material for furniture in the traditional 'colonial' style, and are used by sculptors and other craftsmen. Rum, vanilla and extracts of vetiver, geranium and ylang-ylang are also recommended purchases. In Saint-Denis, the main shopping streets are rue du Mar&eacute;chal-Leclerc, rue Jean-Chatel and rue Juliette-Dodu.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0830-1200 and 1430-1800, Sun 0800-1200; Mon-Sat 0730-1900, Sun 0800-1200 (department stores).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good range of hotels, inns and <em>pensions</em>. Prices are high (and plumbing somewhat basic), but the food is often excellent. Tariffs usually include bed and breakfast, tax and service charges. There are many rooms available in guest houses across the island as well as self-catering studio flats and accommodation in farmhouses. For further information, contact Comit&eacute; du Tourisme de la R&eacute;union (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels range from 1 to 4 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good range of hotels, inns and <em>pensions</em>. Prices are high (and plumbing somewhat basic), but the food is often excellent. Tariffs usually include bed and breakfast, tax and service charges. There are many rooms available in guest houses across the island as well as self-catering studio flats and accommodation in farmhouses. For further information, contact Comit&eacute; du Tourisme de la R&eacute;union (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels range from 1 to 4 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good range of hotels, inns and <em>pensions</em>. Prices are high (and plumbing somewhat basic), but the food is often excellent. Tariffs usually include bed and breakfast, tax and service charges. There are many rooms available in guest houses across the island as well as self-catering studio flats and accommodation in farmhouses. For further information, contact Comit&eacute; du Tourisme de la R&eacute;union (see <em>Contact Addresses</em>).<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Hotels range from 1 to 4 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There are several hospitals and out-patient clinics. The French national health scheme is in force and there is a reciprocal health agreement with the &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom"&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;em&gt;&lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france"&gt;France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; section). Facilities are limited and full health insurance is advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Water is safe to drink. Wash fruit and vegetables before eating.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into R&eacute;union by travellers over the age of 17:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of spirits up to 22% volume.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine.<br />
&bull; 16L of beer.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of &euro;1,000 if arriving from mainland <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> or another EU country.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of &euro;430 if arriving from a non-EU country (or &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fresh fruit, vegetables or seeds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Euro is the official currency for the French Overseas Departments (<em>Départements d'Outre-Mer</em>) of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/french-guiana">French Guiana</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guadeloupe">Guadeloupe</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/martinique">Martinique</a> and Réunion. For further details, see the <em><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a></em> section. US Dollars are also accepted in some places.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major currencies can be exchanged at banks and bureaux de change.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club and Visa are accepted. MasterCard has limited acceptance. Cards can also be used in ATMs.</p><p>Cards can also be used in ATMs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are not generally accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter R&eacute;union, a passport valid for at least three months beyond the last day of stay is required by nationals referred to in the chart above, except (<strong>1</strong>) nationals of EU countries who hold a valid national identity card. EU travellers only require passports/ID cards to be valid for the duration of stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals who do require a visa can only enter R&eacute;union on a Schengen visa if it is marked on the visa sticker; you must advise the consulate that you are planning on visiting R&eacute;union when you apply.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay/Schengen visa: &euro;60; long-stay visa: &euro;99.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay/Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period; long-stay visa: valid for stays of over three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>French Consulate (or consular section at embassy). In the UK, the consulate has outsourced the visa application process to TLScontact (<a href="http://www.tlscontact.com/gb2fr" target="_blank">www.tlscontact.com/gb2fr</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 15 days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>EU nationals staying longer than three months must register at the pr&eacute;fecture to apply for a <em>carte de s&eacute;jour</em>. Other nationals require a long-stay visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-21.145975]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[55.630979]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,507 sq km (968 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>867,214 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>336.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saint-Denis.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>R&eacute;union is an Overseas Department of France and as such is an integral part of the French Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>R&eacute;union lies 760km (407 miles) east of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/madagascar">Madagascar</a> in the Indian Ocean. Running diagonally across the island is a chain of volcanic peaks, separating a green humid eastern zone (<em>Le Vent</em>) from a dry, sheltered south and west (<em>Sous le Vent</em>). The majority of the population lives along the coast. Sugar cane production accounts for over half the arable land in a country where many basic foodstuffs are imported.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the population is Roman Catholic, with a Muslim minority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The islanders follow French fashion. Normal social courtesies should be observed. The immigrants from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/india">India</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/pakistan">Pakistan</a> and Europe have retained their cultural identities.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs have two round pins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President of the Departmental Council&nbsp;Nassimah Dindar since 2004.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Emmanuel Macron since 2017, represented locally by prefect Amaury de Saint-Quentin since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Little is known about the island prior to the arrival of the Portuguese, who landed ashore in 1513. In the 1640s R&eacute;union was occupied by the French, who claimed the land as their own and renamed it &Icirc;le Bourbon. The island was initially used to exile mutineers, before the first settlers arrived in 1665.</p>
<p>The island was renamed R&eacute;union in the 18th century, during which time it became prosperous, along with nearby Mauritius, as it lay on the shipping routes carrying trade between Europe and Asia. Sugar plantations, worked by slaves imported from Africa, formed a major sector of the growing economy.</p>
<p>The island was ruled as a French colony until 1946, except for a five-year period from 1810 when it was snatched by the British. It was granted the status of an Overseas Department of France, under which it is an integral part of the French State, which is represented on the island by a commissioner.</p>
<p>Politics in recent years have been primarily concerned with internal autonomy: most people appear to favour an increase beyond the present level but very few support completely severing the historic link with France, particularly as the island is largely dependent economically on aid from the French government.</p>
<p>Political parties on the island include adjuncts of the main French parties, the Gaullist Rassemblement pour la R&eacute;publique (RPR); the centre-right Union pour la D&eacute;mocratie Fran&ccedil;aise (UDF) and the Parti Socialiste (PS), plus the Parti Communiste R&eacute;unionnais (PCR), and some smaller local parties. One of these, the right-wing France-R&eacute;union-Avenir (literally France-R&eacute;union-Future) has made little headway; another, the FreeDOM party, was a political phenomenon of the early 1990s, which evolved from a pirate television station.</p>
<p>After the pirate broadcasters' leader, Camille Sudre, was banned from political activity, his wife Marguerite became president of the party. It has since become a permanent feature of the political landscape.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	R&eacute;union is one of the outermost regions of the European Union.<br />
&bull;	20 December is celebrated annually as the day slavery was abolished on the island in 1848.<br />
&bull;	The French initially named the island, &Icirc;le Bourbon, to honour the fall of the House of Bourbon during the French Revolution.<br />
&bull;	The Piton de la Fournaise volcano has erupted over 100 times since records began in around 1640.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[French Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7073 1000. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambafrance-uk.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7073 1000. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>58 Knightsbridge<br/>London<br/>SW1X 7JT<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[French Embassy in the USA ]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 944 6000. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambafrance-us.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 944 6000. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Visa appointments are available Mon-Fri 0845-1200. Appointments can be booked online.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>4101 Reservoir Road NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>One of the last vestiges of the French colonial empire, you can hardly blame Paris for keeping hold of this slice of paradise. Floating in the Indian Ocean, east of Madagascar, R&eacute;union serves up an enticing mix of Creole culture, exotic fauna and natural wonders.</p>
<p>Administered directly from Paris (it also flies the tricolore and is part of the Eurozone), the island has a distinct cultural identity, which has resulted from 400 years as a remote outpost of empire.</p>
<p>Its history is best absorbed wandering through the old heart of Saint-Denis, the island&rsquo;s de facto capital. Edifices that would not look out of place in the French capital line streets and public spaces buzz with the sound of French, Creole, Cantonese and Tamil, among myriad other languages. English is almost never one of them.</p>
<p>The beaches are a big draw, but R&eacute;union&rsquo;s flora and fauna is equally enticing. The island&rsquo;s fresh water lakes, rivers and waterfalls support some 90 species of bird, while its coral reefs harbour an abundance of marine life. Whales are also regularly observed from the beaches between May and September.</p>
<p>Away from the coast, much of the island&rsquo;s forested and mountainous interior is protected and designated a UNESCO World Heritage Site. A variety of activities are available, from paragliding to rock climbing and hiking. Trekking paths lead to natural wonders such the 3,000m (10,000ft) extinct volcano Piton des Neiges (the highest point anywhere in the Indian Ocean), or the lunar landscapes around Piton de la Fournaise, one of the most active volcanoes in the world.</p>
<p>With centuries of influence from Europe, Asia and Africa, R&eacute;union offers Gallic charm with a tropical twist, an island where history and natural beauty abound.</p><p>One of the last vestiges of the French colonial empire, you can hardly blame Paris for keeping hold of this slice of paradise. Floating in the Indian Ocean, east of Madagascar, R&eacute;union serves up an enticing mix of Creole culture, exotic fauna and natural wonders.</p>
<p>Administered directly from Paris (it also flies the tricolore and is part of the Eurozone), the island has a distinct cultural identity, which has resulted from 400 years as a remote outpost of empire.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
