<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Romania" ColCode="rom" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ro" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Romania]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Romania is a great year-round tourist destination. The best times to visit in terms of climate are the end of April to the beginning of July and from end of August to the end of October as temperatures are mild and pleasant. Summers can be hot especially in Southern Romania, including <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bucharest">Bucharest</a>, but along the Black Sea Coast, sea breezes offer moderate temperatures. Winters are coldest in the Carpathian Mountains where there is snow from December through to April. Snow also falls throughout most of the country during winter.</p>
<p>The ski season in Romania runs from December to March, although high resorts such as Stana de Vale often remain open until late April. Prices are cheaper at the beginning and the end of the season, with Christmas often the busiest time.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>On the Black Sea Coast, tourism reaches its height between June and August and temperatures during the summer months can reach a sizzling 40&deg;C. Look for deals in May and September, when the weather is still balmy but the season isn&rsquo;t yet in full swing.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Other seasonal activities include bird-watching (from mid-April to mid-May in the Danube Delta) and wine-tasting, which focuses around a series of festivals in September and October.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights are worn in summer on the coast and in low inland areas. Warmer clothes are needed in winter and throughout the year in the uplands. Rainwear is recommended throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>TAROM (<a href="http://www.tarom.ro/" target="_blank">www.tarom.ro</a>) and Blue Air (<a href="http://www.blueairweb.com" target="_blank">www.blueairweb.com</a>) both operate domestic flights.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's easy to explore the Danube Delta by boat. Most trips and cruises depart from the ancient city of Tulcea and sail to Sulina.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bucharest's main station is the Gara de Nord on Calea Grivitei. CFR (tel: +40 21 9521; <a href="http://www.cfrcalatori.ro" target="_blank">www.cfrcalatori.ro</a>) runs several different types of train, varying in speed from the slow personal to the faster accelerat, rapid and express trains, and the more expensive, modern and comfortable Inter-City. Rural services have a way to go - poor onward connections make these an undesirable choice for travellers to the countryside.</p>
<p>You must reserve seats in advance on express routes. There are no platforms of any great height in Romania, making entering and alighting a little difficult for the elderly or infirm.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Romania. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Romania Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Romania. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of tourists travel by road in Romania, although speeding, overcrowded streets and double-parked cars are common hazards.</p>r<p>Road conditions vary widely throughout Romania. Major streets in larger cities and major intercity roads are in fair to good condition, with DN (<em>Drum National</em>) well maintained. Other roads such as DJ (<em>Drum Judetean</em>) are in poor repair, badly lit, narrow and often do not have marked lanes. Drivers need to be alert for horse-drawn carts and livestock, especially at night.</p><p>The public road transport network comprises a combination of buses, coaches, minibuses and maxitaxis. Some timetables are available at Autogari (<a href="http://www.autogari.ro" target="_blank">www.autogari.ro</a>).</p><p>You can hail inexpensive metered taxis in the street or call them from hotels. Although most drivers are honest, it's advisable to agree prices beforehand, especially at the airport.</p><p>A national driving licence or International Driving Permit are required, as is Green Card insurance if you're travelling from outside the EU. Police carry out frequent checks, so observe the speed limit and carry relevant documents.</p><p>Tolls are charges on motorways and main roads, payable in Euros. Drivers must buy a toll badge or <em>rovinieta</em>; these are available for one week or one month at border points, post offices and at most petrol stations (<a href="http://www.roviniete.ro" target="_blank">www.roviniete.ro</a>).</p>
<p>Children under 12 are not allowed to travel in the front seat and front seat passengers must wear a seat belt. Speed limits are 50kph (30mph) in built-up areas, 90-100kph (56-62mph) on main roads, and 130kph (81mph) on motorways.  Car drivers need to have a fire extinguisher and two breakdown triangles in their car at all times.</p><p>Contact the Romanian Automobile Club (ACR) (tel: 9271, in Romania only or +40 21 222 2222; <a href="http://www.acr.ro/" target="_blank">www.acr.ro</a>).</p><p>Available at hotels and at Bucharest Airport from local and international firms. The minimum age for car hire is 21 years. Driving is very erratic, so it might be advisable to hire a car with a driver.</p><p>You can hire bikes in most of the major cities for a reasonable sum.</p><p>Tolls are charges on motorways and main roads, payable in Euros. Drivers must buy a toll badge or <em>rovinieta</em>; these are available for one week or one month at border points, post offices and at most petrol stations (<a href="http://www.roviniete.ro" target="_blank">www.roviniete.ro</a>).</p>
<p>Children under 12 are not allowed to travel in the front seat and front seat passengers must wear a seat belt. Speed limits are 50kph (30mph) in built-up areas, 90-100kph (56-62mph) on main roads, and 130kph (81mph) on motorways.  Car drivers need to have a fire extinguisher and two breakdown triangles in their car at all times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most cities offer efficient and inexpensive bus, trolleybus or tram transport. Bucharest has a good bus and tram system and a metro. You can buy tickets in advance from agents, and there are stamping machines on board buses and trains. Passes and reloadable smartcards are available. A separate minibus network also exists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Romania</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sucava</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Romania</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">sibiu</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30-6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Romania</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">constanta</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00-3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Romania</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">brasov</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Romania's main airline is TAROM (<a href="http://www.tarom.ro/" target="_blank">www.tarom.ro</a>). Other airlines operating direct flights from the UK include Blue Air (<a href="http://www.blueairweb.com" target="_blank">www.blueairweb.com</a>), British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) and Wizz (<a href="http://www.wizzair.com" target="_blank">www.wizzair.com</a>). There are no direct flights from the USA.&nbsp;The cheapest time to fly is between January and March &ndash; the summer months and Christmas are more expensive.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/otopeni-international-airport">Bucharest Henri Coanda International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/romania/cluj-avram-iancu-international-airport">Cluj Avram Iancu International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/romania/sibiu-international-airport">Sibiu International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/romania/timisoara-traian-vuia-international-airport">Timisoara Traian Vuia International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bucharest">Bucharest</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 3 hours 10 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 11 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Bucharest Henri Coanda International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.bucharestairports.ro<p>The airport is located 16.5km (10.5 miles) northwest of central Bucharest.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+40 21 204 1000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constanța (<a href="http://www.portofconstantza.com" target="_blank">www.portofconstantza.com</a>) on the Black Sea is the country&rsquo;s major port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFR (tel: +40 21 9521; <a href="http://www.cfrcalatori.ro" target="_blank">www.cfrcalatori.ro</a>) operates services from many European cities to Bucharest. First- and second-class sleepers are available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Balkan Flexipass:</strong> allows five, 10 or 15 days of travel in a one month across <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>, Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina,&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece">Greece</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/macedonia">Macedonia</a>, Montenegro, Romania, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/serbia">Serbia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey">Turkey</a>. Tickets are available from Rail Europe (<a href="http://www.raileurope-world.com" target="_blank">www.raileurope-world.com</a>) to anyone living outside these countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving to Romania from the UK takes around 24 hours and involves several border crossings. Routes 7, 79 and 78 are the most commonly used by international travellers entering the country from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hungary">Hungary</a> &ndash; drivers need to present their vehicle&rsquo;s registration, proof of address and a valid driving licence. Buses run from several major European cities, including London and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brussels">Brussels</a>. The main international operator is&nbsp;Eurolines (<a href="http://www.eurolines.com" target="_blank">www.eurolines.com</a>).</p><p>Independent travellers need to purchase a low-cost road toll badge (Rovinieta) at the border crossing (<a href="http://www.roviniete.ro" target="_blank">www.roviniete.ro</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public telephones are widely available and can be used for direct international calls; most require a calling card. Hotels often impose a high service charge for long-distance calls, but usually do not charge for local calls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with many international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good around Bucharest and Romania's other large towns but can be variable elsewhere – particularly in upland areas. Local mobile phone hire is available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is becoming increasingly common across the country and is ubiquitous in big cities. Failing that, internet cafés are fairly common in cities and most large towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Romania's media are among the most lively in the region. The 1991 constitution upholds freedom of expression, but prohibits 'defamation of the country'. Private radio stations began to appear in 1990; over 100 of them now broadcast alongside state-run Radio Romania. A boom in the newspaper market followed the 1989 revolution, but many were later forced to close owing to rising costs. Daily papers include <em>Adevarul, Libertatea, Evenimentul Zillei, Romania Libera </em>and<em> Jurnalul National</em>, which has English-language pages. English newspapers and publications include <em>Bucharest Business Week</em>, <em>Nine O'Clock</em> and<em> Vivid</em>.able television is popular, with more than 75% of households now connected to multi-channel cable or satellite TV systems.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Romanian postal service is reliable but still rather slow, although a recent move to privatise the Romania National Post Office Company could transform this. Airmail to Western Europe takes one week.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-2000, Sat 0800-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Bran Castle</p><![CDATA[<p>Let imagination run wild at Bran Castle  (<a href="http://www.draculascastle.com/" target="_blank">www.draculascastle.com</a>), the legendary abode of the medieval king known as Vlad the Impaler, who helped inspire Bram Stoker's novel, <em>Dracula</em>.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Berca mud volcanoes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This awe-inspiring landscape of bubbling mud is like nothing else you'll see in Romania. Located near Buzau, the Mud Volcanoes have been designated a geological and botanical reserve and are fuelled by natural gas eruptions 3km (2 miles) below the surface. Some of the mud craters have reached more than 6m (20ft) in height, but are perfectly safe to view.</p>]]><p><b>Biertan</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See Transylvania's numerous Saxon fortified churches, including the Biertan Church, which stands on top of a hill overlooking the village of Biertan and is a UNESCO World Heritage Site. The village itself still preserves a large Saxon community and boasts some world-class examples of Saxon architecture from the medieval period.</p>]]><p><b>Black Sea Coast</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Allegedly the place where Jason and the Argonauts landed after finding the Golden Fleece, Romania's Black Sea Coast is fast becoming a tourism hotspot. It's dotted with small resort towns such as Eforie, Jupiter, Neptun, Saturn, Venus and Mangalia, where you can swim, try watersports or simply relax on the beach and soak up the sun.</p>]]><p><b>Bran Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Let imagination run wild at Bran Castle, the legendary abode of the medieval king known as Vlad the Impaler, who helped inspire Bram Stoker's novel, <em>Dracula</em> (<a href="http://www.draculascastle.com/" target="_blank">www.draculascastle.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Bucharest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This beautiful old capital was decimated by Nicolae Ceauşescu's programme of systemisation between the 1960s and 1990s, but the historic centre is still a bastion of old world charm. Wander around some of the most important streets in Bucharest: Calea Victoriei (Victory Road) which holds the The Vernescu House and Boulevards Gh. Magheru, Carol I, Calea Mosilor, Calea Dorobantilor and Soseaua Kiseleff.</p>]]><p><b>Ceausescu's Palace of Parliament</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Bucharest, admire the colossal size and exceptional facilities of Ceausescu's Palace of Parliament, which rises out of the city like a giant wedding cake. It is the second largest building in the world, after the Pentagon and one of Romania&rsquo;s premier tourist attractions. It also houses the National Museum of Contemporary Art (<a href="http://www.mnac.ro" target="_blank">www.mnac.ro</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Constanta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the Greek/Byzantine port of Constanta, founded in the sixth century BC and veer inland to interesting archaeological sites including the ancient Greek city ruins of Histria, Tomis and Callatis (<a href="http://www.constanta.ro/" target="_blank">www.constanta.ro</a>). In the city itself, you'll find enough museums, ancient churches and historical monuments to satisfy even the most ardent culture vulture.</p>]]><p><b>Cycle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The terrain in Romania is perfect for mountain biking, in fact there are numerous outfitters which cater specifically to cycling holidays. Trails range from novice to advanced, however most are geared towards cycling enthusiasts.</p>]]><p><b>Fagaras mountain range</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A magnet for walkers and adrenaline junkies, this superb mountain range has fourteen peaks over 2,500m (8,200 ft) and a succession of spectacular alpine lakes. If trekking or mountaineering sound like too much hard work, you can take in the scenery through a drive along the Transfagaras Road – Romania's highest asphalt road, and undoubtedly one of the most scenic routes in the country.</p>]]><p><b>Maramures</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Check out the traditional villages such as Budesti, Sirbi and Calinesti nestled in the picturesque rural idyll of Maramures (<a href="http://www.visitmaramures.ro" target="_blank">www.visitmaramures.ro</a>). Nature lovers will love the volcanic mountains, waterfalls and glacier lakes around Creasta Cocosului reserve, while culture junkies can admire the UNESCO-designated wooden churches and the unique &lsquo;Merry Cemetery&rsquo; at Sapanta.</p>]]><p><b>Museum of History of the Jewish Community</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Housed in an old Bucharest synagogue, this museum is dedicated to the history of Jews in Romania as well as in memory of the Holocaust. On display are artifacts such as a collection of books written and illustrated by Romanian Jews, important paintings, ritual objects as well as anti-Semitic propaganda.</p>]]><p><b>Painted Monasteries</b></p><![CDATA[<p>It's worth the trek to the Painted Monasteries of Bucovina (Voronet, Sucevita, Moldovita and Humor) in Northern Moldavia. These UNESCO World Heritage Sites are painted with frescoes both inside and outside and have been preserved in excellent condition since medieval times.&nbsp;</p>]]><p><b>Pamper yourself</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its curative thermal springs, salt waters and healing mud, Lake Techirghiol is one of Romania's premier spa destinations. Bathing in the waters of the lake is said to heal everything from rheumatism and arthritis to peripheral nervous system diseases, and there is a huge range of spa treatments available in the nearby town.</p>]]><p><b>Sibiu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Sibiu (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sibiu.ro/">www.sibiu.ro</a>), the chief city of the Transylvanian Saxons. Much of the four walls and 40 towers remain, and among its pretty blue, red, apricot and green painted houses are some of Romania's best museums. Don&rsquo;t miss the Brukenthal National Museum (<a href="http://www.brukenthalmuseum.ro" target="_blank">www.brukenthalmuseum.ro</a>), which houses an impressive range of traditional and contemporary art.</p>]]><p><b>Sighisoara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The exquisite medieval town of Sighisoara is a perfectly intact 15th century gem with nine towers, narrow passageways and cobbled streets, burgher houses and ornate churches. Sighisoara is also the birthplace of Vlad Draculea, nicknamed Vlad the Impaler. One of the best-preserved inhabited citadels in Europe, it's no surprise that the town has been designated by UNESCO as a World Heritage Site.</p>]]><p><b>Snagov</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This remote commune is a nature reservation and history buff&rsquo;s paradise, with the main attraction being the Snagov Monastery (<a href="http://www.snagov.ro" target="_blank">www.snagov.ro</a>) &ndash; allegedly one of the burial sites of Vlad the Impaler. The monastery sits on an island in Snagov Lake and is linked to the village itself by bridge and boat.</p>]]><p><b>Traditional entertainment</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Catch some traditional folk music and dancing; shows can be seen in many hotels and restaurants.</p>]]><p><b>Visit a market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The <em>piatas</em> or markets are farmers' markets where fresh produce can be bought. Pick up some home made cheeses and breads, find a scenic spot and have yourself a picnic afterwards.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Carpathian Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>TheThe Carpathian Mountains, a densely forested mountainous area, is ideal for hiking. In winter, resorts such as Poiana Brasov and Predeal offer some of the best skiing in Eastern Europe - or go bob-sleighing at Semenic and Sinaia. Recently, the mountains have also garnered a reputation among cyclists and there's a huge network of upland tracks to explore.</p>]]><p><b>Wildlife on the Danube</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cruise along the Danube Delta, to see over 300 species of birds and foxes, otters, wildcats and boars in a vast expanse of watery wilderness. This is a UNESCO World Heritage Site and biosphere reservation and altogether 3,460 species of animal can be spotted here &ndash; not to mention 1,700 plant species. Most Danube River cruises leave from Tulcea, which also has a museum dedicated to the Danube Delta. See Romania Tourism (<a href="http://www.romaniatourism.com/tulcea.html" target="_blank">www.romaniatourism.com/tulcea.html</a>) for more information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$186.7 billion (2011).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Textiles and footwear, metals and metal products, machinery and equipment, minerals and fuels, chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, fuels and minerals, chemicals, agricultural products, textiles and textile products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Italy, Germany, Turkey, France and UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Since the 1989 revolution, successive governments have concentrated on turning Romania into a market economy. Progress has been difficult, hampered by a largely obsolete industrial base and a pattern of output unsuited to the country's needs. Nevertheless, Romania's economic growth rate was the highest in the EU until the financial crisis saw GDP fall by over 7% in 2009. Unemployment still plagues the country, but the unemployment rate has gradually crept down and now stands at around 7% (2012). GDP growth stood at 2.4% in 2011, and despite an IMF bailout loan Romania is considered to be on the road to economic recovery.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A suit is essential at all business meetings and only on very hot days are shirtsleeves acceptable. English, German and French are used in business circles. Appointments are necessary and punctuality expected. Business cards are widely used. <br />
<br />
Romanians are sociable and love to talk, so mobile phones are a must for doing business in the city. People are extremely friendly and a surprising number speak excellent English, although the older generation may prefer French or German. However, Bucharest natives are also extremely formal, in the old European sense, and business visitors should respect this tradition, making appointments for meetings well in advance. Punctuality is important and suits are expected. On greeting it is customary to shake hands and business cards are often exchanged.<br />
<br />
Business lunches may take two hours, with wine or beer the most popular tipple. Work colleagues may socialise together in the evening at a local bar, although this tends to take place more among those working in multinational companies. It is relatively uncommon for Romanians to invite foreign businesspeople to their homes. Should this occur, gifts such as flowers, chocolates or high quality Scotch will always be appreciated. Summer is not the best period for doing business as many companies go into hibernation. Easter and Christmas are also difficult, as companies and shops close down for an indefinite period.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Romanian Convention Bureau</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (21) 314 4100
					Website:http://www.conventionbureau.ro/
					Address: Sector 1,Calea Victoriei 118,4th Floor,Suite 407,70179 Bucharest,]]><b>The Chamber of Commerce and Industry of Romania</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 030982 ,(21) 319 0114
					Website:http://www.ccir.ro/
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Romanian cuisine is an eclectic mix of different cultural influences, with elements from Turkey, Germany, Hungary all easily discernible. Traditionally, Romanian food tends to be stodgy and meat-based, revolving around dishes such as <em>ciolan afumat </em>(smoked pork knuckle with beans),<em> Mămăligă </em>(cornmeal polenta) and <em>carnaţi de pleşcoi </em>(mutton sausages).Breakfasts almost always include eggs, either soft-boiled, hard-boiled, fried or scrambled, and omelettes filled with either cheese, ham or mushrooms are also frequently served.</p>
<p>The highlight of a traditional Romanian restaurant meal is usually the appetiser dish, most likely a bowl of sour soup called ciorbă. Pork is the main meat used in Romanian cuisine while cabbage is a culinary favourite and is often used in soups and salads.</p>
<p>In rural areas, it&rsquo;s unusual to find restaurants serving anything other than traditional Romanian cuisine. In Bucharest, however, and in bigger cities such as Cluj-Napoca, the culinary scene is far more international, plus there are the odd gastronomic gems where the standard far surpasses the prices.&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Ciorbă (sour soup) is traditional Romanian. It has a few varieties including Ciorbă de burtă (tripe soup), Ciorbă de peşte (fish soup), and Ciorbă țărănească (peasant soup made with vegetables and any kind of meat).</p>
<p>&bull; Sarmale - widely considered as the national dish, it's made with minced meat with rice and wrapped in either pickled cabbage leaves or vine leaves.</p>
<p>&bull; Tochitură - stew made from pork (sometimes beef), traditionally served with mămăligă (mashed cornmeal, a local staple).</p>
<p>&bull; P&acirc;rjoale - minced pork mixed with herbs, rolled in bread crumbs and fried in hot oil.</p>
<p>&bull; Amandine - Romanian chocolate sponge cake with almond and chocolate filling.</p>
<p>&bull; Papanași - like a fried doughnut, usually filled with soft cheese and sweet cream inside and topped with cherry or blueberry preserve.</p>
<p>&bull; Țuică - a plum brandy, traditionally prepared at home from early October to early December. Turț is a double-distilled varity produced in northwest Romania.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Vegetarians had difficulties a decade ago but with many gastropubs offering vegetarian options, you can eat well in big cities like Bucharest. In rural areas there may be challenges as meat is often used to stuff vegetables. Try asking for mancare de post &ndash; food suitable for fasting, which is free from animal products.</p>
<p>Although there are inexpensive self-service snack bars, table service is the norm. There are no licensing hours.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 5 to 10% tip is customary in restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>The legal age for drinking in a bar is 18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bucharest has a growing number of nightclubs offering everything from hiphop and dance nights to jazz acts and ballroom dancing. Entry fees tend to be cheap, even in the capital, and outside the larger cities many clubs offer free entry.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Restaurants at most major hotels double as nightclubs and Bucharest has several Parisian-style cafes, although the locals tend to favour cocktail bars in summer and cosy underground pubs in winter. You&rsquo;ll also find a number of glitzy casinos clustered around the upmarket Calea Victoriei. Opera is performed at the Romanian Opera House and the Romanian Athenaeum has two symphony orchestras, while folk entertainment is performed at the Rapsodia Romana Artistic Ensemble Hall. The National Theatre Bucharest puts on regular events and shows, so it&rsquo;s worth checking what&rsquo;s on before you travel.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The top nightlife spots outside Bucharest include Brasov, Craiova, Sighisoara, Mamaia, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ia%C8%99i"><u>Iasi</u></a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constan%C5%A3a"><u>Constanţa</u></a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gala%C5%A3i"><u>Galaţi</u></a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ploie%C5%9Fti"><u>Ploieşti</u></a> and Timisoara. Cluj-Napoca, with its large student population and funky minimal techno scene, also has a growing reputation as a party city. Don&rsquo;t expect to dance the night away if you&rsquo;re based in a smaller town, although small pubs and teahouses can offer a much better opportunity to get to know the locals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like most countries, Romania has its fair share of generic shopping malls &ndash; but it&rsquo;s far more rewarding to shop with the locals at your nearest market. Even the smallest Romanian village usually has a regular market, and in some areas wares are still transported from place to place by horse-drawn wagon. Local cheese, fruit and fresh vegetables are all daily staples, while some markets also sell national specialities such as embroideries, pottery, porcelain, silverware, carpets, ceramics, crystal, glassware, fabrics, wool jumpers, woodcarvings, metal, leather goods, rugs, glass paintings and silk dresses. Transactions at markets almost always take place in cash &ndash; and don&rsquo;t be afraid to haggle if the price isn&rsquo;t right. </p>
<p>Bucharest is the country&rsquo;s shopping hub. As well as several city-centre malls, it has a colourful flower market, regular arts and crafts events and a thriving antiques industry. Nose out a gem in Str Hanul cu Tei, a narrow cobbled alley in the historic town centre lined with galleries and antiques shops. Or, if your taste runs to luxury, take a stroll down Calea Victoriei, where you&rsquo;ll find an expensive selection of jewellery and designer boutiques.     </p>
<p>Prices in Romania have crept up over the past few years, but it&rsquo;s still possible to pick up high-quality, handmade jewellery for a song in some areas. Iași&rsquo;s Hala Centrala has dozens of jewellery stalls &ndash; for a traditional, low-priced souvenir, look for pieces crafted from Romanian amber set in Turkish silver. On the other side of the country, Timișoara is famous for its arts and crafts scene and hosts a selection of shops selling local artwork, ceramics and handcrafted jewellery.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0900-1800, although this may vary according to season and area. In urban areas, supermarkets can remain open for much of the night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are advised to book accommodation in advance, particularly for summertime visits to coastal resorts. Room prices in lower-end hotels in Romania are very reasonable compared to Western European prices, whereas 4- and 5-star hotels are comparable in both standards and price. Breakfast normally costs extra. Romania's first boutique hotels have opened in Transylvania. For further information, contact the Romanian Tourist Office (<a href="http://www.romaniatourism.com" target="_blank">www.romaniatourism.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation of this type (also called <em>pensiune</em>) is plentiful in Romania and in smaller towns or villages may be the only options. Private rooms tend to be cheaper than hotel rooms and will be basic but comfortable. Bed and breakfast accommodation is classified from 1 to 3 daisies. For further information, contact the Romanian National Tourist Office or ANTREC (<a href="http://www.antrec.ro" target="_blank">www.antrec.ro</a>) which has a good selection of rural guesthouses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are advised to book accommodation in advance, particularly for summertime visits to coastal resorts. Room prices in lower-end hotels in Romania are very reasonable compared to Western European prices, whereas 4- and 5-star hotels are comparable in both standards and price. Breakfast normally costs extra. Romania's first boutique hotels have opened in Transylvania. For further information, contact the Romanian Tourist Office (<a href="http://www.romaniatourism.com" target="_blank">www.romaniatourism.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are advised to book accommodation in advance, particularly for summertime visits to coastal resorts. Room prices in lower-end hotels in Romania are very reasonable compared to Western European prices, whereas 4- and 5-star hotels are comparable in both standards and price. Breakfast normally costs extra. Romania's first boutique hotels have opened in Transylvania. For further information, contact the Romanian Tourist Office (<a href="http://www.romaniatourism.com" target="_blank">www.romaniatourism.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities in Romania are poor and there is a serious shortage of basic medical supplies and qualified personnel. Take particular care if travelling in rural areas, as there have been cases of hepatitis B and HIV transmission through insufficiently sterilised equipment. If necessary, your local embassy or consulate should be able to recommend a physician. European travellers carrying the European Health Insurance Card (EHIC) are entitled to free or reduced cost medical care. In the UK, these are available from health centres or via the Department of Health (&lt;a href="http://www.dh.gov.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.dh.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;). Nationals of countries who do not have a reciprocal health agreement with Romania are expected to pay immediate cash for health services. Health insurance is strongly advised.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated, and whilst relatively safe, may cause abdominal upsets; bottled water is available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis C and tuberculosis occur and hepatitis B is endemic. Stray dogs may carry the tick-borne African typhus disease and rabies is also present. If bitten, seek medical advice without delay. There have been confirmed outbreaks of avian influenza (bird flu) in the Danube Delta, Transylvania and Bucharest. The Romanian authorities have taken measures to contain the outbreaks and no human infections or deaths have been reported. In 2012, several cases of the West Nile Virus were reported by the Romanian National Institute of Health, and travellers to the Danube Delta are recommended to wear long-sleeved shirts and trousers and to apply insect repellent.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Orthodox Easter Monday :
							09 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>National Day :
							01 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Second Day of Christmas :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Romania is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% volume, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Romania by persons over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 40 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of US$450.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ammunition, weapons, explosives, narcotics and counterfeit goods.</p>
<p>There are restrictions on the import of meat and dairy products from outside the EU.</p>
<p>You must obtain a permit to import protected species.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Articles of cultural, historical or artistic value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>New Leu (RON;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/"></a> symbol (plural) Lei) = 100 bani. Notes are in denominations of Lei500, 100, 50, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of Bani50, 10, 5 and 1. (Old notes were in denominations of Lei1,000,000, 500,000, 100,000, 50,000 and 10,000 and coins in denominations of Lei5,000, 1,000, 500 and 100.)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is recommended that visitors bring Euros, as these can be easily exchanged by shops, restaurants and hotels. Pounds Sterling can be easily exchanged in most resorts. All hard foreign currencies can be exchanged at banks, larger hotels and airports and at authorised exchange offices (<em>Birou de Schimb Valutar</em>). Rates can vary from one place to another, so visitors are advised to shop around for the best rate of exchange. Exchanges on the black market are made frequently, but visitors are advised to exchange money through proper exchange channels and to receive a currency exchange receipt, as certain services require visitors to show the receipt as proof of having made at least one financial transaction.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are accepted by large hotels, car hire firms and some restaurants and shops.</p><p>ATMs (<em>bancomat</em>) accepting MasterCard and Visa can be found in main banks, airports and shopping centres but should not be relied upon as a sole source of cash.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like credit and debit cards, these are usually only useful in hotels and for obtaining cash at the bank or selected exchange offices. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Euros.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Passports must be valid for at least three months on arrival in Romania and issued within the last 10 years for non-EU nationals and should be valid for the duration of stay for EU nationals.</p>
<p><strong>1.</strong> EU citizens  can use a national identity card instead of a passport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas allow nationals of certain countries (but not those referred to in the chart above) to travel Romania and can be issued for one, two or multiple transits provided that each period does not exceed five days. Documentation required includes an existing visa for the destination state, a valid travel ticket, and in the case of vehicle drivers a green card, driving licence and vehicle registration documents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Romania is not a member of the Schengen Area. However it is set to join the area once the European Council reaches an agreement. This will allow residents of other Schengen countries (the majority of western Europe excluding the UK and Ireland) to travel freely to Romania without having to negotiate border controls.&nbsp;A decision on an accession date has yet to be made though.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airport transit visa/transit visa/short-stay visa: &pound;46; long-stay visa: &pound;91. Reductions are available for some nationalities and for children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: five days; short-stay visa: 90 days within a six-month period; long-stay visa: 90 days with the potential to extend.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). You can make your initial application online (<a href="http://evisa.mae.ro">http://evisa.mae.ro</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least two weeks for short-stay visas and up to 45 days for long-stay visas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For short-stay visas, proof of financial support totalling at least &euro;50 per day and not less than &euro;500 in total is required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you're an EU national and plan on staying longer than 90 days, you must apply for a registration certificate from the General Inspectorate for Immigration (<a href="http://igi.mai.gov.ro">http://igi.mai.gov.ro</a>).&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To take a pet into Romania, you need a veterinary health certificate and proof that your pet has been vaccinated for rabies within the last six months. Documents not written in English, German or French need to be translated. Large dogs must wear a muzzle when travelling on trains or buses.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[45.839043]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[25.008960]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>238,391 sq km (92,043 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>19,372,734 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>90.9 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bucharest.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Romania is bordered by Moldova and Ukraine to the north and northeast; the Black Sea to the east;&nbsp;Bulgariato the south; and Serbia and&nbsp;Hungary to the west. The country is divided into 41 counties, but essentially there are four geographical regions with decidedly different characters; Transylvania, Moldova, Dobrogea and Muntenia.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Transylvania and Moldova comprise the northern half of the country and are characterised by Alpine massifs and dense forests. The Carpathian Mountains run along the border of these two regions and are made up of 14 mountain ranges above 2,000m (6,560ft) with Moldoveanu  Peak at 2,544m (8,300ft) the highest point.</p>
<p>The terrain around here is a mix of extinct volcanic cones, lunar plains, thick forests and glacial lakes &ndash; perfect for hiking, cycling and adrenaline sports.</p>
<p>Muntenia, also known as Wallachia, lies south of the Carpathians and is home to the capital Bucharest. A relatively flat province, its&nbsp;border with Bulgaria is defined by the River Danube. In the southeast lies Dobrogea, which is home to the Danube Delta. The best-preserved delta in Europe, it is a&nbsp;haven&nbsp;for wildlife and has been declared a biosphere reserve and biodiversity World Heritage Site by UNESCO.</p>
<p>The Dobrogea region boasts nearly 200 km (120 miles) of Black Sea coastline, incorporating the port of Constanta and the Danube Delta.&nbsp;Romania&rsquo;s other major rivers include the Olt, the Siret and the Mures.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>87% Romanian Orthodox, with Greek and Roman Catholic, Reformed/Lutheran, Unitarian, Muslim and Jewish minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A handshake is the most common form of greeting, but Romanian men may kiss a woman's hand when being introduced. Mr or Mrs should be used when greeting someone for the first time. Visitors should follow normal European courtesies on social occasions. Dress tends to be rather conservative but casual wear is suitable. Beachwear should not be worn away from the beach or poolside.</p>
<p>If visiting a home, a small wrapped gift should be given to the host, such as flowers or chocolates (to women only), wine or liquor. Flowers should be given as a gift in odd numbers only. Many Romanians are smokers and gifts of Western cigarettes are greatly appreciated. Other well-appreciated gifts include toiletries. <br />
<br />
The Romanian government bans smoking in every public place, but, as in many countries in Eastern Europe, smokers have little respect for non-smokers and for smoking laws. Smoking is forbidden on planes, on buses and on some trains. Luxury hotels have designated no-smoking floors but very few restaurants have no-smoking sections.</p>
<p>Military installations should not be photographed. Some tourist attractions require visitors to pay a fee (sometimes hefty) for taking photographs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Viorica Dancila, since January 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Klaus Iohannis since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The region of Romania has spent much of its history being shunted to and fro between various foreign powers. The Romans, Goths, Huns, Bulgars and Slavs all laid claim to the area before it was annexed by the Turkish Ottomans in the 15th century. It wasn&rsquo;t until 1878 that Romania was recognised by the rest of Europe as an independent state.</p>
<p>It joined the Allied cause in WWI, but was occupied by the Germans in 1940 and placed in the hands of General Ion Antonescu, who joined the Nazis against the Soviet Union. In 1944, with Soviet forces about to occupy the country, Antonescu was overthrown and replaced by a coalition of communists, liberals and social democrats.</p>
<p>The communists established their political hegemony within the government and in 1947 the monarchy was deposed and the Romanian People's Republic declared. Nicolae Ceausescu assumed the post of First Secretary of the Romanian Communist Party in 1965 and under his rule the regime became increasingly oppressive. Ceausescu destroyed much of the beautiful historic centre of Bucharest, replacing it with bland concrete apartment blocks and a sprawling palace &ndash; the House of the Republic. He held power until the dramatic, bloody and largely unpredicted revolution during Christmas 1989.</p>
<p>This was a turning point in Romanian history. After several days of violent protests and fighting, during which around 1,000 people were killed, the president and his wife were captured, quickly tried and executed. The new government, under the provisional leadership of Ion Iliescu (the former Communist Central Committee Secretary) began the slow and painful process of preparing Romania for peaceful multi-party elections.</p>
<p>Today, Romania is a fully-fledged and cohesive democratic state. Although regular changes of government have held back the country&rsquo;s development and economic progress has been patchy, the country is now a member of both NATO and the European Union and in 2008 it hosted its first NATO summit. Political and economic unrest in 2012 threatened a crisis, but the corner has been turned and the country is experiencing much more positive growth than many of Europe&rsquo;s leading nations.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Romania celebrates Great Union Day on 1 December to mark its joining with Transylvania. <br />
&bull;	In 1986 Steaua Bucharest became the first Eastern European team to win football&rsquo;s European Cup.<br />
&bull;	The Dacia car factory in Mioveni is Europe&rsquo;s fifth largest, producing more than 500,000 units a year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Romania]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(40) 21 201 7200. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/romania</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(40) 21 201 7200. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0830-1700; Fri 0830-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>24 Jules Michelet<br/>Bucharest<br/>010463<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Romania in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7937 9666.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://londra.mae.ro</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7937 9666.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; Mon-Thurs 1000-1300 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Arundel House, 4 Palace Green<br/>London<br/>W8 4QD<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Romania in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 4846 or 2879 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://washington.mae.ro/en</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 4846 or 2879 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1607 23rd Street NW<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Romania has a rich cultural and natural diversity. Its dramatic mountain scenery includes the densely forested Carpathian Mountains, picturesque valleys and miles of fine white sandy beaches on the Black Sea Coast.</p>
<p>The first post of call for most travellers is the bustling capital, Bucharest, which was once known as &lsquo;Little Paris&rsquo; due to its sophisticated charm. Crammed with grand architecture, fascinating museums and traditional restaurants, it&rsquo;s well worth a few days exploration. So too are the resorts along the Black Sea Coast, which surprise many with their stunning sandy beaches and ocean panoramas.</p>
<p>Ultimately, though, Romania remains defined by its small, rural communities, many of which still depend on ancient agricultural practices. From the isolated villages clinging to the Carpathian Mountains to the Saxon towns of Transylvania, a tour of Romania&rsquo;s backcountry will uncover traditional ways of life and a treasure chest of cultural gems.</p>
<p>It is, of course, practically illegal to talk about Transylvania without mentioning the legend of Dracula. The Romanians are all too well aware of the interest in Bram Stoker&rsquo;s fictional vampire and the castle at Bran (supposedly the spot that inspired Stoker&rsquo;s story) has been transformed into one of the country&rsquo;s top tourist attractions.</p>
<p>Elsewhere the forests covering the Carpathian Mountains shelter some of Europe's last remaining brown bears, wolves and lynxes, while racoon dogs and rare muskrats gather around the rivers.</p>
<p>While Romania offers travellers the chance to immerse themselves in a defiantly traditional way of life, that isn&rsquo;t to say the locals don&rsquo;t appreciate their creature comforts. The natural spas scattered across the country purport to cure everything from rheumatism to heart disease, and make a luxurious finale to any Romanian adventure.</p><p>Romania has a rich cultural and natural diversity. Its dramatic mountain scenery includes the densely forested Carpathian Mountains, picturesque valleys and miles of fine white sandy beaches on the Black Sea Coast.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
