<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Russian Federation" ColCode="rus" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="ru" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Russia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As you&rsquo;d expect Russia&rsquo;s climate is hugely dependent on where in the country you find yourself. With temperatures known to hit a tarmac-melting 37&deg;C (99&deg;F) in the cities and fall to -30&deg;C (-22&deg;F) and lower during the Siberian winter, there&rsquo;s no point generalising about Russia&rsquo;s weather except to say, be prepared.</p>
<p>The most favourable temperatures are found along the Baltic coast, where many Muscovites decamp for balmy summer holidays, while the site of the 2014 Winter Olympics, Sochi, also doubles as a beach resort due to its tropical climate, earning it the epithet &lsquo;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america/florida">Florida</a> of Russia&rsquo;. Minus the overly tanned pensioners of course.</p>
<p>While the notion of visiting a snow-blanketed <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-petersburg">St Petersburg</a> has a definite romance, most tourists prefer to come calling in the warm summer months of June, July and August. This means the shoulder seasons of April, May, September and October&nbsp;are good options for visitors keen to avoid the peak crowds &ndash; prices are generally lower from September to May, and tourist sites almost invariably less crowded.</p>
<p>Spring is often characterised by slushy roads. And if your heart&rsquo;s set on that winter wonderland, December&rsquo;s the best bet. Seasonal climates apply elsewhere in Russia &ndash; Siberia can have devastatingly cold winters, while its summers are generally fairly pleasant, if a little rainy. The region of Russia near the Black Sea has mild winters, but again attracts a fair amount of rain.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Those visiting over summer should pack a mixture of lightweight and mediumweight clothing &ndash; natural fibres such as cotton and linen are best. For the winter visitor, meanwhile &ndash; layers, layers, layers. Wools and cashmeres are great material for keeping in the warmth. Sturdy shoes are always a good idea, no matter what time of year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The internal flight network radiates from Moscow's three major airports: Domodedovo, Vnukovo Airport, and Sheremetyevo Airport. There are over 100 regional airlines in Russia, most of which run services from Moscow to their region. These include Aeroflot (<a href="http://www.aeroflot.ru" target="_blank">www.aeroflot.ru</a>) and Rossiya Russian Airlines (<a href="http://www.rossiya-airlines.com" target="_blank">www.rossiya-airlines.com</a>).</p>
<p>Aircraft safety has improved over the past decade or so, although crashes are still not unknown. The purchase of newer craft, and revised safety regulations have seen things slowly get better.</p><p>Pay little attention to timetables you might see posted on walls, especially in smaller towns across the country, as these are likely to be unreliable and possibly even relics from a bygone age.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rail is by far the best (if not quickest) way to travel in Russia. The railway is a vital part of the infrastructure of Russia because of the distances involved in getting from A to B and the sometimes poor road system. Tourists can book tickets at stations or online via the state railway (tel: +7 8800 775 0000; <a href="http://pass.rzd.ru/main-pass/public/en" target="_blank">http://pass.rzd.ru/main-pass/public/en</a>) or via a reputable agency such as Real Russia (<a href="http://www.realrussia.co.uk" target="_blank">www.realrussia.co.uk</a>) who can also organise visas. Tickets are released 45 days in advance.</p>
<p>Children under five years of age travel free, while those aged five to nine pay half fare. Rail travellers are advised to store valuables in the compartment under the bed or seat and not to leave the compartment unattended. There are regular services between Moscow and St Petersburg, including several overnight trains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The network of roads across Russia are certainly improving &ndash; however not fast enough to make then a relaxing option for travelling inside the country, and the frustrations still outweigh the benefits. Furthermore, distances in Russia should not be underestimated, as Russia is a vast country and travel by road takes considerably more time than by train or aeroplane.</p>
<p>The European part of Russia depends heavily on its road network. Generally, the few roads in Siberia and further east are impassable during the winter. It is not recommended to drive in Russia as harassment from traffic police is endless.</p>
<p>If you do decide to drive, it is advisable to pre-plan the itinerary and accommodation requirements. On the majority of tourist routes, signposts are also written in the Latin alphabet. Sample distances: Moscow to St Petersburg, 713km (443 miles); Moscow to Minsk, 718km (446 miles); Moscow to Rostov-on-Don, 1,076km (669 miles); Moscow to Odessa, 1,340km (833 miles). Motorists should avoid driving at night if possible.</p>r<p>Consistently poor, pot holes are commonplace and the further east you travel, unsealed roads are the rule rather than the exception. That said, it is possible and as with all things if you put in the effort there are rewards to be claimed.</p><p>Coaches can be a slightly cheaper way to travel around the country. However, they are much slower, with none of the romance or comfort of the train. If budgets allow, taking a train is usually the better option. Eurolines (<a href="http://www.eurolines.com" target="_blank">www.eurolines.com</a>) operates in the west of the country.</p><p>Taxis are relatively inexpensive and readily available in all towns and cities. For a small fee, just about any car driver will gladly become a taxi.</p><p>An International Driving Permit and a national licence with authorised translations are necessary. Visitors travelling in their own cars must also possess the following documents at all times: passport and visa; car registration number and full details of itinerary; form provided by customs on arrival guaranteeing that the car will be taken out of Russia on departure; and insurance cover documents.</p>
<p>A road tax is payable upon entry to the country. Motor insurance for travel within Russia should be arranged prior to departure, or upon entry to Russia at the offices of Ingosstrakh, the Russian foreign insurance agency. Contact the embassy or a specialist tour operator for further details.</p><p>Traffic drives on the right. Speed limits are to 60kph (37mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (55mph) in non-built-up areas and 100-120kph (62-72mph) on highways. Visiting motorists who have been driving for less than two years must not exceed 70kph (43mph).</p>
<p>Hooting the horn is forbidden except when to do so might prevent an accident. Every car must display registration plates and stickers denoting the country of registration and be fitted with seat belts, a first-aid kit, a fire extinguisher and an emergency sign (triangle) or red light. Also be mindful that if your licence plate is dirty you may receive a fine.</p>
<p>In case of an accident, contact the nearest traffic inspection officer and make sure all participants fill in written statements, to be witnessed by a militia inspector. All repairs will be at the foreign motorist's expense.</p><p>In the event of a car breakdown contact the highway patrol, GAI and your car hire company.</p><p>Available from local and international firms. Chauffeured cars are available in major cities.</p><p>Cycling is something of an extreme pastime in Russia. However, if you&rsquo;ve got the stamina it&rsquo;s a great way to see the country during the summer months.</p><p>Traffic drives on the right. Speed limits are to 60kph (37mph) in built-up areas, 90kph (55mph) in non-built-up areas and 100-120kph (62-72mph) on highways. Visiting motorists who have been driving for less than two years must not exceed 70kph (43mph).</p>
<p>Hooting the horn is forbidden except when to do so might prevent an accident. Every car must display registration plates and stickers denoting the country of registration and be fitted with seat belts, a first-aid kit, a fire extinguisher and an emergency sign (triangle) or red light. Also be mindful that if your licence plate is dirty you may receive a fine.</p>
<p>In case of an accident, contact the nearest traffic inspection officer and make sure all participants fill in written statements, to be witnessed by a militia inspector. All repairs will be at the foreign motorist's expense.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public transport in the cities is comprehensive and cheap. Many services are electric transport (metro, tramway, trolleybus). Stations on the Moscow and St Petersburg metros are always elegant and often palatial.</p>
<p>Entry to the underground is by single-use tokens or a multi-use paper ticket, both of which are inserted into the ticket barrier. Fares are standard for the various forms of transport; weekly and monthly passes are available. Buses operate 0500-0000. Tickets are available in strips or booklets from people outside the metro station or from the drivers or bus conductors (look for the red armband) directly. Tickets must be punched in the machine provided on the bus. Reloadable smartcards are also available.</p>
<p>Taxis are also available; they can be hailed in the street, hired at a rank or booked by telephone. It is safer but far more expensive to use officially marked taxis; they are yellow with chequered signs on the doors, although in practice it is totally safe to flag down any car, agree a destination and price and get in. However, always use common sense.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Russian Federation</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">volgograd</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">14.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Russian Federation</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">st_petersburg</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">9.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Russian Federation</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">khabarovsk</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">97.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Russian Federation</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">irkutsk</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">77.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Russia's main airline, Aeroflot (<a href="http://www.aeroflot.com" target="_blank">www.aeroflot.com</a>), flies&nbsp;from the UK and the USA to Russia. Another airline operating direct flights from the UK is British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>). Flights tend to be pricier in the summer and around Orthodox Christmas in early January.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia/moscow-sheremetyevo-international-airport">Moscow Sheremetyevo International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia/moscow-vnukovo-international-airport">Moscow Vnukovo International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia/moscow-domodedovo-international-airport">Moscow Domodedovo International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia/st-petersburg-pulkovo-airport">St Petersburg Pulkovo Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/strigino-nizhny-novgorod-international-airport">Strigino Nizhny Novogorod International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/samara-kurumoch-international-airport">Samara Kurumoch International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia/sochi-international-airport">Sochi International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia/vladivostok-airport">Vladivostok Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia/ekaterinburg-airport">Ekaterinburg Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/russia/irkutsk-airport">Irkutsk Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 3 hours 45 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 9 hours.</p>
<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-petersburg">St Petersburg</a>: from London - 3 hours 20 minutes; New York - 10 hours 50 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Moscow Domodedovo International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.domodedovo.ru<p>Moscow Domodedovo International Airport is located 42km (26 miles) south of central Moscow.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+7 495 933 6666.</p>]]><b>Moscow Sheremetyevo International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.svo.aero/en<p>Moscow Sheremetyevo International Airport is located 29km (18 miles) northwest of Moscow.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+7 495 578 6565.</p>]]><b>St Petersburg Pulkovo Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.pulkovoairport.ru<p>St Petersburg Pulkovo Airport is located 14km (9 miles) south of St Petersburg.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+7 812 337 3822</p>]]><b>Ekaterinburg Koltsovo Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.koltsovo.ru<p>Ekaterinburg Koltsovo Airport is situated 23km (14 miles) southeast of Ekaterinburg city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+7 343 226 8582</p>]]><b>Irkutsk Airport</b><![CDATA[http://iktport.ru<p>Irkutsk International Airport is situated 8km (5 miles) from the city centre. Irkutsk is in southeastern Siberia, 60km (37 miles) east of Lake Baikal in the Russian Federation.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+7 3952 266 277</p>]]><b>Moscow Vnukovo International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.vnukovo.ru<p>Moscow Vnukovo International Airport is situated 30km (18.5 miles) southwest of central Moscow.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+7 495 937 5555</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The St Peter Line Ferries (<a href="http://www.stpeterline.com" target="_blank">www.stpeterline.com</a>) have regular voyages to St Petersburg between March and December, from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/stockholm">Stockholm</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tallinn">Tallinn</a> and Helsinki. It is also possible to catch a ferry from Trabzon in Turkey to Sochi and Novorossiysk. In the Far East, DBS Cruise Ferry (<a href="http://www.dbsferry.com" target="_blank">www.dbsferry.com</a>) runs ferries from&nbsp;Vladivostok to Sakaiminato, Japan via Dongae, South Korea.</p><p>A lot of sea routes are closed in winter (January to March).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are various connections from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>. The main route is: London-Brussels-Cologne-Warsaw-Moscow/St Petersburg. The journey from London to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brussels">Brussels</a> can be made by a variety of train and ferry services (including via Eurostar), or via the Channel Tunnel. There is a sleeper service from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cologne">Cologne</a> to Warsaw and another from Warsaw to Moscow.</p>
<p>The Allegro high-speed train connects St. Petersburg and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/helsinki">Helsinki</a> and takes 3 hours 30 minutes. There are through trains or coaches from other Western and nearly all Eastern European capitals, from CIS (Commonwealth of Independent States) countries, and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mongolia">Mongolia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey">Turkey</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>There is also a rail connection to Moscow from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a>, which travels via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/poland">Poland</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belarus">Belarus</a>, for which you need a transit visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several routes into the country by road. From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/estonia">Estonia</a> it is possible to cross the border at Narva. From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/finland">Finland</a> there are crossings at Nujamaa and Vaalimaa, although travellers should be aware that there have been numerous reports of bandits active on this road. From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/georgia">Georgia</a> in the south it is possible to follow the Georgian Military Highway, but this route is often closed to foreigners. In the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ukraine">Ukraine</a> the M3 auto route runs from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kiev">Kiev</a> to Moscow.</p><p>A visa is required to enter Russia and visas will not be issued at the border. Thus, it&rsquo;s sensible to assume that entry will be denied if you don&rsquo;t have one. It is also worth bearing in mind that even with the appropriate documentation, crossing Russian borders by car can be a frustrating and time-consuming experience.&nbsp;When travelling by car from Estonia to Russia, a prior online registration of your car on <a href="http://www.estonianborder.eu" target="_blank">www.estonianborder.eu</a>&nbsp;will reduce your waiting time at the border.</p>
<p>Once across the border, driving in Russia is not for the faint-hearted: among other numerous frustrations, roads are poorly maintained, petrol is low quality and traffic police are particularly enthusiastic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Most Moscow hotels have telephone booths with IDD. For long-distance calls within the CIS (Commonwealth of Independent States), dial 8 then wait for the dial tone before proceeding with the call. Collect calls, calls placed using credit cards and calls from direct dial telephones in hotels can be extremely expensive. International calls can be made from phones in the street and phonecards are available from many shops and kiosks in the street.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies. All major cities are covered by at least one operator. Handsets can be hired from some companies and local SIM cards are easily purchased for use within Russia if you have an unlocked handset.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is available within most establishments in larger cities (although they may charge) and at internet cafes. Although Russia does not ostensibly censor the internet, there is an internet blacklist of sites which you will not be able to visit from inside Russia, which includes some independent news sites.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The arrival of Putin in 2000 saw a new era of unofficial government press control for Russia, which appears to be continuing under President Medvedev. Most of the mainstream press is uncritical of the Kremlin. The main quality dailies in Russia are <em>Izvestiya </em>and the business-oriented <em>Kommersant</em>and <em>Vedomosti</em>, all published in Moscow. Big circulation tabloids include <em>Argumenty I Fakti </em>(now owned by the Moscow government) and <em>Komsomolskaya Pravda</em>. The daily <em>Moscow Times </em>and twice-weekly <em>St Petersburg Times </em>are published in English.</p>
<p>In terms of television, there is currently no independently owned national TV network. VGTRK is a state-owned national TV network. NTV is a national network owned by the gas company, Gazprom. Russia Today is an international English news channel run by a state-owned agency. Other networks include STS, TNT, MTV Russia and REN TV. When it comes to radio, Russkoye Radio and Eko Moskvy are privately run, whilst Radio Russia and Radio Mayak are state-run networks. Voice of Russia operates programmes in English and other languages.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is an extensive postal network throughout Russia. Airmail to Western Europe takes over 10 days and has a reputation for being unreliable when it comes to international mail. There are postboxes and post offices in every hotel. Inland surface mail is often slow.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-2000; Sat 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Krasnaya Ploshchad (Red Square)</p><![CDATA[<p>Red Square is bordered by some of Russia&rsquo;s best known monuments - the Kremlin, St Basil's Cathedral and the GUM department store. This enormous, 700m-long (2,300 ft) public space was used for May Day parades back in the Soviet era, and nowadays it serves as a major tourist attraction. The GUM department store functions as an upmarket shopping mall &ndash; symbolic of the country&rsquo;s new found enthusiasm for the market economy. In contrast, the square&rsquo;s west side has Lenin's Mausoleum.</p>]]><br/><p>State Hermitage Museum</p><![CDATA[<p>Home to more than three million artworks and artefacts, St. Petersburg&rsquo;s Hermitage is one the planet&rsquo;s most acclaimed museums. The collection dates back to a number of Western European paintings purchased by Empress Catherine the Great in 1764, and has since gone on to encompass a catalogue of priceless works.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bolshoi Theatre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Moscow's Bolshoi Theatre (<a href="http://www.bolshoi.ru" target="_blank">www.bolshoi.ru</a>) holds regular performances of opera, as well as being home to the world-famous Bolshoi Ballet Company, among the oldest and most prestigious of its kind anywhere.</p>]]><p><b>Catherine Palace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sitting 29km (18 miles) outside of St Petersburg, the Catherine Palace acted as a summer residence for a succession of different tsars. It&rsquo;s perhaps best known for being home to the Amber Room &ndash; a stunning array of amber panels looted by Nazis and since recreated.</p>]]><p><b>Experience ‘White Nights’</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you're in St Petersburg at the height of summer, don't expect too much kip. By dint of its northerly location, the city experiences some three weeks of 24-hour daylight from mid-June, a time at which the streets and riverbanks never sleep.</p>]]><p><b>Go skiing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the Western Caucusus, Krasnaya Polyana (also known as Red Valley) has 25km (16 miles) of runs, making it a magnet for the country&rsquo;s skiers and snowboarders. Elsewhere in the country, the Kamchatka Peninsula has the potential for a dramatic heli-skiing trip, and Sochi, the home of the 2014 Winter Olympics, offers vast slopes with a huge variety of skiing available for all abilities.</p>]]><p><b>Irkutsk</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A common stop-off for those tackling the Trans-Siberian Railway, Irkutsk is worthy of a day or two's exploration, particularly for those interested in learning more about Siberian culture. Try and catch a bandy match – a kind of al fresco ice hockey.</p>]]><p><b>Kola Peninsula</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Kola Peninsula offers exceptional salmon-fishing – 18kg (40lb) catches are almost a regular occurrence – while Siberia and the Far East also provide a rich variety of angling options, catering for everyone from beginners to experts.</p>]]><p><b>Lake Baikal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set close to the Mongolian border, the world's deepest lake is also one of the clearest, and a trip around some, or all, of its 2,000km (1,242 miles) coastline makes for an awe-inspiring wilderness encounter. Unless snowmobiling's your thing, the summer months are best.</p>]]><p><b>Lenin’s Mausoleum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The embalmed body of revolutionary leader Vladimir Lenin has been on public display almost continuously since his death in 1924. Filing past the regularly moisturised corpse – still in a smart dark suit – is an odd experience, but one not easily forgotten.</p>]]><p><b>Moscow’s nightlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Russian capital has a famously wild nightlife. You may have to shell out to get into the trendier spots – this is one city where luxury means luxury – but there's also no shortage of lively places where the emphasis is more on partying than profits.</p>]]><p><b>Mount Elbrus</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mount Elbrus is the tallest mountain in the Caucasus and, indeed, Europe itself. Standing 5,642m (18,510 ft) high, it makes for a strenuous but not overly technical climb. Six-day trekking circuits are available for those who fancy looking down on the rest of the continent.</p>]]><p><b>St Isaac’s Cathedral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An impressive reminder of St Petersburg's tsarist-era design, St Issac's Cathedral was 40 years in its construction, eventually being unveiled in 1858. The bright golden dome was actually repainted grey during the war to avoid undue attention – it's now back to its former glory.</p>]]><p><b>St Petersburg’s Canals</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The size and grandeur of imperial city of St Petersburg has a tendency to amaze first-time visitors, and there are few better ways of appreciating the architecture of the centre than in the comfort of a leisurely canal cruise through its heart.</p>]]><p><b>The Kremlin</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Some visitors are surprised that there's any access at all to the Kremlin – there's actually enough to see to warrant more than one visit. Most famous of its attractions is the Armoury Museum, a treasure-trove of Fabergé eggs and imperial bling.</p>]]><p><b>Trans-Siberian Railway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Trans-Siberian railway is perhaps the single most iconic rail journey in the world. The week-long voyage from Moscow to Beijing is the most popular route, and takes you through some of the planet&rsquo;s most remote wilderness. The sheer length of the trip gives you an idea of the scale of the area you&rsquo;re covering &ndash; over 9,000km (5,600 miles).</p>]]><p><b>Vladivostok</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you've made it this far east, congratulations. Fringed by hills and overlooking the Golden Horn Bay, Vladivostok is actually one of the country's most attractive cities. There's a number of diverting historical sights, as well as good access to beaches.</p>]]><p><b>Volgograd</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Renamed Stalingrad during the socialist era, Volgograd has the dubious honour of being the site of one of WWII's most infamous battles. The city was levelled by the conflict, but has recovered to become an interesting destination for history buffs.</p>]]><p><b>Yusupov Palace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Your jaw will no doubt drop at St Petersburg's gorgeously decorated Yusupov Palace (<a href="http://www.yusupov-palace.ru" target="_blank">www.yusupov-palace.ru</a>). Its rooms are sumptuously decorated in 19th-century style and include a gorgeous mini-theatre. A waxwork exhibition also commemorates Rasputin, who was murdered here.</p>]]><p><b>Zero-gravity flight</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ever wanted to experience complete weightlessness? Join a zero-gravity flight at Star City, part of the Yuri Gagarin Cosmonaut Training Centre (<a href="http://www.gctc.su" target="_blank">http://www.gctc.su</a>), 40km (25 miles) from Moscow. Guests can in a modified cargo plane, which rises to 6000m (19685 ft) before a further steep ascent allows passengers to float weightlessly around the plane. It&rsquo;s not cheap, but then, this isn&rsquo;t your average tourist activity.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$1.3 trillion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum and petroleum products, natural gas, wood and wood products, chemicals and manufactured goods and military hardware.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, vehicles, pharmaceuticals, plastic, meat and sugar.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Ukraine, Netherlands, Italy and China</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main bulk of Russia&rsquo;s economy rides on its huge wealth of energy resources - it has huge deposits of oil and gas (in 2011 it became the world&rsquo;s leading oil producer) as well as coal and minerals including gold, diamonds, nickel, manganese, copper, iron ore and phosphates.</p>
<p>Energy products and heavy industry (production of vehicles, metal goods, construction materials and machinery) are the kernel of Russia's industrial sector. Textiles and chemicals are other important industries. Overall the economic system remains weak and infrastructure and transparency poor. Only Russia's vast energy wealth has managed to override this problem, though the world financial crisis has re-exposed the fundamental weakness of the Russian economic system. <br />
<br />
Since the devaluation of the rouble and Russia's calamitous default on its international debts in 1998, the economy has undergone a significant recovery, although the financial crisis of 2008 stalled this recovery due to the drop in oil prices. The government has got on top of the hyper-inflation that caused so much damage in the initial stages of the reform process, but the boom-and-bust cycles which go along with having such a resource-dependent economy still continue, and subsequent efforts to develop the technological sector and reduce dependency on oil and gas, have not been as successful as initially hoped.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main business centres are Moscow, St Petersburg, Nizhny Novgorod, Novosibirsk and Vladivostok.</p>
<p>Formal business etiquette is very important and both men and women should wear smart, restrained business suits. Appearance is very important, especially in Moscow, where dark suits and polished shoes are essential.</p>
<p>Business visitors should start each meeting with a handshake and exchange business cards, printed in both English and Russian. Visitors should always wait for the senior Russian present to start the meeting and participate only when invited to. Referring to colleagues by their first name and patronymic is a good way to show knowledge of Russian culture.</p>
<p>Business is still largely a male pursuit in Russia, though Western businesswomen will be treated in the same way as male colleagues. If you have a meeting with a Russian woman, only reach out to shake hands if she offers her hand first, as unsolicited physical contact is considered rude.</p>
<p>If you are invited to a Russian home, bring an odd number of flowers (even numbers are reserved for funerals) and wine, champagne, or chocolates as a gift. Always remove your shoes at the front door (generally the host will offer house slippers to wear inside), and try not to discuss business unless the host initiates it. One should never refuse to drink a toast but beware of the effects of Russian vodka and learn when it is allowed to say no.</p>
<p>Directness that can verge on rudeness, and evasiveness that parades as politeness are part of the Russian style of negotiation, so be persistent if you need specific answers to your questions. Be sure to get firm and positive answers - preferably in writing. Russia is still an extremely bureaucratic country, so always be aware of the official regulations. Ignorance will not be accepted as an excuse if you break the rules, and the penalties can be severe.</p>
<p>It is bad form for visitors to criticise the host nation; concentrate instead on the positive aspects of your trip. Be aware that the Russian media is state-controlled so locals may have a different take on international affairs to the accepted view in other countries.</p><p>Mon-Fri 1000-1800, with a lengthy lunch break, usually from 1200-1400, during which no work is done - even telephones are left unanswered.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chamber of Commerce and Industry of the Russian Federation</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (495) 620 0009
					Website:http://www.tpprf.ru/
					Address: ,Ulitsa Ilyinka 6,Moscow,109012]]><b>Ministry for Economic Development and Trade for the Russian Federation - Department for Economic Co-operation with Europe</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (495) 694 0353
					Website:http://www.economy.gov.ru/
					Address: ,A/47 1-aya Tverskaya-Yamskaya Ulitsa,Moscow,125993]]><b>The Trade Delegation of the Russian Federation in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 8340 1907
					Website:http://www.rustradeuk.org/
					Address: London N6 6NL,32-3 Highgate West Hill,UK,]]><b>Russo-British Chamber of Commerce in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7403 1706
					Website:http://www.rbcc.co.uk/
					Address: 3rd Floor,Wilcox House,UK,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Russia's reputation for poor food is now, like so much else in the country, a thing of the past. In the cities it is possible to feast on anything that can be found in Western Europe, restaurants and cafes catering for all tastes and all pockets. With a vast array of international produce and dining experience, from fast food to high end, the visitor is left with an overwhelming selection. Move into the countryside and choice and quality are less guaranteed, but there's certainly no need to go hungry. It is worth noting that away from the big cities it is harder to find menus in English – so a splattering of Russian vocabulary is useful.</p><p>The kind of food visitors will eat from day to day depends on which city they are visiting and the time of year. Breakfast is often similar to that eaten in Scandinavian countries, with cold meats, boiled eggs and bread served with Russian tea. For the midday and evening meal, food is often more traditional, again depending on the region. Some form of soup is still a common staple meal. In Moscow, St Petersburg and many other larger cities, good quality (if expensive) international cuisine and fine dining eateries are readily available.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Kasha:</em>&nbsp;a staple breakfast dish, made with milk and oats, buckwheat or semolina. <br />
&bull; Blini: small pancakes filled with caviar, fish, melted butter or sour cream.<br />
&bull; <em>Ponchiki:&nbsp;</em>hot sugared doughnuts.<br />
&bull; <em>Pirozhky:&nbsp;</em>fried rolls with different fillings, usually meat. <br />
&bull; Borscht: a beetroot soup served hot with sour cream.<br />
&bull; <em>Pelmeni:&nbsp;</em>meat dumplings.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>City centre bars are usually open until the early hours. Drinking on the street is considered perfectly acceptable.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Hotels in Moscow and other large cities include a 10 to 15% service charge. Otherwise 10% is customary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>No age restriction on the consumption of alcohol, but you must be 18 or over to buy it.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Russia&rsquo;s reputation for providing a hedonistic nightlife second to none is richly deserved.  There are a wealth of nightclubs and bars to meet all needs, particularly in Moscow, St Petersburg and other larger cities. New venues pop up at the same speed with which others vanish, however presently in Moscow the following come highly recommended: Solyanka (attracts a very cool crowd), Rodnya (young edgy crowd), Simachev Bar (provides tasteful decadence) and the Strelka Bar (attracting the older intellectual set). In St Petersburg head to Groboedov (now legendary and very fashionable), Purga (where it&rsquo;s New Year&rsquo;s Eve every day of the year), and Dom Beat (for the hipsters).&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are plenty of alternatives for those looking for a more sedate experience. Theatre, circus, concert and variety performances provide more traditional evening entertainment. Tickets are available in advance or can be purchased from ticket booths immediately before performances. Visitors should note that prices can sometimes be higher than those paid by Russian nationals. Theatre repertoires can change on a nightly basis and in the course of one month, 30 different productions may be presented by the Bolshoi Ballet and Opera (<a href="http://www.bolshoi.ru/en" target="_blank">www.bolshoi.ru/en</a>). Visitors will be able to get more information from the service bureau of their hotel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Russia has come along way since the days of long queues and Soviet-style counter service, and the country is now something of a shopping heaven. Whether your tastes are expensive or more inclined to finding a bargain, everyone is catered for in equal measure - it that has vigorously embraced the market economy, and thus it&rsquo;s possible to get most things most of the time. A wide range of goods can be bought at outdoor markets, shopping centres, local shops and hypermarkets. Watches, cameras, wines and spirits, ceramics and glass, jewellery, toys and a good selection of porcelain may be bought in Moscow and St Petersburg, as can caviar and vodka at very reasonable prices.</p>
<p>Some products such as perfume and make-up should be avoided as they tend to be overpriced and of poor quality. Shops take payment in roubles and, usually, by credit card, but it should be noted that it&rsquo;s not always very easy to find English speaking assistance and it is advisable to shop around, as prices vary significantly.</p>
<p>Kholui and Palekh lacquered boxes make attractive souvenirs, while traditional Matryoshka dolls (wooden dolls within dolls) are widely available, but again greatly vary in price &ndash; head to kiosks often located in subways around metro stations for the best deals on potential souvenirs. Wooden cups, pottery figurines, engraved amber and lace are also popular options. Metal tea samovars make good souvenirs.</p><p>Most shops are open from Mon-Sat 0900-1900, with food shops also opening on Sundays. Stores that are open 24 hours a day are becoming more common.</p><p>Antiquities, valuables, works of art and manuscripts other than those offered for sale in souvenir shops may not be taken out of the Russian Federation without an export licence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are around 4,500 hotels in the Russian Federation, of which many now specialise in accommodating foreign guests. Many hotels meet international standards now, especially in big cities, but in its far-flung areas, accommodation can be very basic. Accommodation in Moscow and St Petersburg can range from luxurious (and expensive!) 5-star accommodation, to rough-and-ready rooms in cheaper accommodation. Independent boutique hotels are still something of a rarity, while large resorts and corporate hotel chains continue to move in. Direct reservations by clients are on the increase, although the majority are still booked through tour operators who often have access to the best rates. In lower classes of accommodation, it is advisable not to leave valuables in hotel rooms and to lock the door before going to sleep. A more reputable hotel may be safer, but it&rsquo;s still best to keep valuables on your person, or at the very least, in the hotel safe. Note that anyone travelling on a tourist visa to the Russian Federation must (officially at least) have accommodation arranged before arrival, although this is rarely enforced.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Several companies provide bed &amp; breakfast accommodation with English-speaking families in Moscow, St Petersburg and other cities. Russia isn&rsquo;t known for its effusive customer service however; expect brusque forthright service, and be prepared to have special requests flat out refused. Depending on where you stay, the d&eacute;cor may be a little more Soviet than you&rsquo;re used to, but in general, any lack in interior flourish is made up for by the cheaper prices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are around 4,500 hotels in the Russian Federation, of which many now specialise in accommodating foreign guests. Many hotels meet international standards now, especially in big cities, but in its far-flung areas, accommodation can be very basic. Accommodation in Moscow and St Petersburg can range from luxurious (and expensive!) 5-star accommodation, to rough-and-ready rooms in cheaper accommodation. Independent boutique hotels are still something of a rarity, while large resorts and corporate hotel chains continue to move in. Direct reservations by clients are on the increase, although the majority are still booked through tour operators who often have access to the best rates. In lower classes of accommodation, it is advisable not to leave valuables in hotel rooms and to lock the door before going to sleep. A more reputable hotel may be safer, but it&rsquo;s still best to keep valuables on your person, or at the very least, in the hotel safe. Note that anyone travelling on a tourist visa to the Russian Federation must (officially at least) have accommodation arranged before arrival, although this is rarely enforced.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are around 4,500 hotels in the Russian Federation, of which many now specialise in accommodating foreign guests. Many hotels meet international standards now, especially in big cities, but in its far-flung areas, accommodation can be very basic. Accommodation in Moscow and St Petersburg can range from luxurious (and expensive!) 5-star accommodation, to rough-and-ready rooms in cheaper accommodation. Independent boutique hotels are still something of a rarity, while large resorts and corporate hotel chains continue to move in. Direct reservations by clients are on the increase, although the majority are still booked through tour operators who often have access to the best rates. In lower classes of accommodation, it is advisable not to leave valuables in hotel rooms and to lock the door before going to sleep. A more reputable hotel may be safer, but it&rsquo;s still best to keep valuables on your person, or at the very least, in the hotel safe. Note that anyone travelling on a tourist visa to the Russian Federation must (officially at least) have accommodation arranged before arrival, although this is rarely enforced.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The highly developed health service provides free medical treatment for all citizens. If a traveller becomes ill during a booked tour, emergency treatment is free, with small sums to be paid for medicines and hospital treatment. If a longer stay than originally planned becomes necessary because of the illness, the visitor will have to pay for all further treatment. This can be very expensive; especially if treatment requires evacuation by air, as could be the case with any mountaineering or ski-related injuries. All visitors are strongly advised to have full medical cover that includes medical evacuation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is advisable to take a supply of medicines that are likely to be required (check first that they may be imported legally). If possible, take a doctor&amp;rsquo;s note which indicates what ailments the various medicines are for. Private medical care can be expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A negative HIV-test is required from travellers who stay longer than three months.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;In general, Russia does not pose any serious health risks when it comes to food. Use common sense and caution when deciding what might be safe to eat. Tap water is drinkable, although those with sensitive stomachs may want to stick to bottled water. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption.&amp;nbsp;Be wary of eating smoked fish from street vendors around Lake Baikal. Some travellers have reported cases of food poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations are sometimes recommended for Japanese B encephalitis, meningococcal meningitis and tick-borne encephalitis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Russian Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>Defender of the Fatherland Day :
							23 February </p><p>International Women's Day :
							08 March </p><p>Spring and Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							09 May </p><p>Russia Day :
							12 June </p><p>Unity Day :
							04 November </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Russia by persons aged 18 years and older without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 3L of alcohol.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of &euro;1,500 weighing up to 50kg.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arms and ammunition, undercover surveillance and intelligence gathering equipment, and narcotics.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arms and ammunition, undercover surveillance and intelligence gathering equipment, narcotics, objects of cultural value, plants and seeds, vegetables, raw precious metals, minerals, wild plants and animals, and endangered species (unless you have a permit).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rouble (RUB; symbol руб) = 100 kopeks. Notes are in denominations of 5,000, 1,000, 500, 100, 50, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of 10, 5, 2 and 1, and 50, 10, 5 and 1 kopeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency should only be exchanged at official bureaux and authorised banks. You will usually need your passport to change money. It is wise to retain all exchange receipts. Bureaux de change are numerous and easy to locate. Large shops and hotels offer their own exchange facilities. All major currencies can be converted in big cities. Outside the main cities, travellers are advised to carry US Dollars or Euros. It is illegal to settle accounts in hard currency and to change money unofficially, although in practice both sometimes happen and are not risky. However, in general everyone will want to be paid in Roubles.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major European and international credit and debit cards, including Visa and MasterCard, are accepted in the larger hotels and at foreign currency shops and restaurants, but cash (in Roubles) is more reliable. American Express cards are rarely accepted outside <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/moscow">Moscow</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-petersburg">St Petersburg</a>.</p><p>ATMs are widely available throughout Russia, although if you&rsquo;re venturing into rural areas, they may be less widespread so carry a reserve amount of cash. Most ATMs will offer English as well as Cryllic translations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cash is preferred. If carrying traveller's cheques, major currencies are accepted in big cities, but US Dollars and Euros are preferred elsewhere.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Russia, a passport valid for six months after the visa expires, and with at least two blank pages, is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Children under 18 travelling alone must submit a letter from one of their parents authorising them to travel unaccompanied and must also supply a copy of the parent's passport with their visa application.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa prices vary depending on the nationality of the applicant. See&nbsp;<a href="http://ru.vfsglobal.co.uk/" target="_blank">http://ru.vfsglobal.co.uk</a>&nbsp;or contact your nearest Russian embassy for details.</p>
<p>Single-entry tourist/business visa:&nbsp;&pound;50; double-entry visa: &pound;65; multiple-entry visa (business only): &pound;200.&nbsp;These are the current fees for UK nationals.&nbsp;</p>
<p>As well as the visa fee there is a service charge of &pound;38.40 for seven-day processing or &pound;45.60 for one-day processing. (Note that for next-day processing, the visa fees increase too.)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single- or double-entry tourist visa: 30 days.</p>
<p>Single- or double-entry business visa: 90 days.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Multiple-entry business visa: up to one year with unlimited entries/exits.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). You can apply initially online at&nbsp;<a href="https://visa.kdmid.ru" target="_blank">https://visa.kdmid.ru</a>. Handwritten visa forms, or online forms from other sources will not be accepted. The Russian embassy in the UK has outsourced its visa application to VFS Global (<a href="http://ru.vfsglobal.co.uk" target="_blank">http://ru.vfsglobal.co.uk</a>) so UK nationals should apply for a visa via this route; you must be able to visit a visa centre in London or Edinburgh in person for biometric data collection.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Processing times depend on nationality, type of visa and amount paid. Allow at least five working days for straightforward applications.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Depending on your nationality, you may be asked to provide bank statements from the previous three months when applying for a visa.</p>
<p>Australians, Americans and Canadians and EU-nationals no longer need a proof of income when applying for a visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[58.995311]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[55.371094]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>17,100,000 sq km (6,602,347 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>144,300,000 (2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>8.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Moscow.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Russian Federation covers almost twice the area of the USA, and reaches from the enclave of Kaliningrad in the west over the Urals and the vast Siberian plains to the Sea of Okhotsk in the east. The border between European Russia and Siberia (Asia) is formed by the Ural Mountains, the Ural River and the Manych Depression. All in all, Russia has 16 international borders with countries including Finland, Lithuania, USA, Japan, Ukraine, Azerbaijan and China.</p>
<p>European Russia extends from the North Polar Sea across the Central Russian Uplands to the Black Sea, the Northern Caucasus and the Caspian Sea. Siberia stretches from the West Siberian Plain across the Central Siberian Plateau to the Lena River and takes in the Sayan and Yablonovy ranges in the south. East of Siberia stretches the Russian Far East, a region almost as big as Siberia itself, running to the Pacific coast and including the vast Chukotka and Kamchatka peninsulas.</p>
<p>Given the vast size of the country, Russia&rsquo;s terrain is hugely variable. From the Siberian tundra to the mountains of the Urals, the beaches on the Black Sea coast, and the plains of western Russia, such variable geography means one can experience many different Russias.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mainly Christian with the Russian Orthodox Church being the largest Christian denomination. Muslim, Buddhist and Jewish minorities also exist.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is customary to shake hands when greeting someone, though never across a threshold. Company or business gifts are well received; if you&rsquo;re invited to someone&rsquo;s home do bring a token gift, but avoid clearing your plate when eating; leaving some food is considered as a good sign.</p>
<p>Conservative wear is suitable for most places &ndash; women will need to cover shoulders and wear long skirts to enter an orthodox church &ndash;  and the seasonal weather should always be borne in mind. Smoking and drinking is widely acceptable, but the former has been prohibited in restaurants and cafes since 2014.</p>
<p>Russian society is still highly patriarchal and hierarchical; this may be reflected in chivalrous acts (men holding doors open for women for example) but it may also mean that women are taken less seriously, and engaging in &lsquo;unfeminine&rsquo; behaviour may be interpreted wrongly, although being a visitor may get you some leeway. Be careful with gestures &ndash; in Russia, giving the &lsquo;thumbs up&rsquo; sign is an insult not an &lsquo;OK&rsquo;.<br />
<br />
It is prohibited to take photographs of any military installation and/or establishments or sites of strategic importance. Failure to abide by this could result in police arrest.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. Russia uses a standard European plug with two round pins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Vladimir Putin since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Russia has been through staggering upheaval with consistently profound consequences &ndash; this is one place where history does not pass by quietly. Populated by Slavic tribes, by the mid-ninth century the first East Slavic state of Kievan Rus&rsquo; had emerged, stretching from Kiev in the south to Novgorod in the north, before it fell to the Mongol invasion during 13th century. In the 16th century under the rule of Ivan IV (the Terrible), Russia became a unified state and began the conquest of Siberia. Three centuries of Romanov rule commenced in 1613 when Michael Romanov was elected as tsar. Peter the Great has emerged as the most well known of this dynasty, transferring the country&rsquo;s capital from Moscow to the newly built St Petersburg in 1703 as he looked to the countries of the west for inspiration to create a country that was their equal.</p>
<p>From 1815, following the Napoleonic Wars, Russia saw a series of autocratic leaders and growing revolutionary tension, which came to a head during the reign of Nicholas II, the final Emperor. The October Revolution and death of the tsar and his family in 1917 lead to the formation of the Soviet Union, the world&rsquo;s first Communist state.</p>
<p>The death of the revolutionary leader Lenin saw Joseph Stalin emerge as the dominant force in the Communist Party and the start of Russia&rsquo;s most brutal period in which collectivisation and rapid industrialisation were punctuated by purges and show trials. During the years prior to WWII Stalin dragged the Soviet Union to a position of superpower on the world stage, but at enormous human cost. The post war years ushered in the Cold War &ndash; a tense standoff between the Soviet Union and the West, which only came to a close with the break up of the Soviet Union in 1991.</p>
<p>After the chaos of Yeltsin&rsquo;s presidency in the 1990s, Vladimir Putin has maintained a firm grip over the Kremlin since winning the 2000 presidential election. When Dmitry Medvedev was elected President in 2008 Putin became Prime Minister, but returned to the presidency in 2012. For all his efforts to present a modern Russia to the world Putin seems increasingly content to plough his own furrow &ndash; deploying troops to Ukraine in 2014 and encouraging the accession of Crimea.</p>
<p>Russia&rsquo;s intervention in the Syrian Civil War in support of the Assad regime against Islamic State continues to divide opinion.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; Russia&rsquo;s Soyuz rockets are the only means of transport for astronauts to the International Space Station.</p>
<p>&bull; In 2002,&nbsp;<em>Russian Ark</em> became the first feature-length film to be shot in a single take.</p>
<p>&bull; Russia&rsquo;s national tree is the birch.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Russia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+7 (495) 956 7200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-moscow</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+7 (495) 956 7200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and Fri 1400-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Smolenskaya Naberezhnaya 10<br/>121099 Moscow<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Russian Federation in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 939‑8907 </p><p><b>Website:</b>https://washington.mid.ru/en/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 939‑8907 </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2650 Wisconsin Avenue NW<br/>Washington DC<br/>NW 20007<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Russian Federation in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>Embassy: (020) 7229 6412  Consulate: (020) 3668 7474</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.rusemb.org.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>Embassy: (020) 7229 6412  Consulate: (020) 3668 7474</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>6/7 Kensington Palace Gardens<br/>London<br/>W8 4QP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Russia is at once breathtaking and baffling. Winston Churchill&rsquo;s much-quoted line that the world&rsquo;s largest nation represented &ldquo;a riddle wrapped in a mystery inside an enigma&rdquo; is as true today as it was back then.</p>
<p>Monumental in every respect, it&rsquo;s a land where burnished imperial splendour coexists with icy Siberian tundra, where timeworn Soviet-era monuments backdrop uber-hip urban cultures and where everything from the ruling party downwards functions in its own, impenetrably Russian, way. </p>
<p>The west of the country draws the most visitor attention, thanks to the presence of two extraordinary cities. St Petersburg and Moscow serve up sweeping postcard sights by the dozen. Moscow is the rapidly beating heart of the &ldquo;New Russia,&rdquo; where Asia and Europe combine to create a boisterous, enigmatic metropolis on a grand scale. St Petersburg, meanwhile, with its living film-set of palaces, cathedrals and waterways, is the grandest and most European of Russia&rsquo;s cities, yet still retains a deeply complex character. </p>
<p>Exploration beyond these two main hubs, however, is well advised. The Golden Ring, a collection of ancient towns northeast of Moscow, still has plenty of period architecture and is easily accessed from the capital.  By cruising along the mighty River Volga, meanwhile, it&rsquo;s possible to travel south towards the Caspian Sea and see the country beyond its increasingly westernised veneer. And those heading east, into Siberia, will find a land of varied, often sublime natural beauty. From Lake Baikal to the old imperial city of rkutsk, and from the mountains of the Altai and the shamans of Tuva, Siberia has many secrets. </p>
<p>A combination of the above is drawing an increasing number of tourists to the Russian Federation &ndash; that it remains as obscure and mysterious as ever is all part of the charm. As the poet Fyodor Tyutchev once said: &ldquo;Russia cannot be understood.&rdquo;</p><p>Russia is at once breathtaking and baffling &ndash; much as you might expect from a country so colossal that it stretches unhindered from the Baltic Sea to the North Pacific. Churchill&rsquo;s much-quoted line that the world&rsquo;s largest nation represented &ldquo;a riddle wrapped in a mystery inside an enigma&rdquo; is as true today as it was then.</p>
<p>Monumental in every respect, it&rsquo;s a land where burnished imperial splendour coexists with icy Siberian tundra, where timeworn Soviet-era monuments backdrop uber-hip urban cultures and where everything from the ruling party downwards functions in its own, impenetrably Russian, way.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
