<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Rwanda" ColCode="rwa" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="rw" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Rwanda]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite its proximity to the equator, due to the high altitude of most of the country, Rwanda has a temperate climate with temperatures not often climbing above 25C. The long dry season is from June to September and there are two annual rainy seasons, the first from mid-March until the beginning of June and small rains from mid-September to December. The best time for gorilla and monkey tracking is the dry season - if only to spare you getting drenched (you can still see them in the rain, they just get a bit grumpy). The dry season is also good if you want to see game in Akagera National Park because thirst will draw the animals to the watering holes. You will also find at this time the roads are less dangerous and the risk of malaria is lower. The rainy season is the best time to see chimpanzees and is also the time when the place is at its most lush and green.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights are required for most of the year with warmer clothes for cooler upland evenings. Rainwear is advisable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Akagera Aviation (<a href="http://www.akageraaviation.com" target="_blank">www.akageraaviation.com</a>) provides helicopter flights all over the country. Rwandair (<a href="http://www.rwandair.com" target="_blank">www.rwandair.com</a>) flies internally from Kigali to Kamembe Airport, near the southeastern town of Cyangugu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can hire a boat to take you from Gisenyi to Kibuye if you ask at one of the lakeside hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a lot of work being done to improve the roads. In some places you can find smooth tarmac, while in others you can expect to bump along pot-holed dirt paths. Take extra care at night, as headlight use is erratic. During rainy season some roads can become impassable.</p>r<p>Some local roads are not paved and a 4-wheel drive vehicle is needed. There can be landslides on some of the major roads during annual rainfall in spring and autumn.</p><p>Minibus taxis provide links to and from all towns and some villages. Although it is not usual for foreigners to travel this way, they are quite safe and efficient. However you have to wait until they are full before departure if you get on at the start of the route. The Virunga Express and Onatracom Express provide more direct intercity links.</p><p>Taxis can be found in large towns and cities; look for the official orange stripe. Fares are reasonable, but should be agreed in advance (ask a local if you think you are being overcharged). Tipping is not expected.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required. An entry permit is needed if you have travelled from outside the country, plus your insurance document and driving licence.</p><p>Rwanda drives on the right. It is illegal to use a mobile phone while driving unless with a hands-free set. Seat belts must be worn in the front. Speed limits are 40kph (25mph) in the city and 60kph (37mph) outside the city. If the car in front is using the left indicator it often means it's not safe to overtake; the right indicator tells you the road ahead is clear.</p><p>Most car hire companies can provide you with a number to call in the event of a breakdown. In case of accident, dial 113.</p><p>Europcar hires cars with a driver, or there's a choice of several local companies, with or without a driver. You can find these listed in the Eye magazine given away at the airport and in hotels (<a href="http://www.theeye.co.rw" target="_blank">www.theeye.co.rw</a>).</p><p>Bicycle and scooter taxis are the quickest and cheapest way to get around in the towns, but they are risky.</p><p>Rwanda drives on the right. It is illegal to use a mobile phone while driving unless with a hands-free set. Seat belts must be worn in the front. Speed limits are 40kph (25mph) in the city and 60kph (37mph) outside the city. If the car in front is using the left indicator it often means it's not safe to overtake; the right indicator tells you the road ahead is clear.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kenya Airways (<a href="http://www.kenya-airways.com" target="_blank">www.kenya-airways.com</a>) have flights to Rwanda via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/nairobi">Nairobi</a>, KLM (<a href="http://www.klm.com" target="_blank">www.klm.com</a>) flies via Amsterdam,&nbsp;Brussels Airlines (<a href="http://www.brusselsairlines.com" target="_blank">www.brusselsairlines.com</a>) flies via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brussels">Brussels</a> and Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="http://www.ethiopianairlines.com" target="_blank">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>) flies via Addis Ababa. The national carrier is RwandAir (<a href="http://www.rwandair.com" target="_blank">www.rwandair.com</a>), which flies to the major capitals in the region.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 11 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 17 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Kigali International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.caa.gov.rw<p>The airport, 12km (7.5 miles) east of Kigali (journey time - 25 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rwanda shares its borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/uganda">Uganda</a> to the north, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/congo">Democratic Republic of Congo</a> (DRC) to the east, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/burundi">Burundi</a> to the south and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tanzania">Tanzania</a> to the west. There are roads from all four countries, although the best route is considered to be through Uganda. Although the route into Rwanda from Goma is considered safe, the DRC is still best avoided due to internal conflicts.</p>
<p>If you are driving your own vehicle you need to buy a an entry permit and insurance at the border. Jaguar Executive Coaches (tel:&nbsp;+256 782 811 128, in Uganda) runs regular services to Kampala, while Yahoo Car Express (tel: +250 0830 5334) has services to Bujumbura. Travelling to Tanzania is a little more tricky as there are few major towns on the northeastern side of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The country code is 250. There are no area codes. As mobile phones become more popular, landlines are becoming disused. If you want to contact home more than a couple of times it is best to get a local SIM - do check that you can use it to make international calls. You sometimes have to activate the message centre in order to send texts, again check when you buy the SIM.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handsets are cheap at about £10 and local SIM cards are widely available from street vendors and shops. The two main mobile providers are MTN and Tigo. To make an international call you need to dial 000 before the country code (instead of the usual 00). Both international texts and calls from local mobiles are much cheaper than the roaming charges.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wireless internet is now available throughout the country, either by using a dongle, which can be purchased in Kigali and other major towns, or by using hotspots. MTN hotspots are widespread and you can access them using your mobile phone credit if you have bought an MTN SIM card. There are also many internet cafes in Kigali and other large towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the media is state-owned and there is limited press freedom. The main newspaper is the <em>New Times</em> and the regional <em>East African</em> is also widely distributed. International newspapers may be found in upmarket hotels and copies of <em>Time</em> and <em>The Economist</em> are sold by street vendors. Many of Rwanda's broadcasters are government-owned. The first private radio station was launched in 2004.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes approximately two weeks.</p><p>(Kigali) Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1400-1700, Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Attend the Rwanda Film Festival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Founded in 2004, the Rwanda Film Festival is held every July at locations across the country. Most of the screenings take place in venues around Kigali, but, as part of a drive to bring culture to the farthest corners of this country, pop-up cinemas are erected in rural Rwanda, showing everything from Hollywood blockbusters to contemporary African documentaries. A highlight in the country's calendar.</p>]]><p><b>Chill out in Kibuye</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located on the limpid shores of Lake Kivu, this idyllic resort is a perfect place to unwind. It's also unremittingly beautiful: steep, forested slopes rise from crystalline waters, which are dotted with canoes and fishing boats. The town itself is full of characterful, with a lively market, and there are a burgeoning range of hotels and restaurants right on the shore. It's a great place for swimming, kayaking or just kicking back.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Rwanda’s cool capital, Kigali</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Far from being haunted by its tumultuous past, Kigali is quietly getting on with it. Rwanda's capital is abuzz with hip new bars, restaurants and hotels. Clean and composed, Kigali is very safe city and its rising skyline reflects the country's lofty ambitions. Head to Hillywood, where talented moviemakers are helping shape Rwanda's burgeoning film industry, and visit Nyamirambo, where colourful shops sell second hand gear and offer an authentic slice of local life.</p>]]><p><b>Feed your brain in Butare</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The intellectual capital of the country, Butare is home to Rwanda's national university. The most prominent tourist attraction here is the superb National Museum, which houses perhaps the finest ethnographic collection in East Africa. Absorbing displays of traditional artefacts are illuminated by a selection of turn-of-the-century monochrome photographs, providing insight not only into pre-colonial lifestyles, but also into the subsequent development of Rwanda as a modern African state. Butare also boasts craft shops and a botanical garden.</p>]]><p><b>Go gorilla trekking in Volcanoes National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gorilla trekking in Volcanoes National Park is Rwanda's biggest tourist attraction – and tops many a nature lover's bucket list. Permits must be booked in advance (only 80 are issued daily) and cost $750, which does price many people out of the trek, alas. Those lucky enough to obtain permits are assigned guides and armed guards (to protect them from marauding buffalo) and get to spend an incredible hour observing one of the habituated gorilla families.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the beach in sunny Gisenyi</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rwanda may be landlocked, but you can still hit the beach in Gisenyi: a pretty market town on the edge of Lake Kivu. As well as fine slithers of golden sand, the town lays claim to a large brewery, which proudly produces Rwanda's celebrated beer: Primus. Bustling Gisenyi is on the border with neighbouring Democratic Republic of Congo (the frontier is an attraction in itself) and boasts hot springs nearby.</p>]]><p><b>Look for golden monkeys in Volcanoes National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Volcanoes National Park is best known for its mountain gorillas, but visitors can also go in search of golden monkeys, which are also endangered. These elusive creatures hang out quite low down in the vertiginous national park, so are a good warm up for their loftier-living cousins. A permit to see them is also considerably cheaper than it is for the gorillas.</p>]]><p><b>Pay your respects at the Kigali Genocide Memorial Centre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In 1994 approximately one million Tutsis and scores of Hutus – the two main groups in Rwanda – were murdered during the ghastly Rwandan Genocide. The Kigali Genocide Memorial Centre pays tribute to these victims (many of who are buried in a mass grave outside), and chronicles the events that led to the slaughter. It's heart breaking, of course, but there are uplifting tales amongst the bleakness.</p>]]><p><b>Seek chimpanzees and colobus monkeys in Nyungwe Forest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nyungwe Forest National Park is one of the largest remaining high-altitude rainforests in Africa and is home to the world's largest troop of colobus monkeys, which have a distinctive black and white colouring. A trek to spot them could have you surrounded by hundreds of the pretty primates, as well as chimpanzees, which are often perched high up in ficus trees. If you're really lucky, guides might even show you the local mona monkeys too.</p>]]><p><b>Take a safari in Akagera National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>After the genocide Akagera National Park was overrun by returning refugees and much of the wildlife was wiped out. But the Rwandan government, with the help of Africa Parks, has rehomed these displaced people and begun restoring Akagera to its former glory – its biggest success to date came in 2015 with the reintroduced of lions. Big cats are the star attraction, but visitors also have the chance to see elephants, leopards, crocodiles, hippos, giraffes, apes and some 500 species of bird.</p>]]><p><b>Trek to Dian Fossey’s grave in Volcanoes National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps nobody has done more to conserve mountain gorillas than Dian Fossey, an American zoologist who gave up her life to study the primates in Rwanda. Fossey moved to Volcanoes National Park in 1967, where she fought tooth and nail to protect the critically endangered species. She succeeded, but was murdered in the process by an unknown assailant. Her gravestone has become a pilgrimage site for naturalists, who trek four-hours through the steamy forest to pay their respects. Guides are essential.</p>]]><p><b>Walk in the clouds in Nyungwe Forest</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Opened in 2010, this lofty canopy walk is the first of its kind in the region. Hovering a hair-raising 50m (164ft) above the forest floor, this swaying walkway is not for the faint hearted, but it does offer superb views across the rainforest canopy and, if you're lucky, you might come face to face with rare birds and monkeys.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$5.9 billion (projected 2010).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Tea, coffee, pyrethrum, hides, tin ore.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Foodstuffs, machinery and equipment, steel, petroleum products, cement and construction material.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Belgium, France, Germany, Kenya and South Africa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rwanda's economy, which is based on subsistence agriculture, was devastated by the massacres of 1994, the huge refugee populations that resulted, political upheaval and, since then, ongoing fighting in several parts of the country.<br /><br />Plantains, sweet potatoes, cassava and beans are grown for domestic consumption; tea and coffee are the principal cash crops and there is extensive livestock farming. Some rice and sugar plantations have also been developed.<br /><br />Rwanda has some mineral deposits - principally tin ores, but also several ores containing rare metals such as tungsten and tantalum, which are in heavy demand in the world market. Extraction of the large natural gas reserves discovered beneath Lake Kivu has begun, although it has been disrupted by local fighting.<br /><br />The industrial sector produces tobacco, metal goods, chemicals, rubber and plastics. In the service sector, the embryonic tourism industry (geared towards ecotourism) has had to restart from scratch as a result of the 1994 genocide and subsequent events.<br /><br />Given the political situation, exacerbated by a series of poor harvests during the late 1990s, it is hardly surprising therefore that Rwanda continues to rely heavily on international aid. <br /><br />A new Structural Adjustment Programme was begun in 1998, followed by an ambitious privatisation programme: both are being conducted under the supervision of the IMF and World Bank. In 2002, telecommunications and government-owned tea plantations were put up for sale. The results so far have been quite good: the economy grew 5.8% in 2005 and inflation was 6.7%. But, like most sub-Saharan African economies, Rwanda is especially vulnerable to commodity price movements; these are presently at a very low level.<br /><br />Aid donors have also promised further assistance conditional on Rwanda pulling its troops out of the Democratic Republic of Congo. The main regional cooperation mechanism for Rwanda is the Common Market for Eastern and Southern Africa.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight suits are advised and appointments are necessary. Best time to visit is from April to October or December to January. Knowledge of French is useful as only a few executives speak English. It is also useful to learn one or two greetings in Kinyarwanda, this will be appreciated. <br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1230 and 1330-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie du Rwanda</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 83538/41.
					Website:
					Address: ,,Kigali,BP 319]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the population in Rwanda live off subsistence farming and so their meals rely heavily on starchy crops such as potato, maize and cassava. This is generally served with kidney beans and cabbage and where meat can be afforded it is most often goat. However, the restaurants of Kigali and other towns will generally serve grilled meat with french fries and sometimes rice with spicy stews.<br/><br>Hotels generally serve a reasonable choice of European dishes, while there are Chinese, Greek, Indian, Italian and Middle Eastern restaurants. Some restaurants also serve Franco-Belgian cuisine and African dishes. A fairly good selection of beers, spirits and wines is available. Beer is also brewed locally.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull;You will see brochettes on most menus, these are basically a skewer of your chosen meat or fish served with rice or chips.</p>
<p>&bull;  Tilapia is a white fish found in Lake Kivu and also farmed locally and appears often on menus.  </p>
<p>&bull;<em>Matoke</em> is cooked plantain, and may come when you are expecting potatoes (and sometimes doesn&rsquo;t taste much different).</p>
<p>&bull;Primus is the local beer of choice. Mutzig is very similar but more expensive and often comes in large 700ml bottles.  </p>
<p>&bull;The local banana wine is for the brave, it is called <em>urwangwa</em> and you should be able to pick up a bottle in a supermarket to try in the privacy of your room</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>There is no clear principle on tipping in Rwanda, but most staff in the bigger hotels have come to expect it, as have guides and trackers. A general rule is to tip 10% in restaurants if you feel inclined and give $5 - $10 to guides, trackers and porters.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the major hotels will have live entertainment in the form of traditional dancing and live music. The best local nightlife is found in Kigali, where the young professionals head to the top-floor bars of the MTN centre. There are now several nightclubs, with African, Congolese and Western music. The biggest nightclub in town is New Cadillac, which is open until dawn from Wednesday to Sunday. There are also some live music bars with food and dancing available. The French Cultural Centre runs a variety of activities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best place to buy souvenirs is the Caplaki craft co-operative in Kigali, where a number of craft traders have gotten together to build colourful wooden huts stocking a wide selection of handicrafts. Here you can find wood carvings including traditional masks; raffia work baskets, mobiles and jewellery; musical instruments; paintings; batik; bags, scarves and beading. It is all of good quality, but be prepared to bargain. ln town, the UTC building (Union Trade Centre) houses a good supermarket for buying coffees and teas to take home, and also stocks books, there are also a number of clothes shops and a gallery. Plastic bags are banned in Rwanda, so it is best to take a strong bag with you when shopping, particularly if buying bottles of beer, otherwise everything will be given to you in brown paper bags.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0830-1300 and 1400-1730, Sat 0830-1230.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There have been a lot of improvements in hotel options in the past five years, and you can now get quite high-end accommodation in Kigali, Muzanse, Gisenyi, Kibuye and Nyungwe. It is harder to find something in the $40 to $90 a night bracket - although there are cheap hotels to be found in most towns, they are usually where drivers and guides stay and are pretty basic. <br />
<br />
The Serena in Kigali has been refurbished and is now very smart. The Milles Collines of Hotel Rwanda fame is also still drawing a discerning crowd, although a little tired in places. There is also a Serena in Giseyni, which is very popular with locals at the weekend.<br />
<br />
<strong>Luxury:</strong> There are now a number of luxury options in Rwanda. Virunga and Silverback lodge are excellent choices for the Volcanoes National Park, but are very pricey. There is also a new luxury lodge in Nyungwe Forest run by Dubai World, and Belgian-run Cormoron Lodge in Kibuye is comprised of wooden huts in a picturesque setting.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Outside the main towns there are guest houses, which are generally cheaper than hotels. There is a solar-powered house at the edge of the A'Kagera National Park.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There have been a lot of improvements in hotel options in the past five years, and you can now get quite high-end accommodation in Kigali, Muzanse, Gisenyi, Kibuye and Nyungwe. It is harder to find something in the $40 to $90 a night bracket - although there are cheap hotels to be found in most towns, they are usually where drivers and guides stay and are pretty basic. <br />
<br />
The Serena in Kigali has been refurbished and is now very smart. The Milles Collines of Hotel Rwanda fame is also still drawing a discerning crowd, although a little tired in places. There is also a Serena in Giseyni, which is very popular with locals at the weekend.<br />
<br />
<strong>Luxury:</strong> There are now a number of luxury options in Rwanda. Virunga and Silverback lodge are excellent choices for the Volcanoes National Park, but are very pricey. There is also a new luxury lodge in Nyungwe Forest run by Dubai World, and Belgian-run Cormoron Lodge in Kibuye is comprised of wooden huts in a picturesque setting.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There have been a lot of improvements in hotel options in the past five years, and you can now get quite high-end accommodation in Kigali, Muzanse, Gisenyi, Kibuye and Nyungwe. It is harder to find something in the $40 to $90 a night bracket - although there are cheap hotels to be found in most towns, they are usually where drivers and guides stay and are pretty basic. <br />
<br />
The Serena in Kigali has been refurbished and is now very smart. The Milles Collines of Hotel Rwanda fame is also still drawing a discerning crowd, although a little tired in places. There is also a Serena in Giseyni, which is very popular with locals at the weekend.<br />
<br />
<strong>Luxury:</strong> There are now a number of luxury options in Rwanda. Virunga and Silverback lodge are excellent choices for the Volcanoes National Park, but are very pricey. There is also a new luxury lodge in Nyungwe Forest run by Dubai World, and Belgian-run Cormoron Lodge in Kibuye is comprised of wooden huts in a picturesque setting.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are severely limited and extremely overburdened. Almost all medical facilities in Kigali were destroyed during the civil war, but the situation is now improving and most hospitals function to an acceptable level. However, medical insurance, including cover for emergency repatriation, is essential. Visitors are advised to bring their own personal medication. In emergency dial 912 for an ambulance.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food is generally safe to eat if well-cooked and hot. If in doubt, veer towards larger restaurants in cities and those aimed at tourists, which will have undergone government safety checks. Avoid buying food from the side of the road and don't drink tap water. Use bottled water or otherwise boil or sterilise. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Schistosomaisis, otherwise known as bilharzia, a parasite that lives in fresh water and enters the body through intact skin is present in the country. If you do swim in lake Kivu, then source the treatment - a drug called Praziquantel - locally and take it six weeks to three months after your return. Alternatively you can be tested at a tropical medicine centre on your return.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Heroes' Day :
							01 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Genocide Memorial Day :
							07 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							01 July </p><p>Liberation Day :
							04 July </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Patriotism Day :
							01 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Rwanda by persons over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 250g of tobacco products.<br />
&bull; 1L or spirits or 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 500ml of perfume and eau de toilette, of which up to a quarter may be perfume.<br />
&bull; Goods up to US$500 in value.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited goods include counterfeit coins and notes, pornography, matches made with white phosphorus, distilled beverages such as absinthe, soaps and cosmetics containing mercury, used tyres, and counterfeit goods.</p>
<p>Restricted goods include animal traps, unwrought precious metals and stones, arms and ammunition, historical artefacts, ivory, rhino horn, tortoise shell, coral, and non-indigenous species of fish.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Game trophies can only be exported with special permission of the Game Department.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rwanda Franc (RWF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of RWF 5,000, 2,000, 1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of RWF100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. US dollars are the currency of choice but do make sure you bring newer (and undamaged or torn) bills.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted at major hotels and restaurants in Kigali. MasterCard and Visa are the preferred cards.</p><p>There are several ATMs in Kigali but not all of them acept foreign cards.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Only a few banks in Rwanda accepts American Express travellers cheques.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1400-1700, Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for six months from the date of entry is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above to enter Rwanda. Passports must also have a one blank page for stamps.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visas are valid for 72 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival (if eligible): US$50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa on arrival/single-entry visa: 30 days; multiple-entry/tourist visa: 90 days; East Africa tourist visa: multiple entries within three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy/high commission) or online via&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.migration.gov.rw/">www.migration.gov.rw</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow three days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All visa applicants must be able to show proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you wish to extend your visa, you must apply to the Directorate General of Immigration and Emigration in Kigali before your current visa expires. You are given a period of grace whereby you can leave the country up to five days after your visa expires without penalty. Beyond five days, you risk paying a fine and being refused a further visa.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-2.003012]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[29.923015]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>26,338 sq km (10,169 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>11,882,766 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>480.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Kigali.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rwanda is a small mountainous country in central Africa, bordered to the north by Uganda, to the east by Tanzania, to the south by Burundi and to the west by the Democratic Republic of Congo. The country is divided by great peaks of up to 3,000m (9,842ft), which run across the country from north to south. The Virunga volcanoes, rising steeply from Lake Kivu in the west, slope down first to a hilly central plateau and further eastwards to an area of marshy lakes around the upper reaches of the A'Kagera River, where the A'Kagera National Park is situated.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic 57%, Protestant 26%, Adventist 11%, Islam 5%, indigenous beliefs 0.1%, none 2%</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlike other African countries, Rwanda does not tolerate corruption and you are unlikely to encounter it. You will cause offence if you offer a bribe. Begging is strongly discouraged by the government and you are advised not to give money or plastic bottles to children who ask. You will not see street children in Kigali because there is a rehabilitation centre where they are sent to learn vocational skills. You will also not see litter anywhere in the country and dropping litter is frowned upon. Once a month there is a national clean-up day dedicated to the maintenance of shared areas. Eating and smoking in the street is also considered rude.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are most commonly used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Anastase Murekezi since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Paul Kagame since 2000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To set Rwanda's recent history in a context, you need to go as far back as the late 13th century when pastoral Tutsi tribes arrived from the south and conquered the Hutu and Twa inhabitants of Rwanda, establishing a feudal kingdom.</p>
<p>The Rwandan population was originally made up of 18 different tribes and the terms Bahutu, Batutsi and Batwa were largely socio-economic groupings with the Tutsis as the wealthiest, the Hutus as the farmers and the Batwa pygmies as the marginalised group.</p>
<p>A unified state was established by King Kigeri Rwabuguri during the 19th century, but this lasted only until 1890 when Rwanda was annexed as a province of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_East_Africa" target="_blank">German East Africa</a>. When the Belgians came in the 1920s (after what turned out to be a brief occupation by Germany) they embarked on an aggressive campaign to divide the population into three different groups.</p>
<p>In an act that helped sow the seeds of genocide, the Belgians sponsored the dominance of the Tutsi minority at the expense of the Hutu, but were forced, in the 1960s, to concede independence under majority Hutu rule. Violence between Hutus and Tutsis started to flare up, culminating in <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-13431486" target="_blank">the Rwandan Genocide of 1994</a>: a 100 days of carnage during which some one million Tutsis and moderate Hutus were murdered, while the international community looked on.</p>
<p>Nowadays, peace prevails in Rwanda. The distinctions between Hutus and Tutsis have been resigned to the history books: everyone is simply Rwandan. Rather than being haunted by its bloody past, Rwanda has moved on to become one of Africa&rsquo;s most progressive nations. In 2013 there were more women in parliament here than any other county on Earth and the country is embarking on a series pioneering conservation and environmental initiatives.</p>
<p>Justice is still being served. UN war tribunals are still bringing the architects of the genocide to justice, while an intense programme of education continues to ensure ethnic violence never occurs here again.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong> <br />
&bull; Once a month Rwandans participate in Umuganda &ndash; a day of national housekeeping where everyone, including the president, cleans the streets.<br />
&bull; Rwanda was one of the first countries in the world to ban plastic bags.<br />
&bull; <a href="http://www.worldtravelguide.net/holidays/editorial-feature/feature/remaking-rwanda">Lions were successfully reintroduced to the country in 2015</a> after an absence of 16 years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Rwanda]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>2525 56000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/rwanda</p><p><b>Tel:</b>2525 56000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1200 and 1300-1700; Fri 0800-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Kacyiru-Sud<br/>Parcelle No 1131, Boulevard de l'Umuganda<br/>Kigali<br/>BP 576<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Rwanda in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 232 2882.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.rwandaembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 232 2882.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1875 Conneticut Avenue NW, Suite 418<br/>Washington<br/>DC 20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rwanda High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 722 49 832.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.rwandahc.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 722 49 832.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>120-22 Seymour Place<br/>London<br/>W1H 1NR<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Known as the 'land of a thousand hills', Rwanda is making the headlines again &ndash; and this time, it&rsquo;s for all the right reasons. With the devastating genocide behind it, this small, landlocked nation has emerged as one of Africa&rsquo;s most exciting destinations. A tangible sense of optimism resonates from its towns, cities and colourful villages, which welcome foreign visitors with wide smiles and open arms.</p>
<p>The transformation of this country has been remarkable. In 1994 nearly one million inhabitants were slaughtered senselessly in their homes, churches and streets. It was one of the darkest days in modern African history and, at the time, it was almost unthinkable that Rwanda could bounce back.</p>
<p>But is has. In fact the country has even blazed a trail for others to follow, particularly when it comes to gender equality (in 2014 there were more women in parliament here than anywhere else in the world) and conservation.</p>
<p>Indeed the country is a pioneer in eco tourism, which it has used to fund conservation projects such as mountain gorilla protection in the steamy forests of Volcanoes National Park. Trekking to see these endangered primates is the main attraction in Rwanda, where the famous zoologist, Dian Fossey, studied the great apes and inspired the Hollywood film <em>Gorillas in the Mist</em>.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not all about gorillas, though. Nyungwe Forest is one of the largest remaining rainforests in Africa and is home to 13 primates, including chimpanzees and colobus monkeys, as well as rare orchids and nearly 300 species of bird. And, although landlocked, Rwanda still manages to serve up a coastal vibe on the shores of Lake Kivu, with beaches at Gisenyi and coves at Kibuye.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s also worth spending a few days in the capital, Kigali: a cool, calm and cosmopolitan city, whose rising skyline reflects the country&rsquo;s lofty ambitions. Join hip young things in Hillywood, the beating heart of Kigali&rsquo;s fledgling film industry, or imbibe the vibe in the city&rsquo;s burgeoning collection of bars, restaurants and hotels, which are helping put this country back on the map.</p><p>Known as the land of 1,000 hills, this country couldn't be further from the cliched African image of arid deserts and dry bush. Winding roads hug verdant slopes, every inch carved into fields with crops ranging from banana trees to maize.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
