<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Saba" ColCode="sab" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="xq" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Saba]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hot, but tempered by cooling trade winds. The annual mean temperature is 27°C (80°F), varying by no more than two or three degrees throughout the year; average rainfall is 1,667mm. The temperature can drop to 16°C (60°F) on winter evenings. When climbing Mount Scenery, the temperature will drop by approximately 0.2°C (0.4°F) for each 100m (330ft) gained in altitude.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights and cottons are worn throughout the year. Umbrellas or light waterproofs are needed for the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saba has one road, 15km (9.5 miles) long that bisects the island from the airport to Fort Bay.</p>r<p>Taxis are readily available on Saba and are the most popular way for travellers to get around aside from walking.  Fares are fixed at government approved rates; there is a 25% increase for journeys after 9pm.</p><p>A national driving licence is acceptable.</p><p>Available at the island's only shopping mall, the Breadline Plaza. However driving may be difficult as Saba's main road is steep and driving conditions are often dangerous.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no public transport on the island. Walking, hitching and taxis are the most popular options. Hitchhiking is common on Saba but you should still exercise caution. If walking, bear in mind that distances may not be far, but it usually involves walking up and down steep inclines, so it's important to wear appropriate footwear.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines serving Saba include Winair (<a href="http://www.fly-winair.sx" target="_blank">www.fly-winair.sx</a>). The main airport is Juancho Yrausquin (SAB) at Cove Bay. The runway, at 400m  (1,300ft) is one of the shortest in the world. All international air travel is via St Maarten. Airlines flying to St Maarten include Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) and Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>&nbsp;- 14 hours (including stopovers); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours 45 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$10.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Juancho Yrausquin Airport </b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Small boats operate from the Leo A Chance Pier at Fort Bay. There are regular ferry services to St Maarten (journey time - 1 hour 30 minutes). Cruise ships call occasionally.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Networks are operated by Windward Islands Cellular and East Caribbean Cellular and roaming agreements exist, so many mobile handsets should work on the island. GSM phones will need to be unlocked before they will work.  Most hotels provide long distance dialling worldwide. There are also phone booths in Windwardside and The Bottom.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is currently one internet cafe on the island, in Windwardside.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>The Saba Herald</em> is published monthly in English.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The post office is in The Bottom. Airmail to Europe takes four to six days, surface mail four to six weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire The Bottom</b></p><![CDATA[<p>We're talking about Saba's capital, The Bottom, of course, which is surely one of the world's best-named cities. It's more of a town, actually – and it's a pretty one at that. Nestling in a verdant valley beneath lofty mountains, The Bottom is the entry point for most visitors to the island. There's not an awful lot to do in this town of 500 people, aside from admire the Dutch architecture and peruse the sleepy stores, though it does come alive for Carnival, which takes place over summer.</p>]]><p><b>Delve into an underwater world</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience the stunning marine life along Saba's craggy coastline. Although Saba has no beaches, the waters around the island have been declared a protected marine park in recognition of the unique opportunities for wall diving. Giant sea turtles and humpback whales are seasonal visitors.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy a climber's paradise</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Climb up one of the island's many outcrops as recommended by the Saba Conservation Foundation. With its volcanic terrain and unique geology, Saba is something of a climber's paradise, with a wealth of dramatic drop-offs and boulders to keep even the most hardened adrenaline junky amused.</p>]]><p><b>Go and explore Fort Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the rocky beach at Fort Bay, where a dramatic steep climb has been carved out of the rock. En route to the summit walkers will pass the island's four villages, which are mere clusters of ornate timber cottages perching on the flanks of the mountain.</p>]]><p><b>Go green on Saba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Saba has a burgeoning reputation for having impeccable green credentials and none more so than with its commitment to eco-tourism and exceptional scuba diving, climbing and hiking. Sabans are rightly proud of their history of environmental conservation and endearingly refer to their nation as the "The Unspoiled Queen".</p>]]><p><b>Party at the carnival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In common with most other Caribbean islands, Sabans do like a party and naturally tend to throw an annual carnival. Saba's Carnival shimmies and shakes into life in the last week of July and boasts a dazzling parade, competitions, steel bands and mouth-watering food.</p>]]><p><b>Take a hike on the trails</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Get active and head up one of the many marked hiking trails that lead up to Mount Scenery, from where you can take in the stunning views. Although some of the more difficult trails require a guide, many of the easier routes will take you through Saba's lush rainforests, tide pools and historic ruins.</p>]]><p><b>Take it easy at the Hilltop spa retreat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relax at the island's hilltop spa retreat, where you can indulge in a treatment or meditate with a spot of yoga. Saba's undulating typography can be exhausting for hikers, so the spa can be a welcome sight.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the Harry L Johnson Memorial Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take in the Harry L Johnson Memorial Museum in Windwardside, the restored home of a Dutch sea captain. Windwardside also contains the tourist office, the island's two largest guesthouses and most of its shops.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$3.3 billion (2005).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and electrical equipment, crude oil (for refining and re-export), chemicals and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Venezuela, Guatemala, Singapore and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Economic conditions vary widely between the different islands in the Netherlands Antilles group. Saba relies partly on agriculture, producing sorghum, groundnuts, fruit and vegetables, as well as a modest fishing operation. There is no manufacturing industry other than textiles. Saba has very little of the Netherlands Antilles' recently developed 'offshore' financial services industry; tourism is the most important part of the service sector.<br /><br />Along with Bonaire and St Eustatius, Saba is a net beneficiary of the Netherlands Antilles central treasury. Saba has associate membership of the European Union, as an overseas territory of The Netherlands, and observer status at the Caribbean trading bloc, CARICOM.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business is fairly formal and visitors should wear a suit. Appointments should be made and always kept as it is very discourteous to be late.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0730-1200 and 1330-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Curaçao Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (9) 461 3918
					Website:http://www.curacao-chamber.an
					Address: ,,,]]><b>St Maarten Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 542 3590
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Fine local cuisine is offered at the island's guest houses and there are several public restaurants.  Brigadoon, which serves Mediterranean-influenced dishes, and Swinging Doors steak house are two of the most popular restaurants on the island (you'll need to book ahead for a table at Swinging Doors.) Restaurants and bars are usually closed by midnight.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Calaloo soup (a thick green soup traditionally made from dasheen leaves).<br />
&bull; Curried goat.<br />
&bull; Breadfruit.<br />
&bull; Soursop ice cream.<br />
&bull; Exotic fruit grown on the island - mangoes, papayas, figs and bananas.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A surcharge of 20% is usually added to guest house and restaurant bills to cover government tax and service. Elsewhere, 10 to 15% is expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are few visitors to the island (50 tourists at any one time is considered a busy week) and generally evenings are quiet, but on Friday and Saturday nights there is dancing at some restaurants and some guest houses have lively bars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Embroidery has become Saba's chief claim to fame. The Saba Artisans' Foundation in The Bottom promotes local lacework, silk-screened fabrics and garments printed and handmade by Sabans, as does the Island Craft Shop in Windwardside. Saba Lace Boutique in Hell's Gate sells the largest selection on the island.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1200 and 1400-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are various guest houses including The Cottage Club, Cranston's Antique Inn, Ecolodge Rendez-Vous, The Gate House, Juliana's, El Momo, Queen's Garden Resort, Scout's Place and Willard's of Saba. Most have their own restaurant, bar and swimming pool. Some apartments, cottages and villas are also available. A 5% government tax is added to bills.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There is a hospital in The Bottom and the University School of Medicine. There is also a hyperbaric chamber on the island for divers. The hospital does not treat complex cases so medical insurance is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All mains water on the island is distilled from seawater and is therefore safe to drink. Bottled mineral water is widely available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat but travellers should beware of certain reef fish including barracuda, grouper, and red snapper, as they may carry ciguatera biotoxin.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations for tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Family Day :
							19 February </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							30 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Antillean Day :
							21 October </p><p>Saba Day :
							03 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Saba by travellers over 17 years of age (tobacco products) or over 18 years of age (alcohol) without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigarillos or 25 cigars or 125g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits over 22%; or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% and&nbsp;2L of non-sparkling wine and&nbsp;8L of beer.<br />
&bull; Gifts up to a value of US$500 (or US$150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar (USD; symbol $) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of $100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of $1, and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.</p>
<p>The US Dollar replaced The Netherlands Antilles Guilder or Florin as the currency of Saba on 1 January 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are three banks on the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mastercard and Visa are accepted in larger establishments.</p><p>There are two ATMs in Saba. One is at the Royal Bank of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/trinidad-and-tobago">Trinidad and Tobago</a> in Windwardside; the other is at Windward Island Bank, located in The Bottom.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, US Dollars are recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1530.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Saba, passports must be valid for six months on arrival.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Schengen visa is not valid for travel to Saba.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Short-stay Caribbean visa: &pound;30.&nbsp;The Caribbean visa allows nationals who do require a visa to make short visits to Aruba, Cura&ccedil;ao, St Maarten, Bonaire, St Eustatius and Saba.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Caribbean visa is a multiple-entry visa. Visa holders may visit any of the countries included under the scheme for a maximum of 90 days within one year. Each continuous period in any one country may not exceed 30 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Contact your nearest Dutch Embassy to make an appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Applications for the Caribbean visa are usually processed within 15 calendar days, but processing times vary depending on the country. Applications can be made up to 3 months before the intended travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You cannot extend the Caribbean visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet to Saba, your animal must have a valid international health certificate, current rabies vaccination and up-to-date annual vaccinations. Large dogs must be transported via ferry, as planes to Saba are too small to accommodate dogs weighing more than 23kg (50lb).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[17.626111]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-63.249167]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>13 sq km (5 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1947 (CBS estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>153.8 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Bottom.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Under the direct administration of the Netherlands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saba is one of three Windward Islands in the former Netherlands Antilles. However, geographically it is part of the Leeward Group of the Lesser Antilles, lying 265km (165 miles) east of Puerto Rico, 44km (27 miles) south of St Maarten and 21km (13 miles) west of St Eustatius. Saba is situated upon the peak of a submerged extinct volcano. The highest point of the island is Mount Scenery, which is thick with forest and rises to almost 900m (3,000ft) in less than 2km (1.2 miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roman Catholic majority; also Anglican and Wesleyan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dutch customs are still important throughout the former Netherlands Antilles, but tourism on neighbouring <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/st-maarten">St Maarten</a> has brought some <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> influence to Saba (several businesses are US-owned). Dress is casual and lightweight cottons are advised.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>110 volts AC, 60Hz. North American-style plugs with two flat pins (and sometimes a third grounding pin) are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Mark Rutte since 2010, represented locally by Kingdom Representative Gilbert Isabella since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Willem-Alexander since 2013, represented locally by Governor Jonathan Johnson since 2008.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saba was sighted by Christopher Columbus in 1493, by Sir Francis Drake in 1595 and by two Dutch expeditions in the 1620s. In 1632, a party of Englishmen was shipwrecked on the tiny island and found it uninhabited, although there were traces of Carib occupation. Permanent settlement by Europeans did not occur until the second half of the 17th century, when the Dutch were consolidating their Caribbean empire, based on Cura&ccedil;ao. The settlers founded an agricultural economy with sugar and indigo as the key crops. The decline in these markets forced the population to maintain their modest prosperity through fishing and embroidery which, together with low-key tourism, remain the major sources of income. <br />
<br />
The island changed hands 12 times between 1632 and 1816, when it was finally confirmed as a Dutch possession. As part of the Netherlands Antilles, Saba gained partial independence from The Netherlands in 1954. The issue of the Antilles' constitutional status never left the political agenda, however, and was the subject of a referendum on the three Windward Islands in 1994. All three voted to remain within the Antilles but Saba registered the largest majority of 91 per cent.<br />
<br />
The socialist <em>Frente Obrero Liberashon</em> (Workers' Liberation Front) won the largest number of seats in the 2002 general election, but was excluded from office by a four-party centre-right coalition led by the <em>Partido Antia Restruktura</em> (PAR, Party for the Restructured Antilles). The PAR, based on the island of Cura&ccedil;ao, dominated Antilles' politics since its formation a decade ago. </p>
<p>After the dissolution of the Netherlands Antilles in 2010, Saba became a special municipality of The Netherlands and is under the direct administration of the European country. Saba adopted the U.S. dollar as its currency on 1 January 2011, replacing the Netherlands Antillian Guilder. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Office of the Minister Plenipotentiary of the Netherlands Antilles in the Netherlands]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(70) 306 6111.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(70) 306 6111.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>Badhuisweg 173-175<br/>PO Box 90706<br/>The Hague<br/>2597 JP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Diplomatic Representation]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saba sits majestically at the peak of a submerged extinct volcano. As such, the island abounds with stunning vistas of dramatic cliff faces and spectacular rocky shorelines. With only one road ('The Road') and a population of less than 1,500, Saba is the most unspoilt island of the former Netherlands Antilles, and the superb preservation of the island's unique ecosystem has earned it the nickname of 'The Unspoiled Queen'.</p>
<p>In fact, until 50 years ago, Saba was a secluded oasis, having neither an airport nor a sheltered harbour. There are four villages, which until recently were only connected by thousands of steps cut into the rock. A road now links the airport with the island's capital, The Bottom. The Bottom is situated 250m (820ft) above the ocean on a plateau surrounded by volcanic domes.</p>
<p>Saba, a special municipality of The Netherlands, was a member of the Netherland Antilles until it was dissolved on 10 October 2010.</p><p>Saba sits majestically at the peak of a submerged extinct volcano.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
