<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Saudi Arabia" ColCode="sau" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sa" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia has a desert climate. In seaside Jeddah it is warm for most of the year, though winter is probably the most pleasant time for a visit. Riyadh, which is inland, is hotter in summer and colder in winter, when occasional heavy rainstorms occur. Early spring and late autumn are lovely times to visit this desert capital. The Rub al Khali, or "Empty Quarter," seldom receives rain, making Saudi Arabia one of the driest countries in the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight, long-sleeved shirts and light trousers, sun hats, and sturdy shoes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many domestic airports, and air travel is by far the most convenient way of travelling around the country. Saudia (<a href="http://www.saudia.com" target="www.saudia.com">www.saudia.com</a>) connects all main centres. Budget carriers flynas (<a href="http://www.flynas.com" target="_blank">www.flynas.com</a>) offers&nbsp;economy-class connections to and from Jeddah, Riyadh, and Dammam. Many carriers offer special flights for pilgrims arriving at or departing from Jeddah during the Hajj.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The rail system is operated by the Saudi Railways Organization (<a href="http://www.saudirailways.org" target="_blank">www.saudirailways.org</a>). The main railway line is the 570km (354-mile) Riyadh-Dammam line, which links Dhahran, Abqaiq, Hofuf, Harad and Al Kharj. There is a daily service in air-conditioned trains, which offer first-, second-, and third-class cars, which descend in corresponding levels of seating comfort and food and beverage service. Children under four travel free.</p>
<p>The railway on the west coast made famous by Lawrence of Arabia's raid has long since been abandoned to the desert. Currently, the Haramain High Speed Rail project is about to revive this old connection. The Makkah-Medina high speed rail will link Medina with Mecca, the King Abdulaziz International Airport and Jeddah starting March 2018.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>The road network is constantly being upgraded and expanded and, on the main routes, much of it is of the highest standard.&nbsp;The Corniche, which winds down the escarpment between Taif and Mecca, is as spectacular a feat of engineering as may be seen anywhere, as is the King Fahed Gateway that links Saudi Arabia to Bahrain.&nbsp;</p>
<p>However, standards of driving are erratic, particularly in the Eastern Province.&nbsp;As foreigners are tolerated rather than welcomed in Saudi Arabia, it is best to drive with extreme caution at all times.</p><p>Inter-country bus travel in the Gulf can be daunting, but travel by bus between Saudi Arabia's cities can be quite pleasant. The national bus company SAPTCO (<a href="http://www.saptco.com.sa" target="_blank">www.saptco.com.sa</a>) maintains stations in most major cities. Routes are plentiful, tickets are affordable, and the vehicles themselves are clean and in good condition. A good bet is the Riyadh-Damamm route, a five-hour voyage through deep desert.</p><p>Metered taxi services are available in all major cities. If you're feeling bold, you can attempt to negotiate the fare in advance (especially for long trips or fares that will take you through dense traffic) but it's often easier and not that much more expensive to rely on the meter.</p><p>A national driving licence is valid for up to three months if accompanied by an officially sanctioned translation into Arabic, though this provision is often waived for anyone with an American or British licence. An International Driving Permit (with translation) is recommended, but not required by law.</p>
<p>There are restrictions on women travelling by car with men who are not related by blood or marriage, though officials are sometimes more lenient with citizens from Western countries.</p><p>Women are not allowed to drive vehicles or ride bicycles on public roads. However, women will be allowed to drive starting 2018.</p><p>Most major international car hire agencies have offices in Saudi Arabia, both at the airport and in town. The minimum age is 25.</p><p>The bravest among Saudi Arabian visitors might consider bringing along a bicycle. Be warned: local drivers are unaccustomed to cyclists, and riding near motor vehicle traffic is a risky proposition.</p><p>Women are not allowed to drive vehicles or ride bicycles on public roads. However, women will be allowed to drive starting 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Non-Muslims may not enter Mecca or the immediate area; police are stationed to ensure that they turn off onto a specially built ring road, known among expatriates as the 'Christian Bypass'.</p>
<p>It is possible to explore Saudi Arabia's urban centres by walking, but travellers who set out on foot from their hotels will be met with quizzical staring from drivers and incessant honking from eager taxis, both of whom rarely see anyone walking in the city. This is true partially because of the often-extreme temperatures but also due to the overwhelming ubiquity of the automobile. Take a bottle of water.</p>
<p>A metro system is under construction in Riyadh and expected to open in 2018.</p>
<p>Plans are also afoot for a new integrated public transport network in Jeddah, which is expected to include a metro and light rail system, plus buses and a tram line. In the meantime, taxis are the easiest way to get around.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The cheapest but not necessarily most luxurious way to fly to Saudi Arabia is with national airline Saudia (<a href="http://www.saudia.com" target="www.saudia.com">www.saudia.com</a>), which operates a fleet of sturdy if shop-worn American planes. Regular flights connect Riyadh and Jeddah with London, New York&nbsp;and&nbsp;Washington, DC, plus a long list of regional cities. British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) also has direct flights from the UK.</p>
<p>Prices to and from Saudi Arabia fluctuate with little notice. Before you travel to Saudi Arabia, it&rsquo;s best to arrange a round-trip ticket online or with a travel agent. But if you come in on a one-way ticket, there are a variety of excellent travel agents who can arrange ongoing bookings.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/saudi-arabia/riyadh-king-khaled-international-airport">Riyadh King Khaled International Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/saudi-arabia/jeddah-king-abdulaziz-international-airport">Jeddah King Abdulaziz International Airport </a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/saudi-arabia/dammam-king-fahd-international-airport">Dammam King Fahd International Airport (DMM)</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Jeddah: from London - 5 hours 50 minutes; from New York - 11 hours 45 minutes.</p>
<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/riyadh">Riyadh</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 6 hours 30 minutes; from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 12 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Riyadh King Khaled International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.gaca.gov.sa<p>Riyadh King Khaled International Airport is situated 35km (22 miles) north of Riyadh.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+966 11 2211 000.</p>]]><b>Dammam King Fahd International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.kfia.com.sa<p>Dammam King Fahd International Airport is located 20km (12 miles) northwest of Dammam.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>(03) 883 1000.</p>]]><b>Jeddah King Abdulaziz International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.jed-airport.com<p>Jeddah King Abdulaziz International Airport is located 19km (12 miles) north of central Jeddah.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+966 920 011 233.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports are in the eastern town of Dammam, on the Gulf; and in the eastern centres of Jeddah and Yanbu, which are both on the Red Sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>A sophisticated telecommunications network and satellite, microwave and cable systems span the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors can apply for a mobile telephone number upon arrival at the airport. Prepaid SIM cards, which operate in most handheld devices, are affordable and reliable.   </p>
<p>International roaming agreements exist with some mobile phone companies and coverage is mostly good.  </p>
<p>Hotels and some long-term apartment rentals will include access to a landline, but local and international calls can be much more expensive than calls placed on a landline.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Ministry of Post, Telegraph and Telephones provides internet facilities in most cities. But email can also be accessed from many hotels and internet cafes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia has a very tightly controlled media environment and criticism of the government, the royal family and religious tenets are not really tolerated. Newspapers tend to follow the lead of the state-run news agency on whether or not to publish stories on sensitive subjects. The government blocks access to websites that it deems offensive.</p>
<p>Growing signs of an increasing tolerance have recently been met with new calls for regulating the media, especially blogs and online-only media.</p>
<p>The state-run Broadcasting Service of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (BSKSA) is responsible for all broadcasting in the Kingdom. The Minister of Culture and Information oversees radio and TV operations. But the ubiquitous availability of satellite TV has meant the viewing of many more channels than ever before.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internal and international services available from the Central Post Office. Post is delivered to box numbers. Airmail to Europe takes up to one week.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Discover Medain Saleh</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A southern cousin to the staggering Jordanian site of Petra, the ruins of Medain Saleh are one of the true wonders of the world. Across a wide plain there stands ancient sandstone mountains, into which the Dedan people thousands of years ago carved temples and burial sites. A place of some controversy to traditional Saudis, who think of history as beginning with the prophet, Medain Saleh is a visit that requires a police escort, for your safety.</p>]]><p><b>Discover Timna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the ornate ruins of Timna and Shiban, ancient cities resting amidst orchards of pomegranates, limes and bananas.</p>]]><p><b>Drive down Corniche road</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour Jeddah's astounding corniche road, which winds along the azure waters of the Red Sea. The city has worked to sculpt a pleasant sculpture park and path, which is kept cool by the waters of the sea.</p>]]><p><b>Encounter Asir wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Witness the astonishing landscape and wildlife of the Asir, a range of coastal mountains and the only part of the kingdom where there is significant wild vegetation. Baboon, gazelle and leopard inhabit remoter areas.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Taif</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Look around in Taif to see pink palaces in between the stunning cliff-tops. Such beauty and a mild climate have made this town Saudi Arabia's official summer capital.</p>]]><p><b>Go shopping</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go shopping in the traditional souks, large department stores and mall complexes. Shopping is a much-loved way to spend time in Saudi Arabia - possibly since there are no bars, casinos, nightclubs, theatres or cinemas.</p>]]><p><b>Head to Tarut Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>View a picturesque settlement of fishermen and weavers on Tarut Island in the east of the country. It is also the site of the oldest town on the peninsula.</p>]]><p><b>Journey to Mecca</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Muslim visitors can make a pilgrimage to Mecca, which during the annual holy month of Ramadan can find more than two million visitors traveling to Saudi Arabia for the holy rite. A full visit – which if completed at another time during the year is called Umrah - will include time at the Kaabah, the Mountain of Light, the Plain of Arafat and the House of Abdullah Bin Abdul Muttalib, where Muhammad was born. Non-Muslims are forbidden from entering these holy sites.</p>]]><p><b>Learn the skills of Jebel-al-Qara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Uncover some of Saudi Arabia's ancient crafts and skills. In Jebel-al-Qara, pottery is a skill that has been passed down by eight generations of the same family.</p>]]><p><b>Make a splash in Obhir Creek</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy the Obhir Creek, north of Jeddah. It has good facilities for watersports, including swimming, waterskiing, fishing, snorkelling and sailing. The Red Sea waters here are among the most beautiful in the region.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Ottoman buildings</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the ragged, coral-coloured Ottoman buildings of the ancient city of Jeddah. Its hotels and restaurants are cosmopolitan and the city also features excellent fish and meat markets. </p>]]><p><b>See the ancient saltmines of Abqaiq</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See an ancient saltmine in use. The 5,000-year-old one in Abqaiq is still in operation.</p>]]><p><b>Visit a camel market in Hofuf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover Hofuf, at the centre of the great Al-Hasa oasis, where you'll encounter a traditional Saudi camel market. This is where local agriculture thrives and no visit is complete without a complete sampling of fresh and dried Saudi dates.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the royal city of Riyadh</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit the royal capital, Riyadh, a modern city built on the site of the first town captured by Ibn Saud in 1902. The only trace of the old town that remains is the Masmak Fort and a few traditional Najdi palaces near Deera Square.</p>]]><p><b>Watch the King's Cup</b></p><![CDATA[Each year, Riyadh plays host to a race that takes place on different days each spring during the national Heritage and Cultural Festival at Janadriyah. The annual event is one of the world's most important camel races, with something between 20,000 and 30,000 spectators, 2,000 camels and riders and a winnings purse of hundreds of thousands of dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$646 billion (2015 est.)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Petroleum and petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, food, chemicals, motor vehicles and textiles.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>USA, Japan, China (PR), Korea (Rep) and UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia has the world's largest oil reserves (about 20% of proven deposits) and is also currently the world's largest producer, and the 11th in terms of natual gas production. Oil and natural gas products now account for 35% of Saudi GDP, 75% of government revenue and 85% of export income.  The non-oil economy is devoted to agriculture and newly developed industries. Agriculture products include wheat, fruit, vegetables, barley, eggs and poultry.  The industrial sector produces petrochemicals, steel, engineering and construction materials and a wide range of consumer goods. The service sector is the fastest growing part of the economy at present, with finance and business services, consultancies and property services prominent.   The rapid expansion of the Saudi economy from the 1960s onwards stalled during the late 1980s as overstretched finances and persistently low world oil prices forced the Saudi exchequer to rein in its spending plans (government debt is now nearly 100% of GDP - much of which, such as US$40 billion of loans to Iraq, may not be recovered).  This has had unfortunate consequences for the large body of foreign labour (an estimated 80% of the workforce) upon which the Saudis rely for much of their technical, managerial and menial labour. Foreigners are now barred from a range of occupations as the government seeks to tackle Saudi unemployment, which is estimated to be as high as 15%.  The economy was growing by 3.4% in 2015, with inflation creeping up to 2.3%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Appointments are necessary. Business cards printed in English with an Arab translation are usually exchanged. Men should wear suits for business meetings and formal social occasions. Thursday and Friday are official holidays.<br /></p><p>Sun-Thurs 0800-1200 and 1500-1800 (Ramadan 2000-0100), Fri 0800-1200, with some regional variation.<br />
<br />
<strong>Government office hours: </strong>Sun-Thurs 0730-1430.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Riyadh Exhibitions Company Ltd</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 454 1448.
					Website:http://www.recexpo.com
					Address: ,,Riyadh 11554,PO Box 56010]]><b>Council of Saudi Chambers of Commerce &amp; Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 405 3200
					Website:http://www.riyadhchamber.com
					Address: ,PO Box 16683,Riyadh 11474,]]><b>Saudi Arabian Ministry of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (1) 401 2220.
					Website:http://www.commerce.gov.sa
					Address: Riyadh,11162,Airport Road,PO Box 1774]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Local food is often strongly flavoured and spicy. The most common meats are lamb and chicken, beef is rare and pork is forbidden under Islamic law. The main meat meal of the day is lunch. Foreign cooking is on offer in larger towns and the whole range of international cuisine, including fast food, is available in the oil-producing Eastern Province and in Jeddah.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; Pitta bread (flat, unleavened bread) accompanies every dish. <br />
&bull; Rice, lentils, hummus (chick peas) and <em>burghul</em> (cracked wheat) are also common. <br />
&bull; <em>Kultra</em> (chicken or lamb on skewers) is popular for lunch.<br />
&bull; Kebabs are often served with soup and vegetables. <br />
&bull; Mezze, the equivalent of hors d'oeuvres, may include up to 40 dishes.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Eating, drinking and smoking in public during the fasting hours of Ramadan will incur strict penalties. Restaurants have table service. There are no bars. Alcohol is forbidden by law, and there are severe penalties for infringement; note that this applies to all nationals regardless of religion.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>The practice of tipping is becoming much more common and waiters should be given 10%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Given the Kingdom&rsquo;s strict laws against alcohol and music, visitors should not expect to find clubs, bars, or typical live music. But entertainment is still occasionally on offer, such as traditional sword dancing and drumming, which can be hosted at restaurants or hotels.  </p>
<p>Another good bet is to follow listings at the King Fahd Cultural Centre, in Riyadh, where recent events have included several concerts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Souks sell incense and holders, jewellery, bronze and brassware, richly decorated daggers and swords, and in the Eastern Province, huge brass-bonded chests. Bargaining is often expected, even for modern goods such as cameras and electrical equipment (which can be very good value).</p><p>Sun-Fri 0900-1300 and 1630-2000 (Ramadan 2000-0100). Hours differ in various parts of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good range of hotel accommodation throughout the country. Accommodation is generally easy to find, except during the pilgrimage season when advance reservations are recommended. Service charges are fixed at 15% for deluxe and first-category hotels and at 10% for all others. Hotel charges double in Mecca and Medina during the pilgrimage season, and increase by 25% during the summer months in resort areas such as Abha, Al-Baha, Kamis Mushait and Taif.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> There are seven grades of hotel in Saudi Arabia: deluxe, first-class A and B, second-class A and B, and third-class A and B.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good range of hotel accommodation throughout the country. Accommodation is generally easy to find, except during the pilgrimage season when advance reservations are recommended. Service charges are fixed at 15% for deluxe and first-category hotels and at 10% for all others. Hotel charges double in Mecca and Medina during the pilgrimage season, and increase by 25% during the summer months in resort areas such as Abha, Al-Baha, Kamis Mushait and Taif.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> There are seven grades of hotel in Saudi Arabia: deluxe, first-class A and B, second-class A and B, and third-class A and B.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a good range of hotel accommodation throughout the country. Accommodation is generally easy to find, except during the pilgrimage season when advance reservations are recommended. Service charges are fixed at 15% for deluxe and first-category hotels and at 10% for all others. Hotel charges double in Mecca and Medina during the pilgrimage season, and increase by 25% during the summer months in resort areas such as Abha, Al-Baha, Kamis Mushait and Taif.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> There are seven grades of hotel in Saudi Arabia: deluxe, first-class A and B, second-class A and B, and third-class A and B.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are generally of a high standard, but treatment is expensive. Health insurance is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water from the tap should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Bottled water is cheap and safe. Fresh milk is pasteurised but powdered or boxed milk is also available as an alternative. Avoid dairy products, which are likely to have been made from un-boiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be washed and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water; swimming pools which are well chlorinated and maintained are safe.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region. During Hajj, all government establishments and some businesses will be closed for 10 to 14 days.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>National Day :
							23 September </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Saudi Arabia without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 600 cigarettes or 100 cigars or 500g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of SAR3,000.</p>
<p>Digital devices can be subject to inspection &ndash; and often by officials who may not know how to properly operate such devices. The result can occasionally involve wiped hard drives but is more often just a delay. With the country&rsquo;s ban on pornography, it is wise to remove risqu&eacute; images from your devices.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited imports include pork, dogs, narcotics, alcoholic drinks, anti-Islamic goods and publications, gambling devices, weapons and ammunition, explosives, fireworks, unlabelled medication, nutmeg, goods which prominently display flags of another country, goods bearing names and pictures of celebrities, wild animal hides and counterfeit money.</p>
<p>Restricted imports include live animals, plants, fresh fruit, seeds, eggs, wheat, chemicals, hunting arms, antiques and endangered animals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited exports include livestock, formula milk, animal feeds, natural sand and Zamzam water.</p>
<p>Restricted exports include wild animals, wheat, medication, antiques and endangered animals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabian Riyal (SAR) = 100 halala; 5 halala = 20 qirsh. Notes are in denominations of SAR500, 100, 50, 10, 5 and 1. Coins are in denominations of 1 riyal, 2 riyal and 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1 halala.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most foreign currencies can be exchanged at commercial banks and money-changers, which stay open longer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted. Major hotels, restaurants, and shops occasionally accept American Express and Discover.</p><p>ATMs are widely available and reliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted although they can be hard to change. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Saudi Riyal, Euros, US Dollars or Pounds Sterling and to carry the purchase receipt.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most banks are open from Sat-Wed 0800-1200 and 1700-2000; Thurs 0800-1200. Money-changers often operate longer hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Saudi Arabia, a passport valid for at least six months at the time of the visa application is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are available for business (single- or multiple-entry visas), work, visiting family or religious visits. A certificate of competence is required for work visa applications.</p>
<p>Family visa: US$55; commercial/working visit visa: US$55 (single-entry) or US$140 (multiple-entry);&nbsp;businessmen/women visa: US$280.</p>
<p>US citizens pay US$110 for all visa types.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The visa validity starts from the date of issue.&nbsp;The visa stay period starts from the first day of entry into Saudi Arabia within the visa's valid dates. Be careful not to mix up the validity of the visa with the permitted length of stay, as overstaying is a very serious matter.</p>
<p>Single-entry visas: up to three months; multiple-entry visas: up to six months.</p>
<p>Umrah&nbsp;and Hajj visas: 30 days for stays of up to two weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate (or consular section at embassy). Some nationalities can make the initial application and payment online (<a href="https://enjazit.com.sa">https://enjazit.com.sa</a>); there is a US$10.50 processing fee. Travellers are advised to apply well in advance. Hajj or Umrah visas are only available from the consulate through an authorised travel agent. People visiting the consulate directly for Hajj or Umrah visas will not be successful.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least 24 hours for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[23.888037]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[44.441974]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,149,690 sq km (830,000 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>32,157,974 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>15 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Riyadh.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Absolute monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saudi Arabia occupies four-fifths of the Arabian Peninsula. It is bordered to the northwest by Jordan, to the north by Iraq and Kuwait, to the east by the Gulf of Oman, Qatar, the United Arab Emirates and Oman, and to the south by Yemen. To the west lies the Red Sea. Along the Red Sea coast is a narrow coastal strip (<em>Tihama</em>) which becomes relatively hotter and more humid towards the south and has areas of extensive tidal flats and lava fields.</p>
<p>Behind this coastal plain is a series of plateaus reaching up to 2,000m (6,560ft). The southern part of this range, <em>Asir</em>, has some peaks of over 3,000m (9,840ft). North of these mountains, in the far north, is <em>An Nafud</em>, a sand sea, and further south the landscape rises to <em>Najd</em>, a semi-desert area scattered with oases. Still further south the land falls away, levelling out to unremitting desert, the uninhabited 'Empty Quarter' or <em>Rub al Khali</em>. Along the Gulf coast is a low fertile plain giving way to limestone ridges inland.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of Saudi Arabians follow Islam; around 90% are Sunni Muslim, but Shia Muslims predominate in the Eastern Province.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Saudi culture is based on Islam and the perfection of the Arabic language. The Saudi form of Islam is conservative and fundamentalist, based on the 18th-century revivalist movement of the Najdi leader Sheikh Muhammad Ibn Abdel-Wahhab. This has had a great effect on Saudi society, especially on the position of women, who are required by law to leave the home covered in abaya, (black robes). Some women also wear a niqab, a black mask that covers the face, and gloves, though there are regional variations of dress. The Najd and other remote areas remain true to Wahhabi tradition, but throughout the country this way of life is being altered by modernisation and rapid development.</p>
<p>Shaking hands and kissing on the cheek is the customary form of greeting between men. Invitations to private homes are unusual, though not unheard of. Entertaining is usually in hotels or restaurants and although the custom of eating with the right hand persists, it is more likely that knives and forks will be used. A small gift either promoting the company or representing your country will generally be well received.</p>
<p>Women are expected to dress modestly and it is best to do so to avoid offence. Men should not wear shorts in public or go without a shirt. The norms for public behaviour are extremely conservative and religious police, known as <em>muttawa</em>, are charged with enforcing these standards.</p>
<p>Customs regarding smoking are the same as in Europe and non-smoking areas are indicated. During Ramadan, Muslims are not allowed to eat, smoke or drink during the day and it is illegal for a foreign visitor to do so in public.</p>
<p><strong>Photography</strong><strong>:</strong>  Strictly speaking, photography is not permitted. However, many people do still take photos, but are careful to ask permission of the relevant authority before photographing people or any building. In recent years, the spread of small digital cameras and mobile phones with cameras have eased official and unofficial acceptance of photography.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 60Hz. Two-pin plugs (flat and round pins) and British-style plugs with three square pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King and Prime Minister Salman bin Abdulaziz Al Saud since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King and Prime Minister Salman bin Abdulaziz Al Saud since 2015.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Abyssinians occupied the whole of the Arabian Peninsula until the Persians drove them out of the southern regions in 576 AD. Following the flight of the Prophet Muhammad from Mecca to nearby Medina in 672, many Arabs joined his campaign to recapture Mecca before his death in 632. This allowed for the spread of Islam across the Arabian peninsula and into Syria, Mesopotamia (Iraq), Persia and westwards into Egypt and North Africa. Mecca and Medina, both thriving cultural and commercial centres before and after Muhammad, are the holiest cities of Islam and the Saudis avidly protect their integrity. Arabia was absorbed into the Ottoman Empire during the 16th century, but subsequent local rulers were allowed a great deal of autonomy. In 1914 the British offered the Sherif of Mecca independence on condition that he supported the campaign against the Turks and the Kingdom of Hijaz was duly recognised as independent at the 1920 Treaty of S&egrave;vres. On the other side of the peninsula, the leading potentate was Ibn Saud and throughout the 1920s, military clashes escalated between his troops and those loyal to the Hashemite King of Hijaz. Eventually, Ibn Saud pushed out the Hashemites and in 1926 was recognised as ruler of the Kingdom of Hijaz and Najd, which became Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>In 1933 vast deposits of oil were discovered, setting the country on the road to its current prosperity. Ibn Saud's descendants have ruled Saudi Arabia ever since. When the Saudis sided with the OPEC cartel in trebling the price of oil in 1973, relations were cooled with its previously staunch ally, the USA. The damage to relations was resolved after the revolution in Iran in 1979 and Saudi Arabia invested heavily in Saddam Hussein&rsquo;s Iraq in the Iran-Iraq war only to be astonished when, following the invasion of Kuwait in 1991, it looked as if Saddam was preparing to occupy Saudi territory. The UN coalition was permitted to base its troops in Saudi Arabia before the Desert Storm campaign to repel Iraq.</p>
<p>The current King Salman has overseen Saudi intervention in the civil war in Yemen, a stampede during the annual Hajj pilgrimage in Mina that lead to the death of more than 2,200, and the execution of Sheikh Nimr and 46 other dissidents in 2016.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; Saudi is also known as the Land of the Two Holy Mosques after Al-Masjid al-haram in Mecca and Al-Masjid an-Nabawi in Medina, the two most holy sites in Islam.</p>
<p>&bull; Saudi Arabia adheres closely to the Islamic principal of modesty, the hijab.</p>
<p>&bull; Since 1974 the annual King&rsquo;s Camel Race has been one of the country&rsquo;s biggest sporting events.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Royal Embassy of Saudi Arabia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 342 3800 (information section); +1 202 944 3126 (visa section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.saudiembassy.net</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 342 3800 (information section); +1 202 944 3126 (visa section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>601 New Hampshire Avenue<br/>Washington, D.C.<br/>20037<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Royal Embassy of Saudi Arabia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7917 3000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://embassies.mofa.gov.sa/sites/uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7917 3000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon - Thur 0900-1600, Fri 0900-1500. Consular section: Mon-Fri 0900-1130 (visa applications); Mon-Thurs 1400-1530 (passport collection), Fri 1330-1430.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>30 Charles Street<br/>London<br/>W1J 5DZ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>No country in the world is as misunderstood as the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. And yet, perhaps no other country is as worthy of a visit. Many imagine nothing more than a harsh desert, but in reality Saudi Arabia contains areas of beautiful oases and dramatic mountaintops, beaches, and rivers. The sands themselves are wondrous, especially the Empty Quarter, a beautiful expanse of undulating dunes unlike anywhere in the world. In addition to its natural beauty, Saudi Arabia is a country rich in culture and heritage.</p>
<p>In the west of the country you'll find untamed stretches of Red Sea coast, and southwestern mountain towns such as Taif are definitely worth a look. The ancient history in the north is perhaps one of the country's greatest draws, where the town of Al Ula serves as the gateway to Medain Saleh, a collection of stone dwellings as magnificent as Petra in Jordan.</p>
<p>Then there are the cosmopolitan city centres of Jeddah, the Red Sea port, as well as Riyadh, the throbbing central capital, and Gulf-side Dammam, the large city in the east. All enjoy a lively cafe culture and top-notch restaurants. Saudi Arabians have a reputation for shopping and there are stores galore, from traditional souks to glittering malls with all the latest fashions. Hotels are being built at a rapid pace, and each seems to feature a chef of ever-increasing pedigree.</p>
<p>Few other countries are as rich in historical sites as Saudi Arabia. As the birthplace of the Prophet Muhammad, it is home to nothing less than the two holiest sites in Islam: The Grand Mosque in Mecca and the Prophet&rsquo;s Mosque in Medina, with millions visiting both every year (although these are off-limits to non-Muslims). The Saudis take pride in protecting the integrity of this holy land and Islamic laws are strictly enforced by the <em>Mutaween</em> (religious police).</p>
<p>To a novice visitor, Saudi Arabia can seem like a daunting place for a vacation, and it certainly pays to swot up on cultural rules (such as women not being allowed to drive) before you arrive. But for the intrepid traveller, this is a beautiful country with much to offer.</p><p>No country in the world is as misunderstood as the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, and perhaps no other country – rich with culture, heritage, and natural beauty – is as worthy of a first visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
