<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Senegal" ColCode="sen" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sn" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Senegal]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Situated just above the equator, Senegal benefits from a warm and tropical climate, which sees temperatures hovering from warm to extremely hot throughout the year. The coast tends to see the country's coolest temperatures, ranging from around 18C (F) to 27C (F). Moving into the interior, temperatures hot up, with averages hovering around 30C (F). The hottest temperatures are found in the east on the Malian border, where the mercury has bee known to hit 50C (F) and higher.</p><p>The dry season runs from December through to April with cool trade winds (called harmattan winds) in coastal areas, and this is generally the best time to visit. Throughout the rest of the year, from May to November, a hot monsoon wind blows from the south bringing the rainy season and hot, humid weather. Rainfall is heaviest in the tropical-feeling Casamance and this is where the humidity is highest too. In the southeast and slight in the Sahelian region in the north and northeast, where temperatures tend to be higher.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Senegal's tropical and humid climate mean casual lightweight cottons are recommended for most of the year. Mosquitoes may be another thing to factor in when packing; the likelihood of bites is high, so you may want to stick to long sleeves and pack some high strength mosquito repellent.  If you'll be in the Casamance region during the wet season waterproofs are essential. Sturdy shoes are necessary for any trekking and hiking activities, otherwise, normal shoes and sandals will do.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Senegal Airlines (<a href="http://www.senegalairlines.aero" target="_blank">www.senegalairlines.aero</a>)<em>&nbsp;</em>offers domestic flights linking Dakar to the southern region of Casamance via Cap Skirring and Ziguinchor, gateways to the beautiful stretches of golden sands on the coast. The flight times are around 45 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It is often quicker to travel by sea than road. A ferry line runs from Dakar to Ziguinchor, arriving the morning after departure. Sea shuttles depart regularly from Dakar harbour to the &Icirc;le de Gor&eacute;e. The L'Express du Senegal links Banjul, Dakar and Ziguinchor.</p>
<p>There are also boats, or <em>pirogues</em>, linking N&rsquo;Gor Island, a popular Caribbean-like island near the airport, to N&rsquo;Gor beach on the mainland, that depart on a regular basis from the far left-hand side of the beach when facing the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All rail services are currently suspended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>By far the most used and safest way to travel is by road. There are a number of local transport options depending on your budget and comfort requirements. It's also possible to rent vehicles from private companies or individuals as long as you have a valid driving licence that allows you to drive in this country.</p>r<p>Asphalt roads link the major towns and the coastal region. The network of roads in the interior is rough and may become impassable during the rainy season. It's not advisable to drive at night.</p>
<p>There are often police checkpoints at the entrance and exit to villages to enforce speed restrictions; fines are paid on the spot.</p><p>Regarding inter-city travel, apart from the Sept-place taxi mentioned above, there is the option of taking a minibus, which is often crowded or uncomfortable, or a coach that will often be delayed for departure until it is full. Sometimes you may wait half a day more than the stated time before it leaves.</p><p>Available in most towns; fares are metered. Rates increase after midnight. It's cheaper to hail a taxi in the street than arrange to be collected from the hotel. Taxi prices are theoretically fixed. However, standard practice is to bargain with the driver through the passenger window. To get the best price, you need to refuse the driver&rsquo;s &lsquo;final&rsquo; offer and pretend to hail another taxi; by the time you make it to the back of his car to wave your arm, he&rsquo;ll honk at you to get in at&nbsp;<em>your&nbsp;</em>final offer. Be ready to have exact change and to help direct your driver to your destination; often, they don&rsquo;t know how to get there.</p>
<p>&lsquo;Bush taxis&rsquo; are good for journeys into the interior. By far the quickest and safest way of getting around the country is by&nbsp;sept-place&nbsp;taxi (shared taxi) &ndash; battered Peugeots that negotiate even the most ragged routes of the country.</p><p>A national driving licence or International Driving Permit and Green Card are required.</p><p>In villages and towns, the speed limit is 50kph (31mph). Outside of towns the limit is 130kph (80mph). Seatbelts are obligatory for both driver and passenger, but most commercial vehicles do not have seatbelts.</p>
<p>If you are driving, it is imperative to have a valid driving licence or Internationlal Driving Permit.</p>
<p>It's useful to carry your passport to show officials, as they usually ask for it at check points. However, it's advised to also carry a photocopy of your passport to show instead of the real document as this could avoid frustrating scenarios with corrupt police officials.</p><p>Breakdown service companies in Senegal are non-existent, and people are used to repairing the car by themselves; everyone usually has some kind of mechanical skill. However there are many mechanics in big, medium and small towns that can be relied on to at least get you back on the road again.</p>
<p>If you are renting a car, it's advisable to ask what the options are for breakdown cover from the car hire company you are using. They will probably give you a number to call and will most definitely have their own breakdown service.</p><p>You can find hire car companies such as Hertz and Europcar in Dakar and the main towns. Pick-up points are available at Dakar Airport and at several depots throughout the city.</p><p>Bicycle hire is available in certain smaller towns around Senegal, and is a great way to explore the town and the surrounding countryside. Your best bet to find bicycles is in beach resort towns such as Saly Portudal or Cap Skirring, or in places where community-based tourism projects have been implemented such as Kedougou or Tambacounda. It's not advisable to hire a bike in the hustle and bustle of Dakar.</p>
<p>Unlike a lot of West African countries to the south of Senegal, there are nearly no motorbikes present on the streets. However, in Dakar, you can rent scooters or small bikes. The best bet is to find a reputable garage in town, and keep talking until you are referred to a place that feels OK with you.</p>
<p>Make sure you bring your own helmet and other safety gear. Senegal can be muddy during rainy season, and very dry and dusty the rest of the year. Most rural roads are in poor condition so you need to find an off-road type of bike. Riding in leather might be hot but is generally safer. You might be able to find a bike there, but you will not find the safety gear.</p><p>In villages and towns, the speed limit is 50kph (31mph). Outside of towns the limit is 130kph (80mph). Seatbelts are obligatory for both driver and passenger, but most commercial vehicles do not have seatbelts.</p>
<p>If you are driving, it is imperative to have a valid driving licence or Internationlal Driving Permit.</p>
<p>It's useful to carry your passport to show officials, as they usually ask for it at check points. However, it's advised to also carry a photocopy of your passport to show instead of the real document as this could avoid frustrating scenarios with corrupt police officials.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bus and minibus services operate in Dakar. Blue public buses come every 30 to 60 minutes during the daytime. Smaller<strong>&nbsp;</strong>white public buses come more often but these buses do not stop at many places.</p>
<p>The colourful blue and yellow <em>car rapide</em> is one of Senegal&rsquo;s iconic symbols. Each one is painted differently, and they all state 'ALHAMDOULILAH' (Praise be to God) across their fronts. Car rapide costs vary depending on where you&rsquo;re going.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Senegal Airlines (<a href="http://www.senegalairlines.aero" target="_blank">www.senegalairlines.aero</a>), which flies within the continent. If travelling from the UK, options include flights with Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) via Paris, Iberia (<a href="http://www.iberia.com" target="_blank">www.iberia.com</a>) via Madrid, Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>) via Casblanca, and&nbsp;TAP Portugal (<a href="http://www.flytap.com" target="_blank">www.flytap.com</a>) via Lisbon. Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) operates direct flights from New York to Dakar.</p>
<p>The cheapest time to fly to Senegal is between January and February.</p>
<p>The building of a replacement airport 45 km (28 miles) inland, Aeroport International Blaise Diagne, started in 2007 and is due to be completed in December 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 8 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the past few years there have been reports of luggage going missing at the airport, so make sure you have travel insurance just in case you cannot recover your luggage. It&rsquo;s also advisable to use locks on your luggage to avoid anybody tampering with your belongings when you arrive at Dakar airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the past few years there have been reports of luggage going missing at the airport, so make sure you have travel insurance just in case you cannot recover your luggage. It&rsquo;s also advisable to use locks on your luggage to avoid anybody tampering with your belongings when you arrive at Dakar airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cap Skirring Airport</b><b>Tel: </b><b>Léopold Sédar Senghor International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 17km (10.5 miles) northwest of the city (journey time - 25 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Senegal&rsquo;s main port is Dakar. It's one of the largest deep-water&nbsp;seaports&nbsp;along the&nbsp;West African&nbsp;coast. Other ports major commercial ports are found in Kaolack, Matam, Podor, Richard Toll, Saint-Louis and&nbsp;Ziguinchor.</p>
<p>There are several options if you want to travel to Dakar by sea. Cargo ships on their way from Europe offer passenger services and cruise ships run a regular service from various ports around the world.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Recent reports highlight that the Dakar-Bamako train is no longer running.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's possible to travel to Senegal from Europe by road, and many people do either by their own means or with a tour company. However, recently, because of instability in the north of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/">Mali</a> (one of the entry points to sub-Saharan West Africa) it is not advisable to take the Sahara route.</p>
<p>The following route is recommended if you are thinking of undertaking this adventure: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a> &ndash; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/morocco">Morocco</a> &ndash; Western Sahara &ndash; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mauritania">Mauritania</a> &ndash; Senegal. If you are driving straight through, without stopping, this itinerary should take you about a week to complete.</p>
<p>It's also possible to travel to Senegal by road from other countries in the whole of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/africa">Africa</a>. One of the most popular routes is to and from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa">South Africa</a>. Itineraries for this trip are varied, and it's advisable to enquire within a relevant forum for up-to-date information.</p><p>West African borders are sometimes known for being troublesome to cross for novices to overland travel. Make sure that you have valid multiple-entry visas for all countries you are to cross, as well as a valid driving licence, insurance and proof of vehicle ownership.</p>
<p>Another bit of advice would be to act confident and friendly when talking to immigration officers and border police, know a bit of conversational French and, even though we do not condone this, have a spare bit of cash if it comes to an officer asking you for a back-hander; it does happen unfortunately and it can speed things up tremendously.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Senegal's telephone network is extensive, with landlines in use throughout the country. However, since the advent of mobiles, these have taken over in popularity. It is still possible to make international calls using a prepaid calling card.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile phone coverage is limited to the main cities and tourist areas. Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafes in Dakar, Saint Louis and other major towns. However, out in rural villages, don't expect to be able to get online; and if you do find a connection, it is more likely to be a slow dial-up than super-fast broadband.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Senegal's constitution guarantees freedom of the news media, although there are laws prohibiting reports that discredit the state or incite disorder. Still, the country has traditionally enjoyed a liberal media climate, and private media frequently criticise the government. In recent years, however, there have been a number of attacks on journalists. Publications must be registered, but foreign publications circulate freely and multichannel pay-TV is readily available.</p><p><em>Le Soleil</em> is the state-owned daily whilst <em>Sud Quotidien</em> and <em>Wal Fadjri</em> are privately published. Radiodiffusion Television Senegalaise (RTS) is the state-run national broadcaster that operates the RTS1 and RTS2 TV channels. The RT Salso operates the Chaine Nationale and Chaine Internationale networks, the capital's 94.5 FM and Dakar FM, as well as four regional services. Sud FM is a private station available in Dakar and other cities, whilst Radio Nostalgie is a Dakar-based private station. Sept FM is a private Dakar station operated by Groupe Com 7, while Walf FM is operated by Groupe Wal Fadjri.  BBC World Service and Radio France Internationale are available on FM in Dakar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes between seven and 10 days, and surface mail between two and six weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Cap Vert Peninsula</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Strap on the flippers and discover Senegal's underwater world by scuba diving off the awe-inspiring Cap Vert peninsula. Enthusiasts will find good diving waters all around this area, with February to April being the best months. Located about 80km (50 miles) off the coast of Dakar, the Cape Verde Islands are home to more than 70 shipwrecks that have sunk over the last four centuries.  These include the <em>U.S.S. Yorktown, The Lady Burgess, The Norfolk,<strong> </strong></em>and <em>The Hartwell</em>, among others.  Not all of the older wrecks are accessible to divers, but many of the artefacts are on display in the capital, Praia.</p>]]><p><b>Carabane Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hidden amongst the <em>bolongs</em> (mangroves), in the Casamance region of Senegal, L'île de Carabane is a perfect place for those looking for good value accommodation, in a quiet and relaxed location rich in history, local legends and culture. It's possible to rent a dugout canoe and go fishing, walk to the mouth of the Casamance River, or get a guided tour of the many interesting places that overflow with mysterious stories. Why not ask about why the Colonial General is buried upside down with his dog in the old colonial cemetery? For more information get in touch with the Campement Villageois D'Elinkine (<a href="http://www.campementvillageoiselinkine.e-monsite.com" target="_blank">www.campementvillageoiselinkine.e-monsite.com</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Casamance</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the well-watered, fertile Casamance area in the south of Senegal, and choose to drop into Cap Skirring where you'll find some of the finest beaches in West Africa, can visit some of the inland islands rich in culture, legends and colonial history, or explore the old colonial towns where structural remnants of the infamous transatlantic slave trade still remain. For a list of community-based ecotourism projects contact the Fédération des Campements Villageois (FECAV) (tel: 77 558 1421). Check the latest developments before venturing as the area has been home to a long-running conflict.</p>]]><p><b>Grande Mosquée</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gaze at the soaring Grande Mosquée, Dakar's most famous mosque (noted for its minaret, which is lit at night). Although closed to the public, it is located in Medina, a bustling area that makes for some interesting people-watching. Built in 1964 with financial assistance from King Hassan of Morocco, the building is inspired by the Mohammed V mosque in Rabat in the Maghreb style. It is possible to climb its tall minaret every day except Friday, when the mosque is only open to Muslims for prayer.</p>]]><p><b>Institut Fondamental d'Afrique Noire (IFAN)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Check out the Institut Fondamental d'Afrique Noire (IFAN) (<a href="http://ifan.ucad.sn" target="_blank">http://ifan.ucad.sn</a>), Dakar's main museum, which has a collection of masks, statues and musical instruments from West Africa; and the Palais Présidentiel (Presidential Palace) which is surrounded by luscious gardens. Art, historical artefacts, and ethnographic material have been collected for the IFAN museum since 1941. Now there are other branches of IFAN across West Africa, in Côte d'Ivoire, Guinea, Mali, Benin, Burkina-Faso, Cameroon, Togo and Niger.</p>]]><p><b>Kafountine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join an ecotourism programme in the beautiful town of Kafountine, in the Basse Casamance region. Situated in a typical fishing and farming village, the community-based tourism camp called 'Sitoko' (tel: 77 403 6218) is a great introduction to traditional life in the southern region of Senegal. Other villages around the area also offer traditional accommodation and activities for tourists. (Note that political instability and a long-running conflict in this area means travellers should check before venturing there.)</p>]]><p><b>Kedougou</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Sightsee around eastern Senegal, one of the best-kept secrets of the country, and visit the Bedik, Bassari and Tenda people of the Kedougou area - their villages are situated in the middle of breathtaking landscapes. It is not easy to access the villages of these sometimes nomadic tribes, and therefore it may be advisable to find a guide who is knowledgeable of the tribes' migration patterns, and who speaks the local dialects to avoid any misunderstandings. In Kedougou you can rent bicycles. If you think you are fit enough, cycle all the way to Dindefelo (<a href="http://www.ecosenegal.org/en/kedougou/dindefelloreserve" target="_blank">www.ecosenegal.org/en/kedougou</a>), located at the bottom of a cliff that marks the beginning of the Futa Djalon escarpment and entry point to one of the only two waterfalls in Senegal.</p>]]><p><b>Lac Rose</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Named because of the unusual tint of pink that the lake displays at certain times of the year as a result of a high concentration of algae-eating bacteria associated with very salty bodies of water, the 'Lac Rose' is popular with the adventurous travellers as well as thousands of birds including flamingos, spoonbills, pelicans, herons, terns and waders.  It is possible to swim in the lake, or just float as the high concentration of salt allows for bathers to remain afloat without trying very hard. The locals also farm salt here.</p>]]><p><b>Lac de Guiers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The largest inland lake in Senegal, the Lac de Guiers attracts visitors for its wealth of birdlife and its hunting reserve found to the east of the lake. Fed by the Ferlo River, the lake is also teaming with fish, and during the months of November and January, huge nets are cast from the banks by the local population and drawn in by fishermen in <em>pirogues</em>, the local name for the dugout canoes.</p>]]><p><b>N’Gor Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>L'île de N'Gor is located a few minutes away from Dakar's main airport, and is a gem for unexpected events, good seafood, and fun characters if you are inclined to explore some of the more off-the-beaten track alleyways meandering across this small Caribbean-like paradise. Whether you are looking to catch some of the best surf in West Africa (<a href="http://www.gosurf.dk" target="_blank">www.gosurf.dk</a>), are looking for a culinary treat of fresh fish straight from the sea, prefer to relax on golden sand beaches whilst listening to the reggae rhythms, or are an art enthusiast looking for your next purchase, this is the place to go.</p>]]><p><b>Palmarin N’Gallou</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Palmarin is rural community running along a 17km- (11-mile) peninsula on the most southern stretches of Senegal's Petite Côte. To the west are the sandy beaches skirting the expanse of the Atlantic Ocean. Located to the east is the protected National Reserve de Palmarin, a patchwork delta consisting of mangrove channels, salt flats, grass lands and forest. This unique combination of habitat supports a wide assortment of plant and animal life. An exciting place to stay in Palmarin is at the Lodge des Collines de Niassam (<a href="http://www.niassam.com" target="_blank">www.niassam.com</a>) where there is an option to stay in a tree house, in the mighty Baobab tree.</p>]]><p><b>Parc National Aux Oiseaux Du Djoudj</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Prime the binoculars at Parc National Aux Oiseaux Du Djoudj, a birdwatchers paradise at the southern edge of the Sahara. Created in 1971, the park extends over 60000 hectares (150,000 acres) and is one of the most important bird sanctuaries in the world and is listed by UNESCO as a World Heritage site. Djoudj, the world's ninth most important ornithological site, attracts thousands of birdwatchers every year. The park is open from 1st November to 30th April and closes each day at noon. This means a very early start is required if one is taking a pirogue excursion to Djoudj from St. Louis or driving the 90 minutes ride to the reserve.</p>]]><p><b>Parc National de Niokolo-Koba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spot large mammals in the Parc National de Niokolo Koba (<a href="http://www.niokolo.com" target="_blank">www.niokolo.com</a>). The park encompasses Sudanese savannah and the Guinea forest. Over 84 species of mammal live here, including Africa's largest lions, elephants (extremely rare), panthers, crocodiles and a variety of antelopes. The region is the nearest part of Africa to Europe and the US where it is possible to view such a variety of birds and animals in natural surroundings.</p>]]><p><b>Petite Côte (Little Coast)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At an hour's drive south of Dakar, la Petite Côte (Little Coast) stretches for some 150km (94 miles) and is considered one of Senegal's best beach areas. With a stunning coastline, idyllic climate and a number of good modern hotels, this area has become a magnet for European sun lovers who have little interest for the more adventurous side of Senegal. The main tourist resorts in the area are Mbour and, slightly further north, Saly Portudal.</p>]]><p><b>Popenguine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This small village on the shores of the Atlantic Ocean is located just 70km (43 miles) south of Dakar on the Petit Cote. Popenguine is a member of Global Ecovillage Network of Senegal (GENSEN). It is known for its natural reserve, pristine sandy beach, and religious significance. It is also the weekend getaway for the President of Senegal, as the second presidential residence is located between Popenguine and the village of Ndayane.</p>]]><p><b>Saly</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try your luck with a fishing rod. Deep sea sport fishing can be organised in Saly, or, for a more relaxed fishing experience, float down Senegal's creeks and rivers. Senegal offers fantastic fishing for enthusiasts as well as holidaymakers with a casual interest, from the Nile Perch in the Senegal River to the abundance of sailfish and marlin in its offshore waters.   Deep sea fishing can be arranged in Saly whilst more relaxing trips can be arranged in the creeks, rivers and mangroves of the Sine Saloum delta.  Most hotels organise such trips either in small pirogues or motorised boats.</p>]]><p><b>Siné-Saloum delta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the Siné-Saloum delta, a wild region of mangrove swamps, dunes and lagoons. Go on a trip in a pirogue (traditional African boat) through the Parc National du Delta du Saloum, out to the delta's myriad small islands, scattered between <em>bolongs </em>(channels). Another exciting activity available in the delta is a flight in a ULM or micro-light over the mangroves, where you may, if you are lucky, follow the impressive flight of the pink flamingos as they migrate from one feeding spot to another. For more information on ULM activities, visit Senegal Experience (<a href="http://www.senegal.co.uk" target="_blank">www.senegal.co.uk</a>).</p>]]><p><b>St Louis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Wander the nostalgic and provincial streets of Senegal's former capital, St Louis. Its narrow, atmospheric streets are flanked by beautiful colonial houses, balconies and verandas. The fishing community here is the most interesting area of town, especially when their day's catch is laid out to dry. Don't miss the Faidherbe Bridge, a testament to St. Louis' colonial past or if you happen to be in the city at the right time, the world-renowned St. Louis International Jazz Festival (<a href="http://www.saintlouisjazz.org" target="_blank">www.saintlouisjazz.org</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Toubab Dialao</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This small village to the south of Dakar, past Rufisque, is noted for its spectacular setting. In contrast to the rest of La Petite Côte, Toubab Dialao's beaches are bounded by steep cliffs of red rock. The beach's breathtaking potential reveals itself at sunset, at which time the sun reflects, off the cliff faces, hues of bright orange, red and deep crimson upon the little fishing beach. A Gaudi-esque accommodation option is available at Sobo Bade (<a href="http://www.sobobade.com" target="_blank">www.sobobade.com</a>), or for something a little more quaint and intimate, contact Daouda Fall, a local poet, to stay at his appropriately named 'Chez le Poete' (<a href="http://www.gvcc.sn" target="_blank">www.gvcc.sn</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Île de Gorée (Gorée Island)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head for the tranquil, World Heritage-listed Île de Gorée (Gorée Island) just 3km (1.8 miles) outside of Dakar, and accessible by boat. One of the most infamous slave trading posts in West Africa, it has a long colonial history and is crammed with attractions such as the Maison des Esclaves (Slaves' House), Le Castel, a towering castle-like structure complete with WWII gun turrets, or the many restaurants serving delicious seafood, fish and local dishes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US $15.36 billion (2013).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Fish, peanuts, cotton, petroleum products and phosphate products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food and beverages, capital goods, transport equipment, fuels and computer equipment.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, India, Switzerland, Nigeria, China</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Senegal is the second most industrialised country in French West Africa. In 2007, Senegal signed agreements for major new mining concessions for iron, zircon and gold with foreign companies. There are thought to be oil reserves both on- and offshore.<br/><br/>The country's main export commodity is groundnuts, and the farming industry also produces millet, sorghum, maize, rice and vegetables for domestic consumption. Fish products have become an important export commodity, and the government also accumulates revenues from the sale of fishing licences to other countries, mostly from the EU.<br/><br/>GDP growth in 2013 was up 4.1% and it is forecasted to grow at a rate of 4.9% for the next 4 years. Inflation stood at 0.8% in 2013, but official unemployment rates, from 2007, remain high at 48%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A lightweight suit is advised. French will generally be needed for meetings. Appointments should be made and punctuality is expected, despite the fact that a customer may be slightly late. Business cards are essential, preferably in French and English. The right hand should be used for handshakes and to pass items. The period from July to October should be avoided for business visits, as many people are on holiday.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1300 and 1400-1700. During Ramadan, some offices open 0730-1430.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Chambre de Commerce et d'Industrie et d'Agriculture de la Région de Dakar</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 823 7189
					Website:http://www.cciad.sn/
					Address: 1 place de l'Indépendance,BP 118,Dakar,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The food markets of Senegal teem with colour and the bright clothes that the vendors wear blend with their wares of tropical fruits and vegetables. Senegalese food is considered among the best in Africa, with an unmistakable influence from French and Moroccan cuisine.</p><p>Peanuts are the main crop of Senegal and everywhere the aroma of roasted peanuts fills the air, whilst seafood is the mainstay of the diet. The basis of many dishes is chicken or fish whilst Beef and lamb are eaten less frequently but peanuts infuse a distinctive taste to local dishes. This food is served in many restaurants in Dakar, while provincial rest houses serve less sophisticated but delicious variations. There are bars in some hotels and clubs. Senegal is predominantly a Muslim country, and while there is a conspicuous absence of pork from menus, alcohol is available.</p><p>When dining in one of the excellent Senegalese restaurants, you will usually be offered a selection of appetizers from a list of 20 or so, all prepared with great care. The soups will be rich and full-bodied. There will be entrees in abundance. Then a long list of fancy desserts, all served with great flair, showcasing the French vibe still present in Senegal's cuisine.</p><p>In Dakar you can have fabulous meals at Le Bissap Baobab (<a href="http://www.bissapbaobab.com" target="_blank">www.bissapbaobab.com</a>), Tam Tam, and Les Cannibales Deux; restaurants which could compete with the finest anywhere.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><em>• Chicken au yassa </em>(barbecued chicken in an onion and lemon sauce).<br/><em>• Tiebou dienne</em> (herb-stuffed fishcakes with rice).<br/><em>• Maffé </em>(any West African meat in a peanut sauce).<br/><em>• Dem à la St Louis</em> (stuffed mullet).<br/><em>• Avocat au crevettes</em> (avocado stuffed with shrimp).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>In a Senegalese home you would follow the custom of pouring water over your hands as you enter the dining area and then you would wipe them on a common cloth. It is frowned upon to eat with your left hand, so if you're left-handed make sure you sit on your hand to avoid any faux pas.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A service charge of 10 to 15% is included in all hotel and restaurant bills.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dakar is one of the best cities to witness the most colourful and energetic live music available in the region. There are several nightclubs and music venues playing <em>mbalax</em> (the local modern music). Youssou N'dour, the world renowned king of mbalax and international celebrity, even has a nightclub in Dakar called Le Thiossane known for having the most packed dancefloor in town. Whenever he is not touring N'dour performs for a short time in his club on almost every Friday and Saturday night.</p><p>Just 4 U is another popular nightspot in Dakar. It is located on Avenue de l'Est in the university district, and has a spacious bar restaurant with live music.  The place has become a key fixture on the West African music circuit. The setting – an outdoor patio area with chairs and tables arranged under canvas awnings – adds a cosy, laid-back vibe.</p><p>But Dakar is not the only place where you can find good music. The Senegalese have music in their blood, and wherever and whenever you will find music, dance, laughter and good times.</p><p>Along the beaches, most Saturdays, groups of youngsters carry their sound systems and play a selection of the best reggae sounds, which you can enjoy with a glass of rum, under the stars, with the sound of waves and African beats in the background.</p><p>In most villages around the country, at least one person has a djembe, a traditional drum, or a balafon, a bit like a wooden xylophone, to jam with. With a bit of encouragement, a party will be started in no time. The Senegalese do not need any excuses to let loose and enjoy the best life has to offer.</p><p>There are many cinemas showing the latest French films. The Daniel Sorano National Theatre in the Boulevard de la Republique is a popular venue for theatre, concerts and other arts performances. Dakar is host to traditional Senegalese wrestling matches on weekends.</p><p>The Institut Français (<a href="http://www.institutfrancais-senegal.com" target="_blank">www.institutfrancais-senegal.com</a>), on Rue Carnot in Dakar, is a hotspot for events, films, art displays, theatre productions and good food. Although, it's a little bit on the expat side of the fence, it is still a place that should be visited if you are into modern art and independent films.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors to Senegal should go to some of the many colourful markets. They are abundant with a range of bargains from food to handmade crafts and electronics. Most markets and centres sell wooden carvings, traditional fabric, embroidery, pottery, necklaces of clay beads and costume jewellery of wood or various seeds. There is a craft village at Soumbedioune, on the Corniche de Fann, where the visitor can watch craftspeople at work and buy their handicrafts. Purchases include woodcarving in the form of African gaming boards, masks and statues; musical instruments; and metalwork, including copper pendants, bowls and statuettes.</p><p>However, if you want to get away from the tourist hustle and bustle and immerse yourself in the real market vibe, cross over to the fish market just next door, either early in the morning or in the late evening, to have a chance of seeing what really happens in Soumbedioune.</p><p>Another interesting market is that of Marché des HLM. Located in what would be considered as the council houses district, this market is the best place in the whole of Dakar to find some of the most colourful and exquisite West African style fabrics you could hope for. Just pick a few fabrics you like, bargain the price down to what you can afford, and then take it to a local tailor to make the shirt or dress you have always imagined yourself wearing. There are also a few places here where you can sit down and drink <em>ataya</em>, the local black-leaf tea, and watch the world go by.</p><p>If you are looking for souvenirs and gifts, Marché Kermel is probably your best bet. Located behind Avenue Sarraut, this covered market originally built in 1860 sells a mix of foodstuffs such as herbs, spices and local ingredients as well as some original and unique souvenirs that would make great gifts for friends and family back home. Don't forget to pay attention to the beautiful architecture of the building in which the stalls are located!</p><p>Generally Mon-Sat 0830-1230 and 1530-1930. Some shops open Sunday morning, others are closed Monday.</p><p>Like anywhere in the world, it is advisable to be streetwise when walking through the markets of Dakar. Make sure that your bags are always visible and that you pay careful attention to your pockets to avoid any unpleasant surprises.</p><p>In Senegal, bargaining is part and parcel of the culture. It is a fun way to interact with the traders and can get you a good bargain, if you are patient and insistent enough. The general rule for bargaining is to wait until the trader suggests a price, halve it and suggest that price, and then gradually increase the price, back and forth with the vendor until you reach a price that is agreeable for both parties.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government-controlled expansion of tourism has led to an increasing number of hotels, with international chains such as Pullman and Radisson opening hotels within the country. Increasing investment has led to more and more development and the choices for travellers are far more numerous than they were, even just a couple of years ago.</p><p>Dakar has the lion's share of hotels, but there are a number of ocean-front hotels along Saly-Portugal on the Petite Côte (the stretch of beaches between Dakar and Joal), which are favoured by European visitors. In the Casamance, some luxury resorts have been built. It is advisable to book accommodation in advance, particularly in Dakar, where there is an increased demand during the tourist season, which lasts from December to May. Hotels in Dakar generally have air conditioning but tend to be expensive.<br/><br/>Note that electricity is often cut off at night in Senegal so it is a good idea to have a torch, although the bigger hotels will often have a generator.<br/><br/><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels are classified from 1 to 4 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Campements </em>are loosely translated as 'lodges' or 'inns' and are basically guesthouses in rural areas of Senegal. Note however, that despite the name, they are not a camping ground or a place for tents. Some campements provide cheap, basic accommodation while others have gone upmarket offering similar standards to mid-range hotels. These are good alternative for the more budget-conscious traveller, or those who don't want to stay in a large resort.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government-controlled expansion of tourism has led to an increasing number of hotels, with international chains such as Pullman and Radisson opening hotels within the country. Increasing investment has led to more and more development and the choices for travellers are far more numerous than they were, even just a couple of years ago.</p><p>Dakar has the lion's share of hotels, but there are a number of ocean-front hotels along Saly-Portugal on the Petite Côte (the stretch of beaches between Dakar and Joal), which are favoured by European visitors. In the Casamance, some luxury resorts have been built. It is advisable to book accommodation in advance, particularly in Dakar, where there is an increased demand during the tourist season, which lasts from December to May. Hotels in Dakar generally have air conditioning but tend to be expensive.<br/><br/>Note that electricity is often cut off at night in Senegal so it is a good idea to have a torch, although the bigger hotels will often have a generator.<br/><br/><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels are classified from 1 to 4 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The government-controlled expansion of tourism has led to an increasing number of hotels, with international chains such as Pullman and Radisson opening hotels within the country. Increasing investment has led to more and more development and the choices for travellers are far more numerous than they were, even just a couple of years ago.</p><p>Dakar has the lion's share of hotels, but there are a number of ocean-front hotels along Saly-Portugal on the Petite Côte (the stretch of beaches between Dakar and Joal), which are favoured by European visitors. In the Casamance, some luxury resorts have been built. It is advisable to book accommodation in advance, particularly in Dakar, where there is an increased demand during the tourist season, which lasts from December to May. Hotels in Dakar generally have air conditioning but tend to be expensive.<br/><br/>Note that electricity is often cut off at night in Senegal so it is a good idea to have a torch, although the bigger hotels will often have a generator.<br/><br/><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels are classified from 1 to 4 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Senegal is severely lacking in terms of medical resources – there are only around 20 hospitals in the entire country.  Dakar has the majority of these, a mixture of both private and public. Clinique du Cap on Avenue Pasteuris well-equipped, whilst Principal hospital on  Avenue Nelson Mandela is a modern hospital and training centre. There is much more in terms of facilities available in urban areas, compared to rural villages, where doctors and facilities are minimal. However, it is essential to have health insurance if visiting. For an ambulance in Dakar, call SOS Medecin (tel: 889 151) or SAMU (tel: 33 628 1213).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated, and water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should first be boiled or otherwise sterilised. Bottled water is readily available everywhere. Milk is likely to be unpasteurised and should be boiled. Alternatively, use powdered or tinned milk, both of which are available. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unpasteurised milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water, but it's fine to use swimming pools which are well-chlorinated and maintained; these are likely to be safe. Vaccinations against meningococcal meningitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Korité (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Korité itself. Korité and Tabaski (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Independence Day :
							04 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Ascension Day :
							10 May </p><p>Whit Monday :
							21 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following may be imported into Senegal by travellers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of spirits and 1 bottle of wine.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of perfume and 1 bottle of eau de toilette.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited items include obscene publications, narcotics and subversive publications.</p>
<p>Restricted items requiring a permit include firearms and ammunition, medicines (other than for personal use), meat and endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Restricted exports requiring authorisation include leather, salt, gold and endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>CFA (Communauté Financière Africaine) Franc (XOF) = 100 centimes. Notes are in denominations of XOF10,000, 5,000, 2,000,1,000 and 500. Coins are in denominations of XOF500, 200, 100, 50, 25, 10, 5 and 1.<br/><br/>Senegal is part of the French Monetary Area. Only currency issued by the Banque des Etats de l'Afrique de l'Ouest (Bank of West African States) is valid; currency issued by the Banque des Etats de l'Afrique Centrale (Bank of Central African States) is not. The CFA Franc is pegged to the Euro.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money-changers can be found throughout Senegal, with exchange rates generally more favourable at border points. However, be careful to keep your money in a secure place and watch out for scams.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express is the most widely accepted, although Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa have limited use. Commissions are added for the use of credit cards and many businesses may not accept payments with foreign cards. It is best to carry cash for the majority of transactions</p><p>There are ATMs throughout Senegal (although they are more limited outside the cities) and they are fairly widespread throughout Dakar. However, many do not accept foreign cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are easy to cash in Dakar. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take them in euros rather than dollars. There is limited or no acceptance outside Dakar, however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1115 and 1430-1630.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Turkey"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Switzerland"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Senegal, a passport valid for at least three months from entry is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above. You may be refused entry if no evidence of return or onward travel can be produced.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Children travelling alone must carry a notarised letter of consent from their parents/guardians.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are staying in Senegal for more than three months, you must obtain a 'Carte d'Etranger'.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[14.900006]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-14.599036]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>196,722 sq km (75,955 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>15,589,485 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>71 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Dakar.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Located just above the equator, Senegal is bordered by Guinea Republic and Guinea-Bissau to the south, Mali to the east, Mauritania to the north, and completely encloses the confederated state of The Gambia. To the west lies the Atlantic Ocean. Most land is less than 100m (330ft) above sea level, with plains constituting the majority of the country&rsquo;s geography, apart from the Fouta Djallon foothills in the southeast and the Bambouk Mountains on the Mali border.</p>
<p>On the coast between Dakar and St Louis is a strip of shifting dunes. South of Dakar there are shallow estuaries along the coastline, which is fringed by palm trees. In the northern part of the country, south of the Senegal Basin, lies the arid Fouta Ferlo, a hot dry Sahelian plain with little vegetation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Around 94% Muslim, 5% Christian (mostly Roman Catholic with some Protestants) and a minority holds traditional beliefs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Greetings are appropriate when coming across local people, especially in the bush. Visitors should make the effort to learn these in one of the local languages, and a knowledge of basic French is also advisable. Handshaking on meeting, regardless of how many times a day one meets the person, is common.</p><p>When visiting a village, it is polite to call upon the village headman or schoolteacher to explain that you want to spend the night there or visit the area. They will often act as an interpreter and will be helpful guides in learning the customs of the village and also in terms of money, ensuring that a traveller does not find himself in the embarrassing position of paying for hospitality that was given in friendship.</p><p>Always accept offerings, and return hospitality with a gift of medicines, food or money for the community. It is not advisable to give money indiscriminately as tourists have encouraged the practice of begging. Casual wear is widely acceptable. Scanty swimwear should be reserved for the beach. Smoking is prohibited in some public places (especially mosques).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Various plug types with two or three round pins are in use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Mohammed Dionne since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Macky Sall since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Toucouleur people, among the early inhabitants of Senegal, converted to Islam in the 11th century, although their religious beliefs retained strong elements of animism. The Portuguese had some stations on the banks of the Senegal River in the 15th century and the first French settlement was made at St Louis in 1659 as Gorée Island became a major centre for the Atlantic slave trade through the 1700s. The British took parts of Senegal, but the French gained possession in 1840 and made it part of French West Africa in 1895.</p><p>In 1946 Senegal became an overseas territory of France and on 20 June 1960, it formed an independent republic federated with Mali, but the federation collapsed within four months.</p><p>Senegal has played a prominent role in African politics since its independence. As a black nation that is more than 90 per cent Muslim, it has been a diplomatic and cultural bridge between the Islamic world and other parts of Africa while maintaining closer economic, political and cultural ties to France than many other former colonies.</p><p>Its first president, Léopold Sédar Senghor, an acclaimed poet and member of the Académie Française, towered over the country's political life until his retirement in 1981 although he replaced multi-party democracy with an authoritarian regime.</p><p>In 1973 Senegal co-founded the West African Economic Community, but when rising oil prices and fluctuations in the price of peanuts, a major export crop, ruined the economy in the 1970s, Senghor reversed course and emphasised new industries such as tourism and fishing.</p><p>When the economy continued to stagnate Senghor resigned in favour of his protégé Abdou Diouf who led the country for the next 20 years, initiating further economic and political liberalisation. In March 2000, opposition party challenger Abdoulaye Wade won 60 per cent of the vote in multi-party elections. In January 2001, the Senegalese voted in a new constitution that legalised opposition parties and granted women equal property rights with men.</p><p>In September 2002, 1863 passengers were killed when the state-owned Joola ferry sank. The government accepted responsibility for the disaster, which is considered the second worst non-military maritime disaster in history.</p><p>Despite constitutional term limits, President Wade ran for a third term in 2012 sparking violent protests that threatened to destabilise the country. In the event, Wade lost to former prime minister Macky Sall, who has remained in power since.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• More than 3000 Peace Corps volunteers have served in Senegal since 1963.</p><p>• Senegalese griots have kept their region's oral history alive for thousands of years through words and music.</p><p>• The African Resistance Monument in Dakar is the tallest statue in Africa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Senegal in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7938 4048.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.senegalembassy.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7938 4048.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700; 1030-1500 (consular section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>39 Marloes Road<br/>London<br/>W8 6LA<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Senegal in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ambasenegal-us.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0800-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Senegal]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>823 7392.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/senegal</p><p><b>Tel:</b>823 7392.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thur 0800-1630, Fri 0800-1230.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>20, rue Docteur Guillet<br/>Dakar<br/>6025<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Senegal is 'The Country of Teranga'. Teranga, if you didn't know, means hospitality in the local tongue of Wolof, and you will indeed find this to be one of the friendliest spots in West Africa. Don't be surprised to find yourself being invited into someone's home to eat one of many mouthwatering dishes.</p><p>A simple wander around the local markets will unearth handmade fabrics and authentic arts and crafts, while on almost every street corner in the towns and cities you'll find musicians full of energy. You'll also be tempted into bustling locales serving up rich cuisine influenced by the Maghrebis, French and Portuguese.</p><p>Most visitors land in Dakar, the chaotic, fast-growing capital, which despite its great nightlife and restaurants, can give you a bad first impression of the country. Golden beaches are a stone's throw away, however, while to the north are the mighty Baobab trees of the Sahel.</p><p>Indeed, the diversity of Senegal is perhaps its best feature. In the southeast is the mountainous region of Fouta Djallon, home to secretive tribes and beautiful waterfalls. The southern Casamance region boasts palm-fringed tropical beaches and islands. The west is populated by mangroves and one of the largest concentrations of migratory birds in the world. Top of the country's selling points is perhaps the wildlife, which apart from birds includes giraffes, elephants, hippos, rhinos, lions and panthers.</p><p>Senegal is also an exciting place for outdoor adventure types. Surf some of the best waves in West Africa in year-round warm waters, hike through lush tropical rainforest-clad mountains and discover towering waterfalls, or go deep-sea fishing off the continental shelf.</p><p>Culture vultures won't be disappointed either. There are year-round music and art festivals such as the St Louis Jazz Festival, and well-managed museums displaying some of the most interesting artefacts found in the region. You'll also find well-preserved colonial ruins, as well as reminders of the infamous trans-Atlantic slave trade.</p><p>Easily accessible from Europe and the US, offering an array of experiences, with up to eight months of sun a year, and one of the best infrastructures in the region, what's not to like? Whatever you're after, Senegal probably has it.</p><p>With long sandy-white beaches, a hip music scene, colonial heritage and stunning wildlife, Senegal is <em>the</em> place to head in West Africa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
