<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Serbia" ColCode="srb" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="rs" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Serbia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Serbia has a mild continental climate with cold winters and warm summers. The north of Serbia and the upland regions have a continental climate, with the typical cold winters and hot summers. The summer months of June to August offer a lovely hot climate and little rain. The mountains experience heavy snowfall, and the ski season is generally from December to March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In winter, mediumweight clothing and heavy overcoat; in summer, lightweight clothing and raincoat required.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no internal flights within Serbia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internal rail services are generally poor. Services are often unreliable and slow. Destinations accessible by rail include Belgrade, Nis, Novi Sad, Subotica and Bar on the Montenegrin coast. For further information, contact Serbian Railways (<a href="http://www.serbianrailways.com/" target="_blank">www.serbianrailways.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>InterRail One-Country Pass: offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Serbia. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p>Eurail Croatia-Slovenia-Montenegro-Serbia Pass: offers travel for four, five, six, eight or 10 days in two months within these countries. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving throughout Serbia is relatively safe, but you should check your travel insurance covers you throughout the country.  Driving at night is not advisable on minor roads in the countryside, owing to the poor condition of some roads. There are tollbooths along the motorways, with foreign-registered vehicles charged at a higher toll than local vehicles. The toll also depends on the size of a vehicle. Foreigners may pay in Euros, but at a 20% premium.</p>r<p>Generally roads are kept in good condition within the cities, with quality deteriorating somewhat in rural areas. The Ibarska Magistrala, which links Belgrade to Montenegro, is a particularly dangerous road and should be avoided when possible.</p><p>Travelling by coach is one of the most popular ways to get around Serbia. There is a good network of buses which criss-cross the country and small villages are usually accessible by bus. Lasta (<a href="http://lasta.rs" target="_blank">http://lasta.rs</a>) is one of the most biggest and most reliable coach companies.</p><p>Main cities have metered taxis. In Belgrade, official taxis are identifiable by having a blue taxi sign on the roof of the car. It's possible to negotiate a fare when the meters are not in use, but in this case, agree a fare before setting off.</p>
<p>When arriving at Belgrade airport, only take taxis from the designated area upstairs in departures (not at arrivals). Watch out for taxi drivers who may attempt to scam tourists into paying higher fares by saying a destination is much further away than it should be, or running the meter fast.</p><p>A national driving licence or International Driving Permit is required. No customs documents are required, but car log books, a Green Card and vehicle registration/ownership documents and locally valid insurance policy are necessary.</p><p>Speed limits are 120kph (75mph) on motorways, 100kph (62mph) on major roads, 80kph (50mph) on other roads, and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas. Road signs may be poorly marked and new signs are likely to be in Cyrillic script in some areas of the country. Seat belts must be worn at all times. Children under 12 are not allowed to sit in the front passenger seat.</p><p>For roadside assistance call 1987; for police 192. The number for ambulance services is 194.</p><p>Both major international and local firms offer car hire at airports and main towns.</p><p>Cycling is possible throughout Serbia and a proportion of the local population uses bikes to get around. The Danube Bike Trail allows cyclists to follow a signposted route along the Danube on designated bike paths throughout the entire country and into the rest of the Balkans.</p>
<p>In Belgrade there are dedicated cycling paths which run along the river and on pavements. Bike hire is possible from a few select rental shops; try iBikeBelgrade (tel: +381 66 900 8386; <a href="http://www.ibikebelgrade.com" target="_blank">www.ibikebelgrade.com</a>).</p><p>Speed limits are 120kph (75mph) on motorways, 100kph (62mph) on major roads, 80kph (50mph) on other roads, and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas. Road signs may be poorly marked and new signs are likely to be in Cyrillic script in some areas of the country. Seat belts must be worn at all times. Children under 12 are not allowed to sit in the front passenger seat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are good bus services in the main towns, with tram and trolleybuses in Belgrade. You can use multi-day passes or buy a reloadable smartcard. Some trolleybuses have a conductor seated near the rear of the vehicle.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Serbia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">subotica</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Serbia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">novi_sad</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Serbia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">nis</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Serbia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kragujevac</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main carrier is Air Serbia (<a href="http://www.airserbia.com" target="_blank">www.airserbia.com</a>), whose routes include direct flights from the UK. There are plenty of indirect options via other European cities with airlines such as Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com" target="_blank">www.airfrance.com</a>) or Swiss (<a href="http://www.swiss.com" target="_blank">www.swiss.com</a>). There are no direct flights from the USA.</p>
<p>The major airport is: Belgrade Nikola Tesla Airport.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 40 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 10 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Belgrade Nikola Tesla Airport </b><![CDATA[http://www.beg.aero<p>The airport is located 18 km (11 miles) west from central Belgrade</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+381 11 209 4000</p>]]><b>Nis Constantine the Great Airport </b><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rail services to Belgrade run from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>, Croatia, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/greece">Greece</a>, Hungary, Montenegro, Romania and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/turkey">Turkey</a>. Trains from western Europe travel via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/budapest">Budapest</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/zagreb">Zagreb</a>. The route from Bar on the Montenegro coast, to Belgrade, is famously scenic. For more detailed information contact Voyages SNCF (<a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>). International trains have couchette coaches as well as bar and dining cars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass: </strong>offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Driving to Serbia from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>&nbsp;takes around two days, involving travel across <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belgium">Belgium</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/austria">Austria</a> and much of the Balkans &ndash; it&rsquo;s bordered by <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bosnia-and-herzegovina">Bosnia and Herzegovina</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hungary">Hungary</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/montenegro">Montenegro</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia">Croatia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kosovo">Kosovo</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/macedonia">Macedonia</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/romania">Romania</a>.</p>
<p>The E-75 motorway takes you through Hungary before heading on towards Novi Sad. The E70 motorway comes from the west, via the border with Croatia. An alternative, although longer route is to drive overland through <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/switzerland">Switzerland</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a>, before taking a ferry from Italy to Montenegro, and continuing the journey from there.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are public payphones in Serbia which accept telephone cards rather than cash. These can be bought at any newsagent or post office. Pre-paid Halo telephone cards costing 200-300 dinars allow both local and international calls, whilst a Halo Plus card allows only international calls at a cheaper rate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Double-check with your phone company as to whether Serbia is included as part of Europe for data purposes, as some companies classify it outside of the European zone and will charge higher roaming rates. Coverage is good in the north and in Belgrade, but can be patchier in the south.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafés can be found in the main urban centres. Most hotels and self-catering apartments will have Wi-Fi but it may not be wholly reliable. In Belgrade, free Wi-Fi hotspots can be found within proximity of most Nestle ice-cream stands. You do not have to buy an ice-cream to use their Wi-Fi.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Serbian media is reasonably free and offers differing perspectives that vary from sensationalist to serious along with a spectrum of political stances that range from liberal to nationalist. The main daily newspapers are <em>Vecernje Novosti</em>, <em>Glas Javnosti</em> and <em>Kurir.</em></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Serbian postal service is reasonably good, with yellow post boxes found in most areas. Post to Western Europe takes from 3-4 days for delivery. Post to the USA and Australia is estimated to take from 5-9 days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1900, Sat 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Dine out in Skadarlija</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belgrade's 19th-century bohemian quarter boasts restaurants serving typical Serbian cuisine, especially <em>cevapi</em>, grilled minced meat. If you choose to sit outside, don't be surprised if you're serenaded at dinner. There are also several art galleries nearby.</p>]]><p><b>Disentangle the diverse history of Nis</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the Ottoman sights of Nis, Serbia's third largest city in the southeast boast plenty of relics from the Ottoman era, including a fortress and the gruesome Skull Tower. The remains of the Roman town of Mediana also lie in the vicinity.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the culture wonders of Novi Sad</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Often referred to as the "Serbian Athens", Novi Sad is an attractive city on the Danube and a cultural centre with museums, galleries, libraries and theatres along with numerous churches that represent a wide variety of denominations. The second city is also home to the imposing Petrovaradin Citadel.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the sprawling Djerdap National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The gorgeous Djerdap National Park spans 64,000 hectares (158,146 acres) and is a paradise for nature lovers. Its main attraction is the Djerdap Gorge, a river valley made from four gorges. Other national parks worth a look are Sara, Fruska Gora, Kopaonik and Tara.</p>]]><p><b>Follow Serbia's old wine routes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Serbia is a long-running producer of wines and following some of the old wine routes is rewarding. The Palic wine route follows the trail of "Wines from the Sands" where the winemaking tradition is over 2,000 years old. Other wine routes in Serbia include Vrsac, Oplenac, Smederevo, Negotin and Zupa.</p>]]><p><b>Hike through the Fruska Gora region</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go hiking or birdwatching in the hills of the national park of Fruska Gora to the south of Novi Sad, following woodland trails and discovering half-hidden monasteries. Dominated by a lone mountain, the reserve stretches as far as the Danube River, to the edge of the historic city of Sremski Karlovci.</p>]]><p><b>Make a pilgrimage to the Monastery of Zica</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Near Kraljevo, visit the restored Monastery of Zica where the kings of Serbia were once crowned. It was built by the first King of the Serbs in the 13th century, and is curious red-coloured structure, with a modest Orthodox-style dome. In the same part of central Serbia are the pretty Kalenic and Ljubostina convents, both fine examples of the Serbian Morava School of architecture.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the Sargan Eight Railway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a pleasure ride on the Sargan Eight Railway at Mokra Gora, close to the Bosnian border. An old narrow-gauge railway that was once an important part of the Belgrade to Sarajevo route, it was closed in the 1970s. The hour-long railway journey climbs 300m (1,000ft) in just 3.5km (2 miles), winding through pretty green hills most of the way.</p>]]><p><b>Tap into the cultural buzz of the capital Belgrade</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Belgrade has a bit of everything. In the Old Town, visit Kalemegdan Park and Belgrade Fortress overlooking the confluence of the Sava and Danube rivers. Nearby landmarks include the enormous Cathedral of St Sava and Princess Ljubica's Konak, an 1831 Turkish-style residence. There's also an irreverent nightlife held down by Sava, for which Belgrade has earned the moniker "new Berlin".</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at the museums of Belgrade</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit some of Belgrade's excellent museums and galleries: the Nikola Tesla Museum for live demonstrations of the scientist's impressive inventions and the Museum of Yugoslav History where former prime minister Tito is buried within the grounds. At the Ethnographic Musuem visitors can learn more about Serbia's culture and see handcrafted artefacts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$37.4 billion (2012).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Iron and steel, clothes, rubber, wheat, fruit and vegetables.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil, natural gas, fuels and lubricants, electrical machines, chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Italy, Bosnia & Herzegovina, Montenegro, Germany and Russia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Serbia was the largest constituent republic of the former Yugoslavia. Between 1990 and the overthrow of Slobodan Milosevic in 2000, civil war and the 1999 NATO bombing, followed by economic sanctions, reduced its economy to less than half its previous output. Much of its infrastructure and industrial capacity was destroyed.<br />
<br />
Since 2000, the economic outlook has been brighter and the lifting of sanctions has restored access to international markets and capital. GDP growth for 2007 was estimated at 7.5% but growth has stalled since the start of the financial crisis. Serbia continues to suffer from high unemployment (26% in 2012) but the country has adopted trade agreements with the neighbouring EU, Turkey and Russia. Pending a resolution to the thorny issue of Kosovo&rsquo;s independence, Serbia has expressed a desire to follow in the footsteps of Croatia and join the European Union, with accession talks set to take place in early 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Things can go slowly on account of the cumbersome bureaucracy but most Serbian entrepreneurs are very keen to forge business links with Western Europe. Communication is not a major problem as English is popular as a second language.</p>
<p>When on official business, men may wear a smart suit along with shirt and tie, whilst women may wear formal trousers or skirts. Greeting people for the first time with a handshake; a single kiss (or three if between men) is a less formal greeting for someone you already know. It is customary for guests to bring a modest gift for the host, such as wine or flowers. When making a toast, be sure to make eye contact as it is considered rude to look at the glass or elsewhere.</p>
<p>In 2008, the Government of Kosovo declared independence from Serbia. Serbia has rejected Kosovo's declaration of independence as illegal, but the UK government, and most EU members, have granted recognition. Many Serbs feel strongly about Kosovo, with many opposed to its declared independence. You should be wary about entering into sensitive political discussions with people you do not know well.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Belgrade Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (11) 264 1355
					Website:http://www.kombeg.org.yu
					Address: ,Kneza Milosa 12,Belgrade,11000]]><b>Serbian Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (11) 330 0900
					Website:http://www.pks.rs
					Address: ,Resavska 13-15,Belgrade,11000]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Like most of the Balkans, Serbian cuisine is strongly influenced by its centuries of Ottoman and Austro-Hungarian rule, so expect plenty of <em>cevapcici &ndash;</em> grilled minced meat &ndash; borek-style meat pies, and <em>baklava</em>.</p>
<p>There's also a taste for cured meats here, as well as hearty stews, soups and examples of Western influence such as pickled foods and jams. Turkish-style coffee is popular in Serbia, though it has begun to be overtaken by espresso in recent years, at least amongst the metropolitan crowd.</p>
<p>Diners can also expect plenty of fish on the menu, particularly freshwater fish such as trout and carp. Vegetarian options are, alas, somewhat limited.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pihtije</strong>: Jellied pork or duck.<br />
<strong>Cevapcici</strong>: Charcoal-grilled minced meat.<br />
<strong>Raznjici</strong>. Skewered meat.<br />
<strong>Sarmaorjaprak</strong>: Vine or cabbage leaves stuffed with meat and rice.<br />
<strong>Pljeskavica</strong>: Meat patties of pork, beef and lamb.<br />
<strong>Karađorđeva&scaron;nicla</strong>: Stuffed and bread veal steak, served with tartar sauce.<br />
<strong>Srpskiđuveč</strong>: Casserole prepared with tomatoes, peppers, potatoes, rice, hot chilli peppers, diced pork and onion, first fried and then baked in the oven.<br />
<strong>Teleći&scaron;umadijskikotlet</strong>: Veal cutlet served with Serbian cheese, tomatoes, bacon, sour cream, potato, rice and hot chilli peppers.<br />
<strong>Dimljenave&scaron;alica</strong>: Smoked, grilled strip of pork.<br />
<strong>Pasulj</strong>: Serbian beans preapred in a broth or a soup cooked with onion, bay leaves, bacon or smoked spare-ribs.<br />
<strong>Riblja čorba:</strong> A fiery fish stew made with plenty of pepper and paprika. <br />
<strong>Slivovica:</strong> Potent plum brandy.<br />
<strong>Rakija:</strong> Traditional regional spirit derived from grapes.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>10% is expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cinemas stay open until 2300, restaurants until midnight and nightclubs until 0300 or later. Belgrade has excellent nightlife with a range of performance arts to enjoy: operas, concerts, theatre, many late-night caf&eacute;s and clubs. Many <em>splavovi</em> (rafts) on the Danube and Sava rivers in Belgrade also serve as floating restaurants and nightclubs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shopping isn&rsquo;t Serbia&rsquo;s strong point but there are still gems and bargains to be found. Western brands are thin on the ground (the likes of H&amp;M having just opened in Belgrade) but most urban centres have a smattering of malls housing a variety of brands. For those looking for something different, Belgrade has plenty of independent boutiques where you&rsquo;ll find the best of Serbia's designers stocked.</p>
<p>Concept stores like Supermarket (<a href="http://www.supermarket.rs/">www.supermarket.rs</a>) and Mikser House (<a href="http://mikser.rs/en" target="_blank">http://mikser.rs/en</a>) are great places to pick up interesting design and interiors pieces, as well as fashion, whilst independents like L&rsquo;Atelier (<a href="http://latelierbelgrade.blogspot.co.uk" target="_blank">http://latelierbelgrade.blogspot.co.uk</a>) stock chic high-end pieces from both international and domestic labels. More designer clothing shops can be found along the pedestrianised street of Knez Mikhailova. A couple of regular flea markets are held within the city but the quality of product isn&rsquo;t particularly high. It&rsquo;s fine to haggle if buying in bulk.</p>
<p>For special purchases, look out for markets or street stalls selling embroidery, lace, leatherwork, knitwear, metalwork and Turkish coffee sets.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1500-2000, Sat 0800-1500 (many shops are open all day Sat). Supermarkets and grocery stores keep longer hours. Many shops on Belgrade's Knez Mihailova stay open until late in the evening.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Deluxe/5-star hotels in Serbia are confined to Belgrade and Novi Sad. In the smaller towns there may be little choice beyond the mid-price, state-owned range. Some former state-owned hotels in Serbia have been taken into private ownership and refurbished and a number of small boutique hotels have opened in Belgrade, Novi Sad and Nis.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Classification is from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Motels in Serbia are found on most main roads, usually near the outskirts of towns. Prices are set independently according to region, tourist season and the quality of service.<br />Some people offer rooms, often with meals, to visitors in villages without hotels. Discounts are available off-season. Contact tourist offices or travel agencies for details.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Deluxe/5-star hotels in Serbia are confined to Belgrade and Novi Sad. In the smaller towns there may be little choice beyond the mid-price, state-owned range. Some former state-owned hotels in Serbia have been taken into private ownership and refurbished and a number of small boutique hotels have opened in Belgrade, Novi Sad and Nis.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Classification is from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Deluxe/5-star hotels in Serbia are confined to Belgrade and Novi Sad. In the smaller towns there may be little choice beyond the mid-price, state-owned range. Some former state-owned hotels in Serbia have been taken into private ownership and refurbished and a number of small boutique hotels have opened in Belgrade, Novi Sad and Nis.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Classification is from 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Doctors are well trained but medical facilities are limited. Some medicines may not be as freely available as they are at home. Basic medical treatment is free to UK residents with the better-equipped hospitals located in the bigger cities. Prescribed medicines must be paid for. Private practices and dental clinics will see foreign tourists, but expect to pay a fee; this may be stipulated cash only. Health insurance with emergency repatriation is recommended. Pharmacies are open Mon-Fri 0800-2000 and Sat 0800-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe to drink, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Bottled water is readily available. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat. If in doubt, use common sense and peel, boil or cook food to reduce chances of an upset stomach. Serbia's exchange rate makes it an attractive place to drink and eat out making the risk of a sore head after overindulging all too high!&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tick-borne encephalitis is present in some rural areas. Precautions such as using repellent and wearing long trousers should be taken. Pre-exposure vaccination is not always available. Any ticks found should be carefully removed and medical attention sought. Hepatitis B vaccinations are recommended for trips longer than one month. Avoid contact with animals, as rabies can be found in in Serbia. Consider getting vaccinated if you are likely to be in close proximity to animals.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Orthodox Christmas Day :
							2018<br/>07 January </p><p>St Sava Day :
							2018<br/>27 January </p><p>National Day :
							15 February </p><p>Orthodox Good Friday :
							06 April </p><p>Orthodox Easter Monday :
							09 April </p><p>Labour Days :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							09 May </p><p>St Vitus Day :
							28 June </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into Serbia without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of alcoholic drinks.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of perfume and 1 bottle of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Goods up to the value of &euro;100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drugs, and weapons and ammunition, unless they are for hunting purposes and the hunt is organised by the Hunting Association of Serbia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must obtain permission from the Ministry of Culture to export items of artistic or cultural value. Hunting trophies require a shipping document or trophy certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The official currency in Serbia is the Serbian Dinar. Serbian Dinar (RSD; symbol Дин.) = 100 paras. Notes are in denominations of Дин.5,000, 1,000, 500, 200, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of Дин.20, 10, 5, 2 and 1.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As elsewhere in the ex-Yugoslav republics, the most frequently exchanged currencies are the Euro and US Dollar. Pound Sterling can also be changed with ease. Money should be exchanged through official exchange offices only. There are several money-exchange machines in Belgrade (including one at the airport), accepting Pounds Sterling, US Dollars and Euros, giving back Dinars. Scottish and Northern Irish Pound Sterling bank notes are not accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International credit cards such as Visa and MasterCard are accepted in most shops, hotels and restaurants in Serbia. Diners Club and American Express are not so widely accepted.</p><p>ATMs are commonplace across the larger cities of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/belgrade">Belgrade</a> and Novi Sad, with most accepting international bank cards. Obtaining cash may be more difficult in the countryside so ensure you have enough money before going to a more rural location.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although acceptable in theory, in practice these can be very hard to exchange. It is advisable to take hard currency and credit or debit cards.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0800-1900, Sat 0800-1500. Some are open on Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Serbia, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a valid national ID card.</p>
<p>Make sure you get an entry stamp in your passport on arrival as anyone without one of these can suffer problems and a fine on departure. Do not attempt to enter Serbia via Kosovo as the Serbian government doesn't recognise Kosovo as an official entry point, and doesn't recognise Republic of Kosovo passport stamps.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If a child is travelling with only one parent, the other parent must supply a letter of authorisation. If a child is travelling with a third party, authorisation is required by both parents or the guardian.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Serbia is not a signatory to the Schengen agreement, but it does allow Schengen visa holders to enter without needing to obtain an additional visa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit/short-stay visa: &pound;44. (Fee varies for a few nationalities.)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Transit visa: single, double or multiple stays of up to five days each within a six-month period; short-stay visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nearest consulate or embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For information on temporary residence, visit the Ministry of Interior website (<a href="http://www.mup.gov.rs">www.mup.gov.rs</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least a month for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All travellers to Serbia must have proof of sufficient funds, which are considered to be &euro;50 per day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas can only be extended (up to a further 90 days) in exceptional circumstances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing your pet to Serbia, your animal must have a veterinary certificate for Serbia and a valid rabies vaccination certificate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[43.855025]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[20.590035]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>77,474 sq km (35,246 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>8,812,705 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>92.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Belgrade.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Serbia borders Hungary to the north, Romania to the northeast, Bulgaria to the southeast, Kosovo, Macedonia and Albania to the south, Montenegro to the southwest, Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina to the west and Croatia to the northwest. Northern Serbia is dominated by the flat, fertile farmland of the Danube and Tisa valleys. The scenery varies from rich Alpine valleys, vast fertile plains and rolling green hills to bare, rocky gorges as much as 1,140m (3,800ft) deep, thick forests and gaunt limestone mountain regions. Belgrade, the capital, lies at the confluence of the Danube and Sava rivers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Majority Eastern Orthodox Serbs, with a Muslim ethnic Albanian minority, a Muslim ethnic Slavic minority in the Raska region of the southwest, a Roman Catholic ethnic Serbian and Croatian minority, a Protestant ethnic Hungarian minority (in the province of Vojvodina) and a small Jewish community.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Avoid taking pictures of military installations and of obvious bomb damage from 1999, which may cause ill feeling.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Ana Brnabic since June 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Aleksandar Vucic since June 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Inhabited since prehistoric times and conquered by Celts, Greeks and Romans over the ages, the area occupied by modern-day Serbia has had a potted history. But the country's story really begins with the arrival of the Serbs on the borders of the Byzantine Empire in the 6th and 7th centuries. Cyril and Methodius converted the Serbs to Orthodox Christianity in the 9th century, which led to years of struggle and cooperation with the Byzantines.</p>
<p>By the 13th century, Serbia was independent &ndash; but not for long. As the Byzantine Empire was taken over by the Ottomans, the Turks commenced half a millennium of rule over the Serbs. This era changed many aspects of the country's culture &ndash; notably the cuisine &ndash; without fundamentally altering the Serbian identity, which remained Orthodox Christian and rather proud of its embattled history.</p>
<p>During the 19th century, Serbs gained control over their country again, but the assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand by a Bosnian Serb triggered the invasion of Serbia by Austria-Hungary and the start of WWI. The aftermath of the war saw the beginnings of Yugoslavia, initially a kingdom composed of Croatia, Slovenia, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Serbia and Macedonia.</p>
<p>Serbian resistance to fascist rule during WWII led to great suffering at the hands of the Nazis, though the partisans led by one Josip Broz Tito won the day; Tito eventually became the leader of post-war Yugoslavia, managing to unite the disparate contingents of the country while he lived.</p>
<p>Later, though, Serbian dominance of Yugoslavia led to violence and the bloody disintegration of the composite state. The culmination of this was the attempt by the Serbs to empty Kosovo of its Albanian population, leading to the US and NATO-led bombing of the country in 1999. In 2000, the infamous reign of Milosevic finally came to an end when he tried to deny the results of the country's presidential elections; Serbs took to the streets in Belgrade and in 2001 Milosevic was arrested and extradited to The Hague to face claims of war crimes.</p>
<p>Montenegro left its union with Serbia in 2003, while Kosovo declared independence in 2008; to date, Serbia has not formally recognised the latter state. The country currently has candidate status to become a member of the European Union.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; It is believed that the Vinča, who occupied the Serbian area around 6000 BC, had one of the earliest known forms of writing.<br />
&bull; Due to the indomitable resistance to fascist rule, Serb deaths during WWII are thought to number as much as half a million.<br />
&bull; Prime minister Zoran &ETH;inđić was assassinated in 2003; he was instrumental in bringing about Milosevic's extradition to The Hague.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Serbia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 9049.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.london.mfa.gov.rs</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 9049.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1700. The consular section is open to the public 1000-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>28 Belgrave Square<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8QB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Serbia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 0333.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.serbiaembusa.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 332 0333.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700. The consular section is open to public Mon-Fri 1000-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2134 Kalorama Road<br/>Washington DC<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Serbia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(11) 3060 900.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/serbia</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(11) 3060 900.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs, 0800-1630;    Fri 0800-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Resavska 46<br/>Belgrade<br/>11000<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although its reputation took a hammering during the disastrous collapse of Yugoslavia in the 1990s, Serbia has since become one of Eastern Europe&rsquo;s most entertaining destinations. Much of that is down to Belgrade, which, despite NATO bombing during the Milosevic regime, has emerged as a dynamic, edgy city with an appetite for hedonism.</p>
<p>Home to numerous excellent museums and galleries, a wide range of restaurants and caf&eacute;s, and some of the best nightlife in southeast Europe, Belgrade is drawing comparisons with some of the world&rsquo;s coolest cities. It is also helping lead the rest of the country into a bright and hopeful future, with a young generation of creative and outward-looking Serbs reshaping the historic land that was founded as a principality some 1,200 years ago.</p>
<p>Away from the capital, Novi Sad is an attractive, lively city with an elegant centre and picturesque fortress overlooking over the Danube. In the far north, Subotica has an array of secessionist architecture and a notable Hungarian character.</p>
<p>The province of Vojvodina, north of Belgrade, has some excellent wetland habitats that are home to numerous bird species, while south of the capital the countryside consists of lush, wooded valleys with hidden-away Orthodox monasteries. Scattered among the country's more mountainous regions are a number of vast national parks.</p>
<p>Serbia is known for the forthright character of its citizens; its resilient culture has survived numerous occupiers and foreign rulers over the centuries. Despite their formidable reputation, visitors will find Serbs to be passionate but welcoming. As an Orthodox Christian country, it remains to a large degree deeply religious, though this fact is belied somewhat by the hedonism found in its bigger cities.</p>
<p>While there are still some political problems in Serbia, which has yet to formally recognise Kosovo after it unilaterally declared independence in 2008, the country has turned a corner. It is officially a EU candidate and many Serbs are hopeful of the change in economic fortunes that might be brought by becoming a full member.</p><p>Although its reputation took a hammering during the disastrous collapse of Yugoslavia in the 1990s, Serbia has since become one of Eastern Europe&rsquo;s most entertaining destinations. Much of that is down to Belgrade, which, despite NATO bombing during the Milosevic regime, has emerged as a dynamic, edgy city with an appetite for hedonism. Home to numerous excellent museums and galleries, a wide range of restaurants and caf&eacute;s, and some of the best nightlife in southeast Europe, Belgrade is being compared with some of the world&rsquo;s coolest cities.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
