<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Seychelles" ColCode="syc" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sc" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Seychelles]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lying just below the equator, the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seychelles">Seychelles</a> enjoy a tropical warm climate all year round, which makes it a great place to visit most times of the year. Whilst temperatures reach maximums of around 32°C (90°F) and rarely drop below 23°C (73°F), the islands do receive monsoon rains from November to April with the northwest trade winds, despite being outside the cyclone belt. There is no distinct dry season, but this time of year does tend to be more hot and humid season in general and those visiting from December to March are most likely to experience rain.  From April onwards, the heat gives way to a period of cooler weather, and rougher seas when the trade winds blow from the southeast (May to October).</p><p>In general, Seychelles doesn't have a weather-related tourist season – peak season is more dictated by the timing of school holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For the all round warm weather lightweights and cottons are your best bet, with breathable waterproofs advisable during the rainy season. Sun hats and sunglasses are essential all year round, as is sunscreen.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flying is the only way to reach the more remote islands of the Seychelles. Air Seychelles (<a href="http://www.airseychelles.com" target="_blank">www.airseychelles.com</a>) operates a scheduled shuttle service between Mah&eacute; and Praslin, taking around 15 minutes. It also provides domestic chartered services from Mah&eacute; to Alphonse, Bird, Denis, Desroches Islands and Fr&eacute;gate.</p>
<p>Zil Air (<a href="http://www.zilair.com" target="_blank">www.zilair.com</a>) operates inter-island transfers, excursions and chartered scenic flights throughout the Seychelles. The Islands Development Company (<a href="http://www.idc.sc" target="_blank">www.idc.sc</a>) specialises in charter flights mostly to the Outer Islands.</p>
<p>As flights to the more remote islands are often infrequent, it is essential to book in advance.</p><p>All flights operate from Seychelles International Airport, Mah&eacute;, which is 8km (5 miles) south of the capital, Victoria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cat Cocos&nbsp;offers fast crossings between Mah&eacute; (Inter-Island Quay of Victoria) and Praslin (Baie Ste Anne Jetty). The journey takes an hour.</p>
<p>Inter Island Ferry (<a href="http://www.seychelles.net/iif" target="_blank">www.seychelles.net/iif</a>) runs high-speed catamarans which operate between Praslin (Baie Ste Anne Jetty) and La Digue (La Passe Jetty) and take 15-30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The standard of main roads on Mah&eacute;, Praslin and La Digue is good and they are well sign posted. Apart from Victoria, roads are generally quiet.</p>l<p>There are paved roads only on La Digue, Mah&eacute; and Praslin; elsewhere the roads are sandy tracks. Mah&eacute;&rsquo;s roads are often narrow and steep.</p><p>Independently-operated taxis are widely available on Mah&eacute; and Praslin and a handful on La Digue. Fares are controlled by the government and are reasonable.</p>
<p>It's advisable to use a metered taxi or negotiate the fare beforehand. You can hail taxis from the street and taxi stands. Many drivers offer sightseeing tours for a set tariff.</p><p>A valid EU or international driving licence is required to hire vehicles.</p><p>There is a speed limit of 65kph (40mph) on the open road, 40kph (25mph) in built-up areas and throughout Praslin and 80kph (50mph) on the dual carriageway between Victoria and the airport.</p><p>In the event of a breakdown contact your car hire company.</p><p>Saloon cars and 4-wheel drives are available on Mah&eacute;, and there are a limited number on Praslin. Advance reservations are advisable. The minimum age for drivers is 18.</p><p>Bicycles are widely available for hire on Praslin and La Digue. Mah&eacute; is quite hilly but cycles are available at tourist hotels. The narrow main roads on Mah&eacute; are also busy and best avoided.</p><p>There is a speed limit of 65kph (40mph) on the open road, 40kph (25mph) in built-up areas and throughout Praslin and 80kph (50mph) on the dual carriageway between Victoria and the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Victoria, the capital, is small enough to walk around, as are all the main towns in the Seychelles.</p>
<p>The Seychelles Public Transport Corporation (<a href="http://www.sptc.sc" target="_blank">www.sptc.sc</a>) operates bus routes throughout Mah&eacute; and Praslin. Single flat-rate fares are paid to the driver. The service on Mah&eacute; and Praslin is reasonably reliable with up to four buses an hour depending on your destination. Find timetables from tourist offices or online.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Seychelles</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">praslin</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Seychelles</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">la_digue</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Seychelles</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">denis_is</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Seychelles</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bird_is</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to Mah&eacute; in the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seychelles">Seychelles</a> from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> are operated by several airlines via Addis Ababa,&nbsp;<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/abu-dhabi">Abu Dhabi</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/dubai">Dubai</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;Frankfurt. There are no direct flights at the moment. But British Airways (<a href="https://www.britishairways.com" target="www.britishairways.com">www.britishairways.com</a>) will fly directly from London Heathrow to Mah&eacute; during the summer months starting end of March 2018.</p>
<p>Etihad (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.etihad.com">www.etihad.com</a>) operates flights in partnership with Air Seychelles (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.airseychelles.com">www.airseychelles.com</a>), the national airline, and flies via Abu Dhabi;&nbsp;Emirates flies via Dubai; Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="http://www.ethiopianairlines.com" target="_blank">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>) flies via Addis Ababa; and Lufthansa (<a href="http://www.lufthansa.com" target="_blank">www.lufthansa.com</a>) flies via Frankfurt, with the onward flight provided by Condor (<a href="http://www.condor.com" target="_blank">www.condor.com</a>).</p>
<p>April, May, July August and December are peak months for visitors to the Seychelles, so air fares are generally higher during these months.</p>
<p>The main airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seychelles/seychelles-international-airport">Seychelles International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 19 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Seychelles International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://victoria-seychelles.airport-authority.com<p>Seychelles International Airport is situated 10km (6 miles) southeast of Victoria, on the island of Mahé.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+248 384 000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cargo ships call at the Port of Mah&eacute;, but there are no scheduled passenger services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are public payphones available on the islands, although they have been made somewhat redundant by increasing mobile phone usage. Hotels will usually be equipped with landline telephones for guest use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies and coverage is fine on most of the islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several internet cafes on Mahé. Most of the larger hotels have Wi-Fi access for guest use, but internet connections may be rather slower than what is available in Europe or the USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The media is very much controlled by the island's government, with opposition newspapers and dissenting voices often suppressed, despite freedom of speech being enshrined in the constitution.  The government operates SBC (Seychelles Broadcasting Corporation) national medium wave (AM) services and music station Paradise FM; the BBC World Service and Radio France Internationale are available via FM relays.<em> Seychelles Nation </em>is an English-language newspaper (morning daily except on Sundays) whilst <em>Regar </em>is an opposition weekly publication.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main post office is in Victoria. Airmail collections are at 1500 weekdays and 1200 Saturdays; airmail to Western Europe normally takes up to one week.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600, Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Delve underwater at Sainte Anne National Marine Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Scuba-diving, glass-bottom boat trips and snorkelling are popular activities among the coral reefs of this national park, which comprises six islands off the coast of Mahé. Enjoy a relaxing stay on Sainte Anne and Cerf islands, or a mouth-watering Creole meal of tuna on Round Island.</p>]]><p><b>Explore L’Union Estate</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A cycle ride through the peaceful L'Union Estate on La Digue is a great way to see giant tortoises, visit one of the last working copra mills, or reach the cemetery of the original settlers of La Digue. Cool off at the stunning Anse Source d'Argent beach, which featured in the Bounty television advertisements.</p>]]><p><b>Feel like a castaway on Frégate</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Frégate Island, the most easterly and isolated of the granitic islands, is home to the almost extinct magpie robin and many other important bird species. Pass though unspoiled vegetation on your way to one of the island's picture-postcard beaches such as Anse Victorin or Anse Macquereau.</p>]]><p><b>Get close to a giant tortoise</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The world's largest atoll, and listed by UNESCO as a World Heritage Site, Aldabra is <em>the</em> place to see giant tortoises, with 150,000 individuals in all. The atoll consists of 13 islands, making up about one-third of the Seychelles' land mass. Some tortoises have been exported to Curieuse, now a giant tortoise reserve.</p>]]><p><b>Go diving off Desroches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Aquarium, Madam Zabre and Passe Tambi areas around Desroches Island (largest of the Amirantes archipelago) are the best snorkelling spots for sighting turtles, stingrays and colourful reef fish. Scuba-diving is particularly good here too, with sea cliffs, tunnels and caves open to exploration. Visibility is best from September to May.</p>]]><p><b>Hike through prehistoric forests on Praslin</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A UNESCO World Heritage Site, the Vallée de Mai on Praslin is one of only two places in the world (Curieuse is the other) to see naturally-growing Coco de Mer trees and their enormous fruit, which is shaped like a female's lower torso. Visitors can hike three prehistoric forest trails, looking out for endemic palms and birds such as the shy black parrot.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in colonial Mahé</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take in the bustling market, the Botanical Gardens (with Coco de Mer trees, giant tortoises and orchids), and the replica of London's Vauxhall Bridge Tower Clock in Victoria, the capital of the Seychelles, before setting off around the island to visit colonial-style mansions in graceful decline and plantations of cinnamon and vanilla.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the natural beauty of Thérèse</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Uninhabited by humans, discover the rock pools and tortoise colony of this small islet off the western coast of Mahé.  Explore its two rocky peaks which resemble a giant's staircase, relax on the white sand beaches or enjoy snorkelling, sailing, windsurfing and fishing. The boat journey from Port Glaud, Mahé, takes only five minutes.</p>]]><p><b>Photograph rare birds</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The brush warbler, the Seychelles toc-toc and the fairy tern are just some of the rare birds that nest on Cousin Island during April and May. Twitchers should also head to Bird Island, the famed nesting site for millions of sooty terns, which breed there between May and October.</p>]]><p><b>Relax with La Digue’s slow pace</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Today, La Digue's traditional ox-cart transport is reserved for tourists who want to enjoy a gentle and relaxing trip along the island's coastline or take a short excursion to the Rene Payet Veuve Reserve, home to the endangered Seychelles paradise flycatcher found only on La Digue.</p>]]><p><b>Sail your way to Mahé’s best beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hire a yacht and explore the islands and secret covers of Mahé at your own pace. Anse Major is rated as one of Mahé's best beaches, along with Anse Jasmin, Anse Du Riz, and Petit Anse. Alternatively, seek out one of the island's other 70 white-sand beaches spread over 71km (44 miles) of pristine coastline with safe anchorages.</p>]]><p><b>Soak up the sun on Anse Lazio</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Rated as one of the best beaches in the world by, erm, Giorgio Armani, the powder-white sands fringed with large granite boulders of Anse Lazio (Lazio beach) on Praslin Island are just the place to kick back and enjoy peace and panoramas. The clear, warm turquoise seas are an invitation to snorkel.</p>]]><p><b>Spend a night with turtles</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With numerous hatching sites around Bird, Praslin and Mahé islands, you're in with a good chance of watching a hawksbill turtle lay her soft round eggs and cup her flippers to shovel sand back into the hole to cover them. Lying exhausted, she drags her enormous bulk over the sands before disappearing into the turquoise sea. It's an amazing spectacle.</p>]]><p><b>Take up rod and reel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Marlin can be caught off Denis from October to December. The location of Bird Island, at the edge of the Seychelles continental shelf where the sea floor drops rapidly to 2,000m (5,000ft), makes it a favoured destination for deep-sea fishing, while the best spots for salt-water fly fishing are the Alphonse and Desroches Islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$1.03 billion (2012)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Canned tuna, frozen fish, cinnamon bark, copra and re-exports of petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Foodstuffs, machinery, equipment, fuel and petroleum products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK, France, Saudi Arabia, Singapore and Mauritius.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Seychelles economy is largely service based with tourism, the largest industry, accounting for 25% of GDP. In 2012, this stood at $1.03 billion and the annual growth rate was 4%. Inflation stood at 3.2% in January 2014.</p><p>Manufacturing, construction, and industrial fishing, notably tuna fishing, account for about 28.8% of the GDP. Fishing became increasingly important from the 1980s onwards, both through expansion of domestic operations and the lucrative sale of licences to foreign fleets fishing in territorial waters. However, more recently, piracy in the Indian Ocean has hit the fishing industry hard.</p><p><br/>Industry comprises a small mining sector, boat building and light and small-scale food and drinks businesses such as the privatised Seychelles Tuna Canning Factory. There is also a thriving re-export business based on a recently established export-processing zone.</p><p>The main financial problem for the Seychelles is the size of the country's external debt. As the islands must import many essential products (an expensive process given their location) this consumes the bulk of the foreign exchange earned from tourism.</p><p>The Seychelles' isolation from other markets and its reliance on service-based industry makes to particularly vulnerable to economic downturns and global recessions. In order to make itself less reliant on tourism, it has recently promoted the development of the fishing and farming industries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business attire is generally informal so businessmen do not wear suits and ties. However, a smart appearance is advised for both men and woman. Most executives speak English and/or French.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1600. Most government offices and some private businesses are closed on weekends and public holidays.</p><p>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Seychelles Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 323 812
					Website:
					Address: Ebrahim Building,PO Box 599,Victoria,]]><b>Seychelles International Business Authority</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 380 800
					Website:http://www.siba.net/
					Address: ,PO Box 991,Victoria Mahé,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Seychellois Creole cuisine is influenced by African, Chinese, French and Indian traditions. The careful blending of spices is a major feature and much use is made of chillies, coconut milk and breadfruit, the latter often used as a carbohydrate staple in place of rice. There are 10 varieties of chilli, each with a different flavour considered suitable for particular dishes.</p><p>Fish is served many ways – roasted, grilled, curried and raw – alongside chutney and cooked vegetables such as green mango or aubergine. Raw vegetables are usually served with a vinaigrette dressing. Lobster, octopus, pork and chicken are used more frequently than beef or lamb, which must be imported.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Chatini requin</strong>: Mashed boiled shark with fried onion and lime juice.<br />
<strong>Soupe de tectec</strong>: Clams cooked in tomatoes, garlic and ginger.<br />
<strong>Bouillon br&eacute;de</strong>: Spinach broth.<br />
<strong>Cari bernique</strong>: Curried limpet.<br />
<strong>Chatini Seychellois</strong>: Chutney comprising crushed chillies, ginger and garlic, which is often served with fried fish.<br />
<strong>Palm hearts</strong>: Inner core of certain palm trees used in place of rice or cassava.<br />
<strong>Papaya salad</strong>: Shredded green papayas, onion, chilli and seasoning.<br />
<strong>Rousettes</strong>: Fruit bat, prepared in a number of ways.<br />
<strong>Pulao</strong>: Rice cooked with fish, meat or vegetables.<br />
<strong>Ladob</strong>: Served savoury or sweet, this dessert is made of sweet potato and plantain cooked in coconut milk with nutmeg, sugar and vanilla.<br />
<strong>Kat-kat banana</strong>: Banana cooked in coconut milk.<br />
<strong>Carotte banana: </strong>Bananas wrapped in banana leaves with honey and vanilla.<br />
<strong>Seybrew</strong>: Bavarian-style lager.<br />
<strong>Ekyu</strong>: Local beer.<br />
<strong>Calou</strong>: Alcoholic drink made from coconut sap and used in many Seychellois dishes.<br />
<strong>Coco D&rsquo;Amour</strong>: Tropical liqueur made with coconut extract.<br />
<strong>Bacca</strong>: Alcohol made from sugarcane liquor and mainly used on ceremonial occasions.<br />
<strong>Dark Takamaka rum</strong>: Popular night cap.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>A hotel licence permits hotel residents to drink at any time. Alcohol can be sold to anyone between Mon-Fri 1400-1800, Sat 0800-1200 and 1400-1800. Other bars open 1130-1500 and 1800-2200. It is illegal to drink alcohol in public.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most bills include a tip of 5-10%. For exceptional service, an additional tip is always welcome.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Seychelles is not known for its lively nightlife but there are a few buzzing discotheques for night owls. The upmarket Club Lovenut in the centre of Victoria is popular with a young, affluent crowd. Its DJs play local and international hits.</p><p>Two of the hottest nightclubss on Mahé are Tequila Boom, which also hosts theme nights, and La Faya Bar at Bel Ombre in Beau Vallon. Katiolio, near Anse Royale, was one of the first nightclubs to open on Mahé and is the only one situated on a beach.</p><p>The Jungle and The Dome are two of a handful of discotheques on Praslin. There is only one casino here, the Casino del Iles on the Cote d'Or.</p><p>For a touch of culture, try a theatre production at the International Conference Centre (ICCS) in Victoria. They are often staged in Creole, English and French. Alternatively, catch a movie at Deepam Cinema, the only picture house in Victoria.</p><p>If you fancy a flutter, head to the casinos at the Berjaya Beau Vallon Bay Resort & Casino or the Plantation Club. Note that men must wear long trousers.</p><p>You can enjoy a taste of the local <em>camtolet</em> music with dancing at one of the hotels. Most of them hold evening barbecues where the music and dancing take place.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>No visit to the capital, Victoria, is complete without a trip to the Sir Selwyn Clarke market. Here you can find a wonderful array of traditional souvenirs, spices and crafts. They include batik work, woven baskets and tablemats, straw hats and beautifully-crafted wooden furniture, ornaments and model boats.The market is at its liveliest on Saturday mornings and is closed Saturday afternoon and on Sundays.</p><p>Mahé offers the best shopping. The majority of outlets are small boutiques selling pottery, paintings and jewellery made from green snail shells and sea shells. There are a few small shops on Praslin, too.</p><p>Tea-growing and manufacturing is still done on a small scale in the Seychelles. You can purchase the local tea in the shops or try one of the many blends before you buy at the Tea Tavern at the tea factory on Mahé.</p><p>The Seychelles is one of the best places to buy vanilla pods too. The plant is cultivated as a climber around the base of trees and pollinated by hand. Pods can be bought in shops or at the markets. Another spice worth getting hold of is cinnamon, which grows wild on all the islands. It can be bought as oil or the quills of dried bark can be used whole in cooking or grated. If you are tempted to buy a Coco-de-mer, be aware that you will need an export licence.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700, Sat 0800-1200. Some shops close for lunch 1200-1300 weekdays.</p><p>Market vendors do not accept cards so you will need to pay for your purchases in Seychelles rupees (SCR). If you run out of cash, there is an ATM machine close by. Mastercard, Access and Visa are accepted in shops displaying the relevant card logo on their doors or windows.</p><p>There is no need to worry about carrying large goods back to the UK. Most markets and shops in the Seychelles will arrange international postage for you.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although the Seychelles offer the full range of accommodation from self-catering apartments to 5-star hotels, careful planning has ensured that the islands have retained the astonishing beauty and quiet charm that attracted the first tourists. Right from the start, the government decreed that no new building could be higher than the surrounding palm trees, with the result that big-city levels of comfort and convenience have been achieved in thoroughly Seychellois settings. It is advisable to confirm reservations with a deposit, particularly during the high season from December to January and in July and August.<br/><br/>All recently built hotels come well up to international standards and there are numerous large resort hotels. Older hotels and guest houses on the smaller islands may lack some sophistication, but their charming seclusion has long recommended them to those seeking complete peace and privacy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's not all island resorts and beach front hotels. Many B&Bs and guest houses are former plantation houses modestly modernised and run by the resident owner. Thatched-roof chalets and guest houses, built in the local style, are to be found mainly on outlying islands. Generally room rates are lower, meaning these may better suited to backpackers or those on a budget.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although the Seychelles offer the full range of accommodation from self-catering apartments to 5-star hotels, careful planning has ensured that the islands have retained the astonishing beauty and quiet charm that attracted the first tourists. Right from the start, the government decreed that no new building could be higher than the surrounding palm trees, with the result that big-city levels of comfort and convenience have been achieved in thoroughly Seychellois settings. It is advisable to confirm reservations with a deposit, particularly during the high season from December to January and in July and August.<br/><br/>All recently built hotels come well up to international standards and there are numerous large resort hotels. Older hotels and guest houses on the smaller islands may lack some sophistication, but their charming seclusion has long recommended them to those seeking complete peace and privacy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although the Seychelles offer the full range of accommodation from self-catering apartments to 5-star hotels, careful planning has ensured that the islands have retained the astonishing beauty and quiet charm that attracted the first tourists. Right from the start, the government decreed that no new building could be higher than the surrounding palm trees, with the result that big-city levels of comfort and convenience have been achieved in thoroughly Seychellois settings. It is advisable to confirm reservations with a deposit, particularly during the high season from December to January and in July and August.<br/><br/>All recently built hotels come well up to international standards and there are numerous large resort hotels. Older hotels and guest houses on the smaller islands may lack some sophistication, but their charming seclusion has long recommended them to those seeking complete peace and privacy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;There is a large general hospital in Victoria and there are clinics elsewhere on La Digue, Mahé and Praslin, but medical facilities are limited. Visitors may obtain emergency treatment for a basic consultancy fee. Additional medical insurance is advised, including emergency repatriation; the number for medical emergencies is 151. There are several pharmacies in Victoria, and on other islands, government clinics are used. There are dental clinics on Mahé, Praslin and La Digue. Prices vary according to whether they are government clinics or private ones. Many hotels offer a 24-hour doctor on call services for guests.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, if you have a sensitive stomach, you may want to drink bottled water rather than risk abdominal upsets. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Sea swimming around the islands is generally considered safe, but watch out for strong currents; there are usually warning notices in place when this is the case. Anse Intendance, Anse Takamaka and Grand Anse are known to sometimes have dangerous tides and currents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being so close to the equator, the sunlight can be very strong; be sure to use sunscreen, keep hydrated and stay out of the sun between the hours of 1100 and 1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Corpus Christi :
							31 May </p><p>Liberation Day :
							05 June </p><p>National Day :
							18 June </p><p>Independence Day :
							29 June </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seychelles/seychelles-international-airport">Seychelles</a> by travellers aged 18 years or older without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of spirits and 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 200ml of perfume or eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Food items not exceeding Rs3,000.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited goods (unless prior authorisation has been granted) include dangerous drugs, firearms and ammunition, offensive weapons (including spear guns), plants and plant products, animals and animal products, chemicals, radioactive substances, biological specimens, medicines (unless prescribed), poisons, fireworks and explosives.</p>
<p>Pornography is completely prohibited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Seychelles Rupee (SCR; symbol Rs) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of Rs500, 100, 50, 25 and 10. Coins are in denominations of Rs5 and 1, and 25, 10, 5 and 1 cents.<br/><br/><strong>Note: </strong>Tourists must pay hotel bills in foreign currency (in the form of cash, traveller's cheques or credit or debit cards). Payment in local currency is only allowed if an exchange receipt can be shown as proof of the conversion from foreign currency into local currency. The duty-free shop at the airport only accepts credit cards or foreign cash.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Exchange facilities are available at the airport banks, which are open for all flight departures and arrivals. Some bank branches will exchange traveller's cheques and foreign currency. Currency exchange receipts should be kept in order to facilitate re-exchange on departure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted; Diners Club has more limited use.</p><p>ATMs are available in Mahé and Praslin.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted in most hotels, guest houses, restaurants and shops. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in US Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1430, Sat 0830-1100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter the Seychelles, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single parents are sometimes asked for documentation proving their parental responsibility.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Passengers in transit must have tickets with reserved seats for their onward journey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All travellers should have proof of funds to cover their stay, which is considered to be at least US$150 per day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend your visitor's permit for a period of up to three months from the date of issue and for successive periods not exceeding three months at a time to a maximum period of 12 months. There is a fee of Rs5,000 (approximately &pound;290) for each three-month extension (the first three months are free). You must apply at the Department of Immigration at least a week before your current permit expires.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are coming to the Seychelles as a visitor, bringing your pet isn't an option, as animals can only be imported for a minimum period of six months. If you are planning on staying longer, you must obtain an import permit. Your animal requires an up-to-date rabies vaccination certificate and a veterinary health certificate. Depending on your country of origin, your pet will also need to undergo a period of quarantine of two weeks to six months.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-5.415966]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[54.562973]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>455.3 sq km (176 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>97,026 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>203.1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Victoria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Seychelles Archipelago occupies 400,000 sq km (150,000 sq miles) of the Indian Ocean northeast of Madagascar and contains 115 islands and islets. These fall into two groups of markedly different appearance, stemming from their distinct geologies:</p>
<p>Granitic: A dense cluster of 43 islands, these are the only mid-ocean group in the world with a granite rock formation. Their lush green vegetation is tropical in character.</p>
<p>Coralline: Isolated coral outcrops speckling a vast area of the Indian Ocean to the southwest of the granitic group. They rise only a few metres above sea level but are covered with rich and dense vegetation due to fertilisation by copious amounts of guano. There is no permanent population. Aldabra, the largest atoll in the world, contains one-third of all Seychellois land and is a UNESCO-designated World Heritage site.</p>
<p>The largest island in either group is Mah&eacute;, lying 4&deg; south of the equator. It is 27km (17 miles) long by 8km (5 miles) wide and is where <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia/victoria">Victoria</a>, the capital and main port, and 90% of the population are located. Mah&eacute; is typical of the Granitic Islands, being mountainous and covered with jungle vegetation. Its highest point, indeed the highest point in the Seychelles, is Morne Seychellois which stands 905m (2,970ft) high. The isolated nature of the Seychelles has given rise to the evolution of many unique species of flora and fauna, including the coco-de-mer palm and unique varieties of orchid, giant tortoise, gecko, chameleon and 'flying fox' (fruitbat).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>83% Roman Catholic with Anglican, Seventh Day Adventist, Muslim, Baha'i and other minorities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The people live a simple and unsophisticated island life and tourism is carefully controlled to protect the unspoilt charm of the islands. Before the international airport opened in 1971, the islands could be reached only by sea, and since they are miles from anywhere, visitors were few and far between and the people were little influenced by the outside world. They developed their own language and culture which - like so many things on the islands - are unique.</p><p>Shaking hands is the customary form of greeting. The Seychellois are very hospitable and welcome guests into their homes. When visiting someone's home, a gift is acceptable. A mixture of imperial and metric systems operates. For example, petrol is dispensed in litres, whilst bars sell bottled and draught beer in half-pint measures. Casual wear is essential and formal clothes are only worn by churchgoers. Swimwear should only be worn on the beaches.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President James Michel since 2004.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President James Michel since 2004.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Seychelles is a relatively young nation dating back just 200 years to 1770 when French planters claimed Mah&eacute; and seven other islands for France. Until then, the islands were uninhabited, and many of its 115 islands remain so today.</p>
<p>The islands were under French rule for 44 years until Napoleon was defeated at the battle of Waterloo and the British took power under the treaty of Paris in 1814.</p>
<p>The population of around 3,500 had grown to 7,000 by 1825 under the British. Important estates were established producing coconut, food crops, cotton and sugar cane which employed workers of many nationalities. They later faced economic difficulties following the abolition of slavery.</p>
<p>The islands became a Crown colony in 1903 and achieved independence from Britain in 1976. Shortly afterwards, the Seychelles underwent a period of single party rule by the government of Albert Ren&eacute;, who despite several attempts to depose him, retained control of the one-party state throughout the 1980s. Pressure from France and Britain eventually persuaded the Seychelles to adopt a multi-party system of government.</p>
<p>The first multi-party presidential and legislative elections, held in 1993, were won comfortably by Ren&eacute;. Efforts to build up infrastructure, tourism and public services ensured that Ren&eacute; enjoyed more than a quarter of century in power.</p>
<p>The islands&rsquo; melting pot of cultures has contributed to its colourful history. Throughout the centuries, it has attracted a rich diversity of people that have included freed slaves, European settlers, political exiles and traders of Arab, Persian, Chinese and Indian origin. Its isolation has also contributed to the development of the islands&rsquo; own traditions, language and culture.</p>
<p>Today, the Seychellois society remains faithful to its multi-ethnic roots. Creole music and dance have their roots in African, Malagasy and European culture, whilst the <em>moutya</em>, an erotic dance from slavery days, is still enjoyed, as is the <em>kontredanse</em>, which was introduced by the French court. In this way, visitors can glimpse the diverse culture expressed all over the archipelago, through its arts, food, colonial architecture, music and dance.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Victoria is one of the smallest capital cities in the world with just 26,000 inhabitants.<br />
&bull;	Pirate treasure worth over &euro;100,000 is said to be buried somewhere on the islands.<br />
&bull;	The jellyfish tree is one of the rarest on earth, inhabiting only three hilltops on Mah&eacute; Island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in the Seychelles]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>428 3666.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/seychelles</p><p><b>Tel:</b>428 3666.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs, 0800-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>3rd Floor, Oliaji Trade Centre Francis Rachel Street<br/>Mahé<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Consulate of the Seychelles in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7935 7770.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.seychelles-gov.net</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7935 7770.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1500, Fri 0800-1400.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>111 Baker Street<br/>London<br/>W1U 6RR<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Seychelles in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 972 1785.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mfa.gov.sc</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 972 1785.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/><br/><br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Clich&eacute;d or not, the Seychelles are about as close to paradise as you can get: once you&rsquo;ve felt the sand between your toes here, beach holidays will never be the same again.</p>
<p>Made up of 115 topical islands in all, the Seychelles archipelago is a destination where white, sandy beaches are as pure as the driven snow; where frothy turquoise waters harbour colourful coral reefs and bountiful marine life; where secret coves allow you to have your very own Robinson Crusoe moment with only birds and tortoises for company.</p>
<p>Mah&eacute; may be the biggest &ndash; and the busiest &ndash; of the islands, but it has its fair share of secluded bays, which are accessible only by yacht, motorboat or on foot. Together with its sisters Praslin and La Digue, it attracts the lion&rsquo;s share of tourists.</p>
<p>More adventurous travellers, on the other hand, may prefer to take a flying boat to more remote islands such as Fregate or Bird Island and enjoy secluded beaches all to themselves. These islands are especially popular with birdwatchers and nature lovers, due to their abundance of wildlife.</p>
<p>The absence of people on many of the islands means that rare plant life has thrived on this Indian Ocean archipelago. Tropical life abounds below the waves, too. This is best viewed by going scuba diving or snorkelling, experiences which are made all the more memorable here thanks to the crystalline seas.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not all about nature, though. The Seychelles are a veritable melting pot of cultures: its inhabitants descend from African, Asian and European immigrants, who have brought their customs and traditions with them to the islands. This heady mix is particularly pleasing on the palate thanks to the archipelago's fabulous fusion food.</p>
<p>The Seychelles is a seductive destination all right, and one that&rsquo;s guaranteed to whet your appetite for a return trip &ndash; assuming your bank balance can handle it.</p><p>Clich&eacute;d or not, the Seychelles are about as close to paradise as you can get: once you&rsquo;ve felt the sand between your toes here, beach holidays will never be the same again.&nbsp;Made up of 115 topical islands in all, the Seychelles archipelago is a destination where white, sandy beaches are as pure as the driven snow; where frothy turquoise waters harbour colourful coral reefs and bountiful marine life; where secret coves allow you to have your very own Robinson Crusoe moment with only birds and tortoises for company.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
