<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Sierra Leone" ColCode="sle" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sl" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Sierra Leone]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The climate is tropical and humid all year. Between November and April, it is very hot and dry, although the coastal areas are cooled by sea breezes. In December and January, the dry, dusty Harmattan wind blows from the Sahara. Rainfall can be torrential during the rainy season between May and November.</p>
<p>In March there are sporadic rains, accompanied by strong winds, in the provinces when the heat of the dry season reaches its peak. If you decide to travel to the provinces during the month of March it is advisable to bring waterproof clothing to avoid getting drenched when you least expect it.</p>
<p>In August, during the rainy season there is a period called the &lsquo;seven day rainfall&rsquo; when the rain keeps falling for seven days straight without interruption. This time of the year is best avoided if you are looking for a sun soaked holiday on Sierra Leone&rsquo;s beautiful beaches, but it is also the time when wildlife activity is at its peak and therefore a period of the year that attracts a lot of nature lovers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no restrictions on clothing for men or women, with casual attire such as sleeveless shirts, flip flops and sandals the norm. Lightweight and light-coloured, cotton clothing is recommended due to the hot and humid climate. During the rainy season it is advisable to wear wet-weather clothing, while a light jersey or jacket may be needed in the months when the Harmattan winds blow.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Private airlines can be chartered, connecting Hastings, Bo, Kenema, Yengema and Freetown airports. Ask local travel agents such as VSL Travel (<a href="http://www.vsltravel.com" target="_blank">www.vsltravel.com</a>) or the national touristboard (<a href="http://www.welcometosierraleone.sl" target="_blank">www.welcometosierraleone.sl</a>). Major hotels may also be able to organise flights.</p><p>Most privately-owned, domestic airlines, are owned by mining companies like London Mining and African Minerals. It's at their discretion whether they will charter one of their planes or helicopters. Due to Sierra Leone&rsquo;s small size, it's advisable to travel by road.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferries connect the coastal ports of Freetown, Pepel and Sherbro Island.</p>
<p>A variety of privately owned tourism establishments run chartered boat services along the Western Area Peninsula, below Freetown, connecting the Sierra Leone&rsquo;s pristine and secluded beaches (Bureh Beach, John Obey, Black Johnson, River No.2 and Lakka) and tropical islands (Turtle Island, Banana Island and Bunce Island). For more information enquire with local resorts.</p>
<p>Another option for shorter journeys out to sea is to charter a boat from local fishermen along the coast. Befriending the fishermen suddenly opens the doors to traditional fishing, visiting the smaller islands off the coast or for longer but more exciting beach-hopping tours for a reasonable price.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no commercial rail services in Sierra Leone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Travelling by road in Sierra Leone can be a daunting task, but there are a number of good quality tarmacked roads that connect the major cities, and a good network of dirt roads connecting the smaller more remote towns and villages. It's important to note that although it is possible to travel everywhere by road during the dry season (November-May), during the rainy season there are many roads that aren't accessible.</p>
<p>There are several options for travel by road, each at a different price. You can rent a vehicle from a number of car hire companies or charter a taxi from one of the taxi parks in the major towns.</p>r<p>Although the principal highways have a tarred surface, the secondary roads are poorly maintained and often impassable during the rainy season.</p>
<p>There are some roadblocks at night on major roads near centres of population.</p><p>A regular coach service journeys between the major towns of Freetown, Bo and Kenema throughout the day. For more information contact the Road Transport Corporation (tel: +232 78 524 054).</p><p>In major towns there are reliable taxi services that travel predetermined routes. Taxis are yellow and black, and range from five-seaters to people carriers. Usually, a taxi picks up a number of people along the route and charges a &lsquo;one-way&rsquo; or &lsquo;two-way&rsquo; rate depending on the distance. It's possible to rent a taxi for yourself or to share with a group.</p>
<p>You can charter taxis, for long distances, from all the major cities in Sierra Leone.</p><p>A valid International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>You should carry identification such as a passport with you at all times when driving in Sierra Leone. An International Driving Permit is required, and you must be 18 years of age or over. Inner-city roads usually have a speed limit of 50kph (30mph) while highways and motorways have a 130kph (80mph) limit.</p>
<p>Drink driving and driving while using a mobile phone are illegal, but the regulations are not enforced. It's not uncommon to see people on their mobile phones while driving.</p><p>There are no breakdown services in Sierra Leone. However, there are several private mechanics in major towns who will be willing to come out and assist with a breakdown, at a price of course.</p><p>Car hire (with driver) is available from Sierra Leone Car Hire (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sierraleonecarhire.com">www.sierraleonecarhire.com</a>). Most major hotels and travel agents can arrange car hire.  The Foreign and Commonwealth Office advises against car travel outside of Freetown at night.</p><p><em>Ocadas</em> (motorbike taxis) are abundant all over Sierra Leone. A more risky (but equally exciting) mode of transport, they are a fast and reliable way of crossing one side of a town to the other, and of navigating the dirt roads in the provinces.</p><p>You should carry identification such as a passport with you at all times when driving in Sierra Leone. An International Driving Permit is required, and you must be 18 years of age or over. Inner-city roads usually have a speed limit of 50kph (30mph) while highways and motorways have a 130kph (80mph) limit.</p>
<p>Drink driving and driving while using a mobile phone are illegal, but the regulations are not enforced. It's not uncommon to see people on their mobile phones while driving.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A <em>poda-poda</em> (minibus) is the main means of transport between towns. You can find these at the poda-poda parks in major towns or along the most frequented commuter routes (there are currently no pre-determined stops and buses are run on an ad-hoc basis). Alternatively, take the government bus routes (currently only serving Freetown-Bo-Kenema), or for shorter journeys you can hitch a ride on an <em>okada</em> (motorbike taxi).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Flights to Sierra Leone depart from a variety of European and African destinations and are operated by several airlines. Carriers&nbsp;including Air France (<a href="http://www.airfrance.com/">www.airfrance.com</a>) and Brussels Airlines (<a href="http://www.brusselsairlines.com">www.brusselsairlines.com</a>). British Airways flights from the UK are currently suspended due to concerns about the public health situation in Sierra Leone.</p>
<p>Within Africa, Arik Air (<a href="http://www.arikair.com" target="_blank">www.arikair.com</a>) flies to Sierra Leone directly from Lagos, <a href="http://i/nigeria">Nigeria</a>. Royal Air Maroc (<a href="http://www.royalairmaroc.com" target="_blank">www.royalairmaroc.com</a>) flies from Casablanca.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 9 hours (including stopover); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 16 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If arriving in Freetown after dark, you might want to spend the night in Lungi before continuing on to Freetown the next day, as you&rsquo;ll have to cross the Rokel River to enter the capital. There are several options for crossing this waterway.</p>
<p>The best methods of transit can book up rapidly, so it&rsquo;s best to make your arrangements in as far as possible in advance or as soon as possible after disembarking the plane.</p>
<p>A private speedboat charter is one of the more expensive ways to get to Freetown, albeit one of the most fun too. VSL Travel (<a href="http://www.vsltravel.com" target="_blank">www.vsltravel.com</a>) can charter these. Journey time is around 20-30 minutes.</p>
<p>Water taxis (basically, large speedboats) and are one of the safest ways to transfer to Freetown.<br />
<br />
The cheapest option and one popular with locals is to take the ferry to Freetown. Two ferries operate at scheduled times of day with a later ferry running in sync with the last flight.</p>
<p>Lastly, it is possible to drive from Lungi to Freetown via Port Loko, but the drive takes over four hours and makes more sense if you're heading up country rather than to Freetown. Hiring a car while in Lungi may be difficult, so it&rsquo;s best to pre-arrange all transport whilst at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Usually included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If arriving in Freetown after dark, you might want to spend the night in Lungi before continuing on to Freetown the next day, as you&rsquo;ll have to cross the Rokel River to enter the capital. There are several options for crossing this waterway.</p>
<p>The best methods of transit can book up rapidly, so it&rsquo;s best to make your arrangements in as far as possible in advance or as soon as possible after disembarking the plane.</p>
<p>A private speedboat charter is one of the more expensive ways to get to Freetown, albeit one of the most fun too. VSL Travel (<a href="http://www.vsltravel.com" target="_blank">www.vsltravel.com</a>) can charter these. Journey time is around 20-30 minutes.</p>
<p>Water taxis (basically, large speedboats) and are one of the safest ways to transfer to Freetown.<br />
<br />
The cheapest option and one popular with locals is to take the ferry to Freetown. Two ferries operate at scheduled times of day with a later ferry running in sync with the last flight.</p>
<p>Lastly, it is possible to drive from Lungi to Freetown via Port Loko, but the drive takes over four hours and makes more sense if you're heading up country rather than to Freetown. Hiring a car while in Lungi may be difficult, so it&rsquo;s best to pre-arrange all transport whilst at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Freetown-Lungi International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.freetownairport.com/<p>The airport is 13km (8 miles) north of the city (journey time - 45 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main commercial port is Freetown, from where there are services to Guinea and Liberia. A number of cargo ships, including Grimaldi Lines (<a href="http://www.grimaldi.co.uk" target="_blank">www.grimaldi.co.uk</a>) advertise passenger cabins and offer the possibility of travelling to other countries in West Africa via boat.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no public passenger services at present connecting Sierra Leone to neighbouring countries; the only railways are privately owned by the mining companies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sierra Leone is accessible by road via its two borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guinea">Guinea</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/">Liberia</a>. It is possible to reach Sierra Leone by road from Europe and the rest of Africa. The best route for overland travel from Europe is via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/morocco">Morocco</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mauritania">Mauritania</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/senegal">Senegal</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/gambia">Gambia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guinea-bissau">Guinea-Bissau</a> and Guinea and takes approximately six days.</p>
<p>It is possible to cross the continent from East Africa or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa">South Africa</a> to West Africa, overland, in two weeks.</p>
<p>There are no restrictions on the type of vehicles that enter Sierra   Leone, and it is common to see both left-hand and right-hand drive cars on the roads.</p><p>Road conditions across West Africa vary, but it takes several days to travel overland from Europe to Sierra Leone. We recommend you take into consideration the advice from the Foreign Commonwealth Office (<a href="http://www.fco.gov.uk" target="_blank">www.fco.gov.uk</a>) before undertaking such a journey.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>The are no public telephones away from the Western Area of Sierra Leone and the service is generally poor.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mobile telephone coverage extends all over Sierra Leone, however is stronger near major towns and villages where the mobile phone masts are. The major telephone companies are Airtel, Africell and Comium.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafes all over Freetown, Bo and Kenema where internet access is constant but slow. In 2013, a fibre optic cable was introduced to Sierra Leone to increase the coverage and range of internet connectivity in the country. USB modems are also available from the major mobile phone providers and are an easy, but relatively expensive, way of connecting to the internet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Media freedom in Sierra Leone is limited, especially when it comes to reporting corruption; Broadcasters face many challenges, such as unreliable electricity supplies, a shortage of funds and a lack of advertising revenue. The Sierra Leone Broadcasting Corporation (SLBC) was created in April 2010 and operates television and radio services. There are a number of other radio providers; private stations include Kiss FM and SKYY FM and FM relays of BBC World Service and Radio France Internationale are on the air in Freetown. Freetown-based newspapers include <em>Awoko</em>, <em>The Democrat</em> and <em>Concord Times</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe takes about five days. A number of internaitonal and local postal/courier services operate in Sierra Leone.</p><p>Mon-Thurs 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Tiwai Island Wildlife </p><![CDATA[<p>Tiwai, in Mende language, means 'big island', and at 11 hectares (27 acres) this is the biggest inland island in the whole of Sierra Leone. Situated on the Moa River – a long river starting in Guinea and crossing the Eastern Province – Tiwai is home to 11 species of primates (7 of which are endangered, including the colourful Diana monkey), over 700 species of plants (many of which are used in herbal remedies), a large variety of insects and butterflies, and the elusive pygmy hippo which is endemic to the Upper Guinea Forest. There are only 300 left in the wild, 30 of which are on Tiwai. The island is owned by 8 surrounding communities who you can visit and learn about the Mende culture and everyday life. Tiwai is also an entry point to the Gola Forest National Park, which can be reached by hiking through one of the protected natural corridors.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Camp out in Tiwai Island Wildlife Sanctuary</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An island on the Moa River, Tiwai is home to 11 primate species, more than 700 species of plant, and a large variety of insects and butterflies. Its star is perhaps the elusive pygmy hippo. The island is also an entry point to Gola Forest National Park, reached by hiking through one of the protected natural corridors.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Mount Bintumani</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you're looking for 'off-the-beaten' track experiences, Mount Bintumani, Sierra Leone's highest peak at 1,945m (6,400ft) is the destination for you. Part of the Loma Mountains, to reach the summit you will need to hike across high grass plains, cross rickety rope bridges straddling steep gorges, and scramble over vertiginous cliffs. It's all part of the experience, though.</p>]]><p><b>Enjoy the natural beauty of Bonthe Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Despite being still relatively difficult to access via road, Bonthe Island is a must for those interested in history, culture or big game fishing. Surrounded by mangrove swamps, with fish-rich waters and long untouched beaches, the island has long been a tourist drawer, especially with sport fishing enthusiasts since one of the biggest tarpon ever recorded was caught here.</p>]]><p><b>Experience bustling Bo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to Bo's 'Big Market' to bargain for West African fabrics, rub shoulders with traditional herbal remedy hawkers and walk amongst the dried fish stands, taking in the atmosphere and interacting with the traders. In nearby villages you can sample <em>poyo</em> (palm wine), or taste local delicacies such as coconut cake, plantain chips and groundnut shortbread.</p>]]><p><b>Go wildlife watching in Outamba-Kilimi National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Originally protected because of its high density of chimpanzees, Outamba-Kilimi National Park offers varied and spectacular scenery with a mixture of jungle and savannah grasslands. Elephant, rare pygmy hippos and even rarer bongo antelope are all in residence, along with more than 100 different species of bird and the ancestral graves of the Susu tribe.</p>]]><p><b>Head back to school at Old Fourah Bay College</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Listed in 2007 by the World Monuments Fund as one of the world's 100 most-endangered historic sites, Old Fourah Bay College earned Sierra Leone the nickname the 'Athens of West Africa'. The original building, dating back to 1848, is still visible even after suffering significant fire damage.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about the slave trade on Bunce Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a boat trip up the Rokel River to Bunce Island, one of the first slave trading stations in West Africa. Between 1670 and 1808 tens of thousands of slaves left Bunce Island for the West Indies and North America, and you can learn about the history of the slave trade, as well as its social, political and economic impact both sides of the Atlantic on the island.</p>]]><p><b>Make friends in Sulima</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located on the Moa River estuary, amongst the freshwater oyster-dotted mangroves, Sulima is a relaxing and friendly beach town where you can sunbathe, surf or uncover old tombs from the 19th century, which belonging to British traders. These imperialist merchants used to ply their trade, sometimes in slaves, along the West African coast.</p>]]><p><b>See the sights in the capital, Freetown</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Freetown, surrounded by verdant hills, is both a colourful and historic port town. Attractions include a 500-year-old cotton tree, the De Ruyter Stone, Government Wharf and King's Yard, where freed slaves waited to be given land. Also worth a visit are Marcon's Church and King Jimmy's Market.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in time on Freetown Peninsula</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From atop Leicester Peak, superb views of the capital, which nestles between the Atlantic Ocean and surrounding mountains, unfold. A narrow, steep road through the hills leads to the old Creole villages (dating from 1800) of Leicester, Gloucester and Regent. The area was chosen as a resettlement area for liberated slaves, who went on to build villages including Hastings, Kent, Sussex and Waterloo.</p>]]><p><b>Take in a tribal custom</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Immerse yourself in local culture with a visit one of the numerous villages dotted around the country. Rogbonko Village Retreat, for instance, is a community-based cultural exchange project where it is possible to learn about Temne tribal culture, experience everyday life and relax in the quiet settings of a traditional village.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Tacugama Chimpanzee Sanctuary</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tacugama Chimpanzee Sanctuary, just 30 minutes from Freetown, is home to more than 80 orphaned or illegally-captured chimpanzees, which now live in a luscious forest surrounding the capital. Staff run guided tours twice a day, while the sanctuary also offers overnight accommodation to enable even more time with our closest living relatives.</p>]]><p><b>Witness the meeting of the Moa and Mina Rivers</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Moa River and Mina River confluence, right on the Guinean border, is a perfect location to take in the awesome spectacle of two tropical rivers coming together to form one. With the possibility of camping, renting dugout canoes, swimming over to Guinea, and getting to know the local communities, this place is a secret waiting to be uncovered.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$3.8 billion (CIA, 2012 est.)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Diamonds, rutile, cocoa, coffee and fish.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Foodstuffs, machinery and equipment, fuels and lubricants, chemicals</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China , South Africa, US, UK, India  (CIA, 2011)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Following a permanent end to the country's debilitating civil war, Sierra Leone can now start to rebuild its shattered economy. With an annual per capita income of just US$881, it is one of the world's poorest countries. It is ranked 177th in the 2012 UN Human Development Index: in other words, it is among the worst nations in the world to live.<br />
<br />
The agricultural and mining sectors were particularly badly hit by the fighting. Agriculture employs over two-thirds of the workforce who grow coffee, cocoa, palm kernels, nuts and ginger as cash crops along with rice, bananas and cassava as staples. The fishing industry is also important. <br />
<br />
The principal industrial activity is mining: the country has some of the world's most valuable diamond mines, as well as deposits of gold, bauxite and titanium ore. Diamonds have proved as much a curse as a blessing, as much of the civil war fighting was motivated by control of the mines and both the government and the rebel forces relied on the revenues to sustain their war efforts. The remainder of the industrial sector is devoted to mineral and ore processing, as well as some light manufacturing of consumer goods such as textiles and furniture. <br />
<br />
Sierra Leone's other major economic asset is one of the world's largest natural harbours, which the government is hoping to develop as a hub for international and transit trade for the whole of the region. <br />
<br />
Since the end of the war, the economy has grown healthily at between 4 and 7% annually up until 2012 where it is estimated to have increased to 21.3%. Inevitably, Sierra Leone still depends on large injections of foreign aid to support the economy, and the IMF and World Bank have been involved in the government's reconstruction plans.<br />
<br />
Sierra Leone is a member of the African Development Bank and the West African trading bloc ECOWAS.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>English is the most common language in business circles. Appointments and punctuality are expected. Business cards are essential. September to June are the best months for business visits.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1400-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Sierra Leone Chamber of Commerce, Industry and Agriculture</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (22) 226 305 ,220 904
					Website:
					Address: Lamina Sankoh Street,Guma Building,Freetown,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Sierra Leone has a deep and rich food culture. From the street stalls selling <em>kukhri</em> (rice and sauce) and <em>plassas</em> (fried dough balls and plantain with spicy gravy) in the cities, to the upmarket restaurants selling mouth-watering fish and seafood dishes on the beaches, it's no wonder Sierra Leone has been nicknamed 'Sweet Salone'.</p><p>Most food is spicy and uses salty Maggi stock cubes, but it is also healthy and prepared with local ingredients. At every corner, on every beach, in every village, you will come across a food culture that is deeply engrained in Sierra Leonean society.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Groundnut stew</strong>: Stew made from peanuts, meat, tomatoes and onions.<br />
<strong>Cassava bread</strong>: Bread made from the flour from the starchy root of the cassava plant.<br />
<strong>Okra stew</strong>: Stew made from the vegetable often referred to as 'lady's fingers'.<br />
<strong>Cassava and potato leaf stews</strong>: A little like spinach, these leaves are mixed with various spices and fish stock and served with fish, goat or chicken.<br />
<strong>Krinkrinand fish balls</strong>: Traditional Krio dish usually served in the beach areas of Freetown where fish comes straight out of the ocean and into the pot.<br />
<strong>Yebe</strong>: Thick stew of cassava, yams, onions, chicken, stock, chilli and other spices traditional to the Mende tribe.<br />
<strong>Benny cake</strong>: Moorish sesame seed and sugar biscuit.<br />
<strong>Coconut cake</strong>: Biscuit made from fresh coconut, flour and sugar.<br />
<strong>Plantain chips</strong>: Deep-fried plantain slices eaten like crisps.<br />
<strong>Pepper soup</strong>: Very spicy soup made from hot chilli peppers and tomato paste with fried onion and garlic. Usually served with fish or meat.<br />
<strong>Jollof rice</strong>: Rice fried with beans and served with a spicy onion-based sauce.<br />
<strong>Fufu</strong>: Originating from Ghana, this dish is essentially pounded yam, cassava root or corn served with a sauce such as a basic groundnut stew.<br />
<strong>Star beer</strong>: Lager locally produced by the Sierra Leone Breweries Limited.<br />
<strong>Poyo</strong>: Potent alcoholic brew from the fermented sap of palm trees.<br />
<strong>Ginger beer</strong>: Popular refreshing non-alcoholic alternative to beer.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>The majority of food experiences in Sierra Leone are overwhelmingly positive and it is recommended to try at least one local dish during your visit. However, when eating out, try to stick to places that have been recommended, to reduce the chances of getting an upset stomach due to the poor hygiene practices of some establishments.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most hotels and restaurants include a service charge of 10 to 15%.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>Sierra Leone has no legal drinking age.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best entertainment occurs in Freetown and Bo where there are pubs, bars, nightclubs and casinos. For a lively night out, head to the hotels along Lumley Beach in the popular Cape Sierra district, or down to the closest beaches to Freetown, along the peninsula, many of which organise music, dancing and local entertainment. Aberdeen also offers some great nights out in places like Aces, O&rsquo;Caseys or Paddy&rsquo;s bar. Bo is slowly coming up in the party scene and is competing with Freetown in terms of live music presentations. For live music, head to After Work nightclub or Black &amp; White where local artists show off their talents on a weekly basis. Some beachside clubs also organise concerts by local pop bands.</p>
<p>The only cinema has unfortunately been closed until further notice, but makeshift cinemas (widescreen TVs in a backroom) are popping up all over town, usually showing old cheesy action movies. There is however a booming film industry that is set to compete with Ghana, Burkina-Faso and even Nollywood when it comes to production and filming.</p>
<p>The National Stadium has regular &lsquo;big music acts&rsquo; performing on a weekly basis, and also showcases some impressive national and international sporting events.</p>
<p>When it comes to celebrating bank holidays, Sierra Leoneans know how. You will often come across &lsquo;all-nighter&rsquo; sound systems to which the youth will dance from the evening to the break of dawn, and sometimes for two to three days straight.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Freetown is the major shopping area of Sierra   Leone, where you'll be able to browse local arts and crafts in a number of markets. Victoria Park is one of the largest markets, where visitors can find all sorts of tailored clothes, hats and leather shoes to complement your wardrobe. Big Market (near Government wharf) will be of special interest to those looking for wood and bone carvings, traditionally woven baskets and cultural &lsquo;bush-medicine&rsquo; trinkets to satisfy your curiosity for animistic artefacts.</p>
<p>At Lumley and Aberdeen beaches travellers can find small carvings, jewellery and Batik cloth, perfect gifts to take back to your friends and family. On a number of beaches along the Freetown Peninsula including Bureh beach, River No. 2 and Lakka beach, you can find well established tailors to get your clothes made <em>sur mesure</em>, old artefacts found on the beaches such as old coins, masks and colonial memorabilia, and a beautiful array of accessories such as bags and bracelets that can complement any outfit you decide to wear.</p>
<p>Handmade woodcarvings, baskets, patchwork, jewellery and tie-dye clothing are specialities. There are also numerous small retail outlets and supermarkets in downtown Freetown around Wilkinson Road (the cheapest supermarket being Freetown Supermarket) and Ecowas Street, the busiest road in Freetown.</p><p>Mon-Sat 0800-1200 and 1400-1700.</p><p>It is common to haggle with the craft shopkeepers in Sierra Leone, and a negotiation would normally start with a high price from the shopkeeper. The main technique is to half the price, and then work your way up whilst the shopkeeper works his/her way down until you both reach a reasonable compromise. </p>
<p>There are no real regulations for shopping, but it is common sense not to buy endangered animal parts (skins, bones, etc.) and other internationally banned products such as ivory and firearms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of hotels in Sierra  Leone of international standard with air conditioning and swimming pools, based in Freetown and its suburbs. It is always advisable to make reservations in advance. Additionally, there are luxury hotels located on the peninsula at Lakka and Tokay. Hotels in the interior are rare, although in Bo there is now a hotel which is of international standard. There are also government rest houses, for which application must be made to the Ministry of the Interior; guests must bring their own linen. <br />
<br />
Options in Freetown include Country Lodge Hotel (<a href="http://www.countrylodgesl.com" target="_blank">www.countrylodgesl.com</a>) which has a swimming pool and dining area overlooking Freetown&rsquo;s Lumley Beach area and Aberdeen Creek. It is slightly pricey, but this is compensated by the location and VIP feel.</p>
<p>Family Kingdom (<a href="http://www.freewebs.com/family-kingdom-hotel" target="_blank">www.freewebs.com/family-kingdom-hotel</a>) is another resort located near Lumley  Beach and offers a variety of accommodation options with views on the main beach stretch. It has a restaurant, entertainment facilities and is near to many of the beach bars where you can sip on &lsquo;sundowners&rsquo; whilst watching the locals play football on the beach.</p>
<p>In Bo, Hotel Madam Wokie (tel: 7692 1774 or 7660 0868) offers relatively good quality rooms with a nice restaurant serving local and European food. Sir Milton is also in the centre of Bo, and has an internet caf&eacute;, restaurant and good quality rooms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A number of guest houses can be found in Sierra Leone, with many located in and around Freetown, particularly in the Aberdeen neighbourhood. Lakka Beach Resort (<a href="http://www.lakkabeachresort.com" target="_blank">www.lakkabeachresort.com</a>) is a small guesthouse located on an island just off Lakka Beach. At a distance of 3-5km (2-3 miles) outside of Freetown, along the Peninsula, the resort is an idyllic place to rest away from the hustle and bustle of the capital.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of hotels in Sierra  Leone of international standard with air conditioning and swimming pools, based in Freetown and its suburbs. It is always advisable to make reservations in advance. Additionally, there are luxury hotels located on the peninsula at Lakka and Tokay. Hotels in the interior are rare, although in Bo there is now a hotel which is of international standard. There are also government rest houses, for which application must be made to the Ministry of the Interior; guests must bring their own linen. <br />
<br />
Options in Freetown include Country Lodge Hotel (<a href="http://www.countrylodgesl.com" target="_blank">www.countrylodgesl.com</a>) which has a swimming pool and dining area overlooking Freetown&rsquo;s Lumley Beach area and Aberdeen Creek. It is slightly pricey, but this is compensated by the location and VIP feel.</p>
<p>Family Kingdom (<a href="http://www.freewebs.com/family-kingdom-hotel" target="_blank">www.freewebs.com/family-kingdom-hotel</a>) is another resort located near Lumley  Beach and offers a variety of accommodation options with views on the main beach stretch. It has a restaurant, entertainment facilities and is near to many of the beach bars where you can sip on &lsquo;sundowners&rsquo; whilst watching the locals play football on the beach.</p>
<p>In Bo, Hotel Madam Wokie (tel: 7692 1774 or 7660 0868) offers relatively good quality rooms with a nice restaurant serving local and European food. Sir Milton is also in the centre of Bo, and has an internet caf&eacute;, restaurant and good quality rooms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of hotels in Sierra  Leone of international standard with air conditioning and swimming pools, based in Freetown and its suburbs. It is always advisable to make reservations in advance. Additionally, there are luxury hotels located on the peninsula at Lakka and Tokay. Hotels in the interior are rare, although in Bo there is now a hotel which is of international standard. There are also government rest houses, for which application must be made to the Ministry of the Interior; guests must bring their own linen. <br />
<br />
Options in Freetown include Country Lodge Hotel (<a href="http://www.countrylodgesl.com" target="_blank">www.countrylodgesl.com</a>) which has a swimming pool and dining area overlooking Freetown&rsquo;s Lumley Beach area and Aberdeen Creek. It is slightly pricey, but this is compensated by the location and VIP feel.</p>
<p>Family Kingdom (<a href="http://www.freewebs.com/family-kingdom-hotel" target="_blank">www.freewebs.com/family-kingdom-hotel</a>) is another resort located near Lumley  Beach and offers a variety of accommodation options with views on the main beach stretch. It has a restaurant, entertainment facilities and is near to many of the beach bars where you can sip on &lsquo;sundowners&rsquo; whilst watching the locals play football on the beach.</p>
<p>In Bo, Hotel Madam Wokie (tel: 7692 1774 or 7660 0868) offers relatively good quality rooms with a nice restaurant serving local and European food. Sir Milton is also in the centre of Bo, and has an internet caf&eacute;, restaurant and good quality rooms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are extremely limited and are poor. Missions and foreign aid organisations provide some medical facilities. Health insurance is essential. It is advisable to take personal medical supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no emergency medical services, and therefore it is advisable to be carrying a fully comprehensive travel insurance policy with you at all times so that you can contact them in case of an emergency.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;They will advise you on the best course of action to take in your particular circumstance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If taken ill in Sierra Leone, the best suggestion is to travel to the nearest major town (Bo or Freetown are best equipped) and visit the&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Dr. Yillah hospitals on Cockle Bay Lane, Aberdeen Road, Freetown (tel: (0)3 363 5881)or on Prince Williams Street in Bo (tel: (0) 7663 5881. Opening times are generally Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cost to be seen by a doctor is Le30000 ($6) and prescriptions are usually free if available at the doctors or for a minimal fee if purchased at the pharmacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pharmacies can be found in all major towns and are usually concentrated around one particular area. Ask for the nearest pharmacy for directions.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being potentially contaminated. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water; swimming pools which are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. There is a high incidence of HIV/AIDS. Vaccinations against meningococcal meningitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Other common diseases in Sierra Leone include: Rabies, Lassa fever, water-borne diseases, malaria and other tropical diseases.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Independence Day :
							27 April </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following may be imported into Sierra Leone without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 225g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1.1L of wine or spirits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Narcotics, unlicensed firearms, pornography, and precious metals and stones.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Leone (SLL) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of SLL5,000, 2,000, 1,000, 500, 100, 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of SLL100 and 50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All foreign exchange transactions must conducted through official exchange offices and banks. Currency can also be changed on the side of the street from illegal traders near major banks, however these are not recommended and are to be used at your own discretion.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Credit cards (Visa only) are accepted in some shops, supermarkets, hotels and restaurants in Freetown.</p><p>ATMs are few and far between in Sierra Leone. There are a number of ATMs (Visa only) in Freetown with limited others in other major centres such as Bo, Kenema, Makeni and Koidu. Some are not internationally connected and these are often liable to fraud. There are no Mastercard cashpoints in Sierra Leone.</p>
<p>The ATM system of accessing money is not yet developed enough for elaborate scam schemes to have been put in place, however it is advisable to exercise caution and use common sense when taking money out from an ATM.</p>
<p>Thieves are rare in Sierra Leone as a result of a strict societal sense of justice, however, like anywhere in the world, caution when dealing with money in public places is suggested.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>These are generally not recommended as opportunities to cash them are limited, but they can be exchanged at a number of banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Thurs 0800-1330, Fri 0800-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Sierra Leone, a passport valid for six months from the date of visa application is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no restrictions for entering the country with children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If in transit on a commercial route (flight, cruise ship etc), a visa is not required providing that you do not disembark. If you are on land and are transiting through Sierra Leone, you require a single-entry visa as a minimum.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: &pound;109; six-month multiple-entry visa: &pound;134; one-year multiple entry visa: &pound;159.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: valid for three months from the date of issue for stays of up to 30 days; multiple-entry visas: valid for six months or one year from the date of issue with a maximum stay of 30 days for each visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy or high commission) in your country of residence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least five working days for visa processing. An express service of two to three days is available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You may be required to show proof of your financial status during the visa application process.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets need to be registered with the immigration authorities either prior to entering, or on entry, to Sierra Leone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[8.521006]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-11.844009]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>71,740 sq km (27,699 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>6,592,102 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>82 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Freetown.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sierra Leone is bordered to the northwest, north and northeast by Guinea Republic, and to the southeast by Liberia. To the south and southwest lies the Atlantic Ocean. A flat plain up to 110km (70 miles) wide stretches the length of the coast except for the Freetown peninsula, where the Sierra Lyoa Mountains rise to 1,000m (3,280ft). In some coastal areas, sand bars have formed that stretch out as far as 112km (70 miles). Behind the coastal plain is the central forested area, drained by eight principal rivers, which has been cleared for agriculture. The land rises in altitude eastwards to the Guinea Highlands, a high plateau with peaks rising to over 1,830m (6,000ft) in the Loma Mountains and Tingi Hills area. The Mende tribe is prominent in the southeast and the Temne in the western and northern areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Animist (40%), Islam (40%) and Christian (20%).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of people in Sierra Leone still live a traditional, agricultural way of life, with ruling chiefs, and religions which preserve social stability, as well as local music, dance, customs and traditions. Handshaking is the normal form of greeting. It is usual to be entertained in a hotel or restaurant, particularly for business visitors. Small tokens of appreciation are always welcome. Casual wear is suitable everywhere. Men are rarely expected to wear suits and ties.</p>
<p>Secret societies are a fundamental part of Sierra Leonean culture. You may come across initiation ceremonies for the two big societies, the &lsquo;Poro&rsquo; (men&rsquo;s secret society) and the &lsquo;Bundu&rsquo; (women&rsquo;s secret society) in which, upon reaching puberty, the two genders are taught the essential skills and knowledge important for their role within society.</p>
<p>You may come across two, or sometimes three, people shouting at each other, quite aggressively, and then stop immediately and hug like they were best friends. This is called &lsquo;palaver&rsquo; and is a way of settling disputes immediately to avoid any grudges being held.</p>
<p>The Limba tribe have a very important role in Sierra Leone culture as they are the only people who can &lsquo;tap palm wine (also known as <em>poyo</em>) from the palm tree. It is said that a village will even put up an advert on local notice boards offering incentives for good Palm Wine tappers so that they can provide the village with as much of the naturally fermenting alcoholic drink as possible.</p>
<p>Greetings are very important in Sierra Leonean culture, and are expected to be learnt as a first attempt to learn one or many languages.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Supply subject to fluctuations. Plugs are British-style with three square pins or Indian-style with three round pins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Julius Maada Bio since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Julius Maada Bio since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Though Sierra Leone was first mapped by the Portuguese, the land around Freetown harbour was colonised by Britain as a homeland for freed slaves in the late 18th century. This caused conflict with indigenous tribes such as the Temne and Mende, from which many of Sierra Leone&rsquo;s more recent troubles can be traced.</p>
<p>Gaining independence in 1961, the All Peoples&rsquo; Congress (APC) took charge in 1967 and became the sole political party from 1978. General Joseph Momoh was installed as president in 1985, but after initial success, the government was overthrown by a group of army officers led by Captain Valentine Strasser. The escalating civil war in neighbouring Liberia in the mid-1990s consumed much of Sierra Leone under the Revolutionary United Front (RUF), a home-grown Sierra Leonean movement led by Foday Sankoh.</p>
<p>Sierra Leone called on assistance from African neighbours and the UK, and in 1996 Strasser was deposed and the government returned to civilian rule. The turbulent political situation continued into 1997 as dissident troops led by Major Johnny Koroma seized power. Nigeria, with British backing, restored the original civilian government a year later, but the RUF sustained a vicious guerrilla campaign in the countryside requiring Britain to intervene once more. Its troops proved decisive in tipping the balance against the RUF.</p>
<p>A political settlement, brokered by the United Nations, was concluded in July 1999 but the RUF refused to disarm or relinquish occupied areas, containing most of the country's lucrative diamond fields. Fighting broke out again in May 2000. Peacekeeping forces finally brought conflict to an end in January 2002.</p>
<p>With peace restored, former president Kabbah was re-elected in the same year. The APC&rsquo;s Ernest Koroma was elected Sierra Leone's new president in 2007 with a promise to fight corruption. Since then, Sierra Leone has been stable and experiencing an economic boom. Koroma was re-elected in 2012, in a non-violent, democratic multi-party vote.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The name of the country hails from the words &lsquo;Serra Leao,&rsquo; meaning &lsquo;Lion Mountain Range&rsquo; in Portuguese.<br />
&bull;	Freetown was founded as a home for repatriated former slaves. <br />
&bull;	Sierra Leone&rsquo;s diamond industry helped fund the years of military conflict.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Sierra Leone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(0) 7820 0192.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/sierra-leone</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(0) 7820 0192.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1630; Fri 0800-1300. Consular section: Mon-Thurs 0830-1600; Fri 0830-1230.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>6 Spur Road<br/>Freetown<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Sierra Leone in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 939 9261/2.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://embassyofsierraleone.net</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 939 9261/2.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1701 19th Street<br/>Washington D.C.<br/>20009<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission for the Republic of Sierra Leone in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7404 0140. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.bm2c.co.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7404 0140. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 1000-1300 for visa submissions and 1430-1530 for collections.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Holborn<br/>41 Eagle Street<br/>London<br/>WC1R 4TL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like one of its rough diamonds, Sierra Leone is a destination of exquisite natural beauty and great potential. But despite its lush rainforests, palm-fringed beaches, fascinating history and vibrant culture, the country remains largely unexplored and undiscovered.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s hard to believe now, but Sierra Leone once attracted some 100,000 tourists a year. They were drawn to the country&rsquo;s white sandy beaches, azure waters and swaying palms, until the horrors of civil war ravaged the country and knocked it off the tourism map.</p>
<p>Suffice to say Sierra Leone remains somewhat overshadowed by this bitter and bloody conflict, which raged between 1991 and 2002. Dramatised in the 2006 film Blood Diamond starring Leonardo DiCaprio, the war is still one of the first things most people think about when Sierra Leone is mentioned.</p>
<p>Happily, this negative reputation is gradually receding and a new picture is emerging. Pioneering travellers are also trickling back to this corner of West Africa to rediscover the country&rsquo;s many charms.</p>
<p>In some ways, nothing has changed. Known locally as &lsquo;Sweet Salone&rsquo;, Sierra Leone remains one of the friendliest countries on the continent. The smiling people and relaxed vibe are characteristic of this small nation. Wherever you go, and whomever you meet, you&rsquo;ll be greeted as though you are part of the family.</p>
<p>Another thing you will notice in Sierra Leone is the abundance of wildlife. From hippos, forest elephants and chimpanzees, to bountiful birds and exotic insects, Salone is a dream ticket for nature enthusiasts. Pack your binoculars.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s also paradise for sun-seekers. In fact Sierra Leone&rsquo;s gorgeous sandy beaches are considered by many to be the best in West Africa. Combine this with the country&rsquo;s off-the-beaten track feel, welcoming people, and awe-inspiring scenery, and it&rsquo;s easy to see why &lsquo;Sweet Salone&rsquo; is being vaunted as an up-and-coming destination for intrepid travellers.</p><p>Like one of its rough diamonds, Sierra Leone is a destination of exquisite natural beauty and great potential. But despite its lush rainforests, palm-fringed beaches, fascinating history and vibrant culture, the country remains largely unexplored and undiscovered.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s hard to believe now, but Sierra Leone once attracted some 100,000 tourists a year. They were drawn to the country&rsquo;s white sandy beaches, azure waters and swaying palms, until the horrors of civil war ravaged the country and knocked it off the tourism map.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
