<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Singapore" ColCode="sgp" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sg" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Singapore]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Located just north of the equator, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore">Singapore</a> has a tropical climate and stays hot and humid throughout the year. Temperatures average around 31&ordm; C (88&ordm; F) during the day with little seasonal variation, although it&rsquo;s slightly cooler in December and January, and hottest in April and May. Temperatures are unlikely to dip below 23&ordm; C (74&ordm; F) at night; the lowest temperature ever recorded was just over 19&ordm; C (66&ordm; F).</p>
<p>Singapore receives a considerable amount of rainfall - approximately 2340mm annually. Although there are no distinct wet or dry seasons, the region is affected by two different monsoons. The Northeast Monsoon generally takes place from December to March and is accompanied by more frequent rain, particularly from November to January.</p>
<p>Conversely, the Southwest Monsoon produces a marginally dryer climate from May to September. Despite the slightly lower overall precipitation levels, particularly from June to August, the Southwest Monsoon is characterized by its early-morning rainstorms; these often persist for one or two hours then taper off for the afternoon. Even these drier months experience a fair amount of rain (around 150mm each month), so be prepared for unpredictably wet weather any time of the year.</p>
<p>The beginning and end of the two monsoon seasons are not well defined, but are separated by the shorter inter-monsoon periods of April/May and October/November, during which months afternoon and evening rain showers are likely. These showers are typically sudden and heavy, but often only last for a short time.</p>
<p>The region is extremely humid, with humidity levels usually between 70% and 90%; often the air is muggiest in the early morning, abating somewhat in the afternoon. On rainy days it is not unreasonable to expect the humidity to reach 100%. When visiting, be sure to drink enough water and seek frequent refuge from the sticky heat indoors. March and September are particularly humid and often very uncomfortable.</p>
<p>Thunderstorms are also a very regular phenomenon, occurring on roughly 40% of all days year-round but particularly common during the Southeast Monsoon. In fact, this small city-state has one of the highest rates of lightning activity worldwide.</p>
<p>Despite the unpredictability of the weather, Singapore experiences as much brilliant sunshine as it does rain, and therefore makes for a delightful beach destination. If sunbathing happens to be interrupted by an unexpected shower, there is at least a plethora of indoor entertainment.</p>
<p>As Singapore&rsquo;s weather does not vary drastically throughout the year, tourism in the area is relatively steady year-round. The weather can be erratic and unpredictable, so it may be best to plan a visit based on the festival season rather than the climate; some of the nation&rsquo;s most notable are the grand celebrations of Chinese New Year, the Lantern Festival and the Art Festival. Accommodation prices rise significantly during the Formula One racing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Be sure to pack lightweight cottons and linens to avoid becoming overheated in the muggy Singapore climate.  Also remember to carry an umbrella any time of year, but particularly during the rainy season.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Singapore is too small for domestic flights to be useful or available. Sightseeing flights can be arranged locally through the Republic of Singapore Flying Club<em> </em>(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.singaporeflyingclub.com/">www.singaporeflyingclub.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can take boat tours from several points along the river, including Clarke Quay and Boat Quay. Ferry services to Singapore's Southern Islands leave from the Marina South Pier, and ferries to Pulau Ubin leave from Changi Point Ferry Terminal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Singapore&rsquo;s size means that getting around by car is feasible, although driving tends to be aggressive and traffic is often chaotic. This, combined with an excellent public transport network, mean that it rarely makes sense for tourists to drive in the city.</p>l<p>It can be hard to find an available taxi at peak times in Singapore; in the centre, they only stop at designated ranks and cannot be flagged down in the street. The pricing system is complex, but at least drivers use the meters.</p><p>A national driving licence is sufficient for stays up to one month. For visits beyond one month, an International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>Drive on the left, use seat belts in both the front and the back seats, and do not use mobile phones while driving. All motorists driving into the central business district or travelling on some major roads are required to pay the ERP (Electronic Road Pricing). This toll is automatically collected from an device in the car, into which a special cash card is inserted (it can be charged at petrol stations and 7-Eleven stores).</p><p>Members of the AA can apply for visiting membership of the Automobile Association of Singapore (tel: +65 6748 9911; <a href="http://www.aas.com.sg" target="_blank">www.aas.com.sg</a>), which provides a 24-hour towing service. Numerous other breakdown services operate on the island.</p><p>There are several car hire/self-drive firms with offices at the airport and in hotels. They are expensive however, and public transport is good enough that driving offers few advantages. If you&rsquo;re heading over into Malaysia, it&rsquo;s cheaper to hire a car in Johor Bahru instead.</p><p>Cycling on the main roads is not a very pleasant experience, due to a combination of heavy traffic and aggressive driving. Taking a ride in the main island&rsquo;s various parks, many of which are linked by cycle paths, is a much better idea. Many of the parks have hire outlets.</p><p>Drive on the left, use seat belts in both the front and the back seats, and do not use mobile phones while driving. All motorists driving into the central business district or travelling on some major roads are required to pay the ERP (Electronic Road Pricing). This toll is automatically collected from an device in the car, into which a special cash card is inserted (it can be charged at petrol stations and 7-Eleven stores).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bus:</strong> Singapore&rsquo;s bus network is extensive and efficient. The main operators are SMRT (tel: 1800 336 8900, in Singapore only; <a href="http://www.smrt.com.sg" target="_blank">www.smrt.com.sg</a>) and SBS (tel:&nbsp;1800 225 5663, in Singapore only; <a href="http://www.sbstransit.com.sg" target="_blank">www.sbstransit.com.sg</a>). Pay with the exact change, or using an EZ-Link card or Tourist Pass. The former is pay-as-you-go, while the latter (<a href="http://www.thesingaporetouristpass.com.sg" target="_blank">www.thesingaporetouristpass.com.sg</a>) offers unlimited travel for a day.</p>
<p><strong>Trishaws: </strong>This traditional form of chauffeur-pedalled transport is a fun way to tour the streets of Singapore, but agree on a price before setting off.</p>
<p><strong>Taxi: </strong>These are numerous and relatively cheap, although there can be a wait during peak times, late at night or when it rains. They can be picked up from outside hotels and official ranks or flagged down in the streets. Taxis are metered, but some surcharges are not shown on the meter. It is possible to negotiate hourly rates for round-island tours.</p>
<p><strong>Metro: </strong>The Mass Rapid Transit (MRT) (tel: 1 800 336 8900, in Singapore only; <a href="http://www.smrt.com.sg/" target="_blank">www.smrt.com.sg</a>) is a modern, comfortable, efficient and cheap way to explore Singapore. The MRT system extends out to Changi Airport (journey time from the City Hall interchange is just under half an hour). The metro system is supplemented by three Light Rail Transit (LRT) lines, although these are of most use to commuters.</p>
<p><strong>Cable car:</strong> A cable car runs to Sentosa island from HarbourFront Tower Two, although it&rsquo;s much cheaper to take a bus or just walk across the Boardwalk from VivoCity Shopping Mall.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Singapore Airlines<em>&nbsp;</em>(<a target="_blank" href="http://www.singaporeair.com/">www.singaporeair.com</a>). Two low-cost airlines are headquartered in Singapore: Jetstar Asia Airways (www.jetstar.com), a subsidiary of Qantas, and Tiger Airways (www.tigerair.com).</p>
<p>Flights to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a> are usually most expensive in July and August, as well as around Christmas, New Year and Chinese New Year.</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore/singapore-changi-airport">Singapore Changi Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 13 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 21 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Singapore is a major regional hub, and well-managed Changi airport is regularly voted the best in the world. Facilities include a gym, several gardens and even an outdoor swimming pool. If you&rsquo;re transiting and have at least five hours available, you can register for a two-hour tour of the city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Included in the air fare.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Singapore is a major regional hub, and well-managed Changi airport is regularly voted the best in the world. Facilities include a gym, several gardens and even an outdoor swimming pool. If you&rsquo;re transiting and have at least five hours available, you can register for a two-hour tour of the city.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Singapore Changi Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.changiairport.com<p>Singapore Changi Airport is located 20km (13 miles) northeast of the city of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore">Singapore</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+65 6595 6868</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Singapore is a major port (<a href="http://www.mpa.gov.sg" target="_blank">www.mpa.gov.sg</a>), acting as an intermediate stage for huge quantities of  cargo on their way to other destinations. The city is served by a growing number of international passenger cruise lines. Passenger ferries run to Indonesia and Malaysia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Two lines run from Singapore to Malaysia. One serves Johor Bahru and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kuala-lumpur">Kuala Lumpur</a>, where it&rsquo;s possible to change for <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bangkok">Bangkok</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/thailand">Thailand</a>). The other line, sometimes known as the Jungle Line, runs through the centre of Malaysia as far as the northeast coast. There are three trains a day, with stops including Tanah Merah and Wakaf Bharu (for Kota Bharu).</p>
<p>For more information see Malaysia Railway (KTM)&nbsp;(tel: +603 2267 1200; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.ktmb.com.my/">www.ktmb.com.my</a>). The Eastern &amp; Oriental Express<em> </em>(<a href="http://www.belmond.com/eastern-and-oriental-express" target="_blank">www.belmond.com/eastern-and-oriental-express</a>) is a luxurious train travelling from Thailand and Malaysia to Singapore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Two causeways connect Singapore with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malaysia">Malaysia</a>, the most popular and useful of which links the city with downtown Johor Bahru. Buses run very regularly from around 5am to midnight, and are operated by SBS (<a href="http://www.sbstransit.com.sg" target="_blank">www.sbstransit.com.sg</a>) and Causeway Link (<a href="http://causewaylink.com.my" target="_blank">causewaylink.com.my</a>). The latter are significantly faster. It&rsquo;s possible to drive a Singaporean rental car across the causeway, but much cheaper to rent one in Johor Bahru.</p><p>Bus passengers crossing into Malaysia are required to disembark to carry out border formalities. Take all bags off the bus, as it won&rsquo;t wait around. Instead, make sure you keep your ticket and, once stamped in, get on a bus operated by the same company.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public telephone booths take phone cards, and sometimes credit cards, and can be used to make both local and international calls. For the latter it is usually cheaper to purchase a pre-paid international calling card; these are readily available due to the large number of migrant workers in Singapore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies, although it's also cheap and easy to buy a local SIM card (passports must be shown when making the purchase). Coverage is good.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes throughout Singapore provide public access to internet and email services. Most hotels and hostels offer Internet access, but there is also a free city-wide Wi-Fi service called Wireless@SG. Visitors can register either online or by telephone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Singapore's media environment has the shadow of Singaporean government cast over it. Censorship is common; Internet access is regulated; and private ownership of satellite dishes is not allowed (although cable TV is available). Singapore Press Holdings, with close links to the ruling party, has a virtual monopoly of the newspaper industry. The English-language dailies include <em>The Business Times</em>, <em>The New Paper</em>, <em>The Straits Times</em> and <em>Today.</em></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The postal system is very efficient, and airmail takes up to six working days to the UK and eight working days to the US. In addition to Singapore Post offices, there are limited postal facilities at many hotels.</p><p>Varies but typically Mon-Fri 0830-1700, Sat 0830-1300. The airport branches are open longer hours (daily 0800–2130 in the departure hall, 0600–1030 in terminal 2 transit).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Baba House</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Find out about the Peranakan community, which grew from the marriages of Chinese traders to local women. The lovingly-restored home (<a href="http://www.nus.edu.sg/cfa/museum/about.php" target="_blank">www.nus.edu.sg/cfa/museum/about.php</a>), set up to look much as it did in the 1920s, can be visited only on a free tour &ndash; check the website for days and time.</p>]]><p><b>Changi Museum and Chapel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Remember the dark days of Japanese wartime occupation at the Changi Museum and Chapel (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.changimuseum.com/">www.changimuseum.com</a>), a symbolic replica of similar chapels built by prisoners during WWII.</p>]]><p><b>Chinatown Heritage Centre</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn about the history of the Chinese community in Singapore, at this fascinating museum (<a href="http://www.chinatownheritagecentre.sg" target="_blank">www.chinatownheritagecentre.sg</a>) set within a converted shophouse. Highlights include recorded interviews with elderly residents, and reconstructions of the cramped conditions within which many people lived.</p>]]><p><b>Club Street and Ann Siang Hill</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hang out with the locals in this trendy part of Chinatown, which forms a smart playground for advertising and banking types. Numerous bars and restaurants are housed in the narrow and historic streets.</p>]]><p><b>Explore temples</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Experience a world of religions at Buddhist and Hindu temples, mosques and Anglican and Catholic cathedrals, which are all likely to be encountered during a comparatively brief walk around central Singapore; such is its splendid diversity.</p>]]><p><b>Fort Canning Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Escape from the hot city streets and view what was once an ancient fort of the Malay kings, covering 2.8 hectares (7 acres): Fort Canning Park, on Fort Canning Rise. The colonial ruins of the British citadel can still be viewed, as can a 19th-century Christian cemetery.</p>]]><p><b>Hire a canoe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take to the water and canoe around the island - there are a number of operators hiring out canoes at Changi point, East Coast and Sentosa Island.</p>]]><p><b>Istana</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Give yourself a chance to bump into the President. Open to the public just five times yearly, the Istana (<a href="http://www.istana.gov.sg/" target="_blank">www.istana.gov.sg</a>) is the impressive official residence of the Singaporean ruler. The white neoclassical building dates back to 1869, and the extensive grounds include a nine-hole golf course.</p>]]><p><b>Johore Battery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See a replica of one of three 'monster guns' which once defended Singapore. Installed by the British in 1939, they fired shells with a diameter of 15 inches (38cm) which could reach a distance of 20 miles. Today you can visit the labyrinth of tunnels at the gun emplacement site, which were used to store ammunition. The original guns were destroyed by the British before Singapore fell to the Japanese army.</p>]]><p><b>Jurong Bird Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Come face to face with birdlife at the Jurong Bird Park (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.birdpark.com.sg/">www.birdpark.com.sg</a>) on Jurong Hill, home to South East Asia's largest collection of birds. There is also the world's largest walk-in aviary, a nocturnal house and several spectacular bird shows including one demonstrating falconry. The park is popular with families.</p>]]><p><b>Lau Pa Sat</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tickle your tastebuds at Lau Pa Sat (<a href="http://www.laupasat.biz" target="_blank">www.laupasat.biz</a>), the largest surviving Victorian filigree cast-iron structure in South East Asia. Built in Scotland and shipped to Singapore in 1894 to act as a wet market, the structure has been restored and is now a popular food centre.</p>]]><p><b>Marina Bay and the Gardens by the Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the newest land reclamation projects in Singapore, Marina Bay (<a href="http://www.marina-bay.sg" target="_blank">www.marina-bay.sg</a>) includes one of the city&rsquo;s two huge casinos &ndash; the Sands&nbsp;&ndash; but also an array of bars, restaurants and events spaces. Just across the river are the Gardens by the Bay (<a href="http://www.gardensbythebay.com.sg" target="_blank">www.gardensbythebay.com.sg</a>), which opened in 2012 and have a combination of open-air gardens, conservatories and an aerial walkway.</p>]]><p><b>National Museum of Singapore</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relive the island's past at the refurbished National Museum of Singapore (<a href="http://www.nationalmuseum.sg" target="_blank">www.nationalmuseum.sg</a>), which offers much more than just static collections telling the island state's colourful history, it is also a focal point for numerous festivals and events.</p>]]><p><b>National Orchid Garden</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the National Orchid Garden in Singapore's Botanic Gardens (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.sbg.org.sg/">www.sbg.org.sg</a>), which has the largest collection of orchids in the world. The Botanic Gardens have over 52 hectares (128 acres) of landscaped parkland and primary jungle. There are guided tours of the gardens on Saturdays (times vary).</p>]]><p><b>Night Safari</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enter the fascinating world of nocturnal wildlife at the Night Safari (<a href="http://www.nightsafari.com.sg/" target="_blank">www.nightsafari.com.sg</a>), one of Singapore&rsquo;s most popular attractions and a little over an hour by bus from the city centre. Regular performances complement the park's extensive collections of animals; the world-class Singapore Zoo is next door and operated by the same company.</p>]]><p><b>Parliament House</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Relive colonial days near the Singapore  River, and wander towards the imposing Parliament House (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.parliament.gov.sg/">www.parliament.gov.sg</a>), the oldest government building in the country - the core dates back to the 1820s. Proceedings are open to the public when parliament is sitting, and tours are also offered.</p>]]><p><b>Raffles Hotel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Prop up the bar at the Raffles Hotel (<a href="http://www.raffles.com/singapore/" target="_blank">www.raffles.com/singapore</a>), one of the most famous hotels in the world. A Singapore Sling (a head-spinningly good, if expensive, cocktail) in the Long Bar is almost de rigueur, although it&rsquo;s more pleasant to take a table in the shade outside. A dress code applies indoors, so avoid wearing shorts and sandals.</p>]]><p><b>Sentosa Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take the short trip across to Sentosa Island (www.sentosa.com.sg), with its many and varied attractions ranging from the Universal Studios theme park to an aquarium, a cable car ride, the Tiger Sky Tower, nature trails and plenty of bars and restaurants. It's a great family day out, but be warned that the various entry fees can add up to an expensive day out.</p>]]><p><b>Singapore Flyer</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Enjoy panoramic views over Singapore island and beyond from the 165m (540ft) tall Singapore Flyer (<a href="http://www.singaporeflyer.com.sg" target="_blank">www.singaporeflyer.com.sg</a>), the world's second highest Ferris wheel after the Las Vegas High Roller. Opened in March 2008 at Marina Bay, the enormous wheel offers a magnificent perspective on the bay as well as the city beyond.</p>]]><p><b>Singapore River</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a trip along Singapore River aboard a bumboat. These were once used to ferry goods to and from larger ships moored in the harbour, and nowadays offer an excellent way to see the contrasting historical and modern architectural styles of the city. Departure points include Boat Quay, Raffles Landing and Boat Quay.</p>]]><p><b>World-class shopping</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go shopping in Singapore City's Orchard Road - the 'Fifth Avenue' or 'Oxford Street' of Singapore, and just as bustling, with its vast luxury malls, shops ranging from megastores to vendors of souvenir tat, as well as caf&eacute;s and restaurants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$307 billion (2015 est.)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, consumer goods, chemicals and mineral fuels.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, mineral fuels, chemicals, food and consumer goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China (PR), Hong Kong (SAR), Japan, Korea (Rep), Malaysia and USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Singapore Model combines extensive state intervention in matters such as housing and labour&nbsp;with a strong free market ideology. Since the late 1970s, the government has promoted export-oriented and service industries with the intention of making Singapore a regional economic hub.</p>
<p>Today the country relies on entrep&ocirc;t trade in particular, as well as shipbuilding and repairing, oil refining, electronics and information technology, banking and finance and, to a lesser extent, tourism. The country has weathered recent global economic conditions well and in 2016, Singapore came out second from the top of the World Bank Ease of Doing Business Index.</p>
<p>Singapore's only significant natural resource is its natural harbour, which is the busiest in the world. This accounts in part for the high level of Singapore's re-export trade, which accounts for almost half of all trade. There is a little agriculture, with the cultivation of plants and vegetables, and some fishing; however, most foodstuffs and raw materials have to be imported.<br />
<br />
Singapore is the top convention city in Asia and ranks among the top 10 meetings destinations in the world. There are many hotels with extensive conference facilities, including the latest audio-visual equipment, secretarial services, translation and simultaneous interpretation systems, whilst Raffles City, a self-contained convention city, can accommodate up to 6,000 delegates under one roof. Other popular venues for larger conventions and exhibitions include Suntec Singapore and Singapore Expo.<br />
<br />
Full information on Singapore as a conference destination can be obtained from the Exhibition &amp; Convention Bureau within the Singapore Tourism Board. The bureau is a non-profitmaking organisation with the dual objectives of marketing Singapore as an international exhibition and convention city and of assisting with the planning and staging of individual events.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>English is widely spoken in business circles. Appointments should be made and punctuality is important. Chinese people should be addressed with their surnames, which are the first part of their names. Malays normally use their personal name followed by <em>bin</em> (son of) or <em>binti</em> (daughter of) and then their father's name; common abbreviations include Mohd (Mohammed). Many Indians do not use surnames but instead place the initial of their father's name before their own.</p>
<p>English is the official language of business in Singapore and business is conducted very much on a Western model. However, Asian (and especially Chinese) business ethics often prevail. Business cards are exchanged on every social and business occasion and it is common courtesy to give or receive them with two hands (as with any piece of paper, including money).</p>
<p>Corporate entertaining is high on the agenda and long lunches are often taken, with lavish buffets a popular option. Smoking is prohibited in many places and is not always socially acceptable, so visitors should check before lighting up. Business dress is fairly formal, though a jacket is usually dispensed with apart from at official meetings. Women wear skirts or trouser suits. Some organisations have adopted casual Fridays, although only those departments with no client contact tend to take advantage of this.</p>
<p>Locals and expats alike work long hours; the official working day is roughly 0900-1700 but much longer hours are quite common. There are 11 public holidays a year, the most significant being the Chinese New Year which is in January or February. This is the only occasion when almost everything shuts down - locals spend time visiting their families and expats leave for a long weekend away. During other public holidays, like Christmas Day, banks and offices close but shops stay open.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1400-1700, Sat 0900-1300 if open.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Singapore International Chamber of Commerce</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 6500 0988
					Website:http://www.sicc.com.sg/
					Address: 10-01 Singapore,6 Raffles Quay,,48580]]><b>Singapore Indian Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 6222 2505
					Website:http://www.sicci.com/
					Address: Singapore,101 Cecil Street,Tong Eng Building,Unit 23-01/04,,69533]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Singapore is a gourmet's paradise, with everything from humble street stalls to 5-star restaurants. There are over 30 different cooking styles, including various regional styles of Chinese cuisine, American, English, French, Indian, Indonesian, Italian, Japanese, Korean, Malay, Russian and Swiss.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>The most common, though are Malay, Indian and Chinese cuisines. Malay food is famed for its use of spices and coconut milk; no pork is used, as most Malays are Muslim. The Indian community mostly traces its roots back to South India and their food reflects this, meaning that spicy vegetarian dishes are predominant. To try many small dishes, order a thali (which may be served on a banana leaf). The most popular Chinese regional cuisine is Cantonese, which includes a lot of stir fry dishes as well as dim sum (small dishes, often steamed, which are intended for sharing at lunchtime).</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p>&bull; <em>Beef rendang</em> (coconut milk beef curry).<br />
&bull; <em>Char kway teow</em> (thick rice noodles stir fried in soy sauce and chilli with prawns and clams, often with additional ingredients such as egg).<br />
&bull; <em>Chilli crab</em> (fresh crab with a piquant tomato sauce).<br />
&bull; <em>Gado gado</em> (a fruit and vegetable salad in peanut sauce).<br />
&bull; <em>Hainanese chicken rice</em> (steamed chicken served with rice which has been cooked in chicken stock, along with ginger and chilli dips).<br />
&bull; <em>Ikan assam </em>(fish in a sour tamarind sauce).<br />
<em>&bull; Laksa</em><em> </em>(a coconut-based spicy noodle soup, usually containing prawns or chicken as well as tofu, fishcake and beansprouts).<em> </em><br />
<em>&bull; Masala dosa </em>(a rolled pancake filled with a vegetarian curry, popular as a snack or for breakfast).<br />
<em>&bull; </em><em>Satay</em> (skewers of marinated meat cooked over charcoal, served with spicy peanut sauce, cucumber, onion, rice and coconut).</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Although the Singaporean authorities have closed most of the individual food stalls which were once common, street food is still very much in evidence in dining areas known as hawker centres. These are often open-air, and always contain an array of stalls specialising in different dishes. Other eating options include kopitiam (literally coffee shops, although they also sell food). There are also food courts in malls, often with excellent food, as well as restaurants with waiter service. Bars/cocktail lounges often have table and counter service. There are no licensing hours.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Officially discouraged in restaurants, hotels and the airport. A 10% service charge is included in restaurant bills.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Singapore has a vibrant and exciting nightlife. Alcohol is expensive by the standards of South East Asia, but at least there&rsquo;s a great array of bars, clubs, discos and karaoke pubs in which to enjoy it. Look out for happy hours and ladies&rsquo; nights (which are usually midweek). Non-alcoholic entertainment can be found in street opera, night markets, river cruises, multiplex cinemas, theatre productions and international stage shows. There are casinos within the two huge 'integrated resort' complexes at Marina Bay (<a href="http://www.marinabaysands.com/" target="_blank">www.marinabaysands.com</a>) and on Sentosa (<a href="http://www.rwsentosa.com/" target="_blank">www.rwsentosa.com</a>).</p>
<p>Among the most popular all-in-one entertainment districts are Boat Quay and Clarke Quay, two riverside landmarks that offer a mix of restaurants, informal alfresco dining and lively bars. Moored Chinese junks have been refurbished into floating bars and restaurants. There are, however, several other parts of town which are lively at night; as in any big city, fashions change but it&rsquo;s worth checking out Kampong Glam (particularly around Haji Lane, for shisha bars), Holland Village (popular with expats) and Club Street. If you&rsquo;re around Orchard Road, try the bars in the restored Peranakan shophouses on Emerald Hill Road.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The vast range of available goods and competitive prices have led to Singapore rightly being known as a shopper's paradise. Special purchases include Balinese, Chinese, Filipino, Indian and Malay antiques; batiks; cameras; Chinese, Indian and Persian carpets; imported or tailored clothing; jewellery and shoes, briefcases, handbags and wallets. Silks, perfumes and silverware are other favourite buys.  The herding of shop owners from Chinatown into multi-storey complexes lost some of the exciting shopping atmosphere, although these huge centres do at least provide an air-conditioned environment. Orchard Road is the main shopping street, although many of the large hotel complexes, such as Marina Square, have shopping centres attached.</p>
<p>For electrical goods try Funan Digitalife Mall or Sim Lim Square.  Despite initial impressions shopping in Singapore need not, however, be all about malls. For a quirkier shopping experience try the boutiques on Haji Lane, which attract droves of young and fashionable shoppers. For bargains visit the flea market on Sungei Road, best on weekend afternoons, popularly known as the Thieves&rsquo; Market although it has long since been cleaned up. Although most outlets operate Western-style fixed pricing, bargains can still be made in some places but generally only after good research and shrewd negotiating. Haggling is essential at the Sungei Road flea market.</p><p>Daily 1000-2100, Sat 1000-2200. The Mustafa Centre in Little India is open 24-hours.</p><p>A 7% Goods and Services Tax (GST) is levied on most goods and services purchased from taxable retailers, although this can be claimed back on purchases made from retailers participating in the Tourist Refund Scheme. There are conditions, including: purchases must total S$100 or more from the retailer on a single day (on no more than three receipts); the goods must not be wholly or partially consumed in Singapore; your passport must be shown when making the purchase.</p>
<br />
<p>Refunds may be received at the airport, prior to departing flights. A new electronic system is being introduced, under which retailers issue an eTRS ticket when payment is made. This ticket, and the receipt, are required to use the electronic terminal at the airport. Some retailers still use the old system, where you must complete &ndash; and they must endorse &ndash; a form within the shop. Further details are available from Singapore Customs (<a href="http://www.customs.gov.sg" target="_blank">www.customs.gov.sg</a>).]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide variety of accommodation, ranging from budget to modern, ultra high-class hotels; note though that &lsquo;budget&rsquo; in Singapore terms is significantly more expensive than in many other countries in the region. At the top end the hotels have extensive facilities, including swimming pools, health clubs, several restaurants, full business services and shopping arcades. <br />
<br />
It is advisable to make advance reservations particularly at peak times, notably during the Formula One when prices increase dramatically but rooms can still be hard to find. All rooms are subject to 7% tax and 10% service charge; if a rate says &lsquo;++&rsquo; then this has not yet been added. For further information on accommodation in Singapore, contact the Singapore Tourism Board.<br />
<br />
If you arrive at Changi airport without a reservation, and don&rsquo;t want to walk the streets looking for something, then it&rsquo;s worth consulting the Singapore Hotel Association (<a href="http://www.stayinsingapore.com" target="_blank">www.stayinsingapore.com</a>) desks which are in each terminal. They cover a wide range of prices and, unlike some similar services, they do not charge tourists for the service.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Some hotels are designated as being 'International Standard' with all modern conveniences such as swimming pools and air conditioning. However, there is no formal star system of grading. Expect a Singapore hotel advertising itself as five star to be considerably more luxurious than many of the European equivalents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the guest houses are situated in the area around Bencoolen Street and Beach Road in the Colonial District. Although considerably cheaper than the main hotels, guest houses tend to offer less value for money. Discounts are sometimes available when staying a few days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide variety of accommodation, ranging from budget to modern, ultra high-class hotels; note though that &lsquo;budget&rsquo; in Singapore terms is significantly more expensive than in many other countries in the region. At the top end the hotels have extensive facilities, including swimming pools, health clubs, several restaurants, full business services and shopping arcades. <br />
<br />
It is advisable to make advance reservations particularly at peak times, notably during the Formula One when prices increase dramatically but rooms can still be hard to find. All rooms are subject to 7% tax and 10% service charge; if a rate says &lsquo;++&rsquo; then this has not yet been added. For further information on accommodation in Singapore, contact the Singapore Tourism Board.<br />
<br />
If you arrive at Changi airport without a reservation, and don&rsquo;t want to walk the streets looking for something, then it&rsquo;s worth consulting the Singapore Hotel Association (<a href="http://www.stayinsingapore.com" target="_blank">www.stayinsingapore.com</a>) desks which are in each terminal. They cover a wide range of prices and, unlike some similar services, they do not charge tourists for the service.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Some hotels are designated as being 'International Standard' with all modern conveniences such as swimming pools and air conditioning. However, there is no formal star system of grading. Expect a Singapore hotel advertising itself as five star to be considerably more luxurious than many of the European equivalents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a wide variety of accommodation, ranging from budget to modern, ultra high-class hotels; note though that &lsquo;budget&rsquo; in Singapore terms is significantly more expensive than in many other countries in the region. At the top end the hotels have extensive facilities, including swimming pools, health clubs, several restaurants, full business services and shopping arcades. <br />
<br />
It is advisable to make advance reservations particularly at peak times, notably during the Formula One when prices increase dramatically but rooms can still be hard to find. All rooms are subject to 7% tax and 10% service charge; if a rate says &lsquo;++&rsquo; then this has not yet been added. For further information on accommodation in Singapore, contact the Singapore Tourism Board.<br />
<br />
If you arrive at Changi airport without a reservation, and don&rsquo;t want to walk the streets looking for something, then it&rsquo;s worth consulting the Singapore Hotel Association (<a href="http://www.stayinsingapore.com" target="_blank">www.stayinsingapore.com</a>) desks which are in each terminal. They cover a wide range of prices and, unlike some similar services, they do not charge tourists for the service.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> Some hotels are designated as being 'International Standard' with all modern conveniences such as swimming pools and air conditioning. However, there is no formal star system of grading. Expect a Singapore hotel advertising itself as five star to be considerably more luxurious than many of the European equivalents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The healthcare system in Singapore is of very high quality, generally regarded as one of the best in the world; life expectancy is high and infant mortality is low. Citizens benefit from universal healthcare, funded by compulsory savings deducted from payrolls &amp;ndash; the money accumulates in a nationalised health insurance plan called Medisave, and can be shared across families. All health services are paid for when used, but at a subsidised rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Costs of medical care for those who do not participate in Medisave, such as tourists, can be very high compared to those in other parts of Southeast Asia. It is therefore important to take out appropriate travel insurance, which should include repatriation to your home country in the event of an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call 995 if you require an ambulance. The state-run Singapore General Hospital on Outram   Road (telephone: +65 6222 3322) receives emergency cases and health care is exceptionally good; private establishments include Raffles  Hospital (+65 6311 1111; &lt;a href="http://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com" target="_blank"&gt;www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com&lt;/a&gt;). Pharmacies can easily be found throughout the island, particularly the Watson&amp;rsquo;s and Guardian chains &amp;ndash; and pharmacists should be able to provide advice about minor ailments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also a large private medical sector in Singapore. The quality of care, combined with prices which are usually lower than in Europe and North America, means that Singapore has become a centre for medical tourism - although in recent years cheaper countries such as Malaysia and Thailand have become more popular.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food hygiene is generally good, particularly now that most individual street stalls have been closed down in favour of hawker centres. As always it&amp;rsquo;s safer to avoid raw vegetables, shellfish and reheated foods, and to wash fruit which has not been peeled. The tap water is safe to drink. Hepatitis A infection is not unknown, although rare, and vaccination may be considered.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Before leaving home, visit a doctor or travel health clinic for advice on health risks. Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malaria is not a problem in Singapore, but as in many urban areas of South East Asia dengue fever can be a concern. This disease is spread by the Aedes genus of mosquito, and symptoms include a rash, fever, headaches and pain in muscles and joints. In a small percentage of cases, the disease can become life-threatening. There is no vaccine and so the risk can only be minimised by reducing exposure to mosquito bites. Covering up is a good idea, as is use of a repellent &amp;ndash; most local brands include only citronella, so DEET-based repellent (which is generally more effective) should be brought from home if required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an outbreak of the Zika virus in Singapore in August 2016. The mosquito-borne illness can be spread from a pregnant woman to her unborn baby as well as through sexual contact. Travellers to Singapore should protect themselves from mosquito bites, pregnant women are advised to postpone non-essential travel until after pregnancy and pregnant women whose sexual partners live in or travel to areas with Zika virus transmission should follow safe sexual practices or abstain from sex for the duration of their pregnancy.&amp;nbsp;Women who are pregnant, at risk of getting pregnant, or planning pregnancy should seek further advice from their doctor before travelling to Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday.  (a) Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Hari Raya Puasa (End of Ramadan), Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Hari Raya Puasa itself. Hari Raya Puasa and Hari Raya Haji (Feast of Sacrifice) may last up to several days, depending on the region.  (b) Hindu festivals are declared according to local astronomical observations and it is not possible to forecast the date of their occurrence exactly.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>National Day :
							09 August </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/asia/singapore/singapore-2/">Singapore</a> by travellers aged 18 years and older without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 1L of spirits.<br />
&bull; 1L of wine.<br />
&bull; 1L of beer.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of S$600 (if out of the country for more than 48 hours) or S$150 (if out of the country for less than 48 hours).</p>
<p>There is no duty-free allowance for cigarettes and tobacco products.</p>
<p>These allowances do not apply if arriving from Malaysia&nbsp;or if you've spent less than 48 hours out of Singapore. If you don't use your allowance of spirits, then you may import an additional 1L of either wine or beer without incurring customs duty. Alcohol is expensive in Singapore, so bringing in duty-free drinks within these limits is a popular way to save a little money. You can find further information on the Singapore Customs website (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.customs.gov.sg">www.customs.gov.sg</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Chewing gum, chewing tobacco, electronic cigarettes and other &lsquo;imitation tobacco products&rsquo;, cigarette lighters of revolver or pistol shape, controlled drugs or psychotrophic substances, firecrackers, endangered species of wildlife and their byproducts, all pornographic films and literature, reproduction of copyright material, and seditious or treasonous material. The penalties for possession of narcotics are severe and visitors not complying with drug regulations do so at the risk of death.</p>
<p>A permit is required in order to import various restricted items. These include animals and their byproducts, meat, fruit, vegetables, fish, arms, explosives, bullet-proof clothing, toy guns, weapons, films, videos, video games, publications, audio records, pharmaceuticals, poisons, telecommunication and radio communication equipment and radioactive materials.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Export permits are required for items including arms, ammunition, explosives, animals, telecommunications equipment, film, videotapes and discs, precious metals and stones, and drugs and poisons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Singapore Dollar (SGD; symbol S$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of S$10,000, 1,000, 500, 100, 50, 10, 5 and 2. Coins are in denominations of S$1, and 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 cents.<br /><br />The currency of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brunei">Brunei</a> is also legal tender, although coins may not be accepted; 1 Brunei Dollar = 1 Singapore Dollar. <br /><br />US Dollars, Australian Dollars, Yen and Pounds Sterling are also accepted at many major shopping centres in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/singapore-city">Singapore</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies, traveller's cheques and cheques can be changed at most banks and licensed money changers, the latter generally offering slightly better rates. They can be found throughout the city, particularly on Orchard Road and in Little India. Some banks do not offer this service on Saturdays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa are widely accepted, although cheaper eateries are likely to accept only cash.</p><p>ATMs are widespread and many will accept cards from overseas banks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling. A passport is required when cashing traveller's cheques.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0930-1500, Sat 0930-1230 (some are open later). Branches of certain major banks on Orchard Road open Sun 0930-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Singapore, a passport valid for at least six months beyond the date of departure is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If a transit visa is required, it will be issued on arrival and have a validity of 96 hours. This allows passengers to leave the airport; bus tours of the city are available for passengers with sufficient stopover time.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Entry visa (for those who do require a visa): &pound;15.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa validity varies by nationality.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section of embassy/high commission). In certain countries applications may be submitted online (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ica.gov.sg">www.ica.gov.sg</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A long-term visit pass can be issued for the purpose of visiting family, seeking employment or accompanying a child studying in Singapore. There are long lists of requirements available on the Immigration and Checkpoints Authority website (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ica.gov.sg">www.ica.gov.sg</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visa processing time varies by country, with two tiers: one takes an average of three working days, the other an average of two weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sufficient funds are required either for a visa or visit pass, although &lsquo;sufficient&rsquo; is not explicitly defined.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can apply online for extensions to the visit pass up to 89 days beyond your date of entry (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ica.gov.sg">www.ica.gov.sg</a>). You must have at least three working days remaining on your current visit pass when you apply. Extensions to visas depend on nationality.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[1.321970]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[103.820986]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>697 sq km (269 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5,696,506 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>7,987.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Singapore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The island of Singapore is situated off the southern extremity of the Malay Peninsula, separated from the mainland by the Johor Strait which is about 1km (0.8 miles) wide. Causeways run across the strait carrying roads, a railway and water pipes. The main island is mainly flat with only low hills, the highest being Bukit Timah at 166m (545ft). In the northeast of the island, and in the urban district, large areas have been reclaimed, and much of the original jungle and swamp covering the low-lying areas has been cleared. In addition to the main island, the Republic of Singapore includes more than 60 much smaller islands and islets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buddhist 33%, Christian 18%, Muslim 15%, Taoist 11% and Hindu 5%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Handshaking is the usual form of greeting, regardless of race; Muslims, and some Hindus, would not however normally shake hands with someone of the opposite sex. Social courtesies are often fairly formal. When invited to a private home or entering a temple or mosque, remove your shoes. For private visits, a gift is appreciated and, if on business, a company souvenir is appropriate.</p>
<p>Dress is informal. Most first-class restaurants and some hotel dining rooms expect men to wear a jacket and tie in the evenings; a smart appearance is expected for business meetings.</p>
<p>Laws relating to jaywalking, littering and chewing gum are strictly enforced in urban areas. Smoking is widely discouraged and illegal in enclosed public places (including restaurants). Dropping a cigarette end in the street or smoking illegally can lead to an immediate fine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. British-style plugs with three square pins are standard. Many hotels have 110-volt outlets.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong since 2004.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Halimah Yacob&nbsp; since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Today considered one of South East Asia&rsquo;s economic success stories, the island of Singapore has a long history of trade &ndash; certainly Chinese merchants were visiting many centuries before the arrival of the first European colonists and at various times the island fell under the influence of competing kingdoms based in what are now Indonesia and Malaysia.</p>
<p>The Portuguese arrived in the region early in the 16th century, taking Melaka (on west coast) as their trading port. The Dutch followed, as did the British who took an interest in Singapore following the end of the Napoleonic Wars in 1818.</p>
<p>Under plans drawn up by Sir Stamford Raffles, Singapore was to be turned into a major port alongside Melaka and Penang, both of which were by then under British control. Although Raffles spent little time in the city, his decisions &ndash; such as dividing the city along ethnic lines &ndash;&nbsp;were crucial to its development.</p>
<p>Under the British, Chinese and Indian immigrants flocked to Singapore. Living conditions were often dreadful, but there was money to be made and the city-state became known for a work ethic, which is evident to this day. As in the other settlements a mixed-ancestry community, the Peranakan, arose after Chinese men married local women.</p>
<p>Japan took Singapore in World War 2 to the dismay of its colonial rulers. Conditions under the occupation were harsh for POWs and civilians alike and thousands of Chinese inhabitants were executed.</p>
<p>After the Japanese surrender, British rule was re-established before Singapore achieved independence in 1963 as part of the Malay Federation until Singapore was expelled in 1965.</p>
<p>Under the leadership of Lee Kuan Yew, who was prime minister from 1959 to 1990, the country attracted huge foreign investment but developed a repressive &ndash; though generally popular &ndash; single party political system.</p>
<p>In recent years Singapore has taken a more active role in regional affairs and there has been some improvement in relations between Singapore and Malaysia, whose myriad disputes number access to air space, water resources and territorial boundaries.</p>
<p>Did you know?</p>
<p>&bull; When Lee Kuan Yew died in January 2015, some 1.7 people paid tribute to him at his lying-in-state and at community centre around the island during a week of mourning.</p>
<p>&bull; The island&rsquo;s Chinese, Malay, Indian and Western Festivals are all national holidays.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Singapore in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 537 3100. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mfa.gov.sg/washington</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 537 3100. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300 and 1400-1730.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3501 International Place<br/>Washington D.C.<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[High Commission of the Republic of Singapore in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7235 8315. </p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mfa.gov.sg/london</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7235 8315. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900–1300 and 1400-1700; 0930-1230 (visa section).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>9 Wilton Crescent<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8SP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Singapore]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+65 6424 4200.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/organisations/british-high-commission-singapore</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+65 6424 4200.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1700; Mon-Fri 09-1100 (consular services, by appointment only).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>100 Tanglin Road<br/>Singapore<br/>247919<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Once routinely criticised for being dull, Singapore has reinvented itself as one of Southeast Asia&rsquo;s most modern and dynamic cities. Melding together a mass of different cultures, cuisines and architectural styles, the city-state is now studded with vast new showpiece constructions to complement its colonial-era hotels and civic buildings. Cutting-edge tourist developments continue to spring up. Shopping avenues and underground malls throb with life, as do the food courts, the riverside bars and the temple-dotted outlying neighbourhoods. It&rsquo;s never going to be Bangkok, but it&rsquo;s doing a fantastic job of being Singapore.</p>
<p>Chinese, Indian, Malay and European influences all flow through daily life here. Boring? Hardly. It&rsquo;s true to say, however, that the former British trading post and colony still has a reputation for its cleanliness (it&rsquo;s still panned for its seemingly petty regulations, such as the banning of chewing gum). Likewise, levels of serious crime are very low. It&rsquo;s worth pointing out, too, that Singapore&rsquo;s cultural mix has left it with a genuinely world-class food scene &ndash; and you won&rsquo;t need to spend big to eat well.</p>
<p>Recent years have seen the city really pushing for recognition as an international tourist destination in its own right, rather than as a convenient stopover. Significant investment has resulted in developments such as Marina Bay Sands, the three-towered skyscraper that now stands as Singapore&rsquo;s centrepiece; Resorts World Sentosa, which is home to a Universal Studios theme park; and Gardens by the Bay, a remarkable project complete with &ldquo;supertrees&rdquo; and two colossal plant domes.</p>
<p>More traditional attractions include the designer malls of Orchard Road, the exotic clatter of Chinatown and Little India and the elegance of Raffles Hotel, still standing proud more than 125 years after being built. On the subject of hotels, Singapore now offers one of the best spreads of high-end accommodation in the region: a sign, amongst other things, of its ambition to keep visitors flooding in. It&rsquo;s likely to succeed.</p><p>Once routinely criticised for being dull, Singapore has reinvented itself as one of Southeast Asia&rsquo;s most modern and dynamic cities. Melding together a mass of different cultures, cuisines and architectural styles, the city-state is now studded with vast new showpiece constructions to complement its colonial-era hotels and civic buildings. Cutting-edge tourist developments continue to spring up. Shopping avenues and underground malls throb with life, as do the food courts, the riverside bars and the temple-dotted outlying neighbourhoods. It&rsquo;s never going to be Bangkok, but it&rsquo;s doing a fantastic job of being Singapore.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
