<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Slovakia" ColCode="svk" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sk" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Slovakia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Slovakia lies in a moderate zone and possesses a continental climate with four distinct seasons. The average daily temperature in Bratislava in winter is -2°C (31°F), rising to 21°C (70°F) in the summer. January is the coldest month, the hottest being July and August. The highest peaks are snow-capped 130 days a year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Medium- to heavyweights and sturdy footwear for winter; lightweights for summer. Rainwear is advisable throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Czech Airlines (<a href="http://www.czechairlines.com" target="_blank">www.czechairlines.com</a>) runs domestic flights within Slovakia. Since distances are not too great, it&rsquo;s generally easier and better value to use the excellent bus and rail network however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Danube is the main artery for transport by ship. Lod/Slovak Shipping and Ports (tel: +421 2 5293 2226; <a href="http://www.lod.sk" target="_blank">www.lod.sk</a>) runs cruises on the river.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The rail network is operated by Slovak Republic Railways (ŽSR) (tel: +421 2 4485 8188; <a href="http://www.slovakrail.sk" target="_blank">www.slovakrail.sk</a>). There are several daily express trains between Bratislava and main cities and resorts. You should make reservations in advance on major routes. Fares are low, but supplements are charged for travel by express trains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>InterRail One-Country Pass: offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Slovakia. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p>Eurail Slovakia Pass: offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Slovakia. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The major routes run from Bratislava to Presov and Kosice, via Kralovany and Poprad. The network of roads and supporting services is dense and reliable. Motorways are equipped with emergency telephones every half a mile or less.</p>
<p>The Slovakia emergency system provides a fast and reliable network of garages, tow trucks and medical services. Road signs comply with European standards.&nbsp;Drivers may have to pay tolls on some highways and express roads.&nbsp;<strong><br />
</strong></p>r<p>Roads are standardised as motorways, first-, second- and third-class metalled roads, and are generally in good condition, particularly on the main arteries.</p><p>Buses are more expensive than trains, although weekend bus fares are sharply reduced. Slovak Lines (tel: tel: 18211, in Slovakia only or +421 2 5542 2734; <a href="http://www.slovaklines.sk" target="_blank">www.slovaklines.sk</a>) is the country&rsquo;s major bus service provider with connections to many domestic and international destinations.</p><p>These are available in all the main towns and are metered and cheap; higher fares are charged at night.</p><p>Most hire companies require a valid EU driving licence or International Driving Permit. If you are stopped by police you also need to produce your passport or ID card and your car hire documents, including proof of valid insurance.</p><p>Seat belts are compulsory. Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in towns, 90kph (56mph) outside towns and 130kph (81mph) on motorways. Cars must have their lights on 24 hours a day from 15 October to the 15 March.</p><p>Autoklub Slovakia Assistance (tel: 18112, in Slovakia only); Slovensk&yacute; Autoturist Klub (tel: 18124, in Slovakia only).</p><p>You can book self-drive cars through the tourist office in main towns and resorts, or at Bratislava airport. Drivers must be over 18 (although some companies require the driver to be over 21).</p><p>Slovakia's size and comparatively quiet roads make it relatively easy for visitors to get around under their own steam, either by car, motorbike or bicycle. Cycling in Slovakia is one of the best ways to see the sights through rolling countryside and forests and by the side of lakes, rivers and vineyards. Several companies offer mountain-bike tours and it&lsquo;s possible to hire mountain or road bikes in all major cities.</p><p>Seat belts are compulsory. Speed limits are 50kph (31mph) in towns, 90kph (56mph) outside towns and 130kph (81mph) on motorways. Cars must have their lights on 24 hours a day from 15 October to the 15 March.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buses, trolleybuses and trams exist in Bratislava and several other towns. All the cities operate flat-fare systems, and pre-purchase passes are available. Tickets should be punched in the appropriate machine on entering the tram or bus. A separate ticket is usually required when changing routes. There is a fine for fare evasion. Blue badges on tram and bus stops indicate an all-night service.<strong><br />
</strong></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Slovakia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">poprad</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Slovakia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">piescarontrsquoany_spa</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Slovakia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">koscaronice</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Slovakia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">b_bystrica</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.10</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating direct flights to Slovakia from the UK include Air Explore (<a href="http://www.airexplore.sk" target="_blank">www.airexplore.sk</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To Bratislava: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 15 minutes.</p>
<p>To Vienna, Austria: from London - 2 hours 10 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 8 hours 25 minutes. Trains from Vienna to Bratislava take an hour.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bratislava">Bratislava</a> airport has two terminals: A for departures, B for non-Schengen arrivals and departures.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bratislava">Bratislava</a> airport has two terminals: A for departures, B for non-Schengen arrivals and departures.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Košice International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airportkosice.sk<p>The airport is 10km (6 miles) south of the city .</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Tatry-Poprad International Airport </b><![CDATA[http://www.airport-poprad.sk<p>The airport is 5km (2.5 miles) from the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Bratislava Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airportbratislava.sk<p>Bratislava's airport is located 9km (5.5 miles) northeast of the city centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+421 2 3303 3353</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bratislava (<a href="http://www.spap.sk" target="_blank">www.spap.sk</a>) is the country's main port. International connections from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/austria">Austria</a> are possible on the Danube which flows into the Black Sea, and is also linked with the Rhine and the Main. Services run as follows: Bratislava-Vienna-Bratislava; Bratislava-Hainburg-Bratislava; and Vienna-Bratislava-Budapest, both ways. LOD (tel: +421 2 5293 2226; <a href="http://www.lod.sk" target="_blank">www.lod.sk</a>) is one of the main operators. River cruise ships also stop in Bratislava on their journeys along the Danube.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The most convenient route to Slovakia from Western Europe is via <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/prague">Prague</a> or Vienna. There are also direct connections to Budapest. Further information is available from Slovak Republic Railways (ŽSR) (tel: +421 2 4485 8188; <a href="http://www.slovakrail.sk" target="_blank">www.slovakrail.sk</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass: </strong>offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Buses travel from Vienna&rsquo;s S&uuml;dtiroler Platz to Mlynske Nivy bus terminal in Bratislava. Eurolines (tel: +421 2 5542 2734; <a href="http://www.eurolines.sk" target="_blank">www.eurolines.sk</a>) has regular buses that travel from Vienna International Busterminal to Bratislava&rsquo;s city centre.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public telephone booths are widely available, including special kiosks for international calls. Surcharges can be quite high on long-distance calls from hotels. Dial 112 for all emergency services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good, extending over the whole country, with the exception of remote areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are internet cafés in main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The constitution guarantees freedom of expression. All major daily newspapers are private and there are over 20 private radio stations. The introduction of commercial TV in the 1990s caused public broadcaster Slovak TV to lose a significant amount of viewers, with private TV broadcaster Markiza now claiming much of the audience. Cable and satellite TV are widely watched. Channels from neighbouring countries, such as the Czech Republic and Hungary, have a sizeable audience.</p> 
<p><em>The Slovak Spectator</em>, Slovakia's English-language newspaper, is published weekly. <em>Slovak Foreign Trade</em> is published monthly by the Slovak Chamber of Commerce. The principal dailies are <em>Novy Cas</em>, <em>Pravda</em> and <em>Sme</em>. Popular weekly Slovak magazines include <em>Plus 7 dni</em>, <em>Slovenka</em> and <em>Zivot</em>. Slovak Radio is a public broadcaster, operating five national networks and an external service; <em>Radio Expres</em>, <em>Radio Okey</em> and <em>Radio Twist</em> are all commercial stations, as is commercial news agency Fun Radio.]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most towns and villages have their own post office and some are open on Saturdays. The postal service, operated by Slovensk&aacute; po&scaron;ta (<a href="http://www.posta.sk" target="_blank">www.posta.sk</a>) is efficient, but tends to be slow. Priority service delivery to the UK takes approximately two to four days and economy post can take up to nine days. Priority delivery to the USA takes five to eight days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Follow the Carpathian wine route</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Starting just outside the Slovakian capital, the Small Carpathian Wine Route snakes through glorious countryside, past ancient wine towns and the wonderfully preserved Červený Kameň Castle. The route offers plenty of stopover options where you can sample the local wine.</p>]]><p><b>Get sporty in Vrátna Valley</b></p><![CDATA[<p>From skiing in winter to hiking or biking through glorious countryside in summer, there's plenty to do in the Malá Fatra mountain range resort of Vrátna. The view from the cable car on a sunny day is a must, though impressive all-year-round.</p>]]><p><b>Go underground in Slovakia’s second city</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Waterways, fortifications and the cathedral's foundation are all waiting to be discovered by intrepid visitors willing to head underground at Kosice's archaeological site. There's a labyrinth of passages beneath the earth linking together different parts of the ancient town.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the Tatras National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tatras National Park is the oldest national park in Slovakia and home to the famous High Tatras Mountains. Covering an area of 741 sq km (286 sq miles), it's a hiker's paradise. The landscape incorporates dense forest on the mountains' lower slopes, as well as glacial lakes and mountain streams. It's also famous for its chamois (mountain goats), bears and marmots.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Bratislava's architecture</b></p><![CDATA[<p>To get a sense of the country's past, take a walk up to Bratislava Castle (itself an impressive cultural monument) above the Old Town and gaze out. You'll see the pretty medieval core spread below, while rows of socialist-era tower blocks line up in the distance.</p>]]><p><b>People watch in Kosice</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Slovakia's second city is known for its buzzy atmosphere and pretty Old Town. Grab a coffee in the town square, and then take a terrace seat and watch the world go by. When evening rolls around, visit the State Theatre for a taste of high culture.</p>]]><p><b>Relax in the spas of Starý Smokovec</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its stunning views over the Tatras mountain range, this town famed for its mineral waters has a plethora of therapeutic spas where visitors can frolic in mineral-charged, hot spring waters said to cure everything from asthma to arthritis. Slovakia's copious mineral springs mean the country boasts some of Europe's best spas.</p>]]><p><b>Scale the ramparts of Spis Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spis is the largest castle in Slovakia, and one of the biggest in Central Europe. Standing proud on a 200m high (656ft) dolomite hill, it's as impressive for its setting as it for its medieval architecture. Although many parts of the castle's Gothic tower, chapel ramparts and dungeons stand in ruins, there are fine views from the summit. It was once one of the most important Gothic castles in Europe and there's a small museum inside documenting its history during the late Middle Ages, when it was in its prime.</p>]]><p><b>Settlement of Vlkolinec</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Some 45 traditional log houses, one of which houses a folk museum, cluster together in Vlkolinec, a delightful village that was awarded UNESCO World Heritage Status in 1993. There's perhaps nowhere better in Slovake to glimpse traditional rural life.</p>]]><p><b>Ski in Jasna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take to the piste in Jasna, which offers some of Slovakia's best skiing. The Demanova Valley resort has modern lifts and well-maintained slopes. And with prices at a fraction of its Western European alternatives, what's not to like?</p>]]><p><b>Wander around the Andy Warhol Gallery</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The provincial town of Medzilaborce isn't the most obvious place to find a classy modern art museum, which makes the Andy Warhol Gallery something of a curiosity. Warhol's parents were from the area. The man himself would have been pleased with the collection on show.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$89.6 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Vehicles, machinery and transport equipment, base materials, plastics, chemicals and minerals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, chemicals and fuels.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Czech Republic, Russian Federation, Poland and Australia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>After the division of Czechoslovakia in 1993, the newly independent Slovak government found its heavy industries to be something of a millstone, but they continue to play a central role in the economy. The agricultural sector (almost all of which is now privately owned) produces wheat and grains, sugar beet, vegetables and livestock. However, its relative economic contribution is not substantial. The bulk of the industrial economy has been transferred to the private sector, including the key areas of machinery and chemical industries, textiles, leather, shoes, glass, electronics, nuclear energy and car manufacturing.</p>
<p>After the initial transition shock, the economy performed fairly well in the mid- and late-1990s, but then went into recession. The situation was brought under control from 2002, after which the economy experienced considerable growth. Unemployment was currently at 12.1% in 2015. Slovakia adopted the euro at the start of 2009. Despite the global downturn, international body The Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development expects the country's fiscal growth to continue to be positive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businesspeople tend to wear suits and smart dress. English and German are the business languages, though any knowledge of Slovak is appreciated. Long business lunches are usual and presents are also appreciated. In recent years new media industries have been bringing in a greater degree of informality, especially in Bratislava.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700 (or longer).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Slovak Investment &amp; Trade Development Agency</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 821 01 ,(2) 5826 0100
					Website:http://www.sario.sk/
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Slovak Tourist Board's Congress &amp; Convention Department</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 5070 0801
					Website:http://www.sacr.sk
					Address: ,,,]]><b>National Agency for the Development of Small and Medium Enterprises</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 821 09 ,(2) 5024 4500
					Website:http://www.nadsme.sk/
					Address: ,,,]]><b>Slovak Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 816 03 ,(2) 5443 3291
					Website:http://www.scci.sk/
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Traditional Slovak eating and drinking habits date back to the old Slavic period influenced later by Austrian, German and Hungarian cooking. Slovak food revolves around a variety of soups, gruels, boiled and stewed vegetables, roast and smoked meats and dairy products. The style of cooking varies from region to region. Slovak specialities include both sweet and savoury dishes made with flour, including dumplings.</p><p>Popular drinks include Slovak beer, wine and mineral waters. Wine from the Tokaj region and sparkling wine from the Bratislava region are particular specialities. Restaurants and other catering establishments are many and varied, including cafés, buffets, snack bars, inns, alehouses and wine taverns. All restaurants are graded according to quality. The main meal of the day is usually lunch, comprising soup, a main dish, and dessert.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bryndzov&eacute;haluisky</strong>: Small potato dumplings with sheep's cheese.<br />
<strong>Mutton with sauerkraut</strong>: Flavoured with prunes, mushrooms and apples.<br />
<strong>Cabbage leaves</strong>: Filled with minced meat, served with a milky sauce.<br />
<strong>Sulance</strong>: Potato dough turnovers filled with plum jam.<br />
<strong>Polievka</strong>: Soup infused with garlic (<em>cesnakov&aacute;</em>) or sauerkraut (<em>kapustnica</em>).<br />
<strong>P&aacute;rok</strong>: Hot frankfurter, a typical morning snack.<br />
<strong>Jaternica</strong>: A dish derived from pig&rsquo;s blood and rice.<br />
<strong>Lango&scaron;e</strong>: Deep-fried dough topped with crushed garlic, cheese, ketchup or sour cream.<br />
<strong>Bryndza</strong>: Sheep&rsquo;s cheese that's light and salty, made in the area for centuries.<br />
<strong>Borovicka</strong>: Strong gin.<br />
<strong>Slivovica</strong>: Plum brandy.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A 5 to 10% tip is usual.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Theatre and opera are of a generally high standard - a legacy of the communist state system that supported its favourite branches of the arts. Much of the nightlife activity still takes place in hotels, although nightclubs are to be found in major cities. Bratislava, as the capital, has the liveliest nightlife in the country. It may not exactly be London or New York, but it has come on leaps and bounds since the end of communism.</p>
<p>Today there is a flurry of venues to choose from, whether visitors are looking for an atmospheric old Slovak drinking den or a student dive, a funky bar or bustling tourist-filled Irish theme pub. The rest of the country is playing catch-up, with the large student population in Kosice helping fuel an increasingly lively nightlife scene there too. Visitors are advised to keep their wits about them in rougher venues outside the capital where foreigners are a novelty and can be the subject of unwelcome attention.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Popular souvenirs include pottery, porcelain, woodcarvings, hand-embroidered clothing and food items. There are a number of excellent shops specialising in glass and crystal, while various associations of regional artists and artisans run their own retail outlets. Other special purchases include folk ceramics from all regions of Slovakia, and woodcarvings from the eastern and central parts (Kyjatice, Michalovce and Spi¡sská Belá). Bratislava is steadily attracting Western stores, with neon signs and swish facades brightening up a once slightly staid city, with this trend towards globalisation of the shopping market slowly spreading throughout the country.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800, Sat 0900-1200. Shopping centres open until 2100, with hypermarkets open 24 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel prices compare very favourably with western European hotels, though services and facilities are often more limited. There is a shortage of accommodation in the peak seasons and it is wise to pre-book. At present, higher-standard hotels are to be found primarily in Bratislava, in regional towns (such as Bansk&aacute; Bystrica and Kosice), in spas of national and international significance and in major tourist resorts (such as the High Tatras).</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Future developments and investment will result in upward reclassification of many establishments. The present system is: 5-star, 4-star, 3-star, 2-star and 1-star.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel prices compare very favourably with western European hotels, though services and facilities are often more limited. There is a shortage of accommodation in the peak seasons and it is wise to pre-book. At present, higher-standard hotels are to be found primarily in Bratislava, in regional towns (such as Bansk&aacute; Bystrica and Kosice), in spas of national and international significance and in major tourist resorts (such as the High Tatras).</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Future developments and investment will result in upward reclassification of many establishments. The present system is: 5-star, 4-star, 3-star, 2-star and 1-star.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Hotel prices compare very favourably with western European hotels, though services and facilities are often more limited. There is a shortage of accommodation in the peak seasons and it is wise to pre-book. At present, higher-standard hotels are to be found primarily in Bratislava, in regional towns (such as Bansk&aacute; Bystrica and Kosice), in spas of national and international significance and in major tourist resorts (such as the High Tatras).</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Future developments and investment will result in upward reclassification of many establishments. The present system is: 5-star, 4-star, 3-star, 2-star and 1-star.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Free or reduced-cost treatment is available to European visitors - in most cases on production of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC). More information can be obtained from the Slovak Ministry of Health (&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.health.gov.sk/"&gt;www.health.gov.sk&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Tap water is generally regarded as safe to drink.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations for tuberculosis, hepatitis B and tick-borne encephalitis and Lyme disease are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Independence Day of the Slovak Republic :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Victory Day :
							08 May </p><p>Saints Cyril and Methodius Day :
							05 July </p><p>Slovak National Uprising Day :
							29 August </p><p>Constitution Day :
							01 September </p><p>Day of Our Lady of Sorrows :
							15 September </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Struggle for Freedom and Democracy Day :
							17 November </p><p>Christmas Eve :
							24 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% volume, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Slovakia by persons over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco (if arriving by air).<br />
&bull; 40 cigarettes or 20 cigarillos or 10 cigars or 50g of tobacco (if arriving by road or rail).<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers (reduced to &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Unlicensed firearms and ammunition, meat and dairy products from outside the EEA, and endangered species (unless you have a permit).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Endangered species without a permit.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol €) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of €500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of €2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10 and 5 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currency (including traveller's cheques) can be exchanged at bureaux de change, main hotels, all banks, road border crossings, as well as major travel agencies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Major credit cards (American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard and Visa) and debit cards (Maestro and Visa Electron) are widely accepted.</p><p>ATMs are widely available in Slovakia and machines are generally reliable.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Thomas Cook and Visa traveller's cheques are accepted in banks and at bureaux de change. Exchange rate charges are at least 1% of the nominal cheque value. To avoid additional charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros, US Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0800-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Schengen airport transit visa authorises the holder to transit through the airport's international transit area, but is not required by nationals listed in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Slovakia is part of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa:&nbsp;&euro;60.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). Visitors requiring a visa must first fill out an application form online at <a href="https://ezov.mzv.sk">https://ezov.mzv.sk</a>, then book an appointment with the nearest consulate. Visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Non-EU nationals staying longer than 90 days must apply for a temporary residence permit. EU nationals planning on staying beyond 90 days should register with the police within three days of arrival; you'll have the chance to apply for a Slovak 'green card', which can be used as proof of ID.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The visa application procedure usually takes up to 15 days, but can take as long as 60 days in exceptional cases.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Non-EU nationals should have the equivalent funds of &euro;56 per person, per day, for their stay in Slovakia; this may be checked by customs.</p>
<p>Schengen visa applicants must be able to provide proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa holders can only extend their visas in exceptional circumstances such as <em>force majeure</em> or for humanitarian reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Pets need to be fitted with an ISO microchip and hold&nbsp;a pet passport or veterinary certificate stating that they have been vaccinated by a licensed veterinarian at least 21 days prior to travel.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[48.707048]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[19.486965]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>49,033 sq km (18,932 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>5,429,418 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>111 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bratislava.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Known in full as the Slovak Republic, Slovakia is a landlocked central European country, bordered by the Czech Republic, Austria, Poland, Hungary and Ukraine. Bratislava, Slovakia&rsquo;s capital city, sits in the extreme southwestern corner, close to the Austrian border. This bite-sized country boasts an astounding variety of scenery. From mountains, canyons and caves, to lakes, forests and lowland meadows, Slovakia&rsquo;s natural beauty makes it an appealing year-round destination for outdoor enthusiasts.</p>
<p>Almost half of the country is taken up by the Carpathian Arc, a range of mountains stretching across the north. Within the Arc, smaller ranges include the Lesser Carpathians, White Carpathians, Mal&aacute; (Lesser) Fatra, Vel'k&aacute; (Greater) Fatra, High and Low Tatras and the Slovensk&eacute; rudohorie Mountains (Slovak Ore Mountains).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the population is Roman Catholic. Protestant churches comprise the remainder with Reformed, Lutheran, Methodist and Baptist denominations. There is also a Jewish minority and, in the east of the country, a Greek Orthodox minority.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is the customary form of greeting. Punctuality is appreciated on social occasions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Peter Pellegrini since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Andrej Kiska since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Throughout its history, Slovakia has been dominated by foreign powers. Slavic tribes were settling in this area towards the end of the Roman Empire, when the area was subject to incursions by nomadic Magyar tribes, who settled and created an embryonic Hungarian state. A major military defeat in 1526 at the Battle of Mohacs at the hands of the Ottoman Turks signalled the end of the prosperous and peaceful period they inaugurated.</p>
<p>Allying itself with the Austrian Hapsburg monarchy, the burgeoning Slovak people resisted the Ottoman occupation and remained under the effective control of the Austro-Hungarian Empire until the late 18th century. The first nationalist movements started to emerge during this time. One of the most potent of these was led by Ludovit Stur and Andrej Hlinka (whose name was adopted by the Slovak WWII fascist movement, the Hlinka Guard).</p>
<p>With the end of WWI, and the collapse of the Austro-Hungarian Empire, Czechoslovakia was born, and with it an age of prosperity that lasted until 1938. During WWII, the first Slovak Republic was formed and Slovakia joined the Axis as a client state of Nazi Germany. The Germans occupied the republic in 1944, along with the rest of Czechoslovakia, but were pushed out by the Red Army, Romanian forces and Czechoslovakian troops. The liberated territories then became part of Czechoslovakia.</p>
<p>After WWII, Czechoslovakia became a Soviet satellite state and spent the following decades behind the Iron Curtain. Democratic reforms in November 1989 &ndash; and the fall of the Berlin Wall &ndash; led to the appointment of V&aacute;clav Havel as president, who helped the country introduce a pluralistic political system and a market economy.</p>
<p>While appreciating the new opportunities offered by the post-Soviet order, the Slovaks were worried about the liberalisation programme planned by Havel and his finance minister, V&aacute;clav Klaus, and there was a period of uncertainty. However, the first democratic elections were held in 1990, and the Movement for a Democratic Slovakia (HZDS) became the dominant force in Slovak politics.</p>
<p>The separation of Czechoslovakia into its constituent parts &ndash; the Czech and Slovak Republics &ndash; on 1 January 1993 was one of the rare occasions in history that two nations have accomplished such a divorce peacefully. This separation is known as the Velvet Divorce. A period of economic reforms in the early 2000s preceded Slovakia's entry into the European Union in 2004.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Although the Slovak people have been around since the Roman Empire, the separation of Czechoslovakia in 1993 marked the emergence of an independent and sovereign Slovak nation for the first time.<br />
&bull;	The picturesque village of Čičmany in northern Slovakia, full of traditional wooden houses, claims to be the first reservation of folk architecture in the world.<br />
&bull;	Bordering Austria and Hungary, Bratislava is the only capital in the world that borders two countries.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Slovakia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(2) 5998 2000.</p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/slovakia</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(2) 5998 2000.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0830-1700; Fri 0830-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Panská 16<br/>Bratislava<br/>811 01<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Slovak Republic in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7313 6470 or 90 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mzv.sk/londyn</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7313 6470 or 90 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thur 0900-1130 and 1300-1530, Fri 0900-1130.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>25 Kensington Palace Gardens<br/>London<br/>W8 4QY<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Slovak Republic in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 237 1054.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.mzv.sk/washington</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 237 1054.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>3523 International Court<br/>Washington D.C.<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Like the Czech Republic minus the crowds, Slovakia may sit in the shadows of its neighbour, but the country quietly impresses with its epic alpine scenery, clifftop castles and exquisite capital. <br />
<br />
Following the 'Velvet Divorce' of 1993, which saw Czechoslovakia split into two constituent parts (the Czech Republic and Slovakia), the nation set about reasserting its independent spirit, and today there's a humble, creative nature to Slovakia that wins over visitors of all stripes. Enthusiastic about art and music, the country is even home to a burgeoning hip-hop scene.</p>
<p>A small country of just five million odd inhabitants, Slovakia appeals to a broad range of travellers: from backpackers and businesspeople, to skiers and history buffs. It has one or two surprises up its sleeve. It is, for example, quietly gaining prestige as an alternative skiing destination. With its modern skiing infrastructure and new budget flights, Slovakia&rsquo;s High Tatras mountains are becoming a tantalising destination for winter sports enthusiasts.</p>
<p>As for the capital, it may be compared unfavourably with its neighbour, Prague, but Bratislava is nevertheless an alluring option for a city break. With an air of glamorous Vienna, it is home to gorgeous churches dating back to the 15th century, countless cafes squeezed onto cobblestone streets, and a slew of terrific, sometimes quirky museums.</p>
<p>Part of the Austro-Hungarian Empire for centuries, Bratislava&rsquo;s architecture is grand Central European in style. It was the Hungarian capital for nearly 300 years, with 11 monarchs crowned in the extraordinary 500-year-old St Martin&rsquo;s Cathedral.</p>
<p>Beyond its stunning capital, Slovakia boasts some impressive natural landscapes, which remain relatively unspoiled and uncrowded. The country has 10 national parks to speak of, which offer sprawling forests, rolling hills and meandering rivers.</p>
<p>Though Bratislava and the High Tatras mountains remain the star attractions in Slovakia, beyond them lies a diverse and decidedly beautiful land, rich in rewards for those bold enough to explore it.</p><p>Like the Czech Republic minus the crowds, Slovakia may sit in the shadows of its neighbour, but the country quietly impresses with its epic alpine scenery, clifftop castles and exquisite capital. <br />
<br />
Following the 'Velvet Divorce' of 1993, which saw Czechoslovakia split into two constituent parts (the Czech Republic and Slovakia), the nation set about reasserting its independent spirit, and today there's a humble, creative nature to Slovakia that wins over visitors of all stripes. Enthusiastic about art and music, the country is even home to a burgeoning hip-hop scene.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
