<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Slovenia" ColCode="svn" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="si" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Slovenia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Continental climate with warm summers and cold winters (snowfalls in the Alps). Mediterranean climate on the coast, with the average temperature at 0&deg;C (32&ordm;F) in January and 20&deg;C (68&ordm;F) in July.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Medium-weight clothing and heavy overcoats in winter; lightweight clothing and raincoats for the summer, particularly for the higher Alpine regions in the north.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no scheduled domestic flights in Slovenia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no scheduled domestic water transport in Slovenia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Train travel is generally inexpensive and slow. It is run by Slovenske Železnice (tel: +386 1291 3332; <a href="http://www.slo-zeleznice.si/" target="_blank">www.slo-zeleznice.si</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> Offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Slovenia. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Interrail (<a href="https://www.interrail.eu/en/interrail-passes/one-country-pass/slovenia" target="_blank">www.interrail.eu</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Slovenia Pass:</strong> Offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Slovenia. Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="https://www.eurail.com/en/eurail-passes/one-country-pass/slovenia" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>There is a good network of high-quality roads in Slovenia, which are clearly signposted. Many of the motorways have been built since Slovenia joined the EU and are relatively quiet, especially on Sundays when lorries are banned. Radio reports of traffic jams usually only concern the coastal border crossings at weekends in the summer.</p><p>Efficient coach services operate in the cities, major towns and tourist spots, and from Ljubljana airport to the city centre or Lake Bled. Otherwise, it is usually quicker and easier to go by car or rail. For bus information contact Avtobusna Postaja (tel: 1991, in Slovenia only or +386 1234 4600; <a href="https://www.ap-ljubljana.si/en/" target="_blank">www.ap-ljubljana.si</a>).</p><p>Taxis are relatively easy to find in the major cities, especially around the train station; in towns, you can usually book them from hotels and restaurants. Taxis are metered.</p><p>Full national driving licences with a photograph are accepted. Non-EU visitors can buy an&nbsp;International Green Card at the border. International car insurance is mandatory.</p><p>Speed limits in Slovenia are 110-130kph (68-75mph) on motorways, 90kph (56mph) on non-urban roads and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, sometimes reduced to 30kph (19mph).</p>
<p>Seat belts are compulsory (including in the back, if provided). Dimmed headlights must always be turned on while driving (even during the day). Vignettes (road tax stickers available from petrol stations) are required in order to use the motorways and express roads in Slovenia.</p>
<p>There are hefty on-the-spot fines if drivers are caught without a vignette, speeding, driving under the influence of alcohol (over 0.05%) or using a handheld mobile phone. Drivers should have a reflective jacket, a warning triangle and a first-aid kit in their cars.</p><p>AMZS Roadside Assistance (tel: 1987 in Slovenia only, +385 1530 5353; <a href="http://www.amzs.si" target="_blank">www.amzs.si</a>).</p><p>There are car hire companies, including many international brands, at Ljubljana airport and in the city, but it's best to reserve a vehicle online before you arrive. Drivers must be at least 21 and have been a licensed driver for at least two years.</p><p>Slovenia takes cycling seriously with its own star system to identify accommodation geared towards pedal pushers. Hotels, hostels and guesthouses in the scheme have their own bikes or can point you towards a rental shop. Tourist information centres (TICs) can also help with bike hire and route maps. There are marked routes all over the country. You can also explore Ljubljana with the capital&rsquo;s automated bike sharing system known as BicikeLj (<a href="http://en.bicikelj.si/Ljubljana" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">en.bicikelj.si</a>).</p><p>Speed limits in Slovenia are 110-130kph (68-75mph) on motorways, 90kph (56mph) on non-urban roads and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas, sometimes reduced to 30kph (19mph).</p>
<p>Seat belts are compulsory (including in the back, if provided). Dimmed headlights must always be turned on while driving (even during the day). Vignettes (road tax stickers available from petrol stations) are required in order to use the motorways and express roads in Slovenia.</p>
<p>There are hefty on-the-spot fines if drivers are caught without a vignette, speeding, driving under the influence of alcohol (over 0.05%) or using a handheld mobile phone. Drivers should have a reflective jacket, a warning triangle and a first-aid kit in their cars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s easy, safe and probably more interesting to get around Slovenia&rsquo;s towns and cities by foot, although the buses are quicker and reliable. They are run by Avtobusna Postaja (AP) (tel: 1991, in Slovenia only or +386 1234 4600;; <a href="https://www.ap-ljubljana.si/" target="_blank">www.ap-ljubljana.si</a>).</p>
<p>Ljubljana city buses are operated by the Ljubljanski Potni&scaron;ki Promet (LPP) (tel: 080 1888, in Slovenia only or +386 1582 2460; <a href="http://www.lpp.si" target="_blank">www.lpp.si</a>).</p>
<p>There are no underground trains or trams in Slovenian towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Slovenia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">portoroz</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Slovenia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">novo_mesto</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Slovenia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">murska_sobota</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Slovenia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">maribor</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Slovenia</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">bled</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.15</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline, Adria Airways (<a href="https://www.adria.si" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.adria.si</a>), operates direct flights from many surrounding European destinations to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/ljubljana">Ljubljana</a>. Other airlines offering direct flights from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a>, including easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Wizz (<a href="http://www.wizzair.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.wizzair.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/birmingham">Birmingham</a> - 4 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-new-city">New York</a> - 10 hours 10 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are visiting one of Slovenia&rsquo;s coastal towns, Trieste in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a> is closer than Ljubljana; if you are going to the east of the country, flying to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/zagreb">Zagreb</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia">Croatia</a>) might be a better option.<br />
If you are in search of ski slopes, flying to Graz in Austria is an option, with a bare 40-minute drive to Maribor and direct flights from Birmingham (<a href="https://www.flybmi.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.flybmi.com</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/slovenia/ljubljana-airport">Ljublijana Joze Pucnik Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you are visiting one of Slovenia&rsquo;s coastal towns, Trieste in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/italy">Italy</a> is closer than Ljubljana; if you are going to the east of the country, flying to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/zagreb">Zagreb</a> (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/croatia">Croatia</a>) might be a better option.<br />
If you are in search of ski slopes, flying to Graz in Austria is an option, with a bare 40-minute drive to Maribor and direct flights from Birmingham (<a href="https://www.flybmi.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.flybmi.com</a>).</p>
<p>The major airport is: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/slovenia/ljubljana-airport">Ljublijana Joze Pucnik Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Ljubljana Joze Pucnik Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.lju-airport.si<p>Ljubljana Airport is located 26km (16 miles) north of Ljubljana.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+368 4 206 1000</p>]]><b>Maribor Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.maribor-airport.si]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Portoroz Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.portoroz-airport.si]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors arriving on private vessels can choose from marinas at Izola, Koper, Piran and Portoroz.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Connections and through trains are available from principal eastern and western European cities. International destinations with direct services include Belgrade, Vienna and Zagreb.</p>
<p>Some international trains have couchette coaches, as well as bar and dining cars. Contact Slovenske Železnice (tel: +386  1291 3332; <a href="http://www.slo-zeleznice.si/" target="_blank">www.slo-zeleznice.si</a>) for more information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Interrail:&nbsp;</strong>Offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 15 days or seven days in one month across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Interrail (<a href="https://www.interrail.eu" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.interrail.eu</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail:</strong> Offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 22 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in one month, 7 days in one month, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in up to four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Motorways link Ljubljana with major cities in neighbouring countries, including Trieste and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/venice">Venice</a> in Italy, Rijeka and Zagreb in Croatia, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/budapest">Budapest</a> in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/hungary">Hungary</a>, and Villach and Graz in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/austria">Austria</a>.</p><p>For motorway driving you must display a weekly, monthly or yearly vignette (road tax sticker) in the windscreen. You can buy these at petrol stations as you approach the border or in shops at the border crossing.  In addition, a small fee of around 7 EUR is charged when passing Karavanke tunnel, which lies between Austria and Slovenia. Prices can be found on <a href="http://www.tolls.eu/slovenia" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">www.tolls.eu/slovenia</a>. Winter tyres (or snow chains and at least 3mm tread depth) are required from 15 November to 15 March. Dipped (low-beam) headlights are required at all times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Calls can be made with magnetic phone cards, which are sold at post offices, newspaper kiosks and tobacco shops. For emergencies, dial 112 (ambulance service and fire brigade) or 113 (police).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is generally good. Slovenia&rsquo;s primary mobile networks are Mobitel and Simobil. Slovenian SIM cards are also available if you plan to text or call local numbers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet caf&eacute;s are available in cities. There is also a free Wi-Fi service in Ljubljana when registered with Telekom Slovenije.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The media scene is diverse and free, and the constitution supports freedom of expression. About two-thirds of TV households are connected to cable or satellite. English-language publications include <em>Ars Vivendi</em>, <em>Slovenia Weekly</em>, <em>Slovenian Business Report </em>and <em>Slovenija</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Reasonable internal service. Stamps can be bought at bookstalls.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1800, Sat 0800-1200. Some post offices are open even longer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Explore Postojna Cave</p><![CDATA[<p>Take a train into the spectacular 20km (12-mile) cave of Postojna (<a href="http://www.postojnska-jama.si/" target="_blank">www.postojnska-jama.si</a>), only one hour's drive from the coast, which has been deemed one of the greatest sights of natural beauty, and features gigantic stalagmites and a cavernous hall which can hold over 10,000 people.</p><p>It is considered by experts to be one of the finest examples of karst landscape, where limestone rock has been heavily eroded by underground streams, a phenomenon that has created several other caves in the area.</p><p>Postojna Cave is also home to the Proteus anguinus, the blind "human fish", which can grow up to 30cm (1ft) in length and feeds on small crabs, snails and worms. Speleological equipment can be provided at the cave for caving enthusiasts, and special interest tours can also be arranged.</p>]]><br/><p>Marvel at Bled Castle</p><![CDATA[<p>Perched atop a steep cliff, 130m (426ft) above Lake Bled, is Slovenia&rsquo;s oldest castle. Bled Castle (<a href="http://www.blejski-grad.si/en" target="_blank">www.blejski-grad.si</a>) dates back to 1011, although much of its present look comes from the restoration that followed an earthquake in 1511. The main attractions are the Gothic chapel, built in the 16th century and renovated in Baroque style around 1700, and the views of Bled, the lake, its island and the mountain ranges of the Karavanke and Julian Alps.</p>]]><br/><p>Uncover the legend of Predjama Castle</p><![CDATA[<p>Worth visiting just to hear how Erazem of Predjama, a 15th century robber baron who was holed up in this &lsquo;impregnable&rsquo; castle, finally met his end. Think Elvis. Predjama Castle (<a href="http://www.postojnska-jama.eu/en" target="_blank">www.postojnska-jama.eu</a>) was built into a cliff, 9km from Postojna Cave, in the 12th century.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be beside the seaside</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Slovenia may not boast much in the way of a coast, but what it does have is absolutely beautiful. The coastal towns of Koper, Piran and Portoroz are gateways to the country&rsquo;s best beaches and. They are also home to splendid Venetian architecture, excellent waterfront restaurants and top hotels. Every year the town of Portoroz holds a contemporary art symposium with creations on display in the sculpture park, Forma Viva.</p>]]><p><b>Chill out at Radenci</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This is the best-known of Slovenia's 15 certified natural health resorts, having received its first guests in 1882. It is also known for the Radenska mineral water, which is said to have been served at the imperial court in Vienna and to the Pope in Rome.</p>]]><p><b>Don your skis in Maribor</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Slovenia&rsquo;s second largest city, Maribor offers skiing, shopping, coffee by the river, and wine. Essentially, it has the Pohorje mountain (with floodlit night-time skiing) on one side and vineyards on the other, while the river Drava meanders in-between. In the quaint Lent area by the river is the world&rsquo;s oldest vine, which is said to be more than 450 years old.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Postojna Cave</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a train into the spectacular 20km (12-mile) cave of Postojna, which features gigantic stalagmites and a cavernous hall that can hold over 10,000 people. Considered to be one of Europe&rsquo;s finest karst landscapes, Postojna is also home to an aquatic salamander called olm (aka &ldquo;the blind human fish&rdquo;). Speleological equipment can be provided for caving enthusiasts, and special interest tours can also be arranged (tel: +386 5700 0100; <a href="https://www.postojnska-jama.eu/en/" target="_blank">www.postojnska-jama.eu</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Fall in love with Slovenian wine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gori&scaron;ka Brda is a breath-taking wine region where the climate of the Julian Alps and the Adriatic Sea meet, giving body and freshness to the local wines &ndash; especially varieties such as Rebula. Vipava Valley is another delightful vineyard area with small, family-run wineries producing top whites from rare and ancient grape varieties such as Zelen, Pinela, Klarnica and Pikolit, and top reds from Merlot grapes.</p>]]><p><b>Go on a day trip to Ptuj</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Medieval features abound in this delightful town, which overflows with cobbles, churches and impressive baroque buildings. Officially the oldest settlement in Slovenia, it boasts a castle, thermal spas and some fabulous wines &ndash; underneath the streets are historic wine cellars that contain the country&rsquo;s oldest aperitifs.</p>]]><p><b>Hike around Lake Bohinj</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Slovenia&rsquo;s largest permanent glacial lake, Bohinj is longer, narrower and less crowded than Lake Bled. At the north-western tip is the waterfall Slap Savica, which can be seen after zigzagging up more than 500 steps. The lake is perfect for boating and swimming, while the area is also popular with hikers and cyclists (tel: +386 4574 7590; <a href="https://www.bohinj.si/en/" target="_blank">www.bohinj.si</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Imbibe art at Metelkova Mesto</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ljubljana&rsquo;s military barracks, built for the Austro-Hungarian army and used by Italian and German occupying forces, were taken over by artists in 1994 and transformed into an autonomous cultural centre. It is made up of seven buildings and includes space for musicians and performers, art installations, studios, and several nightclubs (<a href="http://www.metelkovamesto.org/?lang=txt_eng&amp;" target="_blank">www.metelkovamesto.org</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Induce adrenaline at Bovec</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located in Triglav National Park, this pretty little town is a Mecca for adrenalin-junkies, who flock here in the summer for white water rafting, kayaking and canyoning on the Soča River. In the winter, there is skiing at the nearby Kanin Ski Centre (tel: +386 5384 1919; <a href="https://www.bovec.si/en/" target="_blank">www.bovec.si</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at Bled Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Perched atop a steep cliff, 130m (426ft) above Lake Bled, is Slovenia&rsquo;s oldest castle. Bled Castle dates back to 1011, although much of its present look comes from the restoration that followed an earthquake in 1511. The main attractions are the Gothic chapel, built in the 16th century and renovated in Baroque style around 1700. Visitors also flock to the views of Bled, the lake, its island and the mountain ranges of the Karavanke and Julian Alps (tel: +386 4572 9782; <a href="http://www.blejski-grad.si/en/" target="_blank">www.blejski-grad.si</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Pilgrimage to Jeruzalem (no, not that one)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>An hour from Maribor by car, Jeruzalem is a tiny settlement in the middle of the most stunning terraced wine hills. There are plenty of places to taste the local dry and sweet whites and to sample them with the local cuisine. The Tourist Information Centre (TIC) by the old church has both maps and wine.</p>]]><p><b>Search for the Ljubljana Dragon</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The city's symbol, the mighty dragon, is depicted throughout the city on buildings, bridges, iron and woodwork. Visit Dragon Bridge for an up-close encounter with the brave beast or go on a dragon hunt and see how many you can find.</p>]]><p><b>Ski at Kranjska Gora</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This historic alpine town is Slovenia&rsquo;s top ski resort, with 30km (18 miles) of runs to choose from. Located in the Julian Alps, the north-western part of Slovenia, the resort is close enough to the Austrian and Italian border to walk to them in two hours. It has a lively central square, a pretty church, two casinos and great views down the valley. There are plenty of hiking and biking trails, too (tel: +386 4588 5020; <a href="https://www.kranjska-gora.si/en" target="_blank">www.kranjska-gora.si</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Spend a weekend in Ljubljana</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take your time wandering the streets of the country's capital. The Ljubljana River runs through the city with al fresco caf&eacute;s on the bank promenades, great for people watching and refuelling. Structures and buildings you shouldn't miss include Ljubljana Cathedral, the Franciscan Church of the Annunciation, the Fountain of Three Carniolan Rivers, the Town Hall and the gorgeous Nebotičnik Skyscraper&nbsp;(tel: +386 1306 1000; <a href="https://www.ljubljana.si" target="_blank">www.ljubljana.si</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Take a dip in Lake Bled</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This year-round mountain resort, only 35km from Ljubljana airport, is a truly beautiful sight with a church on a tiny island surrounded by glacial waters, mountains and trees. Overlooking it, medieval Bled Castle perches on a cliff edge. In the summer, you can swim, fish or row, perhaps to the island to ring the Wishing Bell (tel: +386 4578 0205;  <a href="http://www.bled.si/en" target="_blank">www.bled.si</a>).</p>]]><p><b>Trek through Triglav National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Taking its name from Mount Triglav, which at 2,864m (9,396ft) it is the highest summit in Slovenia, this park covers 4% of the entire country and is laced with hiking trails. It is also home to glacial lakes such as Bohinj, waterfalls (Savica and Peričnik), and gorges (Blejski Vintgar and Tolmin).</p>]]><p><b>Uncover the legend of Predjama Castle</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This destination is worth visiting just to hear how Erazem of Predjama, a 15th century robber baron who was holed up in this &lsquo;impregnable&rsquo; castle, finally met his end. Think Elvis. Predjama Castle was built into a cliff, 9km (5.5 miles) from Postojna Cave, in the 12th century.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$ 48.08 billion (2016 est.)</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Manufactured goods, machinery and transport equipment, chemicals and food.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and transport equipment, manufactured goods, fuels and lubricants, chemicals and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Germany, Italy, Austria, Croatia and Hungary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Slovenia was one of the most prosperous parts of Yugoslavia and, because of its proximity to Austria and Italy, easily slipped into western European ways when it became independent in 1991.</p>
<p>For the first 15 years Slovenia flourished thanks to its fertile land, strategic location and educated workforce. It was the first of the eastern European countries to join the EU (in 2004) and the first to adopt the Euro (in 2007). It was, however, hit hard by the 2008 global recessions and narrowly avoided a bank bailout.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The government&rsquo;s harsh austerity plans provoked protests in the major cities, and it was only in 2014 that the economy showed signs of stabilising. Since then, with financial growth due to increasing exports and consumer demand, Slovenia&rsquo;s previously high unemployment rate fell just under 7%. Privatising state-owned enterprises and reforming the banking sector has set up the country for a stable and thriving economy in 2018.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business conventions and etiquette in Slovenia are very similar to those in the rest of Europe. Slovenia has been an EU member since 2004 and visitors who have worked within the EU before should encounter few surprises.</p>
<p>Smart dress is advised. Appointments are usual and visitors should be punctual. A firm handshake is the typical start to any business meeting. Business cards are essential. Executives will generally have a good knowledge of German, English and sometimes Italian. There is a well-developed network of local agents, advisers, consultants and lawyers willing to act for foreign companies.</p>
<p>Gifts are welcome for business lunches or dinners and essential when visiting someone&rsquo;s home. The most suitable gifts include luxury items such as a bottle of Scottish whisky or a good bottle of wine.</p><p>Business hours are generally Monday to Friday 0900-1700 (or 1900), although quite a few still operate 0700-1500. Working the weekends is not the norm, though many shops now stay open on Saturdays and some on Sundays too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cankarjev Dom (Culture and Congress Centre)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01) 241 7100
					Website:http://www.cd-cc.si/
					Address: ,Prešernova 10,1000 Ljubljana,]]><b>Chamber of Commerce and Industry of Slovenia</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (01) 589 8000
					Website:http://www.gzs.si/
					Address: ,Dimičeva 13,1504 Ljubljana,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Slovenia's national cuisine consists of simple fresh produce and has been influenced by its neighbours and occupiers, namely Austria, Italy and Hungary. Soup is a typical starter followed by a pork, chicken or turkey dish with seasonal vegetables or salad.</p>
<p>Each region has its own special dessert, but pancakes are also popular. As Germany and Austria supply the bulk of tourists in many parts, dishes such as sauerkraut, grilled sausage and apple strudel can be found on most menus too.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><em>&bull;Potica:</em>&nbsp;a circular cake with a variety of fillings, namely nuts, honey, cream, raisins and cinnamon<br />
<em>&bull;Goulash:</em>&nbsp;a stew of meat and vegetables popular in the Hungarian influenced eastern Prekmurje region<br />
<em>&bull;Gibanica:</em>&nbsp;a popular layer cake made with pastry, cheese and eggs<br />
<em>&bull;Nanos:</em>&nbsp;a Slovenian hard cheese, it is one of many tasty varieties produced across the country<br />
<em>&bull;Seafood:&nbsp;</em>popular along the coast of Slovenia<br />
<em>&bull;Bled cream cake:&nbsp;</em>lashings of vanilla cream between two slices of pastry</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Rounding up is acceptable, though 10% is generally expected in city restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Larger towns have their fair share of nightclubs and cinemas; however, Ljubljana is the cultural capital. It has an opera house, and the symphony orchestra plays regularly in the Big Hall of the Cultural and Congress Centre.</p>
<p>As Ljubljana has a large student population, the bar and club scene is lively with a cosmopolitan feel. Music and fashion are on par with larger European cities and parties can carry on well into the morning.</p>
<p>Metelkova Mesto (<a href="http://www.metelkovamesto.org/" target="_blank">www.metelkovamesto.org</a>), Ljubljana&rsquo;s former military barracks, has some of the most interesting clubs. Maribor is Slovenia's second university city, and it too has a good nightlife. The main action along the coast happens in the resort of Portoroz.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Typical Slovenian souvenirs include bobbin lace, crystal glass and wine. Tourists should also look out for 'beehive art,' also known as<em>panjska koncnica</em>, which stems from the traditional technique of using panels from beehives as canvases. Today, artists still use these panels to paint landscapes, religious scenes and fables, though the tradition is maintained mostly for the tourist trade.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1900, Sat 0800-1300.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Slovenia has more than 200 hotels with over 30,000 beds throughout the country, offering budget friendly rooms, extravagant inns and everything in between.  <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> The hotel categories are 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Slovenia has more than 200 hotels with over 30,000 beds throughout the country, offering budget friendly rooms, extravagant inns and everything in between.  <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> The hotel categories are 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Slovenia has more than 200 hotels with over 30,000 beds throughout the country, offering budget friendly rooms, extravagant inns and everything in between.  <br />
<br />
<strong>Grading:</strong> The hotel categories are 1 to 5 stars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;The EHIC (European Health Insurance Card) gives tourists from EU-countries access to state-provided medical treatment, but comprehensive travel insurance is advised. Travellers from other countries should find out if they are covered by other reciprocal arrangements. Australia, for example, has such an agreement as long as citizens carry their Medicare card. For more information contact the Health Insurance Institute of Slovenia (ZZZS) (&lt;a href="http://www.zzzs.si/" target="_blank"&gt;www.zzzs.si&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is considered safe and drinkable. However, bottled water is available and advised for the first few weeks of the stay. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption. Local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables are generally considered safe to eat.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Tick-borne encephalitis is present in forests. Walkers should take precautions against tick bites. Vaccination is advisable. Immunisation against hepatitis B, diphtheria and tuberculosis is sometimes advised. Rabies is present, albeit rare. For those at high risk, vaccination arrival should be considered. If you are bitten, seek immediate medical advice.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Pre :
							08 February </p><p>Easter Monday :
							02 April </p><p>Resistance Day :
							27 April </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Pentecost :
							20 May </p><p>Statehood Day :
							25 June </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>Slovenians Incorporated into the Mother Nation :
							17 August </p><p>Restoration Day :
							15 September </p><p>Reformation Day :
							31 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Rudolf Maister Day :
							23 November </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Independence Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Slovenia is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/united-kingdom/">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragrance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty. The following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% volume, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Slovenia by persons over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers (reduced to &euro;150 for children under 15).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Meat and dairy products from outside the EEA, endangered species (unless you have a permit), narcotics, unlicensed weapons and ammunition, explosives, medicines (unless for personal use) and some plants.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Endangered species (unless you have a permit), narcotics, unlicensed weapons and ammunition, and fresh or processed mushrooms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol &euro;) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign currencies can be exchanged at banks and some hotels, supermarkets, petrol stations, tourist agencies and exchange bureaux.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners, MasterCard and Visa are accepted at upmarket establishments; elsewhere cash is preferred. Credit cards can be used to get cash advances from banks.</p><p>ATMs are easily accessible, especially in urban areas, where you can withdraw cash 24 hours a day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Widely accepted. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Euros, US Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700 (sometimes an hour break at noon); Sat 0830-1100/1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card that is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another, however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. Though it is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Slovenia is part of the Schengen area.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60/&pound;50. Reductions are available for some nationals and for children.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In person at the consulate (or consular section at embassy). Visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Non-EU nationals staying longer than three months must apply for a residence permit.</p>
<p>EU nationals staying beyond three months must obtain a residence registration certificate in the area where they live. The Ministry of the Interior has a special website for foreigners which has further information (<a href="http://www.infotujci.si">www.infotujci.si</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow 10 to 21 days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa applicants must be able to provide proof of sufficient funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa holders can only extend their visas in exceptional circumstances, such as <em>force majeure</em> or for humanitarian reasons.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If bringing a pet from another EU country, your animal must have a microchip, pet passport and valid rabies vaccination certificate. Animals arriving from outside the EU require a microchip and veterinary certificate confirming they have been vaccinated against rabies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[46.119988]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[14.821031]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>20,273 sq km (7,827 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,055,000 (2017 est.)</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>103 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ljubljana.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parliamentary Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>This compact and strategically important country is dominated by mountains, rivers and major north-south and east-west transit routes. Slovenia borders Italy to the west, Austria to the north, Hungary to the northeast and Croatia to the southeast, with a 47km (30-mile) Adriatic Sea coastline, where Koper serves as the main port.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most of the population is Roman Catholic (about 60%), with small communities of other Christians including Eastern Orthodox. There are also Muslim and Jewish minorities, as well as 10% declared atheist or nonreligious.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shaking hands is the normal form of greeting. Usual European social conventions apply and informal dress is widely acceptable. Smoking is prohibited on public transport, in cinemas, theatres, public offices and in waiting rooms. You must be at least 18 to purchase tobacco products. Slovenia&rsquo;s strict smoking regulations, some of the most stringent in the EU, fall in line with the country&rsquo;s &lsquo;green&rsquo; environmental initiative.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Marjan Sarec since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Borut Pahor since 2012.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An independent nation since 1991, the territory of present-day Slovenia has a rich and tumultuous history that belies its age. Until the early 20th century, foreign kingdoms &ndash; the Frankish Empire, Holy Roman Empire and Austro-Hungarian Empire &ndash; controlled Slovenia. The Kingdom of Serbs, Croats and Slovenes, a territory later renamed Yugoslavia, then absorbed the Slovenian area at the end of WWI.</p>
<p>But the turmoil continued in 1941 when <a href="http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic/46315/Axis-Powers" target="_blank">the Axis powers</a> invaded Yugoslavia and carved up Slovenia between Germany, Italy and Hungary. This invasion was met with unexpectedly fierce resistance in the form of the Yugoslav Communist Party, led by Josip Broz Tito, who helped defeat the aggressors in 1945 and establish the Democratic Federal Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>Slovenia became a constituent republic of this new federation, but the ruling League of Communists of Slovenia (LCS) sought greater autonomy from Belgrade, Serbia's capital. Their opposition was muted, however, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Croatian_Spring" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">after similar calls from Croatia</a> were forcefully suppressed by Tito in 1971.</p>
<p>Slovenia&rsquo;s liberal political atmosphere quickly proved the antithesis of the autocratic climate in Serbia under Slobodan Milosevic. In 1990, it became the first Yugoslavian federal state to hold multi-party elections, which DEMOS, a six-party centre-right coalition, won.</p>
<p>Slovenia&rsquo;s liberal political atmosphere &ndash; the antithesis to the autocratic climate in Serbia under Slobodan Milosevic &ndash; saw it become the first Yugoslavian federal state to hold multi-party elections in 1990, which were won by a six-party centre-right coalition, calling itself DEMOS.</p>
<p>After 14 months, during which both Slovenia and Croatia became increasingly alienated from Belgrade, Slovenia declared independence. The central government immediately sent in armoured convoys to take control of federal border posts and key installations in the capital Ljubljana.</p>
<p>The army clearly did not expect the resistance put up by Slovene irregulars. After a few weeks of sporadic and largely inconclusive fighting, the two sides reached a ceasefire. By October 1991 all federal military forces had left the republic, and Slovenia proclaimed its independence on 8 October.</p>
<p>Full international recognition followed in January 1992, after which the DEMOS government collapsed, having achieved its sole objective of securing global acknowledgment. Slovenia was admitted to the United Nations in May 1992 and joined the EU in May 2004, becoming the first of the former Yugoslav republics to attain membership.</p>
<p>In over two decades, Slovenia has undergone a remarkable transformation from a controlled federal state to an independent, democratic nation and eurozone member. It was a bumpy ride &ndash; the worldwide financial crisis of 2008 hit this fledgling nation particularly hard &ndash; but the future seems to be bright for this young country of two million.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull; Pound for pound, Slovenia is one of the most biodiverse countries on the planet &ndash; it covers just 0.004% of the world&rsquo;s surface, but is home to 1% of all living creatures.<br />
&bull; The town of Maribor boasts the oldest vine in the world, estimated to be approximately 450 years old.<br />
&bull;&nbsp;Slovenia is home to an estimated 700 brown bears, which is one of the largest bear populations in Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Slovenia in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 (202) 386 6601</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.washington.embassy.si</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 (202) 386 6601</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2410 California Street<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Slovenia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7222 5700 or +44 77 1362 8096 (emergencies)</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.london.embassy.si</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7222 5700 or +44 77 1362 8096 (emergencies)</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon 1000-1300; Wed 1000-1300 &amp;amp; 1400-1600; Thu 1000-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>17 Dartmouth Street<br/>London<br/>SW1H 9BL<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British embassy in Slovenia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+386 1200 3910</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/world/organisations/british-embassy-ljubljana</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+386 1200 3910</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0800-1600.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Trg republike 3<br/>Ljubljana<br/>1000<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Green, clean and keen to please, Slovenia might lack the pulling power of its heavyweight neighbours, but this charming country is rich in rewards for travellers willing to take a punt.</p>
<p>Sandwiched between Italy, Austria, Hungary and Croatia, this tiny nation occupies a picturesque pocket of Europe, which is characterised by verdant valleys, glacial lakes and snow-capped mountains.</p>
<p>Slovenia has been greatly influenced by the countries surrounding it; the baroque architecture, ancient castles and sophisticated cuisine are evocative of western neighbours, while the quaint rural villages, Slavic language and low prices have a decidedly eastern feel.</p>
<p>But, Slovenia has its own identity. The first of the former Yugoslavian states to join the EU, the country is a progressive, forward-thinking nation. Its people are easygoing and welcoming to outsiders.</p>
<p>Most travellers begin their Slovenian adventure in the capital, Ljubljana, a charming university city whose resident academics give the place a youthful vibe. Carved in two by the Ljubljana River, the city is peppered with caf&eacute;s, independent shops and a gamut of excellent restaurants. It has a laidback vibe and a calm ambiance, unlike most capitals on the continent.</p>
<p>But it&rsquo;s when you step outside the capital that Slovenia showcases her true charms; the beautiful Adriatic coastal towns; the rolling vineyards of Jeruzalem-Ormož; the picture-perfect lake Bled; the caves of Postojna and &Scaron;kocjan; and the black ski runs of Kranjska Gora.</p>
<p>Slovenia is a particularly attractive proposition to outdoor enthusiasts and adrenaline junkies, who can try anything from cycling, hiking and paragliding to white-water rafting, caving and mountaineering. Less adventurous visitors occupy themselves basking on beaches, people-watching in caf&eacute;s and quaffing some of the country&rsquo;s excellent wines.</p>
<p>However you spend your time in Slovenia, you'll probably leave wondering why more people haven't caught on to her many charms. But, ultimately, her quiet beauty and understated elegance make Slovenia even more appealing.</p><p>For first-time visitors, Slovenia looks as if it has more in common with its Alpine neighbours of Austria and Italy, than those of former Yugoslavia.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
