<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Solomon Islands" ColCode="slb" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sb" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Solomon Islands]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Semi-tropical, mainly hot and humid, with little annual variation in temperature. The wet season (November to April) can bring severe tropical storms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tropical, lightweights and cottons are recommended. Rainwear from November to April.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Solomon Airlines<em> </em>(<a href="http://www.flysolomons.com" target="_blank">www.flysolomons.com</a>) runs domestic flights to around 20 airfields across the country. It's a good idea to book well in advance.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Regular passenger boats run between Honiara and Auiki. A weekly service travels from Honiara to Gizo via Marovo. Otherwise, there are plenty of tour operators running cruises and sightseeing trips.</p>
<p>If arriving by private vessel, make sure you obtain permission from the local chief before landing in individual provinces.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are over 1,300km (800 miles) of roads throughout the islands.  About 455km (280 miles) are main roads and a further 800km (500 miles) are privately maintained roads for plantation use.  Road maintenance is limited and the general condition of the roads is very poor, as are driving standards.  Most of the roads are on Guadalcanal and Malaita.</p>l<p>Available in Honiara, Gizo and Auiki. It is advisable to agree the fare beforehand.</p><p>Most national driving licences are accepted, as are International Driving Permits.</p><p>This is available through hotels in Honiara.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Honiara has a public minibus service. Elsewhere, you might grab a lift in the back of a truck or trailer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Solomon Airlines<em>&nbsp;</em>(<a href="http://www.flysolomons.com" target="_blank">www.flysolomons.com</a>), which flies direct from Honiara to Sydney and Brisbane. Fiji Airways (<a href="http://www.fijiairways.com" target="_blank">www.fijiairways.com</a>) flies from Nadi. If flying from Europe or North America, the most common route is via Australia.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 30 hours (including stopovers); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 27 hours (including stopovers); <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/brisbane">Brisbane</a> - 3 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>SI$40.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Honiara International Airport </b><![CDATA[<p>The airport on Guadalcanal Island is 13km (8 miles) east of Honiara (journey time - 20 minutes).</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:&nbsp;</strong>Honiara  (Guadalcanal Island), Yandina (Russell Islands) and Noro (New Georgia). Cargo lines sometimes offer a limited number of passenger places. It may also be possible to sail with a yacht from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/australia">Australia</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand">New Zealand</a> as part of the crew.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no area codes. There are often technical problems with line connections.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors can hire mobile phones on the islands; payment is preferred in cash (US/AUS/NZ currencies are accepted).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public e-mail facilities are available in Gizo and Honiara.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A high rate of illiteracy means that the radio has more influence than the press. An Australian-led mission to restore order had improved working conditions for local journalists and militia leaders who threatened the press were jailed. The Australian government donated equipment to the <em>Solomon Islands Broadcasting Corporation (SIBC)</em> and has sponsored programmes to promote peace. Taiwan has also granted technical aid.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes approximately seven days.</p><p>(Honiara) Mon-Fri 0900-1630, Sat 0900-1100. Other post office hours: Mon-Fri 0800-1630, Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Experience island life</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Culturally speaking the Solomon Islands are fascinating. Though bound together by their shared maritime heritage, the various societies living on the archipelago differ wildly from island to island. As well as a taste of local life, a visit to the main islands of Choiseul, Guadalcanal, Malaita, New Georgia, San Cristobal and Santa Isabel offers a peek at the Solomon Islands&rsquo; colonial history. </p>]]><p><b>Explore the wildlife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Pack your binoculars because wildlife abounds on the Solomon Islands. Go in search of a range of reptiles (including turtles), as well as marsupials such as flying foxes (fruit bats), phalangers and opossums. The birdlife is also excellent.</p>]]><p><b>Grab a rod and go fishing</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Try a spot of fishing in the Solomon Islands' well-stocked waters. Enquiries may be made at the Point Cruz Yacht Club, which welcomes visitors. The bountiful waters surround the Solomons have well over 700 species of fish that include big game such as sailfish and marlin.</p>]]><p><b>Head to Honiara</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Honiara, the capital city, is a fine place to while away a day or two. It has a pleasant museum, botanical gardens and Chinatown, and its strewn with relics from WWII. Notice boards indicate major battles and incidents that took place during the battle for Guadalcanal. Villages and scenic drives are within easy reach.</p>]]><p><b>Sample the local culture in Guadalcanal</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Go on an excursion around Guadalcanal and other islands. Popular tours include the battlefields of WWII, the Betikama carving centre, and Alite and Laulasi villages on the island of Malaita, where shells are broken, rounded and, after further working, strung together. The strings of shells can be worn as bracelets, necklaces, belts and earrings.</p>]]><p><b>Take part in sports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A variety of sports are enjoyed on the Solomon Islands including rugby union and football. There is a national team for both sports. Other popular sports include futsal and beach football, which the Solomon Islands have excelled at in international competition level.</p>]]><p><b>Take the plunge and go diving</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Much of the best land-based diving located in the Western Province on or near the islands of Gizo and New Georgia. Well-known dive sites in the area include Munda, on the Roviana Lagoon, 15 minutes by plane from Gizo; and Uepi Island, on the north side of New Georgia, across the famous Marovo Lagoon. Diving tours to the numerous WWII wrecks are also possible.</p>]]><p><b>Venture into the tropical rainforests</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tour the tropical rainforests that cover most of the archipelago and scale its verdant volcanoes. Exotic orchids, ferns and palms are widespread and butterflies are abundant. Got a fancy for reptiles? You're in luck because there are more than 70 species in the jungle, as well as fruit bats.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$358 million (2007).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Timber, fish, palm oil, palm kernels, coconuts, cocoa and copra.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, transport equipment and mineral fuels.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Australia, Singapore, Japan, New Zealand, Fiji and Papua New Guinea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The economy depends on subsistence agriculture and fishing, which together employ about 90% of the population. The agricultural sector produces coconuts, sweet potatoes, cassava, fruit and vegetables; livestock rearing has grown steadily. Copra is still produced in commercial quantities, but low world prices have reduced the income from this commodity.<br /><br />The Solomon Islands' main industrial prospect lies in its mostly undeveloped mineral resources. Gold mining is now important and is set for further expansion; in addition, there are confirmed deposits of copper, lead, zinc, silver, cobalt and other ores. In the service sector, there is a small tourism industry which brings in around US$15 million annually, but this has been affected by the poor security situation.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shirt and smart trousers or skirt will suffice. English and French are widely spoken. The best time to visit is May to October.<br /></p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1300-1630, Sat 0730-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Solomon Islands Chamber of Commerce and Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>There are a few restaurants outside the hotels in Honaria. Both Asian and European food is served and the cuisine is generally good. There are two Chinese restaurants in Honiara which are quite popular. Table service is normal. Spirits, wine and beer are available.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><br />&bull;<em> Tapioca</em> pudding. <br />&bull; <em>Taro</em> roots with <em>taro</em> leaves.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>There is no tipping on the Solomon Islands and visitors are requested to honour this local custom.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Honiara is a comparatively quiet town, although there are a few clubs with music and dancing, the occasional film show, and snooker and darts. The clubs offer temporary membership to visitors.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local purchases include mother-of-pearl items, walking sticks, carved and inlaid wood, copper murals, conch shells and rare varieties of cowrie. New Georgia in the western district is known for carved fish, turtles and birds. Carvings in ebony, inlaid with shell, are unique. Duty-free shopping is available at a number of stores in Honiara.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-1700, Sat 0800-1200.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of hotels, motels and lodges in Honiara, but visitors are advised to make advance reservations. Accommodation is also available in Malaita, the Reef Islands and Western Solomons. A number of lodges and resorts on the islands offer a variety of leisure activities. A full list of accommodation and rates is available from the Ministry of Commerce, Employment and Tourism or the Solomon Islands Visitors Bureau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of hotels, motels and lodges in Honiara, but visitors are advised to make advance reservations. Accommodation is also available in Malaita, the Reef Islands and Western Solomons. A number of lodges and resorts on the islands offer a variety of leisure activities. A full list of accommodation and rates is available from the Ministry of Commerce, Employment and Tourism or the Solomon Islands Visitors Bureau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are a number of hotels, motels and lodges in Honiara, but visitors are advised to make advance reservations. Accommodation is also available in Malaita, the Reef Islands and Western Solomons. A number of lodges and resorts on the islands offer a variety of leisure activities. A full list of accommodation and rates is available from the Ministry of Commerce, Employment and Tourism or the Solomon Islands Visitors Bureau.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are very limited and there are drug shortages. There are several hospitals, the largest being the Central Hospital in Honiara. Church missions provide medical facilities on outlying islands. Health insurance is essential.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as being a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should be boiled first or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products that are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Each part of the Solomon Islands has its own Province Day. (If a Province Day falls on a Sunday, the following Monday is observed as a public holiday). These are listed below.<br />
<br />
<strong>25 Feb </strong>Choiseul. <br />
<strong>2 Jun </strong>Isable. <br />
<strong>8 Jun </strong>Temotu. <br />
<strong>29 Jun </strong>Central Island. <br />
<strong>20 Jul </strong>Rennell. <br />
<strong>1 Aug </strong>Guadalcanal. <br />
<strong>3 Aug </strong>Makira/Ulawa. <br />
<strong>15 Aug </strong>Malaita. <br />
<strong>7 Dec </strong>Western Province.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Easter Sunday :
							01 April </p><p>Queen's Birthday :
							09 June <b>Date to be confirmed </b>yes
							</p><p>Independence Day :
							07 July </p><p>National Day of Thanksgiving :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following items may be imported into the Solomon Islands by travellers aged 18 years and older without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 250g of cigars or 225g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 2L of wine or spirits.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to a value of SI$3,000 (SI$1,500 for travellers under 18).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited goods include counterfeit coins and currency, indecent articles and films, honey, matches containing white or yellow phosphorus, narcotics, Royal Arms, flick knives and war relics.</p>
<p>Restricted goods include alcohol (including brandy, whisky and rum), arms and ammunition, cannabis, worn clothing, tobacco (more than 200 cigarettes), electrical equipment and fireworks.</p>
<p>Fruit and vegetables require an import permit, except those from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-zealand">New Zealand</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Solomon Islands Dollar (SBD; symbol SI$) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of SI$50, 20, 10, 5 and 2. Coins are in denominations of SI$1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money can be changed at banks, bureaux de change, some hotels, and larger shops and restaurants. Automated foreign exchange machines are available in Honiara.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All major credit cards are widely accepted in hotels and tourist resorts. There are three ATMs in Honiara.</p><p>There are three ATMs in Honiara.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Can be exchanged at banks, of which there are three in the major towns. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Australian Dollars or Pounds Sterling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0830-1500.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter the Solomon Islands, a valid passport is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>
<p>You may be asked to show return tickets and proof of sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You can extend your visitor's permit by up to three months only if there are special circumstances justifying the extension.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-9.148959]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[160.987010]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>28,896 sq km (11,157 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>594,934 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>21.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Honiara.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Constitutional monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The larger of the islands are 145 to 193km (90 to 120 miles) in length, while the smallest are no more than coral outcrops. The terrain is generally quite rugged, with foothills that rise gently to a peak and then fall away steeply to the sea on the other side. The capital of Honiara is situated on Guadalcanal Island, which also has the highest mountain, Mount Makarakombu, at 2,447m (8,028ft). There are a number of dormant volcanoes scattered throughout the archipelago.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>More than 95% of the population are Christian. The rest is made up of Roman Catholics, South Sea Evangelists and Seventh-day Adventists.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A casual atmosphere prevails and European customs exist alongside local traditions. Informal wear is widely suitable although women often wear long dresses for evening functions. Men need never wear ties. In general, women should dress modestly and appropriately, noting that certain public areas may be exclusively reserved for men. It is customary to cover thighs. Visitors are discouraged from wearing beachwear and shorts around towns and villages. Swearing is a crime and can lead to huge compensation claims and even jail.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>240 volts AC, 50Hz. Australian-type plugs with three flat, angled pins are in use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Rick Hou since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>HM Queen Elizabeth II since 1952, represented locally by Governor-General Sir Frank Kabui since 2009.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The modern nation of the Solomon Islands is an amalgamation of two archipelagos, instigated by the British in the last years of the 19th century and marking the high point of imperial rivalry in the Pacific between the major European powers. The northern group had originally been claimed by the Spanish in the 16th century, was then annexed by the Germans and finally ceded to the British in exchange for part of the Samoan island group. The British already controlled the southern Solomon group and administered the pair together as the British Solomon Islands Protectorate.</p><p>The islands experienced some of the most intense fighting of World War 2 as Japanese forces occupied the territory and doggedly resisted a series of attempts to oust them, most notably the bloody Battle of Guadalcanal. The Solomon Islands remained under British rule until the 1970s. Self-government was granted in 1976 and full independence was achieved two years later.</p><p>The main political debate since then has been over-decentralisation. Advocates support the division of the archipelago into separate administrative regions, while opponents maintain that the process would give an excessive advantage in the future to those islands which are most commercially developed – generally those closer to Papua New Guinea and Australia. Many of the roots of the debate lie in the issue of land ownership and the long-running disputes spilled over into ethnic violence that brought country to its knees. Bankrupt and with the capital in chaos, in 2003 the Solomon Islands appealed to the outside world for help and the Australian-led Regional Assistance Mission to Solomon Islands arrived to put the country back together.</p><p>Queen Elizabeth II remains head of state and the current Prime Minister Manasseh Sogavere is serving his third term in office, but the islands' governments are characteristically weak and politically unstable leaving them open to frequent votes of no confidence and changes of ministerial personnel.</p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• Future US President John F Kennedy was shipwrecked on Plum Pudding Island following his boat's collision with Japanese destroyer 'Amagiri' on 1 August 1943. Kennedy invited his rescuers Biuku Gasa and Eroni Kumana to his inauguration but local officials tricked them out of going.</p><p>• The Solomons were struck by major earthquakes in 2007 and 2013, both were followed by tsunami.</p><p>• <em>Walkabout Long Chinatown</em>, a Pijin language song composed in the 1950s, is often referred to as the islands' national song.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British High Commission in Solomon Islands]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>21 705.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gov.uk/government/world/solomon-islands</p><p><b>Tel:</b>21 705.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1200 and 1300-1600. Fri 0800-1200pm and 1300-1500.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>British High Commission Honiara, Residence of the British High Commissioner <br/>Tanuli Ridge<br/>676<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Permanent Mission of the Solomon Islands to the UN in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 599 6192/3.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.un.int/wcm/content/site/solomonislands</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 599 6192/3.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Suite 400L, 800 2nd Avenue<br/>New York<br/>10017<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Solomon Islands in Belgium]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(02) 732 7085.</p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(02) 732 7085.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Avenue Edouard Lacomble 17<br/>Brussels<br/>1040<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Solomon Islands archipelago is made up of nearly 1,000 tropical islands scattered across the southwestern Pacific, just to the east of Papua New Guinea. The remote location has kept the islands an unspoilt gem of a travel destination, with a slowly developing tourist industry.</p><p>The main islands to visit are Guadalcanal, Malaita, Choiseul, New Georgia, San Cristobal and Santa Isabel. The capital of Honiara, on Guadalcanal, is also well worth some time, with a museum, botanical gardens and its very own Chinatown. Villages and scenic drives are within easy reach of the capital, as are the popular World War II battlefield tours and carving villages on the islands of Rennell and Bellona.</p><p>Many Pacific islands are well geared to tourism today, but Solomon Islands bucks the trend, with a few shambolic guesthouses to stay in and a thoroughly laid-back approach to life. No palatial resorts here. The locals pride themselves in preserving the natural beauty of the islands.</p><p>Wander the jungle-strewn landscapes and take pleasure in stumbling across leaf-hut villages. Indeed, the traditional culture of the islanders endures to this day. Some 70 languages are spoken among the half a million largely Melanesian inhabitants, the majority of whom are Christian, though they also cling to their ancient customs. Many still wear traditional indigenous clothing, while the pan flute can be heard everywhere.</p><p>On the natural side, there are volcanic islands to explore, vast lagoons, spell-binging rainforests and countless tropical islands. Be sure to tour the mangrove forests, but beware of crocodiles. More active visitors can go surfing and kayaking, while the well-kept coral reefs offer ample opportunity for snorkelling. Guided tours into the yawning chasm of an extinct volcano is another unmissable, as are dives down to shipwrecks from World War II.</p><p>The Solomon Islands may not be that well known compared to other regional destinations, but this makes them all the more enticing for the adventurous traveller.</p><p>The Solomon Islands archipelago is made up of nearly 1,000 tropical islands scattered across the southwestern Pacific, just to the east of Papua New Guinea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
