<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Somalia" ColCode="som" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="so" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Somalia]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The <em>Jilal </em>starts around January and is the harshest period, hot and very dry. <em>Gu </em>is the first rainy season lasting from March to June. <em>Hagaa</em>, during August, is a time of dry monsoon winds and dust clouds. The second rainy season is from September to December and is called <em>Dayr</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweights and rainwear.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jubba Airways (<a href="http://www.jubba-airways.com/" target="_blank">www.jubba-airways.com</a>) and Daallo Airlines (<a href="http://www.daallo.com" target="_blank">www.daallo.com</a>)&nbsp;both run regular domestic services.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Modern Somalia is essentially a broad strip of coastal desert. Roads are poor and consequently coastal shipping is an important form of transport, both socially and economically. Piracy is a risk at sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's difficult to travel outside Mogadishu by car.&nbsp;Existing roads run from the capital to Burao and Baidoa.&nbsp;Previously sealed roads running between Kismayu and Mogadishu, and Hargeysa and Mogadishu are now in a state of disrepair.&nbsp;Passenger transport is restricted almost entirely to road haulage.</p>r<p>Available in large towns.</p><p>An International Driving Permit is required.</p><p>Available in Mogadishu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Minibuses and shared taxis&nbsp;run in Mogadishu, but availability may be restricted outside normal working hours (Sat-Thurs 0700-1400).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Jubba Airlines&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.jubba-airways.com/" target="_blank">www.jubba-airways.com</a>) and<em>&nbsp;</em>Daallo Airlines (<a href="http://www.daallo.com" target="_blank">www.daallo.com</a>) run regular services to major destinations within the region, including Dubai, Jeddah and Nairobi.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London - 31 hours (including stopovers); New York - 28 hours (including stopovers).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US$50 landing fee at Mogadishu Airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Mogadishu Aden Adde International Airport</b><![CDATA[<p>The airport is 6km (4 miles) west of the city.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Berbera, Kismayu, Marka and Mogadishu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Outgoing international calls must be made via the operator.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Several companies exist but there are currently no roaming agreements with international comapanies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Somalia's <em>SomaliNet </em>is one of the country's first ISPs. Internet facilities for visitors are yet to be fully established.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Somalia's disintegration has been reflected in its media. Broadcasters and journalists operate in a dangerous environment, affecting their ability to report freely, and many Somalis rely on foreign broadcasts for their news.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Europe takes up to two weeks.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be captivated by beautiful beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Somalia's beaches line the Indian Ocean in the east and are protected by a coral reef running from Mogadishu to the Kenyan border in the south. White sands and shimmering cyan seas offer a picture of paradise; whilst ghostly stretches of abandoned war-torn buildings have their own unique atmosphere.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the former grandeur of Mogadishu</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Were it not for the warlords, parts of the capital would be highly attractive to tourists. Crumbling now, the stone city walls were once grand fortifications that defended the city, whilst lighthouses, mosques and tombs shine a light on a more illustrious past. The Shanghai Old City was once the playground of the wealthy and remains a scenic spot.</p>]]><p><b>See the cave paintings of Las Geel</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Hundreds of well-preserved Neolithic paintings decorate the walls of this inter-connected series of caves and shelters in Somaliland. Las Geel deserves to be a UNECSO World Heritage Site but sadly, due to the current political state of Somalia, and the unrecognised status of Somaliland, this is unlikely to happen anytime soon.</p>]]><p><b>Spot rare species at Kismayo National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With orange sands and green shrubbery, Kismayo National Park contains many common East African species such as elephants, zebras and giraffes, and the rare Hunter's hartebeest. Somalia other great savannah, Hargeisa National Park, situated outside the city of Mogadishu in the north, is a protected slice of oft unseen Africa.</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at Hargeisa's unique War Memorial</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the heart of Hargeisa, the capital of the self-declared state of Somaliland, a war memorial stands to commemorate state's breakaway attempt in the 1980s. Shunning the grandiose or classical styles of traditional war memorials, the monument at Freedom Square consists of crashed MiG-17 fighter plane and a fresco of a citizen with bleeding limbs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$5.38 billion (2007).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Livestock, bananas, hides, fish, charcoal and scrap metal.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Food grains, animal and vegetable oils, petroleum products, construction materials and manufactured products.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Yemen and United Arab Emirates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Somalia's economy has been seriously dislocated by years of fighting and political strife, as well as a severe long-term drought which has affected the whole of East Africa. Somalia now ranks among the poorest countries in the world.<br /><br />Subsistence agriculture and livestock rearing occupy most of the working population, although development is hampered by primitive techniques, poor soil and climatic conditions, and a chronic labour shortage. Bananas are the main cash crop and provide nearly half the country's export earnings; cotton, maize, sorghum and other crops are produced for domestic consumption. Animal products, particularly hides and skins, are another key source of revenue, mainly from Saudi Arabia.<br /><br />Fishing has dwindled to the level of individual small boats, but there are provisional plans to restore this to full commercial capacity. Oil and gas deposits have been located but their exploitation has been in abeyance due to the lack of an effective central government. There is little industry other than small-scale operations to meet domestic needs, mainly food-processing and oil refining.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wear lightweight suits without a tie in hot weather. The best time to visit is October to May.<br /></p><p>Sat-Thurs 0800-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>In peacetime, restaurants in the major cities serve Chinese, European, Italian and Somali food. The majority of Somalis are Muslims and most of the food is halal. Dishes vary from region to region although many show East African, Turkish, Arab, Indian, Turkish, Ethiopian and Italian influences.</p><p>Camel is popular for both its meat and milk, which Somalis believe to be more nutritious than cow or goat milk. Under Islamic law, alcohol is illegal.</p><p>Traditionally, Somalis will perfume their homes after eating, burning incense on hot soapstone coals.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cambuulo: </strong>Azuki beans mixed with butter and sugar.</p><p><strong>Federation: </strong>Equal part rice and spaghetti layered with stewed meats and vegetables, served with salad and banana.</p><p><strong>Otka:</strong> Dried meat, usually camel, fried in butter and spices, very similar to jerky.</p><p><strong>Hilibari: </strong>Goat meat.</p><p><strong>Sambusa: </strong>Somali version of the Indian samosa, spiced with hot pepper and filled with minced meat or fish.</p><p><em><strong>Iskudhexkaris</strong></em><strong>:</strong> A hot pot of rice, vegetables and meat.</p><p><strong>Boorash: </strong>Porridge eaten with butter and sugar.</p><p><strong>Muufo: </strong>Cornbread baked and cut into pieces topped with sesame oil then mashed with black tea. <br/><strong>Canjeero:</strong> A small, thin pancake, eaten for breakfast or with a stew.</p><p><strong>Malawax: </strong>Sweet, greasy flatbread, s staple of many home-cooked meals.</p><p><strong>Lahoh: </strong>Bread often eaten with honey and ghee to accompany tea.</p><p><strong>Basbousa: </strong>Sweet cake made from cooked semolina soaked in syrup.</p><p><strong>Jalaato: </strong>Frozen sweet fruit on a stick, like an ice-lolly.</p><p><strong>Lows iyosisin:</strong> Confection of peanuts and sesame in caramel.</p><p><strong>Xalwo: </strong>Halva made from sugar, cornstarch, cardamom, nutmeg and ghee, sometimes with peanuts.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>A tip off 10-15% is normal in hotels and restaurants.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Buying and drinking alcohol is illegal in Somalia.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Local bands playing African and European music are popular. There are frequent traditional feasts with ritualistic and recreational dance, music and folk<strong> </strong>songs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional crafts include gold, silver jewellery, woven cloth and baskets from the Benadir region, meerschaum and woodcarvings.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0800-1230 and 1630-1900.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the main cities of Hargeisa and Mogadishu, there are international-standard hotels. There are also hotels in Afgoi, Berbera, Borama, Burao, Kismayu and Marka.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Government-run rest houses are located in many places with dormitory accommodation for four to 10 people.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the main cities of Hargeisa and Mogadishu, there are international-standard hotels. There are also hotels in Afgoi, Berbera, Borama, Burao, Kismayu and Marka.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the main cities of Hargeisa and Mogadishu, there are international-standard hotels. There are also hotels in Afgoi, Berbera, Borama, Burao, Kismayu and Marka.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are very limited and visitors are advised to take their own medicines with them. Health insurance is essential. Medical treatment at government-run hospitals and dispensaries is free for Somalians and may sometimes be free for visitors.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is normally chlorinated and, whilst relatively safe, may cause mild abdominal upsets. Access to water may be disrupted. Bottled water is available and advised. Drinking water outside main cities and towns is likely to be contaminated and sterilisation is considered essential. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Powdered or tinned milk is available and is advised. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water; swimming pools which are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. Vaccinations against meningococcal meningitis, tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Somalia has one of the lowest HIV rates in &lt;a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/africa"&gt;Africa&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Muslim festivals are timed according to local sightings of various phases of the moon and the dates given below are approximations. During the lunar month of Ramadan that precedes Eid al-Fitr, Muslims fast during the day and feast at night and normal business patterns may be interrupted. Some disruption may continue into Eid al-Fitr itself. Eid al-Fitr and Eid al-Adha may last up to several days, depending on the region.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Independence Day :
							26 June </p><p>Republic Day :
							01 July </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into Somalia without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 400 cigarettes or 40 cigars or 400g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of wine or spirits.<br />
&bull; A reasonable amount of perfume for personal use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Somali Shilling (SOS; symbol S) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of S500, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of S1, and 50, 10 and 5 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US Dollar bills are the easiest currency to exchange; hotels are the easiest and safest places. Avoid money changers in crowded areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Not accepted.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>US traveller's cheques are preferred but generally not recommended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sat-Thurs 0800-1130.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter Somalia, a passport valid for the duration of stay is required by nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa on arrival: US$50.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas on arrival are valid for one month.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visas are available on arrival at Mogadishu International Airport or from the Somali embassies in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia and Nairobi, Kenya. Note that Somaliland and Puntland issue their own visas at their respective ports of entry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[9.459979]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[47.167015]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>637,657 sq km (246,201 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>11,079,013 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>16.6 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mogadishu.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Federal republic. At the Arta Peace Conference in 2000, an interim parliament was established. The northern part of the country considers itself independent as the Republic of Somaliland with Ahmed Mohamed Mohamoud as president since 2010, although it has not achieved international recognition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Somalia is bordered to the north by the Gulf of Aden, to the south and west by Kenya, to the west by Ethiopia and to the northwest by Djibouti. To the east lies the Indian Ocean.</p>
<p>Somalia is a semi-arid country and the scenery includes mountains in the north, flat semi-desert plains in the interior and a subtropical region in the south. Separated from the sea by a narrow coastal plain, the mountains slope south and west to the central, almost waterless plateau which makes up most of the country. The beaches are protected by a coral reef that runs from Mogadishu to the Kenyan border in the south.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The state religion is Islam and the majority of Somalis are Sunni Muslims. There is a small Christian community, mostly Roman Catholic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traditional dance, music, song and craftsmanship flourish despite gradual modern development. Informal wear is acceptable and there is no objection to bikinis on the beach. Visitors should respect local customs.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Hassan Ali Kheyre since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Muse Bihi Abdi since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Somalia developed from a string of Arab sultanates along the northeast coast of Africa, which in turn had grown up from trading posts established from the 17th century onwards. As Arab influence waned, the British, French and Italians established protectorates on the Somali coast during the late-19th century. These were the subjects of various treaties, forged amid frequent border clashes between the colonial powers and the neighbouring Ethiopians.<br/><br/>Modern Somalia was created on 1 July 1960 from British and Italian Somalilands. Inherited tribal rivalries and territorial disputes have dominated the country's subsequent history. The Somali Youth League held on to power throughout the 1960s, mostly under the leadership of President Shermake. Throughout that decade, the government aggressively pursued claims to the Ethiopian Ogaden region and parts of Kenya's Northern Frontier District, the latter resulting in a severance of diplomatic relations with the UK between 1964 and 1968. After President Shermake was assassinated in October 1969, a military coup installed Mohamed Siad Barre as president of the renamed Somali Democratic Republic. The new government built up close relations with the Soviet Union, which was especially keen to make use of the port of Berbera. However, the Soviets were also close to the revolutionary regime in Ethiopia, whose relations with Somalia deteriorated throughout the 1970s. Forced into a choice, the Soviets opted for Ethiopia, to which Siad Barre responded by building up links with the West and the USA in particular.<br/><br/>His government collapsed in 1991 as civil war broke out and various regional factions jostled for position leaving the country without an effective central government. Various efforts backed by the international community to set a transitional government largely failed, although in 2004 the military was re-established and defeated the Islamic Court Union in the south. That lead to the formation of the militant Al-Shabaab terrorist group.</p><p>However, in 2012 a new provisional constitution was enacted and the Federal Government of Somalia established with its capital in Mogadishu and in 2016 the first US ambassador to Somalia for 25 years took up his post as the United Nations welcomed a new timetable for elections towards the return of a multi-party system in 2018.<br/></p><p>Did you know?</p><p>• Although home to a wealth of diverse regional cultures, all Somali food is halal.</p><p>• Ancient dry stone burial pyramid structures known as 'taalo' litter the landscape.</p><p>• During the early years of the civil war several autonomous regions were set up including Puntland, Somaliland and Galmudug, which survive to this day.<br/> </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Somalia]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+254 (20) 2844 000 or +254 (20) 2873 000. </p><p><b>Website:</b>https://www.gov.uk/government/world/somalia</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+254 (20) 2844 000 or +254 (20) 2873 000. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0700-1600; Fri 0700-1300. Visa section: Mon-Thurs 1330-1530; Fri 1100-1230.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>British High Commission Upper Hill Road, P.O. Box 30465-00100,<br/>Nairobi<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Somali Permanent Mission to the United Nations in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 688-9410.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.un.somaligov.net</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(212) 688-9410.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>425 East 61st Street, Suite 702<br/>New York<br/>10065<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of Somalia in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>07852 280 959.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.uk.somaligov.net</p><p><b>Tel:</b>07852 280 959.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Neasden<br/>Moran House, Suite 9 449-451 High Road,<br/>London<br/>NW10 2JJ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Think Somalia and what springs to mind? Pirates, Civil War, Islamic militants? Suffice to say it&rsquo;s not your average holiday destination. Until 2012 the country had been without a government for two lawless decades and, although the fractured nation has witnessed a period of relative stability recently, it remains highly dangerous.</p>
<p>Travel is possible in the northern districts of the self-proclaimed Republic of Somaliland, a quasi-independent state that has broken away from the rest of Somalia. Travellers, however, should avoid visiting other areas.</p>
<p>And that's a shame, because behind the turmoil lies a destination of considerable beauty. Somalia has a varied landscape of mountains, deserts, tropical rainforests, undiscovered beaches and coral reefs. Sadly, much of it is under threat from unregulated logging, drought and the ongoing civil war.</p>
<p>Modern day Somalia developed from a string of Arab sultanates, which were scattered along the northeast coast of Africa. As Arab influence waned during the late 19th century, the British, French and Italians designated these territories as protectorates. These were the subjects of various treaties, forged amid frequent clashes between the colonial powers and the neighbouring Ethiopians, and between the European powers themselves.</p>
<p>The problems Somalia experiences today were sown in 1960, when the British and Italian Somalilands were merged. Inherited tribal rivalries and territorial disputes have dominated the country's history since.</p>
<p>Years of fighting between rival warlords and an inability to deal with famine and disease have led to the deaths of up to one million people. The area is still extremely volatile, with attacks taking place, especially in the capital of Mogadishu.</p>
<p>Those keen on travelling to the region would be well advised to visit neighbouring Ethiopia or Djibouti instead. But if you are set on Somalia, there are a handful of attractions to see including the Laas Geel cave complex, which offers exquisite Neolithic art and stunning rock formations</p>
<p>Gorgeous beaches and beautiful coral reefs can also be found along the coast, but you&rsquo;d have to be one dedicated beach bum to seek them out.</p><p>Think Somalia and what springs to mind? Pirates, Civil War, Islamic militants? Suffice to say it&rsquo;s not your average holiday destination. Until 2012 the country had been without a government for two lawless decades and, although the fractured nation has witnessed a period of relative stability recently, it remains highly dangerous.</p>
<p>Travel is possible in the northern districts of the self-proclaimed Republic of Somaliland, a quasi-independent state that has broken away from the rest of Somalia. Travellers, however, should avoid visiting other areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
