<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="South Korea" ColCode="kor" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="kr" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[South Korea]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Moderate climate with four seasons, making any season a fine time to visit as long as you wear appropriate clothing. The hottest part of the year is during the rainy season between July and August, and the coldest is December to February. Occasional typhoons bring high winds and floods. Spring and autumn are mild and mainly dry and are generally considered the best times to visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons and linens are worn during summer, with light- to mediumweights in spring and autumn. Medium- to heavyweights are advised during the winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>National airlines Asiana Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://flyasiana.com/">http://flyasiana.com</a>) and Korean Air (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.koreanair.com/">www.koreanair.com</a>) run frequent services around the country. International flights primarily leave from Incheon International Airport, while domestic flights fly to/from Gimpo.</p><p>Air travel within South Korea can be quite reasonable if you book online.  Discounts often rival train fares.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are ferry terminals at: Incheon, Gyeokpo, Mokpo, Yeosu, Jeju, Gunsan, Wando, Tongyeong, Geoje, Donghae and Boryeong, connecting port to port and out to some of the smaller islands. Ferries connect Busan with Jeju Island. Car ferries also operate this route. Cruises operate on the Han River in Seoul, which runs through the centre of the capital from Yeoido.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Korail (<a href="http://www.korail.com" target="_blank">www.korail.com</a>) connects major destinations. There are three classes of trains: Korea Train Express (KTX, the country's high-speed, two-class service); Saemaeul trains (express, first class-grade service); and Mugunghwa trains (local, more of a 'second class' service). KTX has east (Gyeongbu line, ending in Busan) and west (the Honam line ending in Mokpo) routings. Station signs in English are common and English translations of timetables are usually available. The high-speed train from Seoul to Busan takes 2 hours 35 minutes, and from Seoul to Chuncheon takes 1 hour 20 minutes.</p>
<p>A private high speed operator, the Super Rapid Train (SRT), which travels from Seoul to Busan/Mokpo, started in December 2016 but the website is currently in Korean only (https://etk.srail.co.kr).</p>
<p>Korail also runs a network of special tourist trains in summer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Korea</strong><strong> Rail Pass</strong><strong>:</strong> allows visitors travel with reserved seats on any KR train (except subways) within a one-, three-, five- or seven-day period. Saver passes are available for groups of between two and five people, and Youth<em> </em>passes for people aged between 13 and 25 years old. For details and a pass, see www.letskorail.com.<br />
<br />
<strong>Korea</strong><strong> Rail Pack:</strong> includes accommodation and sightseeing services as well as the actual rail journey. Packs include a free pick-up/drop-off service for major hotels in downtown Seoul, hotel accommodation with breakfast and an English-speaking guide throughout. Routes covered include: Seoul-Gyeongju, Seoul-Busan, Seoul-Gyeongju-Busan, Seoul-Gyeongju-Busan-Jeju and Seoul-Gyeongju-Andong.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roads are good quality and well-signed, but erratic drivers and traffic congestion in large cities make driving a challenge for all but the most confident drivers.</p>r<p>Excellent motorways link all major cities, but minor roads may be poorly maintained. Road signs are usually written in Korean and English.</p><p>Bus travel within South Korea is reliable and inexpensive, but often confusing for non-Korean speakers, as many cities have four or more bus terminals, each with different destinations, routes, and timetables.  Making matters worse, many bus operators do not have English speakers or English websites.</p>
<p>However, long-distance luxury coaches and normal buses offer service to almost everywhere in South Korea at very reasonable prices.  Kobus (<a href="http://www.kobus.co.kr/web/eng/index.jsp" target="_blank">www.kobus.co.kr/web/eng/index.jsp</a>) is an English website with scheduling information for all express buses.</p><p>Taxis are ubiquitous and are reasonably safe and cheap. There are two grades of taxi - a black luxury grade and a normal grade.  All taxis are required to be metered; make sure they're using the meter throughout the trip.  Reports of lengthy detours, of charging night rates during the day, and other fee-related issues surface from time to time.  Safety problems are rare, but assaults on women have been infrequently reported.  Exercise judgement and caution when travelling alone.</p><p>International Driving Permit required. Drivers must have more than one year's driving experience, be in possession of a valid passport, and be over 21 years of age.</p><p>Speed limits are 60kph (37mph) on regular roads and 80-120kph (50-75mph) on expressways.</p><p>Contact the Korea Automobile Association (tel: +82 2 565 7001) or check with your car hire company.</p><p>Numerous international and local car hire companies operate in South Korea. However, complex road systems and high traffic density may mean this is an option only for more confident drivers. Alternatively, you can hire a driver to go with you on the road.</p><p>Bike rentals may be possible for sightseeing in some cities.  Ask the local tourist information booths for details.</p><p>Speed limits are 60kph (37mph) on regular roads and 80-120kph (50-75mph) on expressways.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Seoul has underground and suburban railways and well-developed bus services, all of which are very crowded during the rush hour. Underground station names, ticket counters and transfer signs are clearly marked in English as well as Korean. Underground lines are colour-coded, and all trains have multilingual announcements.</p>
<p>Taxis are widely available. Good bus services also operate in other cities. Most major cities have at least one or two underground lines and/or above-ground trolleys.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">South Korea</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">ulsan</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">South Korea</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kyongju</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">South Korea</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">kwangju</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.55</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.20</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">South Korea</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">chonju</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.20</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Asiana Airlines (<a href="http://www.flyasiana.com" target="_blank">www.flyasiana.com</a>) and Korean Air (<a href="http://www.koreanair.com" target="_blank">www.koreanair.com</a>) operate flights to South Korea from across the globe, including direct services from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> and the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a>.</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-korea/seoul-incheon-international-airport">Seoul Incheon International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-korea/busan-gimhae-international-airport">Busan Gimhae International Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 11 hours; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 14 hours 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Busan Gimhae International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport.co.kr<p>Busan Gimhae International Airport is situated 22km (13 miles) west of Busan.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+82 1661 2626</p>]]><b>Seoul Incheon International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport.kr/pa/en/a/index.jsp<p>Seoul Incheon International Airport is located 48km (30 miles) west of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seoul">Seoul</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+82 1577 2600</p>]]><b>Jeju International Airport </b><![CDATA[<p>The airport, located on the island of Jeju, is 4km (2.5 miles) from the town centre.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><b>Seoul Gimpo International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airport.co.kr/mbs/gimpoeng]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports: </strong>Busan  (in the far south), Incheon (due west of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seoul">Seoul</a>) and Donghae (in the far north).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although there have been test runs in the past, there are no passenger services at present between North and South Korea. North Korea can only accessed by train from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>, with services between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/beijing">Beijing</a> and Pyongyang; South Korea is not accessible overland as travel between North and South Korea is forbidden. For details of China-North Korea tours, try Koryo Tours, run by Westerners based in China (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.koryogroup.com/">www.koryogroup.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are currently no routes by land to South Korea, as travel by bus or car through <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/north-korea">North Korea</a> is prohibited.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Public telephones are not ideal for making international calls, and a number of rip off "phone cards" are available on the street or even the airport itself.   Your best and least expensive bet is to use Skype or another voice-over-ip (Voip) service to call home from one of the innumerable internet cafes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Native cellphone service is so good in South Korea that many Koreans do not know the meaning of the term &quot;dropped call,&quot; but international calls and roaming can be prohibitively expensive.  You may still have to hire a relevant Korean handset even though your SIM card works. Cellphones can be easily rented at airport kiosks or at offices in Seoul. South Koreans do not use SIM cards, which makes it difficult for tourists to buy them in South Korea. Nevertheless, it might be worthwhile to buy a tourist SIM-card at <a href="http://www.egsimcard.co.kr" target="www.egsimcard.co.kr">EG SIM CARD</a>, which is cheaper and comes without roaming fees.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet is widely available in Korea. The country is one of the  highest user of internet in the world; according to the OECD, Korea's population has the highest number of wireless broadband subscriptions. There are internet cafes around the country in public places such as airports, train stations and bus terminals in Korea. 'PC bangs' are rooms full of computers, predominantly started for people to play games. They are cheap and many are open 24 hours a day, with snacks available.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are four major national terrestrial networks that dominate TV viewing in South Korea as well as 100 daily Korean cable TV networks. <em>Arirang TV</em> provides a fairly slick and comprehensive series of public service programming in English and is usually available in hotels. There is also patchy reception on the US forces station <em>AFN</em>, which broadcasts American-orientated TV such as news, sitcoms, drama and movies.  High end hotels offer western stations by satellite.  Recent developments have curbed freedom of speech by tying the media closer to the government. The <em>Korea Times</em> is the best known English newspaper.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail to Western Europe or the US takes up to 10 days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800. Gwanghwamun main post office in Seoul: Mon-Fri 0900-2000; Sat-Sun 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire Seoul from way up high</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Ascend the 238m-high (776ft) N-Seoul Tower, a viewing spire conspicuously situated atop landscaped Namsan Mountain, for an unparalleled vista of Seoul's majestic cityscape. It's especially beautiful at night, when the tower is lit up. Appetites can be satisfied at the N-Grill, the tower's revolving restaurant.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise around Hallyeo Maritime National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Travel to the Hallyeo Maritime National Park in the southeast for a cruise around the archipelago, dotted with 400 islands. This is where Admiral Yi Sun-Sin (an Admiral Nelson-like figure) defeated the Japanese in the sea battles of the 16th century. Hire a bike and pedal the well-marked trails for the best of the seascapes.</p>]]><p><b>Dare to try the spicy seafood of Suwon City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>As one of Seoul's largest suburban areas, Suwon has all kinds of things for the tourist to enjoy. The UNESCO-listed city walls and defences of Suwon City and Hwaseong Fortress are among of the most famous sights, but nightlife is another of its big draws. Try the fiery hot seafood broth <em>Jjambbong</em> – and make sure your hotel has a bidet.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the Cheonggyecheon Stream sculptures</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This revitalisation project was quite controversial and cost Seoul taxpayers dearly, but this river (which was once a sewage trickle beneath the pavement) is now a lengthy walking area with art exhibits, performances, sculptures, and even make-out spots for lovers. The Candle Fountain is popular highlight after dark.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the 'museums without walls' at Gyeongju</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Korea's 'museum without walls' at Gyeongju, near Busan. The capital of the Silla Kingdom for 1,000 years, it is packed with history and Buddhist culture, all designated by UNESCO as one of the world's 10 most historically significant sites. After exploring the city, take in the best history museum in South Korea, Gyeongju National Museum.</p>]]><p><b>Hike through Seoraksan National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Seorak mountain range is considered to be the most beautiful landscape in the whole of South Korea, and with its austere pinnacles of rock, its verdant forests, rushing spring streams, waterfalls, and temples, it's got everything a hiker might want to see. For trails over a day long, a guide is recommended.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the slopes at the Alps Ski Resort</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For winter sports, head to the Alps Ski Resort or another of the 13 ski resorts within four or five hours of Seoul. The city of Pyeongchang has plenty of powder, such as the excellent Dragon Valley (Yongpyong), and will host the 2018 Winter Olympics. Odaesan National Park is also famous for its off-piste action.</p>]]><p><b>Meditate in a Buddhist temple</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Learn about South Korea's Buddhist heritage by experiencing the serenity and sanctuary of a temple. The country has over 10,000 temples and 20,000 monks and visitors can even stay at some of them, practising meditation, lantern making, tea ceremonies and simple elements of Buddhism.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the underground to a National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whether you hike, birdwatch or rock climb, check out relics and visit the temples and fortress in the mountains of the Bukhansan National Park. They are some of the most favoured in South Korea, and they're not far outside Seoul - they even have their own stop on the underground.</p>]]><p><b>See the secret side of Seoul</b></p><![CDATA[<p>See the sights of Seoul: Changdeokung is an exquisite Joseon palace and its picturesque <em>Biwon</em> (secret gardens) are enchanting but can only be visited with a guided tour. Nearby Jongmyo Shrine contains ancestral tablets of the Joseon Dynasty. The huge National Museum of Korea is architecturally and culturally fascinating.</p>]]><p><b>Shred nerves at the world's largest theme park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join in the Korean love of theme parks by visiting Lotte World in Seoul as well as the outdoor attractions of Magic Island, which features one of the world's largest indoor theme parks. Else, head an hour outside the capital to the vast Everland leisure complex, which boasts the Caribbean Bay water park, Hoam Art Museum and even a zoo.</p>]]><p><b>Speed to Busan on the KTX train</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Jump on Korea's pride and joy, the KTX high-speed train, launched in 2004 and capable of travelling at 300kph (186mph). Take it to the bustling port of Busan to see Jagalchi Fish Market (not for the squeamish), Busan Tower and the 1,300 year old Beomeosa Temple.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in history at the Korean Folk Village</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In Yongin, about 45 minutes south of Seoul, this excellent folk village is where you can meander through live demonstrations of various traditional Korean arts, crafts and games, and see how buildings were made centuries ago. Fun for all ages and interesting to boot, this living museum is a must see.</p>]]><p><b>Uncover the Buddha above Bulguksa Temple</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Soak up the wonderful atmosphere of Bulguksa Temple. This large wooden temple is beautifully painted and the stone Dabotap features numerous cultural relics. A winding road high on the mountain above leads to the Seokguram Grotto, with the magnificent granite Buddha looking serenely down through his protective glass case.</p>]]><p><b>Unearth the wooden blocks of Haeinsa Temple</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set in the idyllic Gayasan National Park, Haeinsa Temple was originally built in AD 802. It eventually reached its present-day size during the mid-10th century and is famous for housing the Tripitaka Koreana - 80,000 wooden printing blocks carved during the Goryo Dynasty. The temple also houses a great number of artefacts including the Seated Stone Buddha and Stone Pagoda.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the volcanic Jeju-do island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Korea's 'Hawaii' is just off the southwest coast and it features Mount Hallasan, Korea's highest mountain at 1,950m (6,400ft). Atmospheric 'stone grandfather' statues (made from black lava) can be found all over the island, alongside spectacular waterfalls and impressive volcanic scenery. Go underground and marvel at the Manjanggul Lava Tubes or greet the dawn at Seongsan Ilchulbong Peak.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$1.4 trillion (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Semi-conductors, electronics, textiles, ships and cars.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, electronics, oil, transport equipment and organic chemicals.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>China, Hong Kong, Japan, Saudi Arabia and the USA.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The third largest economy in Asia after China and Japan, South Korea is a major force to be reckoned with in electronics, mobile phones, digital displays, steel and semiconductors, amongst other things. It is the world leader in shipbuilding and the automotive business is also large, with great domestic loyalty; 97.3% of all cars sold in South Korea are Korean.</p>
<p>Korea Convention Bureau (KCB), part of the Korea Tourism Organization, is keen to build Korea into a premier destination for tourists, convention delegates and business travellers. There are excellent facilities across the country, as well as good international air links and internal transportation. Four convention cities have been designated nationwide: Seoul, Busan, Daegu and Jeju-shi.</p>
<p>The economy has taken a hit in recent years after the US bubble burst. The Incheon Free Economic Zone (IFEZ) is being built near Incheon International Airport as a business and tourism hub for northeast Asia, and the East Sea Free Trade Zone is also underway in the east coast city of Donghae.</p>
<p>Despite a brief thaw in relations with the North, which saw a growth of economic links, North Korea&rsquo;s sinking of a South Korean patrol boat in 2010 and bombing of a border town has returned relations to a frosty standoff and any economic ties are currently severed.</p>
<p>Unemployment was at 3.6% in 2017.  Inflation was 2% in 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite the modernity of capital Seoul, traditional values hold strong. Business dress is conservative and greetings and thanks are usually made with a bow of the head. New contacts are generally made following an introduction by a third party.</p>
<p>Businessmen are expected to wear a suit and tie. English is widely spoken in commercial and official circles. Meetings should be arranged in advance. You should carry a plentiful supply of business cards and offer them with the right hand or both hands as giving or receiving anything with both hands shows respect. Never scribble on, or hold a business card for too long, as this is seen as impolite. Shoes should be removed when entering a Korean home.</p>
<p>Note that &lsquo;director&rsquo; is a middle management term in Korea so if you are a company director you may wish to refer to yourself as company president when in Seoul.</p>
<p>If you are serious about a business relationship you&rsquo;ll be expected to spend some time nurturing it, including socially. When drinking together, Koreans fill each others&rsquo; glasses, not their own, again, with two hands (or one on the bottle the other on your wrist) is most polite.<br />
<br />
Best months for business visits are February to June.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p>Mon-Fri 0900-1800.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Korea Trade Centre in the UK</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (020) 7520 5300
					Website:http://english.kotra.or.kr/
					Address: Brettenham House North,1st Floor,Lancaster Place,]]><b>Korean Chamber of Commerce and Industry (KCCI)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (2) 6050 3114
					Website:http://www.kcci.or.kr/
					Address: Namdaemun-ro,45 4-ga,Seoul,100-743]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Korean cuisine is punchy and bold flavoured; fermented foods are common and dishes are often heavily laced with red pepper and generous amounts of garlic. Rice is omnipresent at pretty much all meals, except for the odd occasion when noodles take centre stage.</p>
<p>A typical Korean meal consists of warm rice, soup, rice water and between eight and 20 side dishes of vegetables, fish, poultry, eggs, bean curd and sea plants. All dishes tend to be served together and are shared among the group.</p>
<p>Korea&rsquo;s best-selling spirit is <em>soju</em>, a clear liquor similar to, though milder than, vodka. <em>Soju</em> is frequently mixed with beer to create a drink known as <em>somac</em>.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bibimbap:</strong> A bowl of boiled rice mixed with vegetables, chilli peppers, meat and an egg.<br />
<strong>Kimchi:</strong> A beloved funky-flavoured side dish made from fermented Chinese cabbage, turnips, onions, salt, fish, chestnuts and red pepper.<br />
<strong>Bulgogi:</strong> Also known as Korean BBQ, Bulgogi is thin slices of marinated beef cooked on a table-top grill.<br />
<strong>Grilled galbi:</strong> Beef short ribs marinated in <em>ganjang</em> (Korean soy sauce).<br />
<strong>Haemultang:</strong> A spicy stew made with red pepper paste and an assortment of seafood and vegetables.<br />
<strong>Chijimi:</strong> A savoury vegetable pancake.<br />
<strong>Tteokbokki:</strong> This spicy snack of sticky rice cakes in a chilli sauce is a popular Korean street food.<br />
<strong>Soju:</strong> A clear vodka-like spirit usually distilled from rice or sweet potato.<br />
<strong>Hite:</strong> This mild-flavoured lager, along with beer brands Cass and OB, dominate the Korean market.<br />
<strong>Makgeolli:</strong> A low alcohol milky liquor made by fermenting steamed rice and water.<br />
<strong>Ginseng wine:</strong> A strong and sweet wine, similar to brandy, believed to have medicinal properties.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>The most common type of drinking establishment is the <em>suljip</em> (Korean-style wine bar), but there are also pubs serving well-known European brands. Koreans offer glasses of liquor to each other as a gesture of camaraderie; never fill your own glass and remember, juniors pour for seniors.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Although not a Korean custom, most hotels and other tourist facilities add a 10% service charge to bills.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>19.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Korea's nightlife offers a mix of traditional (spellbinding performances of music, dance and theatre) with Broadway/West End-style shows, or pop icons like Boa, a Korean singer who has achieved worldwide renown. Hotel bars are popular in cities; but their nightclubs tend to be expensive. Larger hotels may also have their own private theatre restaurants.</p>
<p>Seoul's fashionable areas are Hongik University area and Apgujeong. Itaweon is aimed squarely at foreigners and the local population of American soldiers, but it is quite a tacky area. Koreans sing their hearts out in karaoke bars, or noraebangs, as they are known here. There are also many cinemas. Operas, concerts and recitals can be seen at the National Theatre and performances of Korean classical music, dances and plays can be seen at Korea House. There are several licensed state-of-the-art casinos throughout the country.</p>
<p>For daily listings of events, consult Korea's English-language papers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The best shopping districts and markets are in the capital, Seoul, and include: <br />
&bull; Namdaemun: Korea's largest general wholesale market.<br />
&bull; Dongdaemun: One of Seoul's oldest markets, good for bargains.<br />
&bull; Myeongdong: Korea's fashion district and home to countless mid-market brands, boutiques, malls and an underground shopping passage leading to Namdaemun.<br />
&bull; Insadong: Delightful street for crafts, antiques and art.<br />
&bull; Itaewon: A modern shopping district popular with foreign tourists, where shopkeepers speak English and sell all kinds of stuff; known for its many tailors, who can whip up shirts and suits.<br />
&bull; Yongsan Electronics Market: Largest electronics and computer market in Korea.<br />
&bull; Koyndang: Oriental medicine, spice and herb market. <br />
&bull; Hwangkhakdong: Flea market, good for second-hand shopping.<br />
&bull; Ahyondong: Home to more than 120 wedding boutiques.<br />
&bull; COEX: Asia's biggest shopping mall is all underground. <br />
&bull; Apgujeong: The poshest shopping district in Korea with designers from Armani to Versace having stores in the area.</p>
<p>Seoul's various markets are the perfect place for a shopping spree.  Insadong is the place to go for Korean craft items ranging from the simple to priceless antiques.  Namdaemun offers alleyway after alleyway of cheap clothes and household items.  Yongsan is the top spot in the country for cameras and electronics.  And Myeongdong is the favorite of fashionistas everywhere. Buy clothes here and you'll look like you've stepped out of the pages of a fashion magazine.  While most tourists can find everything they'd ever dream of in Seoul proper, Korea is a shopper's mecca and you'll find great buys almost everywhere you go.  Favourite tourist items include hand-tailored clothes, textiles, leatherwork, jewellery, ginseng, tea; lacquerware, woodcarvings, baskets and screens. Major cities have foreigners' duty-free shops where people can use foreign currency with a valid passport. </p><p>Mon-Sun 1030-2000 (often until 2200).  Some shopping areas are open 24 hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Modern tourist hotels in Korea in major cities and tourist areas are registered with the government and graded: super deluxe (5-star), deluxe (4-star), first class (3-star), second class (2-star) and third class (1-star). A service charge of 10% and 10% VAT are included in hotel bills; tipping is not necessary.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>This is an inexpensive way to experience Korean culture and meet other tourists. Modest in style and decor, many are re-modelled family homes and so often have a shared bathroom. Contact the <a href="http://english.visitkorea.or.kr/" target="_blank">Korea Tourism Organisation</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Modern tourist hotels in Korea in major cities and tourist areas are registered with the government and graded: super deluxe (5-star), deluxe (4-star), first class (3-star), second class (2-star) and third class (1-star). A service charge of 10% and 10% VAT are included in hotel bills; tipping is not necessary.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Modern tourist hotels in Korea in major cities and tourist areas are registered with the government and graded: super deluxe (5-star), deluxe (4-star), first class (3-star), second class (2-star) and third class (1-star). A service charge of 10% and 10% VAT are included in hotel bills; tipping is not necessary.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;High quality medical care is available in Seoul, Pusan and Daegu, but may be difficult to locate in rural areas. Comprehensive health insurance is recommended, as are the international clinics at hospitals like Seoul's Severance Hospital, Asan Medical Centre or Samsung Medical Centre. Almost all hospitals require payment and registration prior to treatment. Most nurses and receptionists do not speak English.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Though tap water is potable and thus safe to drink, tourists often avoid it due to taste.  Bottled water is available, as is powdered or tinned milk. Korean cuisine is rich and varied and as such, includes all sorts of raw, uncooked, or undercooked meats, seafoods, and delicacies.  Use common sense when ordering.  Those with health concerns may want to exercise caution and avoid unpasteurised milk and products made from it, such as ice cream. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish. Vegetables should be cooked, fruit peeled. Food from street vendors is usually safe but should be eaten at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Japanese encephalitis may be transmitted by mosquitoes between June and October in rural areas. A vaccine is available, and travellers are advised to consult their doctor prior to departure. Hepatitis B is highly endemic. Tuberculosis occurs. Rabies is extremely rare. If you are bitten, seek medical advice without delay.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>* Holiday is from 9-11 February.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Sam Il Jul (Independence Movement Day) :
							01 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Orininal (Children's Day) :
							05 May </p><p>Memorial Day :
							28 May </p><p>Kwang Bok Jul (Independence Day) :
							15 August </p><p>Kae Chun Jul (National Foundation Day) :
							03 October </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into South Korea by travellers aged 19 and over without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes.<br />
&bull; 1 bottle of alcohol up to 1L.<br />
&bull; 60ml of perfume.<br />
&bull; Goods to the value of US$600.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited and restricted goods include weapons, food (small quantities allowed, but you must declare it), counterfeit goods and money, publications infringing upon the constitution and public peace, narcotics and endangered species.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The export of counterfeit goods is taken very seriously and can be subject to a prison sentence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Won (KRW; symbol ₩). Notes are in denominations of ₩50,000, 10,000, 5,000 and 1,000<em>. Chon</em> means 'one thousand'. Coins are in denominations of ₩500, 100, 50 and 10.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Foreign banknotes and travellers cheques can be exchanged at foreign exchange banks and other authorised money changers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>American Express, Diners Club, Mastercard and Visa are widely accepted at major hotels, shops and restaurants in the larger cities. You may not be able use credit cards at small businesses and in rural areas. You may also want to check whether your credit card is accepted by looking at door signs before you enter an establishment. ATMs are available in all major cities, but not all of them will accept international cards. Just keep trying different outlets until you see a logo you recognise on the machine. Cards with the Plus and Cirrus logos are the easiest to use and most widely accepted in Korea.</p><p>ATMs are available in all major cities, but not all of them will accept international cards. KB bank is one of the most reliable for foreign cards. Many of the ATMs in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seoul">Seoul</a> subways accept foreign cards as well.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accepted, but may be difficult to change in smaller towns. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">US</a> dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1700.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter South Korea, a passport valid for a minimum of three months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Some nationals who would normally require a visa may enter South Korea without a visa provided they are in transit to a third country, remain in the Seoul area, and leave South Korea within 24 hours; check with the embassy for eligibility.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Validity usually begins from the date of issue.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow five days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[36.097018]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[127.512974]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>99,720 sq km (38,502 sq miles) excluding demilitarised zone.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>50,503,933 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>492.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Seoul.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Republic of Korea (South Korea) is a peninsula that shares borders to the north with the demilitarised zone (separating it from the Democratic People's Republic of Korea), to the east with the Sea of Japan&nbsp;(East Sea), to the south with the Korea Strait (separating it from Japan), and to the west with the Yellow Sea. There are many islands and bays in the Korea Strait, including the largest, the volcanic island of Jeju-do, which lies off the southwest coast and is also home to South Korea's highest mountain, Mount Halla, at 1,950m (6,397ft). Most of the country consists of hills and mountains with the 30% of flat plain home to the majority of the population and cultivation. Most rivers rise in the mountains to the east, flowing west and south to the Yellow Sea. The Naktong River flows into the Korea Strait near the southern port of Busan, Korea's second largest city after Seoul. The eastern coast is rocky and steep with mountains rising from the sea.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>This is one of the world's most homogeneous populations, but faith is divided largely between Christianity (27.6%) and the country's traditional faith of Buddhism (15.5%), with 56.9% of no formal religion. Confucian philosophy is generally followed out of generational habit, while Shamanism and the belief in ghosts and spirits are also strong. Cheondogyo is a Korean faith that has grown up out of Taoism, Confucianism and Christianity, and there is a small Islamic population.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Shoes must be removed before entering a Korean home.  Small gifts are customary;  traditional etiquette requires using the right hand for giving and receiving. Seniority should always be respected - don't eat before the oldest person at the table has started.&nbsp; Koreans often ask your age and marital status to quickly gauge societal seniority. They can be very reserved, shy and resistant of body contact until they get to know you.</p>
<p>Never leave chopsticks in your rice, and never beckon anyone with palm up using one finger, as this is the way Koreans call their dogs. Writing someone's name in red is bad as this symbolises death. The number four is considered unlucky and to give gifts in multiples of four is considered taboo; giving seven of an item is considered lucky.</p>
<p>Traditional costume, or <em>hanbok</em>, is mainly worn on holidays and special occasions. For men it consists of a short jacket and loose trousers, called <em>baji</em>, that are tied at the ankles. Women's <em>hanboks</em> comprise a wrap-around skirt and a bolero-style jacket and is often called a <em>chima-jeogori</em>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220 volts AC, 60Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Moon Jae-in since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Lee Nak-yon since 2017.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The first unified Korea was under the Silla, a Gyeongju-based empire that stretched over most of the peninsula. The empire fragmented in AD 870, giving way to the Koryo dynasty, who allied themselves with the Song dynasty in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/china">China</a>. The Koryo emulated the Song in establishing an advanced cultural and technological society (including the invention of printing in 1234, two centuries before its discovery in the West).</p>
<p>The peninsula fell to the Mongols in the 1230s. It took until the early 14th century, and the assistance of the Chinese Ming dynasty, to recover Korean independence. The Koryo dynasty was followed by the Choson in the 14th century, who governed Korea until the early 20th century.</p>
<p>The early years of the Choson saw Korea enter a period of outstanding cultural and intellectual achievement; however, during this time, the country suffered invasions by the Japanese and then the Chinese Manchu dynasty.</p>
<p>At the end of WWII, the Soviets and Americans agreed to divide Korea along latitude 38&deg;N (the 38th parallel). As the Cold War evolved, a full-scale war broke out between the two sides in 1950. The three-year war engaged all the major powers and came closer than is often realised to provoking a nuclear conflagration. By 1953, a stalemate had been reached and an armistice was signed. For the next three decades, locked into opposing Cold War blocs, the two Koreas went their separate ways.</p>
<p>South Korea developed a successful capitalist economy, but its political system was far from democratic: until the 1980s the country was run by a series of dictators who punished political dissent with imprisonment. However, the country's political leaders, with their powerbase in the monopolistic Democratic Justice Party, realised that some relaxation of the existing tight political control was necessary. So in 1981, martial law was lifted and within five years, a powerful parliamentary opposition had emerged in the form of the New Korea Democratic Party (NKDP), led by the veteran dissident Kim Dae-Jung.</p>
<p>North-South relations hit a new nadir in 2010 with the sinking of a South Korean warship (and the deaths of 46 sailors on board), which put any hopes of reunification on hold. After a series of skirmishes in 2015, the two sides agreed a deal to defuse tensions.</p>
<p>President Park Guen-hye, the first female president of South Korea, was elected in 2013 but impeached at the end of 2016 over a corruption scandal. Unlike her predecessors, she strove for a close relationship with the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-states-america">USA</a> and spoke of wishing to unify the two Koreas. She was succeeded by Moon Jae-in in 2017. A former human rights lawyer and the son of North Korean refugees, the new president is known for his liberal views.</p>
<p>The region&rsquo;s tumultuous history remains very much a part of present day South Korea and is something many Koreans feel strongly about &ndash; after a few <em>sojus</em>, the topic can get heated.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Koreans count ages differently than we do in the West: when babies are born, they are considered to be one already. Every year at New Year&rsquo;s (and not on their birthdays), they turn a year older.<br />
&bull;	Until 2015, adultery was a criminal offence that could result in prison.<br />
&bull;	The five most popular Korean surnames - Kim, Lee, Park, Choi and Chong &ndash; are used by more than half of the population. <br />
&bull;	Though a ceasefire was signed in 1952, technically, the Korean War has never officially ended.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Korea in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 939 5600 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://usa.mofa.go.kr/english/am/usa/main/</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 939 5600 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri: 0900-1200, 1330-1730&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2370 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of Korea in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 207 227 5500.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://gbr.mofat.go.kr/eng</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 207 227 5500.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 1000-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>83 Victoria Street, 5th Floor<br/>London<br/>SW1H 0HW<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South Korea can come across as inscrutable at first glance. It&rsquo;s a land of stark contrasts and wild contradictions; a place where tradition and technology are equally embraced; where skyscrapers loom over ancient temples; and where the frantic pace of life is offset by the serenity of nature. The country&rsquo;s unique customs and etiquette can seem like a trap laid for foreigners, but arrive with a smile and a respectful attitude and you will be welcomed with open arms by some of the friendliest folk on the planet.</p>
<p>Koreans are fiercely proud of their country, and with good reason. The Korean peninsula has a storied history and this colourful heritage is woven into the fabric of this land. The capital, Seoul, is home to a number of historic highlights, including the spectacular Joseon-era Gyeongbokgung Palace, &ldquo;the great south gate&rdquo; of Namdaemun and the eerie Seodaemun Prison &ndash; all tucked away amid gleaming offices, giant shopping centres, world-class restaurants and hipster bars.</p>
<p>The rest of the country is also littered with fortresses, temples and palaces. Visitors will enjoy the grassy burial mounds of ancient kings in Gyeongju, the Seokbulsa Temple in Busan, which has been carved out of a rock, and the infamous demilitarised zone, a biodiverse no-man&rsquo;s-land separating South and North Korea. It is a scary place, where acres of barbed wire are patrolled by heavily-armed guards on both sides, yet the tension is so trumped up it feels like you&rsquo;ve stumbled onto a Hollywood film set.</p>
<p>But it's not all about history. When it comes to nature, South Korea is wonderfully diverse, with spectacular national parks, remote sandy beaches, hot spring islands and rugged mountain peaks. Gastronomes are well catered for, too, but you may have to open your mind before your mouth; local specialities include <em>kimchi </em>(pickled cabbage) and <em>makgeolli</em> (rice wine).</p>
<p>South Korea can sometimes seem like the most foreign place on Earth; an unfathomable destination of curious customs, strange food and jarring paradoxes. Ultimately, that&rsquo;s what makes it so exciting.</p><p>South Korea can come across as inscrutable at first glance. It&rsquo;s a land of stark contrasts and wild contradictions; a place where tradition and technology are equally embraced; where skyscrapers loom over ancient temples; and where the frantic pace of life is offset by the serenity of nature. The country&rsquo;s unique customs and etiquette can seem like a trap laid for foreigners, but arrive with a smile and a respectful attitude and you will be welcomed with open arms by some of the friendliest folk on the planet.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
