<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="South Africa" ColCode="zaf" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="sj" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[South Africa]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Being in the southern hemisphere, South Africa&rsquo;s seasons are the opposite of European seasons. The climate is seasonal, but the country enjoys at least seven months of sunshine, with temperatures dropping in the winter months of May to August. April and May are the most temperate months. Temperatures above 32&deg;C (90&deg;F) are fairly common in summer, and frequently exceed 38&deg;C (100&deg;F) in the lower Orange River Valley and the Mpumalanga Lowveld. The barren Northern   Cape has some of the most extreme temperatures, sometimes cracking 40&deg;C (104&deg;F) in summer and plummeting to below freezing in winter.</p>
<p>It's pleasantly warm and sunny in spring and autumn, and delightfully hot in summer (November-March) with frequent heavy tropical rains and sudden spring and summer hailstorms to cool things down. The thunder and lightning storms over Africa's big skies can be quite spectacular, but are best enjoyed through a window, not out in the open. These tropical storms can be vicious too, often causing flooding and turning urban streets into temporary streams, making driving hazardous. Wait an hour and it will all be over.<br />
<br />
Even in winters South Africa&rsquo;s chill is nothing compared with European standards, with mild frost occasional, and snow a rarity. The rainiest months in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/cape-town">Cape Town</a> are May to August, although the weather in Cape Town is generally difficult to predict and can deliver all four seasons in one day.</p>
<p>Christmas can be just too hot for game viewing in the safari parks, and it's also peak season for South African holidaymakers. Cape Town is a magnet for Jo'burgers at Christmas, so best avoided - visit in spring and autumn, when the weather is good and the crowds are smaller. Of the main cities, <a href="http://i/durban">Durban</a> is the hottest and can get remarkably hot and sticky in the summer. But it&rsquo;s perfect in winter, where you can still wear shorts in temperatures that the locals consider a bit nippy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For summer in Africa you&rsquo;ll need to keep cool, so pack lightweight clothes. In winter you&rsquo;ll be surprised at how cold it can be in some areas, so bring a jumper or sweatshirt. You will never need a heavy coat or jacket, but a light raincoat can be useful, especially in Cape Town. For a safari bring long sleeves and long trousers, if only to protect against mosquitoes and thorn bushes. The game drives will either start out chilly with an 0600 start and end under the blazing sun, or vice versa, with a hot late afternoon start and a return after sunset, so take a wrap or pullover of some sort.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Several airlines operate domestic routes with regular links between Johannesburg, Cape Town, Durban, George, Nelspruit and Port Elizabeth and relatively frequent flights to several smaller towns and cities too. The main operators are South Africa Airways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flysaa.com/">www.flysaa.com</a>), Comair (a division of British Airways) (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.ba.com/">www.ba.com</a>), Mango (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flymango.com">www.flymango.com</a>), Kulula (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.kulula.com">www.kulula.com</a>) and Airlink (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flyairlink.com/">www.flyairlink.com</a>).</p>
<p>Internal air fares are not particularly cheap, and price wars have taken several airlines that attempted to introduce more affordable flights out of business. But since South Africa is a big country with long distances between its major tourist centres, it generally makes sense to fly.</p>
<p>Public transport at the airports is mostly inadequate, but the sparkly modern Gautrain (<a href="http://join.gautrain.co.za/" target="_blank">http://join.gautrain.co.za</a>) from OR Tambo airport in Johannesburg is a quick and efficient way to reach the city centre, some useful points in the northern suburbs and Pretoria.</p>
<p>Cape Town airport has a cheap shuttle service called MyCiTi (<a href="http://www.myciti.org.za" target="_blank">www.myciti.org.za</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main ports of Cape Town, Durban, East London and Port Elizabeth are industrial or geared towards international cruise liners rather than domestic ferry routes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Intercity services are run by Shosholoza Meyl (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.shosholozameyl.co.za/">www.shosholozameyl.co.za</a>)<em>, </em>with trains between Johannesburg, Durban, East London, Port Elizabeth and Cape Town. Trains are frustratingly slow and the facilities including the dining car and trolley service are basic by European standards. Sleeper cars are available in tourist class, with shared showers. Economy class just buys you a reclining seat. Children under three travel free. Children aged three to nine pay half fare.</p>
<p>Cape Town&rsquo;s Metrorail (tel: +27 21 449 6478;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.metrorail.co.za" target="_blank">www.metrorail.co.za</a>) runs a pleasant coastal route from Cape Town to Simon&rsquo;s Town that passes through quaint Kalk Bay.</p>
<p><strong>Luxury trains: </strong>Premier Classe (tel: +27 11 773 9247; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.premierclasse.co.za/">www.premierclasse.co.za</a>) runs between Johannesburg and Cape Town once a week, and is more comfortable than the regular train. The Blue Train (tel: +27 21 449 2672; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.bluetrain.co.za/">www.bluetrain.co.za</a>) and Rovos Rail (tel: +27 21 421 4020; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.rovosrail.co.za/">www.rovos.com</a>) offer luxurious cabins and gourmet food in elaborate dining cars and run between Cape Town and Pretoria via Johannesburg. Rovos also runs a service between Pretoria and Durban.</p>
<p>The Gautrain (tel: 0800 4288 7246, in South Africa only; <a href="http://join.gautrain.co.za" target="_blank">http://join.gautrain.co.za</a>) runs overground and underground connecting Johannesburg, Pretoria and OR Tambo International Airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roads between the major centres are generally well maintained and well signposted, so getting around by road isn&rsquo;t a problem, except for some of the daunting distances. The Fifa 2010 World Cup saw a major investment in improving the road system, particularly around Johannesburg and Cape Town.</p>
<p>A controversial motorway tolling system electronically identifies number plates, so if you're renting a car, you usually need to pay the car hire company directly.</p>
<p>Petrol stations accept credit cards Car theft and hijacking is a problem, so it's advisable to keep doors locked and avoid picking up hitchhikers.</p>l<p>Roads and national highways link all the major areas. The only untarred roads are in rural areas and in some game reserves. Heavy rains and sometimes dodgy workmanship have left many urban roads riddled with serious potholes however.  Road signs are in English.</p><p>Coaches criss-cross the country between all major towns and cities and a web of tiny off-the-beaten-track towns too. Operators include Intercape (tel: +27 21 380 4400; <a href="http://www.intercape.co.za" target="_blank">www.intercape.co.za</a>), Greyhound (tel: +27 11 611 8000; <a href="http://www.greyhound.co.za" target="_blank">www.greyhound.co.za</a>) and Translux (tel: +27 861 589 282; <a href="http://www.translux.co.za" target="_blank">www.translux.co.za</a>).</p>
<p>The Baz Bus (tel: +27 21 422 5202; <a href="http://www.bazbus.com" target="_blank">www.bazbus.com</a>) is aimed at backpackers and picks up from hostels en route. It runs along the coast between Cape Town and Durban, before heading to the Drakensberg Mountains and Johannesburg.</p>
<p>You can also buy coach tickets through Computicket (tel: +27 861 915 8000; <a href="http://www.computicket.co.za" target="_blank">www.computicket.co.za</a>), which has online booking and kiosks in some shopping malls.</p><p>Available in all towns, hotels and airports, generally with meters fitted, although some still operate without or prefer not to use them. They are not particularly cheap, and it&rsquo;s often cheaper to haggle over the price in advance. Taxis do not cruise and must be ordered by phone or at a taxi rank.</p><p>Foreign licences are valid if they are in English with a photograph of the holder, but the AA recommends an International Driving Permit to prevent potential complications.</p><p>The legal driving age is 18 and driving licences must be carried at all times. The speed limit on highways is 120kph (75mph), 80-100kph (50-62mph) on national roads and 60kph (37mph) in urban areas. Driving is on the left, seatbelts must be worn, and it is illegal to use a mobile phone without a hands-free kit.</p><p>The AA (tel: tel: 0861 000 234, in South Africa only; <a href="http://www.aa.co.za" target="_blank">www.aa.co.za</a>). Yellow SOS telephones are available on major routes, but very sporadically.</p><p>Dozens of car hire firms are operating, including the major international players, and even the smaller airports have a rank of car hire desks. At peak periods it&rsquo;s worth booking in advance. Drivers must be at least 18 years old, and most car hire companies only accept an unendorsed licence that has been valid for a minimum of one year.</p><p>Let&rsquo;s be honest, South African motorists can be pretty careless, and many drive without a licence or insurance. That makes hiring a bike in the cities a dangerous idea. But it&rsquo;s a great country for mountain biking, with plenty of guided tours available.</p>
<p>A couple of companies including Cape Bike Rentals (<a href="http://www.capebikerentals.com" target="_blank">www.capebikerentals.com</a>) rent out motorbikes in Cape Town, and Cape Town Cycle Hire (<a href="http://www.capetowncyclehire.co.za" target="_blank">www.capetowncyclehire.co.za</a>) rents out bikes and mountain bikes.</p><p>The legal driving age is 18 and driving licences must be carried at all times. The speed limit on highways is 120kph (75mph), 80-100kph (50-62mph) on national roads and 60kph (37mph) in urban areas. Driving is on the left, seatbelts must be worn, and it is illegal to use a mobile phone without a hands-free kit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Public transport is generally dreadful. Although there are bus networks in all main towns, reliability is dubious. Routes for the minibus taxis used by local commuters are too confusing to even try to explain to a short-term visitor.</p>
<p>Cape Town buses are run by Golden Arrow (<a href="http://www.gabs.co.za" target="_blank">www.gabs.co.za</a>) and in Johannesburg by Metrobus (<a href="http://www.mbus.co.za" target="_blank">www.mbus.co.za</a>). Metrorail trains (<a href="http://www.metrorail.co.za" target="_blank">www.metrorail.co.za</a>) in larger cities used by commuters are generally not recommended to visitors due to the crime risk.&nbsp;The one bright spot is the MyCiTi bus network (<a href="http://www.myciti.org.za" target="_blank">www.myciti.org.za</a>) in Cape Town.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">South Africa</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">pretoria</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">16.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">26.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">South Africa</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">port_elizabeth</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">7.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">South Africa</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">johannesburg</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">15.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">27.00</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">South Africa</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">durban</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">18.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">38.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many flights to South Africa from Europe, North America and Asia. The national airline is South African Airways (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.flysaa.com/">www.flysaa.com</a>) which runs direct flights from various destinations in UK and the USA to Johannesburg.</p>
<p>British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>) and Virgin Atlantic (<a href="http://www.virgin-atlantic.com" target="_blank">www.virgin-atlantic.com</a>) also offer direct flights from London to Johannesburg. British Airways has a direct service between London and Cape Town, and runs a direct flight between London and Durban starting winter 2018.</p>
<p>Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) flies to Johannesburg from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/atlanta">Atlanta</a>. From Southeast Asia, Singapore Airlines (<a href="http://www.singaporeair.com" target="_blank">www.singaporeair.com</a>) flies direct to Johannesburg from Singapore.</p>
<p>Flights tend to be more expensive in December and January, while April and May are usually cheaper.</p>
<p>Major airporst are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa/cape-town-international-airport">Cape Town International Airport,</a> <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa/durban-king-shaka-international-airport">Durban King Shaka International Airport,</a> <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa/johannesburg-o-r-tambo-international-airport">Johannesburg O.R. Tambo International Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa/port-elizabeth-airport">Port Elizabeth Airport.</a></p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/johannesburg">Johannesburg</a>: from <a hre="/i/london">London</a> - 11 hours 5 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 14 hours 40 minutes.</p>
<p>To Cape Town: from London - 11 hours 35 minutes; New York - 18 hours 35 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Cape Town International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://capetown-internationalairport.co.za<p>Cape Town International Airport is located 18km (11 miles) east of Cape Town.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+27 21 937 1200</p>]]><b>Johannesburg O.R. Tambo International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airports.co.za<p>Johannesburg O.R. Tambo International Airport is located 22km (14 miles) east of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/johannesburg">Johannesburg</a>, and about 35km (20 miles) south of Pretoria.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+27 11 921 6262</p>]]><b>Port Elizabeth Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airports.co.za<p>Port Elizabeth Airport is situated within Port Elizabeth, 5km (3 miles) west of the business district and 3km (2 miles) southwest of Algoa Bay.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+27 41 507 7319</p>]]><b>Durban King Shaka International Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.airports.co.za<p>Durban King Shaka International Airport is located 35km (22 miles) north of central <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/durban">Durban</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+27 32 436 6758</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cape Town, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/durban">Durban</a>, East London and Port Elizabeth all have major ports. For more information regarding the ports, contact Transnet National Ports Authority (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.transnetnationalportsauthority.net">www.transnetnationalportsauthority.net</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South Africa&rsquo;s railway network is sadly under-developed and there is little cohesion between neighbouring countries. That makes arriving by train unfeasible, unless you can afford the luxurious Rovos Rail (<a href="http://www.rovos.com" target="_blank">www.rovos.com</a>) which runs occasionally to and from Victoria Falls in Zimbabwe, Swakopmund in Namibia and&nbsp;<a href="http://i/dar-es-salaam">Dar es Salaam</a> in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/tanzania">Tanzania</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are several borders you can cross to get into South Africa if you are entering the country by car and border posts are open daily. The main border posts are:</p>
<p>&bull;	Namibia Vioolsdrift / South Africa, open 24 hours <br />
&bull;	Mozambique Komatiepoort / South Africa, 0700-2200 <br />
&bull;	Botswana Tlokweng / South Africa, 0700-2200 <br />
&bull;	Zimbabwe Beitbridge / South Africa, 0600-2200 <br />
&bull;	Swaziland Oshoek / South Africa, 0700-2200</p>
<p>Coach operator Intercape (tel: +27 21 380 4400; <a href="http://www.intercape.co.za" target="_blank">www.intercape.co.za</a>) runs regularly to and from points in <a href="http://i/namibia">Namibia</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/botswana">Botswana</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/malawi">Malawi</a>, <a href="http://i/zambia">Zambia</a>, <a href="http://i/zimbabwe">Zimbabwe</a> and <a href="http://i/mozambique">Mozambique</a>.</p><p>Distances are very long and roads are not always well maintained, sometimes making arriving by road an adventure, not a doddle.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>To call home, the cheapest way is to use Skype or an international calling card like the WorldCall card from the national operator, Telkom. That lets you call any destination from a Telkom line, including those in hotels, at standard Telkom rates. Area codes are used even for local calls.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with international mobile phone companies. Coverage extends to most of the country except the very remote areas. GPRS for data coverage is also widespread. Airport kiosks can sell you a phone or local SIM card if you show some ID.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes are common in towns throughout the country and wireless is available at airports and in upmarket hotels. Most hotels charge for connectivity and it's far cheaper to find the nearest internet café.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South Africa's many broadcasters and publications reflect the diversity of the population. Freedom of the press is constitutionally protected and many newspapers have begun to flex their muscles with stronger and more critical political analysis. That includes fighting to retain their freedom, as a new bill that threatens to curb that right has been tabled. The main English language newspapers are<em> The Daily Sun, The Star</em>, <em>Sowetan, The Citizen</em> and weekly <em>Mail &amp; Guardian.</em> International papers are widely available in hotels and airports, and a select few in newsagents and bookshops. One of the most well-respected and analytical news websites is The Daily Maverick (<a href="http://www.thedailymaverick.co.za" target="_blank">www.thedailymaverick.co.za</a>).</p>
<p>The state-run SABC and commercial E.tv networks broadcast nationally, and many viewers subscribe to pay-TV operated by Multichoice. The proliferation of commercial and community radio stations includes Highveld, Jacaranda, 702 Talk Radio and Classic FM.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airmail takes a minimum of two days to Europe, three days to USA and four days to Australia.</p><p>Generally Mon-Fri 0830-1530; Sat 0800-1100; longer in airports and shopping malls. The smaller post offices close for lunch 1300-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Anglo-Boer War Battlefields</p><![CDATA[<p>Wars between the Afrikaans, British and Zulus erupted in bloody skirmishes in KwaZulu-Natal, a beautiful area of rolling grassland and rocky hills dotted with graves and monuments. The Anglo-Boer War began in 1899 in a fight over gold- and diamond-rich land. Knowledgeable guides lead you around the battlefields, telling tales that send shivers down your spine. Talana Museum near Dundee was the site of the first of the Anglo-Boer battle and is a heritage park with a war cemetery.</p>]]><br/><p>Blyde River Canyon Nature Reserve</p><![CDATA[<p>Breathtaking Blyde River Canyon is the third largest gorge in the world, best seen from the viewing point called God's Window. Other attractions include numerous waterfalls, the astonishing Bourke's Luck Potholes ground out by the gushing rapids and Pilgrim's Rest, a former gold-mining town dating from 1873. At the heart of the nature reserve is Blyde Dam, home to hippos and crocodiles.</p>]]><br/><p>Cape Point </p><![CDATA[<p>If you've come to South Africa you have to go all the way. Stand on the continent's tip at Cape Point, a World Heritage Site with buck, baboons and zebra, ending in sheer cliffs towering 200m (660ft) above the sea. The Flying Dutchman funicular takes you up to the old lighthouse to enjoy panoramic views, and the restaurant has splendid ocean views.</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Climb Table Mountain</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Cape Town's famous flat-topped mountain is one of the New Seven Wonders of Nature. It provides a magnificent backdrop when you're exploring Cape Town at street level, whilst from the top the expansive views are truly breath-taking at sunset. Hiking up is a popular option for the fit. The lazier way is to take the cable car to the top.</p>]]><p><b>Drive the Garden Route</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The popular Garden Route is a casual road tripper's dream, winding along the sunny, scenic and perennially verdant southeast coast between Mossel Bay and the mouth of Storms River. Along the way, pass languid lakes and lagoons, dense indigenous forests and pretty towns including Wilderness, Knysna, Oudtshoorn and Plettenberg Bay.</p>]]><p><b>Experience the ‘real’ South Africa on a township tour</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to a history of racial segregation, the majority of South Africans continue to live in so-called townships. But places like Soweto in Johannesburg and Khayelithsa in Cape Town are much more than living <em>apartheid</em> museums – they are also central breeding grounds for South Africa's vibrant contemporary culture. There are a number of tours that will give insight into both aspects.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Apartheid Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Johannesburg's excellently curated and profoundly moving Apartheid Museum recounts the still-recent history of racially segregated South Africa. Your entrance ticket comes in 'white' and 'non-white' versions, determining which entrance you're allowed to use. A particularly poignant and painful chapter of South Africa's history is revealed through photographs, artefacts, newspaper clippings and film footage.</p>]]><p><b>Frolic among the spring flowers in Namaqualand</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The usually bare and arid region of Namaqualand suddenly explodes into colour after the onset of the annual rains between mid-August and mid-September, when wild flowers blanket the landscape like a beautiful mosaic. The West Coast National Park is one of the best places to see the phenomenon, while a number of charming provincial towns provide lodging in the area.</p>]]><p><b>Get the adrenaline going on a shark cage dive</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Adrenalin junkies can get up close and personal with the ocean's apex predator. Seal Island in the Western Cape is a favourite hunting ground for great white sharks, with a veritable buffet of penguins, seals and game fish to feast on. From the (relative) safety of a metal cage, you can observe these formidable fish in their natural habitat.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the Drakensburg mountain trails</b></p><![CDATA[<p>For outdoor enthusiasts, South Africa has excellent hiking, with trails in the dramatic Drakensberg mountain range among the very best. Pass through ancient yellowwood forests and see even older Bushman rock art along the way, whilst presided over by some rare birdlife; camp in caves if you're hard enough, then abseil your way back down.</p>]]><p><b>Play a round of golf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Got golf clubs and some money to burn? South Africa is brilliant for golfing, and the swanky Fancourt Estate on the south coast has three courses designed by Gary Player, South Africa's most famous golfer, including The Links, described as his greatest design feat. There are hundreds of golf resorts and courses across the country, many in scenic coastal locations.</p><p> </p>]]><p><b>See the Big 5 on a game drive</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Big 5 (lion, leopard, elephant, rhino and buffalo) is South Africa's greatest attraction, not to mention its favourite tourism marketing moniker. All can be elusive beasts, but chances of sighting these heavyweights and various other crowd favourites are as good as anywhere in safari stalwarts like Kruger National Park, or the exceptionally accessible Pilanesberg National Park.</p>]]><p><b>See what lies beneath at Sodwana Bay</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The picturesque coastline and warm waters of KwaZulu-Natal offer superb conditions for underwater exploration.  Sodwana Bay near Durban is a particularly popular base for reef dives among turtles and tropical fish, while Aliwal Shoal and Protea Banks further south are favourites for sharks and wrecks. Courses are available for the newbies.</p>]]><p><b>Spot whales in Hermanus</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the world's greatest whale watching spots is Hermanus, which hosts an annual Whale Festival and is an easy couple of hours jaunt down the coast from Cape Town. Southern Right Whales migrate along the coast from around June until September and at Hermanus they come so close to shore you can see them breaching from your hotel window.</p>]]><p><b>Stand on the tip of Africa at Cape Point</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you've come this far, you have to go all the way. As the land runs out, you'll reach sheer cliffs and a historic lighthouse towering above the sea. The surrounding conservation area is populated with buck, baboons, zebra, ostrich and indigenous flora. Winding your way back towards town, duck off the main drag to find a number of secluded white sandy beaches.</p>]]><p><b>Surf South Africa’s famous waves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Surfers are spoilt for choice on both the Indian and Atlantic coastlines of South Africa. The surf mecca of Jeffrey's Bay has long drawn the sport's disciples from all over the world, thanks to what many consider the world's best right hand point break. On the outskirts of Cape Town, Muizenberg's Surfer's Corner is another favourite for beginners and pros alike.</p>]]><p><b>Swim with penguins at Boulders Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A large colony of entertaining African penguins live on a protected part of Boulders Beach in Simonstown, near Cape Town. A modest entrance fee lets you approach the penguins via various walkways and gives you access to the idyllic beach itself, where you can swim with the penguins between the great granite boulders from which the beach takes its name.</p>]]><p><b>Take a turn around Kirstenbosch Botanical Gardens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This immaculate landscaped garden at the foot of Table Mountain was created in 1913 and showcases a wide array of indigenous plants and flowers, particularly those unique to the Cape. There are also a number of manicured lawns perfect for a picnic or the Sunday evening open-air concerts that run throughout the summer.</p>]]><p><b>Taste the Cape Winelands</b></p><![CDATA[<p>More than a dozen wine routes and a bevy of wine estates tempt you with delectable tastings and equally excellent cuisine. The views are unfailingly splendid, with whitewashed Cape-Dutch mansions sitting prettily amongst rolling hills and rugged mountains. The wine price tags are equally easy on the eyes. Organised trips from Cape Town let you avoid drunk driving.</p>]]><p><b>Unearth the history of the Anglo-Boer War</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At the very end of the 19th century, bloody skirmishes between the Afrikaners, British and Zulus raged across the tranquil rolling hills of KwaZulu-Natal, as evinced today by various gravesites and monuments. Knowledgeable guides lead you around the former battlefields, telling tales that send shivers down your spine.</p>]]><p><b>Unwind in the old Transkei</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the Eastern Cape, the peaceful rural idyll and rustic Xhosa villages of the old Transkei still seem to belong to a different time, and belie a turbulent history from which emerged many of South Africa's most iconic freedom fighters, including Nelson Mandela. Head south to the aptly named Wild Coast and you'll find some of South Africa's best-kept coastal secrets.</p>]]><p><b>Walk in Mandela’s footsteps on Robben Island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A short but often rough ferry trip from Cape Town's V&A Waterfront takes you to Robben Island, where Nelson Mandela and other iconic anti-apartheid activists were jailed for many years. It's a strangely bleak and melancholic place, where tours are still conducted by former political prisoners for an accurate personal account of a life in chains.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$295 billion (2016).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Mineral raw materials (coal, diamonds, platinum), agricultural produce, chemical products and machinery.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>UK, US, Germany, Italy and China.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The South African economy dominates Sub-Saharan Africa. Agriculture is strong enough for virtual self-sufficiency in foodstuffs: livestock is reared extensively, and large amounts of sugar, maize and cereals are produced. Wine and fruit are exported in large quantities.<br />
<br />
The industrial sector has traditionally been based on mining as one of the world's largest exporters of gold, platinum and diamonds. It also has considerable deposits of coal, chromium, manganese and vanadium. The telecommunication networks have seen major improvements in recent years as undersea cables have brought international bandwidth in larger amounts at cheaper prices.<br />
<br />
After decades of double-digit inflation, the period from 2004 to the onset of the global financial downturn was marked by healthy growth and inflation of under 5%. In the run up to the 2010 FIFA World Cup a construction boom benefitted the country and inflation was capped to 5.7% in 2010. The inflation rate was recorded at 6.3% in 2016. <br />
<br />
Unemployment remains a major problem, with an official figure of 25.5% in the third quarter 2012, but in many rural and urban townships it is estimated to be much higher. Other long-term problems include poverty, a high level of HIV/AIDS infection and an inadequate infrastructure for public transport and electricity. <br />
<br />
The country still has a legacy two-tiered economy; one rivalling developed countries and a more basic informal sector, leading to an uneven distribution of wealth and income. South Africa is a member of the   Southern African Development Community (SADC) and the African Union (AU).<br />
<br />
South Africa has three major trade show, conference and exhibition venues: Sandton Convention Centre in Johannesburg, Cape Town International Convention Centre, and the International Convention Centre in Durban. Smaller venues exist in the hotels and universities of other major towns. South African Tourism provides information for conference organisers and delegates.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Business practices in South Africa are very westernised. The exchanging of business cards is important and a firm handshake between both men and women is common. Punctuality is still highly prized and it is advisable to address hosts as 'Mr' or 'Ms' until requested to use first names, which usually happens soon after formal greetings are dispensed with. The triple handshake is common among black businesspeople, although the standard handshake usually takes precedence with international visitors.</p>
<p>Cape Town is relatively informal and more laid back than Johannesburg. Its businesses tend to be creative rather than industrial, so suit and ties are not always in evidence. Pushiness and a demand for instant decisions are not appreciated. People like to mull things over and will freeze out anyone too in-their-face. Capetonians joke it's dubbed the Mother City because everything takes nine months to happen. Have patience, bru (brother).<br />
<br />
In Durban, most industries do expect a suit and tie at business meetings. The more modern or artistic industries, such as IT and the media, tend to display a more informal attitude to dress. <br />
<br />
In cosmopolitan Johannesburg, all of South Africa's 11 official languages are spoken, but English is the most widely used language in government and commerce. Businessmen and women in Johannesburg tend to wear suits, although ethnic outfits are increasingly evident.</p>
<p>Gifts are not expected in either business or social situations. Business cards are often exchanged where businesspeople meet informally, such as in hotel lobbies, airport lounges and at product launches. Most initial business-related social contact is along the lines of 'let's do lunch'; dinner and breakfast appointments are far less common.</p><p>There is no single office opening time and it varies from business to business, generally from either 0800 or 0900 to 1630 or 1700, Mon-Fri.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Department of Trade &amp; Industry</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (012) 394 9500
					Website:http://www.dti.gov.za
					Address: Sunnyside,77 Meintjies Street,Pretoria,2]]><b>South African Chamber of Commerce and Industry (SACCI)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: (011) 446 3800
					Website:http://www.sacci.org.za
					Address: Rosebank,Chamber House,24 Sturdee Avenue,Johannesburg,2196]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The <em>braai</em>, South Africa&rsquo;s equivalent of the barbecue, is practically a national sport, a religion even. Almost all campsites, self-catering resorts and picnic spots have built in <em>braai</em> facilities, as does every self-respecting garden.</p>
<p>The long and bountiful South African coastline guarantees a seemingly endless supply of the freshest fish and seafood. The agreeable coastal climate further contributes to the distinctly Mediterranean feel of many of South Africa&rsquo;s beachfront restaurants.</p>
<p>Just inland in the Cape Winelands, the local wine industry is thriving and generally of a very high standard, while many of South Africa&rsquo;s best restaurants are also found on its wine estates.</p>
<p>The country's cosmopolitan heritage is matched in its variety of culinary offerings, with fruity and sweet Cape Malay cuisine a speciality of Cape Town, and a strong Indian influence stirred into Durban's cracking curries.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Boerewors:</strong>&nbsp;A high-quality beef and pork sausage with a variety of spices, essential for a <em>braai.</em><br />
<strong>Bobotjie:</strong> A curried mince bake topped with egg and often studded with raisins.<br />
<strong>Poitjiekos:</strong> A casserole slow cooked on the fire in a cast iron pot.<br />
<strong>Biltong:</strong>&nbsp;Dried meat, typically made from beef, venison or ostrich meat.<br />
<strong>Droewors:</strong>&nbsp;A dried sausage that is eaten as a snack.<br />
<strong>Amagwinya:</strong>&nbsp;A savoury doughnut that often accompanies stews.<br />
<strong>Umgqusho:</strong> A traditional African staple of samp (dried maize kernels) and beans.<br />
<strong>Pap:</strong> A maize porridge staple that often accompanies <em>braai </em>meat.<br />
<strong>Bunny Chow:</strong> Curry filling in a hollowed out half loaf of bread.<br />
<strong>Koeksister:</strong> A syrup-coated doughnut twist sometimes finished with a sprinkling of coconut.<br />
<strong>Melktert:</strong> An Afrikaans desert consisting of pastry and a creamy filling.<br />
<strong>Malva Pudding:</strong>&nbsp;A sweet and gooey sponge desert of Cape Dutch origin, similar to sticky toffee pudding.<br />
<strong>Umqombothi:</strong> A traditional Xhosa beer made with maize and sorghum.<br />
<strong>Pinotage:</strong> A red wine grape bursting with ripe fruit and unique to South Africa.<br />
<strong>Rooibos:</strong> A red-coloured and fragrant caffeine-free tea indigenous to the Western Cape.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>A tip of 10 to 15% is expected.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Night life revolves around restaurants, bars and cinemas, with a scattering of good nightclubs in the main cities too. The most popular areas are the few streets where caf&eacute; spill out onto the pavements for late nights in the balmy summer air. There's a thriving theatre scene, and the quality of stand-up comedy has improved enormously over the years with comedy clubs, theatres and bars running regular comedy nights. Some cities have art house cinemas that screen less mainstream movies and run offbeat film festivals.</p>
<p><br />
Cape Town is the place for jazz, with several live music venues and an annual international jazz festival. South Africa is firmly on the international pop and rock circuit, and the local music scene is also successful, with most cities having a handful of live music venues. Classical music and opera fans will only get their fix in larger cities. There are several stadiums and other large venues where international bands often perform.<br />
<br />
Football and rugby are national addictions, and many bars and some restaurants have large-screen TVs for sports enthusiasts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South Africans love shopping, and tend to do it in huge shopping centres rather than in shopping streets. The Gateway Mall in Durban is reputedly the largest in the southern hemisphere. However, areas where shops and restaurants spill out onto the streets are becoming increasingly popular as both daytime and evening venues.</p>
<p>Johannesburg has three popular weekend markets that have sprung up as part of the city centre&rsquo;s rejuvenation plans: 44 Stanley, Arts on Main and the Neighbourgoods Market. Cape Town&rsquo;s V&amp;A centre at the Waterfront is a tourist-friendly combination of shopping and entertainment with bars, music, restaurants and cinemas, as well a large arts and craft shed. Traditional African arts and crafts are sold in numerous craft markets including Johannesburg's Rosebank Mall craft market. The intricate beadwork necklaces and bold wooden carvings including large masks are particularly attractive, and six foot tall giraffes are often being wrapped for safe transit home in the cargo hold. <br />
<br />
Impromptu craft stalls often appear at the side of the road, particularly on popular tourist routes, and some have become permanent attractions in their own right, such as the one between Johannesburg and Sun City. Haggling is perfectly acceptable and often expected in the craft markets.</p>
<p><br />
Gold, diamonds and local wine also make excellent buys. In general, visitors will find the exchange rate favourable and prices much easier on the pocket than in many other countries.<br />
<br />
Visitors can claim a 14% VAT refund on purchases worth more than R250. You need to show your passport, flight ticket, the items and invoices to the refund desk in airports.</p><p>Many shops stay open until at least 1800, and large shopping malls and tourist spots generally stay open even later. Sunday shopping is very common too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The top-end hotels in South Africa are world class with excellent restaurants, well-equipped fitness rooms, spas and swimming pools. Stylish boutique hotels have become very prevalent in the last two years, and almost every town increased the quality and quantity of its accommodation options in the run up to the 2010 FIFA World Cup.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong>The Tourism Grading Council of South Africa runs a voluntary accommodation grading system. Establishments that join the scheme are awarded 1 to 5 stars. The type of accommodation is taken into account, so there are 5-star bed and breakfasts, and caravan parks, as well as 5-star hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfast accommodation is found everywhere, from rural villages to urban townships. Many have a bit more charm than standard bed and breakfasts. Some are housed in historical buildings decorated with antiques, while others may be on a working farm where guests can get involved.The hosts may provide dinner on request. Advance bookings in the high season of October to April are becoming essential, especially in the Western Cape. Local tourist offices are the best source of information.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The top-end hotels in South Africa are world class with excellent restaurants, well-equipped fitness rooms, spas and swimming pools. Stylish boutique hotels have become very prevalent in the last two years, and almost every town increased the quality and quantity of its accommodation options in the run up to the 2010 FIFA World Cup.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong>The Tourism Grading Council of South Africa runs a voluntary accommodation grading system. Establishments that join the scheme are awarded 1 to 5 stars. The type of accommodation is taken into account, so there are 5-star bed and breakfasts, and caravan parks, as well as 5-star hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The top-end hotels in South Africa are world class with excellent restaurants, well-equipped fitness rooms, spas and swimming pools. Stylish boutique hotels have become very prevalent in the last two years, and almost every town increased the quality and quantity of its accommodation options in the run up to the 2010 FIFA World Cup.<br />
<br />
<strong>Grading: </strong>The Tourism Grading Council of South Africa runs a voluntary accommodation grading system. Establishments that join the scheme are awarded 1 to 5 stars. The type of accommodation is taken into account, so there are 5-star bed and breakfasts, and caravan parks, as well as 5-star hotels.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No**]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Sometimes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Medical facilities are good in urban areas but can be limited elsewhere. Doctors and hospitals often require immediate cash payment. Comprehensive health insurance is recommended to cover the fees of private facilities. The National Tourism Information and Safety Line is 083 123 2345. The general emergency services number is 10111. Netcare 911 (tel: 082 911; &lt;a href="http://www.netcare911.co.za" target="_blank"&gt;www.netcare911.co.za&lt;/a&gt;) is a private emergency service offering road assistance and evacuation, ambulances, private hospitals and emergency over the phone medical advice.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Mains water is safe to drink. Milk is pasteurised and dairy products are safe for consumption, as are local meat, poultry, seafood, fruit and vegetables. Diarrhoea remains the most common cause of ill health in travellers, with South Africa graded as an intermediate risk country. The standard of food safety and preparation is generally good and poses little threat to your health, but sensitive travellers should follow the advice to &amp;lsquo;cook it, peel it or leave it.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Avoid swimming and paddling in stagnant or slow-moving water as there is a low risk of contracting bilharzia, and a risk of catching E.coli. Cholera is spread by contaminated food or water and occurs in some rural areas of Limpopo, Mpumalanga, KwaZulu-Natal and the Eastern Cape, where it can be picked up from swimming in contaminated streams. Swimming pools that are well chlorinated and maintained are safe. Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Department of Health statistics show the prevalence of HIV/AIDS remains high despite increasing efforts to combat it, with 178 out of 1,000 adults infected, compared to a global average of just 8 in 1,000. Malaria is found in Limpopo, Mpumalanga and the north-east of KwaZulu-Natal, and the Department of Health recommends taking preventative drugs during the peak period between September and May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunburn is a much more common risk, with the African sun being far fiercer than most people realise. Tourists are also vulnerable to theft or mugging and the usual precautions apply &amp;ndash; keep jewellery, cameras, handbags and other valuables out of sight, do not carry large sums of money, and avoid walking at night or along isolated beaches and streets. Motorists should park in well-lit areas, be alert when waiting for traffic lights to change, and if a hijacking does occur, keep your hands where the attackers can see them and do not try to resist.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Holidays falling on Sunday are observed the following Monday.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Human Rights Day :
							21 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Family Day :
							02 April </p><p>Freedom Day :
							27 April </p><p>Workers' Day :
							01 May </p><p>Youth Day :
							16 June </p><p>National Women's Day :
							09 August </p><p>Heritage Day :
							24 September </p><p>Day of Reconciliation :
							16 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Day of Goodwill :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The following goods may be imported into South Africa by passengers over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes and 20 cigars and 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits or liqueurs and 2L of wine.<br />
&bull; 50ml of perfume and 250ml of eau de toilette.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to a value of R5,000 (R25,000 if arriving from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/botswana">Botswana</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lesotho">Lesotho</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/namibia">Namibia</a> or <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/swaziland">Swaziland</a>); this allowance is valid once per person in a 30-day period and only if you have been out of the country for at least 48 hours.<b><br />
</b></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prohibited goods include narcotics, firearms, weapons and ammunition, poison, cigarettes with a mass of more than 2kg per 1,000, counterfeit goods, unlawful reproductions of any works subject to copyright, and prison-made goods.</p>
<p>Restricted goods requiring an import permit include South African bank notes in excess of R25,000, gold coins, coin and stamp collections, unprocessed gold, endangered species, food, plants, animals, biological goods, and medicines (excluding three months' personal supply accompanied by a letter or certified prescription from a registered doctor).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You may require a licence to export precious stones or minerals.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Rand (ZAR; symbol R) = 100 cents. Notes are in denominations of R200, 100, 50, 20 and 10. Coins are in denominations of R5, 2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10 and 5 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money can be changed at banks, bureaux de change and some hotels. Proof of identity may be requested so take your passport. Visitors are restricted to bringing in and taking out a maximum of R5,000 in cash.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard and Visa are preferred. American Express and Diners Club are also widely accepted. ATMs are available in all towns, cities and shopping malls and most petrol stations, and accept international cards. Almost all hotels, shops, restaurants, national parks and game reserves accept credit cards. They are now acceptable at most petrol stations too, but since that is a relatively new measure, it's worth checking before you fill up.</p><p>ATMs are available in all towns, cities and shopping malls and most petrol stations, and accept international cards. Be alert when using ATMs, and do not accept help from anybody as conmen are adept at switching cards. Check your statements afterwards for a few weeks too, as cloning machines are occasionally planted in ATMs. More obviously, be aware of who is hanging around and don't withdraw money if your instinct tells you not to.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Valid at banks, hotels, restaurants and some tourist-orientated shops. To avoid additional exchange rate charges, travellers are advised to take traveller's cheques in Pounds Sterling or US Dollars.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mon-Fri 0900-1530, Sat 0830-1100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No/1</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To enter South Africa, a passport valid for at least 30 days after the intended date of departure is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>
<p>Passports must have at least two blank pages for entry stamps.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals requiring a visa to visit South Africa must obtain a transit visa if travelling through South Africa to visit a neighbouring country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitor's visa: &pound;35.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitor's visa: up to 90 days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at high commission/embassy). In the UK, VFS Global (<a href="http://www.vfsglobal.com/southafrica/uk" target="_blank">www.vfsglobal.com/southafrica/uk</a>) handles visa applications on behalf of the high commission; an additional &pound;35 service charge applies.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you intend to work in South Africa, including any voluntary or paid employment or studies, you must apply for a work, study or exchange visa before you arrive.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>For applications in the UK, allow at least seven days for visa processing in the London visa centre and nine days for processing in Manchester or Edinburgh.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Nationals requiring a visa must show bank statements with at least &pound;600.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you need to extend your visa, you should contact the nearest branch of the Department of Home Affairs. If you plan to visit for longer than 90 days, you normally need to apply for a temporary residence permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An import permit is required for all pets, applied for through the Directorate of Animal Health in South Africa. A 14-day quarantine period applies to dogs from many countries. Cats are exempt from quarantine. Animals must be vaccinated against rabies except those coming from the UK, Australia and New Zealand. It&rsquo;s worth checking first whether you will be allowed to take pets back into your home country again after they have been in South Africa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[-29.045996]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[25.062993]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,219,912 sq km (471,011 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>56,717,156 (2017).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>46 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Cape Town (legislative); Pretoria (executive); Bloemfontein (judicial).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Republic of South Africa fills the southern tip of the continent and is lapped by the Atlantic Ocean to the west and the Indian Ocean to the east, and a swirling mixture of the two at the very tip.</p>
<p>It totally encloses the independent kingdom of Lesotho, and is bordered by Namibia, Botswana, Zimbabwe, Mozambique and Swaziland to the north.</p>
<p>A vast, interior plateau has sharp escarpments that rise above the lowland plains. Mountainous regions include the Drakensberg and Magaliesberg.</p>
<p>The west coast is arid, while the south and southeast coasts are semi-arid, with vegetation fringed by sandy beaches and rocky coves. In contrast, the subtropical northeast has lush wetlands and coastal forests. The wildlife viewing areas are scattered throughout the country, with the famous Kruger National Park so vast that it encloses a wide variety of eco-systems.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Of its nine provinces, Gauteng, which houses Johannesburg and Pretoria in the northeast, is the smallest and most densely populated. The Northern Cape is the largest province covering between a third and quarter of the country, but containing only a tiny percentage of the population in this territory of desert and semi-desert wilderness.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Around two thirds of South Africans are Christian of some form including Catholics, Anglicans, Dutch Reformed or African independent churches. Many Africans believe in traditional healers called sangomas, who give readings &ndash; including throwing the bones &ndash; and provide spiritual and emotional counselling and dispense African traditional medicines or muti. There are also significant Hindu, Muslim and Jewish communities.  <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/johannesburg">Johannesburg</a> has areas that the descendants of former immigrants have made their own, including Fordsburg for the Indian community and Chinatown in Cyrildene.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South Africa&rsquo;s biggest cities are very westernised and hold few cultural surprises for Europeans. Handshaking is the usual form of greeting, sometimes in a more elaborate African handshake that foreigners will pick up readily. Casual wear is widely acceptable, especially in less formal <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-africa/cape-town-international-airport">Cape Town</a>. Smoking is prohibited in public buildings and on public transport.</p>
<p>The presence of so many diverse ethnic backgrounds certainly adds some spice outside of the main business centres. Rural areas most likely to be visited by travellers include Zulu land in KwaZulu Natal where communities are based in small traditional villages with round huts (<em>rondevals</em>) and a few hustling, bustling relatively poor towns.</p>
<p>In Durban you&rsquo;ll be entertained by beach-front Zulu dancers wearing full animal skin tribal regalia. A more modern form of culture is the now commercialised Gum Boot dance, performed in wellingtons and mining outfits and developed in men&rsquo;s only mining hostels when entertainment was scarce.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>220/230 volts AC, 50Hz. Plugs have three fat round pins (type M from world standards).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Cyril Ramaphosa since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Cyril Ramaphosa since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In 1487, Bartolomeo Dias of Portugal became the first European to lay eyes on South Africa. A little over a century later, the Dutch East India Company set up a refreshment station at the Cape for ships and slaves toing and froing from Asia. The increasingly insatiable imperial appetite of the British meant they were never going to be far behind.</p>
<p>As European influence and ambition gradually expanded into the hinterland, the indigenous population and various other African ethnic groups, who had migrated south over preceding centuries, were increasingly subjugated and outgunned.</p>
<p>The white settlers&rsquo; bullying and bloodletting of black South Africans was formally institutionalised by the apartheid system of the National Party, which came to power in 1948 and whose reign was to be characterized by their forced removals of &lsquo;non-whites&rsquo; from most urban areas and their increasingly violent suppression of anti-apartheid activists.</p>
<p>The brutal suppression of black activism, which was carried out with callous efficiency, saw sanctions imposed by countries around the world. International isolation and increasingly violent civil unrest eventually broke the apartheid system, which officially began to dismantle in 1990 after negotiations between President FW De Klerk and the African National Congress (ANC) leader Nelson Mandela, in jail at the time on Robben Island.</p>
<p>In 1994, South Africa&rsquo;s first fully democratic elections swept the ANC to power and the iconic Mandela, finally a free man after serving 27 years behind bars, became the first president of the new South Africa, unswerving in his philosophy of forgiveness and reconciliation.</p>
<p>But since Mandela&rsquo;s retirement, South Africa&rsquo;s young democracy has continued to be hampered by the legacy of apartheid, as is apparent in the stark socioeconomic and even geographical disparity between white South Africans and a small black elite on the one hand, and the vast majority of black South Africans on the other.</p>
<p>Mandela&rsquo;s successors have failed to fill his shoes, with the aloof Thabo Mbeki doing little to combat the twin ravages of violent crime and an AIDS pandemic, and current ANC leader Jacob Zuma and his cabinet better known for corruption, factionalism and philandering than effective governance.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; South Africa is the only country that boasts two Nobel Prize winners who lived on the same street. Nelson Mandela and Archbishop Desmond Tutu both had houses on Soweto&rsquo;s Vilakazi Street.<br />
&bull; There are more than 2,000 shipwrecks along South Africa&rsquo;s coastlines, many of which date back at least 500 years.<br />
&bull; In 2010, South Africa was the first African country to host the FIFA World Cup.<br />
&bull; South Africa still has seven recognized royal families. 20 million South Africans fall within the various royal kingdoms.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the Republic of South Africa in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 232 4400 / (202) 274 7991 (consular section).</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.saembassy.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 232 4400 / (202) 274 7991 (consular section).</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1230 and 1300-1700; Fri 0800-1400. Consular section Mon-Fri 0830-1200.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>3051 Massachusetts Avenue<br/>Washington <br/>20008<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[South African Consulate in the UK (Visa services)]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b>http://southafricahouseuk.com/visas/vis_needvis.php</p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;By appointment only.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>66 Wilson Street<br/>London<br/>EC2 A2JX<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[South African High Commission in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7451 7299.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://southafricahouseuk.com/index.html</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7451 7299.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1100 (appointments only).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Trafalgar Square<br/>South Africa House<br/>London<br/>WC2N 5DP<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[The British High Commission in South Africa]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(012) 421 7500.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinsouthafrica.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(012) 421 7500.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Thurs 0800-1700; Fri 0800-1230.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>Arcadia<br/>255 Hill Street<br/>Pretoria<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With golden beaches, jagged mountains and national parks overflowing with wildlife, South Africa is the Africa you&rsquo;ve always imagined. While memories of a troubled past remain, the republic is well on the way to regaining its throne as the holiday capital of Africa, visited by nearly 10 million people every year.</p>
<p>Topping a long list of attractions is the republic&rsquo;s spectacular wildlife and natural scenery. National parks and nature reserves preserve an incredible variety of landscapes &ndash; rolling plains, towering mountains, arid deserts, coastal <em>fynbos</em> (shrubland) and pure blue oceans &ndash; home to an incredible variety of wildlife, from lions and elephants to great white sharks and playful penguins.</p>
<p>South Africa's cities are no less varied. In the far south, lorded over by iconic Table Mountain, Cape Town is South Africa&rsquo;s most accessible gateway, with gorgeous beaches, vibrant, multicultural neighbourhoods, famous vineyards, a lively nightlife and fine dining to rival any European capital. You&rsquo;ll find a similarly cosmopolitan vibe in Johannesburg, the energetic capital, and in beachside Durban, where the hot sunshine is matched by the scorching curries cooked up by the South Asian community.</p>
<p>In between you can lose yourself for days on safari. The undisputed top spot for wildlife spotters is world-famous Kruger National Park, where the Big Five &ndash; lions, leopards, elephants, buffaloes and rhinos &ndash; are joined by hundreds of other African species.</p>
<p>If the landscape sounds diverse, wait until you meet the people. South Africa boasts 11 official languages and more than a dozen tribes, living alongside communities from Africa, Europe and the Indian subcontinent &ndash; little wonder this is known as the Rainbow Nation. This diversity is tangible everywhere, from the architecture and language to the nation&rsquo;s spectacular cuisine.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, huge inequality remains, still sharply marked out along racial lines. To understand modern South Africa, everyone should visit Johannesburg&rsquo;s moving Apartheid Museum, and Robben Island prison, where Nelson Mandela was held for 18 years. Or you could join a township tour in Soweto, which, like the rest of your trip, you&rsquo;ll never forget.</p><p>With golden beaches, jagged mountains and national parks overflowing with wildlife, South Africa is the Africa you&rsquo;ve always imagined. While memories of a troubled past remain, the republic is well on the way to regaining its throne as the holiday capital of Africa, visited by nearly 10 million people every year.</p>
<p>Topping a long list of attractions is the republic&rsquo;s spectacular wildlife and natural scenery. National parks and nature reserves preserve an incredible variety of landscapes &ndash; rolling plains, towering mountains, arid deserts, coastal <em>fynbos</em> (shrubland) and pure blue oceans &ndash; home to an incredible variety of wildlife, from lions and elephants to great white sharks and playful penguins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
