<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="South Sudan" ColCode="sou" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[South Sudan]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><a  class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/south-sudan>South Sudan</a> has wet season lasting May to October, often causing widepsread floods and interruption of transport infrastructure. Temperatures are high throughout the year.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight clothes are suitable all year round. If travelling during the rainy season, bring waterproofs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internal flights are the easiest way to get around South Sudan, but note that certain carriers, including Kush Air (<a href="http://www.kushair.net" target="_blank">www.kushair.net</a>) and South Supreme Airlines, are banned in the EU.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>Asphalted roads are effectively non-existent outside Juba. Road conditions are poor outside towns, roads to the north are often closed during the rainy season (July to September), and street lights are non-existent.  Owing to the bad conditions, you should carry a full set of spare parts for long journeys.  Vehicles must be in good working condition.</p><p>Rough and ready minibuses connect Juba to towns in the south. During the May-December rainy season, roads can become impassable and certain destinations (such as Wau) are only accessible by air.</p><p>Urban taxis in Juba are plentiful, along with motorbike taxis. Road safety is not always a primary concern of drivers. Taxis are not metered; fares must be agreed in advance.</p><p>A Carnet de Passage, adequate finance and roadworthiness certificate (from the embassy) are all needed. An International Driving Permit is recommended, although not legally required.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 130kph (81mph) on motorways, 110kph (68mph) on highways, 90kph (56mph) outside built-up areas and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas. Heavy fines are imposed for speeding. It is compulsory for front and rear passengers to wear seat belts. It is illegal to use a handheld mobile telephone while driving. Headlights should be turned on at all times.</p><p>Available in Juba.</p><p>The minimum driving age is 18. Speed limits are 130kph (81mph) on motorways, 110kph (68mph) on highways, 90kph (56mph) outside built-up areas and 50kph (31mph) in built-up areas. Heavy fines are imposed for speeding. It is compulsory for front and rear passengers to wear seat belts. It is illegal to use a handheld mobile telephone while driving. Headlights should be turned on at all times.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Airlines operating flights to South Sudan include: Egyptair (<a href="http://www.egyptair.com" target="_blank">www.egyptair.com</a>) from Cairo; Ethiopian Airlines (<a href="http://www.ethiopianairlines.com" target="_blank">www.ethiopianairlines.com</a>) from Addis Ababa; flydubai (<a href="http://www.flydubai.com" target="_blank">www.flydubai.com</a>) from Dubai, Fly540 (<a href="http://www.fly540.com" target="_blank">www.fly540.com</a>) and Kenya Airways (<a href="http://www.kenya-airways.com" target="_blank">www.kenya-airways.com</a>) from Nairobi; and RwandAir (<a href="http://www.rwandair.com" target="_blank">www.rwandair.com</a>) from Kigali and Entebbe (Uganda). The quickest routes from the UK are usually via Addis Ababa or Nairobi.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 12 hours (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Very slow, irregular river barges from the Kosti in Sudan to Malakal and Juba, but it&rsquo;s much more preferable to fly.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The land borders with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/kenya">Kenya</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/uganda">Uganda</a> are open, and there are direct bus services from Juba to Nairobi via Kampala.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>There are no landlines. Roaming agreements exist with some international mobile phone companies. Coverage is available in main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet access is available in main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The <em>Sudan Tribune</em> (<a href="http://www.sudantribune.com" target="_blank">www.sudantribune.com</a>) is the main English language newspaper.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>International couriers operate in South Sudan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Attend a wrestling match</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps the most popular sport in the country, wrestling competitions are major events. Renowned wrestlers covered in dust do battle in stadiums complete with floodlights. Large crowds shout support over blaring music and beating drums. Watch – or have a go yourself – and understand why the sport elicits such frenzied admiration. The town of Bor hosts events every weekend.</p>]]><p><b>Experience old and new in Wau</b></p><![CDATA[<p>South Sudan's second city, Wau is home to a plethora of colonial-era buildings and a mix of tribes that give the city a cosmopolitan air. Its domed 1913 cathedral is the largest in the region, while Wau is also the terminus of the country's only rail line, snaking its way slowly north to Babanosa in Sudan.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the Sudd by canoe</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A vast inland sea formed by the Nile, the impenetrable nature of the Sudd's tangled vegetation has made it a fantastic place to witness a wetland habitat undisturbed by the modern world. For a magical journey take a canoe out onto the water and paddle amongst the hippos that live there.</p>]]><p><b>Go on safari</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nimule National Park is the country's most accessible. Visitors can hire a boat to Opekoloe Island for the best sightings of elephant, before heading out to Fola Falls with a an expert ranger. Here you can not only witness the impressive spectacle of the cascading water, but also watch fishermen cast out their nets under the watchful gaze of crocs and hippos.</p>]]><p><b>Hike through the Imatong Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Still in its infancy, like South Sudan itself, there is a burgeoning hiking scene in the forests of the Imatong Mountains, whose peaks offer spectacular views over the plains into Uganda. With luck, you'll be able to catch sight of elephant and leopard too.</p>]]><p><b>Kick back in the capital, Juba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The world's newest capital city is the place to visit if you want ringside tickets for the spectacle that is nation building. Juba is a fast-growing boomtown, with new buildings being thrown up on a weekly basis. Of the sites to visit the most important is the memorial to John Garang, who led the Sudan People's Liberation Army for over 20 years.</p>]]><p><b>Observe an unchanged way of life at a cattle camp</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The majority of the Dinka tribe remain nomadic farmers, so their cattle camps offer a fascinating view into a traditional way of life and show the importance of cattle to the tribespeople. Boys live alongside herds of more than 500 long-horned cattle in the camps, which are generally situated around Bor.</p>]]><p><b>Sip a sundowner on the Nile</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With 90% of South Sudan sitting in the White Nile basin, including the capital, Juba, the Nile plays a significant part in everyday life. Head to one of the capital's many restaurants or bars for views of the longest river in the world as the sun sets in a magnificent display of colour.</p>]]><p><b>Walk through history in Fashoda</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A closed city for almost 500 years, due to its sacred connections for the kings of Shilluk, Fashoda, now rechristened Kodok, is also famously the site where France and Britain almost come to blows over control of the region in the 19th century.</p>]]><p><b>Witness the world’s largest animal migration</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Forget Serengeti's wildebeest migration – for the world's largest mammal migration head to Boma National Park. This protected area is home to millions of white-eared kob and tiang antelope, which thunder across South Sudan every October. This great spectacle has endured many wars, though threats from conflict remain. As well as antelope, the park is home to lions, elephants, giraffe and cheetah, to name a few.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>No figures currently available</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Crude oil, timber, sorghum, peanuts, meat, hides, live animals.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Oil and petroleum products, wheat and wheat flour, transport equipment, food, and manufactured goods.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>Sudan, Uganda, Kenya</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are two cornerstones of the South Sudanese economy at independence: oil and aid. South Sudan has large oil reserves, which were much-contested during the long years of civil war with the north. South Sudan remains dependent its northern neighbour for transit, as oil pipelines head to Port Sudan on the Red Sea for refining and export. Years of fighting and internal displacement left large numbers of the population dependent on foreign aid, with numbers swelling following the return of many Southerners from Sudan in the run-up to independence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Businessmen should wear a lightweight suit. Punctuality is less important than patience and politeness. Personal introductions are an advantage.</p><p>Sat-Thurs 0800-1430.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Food here is traditionally simple, based around pounded millet, from which most South Sudanese get the majority of their daily energy requirements. In urban areas, cassava fritters and bread can also be found.</p><p>The key ingredient is perhaps the peanut, which acts as a base and thickener to many dishes. Meat, particularly goat, beef and chicken, is regularly consumed, but in small portions as part of a sauce which tops and adds flavour to the pounded millet. Cuisine from neighbouring Ethiopia is also ubiquitous.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Kisra</strong>: Flatbread made from sorghum flour.<br />
<strong>Wala-wala</strong>: Thick, starchy and plain tasting balls of millet flour that typically make up a meal&rsquo;s carbohydrate quota.<br />
<strong>Combo</strong>: Stewed spinach, peanut butter and tomato sometimes served with meat.<br />
<strong>Ful</strong>: Arabic stewed fava beans.<br />
<strong>Tamia</strong>: Balls of deep-fried ground chickpeas, in other words, falafel.<br />
<strong>Tomato Salad</strong>: Basic salad majoring in tomato, with onion and chilli. The best are served with a peanut butter and lime dressing.<br />
<strong>Goat stew</strong>: Mildly-flavoured concoction of chunks of goat meat, onion and a touch of chilli.<br />
<strong>Salaat zabadi</strong>: Vegetables including carrot, cucumber and tomato in locally-produced yoghurt.<br />
<strong>Perch</strong>: Smoked or deep-fried pieces of fish served with a chilli relish.<br />
<strong>Baseema</strong>: Cake made with yoghurt, sesame oil and sugar.<br />
<strong>Miris</strong>: Stew containing sheep&rsquo;s fat, onion and dried okra.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Not customary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Juba has a large number of restaurants, bars and nightclubs. Alcohol is widely consumed.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Basketwork, fabrics and local jewellery are among some of the wares you'll find on sale.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation is scarce outside Juba. There are a large number of hotels in the city of varying quality, although finding a room for under US$120 is difficult. Another option are permanent tented camps, which flourished following the influx of international workers following the peace deal with the north. There are a few smaller hotels in the main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation is scarce outside Juba. There are a large number of hotels in the city of varying quality, although finding a room for under US$120 is difficult. Another option are permanent tented camps, which flourished following the influx of international workers following the peace deal with the north. There are a few smaller hotels in the main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Accommodation is scarce outside Juba. There are a large number of hotels in the city of varying quality, although finding a room for under US$120 is difficult. Another option are permanent tented camps, which flourished following the influx of international workers following the peace deal with the north. There are a few smaller hotels in the main towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes*]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Diptheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diptheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Good medical facilities are available in Juba, with reasonable but limited facilities in Wau, Yei and Malakal. But health insurance is essential and should include cover for emergency repatriation.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;All water should be regarded as a potential health risk. Water used for drinking, brushing teeth or making ice should have first been boiled or otherwise sterilised. Milk is unpasteurised and should be boiled. Avoid dairy products which are likely to have been made from unboiled milk. Only eat well-cooked meat and fish, preferably served hot. Vegetables should be cooked and fruit peeled.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Avoid swimming and paddling in fresh water. Vaccinations against tuberculosis and hepatitis B are sometimes recommended. Anti-malarial drugs are highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Sudanese Pound (SDG) = 100 piasters. Notes are in denominations of SDG50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1. Coins are in denominations of 50, 20, 10, 5 and 1 piasters.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's best to bring plenty of cash (US$) rather than rely on card transactions in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/sudan">Sudan</a>.</p><p>There are currently no ATM facilities in South Sudan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>Yes</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>Yes</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for at least six months is required by all nationals referred to in the chart above.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: &pound;50; multiple-entry visa: &pound;100.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Single-entry visa: one month; multiple-entry visa: three months.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South Sudan Embassy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow seven working days for visa processing.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>You must show bank statements when applying for a visa to prove you have sufficient funds to cover your stay in South Sudan.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you plan to stay beyond the length of your visa, you need to apply for an extension at the Ministry of Interior before your visa expires.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><b>Longitude: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>644,329 sq km (248,777 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>12,733,427 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>18.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Juba.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Republic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>South Sudan is bordered by Sudan to the north, Ethiopia to the east, Kenya, Uganda and the Democratic Republic of the Congo to the south, and the Central African Republic to the west. The White Nile river runs from south to north through the country, joined by its major tributaries, the Bahr al-Ghazal and the Bahr al-Arab and the Sobat. The centre of the country is dominated by the Sudd, a 120,000 sq km (46,332 sq miles) marshland. This gives way to equatorial forest towards the south, rising to the jungle and the Imatong mountains on the Ugandan border, which include the country&rsquo;s highest peak, Mount Kinyeti, at 3,187m (10,456ft).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A mixture of Christian and traditional animist beliefs.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many restrictions on photography: the authorities regard many sites as sensitive or strategic. Such decisions are often made on the spot and with seeming arbitrariness.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European-style plugs with two round pins and Indian-style plugs with three round pins are used.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Salva Kiir Mayardit since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>President Salva Kiir Mayardit since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It was the great migrations of tribes that gave South Sudan its modern shape and ethnic mix. In the 15th century the Shilluk settled along the White Nile, followed by the pastoralist Dinka, and Azande from the Congo basin, two centuries later.</p>
<p>In the mid-19th century, Egypt pushed south into the Sudd, as other foreigners were also penetrating South Sudan. The 1860s saw the expeditions of the explorers John Hanning Speke, James Grant and Samuel and Florence Baker, all attempting to map the source of the Nile.</p>
<p>After the British crushed the Mahdist uprising in 1898, Sudan was governed as an Anglo-Egyptian Condominium, ostensibly ruled by both countries but in practice a British colony. The British enacted the Closed Districts Ordinance, effectively shutting the South off from Khartoum, with many envisaging the south becoming part of British East Africa.</p>
<p>The split from the north began to become irrecoverable even before Sudanese independence in 1956. An army mutiny in the south in 1955 broke into full-scale civil war on independence. The war lasted until 1972, when significant political autonomy was granted to the south.</p>
<p>Peace lasted until 1983, when the north repealed this agreement, and Islamic sharia law was introduced. There was intense hardship and famine for the civilian population, caused by drought but exacerbated by renewed war.</p>
<p>In 2002, internationally-sponsored talks produced a rolling ceasefire. The following year a formal end to hostilities was announced. As part of negotiations, John Garang, leader of the South&rsquo;s rebel army, was made Sudanese vice-president.</p>
<p>Garang was killed in a helicopter crash several months later. His successor, Salva Kiir, was left to implement the peace deal. The needs for reconstruction were massive, and border disputes over the oil-rich Abyei region, split between north and south, dominated events. In February 2011, a referendum on Southern independence was held in a largely peaceful atmosphere, with over 98% of southerners voting to secede from Sudan. Africa&rsquo;s newest nation was born six months later on 9 July.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	Alternative names in contention for the new nation included Nile Republic, Azania, and Kush Republic.<br />
&bull;	83% of the population live in traditional round stick and mud constructions called tukels.<br />
&bull;	The first baby born in South Sudan, on Independence Day itself, was a boy later named Independent.<br />
&bull;	The national anthem was chosen after holding an open competition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of South Sudan in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7554 8785</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.goss-london.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7554 8785</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>amilton House, Mabledon Place<br/>London<br/>WC1H 9BB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy of the South Sudan in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 293 7940.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.gossmission.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 293 7940.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>1233 20th Street N.W., Suite 602<br/>Washington<br/>20036<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s off-piste, and then there&rsquo;s South Sudan. Officially the world&rsquo;s newest nation, its poor infrastructure and volatile political climate will deter most from visiting this fledgling nation. But the intrepid few who do visit will discover some of the least known and most extreme natural phenomena on Earth.</p>
<p>After a messy divorce from Sudan in 2011, the South Sudanese people are fiercely proud of their hard-fought independence and both surprised and pleased when someone choses to visit.</p>
<p>Somewhat chaotic, and growing rapidly, the capital, Juba, has a superb location on the banks of the White Nile. Founded in the 1920s, it exhibits some excellent examples of British colonial architecture around the Hai Jalaba district, though most visitors will want to leave man-made structures behind and head for the country&rsquo;s natural wonders.</p>
<p>The vast swampy Sudd region, known locally as <em>Bahr el Jebel</em> or &ldquo;Mountain Sea&rdquo; is where the Nile forms one of the world&rsquo;s largest inland wetlands. A habitat safe from poachers for large populations of hippos, it is a unique experience to explore its vast islands of reeds by canoe.</p>
<p>Boma National Park not only boasts large populations of Africa&rsquo;s most iconic wildlife species, including elephant, giraffe and lion, but also the greatest migration of mammals on Earth, when an estimated two million grazing animals flee en mass for pastures new. The region is also renowned for its traditional tribal homesteads, which dot the plains.</p>
<p>Not content with rivers, swamps and savannah, South Sudan&rsquo;s natural prowess extends to the Imatong Mountains, and the star attraction here is Kinyeti, the highest mountain in the country at 3,200m (10,500ft).</p>
<p>The South Sudanese consider their homeland blessed and it&rsquo;s hard to disagree when you see the sheer diversity of natural landscapes the country has to offer. Road travel can be uncomfortable, but the end result is certainly well worth any hardship.</p><p>There&rsquo;s off-piste, and then there&rsquo;s South Sudan. Officially the world&rsquo;s newest nation, its poor infrastructure and volatile political climate will deter most from visiting this fledgling nation. But the intrepid few who do visit will discover some of the least known and most extreme natural phenomena on Earth.</p>
<p>After a messy divorce from Sudan in 2011, the South Sudanese people are fiercely proud of their hard-fought independence and both surprised and pleased when someone choses to visit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
