<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Lanzarote" ColCode="LAZ" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Lanzarote]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lanzarote has a warm, pleasant climate throughout the year with annual average temperatures of around 22°C (78°F) and very little rainfall (averaging less than 16 days per year). December and January are the months when this rainfall is most likely to occur. The north of the island tends to be windier and more cloudy.<br /><br />Occasionally temperatures can soar to 40°C (104°F) and above when the sirocco wind brings hot, dry and sandy air from the Sahara. This can last from a few hours to a week.<br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight, plus some wind protection according to the season.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All of the seven Canary Islands have their own airports. Lanzarote Airport – also known as Arrecife Airport – is located 5km (3 miles) south of Arrecife. Inter-island travel is served by Binter Canarias (<a href="http://www.bintercanarias.com/" target="_blank">www.bintercanarias.com</a>) and Canaryfly (<a href="http://www.canaryfly.es/" target="_blank">www.canaryfly.es</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An alternative means of travelling from island to island is by ferry. Two companies operate routes from Arrecife to Tenerife (journey time: from 11 hours): Armas (tel: +34 902 456 500; <a href="http://www.navieraarmas.com/" target="_blank">www.navieraarmas.com</a>) and Lineas Fred Olsen (tel: +34 902 100 107, <a href="http://www.fredolsen.es/" target="_blank">www.fredolsen.es</a>).</p>
<p>Fred Olsen ferries also link Lanzarote to Fuerteventura and Gran Canaria departing from Playa Blanca.</p>
<p>There is also a ferry between Orzola and the island of La Graciosa, which is operated by Lineas Maritimas Romero (tel: +34 928 842 055; <a href="http://www.lineasromero.com" target="_blank">www.lineasromero.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no rail network in Lanzarote.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roads in Lanzarote are generally a joy to drive on with very little traffic (outside of Arrecife) and long straight runs. Signposting is clear and it's quick and easy to navigate the entire island. The main thing to watch out for are the hordes of cyclists and runners you'll encounter along the way.</p>r<p>Two motorways (LZ1 and LZ2) link Arrecife with north and south along the eastern coast and are of a good quality and well maintained. Good quality B roads connect the rest of the island to the motorways with just one road, the LZ67, running through the outskirts of Timanfaya.</p><p>Taxis are metered, reasonably priced and widely available at the airport, in Arrecife and at all the main resorts.</p><p>Most foreign licences, including Canadian, EU and US, are accepted. Minimum third party insurance is compulsory. An original driving licence and proof of identity must be carried in the car at all times.</p><p>Two red hazard triangles and a reflective vest or jacket must be kept in all vehicles &ndash; the latter in the car, not in the boot. Parking laws are rigorously enforced and towing is prevalent. The speed limit for motorways is 120kph (80mph). In built-up areas it's 50kph (30mph) and on other roads it's 90kph (56mph).</p>
<p>There are fixed speed cameras between Arrecife and Playa Blanca on stretches where the speed limit is down to 100kph (62mph) and mobile speed traps are common. Front and rear safety belts are compulsory. Drink driving is a serious offence in Lanzarote. The legal limit is just 0.25%, equivalent to less than one pint of beer.</p><p>Real Automóvil Club de España (RACE) (tel: +34 928 806 881; <a href="http://www.race.es/" target="_blank">www.race.es</a>).</p><p>Several major car hire companies are represented at Lanzarote Airport and in the main urban centres. Car hire is good value for money on the island and most cars are less than two years old. Drivers must be over 21 to hire a car and you will need a passport, driving licence and credit card.</p><p>Bicycles are more popular than cars on Lanzarote and bike hire is available all over the island. With many flat, open roads, cycling is a cheap and healthy way of getting around, but be prepared for some major ascents if you head north or into the central part of the island. Riders of motorcycles over 75cc must be at least 18. Crash helmets are compulsory.</p><p>Two red hazard triangles and a reflective vest or jacket must be kept in all vehicles &ndash; the latter in the car, not in the boot. Parking laws are rigorously enforced and towing is prevalent. The speed limit for motorways is 120kph (80mph). In built-up areas it's 50kph (30mph) and on other roads it's 90kph (56mph).</p>
<p>There are fixed speed cameras between Arrecife and Playa Blanca on stretches where the speed limit is down to 100kph (62mph) and mobile speed traps are common. Front and rear safety belts are compulsory. Drink driving is a serious offence in Lanzarote. The legal limit is just 0.25%, equivalent to less than one pint of beer.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main resorts are relatively compact and easily navigable on foot with good parking options, often free of charge. For longer journeys metered taxis are readily available and taxi ranks abound. The public bus service is a cheap way of getting around and you can buy a Bono discount card for &euro;2 and top it up with a minimum of &euro;10 and it will give you 20% discount on all journeys. Ideal if you plan to use the bus a lot.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Lanzarote</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">puertodel_carmen</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Lanzarote</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">playa_blanca</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Lanzarote</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">costa_teguise</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Lanzarote</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">arrecife</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The national airline is Iberia (<a href="http://www.iberia.com/" target="_blank">www.iberia.com</a>), which flies to Lanzarote from mainland Spain and much of Europe. Budget airlines including Easyjet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com/" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) also fly to Lanzarote from the UK.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London to Lanzarote is 4 hours 20 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Lanzarote Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Lanzarote Airport is located 5km (3 miles) to the west of Arrecife.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 902 404 704</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Ferries from mainland Spain serve Lanzarote and other Canary Islands. Cruise ships also call at the island. Marmoles, a 30-minute walk from the centre of Arrecife, is the main port on the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lanzarote cannot be reached by rail.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lanzarote cannot be reached by road.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Emergency calls: 112. Area codes are incorporated within a nine digit number.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good across most of the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a variety of internet cafes in most urban areas. <br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>In the press <em>El Independiente</em> and <em>Canarias 7</em> are Spanish dailies covering the Canary Islands whilst <em>El Dia</em> is a pro-independence, Spanish daily with a wide readership, covering all the islands. <em>La Voz</em> is a local Spanish-language newspaper published in Lanzarote and <em>Lanzarote Gazette</em>&nbsp;(<a href="http://gazettelife.com" target="_blank">http://gazettelife.com</a>) is an English-language magazine and tourist guide.</p>
<p>Broadcasting in Spain has witnessed a spectacular expansion in recent  years with the emergence of new commercial operators and the launch of  digital services. TV Canaria and TV Canaria 2 are local channels for the islands whilst state-owned TVE operates TV-1 (La Primera) and TV-2 (La Dos). Antena 3, La Cuatro, Telecinco and La Sexta are privately run channels. With regards to radio RNE is state-run and operates Radio 1, Radio Clasica, Radio 3 and Radio 5. Cadena SER, Onda Cero and Cadena 40 Principales are popular commercial stations. whilst PowerFM is an English-language radio station broadcasting from Lanzarote and Tenerife.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are efficient internal and international postal services (<em>correos</em>) to all countries. Airmail within Europe usually takes around five days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask on beautiful beaches</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Home to arguably the best beaches in the Canary Islands, the jewel in Lanzarote's coastal crown is the stunning Papagayo Beach on the southern tip of the island. Set in a sheltered cove, its golden sands are the perfect place to top up the tan and go for a paddle.</p>]]><p><b>Call in at the Cesar Manrique Foundation</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The late artist, Cesar Manrique, was the architect behind some of Lanzarote&rsquo;s most outlandish buildings. However, his finest work can be found at the Cesar Manrique Foundation (<a href="http://www.cesarmanrique.com" target="_blank">www.cesarmanrique.com</a>), which occupies the artist&rsquo;s former home. Typically, this is no ordinary home; Manrique converted air pockets in the nearby lava fields into rooms, where he lived and worked until his untimely death in 1992.</p>]]><p><b>Cruise to La Graciosa and Alegranza</b></p><![CDATA[<p>If you have a day free hop aboard a sailing boat or ferry in Orzola and cruise to the nature reserve of Alegranza, the most northerly point of the Canary Islands and the only Atlantic nesting spot for the rare Eleonora's falcon. Continue your sailing sojourn with a detour to the tiny volcanic island of La Graciosa, where crystal clear seas and white sand beaches await.</p>]]><p><b>Delve into Lanzarote’s pirate history</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The oldest fortification on Lanzarote, Santa Barbara Castle was built in the 16th century to keep pirates at bay. Today it houses the Museo de la Pirater&iacute;a (<a href="http://www.museodelapirateria.com" target="_blank">www.museodelapirateria.com</a>), which offers room after room of exhibits about Lanzarote's cursed relationship with pirates over the centuries. The views are spectacular, too.</p>]]><p><b>Eat volcano-roasted chicken</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lanzarote's most popular tourist attraction, Timanfaya National Park is a protected volcanic reserve formed during a mega eruption in 1730. The volcanic activity continues to this day, much to the delight of diners at El Diablo, whose chefs cook chicken and other Canary island specialities over a geothermal barbecue. If you're not feeling peckish you'll soon work up an appetite hiking in the national park, which features geysers and a unique variety of flora and fauna.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the cosy capital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The capital of Lanzarote, Arrecife is a small port city, North African in style. Kick back on the lovely and uncrowded Playa Del Reducto beach; head to the pretty Charco de San Ginés for a waterfront stroll and visit Castillo de San José for modern art installations in an incongruously kitsch castle.</p>]]><p><b>Go underground at Cueva de los Verdes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the rabbit warren of subterranean caves and grottos at Cueva de los Verdes, where visitors will find caverns the size of cathedrals and secret <em>Lord of the Rings-</em>esque passageways. An underground world of extraordinary beauty, do expect crowds during peak season.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the green lagoon of El Golfo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of the most photographed geological sights on the island, Charco de los Clicos (green lagoon) is a natural, ochre-coloured pool made all the more spectacular by the black volcanic backdrop. The lagoons is located a short walk from the town of El Golfo, which is well-known for its delicious fish lunches.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the waves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Lanzarote's golden sands are not just for sun-seekers, you know; the island's windy coastline makes it a magnet for water sports enthusiasts. Playa Las Cucharas in Costa Teguise is a favourite with windsurfers and La Famara is where to go if you like kitesurfing. Surfing is also popular around the island.</p>]]><p><b>Slip into a different world at Jameos del Agua</b></p><![CDATA[<p>More César Manrique magic is woven into this natural underground lagoon, which has been landscaped into a fairy grotto. Spiral staircases and palm fronds lead to the shimmering, sapphire pool where tiny, blind crabs live. Tropical gardens, volcanic sculptures, an auditorium and a nightclub add to the appeal of this otherworldly attraction.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll around Jardin de Cactus</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Designed by Cesar Manrique, the Jardín de Cactus (Cactus Garden) is home to an astounding 1,420 species of cacti, which raise their spiky arms to the sky and punctuate the barren volcanic landscape. A restored windmill gives a window onto the surrounding landscape and there's a pretty café overlooking the thorny garden.</p>]]><p><b>Take in the Timple Museum</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At Casa Spinola in Teguise, there's a museum (<a href="http://casadeltimple.org" target="_blank">http://casadeltimple.org</a>) dedicated to the humble timple, a small guitar, a bit like a ukulele, that has been a traditional instrument on Lanzarote since the 18th century. The timple's greatest moment came in 2009 when musician Benito Cabrero performed a show with one at The Carnegie Hall.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the former capital</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The island's original capital, Teguise is an archetypal Lanzarote town. Uniform white, single storey cottages line narrow, bougainvillea draped alleyways, and tinkling fountains adorn cobbled plazas. Excellent artisan shops and good tapas bars abound. Join the hordes on Sunday mornings for Lanzarote's largest flea market; avoid Sundays if you'd prefer to experience the real Teguise – quiet and traditional.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Bananas, fish, tomatoes, onions and wine.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Cars, electronics, meat.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If manufacturing is scarce in the Canary Islands, it's conspicuous by its absence on Lanzarote. Having lurched from one monoculture to another during its turbulent economic  history, Lanzarote's pecuniary fortunes have run the gamut of sugar, wine, cochineal, salt and fishing before settling into its biggest ever earner – tourism.</p><p>With the island's burgeoning reputation as a sports destination, this specialised group within the tourism industry is playing an increasingly important role. Allied to tourism, the island's construction industry is showing signs of finally casting off the crippling effects of the crisis and thanks to those looking to retire to the sun, its property market is surprisingly buoyant.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If anything, Lanzarote's business people are even more laid back than those on Tenerife and Gran Canaria. You're about as likely to see a man in a suit, shirt and tie as you are an umbrella manufacturer, and business transactions are almost always conducted over a glass of wine or on the golf course.</p><p>Don't expect appointments to be set in concrete, <em>mas o menos</em> (more or less) is the mantra that applies to most aspects of life on Lanzarote and business is no exception. Equally, formal contracts are rarely issued and even more rarely enforced; business is concluded by a shake of the hand and a slap on the back.</p><p>In line with the example set by the island's favourite son, César Manrique, there's a rich vein of entrepreneurship and creativity running through Lanzarote, which has spawned thousands of self-employed businesspeople who capitalise on market opportunities wherever they crop up.</p><p>Mon-Thurs 0900-1700, Fridays 0900-1430.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Simple meat, fish and tapas dishes are the dietary default in Lanzarote. More recently, however, a handful of local chefs have observed the gastronomic revolution emanating from Tenerife and are raising the culinary bar.</p><p>As Lanzarote's lack of rainfall makes for difficult farming conditions, tropical fruits and locally grown vegetables are less abundant than on the neighbouring western islands, but what the island lacks in greens, it makes up for in white wines.</p><p>An iconic feature of the landscape, vines are grown in circular pits dug into the black, volcanic terrain and protected from prevailing winds by semi-circular stone walls. Taking moisture from low cloud and trapping it beneath the surface, the volcanic piton enables the vines to grow without irrigation, imparting its distinctive, mineral essence to the grapes that grow on its surface and producing some of the world's finest Malvasía and Moscatel wines.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fish dishes</strong>: Including <em>cherne</em> (wreckfish), s<em>ama</em> (red sea bream), <em>vieja</em> (parrotfish), <em>dorado</em> (gilt-head sea bream), <em>merluza</em> (hake), <em>pezespada</em> (swordfish), squid, sardines and tuna.<br />
<strong>Conejo al Salmorejo</strong>: Rabbit in sauce.<br />
<strong>Sancocho</strong>: A dry, salty fish stew made with bass or bream and sweet potatoes.<br />
<strong>Morcilla</strong>: Sweet black pudding, a popular starter.<br />
<strong>Bienmesabe</strong>: An almond, sugar and egg yolk dessert.<br />
<strong>Papas arrugadas con mojo</strong>: Small, salty, wrinkled potatoes served with coriander and red pepper sauce.<br />
<strong>Gofio</strong>: A flour made from toasted cereal crops, flavouring everything from soup to ice cream.<br />
<strong>Malvasia</strong>: An old world grape, producing white wine ranging from sweet to dry.<br />
<strong>Moscatel:</strong> Sweet, aromatic dessert wine.<br />
<strong>Tropical and Dorada</strong>: Local beers.<br />
<strong>Ron miel</strong>: Honey rum.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Few restaurants include a service charge in the bill. Tipping is discretionary and usually involves rounding up to a maximum of 10% in restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>By Tenerife and Gran Canaria&rsquo;s standards, Lanzarote's nightlife is less raucous. Those who hanker after a hard drinking, hip-shaking night on the tiles should head to Puerto Del Carmen, where Avenida de Las Playas, Centro Atlantico and Los Pocillos offer bountiful cabaret clubs, karaoke bars and live music.</p>
<p>As far as the local hedonists are concerned, Arrecife is where it's at. Weekends see Calle Jos&eacute; Antonio buzzing with the Latino beat emanating from its numerous bars and clubs. Drinks are cheaper than in the resorts, but with hours being strictly Spanish, a disco nap is in order to ensure you've got the energy to stay the course.</p>
<p>Costa Teguise is a more family-oriented scene with plenty of karaoke and entertainment bars lining the top of Playa Las Cucharas, while Pueblo Marinero provides pubs for the ex-pat population and visitors alike. The Lively Lady Show Bar on Avenida Islas Canaria puts on an excellent drag night.</p>
<p>In Playa Blanca everything is that little bit more laidback and the evening's entertainment tends to revolve around Marina Rubicon&rsquo;s upmarket restaurants.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Small, local markets pop up on Saturday and Sunday mornings across the island, but the largest is the Sunday morning flea market in Teguise, which attracts coachloads of visitors from across the island.</p><p>A quieter alternative is La Recover Market in Arrecife, which opens every morning except Sunday. Here shoppers will find artisan workshops and local souvenirs, with a flea market added on every Saturday. Another local bazaar worth checking out is the Haría Saturday morning market, which takes place in a leafy plaza in the centre of town.</p>
Canarian basketry, embroidered lace, Malvasía wine, aloe vera products and anything bearing the designs of Cesar Manrique are the island's most popular souvenirs. With no VAT on the island, alcohol and tobacco are also favourite purchases and you'll get far better prices in shops and supermarkets than at the airport.</p><p>Electrical stores are ubiquitous on the island with some commercial centres being almost entirely dedicated to them. Unfortunately, cheap, faulty copies abound. It pays to research UK prices before you arrive and if it seems to be good to be true, it probably is. Ensure goods are fully functioning and check guarantees and instructions thoroughly before leaving the shop.</p><p>The largest commercial centres can be found in Playa Honda and Puerto del Carmen, where fashion outlets and hypermarkets abound. More stylish and upmarket shops can be found at the Rubicon Marina in Playa Blanca, where you'll find quality local crafts along with designer labels. Most resorts offer a decent range of retail outlets providing everything holidaymakers are likely to need.</p><p>Monday to Saturday 0930-1330 and 1700-1900 are the usual hours, though Commercial Centres and shops in tourist areas tend to stay open all day until 2200. Most shops are closed on Sunday.</p><p>Lanzarote falls outside of the EU duty free allowances at Customs. Check allowances carefully to avoid paying unexpected duty on arrival back in the UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many hotels on the island, the vast majority being in the two main resorts of Corralejo in the north and Morro Jable in the south. Many belong to international chains and are block-booked by package tour operators through the busy summer and winter sun seasons.</p>
<p>Accommodation options range from room only through to all inclusive.&nbsp;Small boutique-style hotels are becoming increasingly popular on the island, particularly in the south-west.<br />
<strong><br />
</strong>All hotels in Lanzarote are graded from 1 to 5 stars, with the exception of the ultra-luxurious which are classified as 5-star GL (<em>Gran Lujo</em> or Grand Deluxe).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many hotels on the island, the vast majority being in the two main resorts of Corralejo in the north and Morro Jable in the south. Many belong to international chains and are block-booked by package tour operators through the busy summer and winter sun seasons.</p>
<p>Accommodation options range from room only through to all inclusive.&nbsp;Small boutique-style hotels are becoming increasingly popular on the island, particularly in the south-west.<br />
<strong><br />
</strong>All hotels in Lanzarote are graded from 1 to 5 stars, with the exception of the ultra-luxurious which are classified as 5-star GL (<em>Gran Lujo</em> or Grand Deluxe).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many hotels on the island, the vast majority being in the two main resorts of Corralejo in the north and Morro Jable in the south. Many belong to international chains and are block-booked by package tour operators through the busy summer and winter sun seasons.</p>
<p>Accommodation options range from room only through to all inclusive.&nbsp;Small boutique-style hotels are becoming increasingly popular on the island, particularly in the south-west.<br />
<strong><br />
</strong>All hotels in Lanzarote are graded from 1 to 5 stars, with the exception of the ultra-luxurious which are classified as 5-star GL (<em>Gran Lujo</em> or Grand Deluxe).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Canary Islands are an Autonomous Community within Spain and, although the archipelago is part of the EU, it has not signed up to the same duty free agreements.</p><p>There are, therefore, restrictions on what you can bring in and take out of the Canary Islands – even when travelling to and from other parts of the EU. The following goods may be taken into the Canary Islands by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p><p>• 200 cigarettes, 100 cigarillos, 25 cigars or 250g of other tobacco products.</p><p>• 1L of spirits.</p><p>• 2L of fortified wine (such as sherry or port), sparkling wine or any other drink that is less than 22% volume.</p><p>• In addition you may also bring back 1L of beer or 4L of still wine.</p><p>• Other goods to a value of €430.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Meat and dairy products from outside the EU, unlicensed drugs and unauthorised firearms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Endangered species require an export permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol €) = 100 cents (<em>céntimos</em>). Notes are in denominations of €500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of €2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money can be changed in any bank, and at most travel agencies, major hotels and airports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard/Cirrus and Visa/Plus are accepted in nearly all ATMs, which are common throughout the country. These credit cards can generally be used outside main towns and cities, although cash is your safest bet.</p><p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard/Cirrus and Visa/Plus are accepted in nearly all ATMs, which are common throughout the country. There are usually at least one bank and ATM in each village.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are disappearing from use fast, and it's far more convenient to travel with credit cards these days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0830-1400. Some branches open Saturdays too, from October to April.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[28.930008]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-13.658976]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>846 sq km (327 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>143,209 (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>169.3 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Arrecife.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lanzarote is the most northerly and the most easterly of the seven <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands">Canary Islands</a>. The island lies in the Atlantic Ocean approximately 125km (78 miles) off the border between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/morocco">Morocco</a> and Western Sahara, and 1,020km (634 miles) from the Iberian Peninsula. The highest point on <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mallorca/lanzarote-airport">Lanzarote</a> is Pe&ntilde;as del Chache at 670m (2,198ft).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no official religion, but the majority of the population is Roman Catholic. <br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spanish life has undergone rapid change in recent decades and many of the stricter religious customs are giving way to more modern manners, particularly in the cities and among women. In spite of this, traditions remain strong; hospitality, chivalry and courtesy thrive. <br />
<br />
Handshaking is the customary form of greeting between men, while women to whom one has already been introduced may be greeted with a fleeting kiss to either cheek. Normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home and a small gift is always appreciated. The evening meal is taken late, generally 2100-2200. The Spanish have two family names; the maternal surname follows the paternal, but is rarely used outside a formal context. <br />
<br />
Conservative casual wear is widely acceptable. A black tie is only necessary for very formal occasions and is usually specified if required. Outside resorts, scanty beachwear should be confined to beach or poolside.<br />
<br />
Smoking has long been banned in offices, shops, schools, hospitals, cultural centres and on public transport, but in 2011 that ban was extended to all bars, cafes and restaurants. Spain now has one of the toughest anti-smoking laws in Europe.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The second oldest island in the Canary archipelago after Fuerteventura, Lanzarote rose from the sea during a massive volcanic eruption some 15 million years ago.</p>
<p>Lanzarote was first inhabited from around 1000 BC by a primitive, pastoral tribe known as Majos. Constantly struggling for survival on an island short of resources, by the time the Europeans arrived the Majos had barely progressed beyond Stone Age conditions, living in caves, wearing animal skins and herding livestock.</p>
<p>In 1402 Lanzarote was claimed by Juan de B&eacute;thencourt, marking the start of the Spanish conquest. After repeated pirate raids the depleted indigenous population was in no state to resist and welcomed their conquerors hoping they would bring protection against seafaring slavers.</p>
<p>However, despite Spanish claims to the island, French and Moroccan pirates, as well as British buccaneers, continued to raid Lanzarote, inflicting misery on the handful of hardy inhabitants who remained.</p>
<p>Already hard, life on the island got much worse in 1730 when it experienced one of the longest volcanic eruptions on record. For six dark years, Timanfaya billowed ash and lava, which blocked out the sunlight and destroyed a quarter of the island.</p>
<p>However, life on Lanzarote improved immensely after the eruption, which left behind a thick layer of rich and fertile soil &ndash; a boon for local farmers, who prospered greatly by cultivating cash crops such as sugar cane, tobacco and cereal.</p>
<p>By the 1970s, Lanzarote&rsquo;s once thriving agricultural industry had fallen into decline; plantations were mothballed, production moved elsewhere. Luckily, the island&rsquo;s fledgling tourism industry was able to pick up the slack thanks to a boom in commercial air travel &ndash; the doors to mass tourism had opened and Lanzarote has never looked back.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Between 1730 and 1736, Lanzarote was under a heavy cloud of black, volcanic ash, which obscured the sun for six long years.<br />
&bull; When pirates attacked the island during the 16th and 17th centuries, locals hid in the volcanic tubes of Cueva de Los Verdes, only emerging when the coast was, quite literally, clear.<br />
&bull; In 2012 a scientific marine expedition found 15 fossilised teeth, which showed that the waters off La Graciosa were home to the largest predator that ever existed: the 20m-long (65.5ft), 100-tonne Megalodon shark, which has been extinct for approximately 3 million years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy and Consulate of the Kingdom of Spain in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2375 Pennsylvania Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20037<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Consulate General in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>20 Draycott Place<br/>London<br/>SW3 2RZ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>39 Chesham Place<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8SB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lanzarote is an island of extraordinary beauty and spectacular contrasts; a place of black deserts and white houses; limpid lagoons and rolling surf; soaring volcanoes and sweeping sandy beaches. It&rsquo;s bleak and beautiful, stark and stunning.</p>
<p>Unlike its bigger, brasher neighbours to the west &ndash; Tenerife and Grand Canaria &ndash; Lanzarote has refrained from selling out to stack-&lsquo;em-high-sell-&lsquo;em-cheap package holidays and favoured a more sustainable, intimate brand of tourism.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not devoid of big resorts and bustling beaches &ndash; with 300 days of sunshine annually the island has an obvious appeal amongst sun-seeking Europeans &ndash; but, despite this, Lanzarote has retained a traditional charm and authentic aesthetic that many find lacking elsewhere on the Canary archipelago.</p>
<p>This is thanks largely to C&eacute;sar Manrique, the late, great artist and architect who turned Lanzarote and its people onto the merits of sustainable development. Manrique is behind some of the island&rsquo;s most revered attractions; from urban murals and intriguing art installations to cosy cave bars and verdant cactus gardens.</p>
<p>Manrique&rsquo;s legacy, not to mention Lanzarote&rsquo;s stunning scenery, remain a big draw for travelling artists, who come from all over the world to visit the island. They tackle the local landscapes rather differently to the many sports enthusiasts, who come to test their mettle in what is considered to be one of Europe&rsquo;s top outdoor destinations.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s easy to see why Lanzarote has gained such a reputation; the island&rsquo;s smooth, straight roads are a veritable paradise for cyclers, while its dried lava fields and lofty hiking trails offer perfect conditions for runners and ramblers.</p>
<p>Of course, there's plenty of sand, sea and Sangria for those who want it, but ultimately, for most visitors, Lanzarote&rsquo;s appeal lies not in its opportunities for boozy beach holidays, but in its untamed natural beauty, traditional charm and strong artistic heritage, which lure many back for repeat visits.</p>Lanzarote, the most easterly of the Canary Islands, is a tidy garden of sugar-cube villages and compact resorts within a lunar landscape.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
