<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Tenerife" ColCode="tnr" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Tenerife]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tenerife has a relatively stable climate throughout the year with average daytime temperatures varying between 15°C (59°F) and 25°C (77°F). August is generally the hottest month, January and February the coolest, during which time snow can appear on the highest ground. The north of the island tends to be a little cooler with more chance of cloudy days.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight except in winter when the evenings can be cool. Warm clothing is required for visiting the mountain areas in winter.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All seven Canary Islands have their own airports. Tenerife has two; Reina Sofia in the south and Los Rodeos in the north. Most European flights land at Tenerife South airport while Tenerife North is better served by flights from mainland Spain and elsewhere in the Canaries.</p><p>Inter-island connections are served by BinterCanarias (<a href="http://www.bintercanarias.com/" target="_blank">www.bintercanarias.com</a>) and CanaryFly<em> (</em><a href="http://www.canaryfly.es/" target="_blank">www.canaryfly.es</a><em>)</em>. Although routes run between Tenerife South Airport and airports on the other islands, they are infrequent compared to the multiple daily services that depart from Tenerife North Airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>An alternative means of travelling from island to island is by ferry. Two companies operate the various routes: Lineas Fred Olsen (<a href="http://www.fredolsen.es/" target="_blank">www.fredolsen.es</a>) and Naviera Armas (<a href="http://www.naviera-armas.com/" target="_blank">www.naviera-armas.com</a>).</p><p>In Tenerife the ferry terminals are in Santa Cruz and Los Cristianos. Ferries to the western Canary Islands of La Gomera, El Hierro and La Palma operate from Los Cristianos and ferries to the eastern islands of Lanzarote, Gran Canaria and Fuerteventura depart from Santa Cruz.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no rail network in Tenerife, although a tram service operates between the northern cities of Santa Cruz and La Laguna (<a href="http://www.tranviatenerife.com/" target="_blank">www.tranviatenerife.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tenerife's established road infrastructure and clear signposting makes it an easy island to drive around. It helps to beware that local drivers use their indicators instead of hazard warning lights to warn of dangers or even to warn they will be stopping at a pedestrian crossing. Roundabouts appear to be a mystery to local drivers with most using the outside lane only.</p>r<p>Motorways and major roads are of a high standard with smooth surfaces and clear markings. Mountain roads can be narrow and winding and some surfaces can be rough, especially in more rural locations.</p><p>Taxis (tel +34 922 397 074;&nbsp;<a href="http://www.officialtaxitenerife.com" target="_blank">www.officialtaxitenerife.com</a>) are metred and regulated. They can be found in all resorts, cities, towns and even most villages across Tenerife. You can flag down taxis in the street.</p><p>Most foreign licences including Canadian, EU and US are accepted. Minimum third party insurance is compulsory. An original driving licence and proof of identity must be carried in the car at all times.</p><p>Two red hazard triangles and a reflective vest or jacket must be kept in all vehicles &ndash; the latter in the car, not in the boot. Hire cars are equipped with all necessary legal requirements. Parking laws are rigorously enforced and illegally parked cars are often towed away.</p>
<p>The speed limit for motorways is 120kph (80mph). In built-up areas it's 50kph (30mph) and on other roads it's 90kph (56mph). Speed cameras are in operation on motorways and major roads. Safety belts are compulsory front and rear. Drink driving is a serious offence in Tenerife. The legal limit is just 0.25%, equivalent to less than one pint of beer or two glasses of wine.</p><p><strong>Emergency breakdown service: </strong>Real Autom&oacute;vil Club de Espa&ntilde;a (RACE) (tel: 902 404 545; <a href="http://www.race.es/" target="_blank">www.race.es</a>).</p><p>There are more than 100 car hire companies on Tenerife including most of the major car hire companies who have offices at the two airports and in the main urban centres. Car hire is good value for money on the island and most cars are less than two years old. Drivers must be over 21 to hire a car.</p><p>Road and mountain bikes can be hired from resorts and towns across the island, but be warned; there are some very steep hills in Tenerife. Not that that bothers Britain's Olympic cycling team or Bradley Wiggins, who use the island as a training ground.</p>
<p>For something more powerful, motorcycles and mopeds are available for hire in most major towns and resorts. Riders of motorcycles over 75cc must be at least 18. Crash helmets are compulsory.</p><p>Two red hazard triangles and a reflective vest or jacket must be kept in all vehicles &ndash; the latter in the car, not in the boot. Hire cars are equipped with all necessary legal requirements. Parking laws are rigorously enforced and illegally parked cars are often towed away.</p>
<p>The speed limit for motorways is 120kph (80mph). In built-up areas it's 50kph (30mph) and on other roads it's 90kph (56mph). Speed cameras are in operation on motorways and major roads. Safety belts are compulsory front and rear. Drink driving is a serious offence in Tenerife. The legal limit is just 0.25%, equivalent to less than one pint of beer or two glasses of wine.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most coastal resorts have central pedestrianised areas. Metered taxis are readily available and taxi ranks abound. The public bus service, TITSA (<a href="http://www.titsa.com" target="_blank">www.titsa.com</a>), is a cheap and reliable way of getting around, and so is the tram that runs between Santa Cruz and La Laguna.</p><p>Bono prepaid cards offer a 50% discount on bus and tram journeys. They can be bought at any bus station or in kiosks displaying the green Bono circle.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tenerife</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">santa_cruz</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.50</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tenerife</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">reina_sofiaairport</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.15</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tenerife</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">mount_teide</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.0</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Tenerife</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">los_gigantes</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spain's national airline is Iberia (<a href="http://www.iberia.com/" target="_blank">www.iberia.com</a>), which provides frequent flights to Tenerife from mainland Spain and destinations across Europe. Budget airlines including EasyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com/" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) have frequent flights to Tenerife from across the UK.</p>
<p>Flights are cheaper and more frequent during the winter high season from September/October to March/Easter.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London to Tenerife is approximately 4 hours 20 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Tenerife Sur Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Tenerife Sur Airport is situated 62km (38 miles) south of Santa Cruz, on the island of Tenerife.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 902 404 704</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tenerife has a major port in its capital city of Santa Cruz (<a href="http://www.puertosdetenerife.org/" target="_blank">www.puertosdetenerife.org</a>) which is currently the only port of entry for goods ships and passenger liners. Plans for a second port, in Granadilla in the south east of the island, met strong local opposition on ecological grounds but should be completed by 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Emergency calls: 112. Area codes are incorporated within a nine digit number.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good throughout most of the country.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes can be found all over. Wi-Fi is usually available in hotels but costs vary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Tenerife News</em>&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.tenerifenews.com" target="_blank">www.tenerifenews.com</a>) is another English-language fortnightly paper, more orientated to the north of Tenerife whilst<em><em> </em>Living Tenerife</em>&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.livingtenerife.com" target="_blank">www.livingtenerife.com</a>) is a glossy, English-language island lifestyle magazine published monthly.<em><em> </em>El Dia</em>&nbsp;(<a href="http://eldia.es" target="_blank">http://eldia.es</a>) is a nationalistic Spanish-language daily printed in Tenerife whilst<em><em> </em>Diario de Avisos</em>&nbsp;(<a href="http://diariodeavisos.elespanol.com" target="_blank">http://diariodeavisos.elespanol.com</a>) provides a more mixed view of Canary Island news.<em><em> </em>La Opinion</em>&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.laopinion.es" target="_blank">www.laopinion.es</a>) also provides a more mixed view of the goings on in the archipelago. On the televisionTV Canaria and TV Canaria 2 are local channels for the Canary Islands. RNE radio is state-runa and operates Radio 1, Radio Clasica, Radio 3 and Radio 5. Cadena COPE is a radio station controlled by the church.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are efficient internal and international postal services (<em>correos</em>) to all countries. Airmail within Europe usually takes around five days.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the architecture at La Laguna</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The former capital and now a UNESCO World Heritage Site, La Laguna's layout was the blueprint for many Latin American cities, including Cuba. Its old quarter has fine architecture from the 16th, 17th and 18th centuries and its Cathedral has been refurbished. Excellent daily market on Plaza Cristo and some mighty fine eateries.</p>]]><p><b>Bathe in rock pools at Garachico</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Once Tenerife's wealthiest town, Garachico's fortunes were swept away by a volcanic eruption in 1706, which destroyed the harbour and buried many of its fine buildings. Today the town's rock pools, hewn from solidified lava, are popular with locals and visitors alike, and are a brilliant place to swim amongst the tropical fish.</p>]]><p><b>Climb Mount Teide</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visitors can (very nearly) reach the summit of Spain's highest peak by cable car, which runs up the side of this vast volcano (get there early to avoid queues). Take the path west to Pico Viejo for satellite views over the old crater and to see La Gomera, El Hierro and La Palma shimmering on the horizon.</p>]]><p><b>Cool off at Siam Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Siam Park is one of Europe's biggest water parks. This Thai-inspired aquatic complex has some of the highest, fastest and longest water rides in the world including a wave machine that supplies surf-sized waves alongside a white sand beach. There's also the appropriately named Tower of Power, a vertical water slide that plunges 28m (92ft) into a pool below.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Teide National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Teide National Park has a plethora of walking trails, the toughest and most rewarding being the hike up all 3,718m (12,198ft) of Mount Teide to watch the sunrise. A night in the Altavista mountain refuge avoids the need for bureaucratic permissions and presents the opportunity for stargazing.</p>]]><p><b>Get lost in underground lava caves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Formed by lava flows from the nearby Pico Viejo volcano, Cueva del Viento is a 17km (10 mile) labyrinth of underground tunnels. Located at Icod de los Vinos, the subterranean network is home to fascinating lava formations and 48 species of troglobites including blind cockroaches. Daily tours are available and reservations essential.</p>]]><p><b>Go whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>In the warm Atlantic water between Tenerife and La Gomera, pods of bottle-nosed dolphins and pilot whales gorge on a constant tide of unsuspecting fish making this one of the best places on the planet to see these cetaceans in their natural habitat. Boats go out three times daily from the harbour at Los Gigantes.</p>]]><p><b>Hike the Masca Ravine</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The village of Masca is perched on a rocky outcrop and flanked by towering massifs on the edge of the Teno Mountains. Inaccessible until the 1970s, Masca is the starting point for a challenging, three-hour trek down the Masca Ravine to the sea, where boats take weary hikers to Los Gigantes. Make sure you pick up tickets for the boat in the village before you set off.</p>]]><p><b>Imbibe culture at Candelaria</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Well off the tourist trail, charming Candelaria is the spiritual capital of Tenerife. Its landmark basilica is certainly worthy of a visit and is most notable for its murals and statue of Black Madonna. The Plaza de la Patrona is another must see, with its grand bronze statues that represent the nine kings that ruled Tenerife prior to Spanish conquest. Tapas bars and great bakeries add to the town's appeal.</p>]]><p><b>Question the history books at Guimar</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Guimar is home to Tenerife's most enigmatic and enduring mystery; ancient pyramids. Some theorists believe the Pyramids of Guimar are proof that the Egyptians could make long sea voyages and may have discovered America. Most historians dispute this theory. Whatever you believe, the pyramids make for a compelling day trip.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the waves in El Medano</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A magnet for surfers, windsurfers and kitesurfers, El Medano has the best natural beaches on the island, several of them favoured by naturists. The resort's laid back, bohemian culture and its great cafes make it an attractive alternative to the busier southwest coast resorts.</p>]]><p><b>Saunter around Puerto de la Cruz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tenerife's original resort, Puerto de la Cruz still retains its Canarian culture and roots. Photogenic plazas surrounded by bars and restaurants; a fishermen's quarter which has morphed into the town's restaurant district; and a pretty harbour hosting year-round cultural events make it worthy of a visit.</p>]]><p><b>Scuba dive at Las Galletas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The warm, clear Atlantic waters off Las Galletas conceal a submerged wonderland of volcanic arches, tunnels and caves teeming with tropical marine life and offer some of the best diving in Europe. Other excellent dive locations include Los Gigantes and Puerto de la Cruz, where you can explore the wreck of a DC3 plane crash.</p>]]><p><b>Step back in time in La Orotava</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tenerife's most aristocratic town, sited in the lush valley from which it takes its name, La Orotava has a picturesque old quarter where you can see some of the best examples of traditional balconied mansions. Pavement cafes, tapas bars, gardens and antique shops add to its colonial attractions.</p>]]><p><b>Take a city break in Santa Cruz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Capital of the western Canary Islands, the city of Santa Cruz is a great city break destination. Impressive architecture, leafy plazas bustling with cafes, art galleries and museums are all in easy strolling distance. City highlights are Parque Garcia Sanabria, Museum of Man & Nature, Plaza España and TEA art gallery. Evening entertainment centres around the trendy bars and restaurants of the Noria District.</p>]]><p><b>Trek through the Anaga Mountains</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The ancient peaks of the Anaga Mountains are perfect for a spot of hill walking. Carved by plunging ravines, peppered with white-walled hamlets and coated in lichen-dripping laurisilva forests, life in the Anagas has changed little in centuries. Challenging and dramatic, the mountains test and reward hikers in equal measure.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Blessed with fertile soil and an abundance of fish, Tenerife has always had a strong culinary tradition. But recently, its cuisine has been given a gourmet makeover by some of Spain's most exciting young chefs, who ply their trade in upmarket restaurants and five-star hotels.</p>
<p>In the resorts of the south and west, you'll find everything from full English breakfasts to Japanese sushi. For more traditional fare diners should head inland or to the north. Here they will find authentic island cuisine, which typically features grilled meat or fish accompanied by the ubiquitous <em>papas arrugadas con mojo </em>(Spanish wrinkled potatoes with traditional Canarian sauce).</p>
<p>Vegetables are usually conspicuous by their absence, turning up in stews where they supplement meat leftovers and chickpeas. Salads often run simply to fresh tomatoes and raw onions.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fish dishes</strong>: <em>Cherne</em> (wreckfish)<em>, sama</em> (red sea bream), <em>vieja</em> (parrot fish), <em>dorado</em> (gilthead sea bream), <em>lubina</em> (sea bass), <em>calamari </em>(squid), <em>at&uacute;n</em> (tuna), <em>camarones&nbsp;</em>(shrimp), <em>choco</em> (cuttlefish), <em>pulpo</em> (octopus) and sardines.<br />
<strong>Conejo al Salmorejo</strong>: Rabbit in sauce.<br />
<strong>Cabra con papas</strong>: Goat with potatoes or fries.<br />
<strong>Carne con papas</strong>: Beef with potatoes or fries.<br />
<strong>Rancho Canario</strong>: Salted ribs, chorizo, chickpea, potato and noodle stew.<br />
<strong>Ropavieja</strong>: A thick mixture of shredded chicken or beef with chickpeas, potatoes and garlic.<br />
<strong>Puchero</strong>: Chorizo sausage, bean and potato stew.<br />
<strong>Morcilla</strong>: Sweet black pudding.<br />
<strong>Papasarrugadas con mojo</strong>: Small, salty, wrinkled potatoes served with coriander and sweet red pepper sauce.<br />
<strong>Gofio</strong>: A flour made from toasted cereal crops, appearing in everything from soup to ice cream.<br />
<strong>Lecheasada</strong>: Milk flan.<br />
<strong>Arroz con leche</strong>: Rice pudding.<br />
<strong>Brumas de Ayosa</strong>: A fruity white wine produced in the south, light and refreshing.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Few restaurants include a service charge in the bill. Tipping is discretionary and usually involves rounding up the charge to around 10% in restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tenerife may have calmed down in its old age, but the island&rsquo;s hedonistic alter ego is still lured by the bright lights and pumping beats of Playa de Las Am&eacute;ricas. Now confined largely to the Veronicas and Starcos commercial centres, the clubbing resort continues to attract raucous young revellers.</p>
<p>The older crowd, meanwhile, head for Papagayo Beach Club (<a href="http://www.papagayobeachclub.es" target="_blank">www.papagayobeachclub.es</a>), where sunset cocktails segue into a night on the dance floor. Others are drawn to The Patch by karaoke, pub quizzes and jazz.</p>
<p>Locals rarely venture out before midnight, so nightclubs open late and close early in the morning. Achman Discopub in Costa Adeje is popular with locals as much as tourists and offers inexpensive drinks and Latin music.</p>
<p>Head north and you'll find a more localised party scene dominated by Latino sounds and salsa. Puerto de la Cruz is where the capital's hedonists go. Blanco Bar (<a href="http://www.blancobar.com" target="_blank">www.blancobar.com</a>) and Limbo are popular warm-up venues, and then it&rsquo;s on to Azucar for Cuban salsa music.</p>
<p>If clubbing long ceased to ring your bell, there are plenty of seafront terraces and candlelit tables where you can linger over dinner and cocktails.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The largest shopping centres are in Santa Cruz and La Laguna where visitors will find a wide range of familiar fashion outlets, hypermarkets and restaurants. In La Laguna at the Centro Commercial Santa Maria del Mar you'll also find hyper stores such as Decathlon and Ikea. In the south, Las Chafiras is the closest hypermarket to the main resorts and gets very busy from 6pm.</p>
<p>For a more artisanal experience, drop in on one of the small, local markets which pop up on Saturday and Sunday mornings across the island. Amongst the most popular are the Sunday morning flea market near Se&ntilde;ora de Africa Market in Santa Cruz; the Costa Adeje Thursday and Saturday morning markets (opposite Costa Adeje Gran Hotel) and the Los Cristianos Sunday and Tuesday morning market (alongside Arona Gran Hotel). You'll find a wide selection of arts, crafts and clothing at these markets.</p>
<p><strong>For fresh</strong> fruit and vegetables, honey, cheeses and fine local wines, head to one of the island&rsquo;s famers&rsquo; markets. The best are in Plaza del Cristo, La Laguna every morning and Thursday evenings; Tacoronte (on the Tejina road) every Saturday and Sunday morning; and at the Se&ntilde;ora de Africa Market in Santa Cruz every morning until 1400.</p>
<p>With no VAT on the island, alcohol and tobacco are most people's favourite buys and you'll get far better prices in shops and supermarkets than at the airport. Cameras and IT are also good buys, but it pays to research prices before you arrive. Only use large, established companies such as Visanta, and check guarantees, instructions and merchandise thoroughly before leaving the shop.</p><p>Most department stores and supermarkets are open Monday to Saturday 1000-2200 and closed on Sundays and festivals. Outside of the resorts and in traditional towns smaller shops still observe the siesta, closing between 13.30 and 17.30pm.</p><p>As Tenerife is a VAT free island it falls outside of the EU duty free allowances at Customs. Check allowances carefully to avoid paying unexpected duty on arrival back in the UK.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are literally hundreds of hotels in Tenerife, most of them located in the southern coastal resorts. Many belong to international chains and are block-booked by package tour operators through the busy summer and Christmas seasons. Accommodation options range from room only through to all inclusive.<br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> Hotels and <em>pensiones</em> in Tenerife are graded from 1 to 5 stars, with the exception of the ultra-luxurious which are classified as 5-star GL (<em>Gran Lujo</em> or Grand Deluxe).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><em>Pensions </em>are family-run guest houses. In Tenerife they usually offer basic facilities on a bed and board-only basis.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are literally hundreds of hotels in Tenerife, most of them located in the southern coastal resorts. Many belong to international chains and are block-booked by package tour operators through the busy summer and Christmas seasons. Accommodation options range from room only through to all inclusive.<br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> Hotels and <em>pensiones</em> in Tenerife are graded from 1 to 5 stars, with the exception of the ultra-luxurious which are classified as 5-star GL (<em>Gran Lujo</em> or Grand Deluxe).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are literally hundreds of hotels in Tenerife, most of them located in the southern coastal resorts. Many belong to international chains and are block-booked by package tour operators through the busy summer and Christmas seasons. Accommodation options range from room only through to all inclusive.<br /><strong><br />Grading:</strong> Hotels and <em>pensiones</em> in Tenerife are graded from 1 to 5 stars, with the exception of the ultra-luxurious which are classified as 5-star GL (<em>Gran Lujo</em> or Grand Deluxe).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Canary Islands are an Autonomous Community within Spain and, although the archipelago is part of the EU, it has not signed up to the same duty free agreements.</p><p>There are, therefore, restrictions on what you can bring in and take out of the Canary Islands – even when travelling to and from other parts of the EU. The following goods may be taken into the Canary Islands by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p><p>• 200 cigarettes, 100 cigarillos, 25 cigars or 250g of other tobacco products.</p><p>• 1L of spirits.</p><p>• 2L of fortified wine (such as sherry or port), sparkling wine or any other drink that is less than 22% volume.</p><p>• In addition you may also bring back 1L of beer or 4L of still wine.</p><p>• Other goods to a value of €430.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Meat and dairy products from outside the EU, unlicensed drugs and unauthorised firearms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Endangered species require an export permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol €) = 100 cents (<em>céntimos</em>). Notes are in denominations of €500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of €2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money can be changed in any bank, and at most travel agencies, major hotels and airports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard/Cirrus and Visa/Plus are accepted in nearly all ATMs, which are common throughout the country. These credit cards can generally be used outside main towns and cities, although cash is your safest bet.</p><p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard/Cirrus and Visa/Plus are accepted in nearly all ATMs, which are common throughout the country. There are usually at least one bank and ATM in each village.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are disappearing from use fast, and it's far more convenient to travel with credit cards these days. Nevertheless, you can still change them in main bank branches and exchange bureaux, and they are accepted in major hotels. It is advisable to bring them in sterling or dollars as there have been increasing reports of Euro cheques being refused.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0830-1400. Some branches open Saturdays too, from October to April.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[28.291564]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-16.629130]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,034 sq km (785 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>888,184 (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>436.7 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Santa Cruz de Tenerife.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tenerife is the largest of the seven <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands">Canary Islands</a> and lies in the Atlantic Ocean approximately 320km (200 miles) off the border between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/morocco">Morocco</a> and Western Sahara, and 1,300km (812 miles) from the Iberian Peninsula. At its centre is Mount Teide, the highest point in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a> at 3,718m (12,198ft).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no official religion, but the majority of the population is Roman Catholic. <br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spanish life has undergone rapid change in recent decades and many of the stricter religious customs are giving way to modernity, particularly in the cities and among women. In spite of this, traditions remain strong; hospitality, chivalry and courtesy thrive. Handshaking is the customary form of greeting between men, while women to whom one has already been introduced may be greeted with a fleeting kiss to either cheek. Normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home and a small gift is always appreciated. Conservative casual wear is widely acceptable.<br />
<br />
The evening meal is taken late, generally 2100-2200. Smoking has long been banned in offices, shops, schools, hospitals, cultural centres and on public transport, but in 2011 that ban was extended to all bars, cafes and restaurants. Spain now has one of the toughest anti-smoking laws in Europe.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Although territorially belonging to Spain, Tenerife and the Canary Islands have many similarities to the Americas. Before their invasion by the Spanish in the 15th century, the islands were populated by a race of fishermen and farmers probably related to the North African Berbers.</p>
<p>The new settlers quickly planted sugarcane which thrived in the tropical climate of the north of Tenerife and soon brought financial rewards. A near-perfect climate, an alluring landscape and the prospect of new horizons attracted merchants, artisans and holy orders in their droves. In the 17th century, when the sugar trade was undercut by cheaper production in the Antilles, vines were planted and Tenerife's Malmsey wine became the best in the world.</p>
<p>Strategically placed at the crossroads between Europe and the New World, Tenerife became a frontier land, grown rich with the spoils of trade and a constant target for every brigand, pirate and navy man working in the Atlantic Ocean, including one Admiral Nelson who lost his arm during an unsuccessful attempt on the capital in 1797.</p>
<p>But when market forces drove crops into decline and hunger followed, it was to the new American colonies that much of the population fled, seeking work and an escape from hunger. It was Tinerfe&ntilde;os (natives of Tenerife) who, in the 19th century, founded the cities of Montevideo in Uruguay and San Antonio in Texas. Others fled to Cuba and Argentina, returning to their homeland once they&rsquo;d made their fortunes.</p>
<p>In the late 19th century banana production was introduced to Tenerife and remains the largest single food export, its giant leaves adorning plantations across the island. In economic terms, however, agriculture has long since played second fiddle to the new cash crop of tourism.</p>
<p>In 1936 when a commander-in-chief of the Spanish army was suspected of plotting to overthrow the government, he was posted to Tenerife as Governor of the Canary Islands to keep him out of the way. The plan didn't work, and it was from here that General Francisco Franco launched his offensive that began the Spanish Civil War.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; As part of his annual salary, William Shakespeare was paid with one barrel of wine from Tenerife.<br />
&bull; The whodunnit writer Agatha Christie wrote much of <em>The Mystery on the Blue Train </em>while holidaying in Tenerife.<br />
&bull; Queen&rsquo;s hit song <em>Tie Your Mother Down </em>was written by Brian May while he was studying astronomy in Tenerife.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy and Consulate of the Kingdom of Spain in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2375 Pennsylvania Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20037<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Consulate General in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>20 Draycott Place<br/>London<br/>SW3 2RZ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>39 Chesham Place<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8SB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tenerife is undergoing something of a metamorphosis. Long synonymous with crass commercialism, the island has been pursuing a more discerning clientele in a bid to confine its pies, fries, and beer image to the history books.</p>
<p>Offering a closer and cost-effective alternative to the Caribbean, its verdant peaks and sandy shores are indeed attracting more refined pilgrims; those who come in search of sun and solace, rather than cheap booze and casual sex.</p>
<p>The hotel scene is changing, too. Once dominated by pile-them-high-and-sell-them-cheap apartments, the island&rsquo;s accommodation offering has been enhanced by luxury resorts, where guests can practice yoga on manicured beaches, tee-off overlooking the Atlantic or go horse riding in the surf.</p>
<p>In line with its image change, Tenerife's gastronomic scene is also experiencing a revolution. Promenades still tempt sunbathers with all day British breakfasts and cheap beer, but in hotel dining rooms and chic restaurants a culinary movement is gathering pace. The island's excellent wines are also finding a new faithful amongst the tippling cognoscenti of Europe.</p>
<p>Tenerife, the largest and most populous of the Canary Islands, was formed in the aftermath of a mighty volcanic eruption. Mount Teide is a reminder of its fiery past, looming large over the island.&nbsp;</p>
<p>A UNESCO World Heritage Site, Teide is the third largest volcano in the world and, while she sleeps a deep slumber, she remains active. During the winter her obsidian flanks turn white with snow and in spring her dark surface is streaked scarlet by the dazzling spikes of tajinaste plants.</p>
<p>Mother Nature's less explosive contributions include the mountain rainforests of Anaga; the sandy beaches of El Medano; and the vertiginous cliffs of Los Gigantes in the wild west.</p>
<p>Bathed in year-round sunshine and possessing an impressive diversity of landscapes and micro climates, visitors to Tenerife can go from snowboarding to surfing in the space of a few hours and still have time to sip fine wine over a scarlet sunset and stargaze in some of the world's clearest skies.</p>Painted with the most luxuriant greens, the deepest blues and a technicolour palette of exotic foliage, Tenerife is much more than a resort destination.]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
