<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Mallorca" ColCode="mlr" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="es" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Mallorca]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The island enjoys a temperate, Mediterranean climate. The height of summer can get very hot &ndash; in excess of 40&deg;C - but the cooling influence of the sea means it's seldom excessively uncomfortable or humid. Summer is the busiest time of the year and prices are at their highest in July and August. During the rest of the year Mallorca has an ideal climate, with comfortable temperatures in the mid- to high-twenties during the spring and autumn months. Combined with fewer visitors and lower hotel prices, this makes for the best time to visit and is also the best time for outdoor activities such as cycling and hiking holidays. The climate during the winter is generally mild and dry with occasional showers, making Mallorca an ideal winter getaway. The shoulder seasons (April-May and September-October) are generally the perfect time to get the best of the weather and to avoid the crowds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The summer months are extremely hot so lightweight clothing is needed. Long-sleeved cotton tops are recommended as they protect from the fierce sun, especially for sightseeing or activities. Autumn and spring attire should be medium-weight clothing, mainly layers, with some light rainwear, while the winters can be cold so a good jacket, scarf and gloves might be necessary.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no domestic flights within Mallorca.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many companies offering sightseeing day cruises from all major resorts around the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Fast, efficient, affordable train services run between Palma (Plaza Espaňa) and Inca, stopping at towns such as Santa Maria, Binissalem and Festival Park shopping outlet. There are also connections between Inca and Sa Pobla and Manacor. Schedules and fares can be found at <a target="_blank" href="http://www.tib.org">www.tib.org</a>. A short metro line connects Palma city centre to the university.</p>
<p>The S&oacute;ller railway (<a href="http://www.trendesoller.com">www.trendesoller.com</a>), an antique wooden train aimed at tourists, runs from Palma to S&oacute;ller several times a day.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Road is the main form of transport in Mallorca. Three motorways connect Palma and the airport with other parts of the island, notably the north.</p>
<p>Use of the horn is common, and it's also common practice for drivers to temporarily stop their vehicles in the street with hazard lights on as a warning. Foreign drivers should note that pedestrian crossings are denoted by black and white lines (not flashing orange lights).</p>r<p>Road quality is generally good, although steep, narrow mountain routes can make it difficult for coaches and cars to pass other than at special points. Heavy traffic congestion is rare.</p><p>Getting around by bus is easy, efficient and cheap. Buses serve almost all towns and villages, although services are limited in rural areas. Palma&rsquo;s main bus station is located adjacent to the train station in Plaza Espaňa. The number 1 bus connects Palma and the airport. See <a href="http://www.emtpalma.es" target="_blank">www.emtpalma.es</a> for bus routes.</p><p>Taxis are a safe and popular way of getting to and from the airport, as well as around Palma. Taxis can be hailed from the street or telephoned, and all use a meter.</p><p>You will need your national driving licence and a credit card.</p><p>Seatbelts are compulsory.</p><p>Break down services are usually provided by individual car hire companies. If not, try Real Autom&oacute;vil Club de Espanya (RACE) (tel: 902 300 505; <a target="_blank" href="http://www.race.es">www.race.es</a>).</p><p>Car hire is available from Palma airport and in all the resorts. Major international and (often cheaper) local firms operate. The minimum age of car hire is 18, but most companies hire only to over 21s.</p><p>Scooters and motorbikes are available for hire, but check this doesn't invalidate your health insurance. Cycling is a popular way to explore the island.</p><p>Seatbelts are compulsory.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most people arrive in Mallorca by air, and the large Palma de Mallorca Airport (PMI) caters to the millions of tourists that arrive from across Europe every year. Spain's national airline is Iberia (IB) (<a href="http://www.iberia.com" target="_blank">www.iberia.com</a>), and while they offer competitive prices on domestic routes, budget, low-cost and charter airlines form the bulk of European carriers to the island.</p>
<p>There are regular international flights to Mallorca from all over Europe, with many carriers offering multiple flights a day during the summer peak season. Scheduled carriers from the UK include Easyjet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>),&nbsp;Flybe (<a href="http://www.flybe.com" target="_blank">www.flybe.com</a>) and British Airways (www.ba.com), while Thomas Cook (<a href="http://www.thomascook.com" target="_top">www.thomascook.com</a>) a charter company also sells&nbsp;seats in the summer. Air Europa (<a href="http://www.air-europa.com" target="_blank">www.air-europa.com</a>), Iberia (<a href="http://www.iberia.com" target="_blank">www.iberia.com</a>), Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) and Air Berlin (<a href="http://www.airberlin.com" target="_blank">www.airberlin.com</a>) fly between the islands and mainland Spain as well as further afield to other European destinations. There are many flights a day to Barcelona from where it is possible to connect to and from worldwide destinations.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London to Palma is around 2 hours 15 minutes, while Manchester is approximately 2 hours 45 minutes. The flight time to Barcelona is around 30 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On entering Palma de Mallorca from the UK it is necessary to go through passport control as the UK is not within the Schengen Agreement. Those travelling to and from most other EU destinations do not need to go through passport control.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Departure taxes are included in the price of airline tickets and therefore nothing further needs to be paid at the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>On entering Palma de Mallorca from the UK it is necessary to go through passport control as the UK is not within the Schengen Agreement. Those travelling to and from most other EU destinations do not need to go through passport control.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Palma de Mallorca Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Palma de Mallorca Airport is located 8km (5 miles) east of Palma de Mallorca.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 91 321 1000</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mallorca has long been a Mediterranean centre of yachting, and every year many hundreds of people arrive on cruise ships, by ferry, or on private superyachts, charter vessels and small private boats.</p>
<p>There are countless ports and marinas around the island, the main commercial ones being located in Palma and Alc&uacute;dia. For private vessels, marinas such as Puerto Portals and Port Adriano offer a range of facilities, and there are dozens of marinas catering to small craft.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Emergency calls: 112. Area codes are incorporated within a nine digit number.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good throughout the island. <br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Internet cafes are growing increasingly rare. Hotels usually offer Wi-Fi, and it's becoming more common in cafes and public areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mallorca has newspapers in several languages, the main ones being the <em>Diari de Balears</em> (a Catalan-language newspaper based in Palma), <em>Diario de Mallorca</em> (the main Spanish-language daily newspaper) and the <em>Majorca Daily Bulletin</em>, Spain's oldest English-language newspaper, which is also online at <a href="http://majorcadailybulletin.com" target="_blank">http://majorcadailybulletin.com</a>. There are several radio stations in Spanish and English throughout the islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are domestic and international postal services (<em>correos</em>) to all countries, although postal services are not as reliable as on the mainland. Airmail within Europe takes around five days. The main post office in Palma is at Cerrer de Constitucio 5. All the main courier companies are represented on the island including FedEx and DHL.</p><p>Post Office opening hours are usually Mon-Fri 0800-1200 and 1700-1930. In Palma major post offices open throughout the day and limited hours on Saturday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Admire the palimpsest Palau de l'Almudaina</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Originally home to Mallorca's Moorish rulers and expanded for the Catalan kings, the "palace of the citadel" in Palma is a graceful mix of Moorish, Gothic and Renaissance styles. It was an official island residence of King Juan Carlos I before his abdication in 2015. The gardens and fountains are beautiful.</p>]]><p><b>Ascend to Castell de Bellver for an unbeatable view</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This unusual, round, 14th-century castle surrounded by forests and paths offers breath-taking views of Palma de Mallorca. Formerly a royal residence it now houses an excellent museum, including a collection of classical sculptures. The castle is located on a hill above the city and is a major feature of Palma's skyline.</p>]]><p><b>Browse Inca Market</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Weekly town markets are an important part of Mallorcan life, and Inca's market is one of the biggest. Stalls fill the town centre where everything from toys to flowers to fruit and vegetables are sold. It's most famous for its leather goods including wallets, belts, bags and shoes.</p>]]><p><b>Cap de Formentor</b></p><![CDATA[<p>At Mallorca's easternmost pinnacle lies the Formentor cape, one of the most picturesque parts of the island. Tall cliffs dip into deep blue seas, sporadic pine trees grow along its shore and seabirds swoop overhead. A winding road weaves along the coast here, providing the most spectacular views.</p>]]><p><b>Climb the La Sierra de Tramuntana</b></p><![CDATA[<p>La Sierra de Tramuntana Mountains run ragged across Mallorca's northern coast, offering scintillating views and challenging bike rides, with a diverse mix of <em>calas</em> and rocky outcrops dotted along the way. Steep cliffs drop into the blue sea below and picturesque villages such as Deiá perch on the mountainsides.</p>]]><p><b>Explore Palma de Mallorca's old town</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The long and multi-faceted history of Palma is well preserved by its old city, where cobbled streets, stout city walls, grand courtyards and gothic buildings beg to be explored. Busy shopping streets, grand squares, pavement cafés, chic restaurants, trendy bars and a flourishing art scene bustle with locals and tourists alike.</p>]]><p><b>Explore the idyllic village of Valldemosa</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Tucked high in the Tramuntana Mountains is the quaint, cobbled-lane village of Valldemosa. At its heart is the medieval Royal Monastery complex (the Real Cartoixa), which is associated with the French writer George Sand and composer Frédéric Chopin, who shared a room here in 1838-39. It's a magical little town in a beautiful setting.</p>]]><p><b>Get a taste of farm life at La Granja</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This rural <em>finca </em>(farm) in the mountains is surrounded by tranquil gardens and has been beautifully preserved to show a traditional Mallorcan working farm. La Granja hosts craft demonstrations and folk dancing (Wednesday and Friday afternoons). There are also displays of antique furnishings, costumes, food tasting and farm animals.</p>]]><p><b>Go on pilgrimage to Santuari de Lluc</b></p><![CDATA[<p>High up in the Tramuntana Mountains is Lluc monastery, Mallorca's most famous pilgrimage destination. Since the 13th century, pious Catholics and others have made their way here to pay homage to La Moreneta, "the little dark one", a statue of the Virgin Mary. There is also a simple but unique hostel inside the monastery.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the dancefloor</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Although the Balearic Islands have started to move on from their party image in recent years, they still attract many visitors keen on irreverent nightlife. There are several "super clubs" in Mallorca, many of them in Palma's trendy Paseo Maritimo district. And if all else fails, there's always Magaluf.</p>]]><p><b>Pay homage to Robert Graves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>One of Britain's most famous war poets, after a tumultuous life in the trenches – and a somewhat colourful life in London – the venerable writer moved to Deiá, a sleepy Mallorcan village where he wrote his most celebrated works. Fans can explore his rambling villa, which is home to a small but informative museum, and visit the late poet's grave in the nearby cemetery.</p>]]><p><b>Practice watersports around the island</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The crystal waters encircling Mallorca are perfect for sports. The island is a popular yachting destination, while the warm sea is ideal for swimming, snorkelling, diving or kayaking. Day boat cruises are a great way to see the coast and there are many excursions that can be booked locally.</p>]]><p><b>Ride the Palma Sóller Railway</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Palma Sóller Railway is the best way to get to the charming, traditional town of Sóller, nestled amongst the Tramuntana Mountains. The vintage wooden 1912 locomotive makes a scenic 27km (16.7 miles) trip through mountains, forests and olive and orange groves offering spectacular scenic views of rural Mallorca.</p>]]><p><b>Visit S 'Albufera Nature Reserve</b></p><![CDATA[<p>S 'Albufera Nature Reserve in Alcúdia bay is a large tranquil area of marshy coastline formed by lakes, and natural and artificial canals. The park is home to 200 species of bird, a huge variety of plants and wildflowers, insects, fish, and some unusual amphibians, reptiles and mammals.</p>]]><p><b>Walk into a fairy-tale at Cuevas del Drach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Walk through the fairy-tale world of the "dragon's cave" on the island's northeast coast. You'll pass fantastically shaped stalagmites, beneath a million needle-shaped stalactites, before reaching an amphitheatre for the grand climax – an unforgettable classical concert on an underground lake. The tour is guided in several languages.</p>]]><p><b>Wander dozens of beaches and coves</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Mallorca's coastline is pocketed with natural coves, whose clear sparkling waters attract sailboats, traditional fishing boats and are perfect for swimming in. Of these Cala Pi, Cala D'Or and Sa Calobra are particularly beautiful. Golden beaches can be found all around the island. Some especially attractive ones are Es Trenc, Alcúdia and Sa Coma.</p>]]><p><b>Wonder at the astonishing Palma Cathedral</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The cathedral is a splendid example of Gothic architecture, remarkable for its vast size and stained glass windows. Construction began 1306 and continued for four centuries. It was remodelled by Gaudí from 1902 to 1914. Beautifully illuminated at night, the cathedral is Palma de Mallorca's most famous landmark.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>$1.303 trillion (Spain) (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Olive oil, almonds, potatoes and fruit.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, fuels, chemicals, semi-finished goods and food. (Spain)/</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Germany, Italy, UK and Portugal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Tourism forms the core of Mallorca&rsquo;s economy, with most of its tourists arriving from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/germany">Germany</a>, the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> and Scandinavia. In addition, construction businesses plus the buying and selling of properties and businesses such as restaurants, bars, hotels and shops accounts for a substantial part of the economy. Farming accounts for much of what remains with almonds, potatoes, olive oil, fruit and wine being the main exports. Palma is the commercial centre of the island.</p>
<p>Mallorca is a relatively wealthy part of the nation and it is estimated that the island GDP per head is more than 50% above the Spanish average.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mallorcans in general dress well and especially so when conducting business. Smart attire is expected, including suits for men and skirts or trouser suits for women. English is widely spoken in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/palma">Palma</a> and the resorts but less so elsewhere. Some knowledge of the Spanish language (and perhaps Catalan/Mallorqu&iacute;n) is always appreciated and sometimes essential. Punctuality is important. Greetings are by way of a handshake if you haven&rsquo;t met before (or between men) and a kiss on both cheeks for women.</p><p>Tend to vary but base hours of 0900-1330 and 1400-1800 are fairly typical. During the height of summer shops in Palma tend to stay open until 2000 or 2100. Many offices close throughout August or operate much shorter working hours.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Mallorca Chamber of Commerce (Cámara de Comercio)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 971 710 188
					Website:http://www.cambramallorca.com
					Address: ,Calle Estudi General 7,,]]><b>Mallorca Convention Bureau (FEMP)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 
					Website:http://www.mallorcacb.com
					Address: ,,,]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Mallorcan food is typically hearty fare, with meats and stews showing up on most menus as well as the popular suckling pig. Being an island, seafood is understandably a common staple, with monkfish and sea bream served up in all manner of sauces. Following the Spanish tradition, tapas (a selection of small dishes) are often served as starters, or as a lighter meal.</p><p>Eating out in Mallorca, as in the rest of Spain, is an important part of life. Evening meals are taken late, usually after 2100, and it is not uncommon to see families sitting down for a meal at 2230, especially in summer.</p><p>On Saturday mornings, Palma's traditional indoor food markets such as Mercado Olivar and Mercado Santa Catalina are teeming with the city's trendy residents who enjoy fresh oysters and champagne amidst the bustling fish stalls.</p><p>House wines are usually of good quality and extremely well priced. Local wines such as Jose Ferrer and Macias Batle are excellent.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Coca de patata</strong>: Sweet bread-like bun made from potato flour and dusted with icing sugar.<br />
<strong>Sobrasada</strong>: Soft, spreadable red chorizo-like sausage, typically spicy.<br />
<strong>Sopas Mallorquinas</strong>: Mallorcan stew made from liver or seafood with vegetables and potatoes.<br />
<strong>Tumbet</strong>: Baked dish of layered potato, courgette, aubergine and tomato sauce.<br />
<strong>Pa amboli</strong>: A snack of bread and olive oil often supplemented by island cheese, jam&oacute;n (cured ham), or chorizo.<br />
<strong>Lomo con col</strong>: Pork wrapped in cabbage leaves.<br />
<strong>Suckling pig</strong>: Typically roasted.<br />
<strong>Parrillada depescado</strong>: Mixed grilled fish and seafood platter.<br />
<strong>Gat&oacute; de almendras</strong>: A very traditional spongy cake made with almonds.<br />
<strong>Ensaimada</strong>: Spiral-shaped cake, dusted with icing sugar sometimes filled with cream or jam.<br />
<strong>Herbes de Mallorca</strong>: Aromatic herby liqueur.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Around 10% in restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Mallorca is famous for its nightlife, which ranges from sophisticated in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/palma">Palma</a> to notorious in Magaluf. All the main resorts have a good selection of clubs and bars.</p>
<p>Hundreds of small, trendy, unusual bars are scattered throughout the old city of Palma, and come the weekend most are in full swing. For something more refined, Puerto Portals on the south coast offers a swanky selection of bars and restaurants which cater to the yachting elite.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In Palma, locals tend to start the evening late and finish in the early hours of the morning. After a late meal on a Friday or Saturday night, young Mallorcans will head to the bars around midnight, and on to clubs no earlier than 0200. <br />
<br />
For the latest news on the local nightlife, and details of current events in Mallorca, see the local English-language newspaper, the <em>Majorca Daily Bulletin </em>(<a href="https://majorcadailybulletin.com" target="_blank">http://majorcadailybulletin.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a strong tradition of craftsmanship on Mallorca, and many visitors enjoy taking some traditional crafts home with them. Solid wood furniture, hand-embroidered works, brightly coloured hand-painted ceramics, carved olive-wood, wrought ironwork, blown glassware, items made from raffia and palm leaves, handmade shoes and pearls are all of high quality. Indeed, Mallorca is particularly well-known for its leather products, and shoes, belts, handbags and wallets can be bought in specialist shops throughout <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/palma">Palma</a> or at the leather market in Inca on Thursday mornings (which also sells many other handicrafts and goods) &ndash; the market is the largest on the island.</p>
<p>Mallorcans love to shop and Palma&rsquo;s old city streets are bursting with boutiques, high street shops, big name brands and designer goods. The main streets are Jaime III (where you will find designer boutiques) and Carrer del Sindicat, Carrer de Sant Miguel and other streets radiating off Plaza Mayor. The main Avinguda d&rsquo;Alexandre Rossell&oacute; street that has many high street shops as well as a large branch of El Corte Ingl&eacute;s, an upmarket department store.</p>
<p>The markets are always a draw for visitors to the island, and most of the larger villages or towns have one. Apart from Inca, Santa Maria has a big Sunday market as does Sineu on Wednesdays. While some of the traditional items have been lost from these markets, and there are more commercial imported clothes sold than before, they are a great place to buy artisan cheeses, meats and fruit and vegetables, as well as pottery and artisan products.</p><p>Traditional shopping hours are Monday to Saturday 0900-1400 and 1700-2000. Supermarkets and department stores are open 1000-2200. Big shopping centres and tourist shops also open on Sundays, as are the big shops along Jaime III in Palma.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With millions of tourists visiting Mallorca every year, there are thousands of hotels all across the island. All resorts have good quality hotels which are usually 3 and 4-starred, offering swimming pools and good facilities. These types of hotels tend to be reasonably-priced, especially in off-season periods where there is less demand. Many sizeable hotels and apartments in the resorts tend to be block-booked by package tour operators.</p>
<p>High quality 5-star hotels are also in abundance, with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/palma">Palma</a> playing host to many of these top establishments. There are also some famous 5-star hotels on other parts of the island which exude opulence and class.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Lower-starred hotels and hostels are less common because of the availability of well-priced hotels, but there is a handful of <em>pensiones</em> and hostels in Palma and in scenic spots around the island which cater for budget travellers. Monastery stays offer basic rooms, but a unique (and very tranquil) experience with some of the most spectacular views on the island.</p>
<p><em>Agriturismo </em>(rural tourism) has seen an incredible boom in the last few years, and today there are some beautiful, traditional and very high quality rural hotels scattered across the island. Offering sumptuous rooms, fine dining, often spas and access to pristine countryside or idyllic villages, they are an ideal way to get away from the crowds and enjoy rural Mallorca.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Bed and breakfasts in the traditional sense are relatively rare in Mallorca, probably due to the abundance of other accommodation options. In some of the towns and villages that cater to tourists (such as Sóller) it is possible to find one or two bed and breakfasts.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With millions of tourists visiting Mallorca every year, there are thousands of hotels all across the island. All resorts have good quality hotels which are usually 3 and 4-starred, offering swimming pools and good facilities. These types of hotels tend to be reasonably-priced, especially in off-season periods where there is less demand. Many sizeable hotels and apartments in the resorts tend to be block-booked by package tour operators.</p>
<p>High quality 5-star hotels are also in abundance, with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/palma">Palma</a> playing host to many of these top establishments. There are also some famous 5-star hotels on other parts of the island which exude opulence and class.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Lower-starred hotels and hostels are less common because of the availability of well-priced hotels, but there is a handful of <em>pensiones</em> and hostels in Palma and in scenic spots around the island which cater for budget travellers. Monastery stays offer basic rooms, but a unique (and very tranquil) experience with some of the most spectacular views on the island.</p>
<p><em>Agriturismo </em>(rural tourism) has seen an incredible boom in the last few years, and today there are some beautiful, traditional and very high quality rural hotels scattered across the island. Offering sumptuous rooms, fine dining, often spas and access to pristine countryside or idyllic villages, they are an ideal way to get away from the crowds and enjoy rural Mallorca.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With millions of tourists visiting Mallorca every year, there are thousands of hotels all across the island. All resorts have good quality hotels which are usually 3 and 4-starred, offering swimming pools and good facilities. These types of hotels tend to be reasonably-priced, especially in off-season periods where there is less demand. Many sizeable hotels and apartments in the resorts tend to be block-booked by package tour operators.</p>
<p>High quality 5-star hotels are also in abundance, with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/palma">Palma</a> playing host to many of these top establishments. There are also some famous 5-star hotels on other parts of the island which exude opulence and class.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Lower-starred hotels and hostels are less common because of the availability of well-priced hotels, but there is a handful of <em>pensiones</em> and hostels in Palma and in scenic spots around the island which cater for budget travellers. Monastery stays offer basic rooms, but a unique (and very tranquil) experience with some of the most spectacular views on the island.</p>
<p><em>Agriturismo </em>(rural tourism) has seen an incredible boom in the last few years, and today there are some beautiful, traditional and very high quality rural hotels scattered across the island. Offering sumptuous rooms, fine dining, often spas and access to pristine countryside or idyllic villages, they are an ideal way to get away from the crowds and enjoy rural Mallorca.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[39.695263]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[3.017571]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>3,640 sq km (1,405 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>882,964 (INE value 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>236.1 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Palma de Mallorca.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parliamentary monarchy since 1978.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Located in the middle of the Mediterranean Sea, approximately 210km (130 miles) south of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/barcelona">Barcelona</a> and 300km (185 miles) north of the African continent (<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/algeria">Algeria</a>), Mallorca has an idyllic geographical setting. Measuring 3,640 sq km (1,405 sq miles), it is the largest of the four <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/balearic-islands">Balearic Islands</a>&nbsp;(<a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/balearic-islands/ibiza">Ibiza</a> and Formentera to the west and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/balearic-islands/menorca">Menorca</a> to the east) and has a hugely varied landscape.</p>
<p>Its main geographical feature is the Sierra de Tramuntana mountain range, which extends from the southwest to northeast of the island over 70km (44 miles), the highest peak being Puig Major at 1,445m (4,741ft). The coast is mainly rocky, pocketed with small coves, sandy beaches and caves. Three large bays provide shelter from the open seas &ndash; Palma Bay, Alc&uacute;dia Bay and Pollensa Bay. The interior of the island is covered with lush pine forest, olive and almond trees, and in the central plains agricultural terrain and vineyards.</p>
<p>Protected nature reserves are important for wildlife, the most significant of these being the Cabrera Island Marine Reserve and the S&rsquo;Albufera Nature Reserve near Alc&uacute;dia. There are hundreds of bird species that call Mallorca home, although wild mammals are today rare, the main exception being the wild goat that can be seen in the mountainous regions.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no official religion, but the majority of the population is Roman Catholic. Much of the population is practicing, and Sunday church visits and holy communions play an important part of daily life.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spanish life has undergone rapid change in recent decades and many of the stricter religious customs are giving way to modernity, particularly in the cities and among women. In spite of this, traditions remain strong; hospitality, chivalry and courtesy thrive. Handshaking is the customary form of greeting between men, while women to whom one has already been introduced may be greeted with a fleeting kiss to either cheek. Normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home and a small gift is always appreciated.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The evening meal is taken late, generally 2100-2200, and bars and nightclubs don&rsquo;t get busy until the small hours of the morning. A law banning smoking in offices, shops, schools, hospitals, cultural centres and on public transport was introduced on 1 January 2006, although smoking in bars and restaurants was not strongly prohibited until 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. Generally, European plugs with two round pins are in use.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy since 2011.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Felipe VI since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Owing to its central location on the ancient Mediterranean trading route, the island of Mallorca has seen its share of conquerors, invaders and settlers over the centuries.</p>
<p>The first settlers are dated to at least 3000 BC, but this was small scale. Later the Greeks and the Phoenicians set up trading posts on the island, which then became part of the Carthaginian trading empire from North Africa. But it wasn&rsquo;t until the Roman period that the island was settled in any great numbers.</p>
<p>In 123 BC the Romans conquered the island, and for almost 600 years Mallorca&rsquo;s life and prosperity was intricately linked with Rome. Two main centres emerged, Pollentia (today Alc&uacute;dia) and Palma.</p>
<p>In the 5th century AD, Mallorca (and the other Balearic islands) were conquered by the Vandal Kingdom of Africa, who demolished much of the Roman infrastructure. In 534 AD the islands became part of the Byzantine Empire.</p>
<p>As the spread of Islam in the 7th century reached North Africa, the Moors conquered Spain and shortly after, the Balearics. Four hundred years of Arab dominance followed, and while they were eventually ousted by King Jaume I, who annexed the island to his Kingdom of Aragon (thus making Mallorca part of the Catalan empire), some of their influence still remains in local culture and tradition. A prosperous era followed, to which many of the island&rsquo;s most important buildings, including Bellver Castle, the Almudaina Palace and the Convent of Sant Francese, owe their origins.</p>
<p>During the Spanish Civil War, Mallorca was attacked by the Republicans for being a nationalist stronghold. What became known as the Battle of Mallorca in August 1936 saw the nationalists ultimately succeed in defending the island.</p>
<p>Since the 1950s, Mallorca has been one of Europe&rsquo;s first and most popular tourist destinations. Mass tourism throughout the following three decades saw Mallorca&rsquo;s resorts boom, but it unfortunately got a reputation as a cheap, sun holiday for lager louts. A clean-up operation has seen the island enter a new phase of sophisticated tourism. Over 13 million tourists visit Mallorca each year.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Mallorca is one of the world's most important training locations for professional cyclists.<br />
&bull; The name Mallorca comes from the Latin for 'larger one', as opposed to Minorca, the 'smaller one'<br />
&bull; Chopin, George Sand and Robert Graves all lived on Mallorca in the picturesque villages of Deia and Valldemossa.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy and Consulate of the Kingdom of Spain in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 728 2330. </p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b>(202) 728 2330. </p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1300.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b>DC 20037<br/>2375 Pennsylvania Avenue NW<br/>Washington<br/><br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Consulate General in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7589 8989.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.conspalon.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7589 8989.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>20 Draycott Place<br/>London<br/>SW3 2RZ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 5555.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.conspalon.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>(020) 7235 5555.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>39 Chesham Place<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8SB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It doesn&rsquo;t take a genius to work out why Mallorca endures as one of Europe&rsquo;s top destinations. Clean beaches? Check. Upmarket resorts? Check. Reliable weather? Check. It has all the hallmarks of a sizzling summer holiday.</p>
<p>Resorts big and small can be found along much of the coast, offering everything from tranquil getaways to raucous fun in the sun. Mega yachts, small sailboats and wooden fishing boats ply the waters around the island.</p>
<p>But Mallorca is more than just a beach destination. In recent years the island&rsquo;s capital, Palma, has developed into one of Spain&rsquo;s most beguiling small cities. Fronted by the beautifully imposing cathedral and royal palace, its narrow cobbled lanes weave away from the seafront into the heart of the old city, where pedestrianised shopping streets, charming squares, ancient courtyards and chic bars attract locals and foreigners alike. As well as its vibrant nightlife, Palma boasts a strong arts scene.</p>
<p>Excellent food abounds in Mallorca. Seafood predominates in coastal resorts, while regional dishes are served in traditional restaurants throughout the island. The restaurant scene is thriving in Palma, where foodies can quaff anything from local cuisine to Japanese fare.</p>
<p>Head inland and a completely different (and much less touristy) picture of Mallorca emerges. Traditional villages lie scattered across the countryside, sheep bells tinkle, white almond blossom floats in the air and a rural tranquillity prevails.</p>
<p>The central plain is the agricultural heart of the island, with vineyards, sleepy hamlets and weekly markets. Along the west coast, the great Sierra de Tramuntana mountains, covered in pine forests, tower over the plains, their sharp cliffs looming large above the deep blue sea. It&rsquo;s the Spain of yesteryear and it should not be missed.</p><p>It doesn&rsquo;t take a genius to work out why Mallorca endures as one of Europe&rsquo;s top destinations. Clean beaches? Check. Upmarket resorts? Check. Reliable weather? Check. It has all the hallmarks of a sizzling summer holiday.&nbsp;Resorts big and small can be found along much of the coast, offering everything from tranquil getaways to raucous fun in the sun. Mega yachts, small sailboats and wooden fishing boats ply the waters around the island.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
