<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Canary Islands" ColCode="cai" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="qc" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Canary Islands]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Summer sunshine is guaranteed on all the islands. At other times of year however El Hierro and La Palma can be cool, with a west European spring-like climate. Both <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/tenerife">Tenerife</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/gran-canaria/gran-canaria-airport">Gran Canaria</a> have a north-south divide with parched southern shores and cooler, slightly wetter northern climes. However, by European standards rainfall is low throughout the islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight cottons for much of the year with shower protection and warmer wear in winter.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Multiple airlines operate regular international flights to Tenerife, Lanzarote, Fuerteventura and Gran Canaria from all over Europe. La Palma airport receives a limited number of international flights. Local flights run by Binter (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.bintercanarias.com/">www.bintercanarias.com</a>) link all the islands and also go to Madeira, Morocco, Western Sahara and Mauritania. Iberia (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.iberia.com/">www.iberia.com</a>) and Air Europa (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.air-europa.com/">www.air-europa.com</a>) also fly between the islands and mainland Spain.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London - 4 hours 30 minutes; New York - 13 hours 30 minutes (including stopover).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Gran Canaria Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Gran Canaria Airport is situated 18km (11 miles) south of Las Palmas, and 25km (16 miles) north of the popular tourist areas on the south coast of the island.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 902 404 704</p>]]><b>Lanzarote Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Lanzarote Airport is located 5km (3 miles) to the west of Arrecife.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 902 404 704</p>]]><b>Tenerife Sur Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Tenerife Sur Airport is situated 62km (38 miles) south of Santa Cruz, on the island of Tenerife.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 902 404 704</p>]]><b>Fuerteventura Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Fuerteventura Airport is located 5km (3 miles) south of the capital of the island, Puerto del Rosario.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 902 404 704</p>]]><b>Tenerife North Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena-aeropuertos.es<p>The airport is 11km (7 miles) west of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/santa-cruz-cruise">Santa Cruz</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>Main ports:</strong> Las Palmas  and Tenerife.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It's easy to explore the Canary Islands by car, and all the big car hire companies have offices here.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Enjoy the buzz of Las Palmas</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its magnificent location between two bays, Las Palmas is the impressive capital of Gran Canaria. A pretty, modern town and the island's liveliest, it sees plenty of action, and boasts a plethora of sights including Casa de Colón (Columbus House), the cathedral, market, Pueblo Canario and several museums. There's a fine beach too.</p>]]><p><b>Feel the heat at Timanfaya National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Timanfaya National Park is an awe-inspiring moonscape created by an 18th-century volcanic eruption that covered around one-third of Lanzarote in lava. Take the coach tour, or to feel the heat of the volcano, book a walking tour; don't worry, it's dormant.</p>]]><p><b>Go windsurfing in Fuerteventura</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Join the pros and go windsurfing or kitesurfing off Fuerteventura's fabulous soft golden beaches. Giant dunes back unspoiled beaches in both the north of the island, at Corralejo, and in the south at Jandía, where world championship events are staged.</p>]]><p><b>Head back to the start at Puerto de la Cruz</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Spend a day in Puerto de la Cruz on Tenerife's north coast, which was the birthplace of tourism in the Canaries back in the 19th century. Splash out in the César Manrique-designed Costa Martiánez lido, explore the colonial-style old town and enjoy Loro Parque, one of the world's finest marine and wildlife parks.</p>]]><p><b>Hike in the volcanic crater of Caldera de Taburiente</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Take a hike in the Caldera de Taburiente on La Palma, one of the largest and most fertile volcanic craters on Earth, or just take in the view from the Mirador de La Cumbrecita. This national park is a wondrous green landscape of valleys and mountainous forms wreathed in cloud.</p>]]><p><b>Marvel at the works of Lanzaroteño artist César Manrique</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Don't miss the many César Manrique-related attractions. This great Lanzaroteño artist, landscape designer and ecological champion is seen by many as the patron saint of the island's culture, thanks to his fantastic creations. Jameos del Agua – elaborate sculpted caves – and Jardín de Cactus are perhaps the highlights.</p>]]><p><b>Party at the Canaries' massive carnival</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The best time to visit the Canary Islands has to be between February and March, when the carnival wave reaches Spain's southernmost frontier. The celebrations on Tenerife, in Santa Cruz and Puerto Cruz, are some of the biggest and most colourful outside Rio de Janeiro in Brazil.</p>]]><p><b>Soak up Teguise's history in Lazarote</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head to Teguise, the picturesque colonial-style former capital of Lanzarote, for its aristocratic palaces, historic convents, churches and a castle built on a volcanic cone with great views over the town. Visit on a Sunday to enjoy the buzzing, colourful market.</p>]]><p><b>Take a cable car up Mount Teide</b></p><![CDATA[<p>On Tenerife take the cable car up Mount Teide, the highest point in all Spanish territory at 3,718m (12,198ft). It climbs to within 300m (1,000ft) of the summit – from where you can walk the rest (free permit required). Teide National Park was declared a World Heritage Site in 2007.</p>]]><p><b>Visit the lively Santa Cruz de Tenerife</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the cosmopolitan city of Santa Cruz, Tenerife's lively capital. Enjoy its rich architecture, churches, museums and bustling market, before relaxing on the golden sands of Playa de Las Teresitas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>The cuisine of the Canary Islands shares much in common with that of the Spanish peninsula, but there are key distinctions that mark them out from the rest of the country. Canarian fare bears influences from its aboriginal inhabitants, Latin American immigrants, and nearby Africa.</p>
<p>A staple of the Canarian diet is <em>papas</em>, which is thought to have been invented when the first potatoes were brought over from Latin America by the conquistadores. Locals like to mash them with a special sauce called <em>mojo picon</em> derived from garlic, paprika, cumin and white vinegar; this potato dish is served with almost every meal. Fish soups are very common, too, as is goat meat, and various stews. Bananas, tomatoes, avocados and papayas are grown locally and widely consumed.</p>
<p>In the main resorts, restaurants offer the full range of international cuisine, Spanish dishes and a limited choice of local delicacies. Often restaurants and bars, particularly at the cheaper end of the scale, simply cater for the tastes of particular holidaymaker's nationalities. British-oriented, and to a lesser degree, German-oriented establishments are common in the main resorts. Spanish wines and spirits are the best value. Local beers are pilsner-type lagers.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mojos</strong>: Olive oil based sauces.<br />
<strong>Pic&oacute;n</strong>: Spicy red sauce to accompany meat.<br />
<strong>Verde</strong>: Sauce from parsley and coriander to accompany fish.<br />
<strong>Papasarrugadas</strong>: Wrinkly new potatoes boiled in sea salt.<br />
<strong>Potaje</strong>: Vegetable-only soupy stew.<br />
<strong>Pucherocanario</strong>: A meat soup of chicken, beef and pork meat, plus corn cobs, chickpeas, sweet potatoes and other vegetables.<br />
<strong>Sancocho</strong>: Stew of salted fish, sweet potatoes and vegetables.<br />
<strong>Ropavieja</strong>: Meaning 'old clothes', this dish mixes chicken and beef with potatoes and chickpeas.<br />
<strong>Conejo en salmorejo</strong>: Rabbit stew marinated in coriander sauce.<br />
<strong>Costillas con pi&ntilde;a</strong>: Ribs with corn cob.<br />
<strong>Pella de gofio</strong>: Gofio is a kind of milled grain with a whole range of culinary uses in the Canaries. Pella de Gofio is a kind of soft, doughy loaf.<br />
<strong>Ronmiel</strong>: A rum-honey liquor.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>There is not a huge culture of tipping in the Canaries, but 10% in restaurants is acceptable</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>All the major Canarian resorts are well equipped with bars and nightclubs. Revellers head for Playa de las Am&eacute;ricas on <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/tenerife">Tenerife</a> or Playa del Ingl&eacute;s on <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/gran-canaria/gran-canaria-airport">Gran Canaria</a>; the latter also hosts one of Europe's largest gay scenes. Both are famous, sometimes notorious, for their full-on nightlife. The resorts also stage Canarian folklore and flamenco shows, even though the latter has nothing to do with the islands.<br />
<br />
As the only major city in the archipelago <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/las-palmas">Las Palmas</a> offers a full range of cultural activities including theatres and more sophisticated nightclubs. In Lanzarote Puerto del Carmen is the most lively after-dark resort, while Corralejo flies the nocturnal flag for <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mallorca/lanzarote-airport">Lanzarote</a> - both however are small scale compared to Tenerife and Gran Canaria. On the other islands peace and quiet predominate.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The islands are known for their duty-free shopping, which means bargains on electrical goods, cameras, jewellery, perfume, tobacco and spirits. Island handicrafts include open-work and embroidery, pottery, rugs, woodcarvings and basket-work based on palm leaves, cane and reed. Highly regarded Cuban-style cigars are a speciality of La Palma. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mallorca/lanzarote-airport">Lanzarote</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/tenerife">Tenerife</a> produce good-quality wines. Specially boxed <em>strelitzias</em>, the most exotic of the islands' flowers, and Canarian <em>mojo</em> sauces are ubiquitous souvenirs.</p><p>Traditional hours are Mon-Sat 0900-1300 and 1600-2000. Large shopping centres are open all day and Sunday too.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a large selection of hotels, self-catering apartments and holiday homes in all categories with 3-star and (increasingly) 4-star becoming the norm. There are also many new 5-star hotels, particularly in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/tenerife">Tenerife</a>. Hotels and apartments in the large resorts tend to be block-booked by package tour operators. There are state-run <em>paradores</em><strong> </strong>(tourist inns) on La Palma, La Gomera and Tenerife. <em>Pensiones </em>(guest houses), which just provide bed and board are not so easy to find, particularly in tourist zones. There are a small but increasing number of places that offer <em>turismo rural</em> (rural tourism) in the islands' interiors, typically staying in renovated older properties set in rural locations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a large selection of hotels, self-catering apartments and holiday homes in all categories with 3-star and (increasingly) 4-star becoming the norm. There are also many new 5-star hotels, particularly in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/tenerife">Tenerife</a>. Hotels and apartments in the large resorts tend to be block-booked by package tour operators. There are state-run <em>paradores</em><strong> </strong>(tourist inns) on La Palma, La Gomera and Tenerife. <em>Pensiones </em>(guest houses), which just provide bed and board are not so easy to find, particularly in tourist zones. There are a small but increasing number of places that offer <em>turismo rural</em> (rural tourism) in the islands' interiors, typically staying in renovated older properties set in rural locations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is a large selection of hotels, self-catering apartments and holiday homes in all categories with 3-star and (increasingly) 4-star becoming the norm. There are also many new 5-star hotels, particularly in <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/tenerife">Tenerife</a>. Hotels and apartments in the large resorts tend to be block-booked by package tour operators. There are state-run <em>paradores</em><strong> </strong>(tourist inns) on La Palma, La Gomera and Tenerife. <em>Pensiones </em>(guest houses), which just provide bed and board are not so easy to find, particularly in tourist zones. There are a small but increasing number of places that offer <em>turismo rural</em> (rural tourism) in the islands' interiors, typically staying in renovated older properties set in rural locations.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Canary Islands are an Autonomous Community within Spain and, although the archipelago is part of the EU, it has not signed up to the same duty free agreements.</p>
<p>There are, therefore, restrictions on what you can bring in and take out of the Canary Islands &ndash; even when travelling to and from other parts of the EU. The following goods may be taken into the Canary Islands by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes, 100 cigarillos, 25 cigars or 250g of other tobacco products.<br />
&bull; 1L of spirits.<br />
&bull; 2L of fortified wine (such as sherry or port), sparkling wine or any other drink that is less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; In addition you may also bring back 1L of beer or 4L of still wine.<br />
&bull; Other goods to a value of &euro;430.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Meat and dairy products from outside the EU, unlicensed drugs and unauthorised firearms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Endangered species require an export permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol €) = 100 cents (<em>céntimos</em>). Notes are in denominations of €500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of €2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money can be changed in any bank, and at most travel agencies, major hotels and airports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard/Cirrus and Visa/Plus are accepted in nearly all ATMs, which are common throughout the country. These credit cards can generally be used outside main towns and cities, although cash is your safest bet.</p><p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard/Cirrus and Visa/Plus are accepted in nearly all ATMs, which are common throughout the country. There are usually at least one bank and ATM in each village.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are disappearing from use fast, and it's far more convenient to travel with credit cards these days. Nevertheless, you can still change them in main bank branches and exchange bureaux, and they are accepted in major hotels. It is advisable to bring them in sterling or dollars as there have been increasing reports of Euro cheques being refused.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0830-1400. Some branches open Saturdays too, from October to April.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[28.291564]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-16.629130]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>7,242 sq km (2,796 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>2,100,306 (INE value 2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>290 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Provincial capitals are Las Palmas de Gran Canaria and Santa Cruz de Tenerife.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Canary Islands are situated between 96km (60 miles) and 304km (189 miles) off the northwest coast of Africa. The southern coast of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain">Spain</a> lies 1,120km (696 miles) south. <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/las-palmas">Las Palmas</a> comprises the islands of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/gran-canaria/gran-canaria-airport">Gran Canaria</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/fuerteventura/fuerteventura-airport">Fuerteventura</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mallorca/lanzarote-airport">Lanzarote</a>. Santa Cruz de Tenerife is made up of Tenerife, La Palma, Gomera and Hierro. All the islands are of volcanic origin and the climate is subtropical. The landscape is varied, and includes mountain ranges, valleys, deserts, cliffs, craters and forests.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Believed by some to be part of the remains of the mythological lost continent of Atlantis, the Canary islands' human history stretches back to antiquity. There is some evidence that the Phoenicians landed there as far back as the 12th century BC, while the Romans knew them as the 'Fortunate Isles' &ndash; but did not occupy them.</p>
<p>Little is known about the islands' original inhabitants, though they are today believed to be related to Berbers. Genoese traders landed on the Canaries in the early 14th century, with a Captain Lanzarotto lending his name to one of the islands &ndash; which were finally conquered in the 15th century.</p>
<p>Jean de B&eacute;thencourt, an adventurer-lord of Granville in Normandy, set out to convert the islands to Christianity in 1402, or so he claimed. The mission turned ugly, with many of the natives sold into slavery. The islands gradually came under Spanish imperial control over the course of several bloody campaigns.</p>
<p>The native inhabitants proved highly rebellious and difficult to control, but many continued to be sold as slaves, and the remainder converted to Christianity. Some slaves were later freed, returned and assimilated with the colonisers, but their language and culture all but disappeared.</p>
<p>Pirate raids between the Moroccan coast and the archipelago went on over subsequent years, while in the 17th and 18th centuries, Britain continually challenged Spain for control of the islands, culminating in Nelson&rsquo;s strike on Santa Cruz; the Admiral lost his right arm in the attack, and British adventures in the area came to end.</p>
<p>After this, the main threat to the Canaries came from within, as rivalries between the islands threatened to split the province apart. This did finally happen in 1927, when Madrid turned the Canaries into two provinces.</p>
<p>In 1936, General Franco was transferred to the islands by a central government suspicious of a coup. Franco justified their fears by taking control of the islands, using them as a launchpad for the Spanish Civil War. After the war, many Canarios emigrated to escape economic ruin. Only when Franco began to court tourism did the islands recover.</p>
<p>When Franco died and power was devolved to regions in the new democratic Spain, the islands became a <em>comunidadaut&oacute;noma</em>. A small but significant independence movement that first stirred under Franco has grown steadily ever since. Apart from tourism, immigration from Africa has transformed the islands in recent years, with the islands now putting emphasis on investment in their African neighbours to relieve the pressure.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?<br />
</strong>&bull; Christopher Columbus stopped at the islands more than once en route to discovering the Americas in 1492.<br />
&bull; One of England's greatest military victories over Spain came in 1657, when the Royal Navy completely destroyed a Spanish treasure fleet at the cost of only one ship near Tenerife.<br />
&bull; For many years, Gran Canaria and Tenerife were fierce rivals for control over the archipelago, nearly leading to war between them.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Drifting like flotsam off the coast of northwest Africa, the Canary Islands have long been a popular destination for sun-seeking Europeans. Synonymous with sandy beaches, sprawling holiday resorts and glorious weather, the archipelago is comprised of seven islands, which form one of Spain&rsquo;s most distant territories. <br />
<br />
Gran Canaria and Tenerife are probably the most mainstream islands. Their family-friendly resorts and sweeping beaches are packed most of the year with tourists from Europe and beyond. Meanwhile, Fuerteventura is famous for its wind-driven water sports and has some of the finest beaches in the region.</p>
<p>Tourism is the lifeblood of these islands, but their dependency on this source of income has led to some unsettling consequences, such as rampant development of once beautiful coastlines and hedonistic holidaymakers breaching the peace.</p>
<p>While not all of the islands have found the balance between developing tourism and preserving local life, Lanzarote has managed to combine modern resorts with eco-friendly developments and more aesthetically sensitive designs.</p>
<p>While most visitors come to the Canaries for sun, sea and sand, the archipelago is of volcanic origin and offers strikingly diverse landscapes including sub-tropical flora, abundant pine forests, giant sand dunes and mountain peaks.</p>
<p>Want to escape the crowds? La Gomera is a charming and undeveloped island, which can be visited as a day-trip from Tenerife (just 30 minutes by ferry). Meanwhile, little-visited La Palma is green, uncommercialised and arguably the most beautiful island. And most westerly of all is El Hierro, windblown and well off the beaten track, it attracts a handful of hardy hikers each year.</p>
<p>Closer to Africa than Spain, the islands were conquered by the Castilians in the early 15th century and although they remain part of the motherland, the Canarians have a distinct culture, with many calling for greater autonomy and some independence.</p><p>Drifting like flotsam off the coast of northwest Africa, the Canary Islands have long been a popular destination for sun-seeking Europeans. Synonymous with sandy beaches, sprawling holiday resorts and glorious weather, the archipelago is comprised of seven islands, which form one of Spain&rsquo;s most distant territories.</p>
<p>Gran Canaria and Tenerife are probably the most mainstream islands. Their family-friendly resorts and sweeping beaches are packed most of the year with tourists from Europe and beyond. Meanwhile, Fuerteventura is famous for its wind-driven water sports and has some of the finest beaches in the region.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
