<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Gran Canaria" ColCode="GRN" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Gran Canaria]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>As with all the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands">Canary Islands</a>, the climate of Gran Canaria is as near perfect as you're likely to find anywhere in the world. Winter temperatures very rarely dip below 16&deg;C (61&deg;F) in winter and only occasionally rise higher than 32&deg;C (90&deg;F) in summer. The coolest month is January, with average daytime temperatures of 18&deg;C (64&deg;F). The warmest is August with an average daytime temperature of 26&deg;C (79&deg;F). The north of the island is slightly cooler and less arid than the south.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Lightweight, plus some wind protection according to the season and a warm jacket for the occasional chilly evening in winter.<br /><br /></p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are no internal flights on the island, but travellers can fly from Gran Canaria to other Canary Islands with BinterCanarias (<a href="http://www.bintercanarias.com/" target="_blank">www.bintercanarias.com</a>) and CanaryFly (<a href="http://www.canaryfly.es/" target="_blank">www.canaryfly.es</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no railway in Gran Canaria.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A car offers the greatest flexibility for getting around Gran Canaria. Around Las Palmas the motorway can get busy during rush hour, but beyond the capital traffic is light and driving is a pleasure.</p>
<p>Watch for unusual use of the indicator; it's rarely used to notify a directional change and usually in place of hazard warning lights or to advise that the car is stopping at a pedestrian crossing. On roundabouts, which are still something of a mystery to local drivers, it's best to stick to the outside lane or risk getting cut up when you try to exit.</p>r<p>Highways are generally well-maintained and well sign-posted, but the mountain roads can be steep and narrow.</p><p>The island is well served by the local bus service. Routes, timetables and fares are available on the website (<a href="http://www.globalsu.es/" target="_blank">www.globalsu.es</a>).</p><p>Taxis on Gran Canaria are metered and well regulated. They can be found at the airport and ferry terminals, as well as in all resorts and major centres.</p><p>Most foreign licences, including Canadian, EU and US, are accepted. Minimum third Party insurance is compulsory. An original driving licence, proof of insurance and another piece of identification must be carried in the car at all times.</p><p>Two red hazard triangles and two reflective vests or jackets must be kept in all vehicles – the latter in the car, not in the boot. Parking laws are rigorously enforced and towing is prevalent. The speed limit for motorways is 120kph (80mph). In built-up areas it's 50kph (30mph) and on other roads it's 90kph (56mph).</p><p>Speed cameras are in operation on motorways and major roads. Front and rear safety belts are compulsory. Drink driving is a serious offence in Gran Canaria. The legal limit is just 0.05%. The use of a mobile phone whilst driving is classed as a serious offence.</p><p>Real Autom&oacute;vil Club de Espa&ntilde;a (RACE) (tel: +34 900 112 222; <a href="http://www.race.es/" target="_blank">www.race.es</a>).</p><p>Car hire is good value in Gran Canaria. Several major car hire companies are represented at the two airports and in urban centres, but many firms operate from industrial estates outside the airport and offer a shuttle bus to and from the airport. Drivers must be over 21 to hire a car and you will need a passport, driving licence and credit card.</p><p>Riders of motorcycles over 75cc must be at least 18. Crash helmets are compulsory. Cycling is popular in Gran Canaria and bikes are widely available for hire, but cycle lanes are few and far between.</p><p>Two red hazard triangles and two reflective vests or jackets must be kept in all vehicles – the latter in the car, not in the boot. Parking laws are rigorously enforced and towing is prevalent. The speed limit for motorways is 120kph (80mph). In built-up areas it's 50kph (30mph) and on other roads it's 90kph (56mph).</p><p>Speed cameras are in operation on motorways and major roads. Front and rear safety belts are compulsory. Drink driving is a serious offence in Gran Canaria. The legal limit is just 0.05%. The use of a mobile phone whilst driving is classed as a serious offence.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main resorts are relatively flat, compact and easily navigable on foot, except for Puerto Rico, which is built on a hill. The public bus service is a cheap, safe and reliable way of travelling.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gran Canaria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">puertode_mogaacuten</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.45</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gran Canaria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">maspalomas</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.35</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gran Canaria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">airport</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.20</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Gran Canaria</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">agaete</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">0.40</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Low cost carriers such as easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com/" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>) operate frequent flights to Gran Canaria from airports across the UK.</p>
<p>Other flight operators include British Airways (<a href="http://www.britishairways.com" target="_blank">www.britishairways.com</a>) and Thomas Cook Airlines (<a href="http://www.thomascookairlines.com/" target="_blank">www.thomascookairlines.com</a>). Spain's national airline is Iberia (<a href="http://www.iberia.com/" target="_blank">www.iberia.com</a>) which has frequent daily flights to Gran Canaria from Madrid and Barcelona, and regular flights from other points in mainland Spain and across Europe.</p>
<p>Gran Canaria also offers direct flights to destinations in Africa, Cape Verde and Madeira via BinterCanarias (<a href="http://www.bintercanarias.com/" target="_blank">www.bintercanarias.com</a>). Flights are cheaper and more plentiful during the winter high season between September and March.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From London to Gran Canaria is 4 hours 30mins.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Gran Canaria Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Gran Canaria Airport is situated 18km (11 miles) south of Las Palmas, and 25km (16 miles) north of the popular tourist areas on the south coast of the island.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 902 404 704</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are ferry services from to Gran Canaria from mainland Spain. Ferries also operate between Gran Canaria and other Canary islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: ]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Bask on Maspalomas Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Considered the most beautiful of all the beaches on the island, Maspalomas has fine white sand backed by vast, wind-sculpted dunes. At over 5.5km (3.5 miles) long, there's plenty of room even on the busiest days.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the lost village of Cueva Pintada</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Set within caves excavated into the cliffs of Galdár, Cueva Pintada is the remains of an aboriginal village discovered in 1987 that comprised some 50 houses. The caves contain wall paintings made by the island's earliest inhabitants as well as archaeological findings dating from the 6th to the 16th centuries. Walkways take you through reconstructed houses for a glimpse into their primitive lives.</p>]]><p><b>Get wet at Aqualand</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The biggest water park on the island, Aqualand in Maspalomas (<a href="http://www.aqualand.es/maspalomas" target="_blank">www.aqualand.es/maspalomas</a>) has a plethora of pools, water attractions and slides, some of which are white-knuckle affairs. On-site extras such as lockers and sun beds are costly. Look out for discount coupons being given out at the airport on arrival.</p>]]><p><b>Go twitching at Palmitos Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>A botanical and zoological wonderland, Palmitos Park (<a href="http://www.palmitospark.es" target="_blank">www.palmitospark.es</a>) has 200 different species of birds plus a butterfly house, an aquarium, an orchid house and extensive cactus gardens. There's also Primates Island, home to a community of white-handed gibbons, and don't miss the Meercats who are endlessly entertaining.</p>]]><p><b>Go whale watching</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Whales and dolphins can be seen all year round in the waters off the Canary Islands. Species that call at the archipelago include sperm whales, short finned pilot whales and bottlenose dolphins. Various operators offer whale watching tours. Boats leave from Puerto Rico.</p>]]><p><b>Hike through dramatic landscapes</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gran Canaria's varied typography is a big draw for hikers – some say it's the best destination in Europe for ramblers. It certainly ticks all the boxes; the island has everything from deserts and mountains to coastal paths and valleys, with trails for all abilities. Gran Canaria's hiking paths also reveal bucolic villages, forests and fabulous flora.</p>]]><p><b>Learn about the Cañari at Museo Canario</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Ca&ntilde;ari<strong>, </strong>Gran Canaria's original inhabitants, are the sole stars of the Museo Canario in Las Palmas (<a href="http://www.elmuseocanario.com" target="_blank">www.elmuseocanario.com</a>), which is dedicated entirely to understanding the lives of the island's original inhabitants. The museum comprises the most comprehensive archaeological collection in the Canary Islands. The most popular room is the anthropology collection, which has wall-to-wall skulls and the mummified remains of Ca&ntilde;ari<strong>.</strong></p>]]><p><b>Nip down to Cocodrilos Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Otherwise known as Crocodile Park, Cocodrilos Park Zoo (<a href="http://www.cocodriloparkzoo.com/es/cocodrilopark" target="_blank">www.cocodriloparkzoo.com</a>) this popular attraction is home to the biggest collection of crocodiles anywhere in Europe &ndash; over 300 of the snappy beasts call the park home. Virtually all the crocodiles have been rescued from illegal traders or from being kept in unsuitable conditions as pets. There's also a tiger, a large collection of birds and monkeys and tropical fish.</p>]]><p><b>Quaff away at the quay in Puerto de Mogán</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Nicknamed the 'Venice of Gran Canaria,' due to the canals that crisscross the town, this scenic harbour is home to gleaming yachts, a pretty beach and narrow, bougainvillea-draped alleyways that are lined with craft shops. Come nightfall, the quayside restaurants are the perfect place to enjoy a romantic seafood dinner.</p>]]><p><b>Strut your stuff at Las Canteras Beach</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Gran Canaria's answer to Ipanema and Bondi, Playa Las Canteras in Las Palmas is a golden beach lined with a multitude of bars, restaurants and shops. The favoured lunch venue for city workers and playground for surfers, sunbathers and posers, Las Canteras is the focal point of the city and the only urban beach in the Canaries.</p>]]><p><b>Take a stroll around La Vegueta</b></p><![CDATA[<p>While away an afternoon strolling around the 16th-century streets of La Vegueta, Las Palmas' charming old town. Sights include the 17th-century Palacio Regental, now the High Court of Law, and the Gothic Cathedral of Santa Ana. Join the locals for a coffee on the terrace of the charismatic Hotel Madrid before losing yourself in the alleyways of independent shops.</p>]]><p><b>Take in a show at Alfredo Kraus Auditorium</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Standing like a beacon of culture at the end of Las Canteras beach in Las Palmas, the Alfredo Kraus Auditorium (<a href="http://auditorioteatrolaspalmasgc.es" target="_blank">http://auditorioteatrolaspalmasgc.es</a>)&nbsp;was designed by Oscar Tusquets, inaugurated by the Prince of Asturias (the newly crowned King of Spain) and dedicated to Alfredo Kraus, the Canary Island's most famous tenor. The iconic building is the venue for concerts ranging from classical through jazz to hip-hop.</p>]]><p><b>Tee off at Anfi Tauro Golf Club</b></p><![CDATA[<p>With its year-round sunshine, Gran Canaria provides 365 possible golfing days a year, which, unsurprisingly, make it a magnet for the Pringle sweater wearing set. There are seven excellent courses to choose from including the Anfi Tauro, par 72 championship course in Mog&aacute;n. Designed by von Hagge, Smelek and Baril, the Arizona style course provides challenges and vistas in equally breathtaking measure.</p>]]><p><b>Trek to Caldera de Bandama</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Caldera de Bandama, a 200m (660ft) deep volcanic crater, has an observation platform on its peak from which you can gaze down at the rich tapestry of endemic plants that cover its floor. But the real joy of Bandama is to trek down to the crater floor and discover the caves where the Cañari are buried.</p>]]><p><b>Wander around Viera y Clavijo Botanical Gardens</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Located a short drive from Las Palmas, Viera y Clavijo Botanical Gardens has over 2,000 species of plants including 500 endemic to Gran Canaria. Free to enter, the park is a favourite with newlyweds for photos amongst the spurges and palm trees. With a fascinating collection of exotic flora and pathways that take you alongside a lake and waterfall, this is a gardener's paradise far from the madding crowd.</p>]]><p><b>Watch the action at Sioux City</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Built in 1971 Sioux City is a western film set, which is the scene of movie-inspired performances such as Duel Until Death, Bank Robbery, Town Square Hanging and Indian Rain Dance. If formation foot moves are your thing, you'll enjoy the late afternoon line dancing sessions. The park also features horse riding.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><b>Main Exports: </b><b>Main Imports: </b><b>Main Trade Partners: </b></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Although some way behind its larger neighbour, Tenerife, Gran Canaria has a burgeoning collection of high-end restaurants, most of which can be found in the capital and holiday resorts. Typically, though, island gastronomy is dominated by fish, seafood and meat dishes served with the ubiquitous <em>papas arrugadas con salsa mojo</em> (Canarian wrinkly potatoes with sauce). Recipes are not fancy, with the emphasis being on flavour and ability to fill stomachs, rather than presentation. Vegetables can be a bit of a rarity except in soups and stews, which is surprising given the range and quality of fresh produce available in farmers' markets.</p><p>Las Palmas has possibly the best selections of tapas bars on any of the islands and you can enjoy tapas nights every Thursday in the old quarter of Vegueta where participating restaurants offer deals on tapas and alcoholic drinks.</p><p>Gran Canaria is home to the only remaining coffee plantation in the Canarian archipelago, Los Berrazales, which is the most northerly plantation in the world and produces smooth, chocolaty beans. Finally, Gran Canaria's award-winning goat cheeses are worth looking out for, and its <em>mole</em> (egg yolk beaten with lemon curd) is a favourite with the sweet-toothed locals.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fish:</strong> <em>Cherne</em> (wreckfish)<em>, sama</em> (Red sea bream)<em>, vieja</em> (parrot fish)<em>, dorado</em> (gilt-head sea bream), <em>lubina</em> (sea bass)<em>, </em>calamari<em>, </em>sardines<em>, choco</em> (cuttlefish), <em>pulpo</em> (octopus) and <em>lapas</em> (limpets baked and then drizzled in garlic oil).<br />
<strong>Carajacas</strong>: Liver marinated in a spicy sauce, fried and then boiled in a clay pot.<br />
<strong>Sancocho</strong>: A dry, salty fish stew made with bass or bream and sweet potatoes.<br />
<strong>Cabra con papas</strong>: Goat with potatoes or fries.<br />
<strong>Mole</strong>: Egg yolk beaten with lemon curd.<br />
<strong>Potaje</strong>: Watercress soup.<br />
<strong>RopaVieja</strong>: A thick paste of shredded chicken or beef with chickpeas, potatoes and garlic.<br />
<strong>Sweet potato truchas</strong>: Little almond and cinnamon flavoured pies.<br />
<strong>Conejo al Salmorejo</strong>: Rabbit in sauce.<br />
<strong>Puchero</strong>: Chorizo sausage, bean and potato stew.<br />
<strong>Tinto del Monte</strong>: Meaning 'mountain red', this is the local speciality wine.<br />
<strong>Tropical</strong>: Locally brewed beer.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Few restaurants include a service charge in the bill. Tipping is discretionary and usually involves rounding up the charge to a maximum of around 10% in restaurants.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>18.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The resorts of Playa del Ingles and Maspalomas are Gran Canaria&rsquo;s hedonistic hotspots. Renowned for their great nightlife and laid-back attitude, they are enjoyed by those of every sexual orientation.</p>
<p>The Yumbo Centre (<a href="http://www.cc-yumbo.com/" target="_blank">www.cc-yumbo.com</a>) and Kasbah Centre are the epicentres of the nightlife scene with a heady mixture of gay and straight bars, clubs and family-friendly pubs.</p>
<p>In Puerto Rico the noise and neon emanates predominately from the Centro Comercial. Over in Las Palmas, Plaza de Espa&ntilde;a is at the heart of the action, especially where live music is concerned &ndash; El Cuasqu&iacute;as in Vegueta and Cafe El Gallinero are the premier venues for local bands and DJs.</p>
<p>Many bars welcome children and it's not unusual to see toddlers sitting with their parents until late. Perhaps not one for youngsters is the risqu&eacute; and enduringly popular drag queen show at The Music Hall Tavern (<a href="http://www.musichalltavern.com" target="_blank">www.musichalltavern.com</a>) opposite the go-karting in Las Palmas. Tickets include a three course meal with drinks included and transport to and from the venue.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, high rollers can take on the penny punters at the island's two casinos &ndash; one in Las Palmas (Casino Las Palmas) and the other in San Agust&iacute;n (Casino Gran Canaria).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Despite Spain's entry into the European Union, the Canary Islands have special status as a free trade zone with minimal import duties. Because of this, items such as alcohol and tobacco are much cheaper than elsewhere in Europe.</p>
<p>Electrical and IT goods are not as competitive as they were before the recession and with fake goods prevalent, guarantees should be fully scrutinised &ndash; if it looks too good to be true, it probably is.</p>
<p>Las Palmas provides many opportunities to melt your credit card. Popular shopping centres include El Corte Ingl&eacute;s and Las Arenas. The street of Calle Mayor de Triana is also a hotbed of commerce.</p>
<p>In southern Gran Canaria, the biggest variety of shops can be found in the four-storey Yumbo Centre with retailers selling everything from shoes to Champagne. For something more bijou, explore the lanes off the main street which are home to funky fashion and hand made jewellery outlets.</p>
<p>The island's markets also provide a good way to find locally produced handicrafts and souvenirs. The Saturday and Sunday morning farmers' market in San Mateo is by far the best, but the one in Santa Brigida is also worth visiting, as is the Sunday morning San Lorenzo market outside Las Palmas.</p>
<p>If you're out and about on a Sunday, take a trip to Teror for its street market (open until 1400) where you'll find the famous chorizo de Teror, a spicy sausage, and morcilla de Teror, a sweet black pudding.</p>
<p>Canarian basketry, embroidered lace, pottery, aloe vera products and gourmet coffee from Agaete, the world's most northerly coffee plantation, are the island's most popular souvenirs.</p><p>Monday to Saturday 0930-1330 and 1700-1900 are the usual hours, though some bigger shops and those in tourist areas tend to stay open all day. Most shops are closed on Sunday.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many hotels on the island, the vast majority in the southern resorts of Puerto Rico and Maspalomas. Many belong to international chains and are block-booked by package tour operators through the busy summer and wintersun seasons. Several rural hotels are also available within the interior mountain region. Accommodation options range from room only through to all inclusive.<br />
<strong><br />
Grading: </strong>All hotels in Gran Canaria are graded from 1 to 5 stars, with the exception of one ultra-luxurious hotel graded 5-star L (Luxury) and small country hotels graded 1 or 2 'palms'.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many hotels on the island, the vast majority in the southern resorts of Puerto Rico and Maspalomas. Many belong to international chains and are block-booked by package tour operators through the busy summer and wintersun seasons. Several rural hotels are also available within the interior mountain region. Accommodation options range from room only through to all inclusive.<br />
<strong><br />
Grading: </strong>All hotels in Gran Canaria are graded from 1 to 5 stars, with the exception of one ultra-luxurious hotel graded 5-star L (Luxury) and small country hotels graded 1 or 2 'palms'.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are many hotels on the island, the vast majority in the southern resorts of Puerto Rico and Maspalomas. Many belong to international chains and are block-booked by package tour operators through the busy summer and wintersun seasons. Several rural hotels are also available within the interior mountain region. Accommodation options range from room only through to all inclusive.<br />
<strong><br />
Grading: </strong>All hotels in Gran Canaria are graded from 1 to 5 stars, with the exception of one ultra-luxurious hotel graded 5-star L (Luxury) and small country hotels graded 1 or 2 'palms'.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p/><p/><p/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><b>Intro:</b></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The Canary Islands are an Autonomous Community within Spain and, although the archipelago is part of the EU, it has not signed up to the same duty free agreements.</p><p>There are, therefore, restrictions on what you can bring in and take out of the Canary Islands – even when travelling to and from other parts of the EU. The following goods may be taken into the Canary Islands by travellers over 17 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p><p>• 200 cigarettes, 100 cigarillos, 25 cigars or 250g of other tobacco products.</p><p>• 1L of spirits.</p><p>• 2L of fortified wine (such as sherry or port), sparkling wine or any other drink that is less than 22% volume.</p><p>• In addition you may also bring back 1L of beer or 4L of still wine.</p><p>• Other goods to a value of €430.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Meat and dairy products from outside the EU, unlicensed drugs and unauthorised firearms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Endangered species require an export permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol €) = 100 cents (<em>céntimos</em>). Notes are in denominations of €500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of €2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money can be changed in any bank, and at most travel agencies, major hotels and airports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard/Cirrus and Visa/Plus are accepted in nearly all ATMs, which are common throughout the country. These credit cards can generally be used outside main towns and cities, although cash is your safest bet.</p><p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard/Cirrus and Visa/Plus are accepted in nearly all ATMs, which are common throughout the country. There are usually at least one bank and ATM in each village.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are disappearing from use fast, and it's far more convenient to travel with credit cards these days.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0830-1400. Some branches open Saturdays too, from October to April.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[27.920220]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-15.547437]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>1,560 sq km (602 sq miles).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>847,830 (2015).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>543.5 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Las Palmas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Gran Canaria is the most southerly of the seven <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands">Canary Islands</a> and lies in the Atlantic Ocean approximately 217km (135 miles) off the border between <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/morocco">Morocco</a> and Western Sahara, and 1,150km (715 miles) from the Iberian Peninsula. The highest point on Gran Canaria is Pico de las Nieves at 1,949m (6,394ft).</p>
<p>Gran Canaria is made up of 21 municipalities with the capital, <a href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/guides/europe/spain/canary-islands/gran-canaria/las-palmas/" target="_blank">Las Palmas</a> located in the North of the island. Las Palmas is the largest city in all of the Canary Islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no official religion, but the majority of the population is Roman Catholic.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spanish life has undergone rapid change in recent decades and many of the stricter religious customs are giving way to more modern ways, particularly in the cities and among women. In spite of this, traditions remain strong; hospitality, chivalry and courtesy thrive. <br />
<br />
Handshaking is the customary form of greeting between men, while women to whom one has already been introduced may be greeted with a fleeting kiss to either cheek. Normal social courtesies should be observed when visiting someone's home and a small gift is always appreciated. The evening meal is taken late, generally 2100-2200. The Spanish have two family names; the maternal surname follows the paternal, but is rarely used outside a formal context.<br />
<br />
Conservative casual wear is widely acceptable. A black tie is only necessary for very formal occasions and is usually specified if required. Outside resorts, scanty beachwear should be confined to beach or poolside. <br />
<br />
Smoking has long been banned in offices, shops, schools, hospitals, cultural centres and on public transport, but in 2011 that ban was extended to all bars, cafes and restaurants. Spain now has one of the toughest anti-smoking laws in Europe.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prior to the conquest of Gran Canaria by the Crown of Castille &ndash; a medieval state in the Iberian Peninsula &ndash; the island was populated by an indigenous people related to North African Berbers. Living in caves excavated from cliffs, the native Canarios had a sophisticated social hierarchy topped by two leaders who each ruled a kingdom. Many locals view the Canarios, who were decimated under early Castilian rule, as their heroic ancestors.</p>
<p>With the Canarios conquered, the island was planted with sugar cane, a valuable commodity that brought great wealth to Gran Canaria for more than century, until it was usurped by cheaper production in the Antilles. A long period of economic depression ensued until the mid-19th century when steam ships began arriving from Britain with well-heeled Victorians looking to winter in warmer climes. In 1881, Las Palmas developed its port and thanks mainly to those British visitors it soon became the busiest in the Canary Islands.</p>
<p>In 1821 when Tenerife was declared capital of the Canary Islands, it began to use its position to channel funding from the Spanish government into its own projects, at the expense of Gran Canaria. This led to a rift between the two islands, now best seen in rival beers and football teams. It wasn't until 1927 that Gran Canaria finally won her hard-earned billing as joint capital of the Canaries.</p>
<p>Mass tourism began in earnest in the 1960s when the superior beaches of Gran Canaria attracted bohemians to the Maspalomas dunes. Resorts responded with the construction of grand hotels and tourism has been the mainstay of the island's economy ever since.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	The Canary Islands boast their own sport, Canarian wrestling, which takes place at festivals. It's thought to be one of the oldest recognisable forms of wrestling.<br />
&bull;	Despite its name, Gran Canaria is the third largest of the islands after Tenerife and Fuerteventura.<br />
&bull;	Franco was military commander of the Canaries when the Spanish Civil War started in 1936; the plan to keep him out of the way by stationing him there didn't exactly work out &ndash; he went on to rule Spain for nearly 40 years.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Consulate General in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>20 Draycott Place<br/>London<br/>SW3 2RZ<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>39 Chesham Place<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8SB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Embassy and Consulate of the Kingdom of Spain in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Website:</b></p><p><b>Tel:</b></p><p><b>Opening Times:</b></p><p><b>Address:</b>NW<br/>2375 Pennsylvania Avenue<br/>Washington<br/>20037<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Often described as a &ldquo;miniature continent,&rdquo; Gran Canaria is home to a staggering diversity of landscapes; from sweeping sandy beaches and red-earthed pine forests to undulating mountains and dusty deserts.</p>
<p>Forming part of the Canary Islands &ndash; a Spanish archipelago floating off the coast of Western Sahara &ndash; the island has long been used as a shortcut to the sun for European holidaymakers. Cheap package deals and boozy British tourists have sullied its sunny image, but in recent years the island has been reinventing itself as a more salubrious destination. Led by the deluxe end of the market, Gran Canaria&rsquo;s hotels and restaurants are experiencing something of a makeover, as the island ditches its tacky seventies aesthetic for one of retro chic and boho beau monde.</p>
<p>Located on a nautical crossroads between Europe, Africa and the Americas, Gran Canaria was an important trading post for many centuries and has long welcomed foreign influences, which are evident in everything from local cuisine to the island&rsquo;s ubiquitous Latino beats.<br />
With its year-round sunshine, most come to Gran Canaria to bathe on sweeping sandy beaches, top up on vitamin D and imbibe the island&rsquo;s legendary nightlife. Others come armed with hiking boots and a desire to discover Gran Canaria&rsquo;s glorious interior, which opens up to reveal some truly remarkable landscapes.</p>
<p>The interior remains largely crowd free. Forget sprawling resorts and pumping clubs, its all boutique hotels and bucolic retreats in rural Gran Canaria, where evening entertainment revolves around games of dominoes with locals and watching the sunset over neighbouring Tenerife.<br />
There&rsquo;s also the northern hinterland, which is characterised by verdant mountains, leafy gorges and quaint villages. These landscapes are an extraordinary contrast to the sandy south, where a seemingly vast desert belies the island&rsquo;s diminutive size.</p>
<p>Whether you come to party, soak up the sun or hike through the hills, it&rsquo;s hard not to be charmed by Gran Canaria. The island might be a mainstream destination, but it has the capacity to surprise and that lies at the heart of its appeal.</p><p>Often described as a &ldquo;miniature continent,&rdquo; Gran Canaria is home to a staggering diversity of landscapes; from sweeping sandy beaches and red-earthed pine forests to undulating mountains and dusty deserts. Forming part of the Canary Islands &ndash; a Spanish archipelago floating off the coast of Western Sahara &ndash; the island has long been used as a shortcut to the sun for European holidaymakers. Cheap package deals and boozy British tourists have sullied its sunny image, but in recent years the island has been reinventing itself as a more salubrious destination.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
