<?xml version="1.0"?>
<WTG xmlns:fn="http://www.w3.org/2005/xpath-functions"><Region Name="Spain" ColCode="esp" ParentName="" ParentColCode="" RootName="" RootColCole="" TimaticCode="es" FederalCode="" LocationCode="" LocationName="" RegionLevel="0" RootTimaticCode="" ParentTimaticCode=""><RegionTitle><![CDATA[Spain]]></RegionTitle><Section Name="Climate"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Climate]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Climate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Introduction]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spain's climate varies from temperate in the north to dry and hot in the south. As it is a big country with varying terrain and altitudes, climate can be extremely distinctive from one corner to another. Overall, the coastal regions in the South and Eastern parts of Spain are excellent to visit all year round thanks to the Mediterranean climate (mild temperatures and long days). Northern Spain generally experiences colder temperatures than the South, while Central Spain stays hot and dry due to its location on a plateau.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>The best time to visit depends on the region and type of travel experience you&rsquo;re seeking. For a beach vacation, the best months for guaranteed sunshine are June to August. Naturally, these are also the busiest months for tourism along the coast and on the Spanish islands, so be prepared for high prices and crowds. If you&rsquo;re looking to escape the crowds, head inland to cities like <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seville">Seville</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/madrid">Madrid</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/granada">Granada</a> where temperatures are sizzling but streets are empty.</p>
<br />
<br />
<p>The shoulder season for travel in Spain is usually late spring and autumn: from April to end of May and October to November. These are when tourist destinations are least crowded and weather is still pleasant. January to February is the best time to ski, as snow is ample and the sun is shining. Especially in the Sierra Nevada, the sun can be quite overwhelming even in the snow &ndash; come prepared with snow goggles and sunscreen.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Requiredclothing" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Required Clothing]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From June to August on the coastal areas, casual beach wear like flip flops, vests, loose fitting clothing and shorts will suffice. It can get unbearably hot in the city, so be prepared to brave the weather with plenty of water, a hat and sunscreen.</p>
<p>In between high and low season (April-May; October-November) climate can be unpredictable in certain parts of the country&ndash; be sure to pack your umbrella, raincoat and a light jacket for the night.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TravelInternal"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around By Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Most major provincial cities have an airport served by Iberia (<a href="http://www.iberia.com" target="_blank">www.iberia.com</a>) or its subsidiaries. Other airlines flying domestic routes include Air Europa (<a href="http://www.aireuropa.com" target="_blank">www.aireuropa.com</a>), Spanair and budget operator Vueling (<a href="http://www.vueling.com" target="_blank">www.vueling.com</a>).</p>
<p>Air travel within Spain is generally inexpensive and comfortable. Major domestic routes like Madrid-Barcelona, Madrid-Seville and Madrid-Palma de Mallorca have regular departures. If you&rsquo;re travelling to the islands, flying is the best way to get there, as ferries take much longer time and can cost more than flying. Although bus and train travel in Spain is cheap and comfortable, domestic flights are a good way to save time if you're on a tight schedule. Booking domestic flights in advance is advisable to ensure availability.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main domestic sea routes run from Barcelona, Denia, and Valencia to the Balearic Islands. Other water routes go from C&aacute;diz to the Canary Islands and from Algeciras, Almer&iacute;a, and M&aacute;laga to the North African enclaves of Ceuta and Melilla. Trasmediterranea (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.trasmediterranea.es">www.trasmediterranea.es</a>) is one of the principal operators, while the website&nbsp;<a href="http://www.directferries.es" target="_blank">www.directferries.es</a> covers all routes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spain's high-speed rail network is rapidly expanding, making this a convenient, though expensive way to explore the country. Major internal rail routes are mostly served by high-speed trains: Madrid-Seville, Madrid-Valencia and Madrid-Barcelona (overnight train also available). Another high speed rail route runs Barcelona&ndash;Girona&ndash;Figueras. Nearly all train services are operated by the national rail company RENFE (tel: +34 902 320 320; <a href="http://www.renfe.com" target="_blank">www.renfe.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail One-Country Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month within Spain. Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Travellers under 26 years receive a reduction. Children under 12 travel free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurail Spain Pass:</strong> offers travel for three, four, five or eight days in one month within Spain. Available to non-EU nationals from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Renfe Spain Pass:</strong> allows non-residents to take four, six, eight, 10 or 12 journeys within a month. Available from RENFE (<a href="http://www.renfe.com" target="_blank">www.renfe.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingAroundByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[r<p>In general, roads in Spain are well maintained and form a comprehensive network across the whole country. Some motorways are operated by tolls and they can be paid in cash or by card. More highways are clearly marked and road signs are easy to read, although most of the time they are only in Spanish. Rural roads are of differing quality. Roads within city centres can be narrow and congested with traffic (especially during peak hours). Regardless of your driving experience, it's generally easy to get around Spain.</p><p>Travelling by bus is the most popular way of getting around Spain. Major domestic coach routes include Madrid-Seville, Madrid-Barcelona and Madrid-Valencia. The main bus operators are Avanza (tel: +34 91 272 2832;&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.avanzabus.com">www.avanzabus.com</a>), ALSA (tel: +34 902 422 242;&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.alsa.es">www.alsa.es</a>) and Eurolines (tel: +34 91 506 3360;&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.eurolines.es">www.eurolines.es</a>).</p><p>Taxis in Spain are generally safe and easy to find, especially in major cities. In small towns, it&rsquo;s best to look up the taxi hotline beforehand and dial a cab when you need it. As compared to most western European cities, taxis in Spain are reasonably priced. There is a surcharge when taking taxis from the airport, bus terminal or train station; be sure to check with your taxi driver beforehand.</p><p>A passport and a valid driving licence are required. Most foreign licences including Canadian, EU and US are accepted. A valid international insurance policy is also necessary, although this can be purchased at the time of hire.</p><p>Seat belts must be worn at all times when driving in Spain.<strong> </strong>Spare bulbs, red hazard triangles and a reflective vest or jacket must be kept in all vehicles. Parking laws are rigorously enforced. Speed limits are 120kph (75mph) on motorways, 100kph (62mph) on dual carriageways, 90kph (56mph) outside built-up areas and 50kph (31mph) within towns.</p><p>Real Autom&oacute;vil Club de Espa&ntilde;a (RACE) (tel: +34 900 100 992, <a href="http://www.race.es" target="_blank">www.race.es</a>).</p><p>All major car hire companies like Avis, Europcar and&nbsp;Hertz&nbsp;are represented in major cities, resorts and airports. Drivers must be over 21 to hire a car.</p><p>There have been many improvements to the network of cycling paths all over Spain, especially in Madrid, Barcelona and Seville. Bicycles are cheap and easy to hire in most Spanish cities and some of them have public bikeshare systems.</p>
<p>Bicing (<a href="http://www.bicing.cat" target="_blank">www.bicing.cat</a>) in Barcelona provides affordable rental to the public. Sign up for a card online, swipe it in any of the bike stations around Barcelona and a bike is unlocked and ready for use. Sevici in Seville (<a href="http://www.sevici.es" target="_blank">www.sevici.es</a>) works the same way; a deposit is required but hire rates are very cheap. In Madrid, you can try out BiciMAD (<a href="http://www.bicimad.com" target="_blank">www.bicimad.com</a>).</p><p>Seat belts must be worn at all times when driving in Spain.<strong> </strong>Spare bulbs, red hazard triangles and a reflective vest or jacket must be kept in all vehicles. Parking laws are rigorously enforced. Speed limits are 120kph (75mph) on motorways, 100kph (62mph) on dual carriageways, 90kph (56mph) outside built-up areas and 50kph (31mph) within towns.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Urban" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting Around Towns and Cities]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traffic in major Spanish cities can get chaotic, and urban driving takes some time to adjust to. City public transport facilities are generally affordable and safe, although it&rsquo;s advisable to be careful of pickpockets on the metro.</p>
<p>Barcelona, Bilbao, Madrid, Malaga, Sevilla and Valencia have metro systems. All cities and towns have bus networks, although buses in small towns tend to have limited departures (be sure to check the timetable). Other towns and resorts are well served by local buses. Metered taxis are available in all major towns and cities.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="JourneyTimes" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Journey Times]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><table class="DataTable"><tr><td CLASS="DataHead">From</td><td CLASS="DataHead">To</td><TD CLASS="DataHead">Air</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Road</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">Rail</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Spain</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">servilla</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">5.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Spain</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">palma</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.10</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">4.30*</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00*</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Spain</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">canary_is</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">2.30</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">n/a</TD></tr><tr><TD CLASS="DataHead">Spain</TD><TD CLASS="DataHead">barcelona</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">1.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">6.00</TD><TD CLASS="DataCell">3.00</TD></tr></table></DataInfo></OutputData></Section>
	--&gt;
	<Section Name="TravelInternational"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Getting There]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Air]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spain's main carrier is Iberia (<a href="http://www.iberia.com" target="_blank">www.iberia.com</a>). Multiple airlines offer flights to Spain from the UK, including British Airways (<a href="http://www.ba.com" target="_blank">www.ba.com</a>), easyJet (<a href="http://www.easyjet.com" target="_blank">www.easyjet.com</a>) and Ryanair (<a href="http://www.ryanair.com" target="_blank">www.ryanair.com</a>). American Airlines (<a href="http://www.aa.com" target="_blank">www.aa.com</a>), Delta (<a href="http://www.delta.com" target="_blank">www.delta.com</a>) and United (<a href="http://www.united.com" target="_blank">www.united.com</a>) are among the airlines flying direct from the USA.</p>
<p>Flights tend to be most expensive in summer, from June to September. The cheapest time to travel is from November to December (outside of the Christmas season).</p>
<p>Major airports are: <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/alicante-airport">Alicante Airport</a>,  <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/barcelona-airport">Barcelona Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bilbao-airport">Bilbao Airport</a>, Federico Garcia Lorca Granda-Jaen Airport, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/madrid-barajas-airport">Madrid Barajas Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/malaga-airport">Malaga Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/seville-airport">Seville Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/valencia-airport">Valencia Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/balearic-islands/ibiza/ibiza-airport">Ibiza Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/balearic-islands/menorca/menorca-airport">Menorca Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/palma/palma-de-mallorca-airport">Palma Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/gran-canaria/gran-canaria-airport">Gran Canaria Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/mallorca/lanzarote-airport">Lanzarote Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/tenerife/tenerife-south-reina-sofia-airport">Tenerife Sur Airport</a>, <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands/fuerteventura/fuerteventura-airport">Fuerteventura Airport</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/jerez-airport">Jerez Airport</a>.</p>]]></DataInfo><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>To <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/madrid">Madrid</a>: from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/london">London</a> - 2 hours 20 minutes; <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/new-york-city">New York</a> - 7 hours 15 minutes.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Air Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAir" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Departure Tax]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>None.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByAirNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="InternationalAirports" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Main Airports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Alicante-Elche Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Alicante Airport is located 9km (5.3 miles) southwest of <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/alicante">Alicante</a>.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 91 321 1000.</p>]]><b>Barcelona Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Barcelona Airport is located 12km (8 miles) southwest of central Barcelona.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 913 211 000</p>]]><b>Adolfo Suárez Madrid-Barajas Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Madrid-Barajas Airport is located 12km (8 miles) northeast of Madrid.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 91 321 1000</p>]]><b>Malaga Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Malaga Airport is situated 8km (5 miles) southwest of Malaga city centre, and 5km (3 miles) north of Torremolinos.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 91 321 1000</p>]]><b>Palma de Mallorca Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Palma de Mallorca Airport is located 8km (5 miles) east of Palma de Mallorca.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 91 321 1000</p>]]><b>Valencia Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Valencia Airport is located 8km (5 miles) to the west of Valencia.</p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 902 40 47 04</p>]]><b>Seville San Pablo Airport</b><![CDATA[http://www.aena.es<p>Seville Airport is located 10km (6 miles) to the northeast of Seville, </p>]]><b>Tel: </b><![CDATA[<p>+34 902 404 704</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByWater" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Water]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>With its coastlines surrounded by the Mediterranean Sea and Atlantic Ocean, Spain is an excellent destination to explore on water. By boat, it is easy and convenient to travel from Spain to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/morocco">Morocco</a>, France, the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/balearic-islands">Balearic Islands</a> and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/spain/canary-islands">Canary Islands</a>. Its major ports include Algeciras (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.apba.es">www.apba.es</a>), <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/bilbao">Bilbao</a> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.bilbaoport.es">www.bilbaoport.es</a>), Barcelona (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.apb.es">www.apb.es</a>), Santander (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.puertosantander.es">www.puertosantander.es</a>) and <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/valencia">Valencia</a> (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.valenciaport.com">www.valenciaport.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Rail]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The main rail route from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a> is through the Channel Tunnel, with connections from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/paris">Paris</a> to Spain. Eurostar (tel:&nbsp;+44 1233 617 575, in the UK; <a href="http://www.eurostar.com" target="_blank">www.eurostar.com</a>) operates direct high-speed trains from London to Paris (Gare du Nord).</p>
<p>There are direct trains from <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/france">France</a> and Portugal to Madrid and Barcelona. Border connections link with the French TGV (high-velocity route) and the rest of the high-velocity routes in Europe. RENFE (tel: +34 902 320 320; <a href="http://www.renfe.com" target="_blank">www.renfe.com</a>) operates the Spanish railway network.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRail" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Rail Passes]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p><strong>InterRail:</strong> offers unlimited first- or second-class travel in up to 29 European countries for European residents of over six months with two pass options. The Global Pass allows travel for 15 days, 22 days, one month, five days in 10 days or 10 days in 22 days across all countries. The One-Country Pass offers travel for three, four, six or eight days in one month in any of the countries except Bosnia &amp; Herzegovina and Montenegro.</p>
<p>Travel is not allowed in the passenger's country of residence. Reductions are available for travellers under 26. Children under 12 are free when travelling with an adult using an Adult Pass. Supplements are required for some high-speed services, seat reservations and couchettes. Discounts are offered on Eurostar and some ferry routes. Available from Voyages-sncf.com (tel: +44 844 848 5848, in the UK; <a href="http://www.voyages-sncf.com" target="_blank">www.voyages-sncf.com</a>).</p>
<p><strong>Eurailpass:</strong> offers unlimited train travel in up to 28 European countries. Tickets are valid for 15 days, 21 days, one month, two months, three months, five days in 10 days, 10 days in two months or 15 days in two months. The Global Pass allows travel across all participating countries. The Select Pass is valid in four bordering countries. The Regional Pass lets you travel in two bordering countries. The One Country Pass offers travel in one of 27 countries.</p>
<p>Adult passes are valid for first-class travel, while youth passes (under 26) are valid for second-class travel. Children under 12 are free when accompanied by an adult using an Adult Pass. The passes cannot be sold to EU citizens or residents. Available from Eurail (<a href="http://www.eurail.com" target="_blank">www.eurail.com</a>).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GettingThereByRoad" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Getting There by Road]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Road conditions in Spain are generally good, but beware of steep and narrow mountain roads. The country is mapped out with well-connected roads, making cities and towns easily accessible by car.</p>
<p>The major driving routes into Spain cut through the French and Portuguese borders. The N-I links the French border to Madrid (via Burgos and Ir&uacute;n) and the N-II to <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/barcelona">Barcelona</a> (via Zaragoza). From <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/portugal">Portugal</a>, the southern route via the coast, E1 (A49), passes through <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/seville">Seville</a>, Huelva and Faro; while the northern route, E90 (A6) links Badajoz with <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/lisbon">Lisbon</a>.</p>
<p>Eurolines international coach services (<a href="http://www.eurolines.com" target="_blank">www.eurolines.com</a>) has several bus routes that serve major cities in Spain, with connections to destinations across Europe.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Communications"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Communications]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[
				Country Code: <p>Most telephone boxes require telephone cards that can be purchased in grocery stores. Call centres and internet cafés allow you to call overseas at a lower rate. Area codes are incorporated within a nine digit number dialled from wherever you are. Emergency calls: 112.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Mobile telephone" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Mobile Telephone]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Roaming agreements exist with most international mobile phone companies. Coverage is good throughout most of the country. It is relatively easy to get a mobile phone to use temporarily in Spain. Most service providers like Vodafone, Orange and Telefonica offer prepaid SIM cards (that include data roaming). Spanish mobile numbers begin with 6.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Internet" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Internet]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi is ubiquitous across much of Spain, and is often available free of charge in hotels, restaurants and other establishments. Internet cafés are available in most urban areas.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Media" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Media]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Broadcasting in Spain has witnessed a spectacular expansion in recent years with the emergence of new commercial operators and the launch of digital services. The main TV broadcaster is the state-owned TVE which operates TV-1 and TV-2. Antena 3, La Cuatro, Telecinco and La Sexta are privately run channels.</p>
<p>The main English language papers in Spain are <em>The Olive Press</em> (<a href="http://www.theolivepress.es" target="_blank">www.theolivepress.es</a>; available in various restaurants and hotels in Andalusia) and <em>Sur in English</em> (<a href="http://www.surinenglish.com" target="_blank">www.surinenglish.com</a>; found in establishments along the southern coastline). UK papers are mostly available in Madrid, Barcelona and major tourist beach towns in Costa del Sol and the Balearic Islands.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Post" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Post]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There are efficient internal and international postal services to all countries from Spain. The postal service is generally cheap and efficient. The main postal company in Spain is Correos, but there are also private companies like Fedex and Sears for express delivery service.  Airmail within Europe usually takes around five days.</p><p>Mon-Fri 0800-2000 and Sat 0800-1400.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToSee"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToSee" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To See]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>Acueducto de Segovia (Roman Aqueduct at Segovia)</p><![CDATA[<p>One of the best preserved Roman constructions, the Roman Aqueduct at Segovia was still in use as recently as 50 years ago. Constructed around AD 50 during the reign of the Roman Emperor Trajan out of some 200,400 granite blocks, the aqueduct was made without concrete and stands due to the equal balance of forces. When in use, it carried water from the River Frio to the city of Segovia over a distance of 16km (ten miles). The portion of the aqueduct that is above ground is 728m (2388ft) in length and consists of 165 arches, each over 9m (30ft) high, which are spectacularly illuminated at night. It is possible to climb a staircase next to the aqueduct to get views over the structure itself as well as the city.</p>]]><br/><p>Caves of Drach (Cuevas del Drach)</p><![CDATA[<p>The Caves of Drach are the most famous tourist attraction on the island of Mallorca. There are three chambers inside the caves, Cueva Negra (Black Cave), Cueva Blanca (White Cave) and Cueva Luis Salvator (Luis Salvator Cave). The latter is named after the Archduke Ludwig Salvator of Austria who invited &Eacute;douard-Alfred Martel to explore the caves in 1896; the caves are also home to Lago Martel (Lake Martel), one of the largest subterranean lakes in the world. Visitors can take a boat ride on the lake and see the beautiful limestone formations, including stalagmites protuding from the rockface and stalactites hanging down from the roof of the cave. As part of their journey underground, they are accompanied by the sound of musicians performing classical music, including compositions by Chopin, every hour on a boat.</p>]]><br/><p>Garajonay National Park</p><![CDATA[<p>Situated in the very centre of the island of La Gomera in the Canary Islands archipelago, Garajonay National Park boasts stunning scenery set amongst rocky vistas and is a popular visit for outdoor enthusiasts. Measuring 3,984 hectares (9,845 acres), the area became a designated national park in 1981 and was inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage list in 1986 in recognition of the its outstanding natural beauty. Laurel forest covers 70 per cent of the park and numerous springs and streams and the regularity of the ocean mist assure the growth of lush vegetation much of which is unique to the park. Garajonay is a welcome respite from the livelier towns and resorts of the Canary Islands and is tranquil haven that attracts approximately 450,000 visitors each year. There's also a visitor information and education centre at Juego de Bolos just outside the park boundary.</p>]]><br/><p>Monastery of San Lorenzo de El Escorial</p><![CDATA[<p>The Monastery of San Lorenzo de El Escorial was built in the latter half of the 16th century by King Philip II of Spain, to commemorate his victory over the French at the battle of San Quentin. Housing a monastery, two palaces and a library, the complex was intended to serve all the functions of church and state. The magnificent interior houses numerous works of art as well as 40,000 volumes in the library that was founded by Philip II himself. The monastery is famous for its symmetrical design, with four towers marking each of the monastery's four corners, and for being the resting place of the remains of many Spanish kings and queens in the Baroque Royal Pantheo<em>n</em>.<strong><br />
</strong></p>]]><br/><p>Pilgrim's Way</p><![CDATA[<p>The Pilgrim's Way (also known as St James' Way) is in fact a number of different walking trails that all lead to the cathedral of St James in Santiago de Compostela in Galicia in northwest Spain. It's here where the body of the fisherman and apostle Saint James the Great is said to have been laid to rest in the eighth century. The origins of the trail date back to this time when Christian pilgrims would set off on the annual journey to the saint's final resting place. It is one of the most important Christian pilgrimages alongside those to Rome and Jerusalem. The Pilgrim's Way still attracts thousands of pilgrims each year in addition to recreational walkers who come to enjoy this popular walking trail.  The route is marked with a scallop shell, the symbol of St James.</p>]]><br/><p>Terra Mítica</p><![CDATA[<p>Opened in 2000, Terra Mítica is a giant amusement park located just outside the popular Spanish resort of Benidorm. As well as regular live shows, there are five different areas at the park, all of which are associated with the Mediterranean Sea: <em>Egypt, Iberia, Greece, Rome </em>and<em> The Islands</em>. At the park, visitors can travel through ancient civilisations and go on the many themed rides. En route, visitors will encounter characters and creatures from many myths and legends, including coming face-to-face with the Minotaur on <em>El Laberinto del Minotauro</em> (Minotaur's Labyrinth) and attempting to rescue Ulysses on the <em>El Rescate de Ulises</em> (Ulysses' Rescue) ride.<br /><strong>Air:</strong> Alicante Airport. <strong>Rail:</strong> Train: Terra Mítica Station. <strong>Road:</strong> Car: A-7 to Terra Mítica's exit which is signposted between Benidorm and Villajoyosa (from Valencia or Alicante).</p>]]><br/><p>Universal Mediterranea</p><![CDATA[<p>This giant theme park, which opened in 1994, attracts thousands of holidaymakers every year who journey through its five worlds (<em>Mediterránia, Far West, Mexico, Polynesia </em>and<em> China</em>) on its many rides and attractions. Enjoying an enviable coastal location, between Salou and Vila-seca on Spain's Costa Dorada, this 117-hectare site (289 acre) boasts entertainment aimed at all age groups. There are nightly shows, including <em>Fiestaventura</em> in the Mediterranean world, as well as many other attractions, including the<em> Sea Odyssey</em> underwater adventure, the<em> Stampida</em> roller coaster ride, and the <em>Grand Canyon Rapids</em> and <em>Tutuki Splash</em> water rides. Visitors who wish to spend a few days in the park can stay in one of the many hotels on site.<br /><strong>Air:</strong> Barcelona International Airport, Reus Airport. <strong>Rail:</strong> Train: Port Aventura Station.<strong> Road:</strong> Car: Hwy-A7 or Hwy-N340 (from Valencia or Barcelona); Hwy-N240 or Hwy-N420 (from Tarragona).</p>]]><br/></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="TopThingsToDo"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="TopThingsToDo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Top Things To Do]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Be captivated by culture in Madrid</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Culture lovers should explore Spain's capital, Madrid. Museu del Prado is a must; it boasts one of Europe's finest collections of art. Also worthy of a visit is the Museo Nacional Centro de Arte Reina Sofia, which focuses on modern art and houses Picasso's famous Guernica. Don't miss the Museo Thyssen-Bornemisza, Madrid's Royal Palace, the atmosphere around Puerta del Sol and Madrid's historic square, the Plaza Mayor<strong>.</strong></p>]]><p><b>Be charmed by Córdoba</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Discover Moorish Spain in the winding streets of Córdoba, the former seat of the 10th-century Caliphate. The Mezquita (Great Mosque) is a mystic wonder and World Heritage Site. Originally a pagan temple, then a Christian Church, the Moors converted it into a mosque. Just outside the city, the ruins of Medina Azahara are similarly atmospheric.</p>]]><p><b>Board a boat to the Caves of Drach (Cuevas del Drach)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Explore the Caves of Drach on the island of Mallorca. There are three chambers inside, Cueva Negra (Black Cave), Cueva Blanca (White Cave) and Cueva Luis Salvator (Luis Salvator Cave), as well as Lago Martel (Lake Martel), one of the largest subterranean lakes in the world. Take a boat ride to this otherworldly spot and see the beautiful limestone formations.</p>]]><p><b>Brave a bullfight (or at bull ring tour)</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The controversial tradition of bullfighting is still very much alive in Spain, especially so in Madrid. Most towns only hold bullfights during their annual spring or summer fiestas, but Madrid's Las Ventas Bullfighting Ring hold regular corridas. If an actual bullfight seems to much, Las Ventas also offer guided tours for those that wish to understand the history.</p>]]><p><b>Discover the dazzling Garajonay National Park</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Situated in the very centre of La Gomera in the Canary Islands, Garajonay National Park boasts stunning scenery set amongst rocky vistas. Measuring 3,984 hectares (9,845 acres), the area was inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage list in 1986 in recognition of the its outstanding natural beauty. Well-marked trails make it a popular visit for outdoor enthusiasts. </p>]]><p><b>Explore the Catalan capital, Barcelona</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Immerse yourself in Barcelona, from the cramped alleyways of the Barri Gótic (Gothic quarter) to the 19th-century Eixample quarter, where many Gaudi buildings lie. Stroll along the Rambla and onto old Barceloneta and the seafront. Sights include the Sagrada Familia (Holy Family), the Seu (old cathedral), the Episcopal Palace and the Palau de la Generalitat. </p>]]><p><b>Have a scream at Universal Mediterranea</b></p><![CDATA[<p>This giant theme park, which opened in 1994, boasts five different worlds (Mediterránia, Far West, Mexico, Polynesia and China) of rides and attractions. Enjoying an enviable coastal location, between Salou and Vila-seca on Spain's Costa Dorada, this 117-hectare site (289 acre) is aimed at all ages and includes on-site hotels.</p>]]><p><b>Hear the blast of bagpipes in Asturias</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The green valleys and picturesque fishing villages of this northern province don't feel like traditional Spain, and when you encounter the cider culture and bagpipes you'll wonder just how strong Celtic roots can be. Super seafood and hospitality redeem the regular rain showers.</p>]]><p><b>Hit the coast for some watersports</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Swimming, jetskiing and waterskiing facilities can be found at nearly all seaside resorts. Spain's premier resort for windsurfing and kitesurfing is Tarifa, on the Atlantic coast, and it is blessed with strong winds and a beautiful stretch of aqua-blue sea. Surfing is big in the north, particularly around the Basque village of Mundaka. Spain is also great for sailing.</p>]]><p><b>Immerse yourself in the Cádiz province</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The province that packs it all in could take weeks of your time, from the hiking around the picturesque white villages of its interior to its breezy Atlantic beaches and world-famous Sanlúcar prawns. Cádiz itself is a spectacular peninsular city with a unique atmosphere, while Jerez is home of sherry.</p>]]><p><b>Play a round of Golf</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Golf is immensely popular, with Costa del Sol and La Manga two of Spain's premier golfing destinations. The south of Spain has over 200 golf courses including the famed fairways of Valderrama, plus many of mainland Europe's finest championship courses. PGA Catalunya, near Girona is a challenging round for amateurs and professionals alike.</p>]]><p><b>Run with bulls in Pamplona</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Run with (or rather, from) the Jandilla fighting bulls or join with the crowds at the Festival of San Fermín in Pamplona. The famous Running of the Bulls through the streets of the centre takes place in July and attracts huge numbers of tourists.</p>]]><p><b>Savour the delights of Bilbao</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Visit Frank Gehry's marvellous Guggenheim Museum, which has turned the main city of the Basque region into a top tourist destination. The museum is a masterpiece of 20th-century architecture. Bilbao's Old Town is extensive with a gothic cathedral and atmospheric shopping streets studded with gourmet <em>pintxo</em> bars.</p>]]><p><b>See the symmetrical Monastery of San Lorenzo de El Escorial</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The Monastery of San Lorenzo de El Escorial was built in the 16th century by King Philip II of Spain. Famed for its symmetrical design, with four towers marking each of the monastery's four corners, the magnificent interior houses art world and a 40,000-volume library. Its baroque Royal Pantheon is the resting place of many Spanish monarchs.</p>]]><p><b>Seek out the sights of Sevilla</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Andalucía's hedonistic capital, Sevilla, is the romantic heart of Spain and home of flamenco, Carmen and Don Juan. Wander the narrow streets of the Jewish quarter, snacking at tapas bars, and admire the immense cathedral, the world's largest gothic temple and third largest Christian church. Opposite, the Alcázar is a superb example of Mudéjar (Christian-Moorish) architecture.</p>]]><p><b>Stand in awe at the Alhambra</b></p><![CDATA[<p>The impressive palace-fortress of Alhambra is a supreme creation of Moorish Spain, featuring majestic Arabic gates, intricate carvings and patios – Spain's most significant Islamic architecture. Perched on the hilltop of Granada city, this UNESCO World Heritage Site is one of the most visited monuments in Spain.</p>]]><p><b>Stroll Spain's ancient capital, Toledo</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Head south of Madrid to this ancient Spanish capital, which is dominated by the magnificent cathedral and Alcázar. The cathedral has a magnificent series of paintings by El Greco, who made his home here; his <em>Burial of the Count of Orgaz</em> is in the Santo Tomé Church.</p>]]><p><b>Trek the pilgrim way, Camino de Santiago</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Known as St James' Way, the pilgrimage route is a number of different walking trails that lead to the St James Cathedral in Santiago de Compostela, Galicia in northwest Spain. This was originally a pilgrimage route, although it has become a recreational trail. The route is marked with a scallop shell, the symbol of St James.</p>]]><p><b>Uncover the Holy Grail in Valencia</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Check out Santiago Calatrava's City of Arts and Science Park in this forward-looking southeastern city. The Hemispheric, an amazing glass structure, houses a planetarium, IMAX dome and laserium. While in Valencia, visit the cathedral, it claims possession of the Holy Grail, the chalice used at the Last Supper.</p>]]><p><b>Visit Spain's attractive monasteries</b></p><![CDATA[<p>Heartbreakingly beautiful Romanesque and gothic architecture can be found across the north of the country, with the lonely San Juan de la Peña in the Pyrenees competing with Soria's San Juan de Duero and Burgos province's Santo Domingo de Silos as the most atmospheric cloisters.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="BusinessProfile"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Business]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Statistics" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Statistics]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>GDP: </b><![CDATA[<p>US$1.303 trillion (2017).</p>]]><b>Main Exports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery, motor vehicles, food, pharmaceuticals and medicines.</p>]]><b>Main Imports: </b><![CDATA[<p>Machinery and equipment, fuels, chemicals, semi-finished goods and food.</p>]]><b>Main Trade Partners: </b><![CDATA[<p>France, Germany, Italy, UK and Portugal.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Economy" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Economy]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The economy in Spain suffered tremendously under the global economic downturn of the early 21st century. The unemployment rate reached a new Eurozone high at 21.3% in early 2011, with a record of 4.9 million people unemployed, but by 2017 it had fallen to 18.9% - the lowest in six years - and things are improving.&nbsp;The inflation rate in Spain fluctuated from 3 to 3.8% in 2011 but was 2.9% in early 2017.</p>
<p>The agricultural sector produces cereals, vegetables, fruit, olive oil, meat and wine. The fishing fleet, although reduced, remains one of the world's largest. In the Canary Islands, bananas are the main crop produced by the agricultural industry, with  just over 90% of produce going to the mainland. In fact, the Canary Islands  are the largest banana producer in the EU. The next most important crop  is tomatoes, followed by potatoes, flowers and ornamental plants and  vines.</p>
<p>Many of the larger hotels have comprehensive conference centres.  There are also a number of dedicated convention centres both in the  north and south of the island.In the service sector, Spain is the second most-popular destination in the world and has a vast tourism industry.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Business" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Etiquette]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s important to understand the language nuances in Spain. Many Spanish business people speak English or French. In Barcelona, Catalan is used in a business setting among native speakers; otherwise Castilian Spanish is used, like in other parts of Spain.</p>
<p>When greeting business acquaintances, you usually shake hands; although in a more casual setting, you will probably be greeted with double kisses and a hug. For ladies, expect two kisses (right cheek followed by left) whereas men may just receive a quick hug or handshake from the same gender.</p>
<p>Formal wear is the norm and both men and women should wear a suit for business meetings - men usually wear a tie to business meetings, although in summer this is more relaxed. Scruffiness is frowned upon.</p>
<p>Business cards are usually exchanged after introduction. All Spaniards have two family names - only the first is used in conversation, but any academic or professional titles should be acknowledged.</p>
<p>In Barcelona, invitations to homes are not common and clients or business associates tend to be invited out, usually to pre-dinner drinks and tapas or dinner. In Madrid, breakfast meetings are also popular.</p><p>In Barcelona, Seville and Granada, business hours are generally 0800/0900-1800/1900, with an extended lunch break from 1330-1500/1600. In Santiago de Compostela and Malaga, office hours are generally 0900-1400 and 1700-2000. Banks and government offices open only in the morning.</p>
<p>In Madrid, standard business hours are Monday to Friday 0900-1400 and 1600-1900, although 0800-1500 is quite common during summer. Larger companies and multinationals, however, are increasingly working through the day, in line with the rest of Europe</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CommercialInfo" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Business Contacts]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Consejo Superior de Cámaras de Comercio</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 915 906 900
					Website:http://www.camaras.org/
					Address: Calle Ribera del Loira 12,Industria y Navegación de España,Madrid,28042]]><b>Madrid Espacio y Congresos</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 917 220 400
					Website:http://www.madridespaciosycongresos.com
					Address: ,Avda. Capital de España Madrid 7,Madrid,28042]]><b>Spain Convention Bureau (FEMP)</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 9136 4 3700
					Website:http://www.scb.es/
					Address: ,Calle Nuncio 8,Madrid,28005]]><b>Ministerio de Industria, Turismo y Comercio</b><![CDATA[
					Telephone: 9024 46006
					Website:http://www.comercio.es/
					Address: ,Paseo de la Castellana 160,Madrid,28046]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="SocialConventions"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Going Out]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="FoodDrink" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Spain's eating and drinking culture is one of its greatest attractions, and a very sociable one too, with people rubbing shoulders in tapas bars and caf&eacute;s. The Spaniards take their food seriously &ndash; be it diner-style <em>menus del dia</em> (menus of the day) or elaborate, nouveau cuisine in gourmet restaurants. Food is generally dictated by the seasons and fresh, whichever corner of Spain you go to.</p>
<p>An excellent way to understand different facets of Spanish cuisine is to sample tapas (<em>pintxos</em> in the Basque Country): small snacks served with drinks in local bars across the country. They can range from gourmet canap&eacute;s to simple plates of olives, cheeses and cured meats, and may be charged or given free.</p>
<p>Spanish drinks have also brewed up quite a storm worldwide &ndash; from the thirst-quenching sangria to bubbly Cava to the sophisticated Rioja wine.</p>]]><b>Regional Specialities: </b><![CDATA[<p><strong>Paella:</strong> A Valencian rice dish loaded with seafood and chicken or rabbit, saffron and vegetables. <br />
<strong>Croquetas:</strong> Fried bread-crumbed fritters with a creamy, potato interior. <br />
<strong>Cocido:</strong> A fragrant and rich chickpea and meat stew popular in Madrid. <br />
<strong>Tortilla Espaniola:</strong> A rich, chunky potato omelette &ndash; a staple throughout Spain.<br />
<strong>Gazpacho:</strong> A chilled tomato-based, tangy vegetable soup from Andaluc&iacute;a.<br />
<strong>Jam&oacute;n:</strong> One of many cured Spanish meats, Jam&oacute;n is a type of finely sliced cured ham.<br />
<strong>Pulpo &aacute; feira:</strong> Tender, boiled lobster seasoned with paprika and salt and drizzled in olive oil.  <br />
<strong>Chorizo:</strong> A dried and course pork sausage seasoned with smoked paprika.<br />
<strong>Bacalao al pil:</strong> A Basque Country dish of salt cod with a velvety white olive-oil emulsion. <br />
<strong>Sherry:</strong> A fortified wine available in several styles: Fino and Manzanilla (pale and dry), amontillado (dry, richer in body and darker in colour), Oloroso (medium, full-bodied, fragrant and golden) and sweet sherries such as Pedro Xim&eacute;nez.<br />
<strong>Rioja:</strong> Spain&rsquo;s flagship red wine, made from Tempranillo and Garnacha grapes.<br />
<strong>Cava:</strong> A sparkling wine from Catalonia made using the same method used to produce Champagne.<br />
<strong>Albondigas:</strong> Fried Spanish-style meatballs, usually smothered in tomato sauce.</p>]]><b>Things to Know:</b><![CDATA[<p>Most restaurants serve a <em>men&uacute; del d&iacute;a</em> at lunchtime; this is a three-course meal including drinks that generally costs from &euro;10 to &euro;20 and can be very good value.</p>]]><b>Tipping:</b><![CDATA[<p>Spanish VAT (IVA) of 10% is included in most menu prices and 5% is customary.</p>]]><b>Drinking Age:</b><![CDATA[<p>16 for wine and beer, 18 for spirits.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Nightlife" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Nightlife]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spaniards often start the evening with<em> el paseo</em> - a leisurely stroll through the city&rsquo;s streets. A caf&eacute; terrace is an excellent vantage point to observe this tradition. The atmosphere is especially vibrant at fiesta time. They then continue the night with a tapeo, moving between tapas bars, drinking and snacking. Tapas culture is especially rich in Madrid and Andalusia, whilst San Sebastian and Bilbao are famed for the more sophisticated version &ndash; <em>pintxos</em>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Then it's time for <em>copas</em> or <em>cubatas</em> - mixed drinks in bars, pubs, or nightclubs. Trendy nightlife can be found in the major cities like Barcelona and Madrid, and in coastal resorts like Ibiza or Marbella, but even small villages will have somewhere where you can dance till dawn.</p>
<p>For a taste of something local, head out to the <em>flamenco</em> <em>tablaos</em> for a spectacle. The best places to see a flamenco spectacle are in Andaluc&iacute;a, specifically Sevilla, where veteran dancers take to the stage and stomp their feet to atmospheric tunes in authentic caves.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re seeking something mellower, jazz bars in Barcelona, Madrid and Granada are well worth a visit. In summer, music concerts are filled to the brim with partygoers where music performances go late into the night &ndash; with the most popular ones being Sonar and Primavera Sound Festival. Rave parties are aplenty especially on Ibiza island, where the fun continues until the sun comes up.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Shopping" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Shopping]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for unique souvenirs, there are plenty of artisan markets in Madrid and Andaluc&iacute;a. A myriad of handicraft, porcelain figures and accessories are sold in these markets. They are often set up during festive season like Christmas and New Years.</p>
<p>Spanish leather goods, particularly those from Andaluc&iacute;a, combine excellent craftsmanship with high-quality design. Catalonian textiles are internationally famous and there are mills throughout the region. Fine rugs and carpets are made in C&aacute;ceres, Granada and Murcia. The numerous excellent sherries, wines and spirits produced in Andaluc&iacute;a make good souvenirs to take home, as do bottles of Spain's excellent olive oil. Fine, handcrafted wooden furniture is one of the outstanding products of Valencia, which holds an annual international furniture fair. Alicante is an important centre for toy manufacturing.</p>
<p>Spanish fashion is taking the world by storm these days, but even in globally renowned stores like Zara you find plenty of clothing lines that don't make it beyond the border. The best cities for shopping are Madrid and Barcelona, but all provincial capitals have a decent range of retail outlets. Prices have risen in recent years but are still cheaper than in much of northern Europe.</p>
<p>Every town in Spain has its own market halls where you can buy fresh produce direct from growers, and many have a <em>rastro</em> (flea market); Madrid's characterful el Rastro on Sundays is particularly famous.</p><p>Mon-Sat 1000-1400 and 1700-2000. Supermarkets and department stores tend to open 0930-2100/2200, and may open on Sundays in large cities.</p><p>For non-EU visitors it is possible to get a tax refund on purchases made in Spain. The items must be exported back to your country of origin (hotels and restaurants, for example are not eligible) and each individual bill must be over &euro;90.15. Show your passport, ask the vendor for a VAT (IVA) refund form and submit it at the airport upon your departure. VAT in Spain is 21%.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Accommodation"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Hotels" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Hotels]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Both international and domestic tourism are huge in Spain, with tourism being the main industry of the country, so don&rsquo;t be surprised by the vast range of accommodation available throughout Spain. Hotels in Spain usually offer <em>media pensi&oacute;n</em> or <em>pensi&oacute;n completa</em> (half-board or full-board) rates, differing in the amount of meals included. Large city hotels usually offer discounted weekend rates and most charge extra for parking, while bed and breakfasts and lodges in the countryside rarely do so. It is always advisable to book accommodation well in advance, particularly during festivals or at popular resorts on the coast from late spring to October. Most hotels in Spain offer Wi-Fi service, although mostly are charged based on an hourly rate.</p>
<p><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels are graded from 1 to 5 stars with some regional variations. Hotels of three stars and above must have bar/caf&eacute; service with breakfast available and many of these categories have full restaurants. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="GuestHouses" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Guest Houses/Bed and Breakfast]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The twin staples of Spanish budget accommodation are the <em>hostal</em> (guest house) and <em>pensi&oacute;n</em>, providing private rooms with or without bathroom. They are usually run by families and may provide meals. Classification varies by region, but these accommodation options generally range from 1 to 2 stars. Prices can differ greatly depending on location (city or countryside).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CampingCaravaning" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Camping/Caravanning]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Both international and domestic tourism are huge in Spain, with tourism being the main industry of the country, so don&rsquo;t be surprised by the vast range of accommodation available throughout Spain. Hotels in Spain usually offer <em>media pensi&oacute;n</em> or <em>pensi&oacute;n completa</em> (half-board or full-board) rates, differing in the amount of meals included. Large city hotels usually offer discounted weekend rates and most charge extra for parking, while bed and breakfasts and lodges in the countryside rarely do so. It is always advisable to book accommodation well in advance, particularly during festivals or at popular resorts on the coast from late spring to October. Most hotels in Spain offer Wi-Fi service, although mostly are charged based on an hourly rate.</p>
<p><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels are graded from 1 to 5 stars with some regional variations. Hotels of three stars and above must have bar/caf&eacute; service with breakfast available and many of these categories have full restaurants. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="OtherAccommodation" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Accommodation Information]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Both international and domestic tourism are huge in Spain, with tourism being the main industry of the country, so don&rsquo;t be surprised by the vast range of accommodation available throughout Spain. Hotels in Spain usually offer <em>media pensi&oacute;n</em> or <em>pensi&oacute;n completa</em> (half-board or full-board) rates, differing in the amount of meals included. Large city hotels usually offer discounted weekend rates and most charge extra for parking, while bed and breakfasts and lodges in the countryside rarely do so. It is always advisable to book accommodation well in advance, particularly during festivals or at popular resorts on the coast from late spring to October. Most hotels in Spain offer Wi-Fi service, although mostly are charged based on an hourly rate.</p>
<p><strong>Grading: </strong>Hotels are graded from 1 to 5 stars with some regional variations. Hotels of three stars and above must have bar/caf&eacute; service with breakfast available and many of these categories have full restaurants. </p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Health"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Health]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="HealthTable" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Vaccinations]]></DataTitle><HealthInfo>Diphtheria<HealthPrecaution Name="Diphtheria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Hepatitis A<HealthPrecaution Name="Hepatitis A"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Malaria<HealthPrecaution Name="Malaria"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Rabies<HealthPrecaution Name="Rabies"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Tetanus<HealthPrecaution Name="Tetanus"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[Yes]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Typhoid<HealthPrecaution Name="Typhoid"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution>Yellow Fever<HealthPrecaution Name="Yellow Fever"><SpecialPrecaution><![CDATA[No]]></SpecialPrecaution></HealthPrecaution></HealthInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Health" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Health Care]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p>&lt;p&gt;Comprehensive travel insurance is advised for all other nationals, although basic health insurance is not essential. If suddenly ill or involved in an accident during a visit to Spain, free or reduced-cost necessary treatment is available for all nationalities. You just need to show your passport. In some medical cases, if you are European, you might be able to receive free treatment &amp;ndash; all you need is to show proof of a valid European Health Insurance Card (EHIC) obtained in their country of origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case of an emergency, call the Spanish emergency services at 112. This number should be dialled when you urgently require medical assistance or in case of fire or crime. You can dial the number from any public telephone booth, which is easily available in most Spanish cities and towns. However, keep in mind that the Spanish emergency services staff may not speak English, although some do. It is therefore useful to learn basics of the language like numbers and commonly used phrases. In such scenarios, try to be patient and speak as clearly as possible. Alternatively, look for help on the streets or in nearby shops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other numbers that you should take note of in case of emergency are:&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull;	Ambulance service &amp;ndash; 061&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull;	Fire service &amp;ndash; 080&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull;	Police &amp;ndash; 091&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull;	Duty pharmacies &amp;ndash; 010&lt;br /&gt;
If you are in dire need to get to the hospital, ask for a ride from people on the streets. Note that by law Spanish, it is obligatory for taxi drivers to transport medical emergencies to hospital when asked to do so. Any driver can also convert his vehicle into an ambulance in case of emergency. To do so, switch on the hazard lights of your vehicle and wave a white piece of cloth from the window to signal urgency. Misuse of this system will result in a heavy fine.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;Food in Spain is generally safe to eat. Most restaurants and bars adhere to a certain standard of hygiene. For those with sensitive stomachs, try to avoid street food, such as churros, kebabs and jacket potatoes. These are usually sold in small street-side stores especially in big cities like Madrid and Barcelona. Other foods to look out for include seafood that might not be fresh and sandwiches and omelettes that might have been left out for too long. Tapas bars may sometimes serve foods that have been kept overnight, so be careful what you eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foods sold in local markets are generally fresh and affordable. If you&amp;rsquo;re extremely careful about what you eat, these are the best places to look for clean and fresh produce. Tap water in Spain is safe to drink but some complain that tap water in Ibiza can be quite salty. Bottled and  mineral water are easily available throughout the country and can be  found in supermarkets and grocery stores.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;p&gt;In mid-summer temperatures can reach over 40&amp;deg;C and heat-related risks  are high. Be sure to drink plenty of water, avoid excessive alcohol consumption, wear strong  sunscreen and cover your skin with a hat and loose clothing. If  partaking in hiking, cycling or other outdoor activities avoid the  midday hours and limit exercise to early mornings or late evenings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The national police have set up a telephone hotline for tourists to use in non-emergencies. Those who wish to report a crime such as theft or lost property should call 902 102 112; callers can speak German, English, French or Italian. On islands such as  Ibiza be aware that alcohol and drugs are prevalent. Stay hydrated when consuming alcohol and be aware that spirit measurements are generous.&amp;nbsp;Taking drugs is illegal and drug dealing is dealt with very severely by the local police and courts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 20.3999996185303px;"&gt;In Mallorca in late summer waves of jellyfish can make an appearance, and while these are not deadly, they can give a very painful sting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PublicHolidays"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PublicHolidays" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Public Holidays]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Note:</b><![CDATA[<p>Additional dates are celebrated as regional public holidays.  * Regional observation only.</p>]]><b>Intro:</b><![CDATA[<p>Public holidays are listed here.</p>]]><p>New Year's Day :
							2018<br/>01 January </p><p>Epiphany :
							2018<br/>06 January </p><p>Day of the Balearic Islands :
							01 March </p><p>St Joseph's Day :
							19 March </p><p>Maundy Thursday :
							29 March </p><p>Good Friday :
							30 March </p><p>Labour Day :
							01 May </p><p>Assumption :
							15 August </p><p>National Day :
							12 October </p><p>All Saint's Day :
							01 November </p><p>Constitution Day :
							06 December </p><p>Immaculate Conception :
							08 December </p><p>Christmas Day :
							25 December </p><p>Boxing Day :
							26 December </p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="DutyFree"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Duty Free]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spain is within the European Union. If you are travelling from the <a class="internal" href="https://www.worldtravelguide.net/united-kingdom">UK</a>, you are entitled to buy fragrance, skincare, cosmetics, Champagne, wine, selected spirits, fashion accessories, gifts and souvenirs - all at tax-free equivalent prices.</p>
<p>If you are travelling from within the EU, there is no limit on the amount or value of goods you may import, providing your goods are for personal consumption. Goods imported for commercial purposes are subject to duty and the following guideline amounts are in place to determine whether this is the case:</p>
<p>&bull; 800 cigarettes or 400 cigarillos or 200 cigars or 1kg of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 10L of spirits over 22% volume, 20L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume, 90L of wine (no more than 60L of sparkling wine) and 110L of beer.</p>
<p>If you are arriving from a non-EU country, the following goods may be imported into Spain by persons over 18 years of age without incurring customs duty:</p>
<p>&bull; 200 cigarettes or 100 cigarillos or 50 cigars or 250g of tobacco.<br />
&bull; 4L of wine and 16L of beer and 1L of spirits over 22% volume or 2L of alcoholic beverages less than 22% volume.<br />
&bull; Other goods up to the value of &euro;430 for air and sea travellers and &euro;300 for other travellers.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Imports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Meat and dairy products from outside the EU, and unauthorised firearms and ammunition.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Prohibited Exports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Endangered species require an export permit.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Regulations]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Import Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Export Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Dutry Free]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="DutyFree" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[EU Import/Export]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Currency"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Money]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Currency" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Euro (EUR; symbol &euro;) = 100 cents (<em>c&eacute;ntimos</em>). Notes are in denominations of &euro;500, 200, 100, 50, 20, 10 and 5. Coins are in denominations of &euro;2 and 1, and 50, 20, 10, 5, 2 and 1 cents.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyExchange" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Exchange]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Money can be changed in any bank, and at most travel agencies, major hotels and airports.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Cards" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Credit/Debit Cards and ATMs]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard/Cirrus and Visa/Plus are accepted in nearly all ATMs, which are common throughout the country. These credit cards can generally be used outside main towns and cities, although cash is your safest bet.</p><p>American Express, Diners Club, MasterCard/Cirrus and Visa/Plus are accepted in nearly all ATMs, which are common throughout the country. There are usually at least one bank and ATM in each village.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="TravellersCheques" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Traveller's Cheques]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Traveller's cheques are disappearing from use fast, and it's far more convenient to travel with credit cards these days. Nevertheless, you can still change them in main bank branches and exchange bureaux, and they are accepted in major hotels. It is advisable to bring them in sterling or dollars as there have been increasing reports of Euro cheques being refused.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CurrencyRestrictions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Currency Restrictions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="BankingHours" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Banking Hours]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Generally Mon-Fri 0830-1400. Some branches open Saturdays too, from October to April.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExchangeRate" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Exchange Rate Indicators]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData></Section><Section Name="PassportVisaRequirements"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Passport/Visa]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="PassportTable" ContentTypeID="14"><DataTitle><![CDATA[Summary]]></DataTitle><PassportInfo><PassportInfoCountry Name="British"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Australian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Canadian"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="USA"><PassportRequired>Yes</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry><PassportInfoCountry Name="Other EU"><PassportRequired>1</PassportRequired><ReturnTicketRequired>No</ReturnTicketRequired><VisaRequired>No</VisaRequired></PassportInfoCountry></PassportInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainPassportFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Passports]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A passport valid for three months beyond the length of stay and issued within the past 10 years is required by all nationals listed in the chart above except (<strong>1</strong>) EU nationals holding a passport or national ID card which is valid for the duration of stay.</p>
<p>If travelling from one border-free Schengen country to another however, EU nationals are not required to show a passport or national ID card. It is still recommended that you travel with your passport or ID card to prove your identity if necessary though. Note that Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Ireland, Romania and the UK are not part of the Schengen area, so a passport or ID card is required if travelling to/from these countries.</p>
<p>EU nationals are not required to possess a return ticket or show sufficient funds.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Children]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="MainVisaFields" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Visa Note]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Transit]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>A transit visa will only allow entrance into the international transit area and not into Spain. You are not allowed to leave the airport.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Schengen Visas]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spain is part of the Schengen visa scheme.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Types of Visa and Cost]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: &euro;60.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Validity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa: 90 days within a six-month period.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Applications to:]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Consulate (or consular section at embassy). UK residents should apply to the Spain Visa Application Centre (<a href="https://uk.blsspainvisa.com" target="_blank">https://uk.blsspainvisa.com</a>), which charges an additional processing fee. All visa applicants aged 12 and over must submit biometric data at their visa appointment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Temporary Residence]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>If you're a non-EU citizen planning on staying longer than 90 days, you should apply for a <em>visado de residencia</em> (residence visa) from the Spanish Embassy in your home country before departure. This allows for the residency application process to begin.</p>
<p>EU citizens staying beyond 90 days must obtain a registration certificate at the Oficina de Extranjeros or local police station.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="VisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Working Days Required]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Allow at least five working days for visa processing. Some cases may take longer however.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="SufficientFunds" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa applicants must be able to provide proof of funds to cover their stay.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="ExtensionOfStay" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle/><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Schengen visa holders wishing to stay longer than 90 days in Spain should obtain an extension from the Spanish immigration authorities. This will only be granted under exceptional circumstances.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PassportVisaNote" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Entry With Pets]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Visitors are allowed to bring pets into Spain, provided that they carry the pet passport or international vaccination health certification with them. If you&rsquo;re travelling from the UK to Spain with your pet, you need to check the regulations of the pet travel scheme (<a href="http://www.gov.uk/take-pet-abroad/pet-passport" target="_blank">www.gov.uk/take-pet-abroad/pet-passport</a>). If you&rsquo;re travelling from elsewhere, be sure to have a valid veterinary certificate, valid rabies vaccines and a microchip. Before flying to Spain, you should check with your airline regarding their pet travel regulations. Some carriers do not transport pets in the luggage compartment.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="General"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Key Facts]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="Location" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Location]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><b>Latitude: </b><![CDATA[40.396016]]><b>Longitude: </b><![CDATA[-3.551021]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Area" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Area]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>504,782 sq km (194,897 sq miles). Includes Balearics, Canaries, Ceuta, and Melilla.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Population" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>46,064,604 (UN estimate 2016).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="PopulationDensity" ContentTypeID=""><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>95.4 per sq km.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="CapitalCity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Capital]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Madrid.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Government" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Parliamentary monarchy.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Geography" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Geography]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spain shares the Iberian Peninsula with its smaller neighbour, Portugal, and is bordered to the northeast by the Pyrenees mountain range that cuts across France and Andorra. Surrounded by the Atlantic Ocean and the Mediterranean Sea, Spain has numerous stretches of coastline that are extremely crowded especially in summer.</p>
<p>Spain has two main groups of islands that are popular with tourists: the Balearic Islands (Mallorca, Menorca, Ibiza and Formentera) located 193km (120 miles) southeast of Barcelona, and the Canary Islands off the west coast of Africa (mainly Tenerife, Gran Canaria, Fuerteventura, Lanzarote and La Palma). Located in continental Africa, the tiny enclaves of Ceuta and Melilla also form a part of Spain.</p>
<p>Mainland Spain is the second highest and most mountainous country in Europe, with an average height of 610m (2,000ft). The Pyrenees stretch roughly 400km (249 miles) from the Basque Country's Atlantic coast. In places the peaks rise to over 1,524m (5,000ft), the highest point being 3,404m (11,169ft).</p>
<p>The main physical feature of Spain is the vast central plateau, or <em>meseta</em>, divided by several chains of sierras. The higher northern area includes Castile and Le&oacute;n and the southern section comprises Castile-La Mancha and Extremadura. In the south, the high plains rise further at the Sierra Morena before falling abruptly at the great valley of the Guadalquivir.</p>
<p>Southeast of Granada is the Sierra Nevada, which runs parallel to the Mediterranean. Its summit Mulhacen, at 3,718m (12,198ft), is the highest point on the Spanish peninsula. The highest peak in Spain is the Pico del Teide on Tenerife in the Canaries, measuring a height of 3,718m (12,198ft).</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Language" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Language]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Religion" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Religion]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>There is no official religion in Spain. Approximately 73% of the population is Roman Catholic, while 22% has no religion. The young generation are less religious than before, but most still celebrate religious festivals. There are approximately 1 million Muslims (2.3% of the country) living in Spain.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Time" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Time]]></DataTitle><DataInfo/></OutputData><OutputData Name="Social Conventions" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Social Conventions]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Spanish life has undergone rapid change in recent decades and stricter religious customs have been superseded by more modern ways, particularly in the cities and among women. In spite of this, traditions remain strong; hospitality, chivalry and courtesy thrive. Handshaking is the customary form of greeting between men, while women (outside of a business context) are greeted with a fleeting kiss to either cheek (left then right). <br />
<br />
Spaniards eat late; lunch around 1400-1530; the evening meal 2100-2300. The Spanish have two family names; the maternal surname follows the paternal, but is rarely used outside a formal context. Smoking has long been banned in offices, shops, schools, hospitals, cultural centres and on public transport, but in 2011 that ban was extended to all bars, cafes and restaurants. Spain now has one of the toughest anti-smoking laws in Europe.&nbsp;</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="Electricity" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Electricity]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>230 volts AC, 50Hz. European plugs with two round pins are standard.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfGovernment" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of Government]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister&nbsp;Pedro S&aacute;nchez since 2018.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="HeadOfState" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Head of State]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>King Felipe VI of Spain since 2014.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="RecentHistory" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Recent History]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>The human history of the area now known as Spain is a long one. Remains found in the Atapuerca Mountains indicate that man first arrived in Spain almost one million years ago. The Phoenicians, Greeks, Romans and Visigoths would all later settle here and, in the 8th century, Muslims came to the Iberian Peninsula, kick-starting a centuries-long power struggle between Muslims and Christians, with the latter group eventually establishing the upper hand in the 15th century.</p>
<p>In terms of global influence, Spain&rsquo;s heyday came between the 16th and mid-17th centuries. During this era, the Spaniards led a charge on the newly discovered New World, hijacking valuable minerals and metals to bankroll the Crown. The Spanish Empire soon became the most extensive the world had ever seen, encompassing territory across Europe, the Americas, Africa and Asia. However, the superpower began to fade in the early 1800s when Napoleon took over Spain. An atmosphere of political instability and uncertainty gave rise to anti-colonial revolts, while many of the country&rsquo;s colonial conquests broke free.</p>
<p>In the 1930s, Spain suffered tremendously from a civil war, resulting in massacres of civilians and prisoners all over the nation. The war cost hundreds of thousands of lives and ended in a nationalist dictatorship, led by General Francisco Franco. During his 36-year rule, Spain remained largely isolated from the outside world &ndash; both economically and culturally.</p>
<p>The death of Franco in 1975 marked a new era for Spain: a rapid transition from dictatorship to liberal democracy and the return of the Bourbon monarch headed by Prince Juan Carlos. In 1981, members of the Guardia Civil attempted a coup d&rsquo;etat, but failed thanks to the intervention of the King.</p>
<p>Spain joined the European Union (then known as European Economic Community) in 1986 and adopted the Euro in 1999. Since hosting the 1992 Olympics and Seville Expo, the country has undergone significant progress in development, including social reforms such as the legalisation of same-sex marriage, the modernisation of divorce laws and an increase of the minimum wage, as well as infrastructural improvements.</p>
<p>Like many of the European states, Spain was hit hard by the 2008 recession and required a rescue package to help keep its shaky banking sector afloat. Though Spain has shown signs of recovery, unemployment remains high and the political landscape is somewhat uncertain: the 2015 election resulted in the most fragmented parliament in Spain&rsquo;s history. Meanwhile, Catalonia, in northeast Spain, claims it will become independent in 2017.</p>
<p><strong>Did you know?</strong><br />
&bull;	In 2015, more than 100 years after building began, Gaud&iacute;&rsquo;s Sagrada Fam&iacute;lia basilica in Barcelona entered its final stage of construction.<br />
&bull;	While other countries have the tooth fairy, Spain has Ratoncito P&eacute;rez, a mouse who exchanges lost teeth for gifts.<br />
&bull;	The United Nations have predicted that by 2050, Spain will have the oldest population in the world, with 40% of its citizens over 60.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="ContactAddresses"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Contact Addresses]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Embassy and Consulate in the USA]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 452 0100.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.spainemb.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+1 202 452 0100.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0900-1700.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>2375 Pennsylvania Ave NW<br/>Washington<br/>20037<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Consulate in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7589 8989.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.conspalon.org</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7589 8989.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1400 (visa information by appointment only).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>20 Draycott Pl<br/>London<br/>SW3 2SB<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Spanish Embassy in the UK]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7235 5555.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://spain.embassyhomepage.com</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+44 20 7235 5555.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0930-1400&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>39 Chesham Pl<br/>London<br/>SW1X 8HW<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData><OutputData Name="UsefulAddress" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[British Embassy in Spain]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><p><b>Tel:</b>+34 917 146 300.</p><p><b>Website:</b>http://www.ukinspain.fco.gov.uk</p><p><b>Tel:</b>+34 917 146 300.</p><p><b>Opening Times:</b>&lt;p&gt;Mon-Fri 0830-1600 (phone line); Mon-Fri 0830-1330 (consulate).&lt;/p&gt;</p><p><b>Address:</b><br/>Paseo de la Castellana, 259D<br/>Madrid<br/>28046<br/></p></DataInfo></OutputData></Section><Section Name="Overview"><SectionTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></SectionTitle><OutputData Name="CountryOverview" ContentTypeID=""><DataTitle><![CDATA[Overview]]></DataTitle><DataInfo><![CDATA[<p>From riotous fiestas and sizzling cuisine to world-class museums and cutting-edge art galleries, there&rsquo;s a reason why Spain endures as one of the world&rsquo;s most popular destinations. Like the country&rsquo;s famous tapas, Spain itself is a tempting smorgasbord of bustling cities, scenic countryside and sunny islands, which visitors can nibble away at on repeat trips or consume in one giant feast. Either way, it is one appetising nation.</p>
<p>In spite of its myriad attractions, most come to Spain for sun, sand and self-indulgence, flocking to the likes of the Costa del Sol and Costa Brava to while away days on beaches and nights in clubs. An early pioneer of package holidays, Spain&rsquo;s leading resorts have long been geared up for the mass market &ndash; from the Balearics to the Canary Islands &ndash; but it&rsquo;s not all sprawling hotel complexes; quaint fishing villages, bijou retreats and secluded beaches abound if you&rsquo;re looking to veer off the tourist trail.</p>
<p>Spain is much more than holidays in the sun, though. Away from the beach there&rsquo;s an extraordinary variety of things to do; from climbing snow-capped peaks in the Pyr&eacute;n&eacute;es to hiking the ancient pilgrimage route of St James&rsquo;s Way; from diving in the protected Medes Islands to stargazing in Tenerife. Alternatively, you could drop in on one of the country&rsquo;s many festivals (think Running of the Bulls, La Tomatina and the Baby Jumping Festival) which are madder than a box of frogs.</p>
<p>And then there are the cities; Madrid, Barcelona, Bilbao, Seville, Valencia, the list goes on. Each one of these vibrant metropolises has their own distinct flavour; the Dali architecture and sweeping beaches of Barcelona seem a long way from the wide boulevards and soaring skyscrapers of Madrid (though the Catalans wish it was further).&nbsp;</p>
<p>But for all their disparities, these cities are bound by Spain&rsquo;s remarkable history and enviable cultural feats, which are proudly displayed in the country&rsquo;s museums, galleries and UNESCO World Heritage Sites. Suffice to say, its popularity shows no sign of waning.</p><p>From riotous fiestas and sizzling cuisine to world-class museums and cutting-edge art galleries, there&rsquo;s a reason why Spain endures as one of the world&rsquo;s most popular destinations. Like the country&rsquo;s famous tapas, Spain itself is a tempting smorgasbord of bustling cities, scenic countryside and sunny islands, which visitors can nibble away at on repeat trips or consume in one giant feast. Either way, it is one appetising nation.</p>]]></DataInfo></OutputData></Section></Region></WTG>
